<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<rdf:RDF
 xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
 xmlns="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/"
 xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
 xmlns:taxo="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/taxonomy/"
 xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
 xmlns:syn="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
 xmlns:admin="http://webns.net/mvcb/"
>

<channel rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/">
<title>nlin.AO updates on arXiv.org</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">Nonlinear Sciences -- Adaptation and Self-Organizing Systems (nlin.AO) updates on the arXiv.org e-print archive</description>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:date>2022-11-03T20:30:00-05:00</dc:date>
<dc:publisher>help@arxiv.org</dc:publisher>
<dc:subject>Nonlinear Sciences -- Adaptation and Self-Organizing Systems</dc:subject>
<syn:updateBase>1901-01-01T00:00+00:00</syn:updateBase>
<syn:updateFrequency>1</syn:updateFrequency>
<syn:updatePeriod>daily</syn:updatePeriod>
<items>
 <rdf:Seq>
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01698" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01831" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01955" />
 </rdf:Seq>
</items>
<image rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif" />
</channel>
<image rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif">
<title>arXiv.org</title>
<url>http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif</url>
<link>http://arxiv.org/</link>
</image>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01698">
<title>Scaling up the self-optimization model by means of on-the-fly computation of weights. (arXiv:2211.01698v1 [nlin.AO])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01698</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The Self-Optimization (SO) model is a useful computational model for
investigating self-organization in &quot;soft&quot; Artificial life (ALife) as it has
been shown to be general enough to model various complex adaptive systems. So
far, existing work has been done on relatively small network sizes, precluding
the investigation of novel phenomena that might emerge from the complexity
arising from large numbers of nodes interacting in interconnected networks.
This work introduces a novel implementation of the SO model that scales as
$\mathcal{O}\left(N^{2}\right)$ with respect to the number of nodes $N$, and
demonstrates the applicability of the SO model to networks with system sizes
several orders of magnitude higher than previously was investigated. Removing
the prohibitive computational cost of the naive $\mathcal{O}\left(N^{3}\right)$
algorithm, our on-the-fly computation paves the way for investigating
substantially larger system sizes, allowing for more variety and complexity in
future studies.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/nlin/1/au:+Weber_N/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Natalya Weber&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/nlin/1/au:+Koch_W/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Werner Koch&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/nlin/1/au:+Froese_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Tom Froese&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01831">
<title>Polynomial Life: the Structure of Adaptive Systems. (arXiv:2211.01831v1 [nlin.AO])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01831</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We extend our earlier work on the compositional structure of cybernetic
systems in order to account for the embodiment of such systems. All their
interactions proceed through their bodies&apos; boundaries: sensations impinge on
their surfaces, and actions correspond to changes in their configurations. We
formalize this morphological perspective using polynomial functors. The
&apos;internal universes&apos; of systems are shown to constitute an indexed category of
statistical games over polynomials; their dynamics form an indexed category of
behaviours. We characterize &apos;active inference doctrines&apos; as indexed functors
between such categories, resolving a number of open problems in our earlier
work, and pointing to a formalization of the &apos;free energy principle&apos; as adjoint
to such doctrines. We illustrate our framework through fundamental examples
from biology, including homeostasis, morphogenesis, and autopoiesis, and
suggest a formal connection between spatial navigation and the process of
proof.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/nlin/1/au:+Smithe_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Toby St Clere Smithe&lt;/a&gt; (Topos Institute)</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01955">
<title>Quantifying the `end of history&apos; through a Bayesian Markov-chain approach. (arXiv:2211.01955v1 [physics.soc-ph])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01955</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Political regimes have been changing throughout human history. After the
apparent triumph of liberal democracies at the end of the twentieth century,
Francis Fukuyama and others have been arguing that humankind is approaching an
`end of history&apos; (EoH) in the form of a universality of liberal democracies.
This view has been challenged by recent developments that seem to indicate the
rise of defective democracies across the globe. There has been no attempt to
quantify the expected EoH with a statistical approach. In this study, we model
the transition between political regimes as a Markov process and -- using a
Bayesian inference approach -- we estimate the transition probabilities between
political regimes from time-series data describing the evolution of political
regimes from 1800--2018. We then compute the steady state for this Markov
process which represents a mathematical abstraction of the EoH and predicts
that approximately 46 % of countries will be full democracies. Furthermore, we
find that, under our model, the fraction of autocracies in the world is
expected to increase for the next half-century before it declines. Using
random-walk theory, we then estimate survival curves of different types of
regimes and estimate characteristic lifetimes of democracies and autocracies of
244 years and 69 years, respectively. Quantifying the expected EoH allows us to
challenge common beliefs about the nature of political equilibria.
Specifically, we find no statistical evidence that the EoH constitutes a fixed,
complete omnipresence of democratic regimes.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Klimm_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Florian Klimm&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
</rdf:RDF>