<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns:yt="http://www.youtube.com/xml/schemas/2015" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
 <link rel="self" href="http://www.youtube.com/feeds/videos.xml?channel_id=UC0uTPqBCFIpZxlz_Lv1tk_g"/>
 <id>yt:channel:UC0uTPqBCFIpZxlz_Lv1tk_g</id>
 <yt:channelId>UC0uTPqBCFIpZxlz_Lv1tk_g</yt:channelId>
 <title>Protesilaos Stavrou</title>
 <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC0uTPqBCFIpZxlz_Lv1tk_g"/>
 <author>
  <name>Protesilaos Stavrou</name>
  <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC0uTPqBCFIpZxlz_Lv1tk_g</uri>
 </author>
 <published>2014-05-06T07:48:51+00:00</published>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:cje3uS9PuOg</id>
  <yt:videoId>cje3uS9PuOg</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UC0uTPqBCFIpZxlz_Lv1tk_g</yt:channelId>
  <title>Philosophy: on dignity</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=cje3uS9PuOg"/>
  <author>
   <name>Protesilaos Stavrou</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC0uTPqBCFIpZxlz_Lv1tk_g</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-11-04T10:43:51+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-11-05T01:51:54+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Philosophy: on dignity</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/cje3uS9PuOg?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i4.ytimg.com/vi/cje3uS9PuOg/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>Find all my publications on my website: https://protesilaos.com

* * *

I hiked for about an hour while expounding on the philosophical theme of dignity.  This is the continuation of my previous two presentations (each of which is ~1 hour long):

* About &quot;sorry for being a burden&quot;: https://protesilaos.com/books/2022-10-31-sorry-for-being-burden/.
* On the meaning and purpose of life: https://protesilaos.com/books/2022-11-02-meaning-purpose-life/.

It is not necessary to watch the previous two, as I summarise the points relevant to dignity.  Though you may still want to watch or listen to them as they contain lots of ideas.

Overview of what I talked about today:

* I made a mistake for saying that &quot;today is Thursday&quot;.  It is Friday, 4 November 2022.
* Explanation of the underpinnings of &quot;sorry for being a burden&quot;.  In short, it consists of (i) selfcentredness, (ii) obsession that turns into a bias that reduces others into the opposite of what the object of obsession is, and (iii) a rationalisation that self-loathing or self-hatred is a virtue because the person only does it for the good of others.
* Self-loathing masquerading as altruism is not really altruistic because it still contains misanthropy (misanthropy==hatred of humans) for someone: the self.
* Note what &quot;meaning&quot; in life is.  Basically, it is a subjective evaluation of experiences in one's life that keeps them going.  When we find meaning in things we do, we continue doing them.
* I decouple &quot;purpose&quot; for meaning for reasons that I explain at length in the aforementioned presentation.  The gist is that we can have meaning without it.
* Dignity is the inherent worth of someone.  Loss of dignity is a subjective affair.  A state of mind where the person assess their worth and concludes that their life's experiences no longer have meaning.
* I don't think we can say anything about the subjectivity as such.  If a person thinks they have no dignity, that is for them to say (this point is revisited and explained further in the video).  Though we can still comment on matters surrounding the subjective evaluation as such.
* Consideration of examples that cover matters of tunnel vision, the balance in one's life experiences when seen holistically, and the dynamism of the case (basically, the lack of a person's omniscience and how that relates to hope).  I essentially ask the person to set a high bar and not take this issue lightly.
* Comment on matters of euthanasia and suicide in reference to the movie &quot;Mar adentro&quot;.  In short: there comes a point where the person is stating in full conscience that their life has no meaning to them.  We should acknowledge their agency, the dignity inherent therein, and accept their decision.
* There cannot be an objective, one-size-fits-all criterion because that contradicts subjectivity.  What a person thinks of their own self is no longer relevant if some committee/authority decides on their behalf.  Generalising this means that dignity cannot exist, as each individual's inherent worth would be cancelled through the denial of their agency and capacity to know what they feel.
* More comments on suicide and how it is narrow-minded (i.e. wrong) to dismiss concerns for dignity as merely one seeking attention.

At several points in the video I show some breathtaking vistas and use them as metaphors for our life.  We may be walking on a dirt road, thinking that it is like all other dirt roads we have traversed before.  But we do not know what we might find at the next turn.</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="19" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="174"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:yucjFSm1ERQ</id>
  <yt:videoId>yucjFSm1ERQ</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UC0uTPqBCFIpZxlz_Lv1tk_g</yt:channelId>
  <title>Philosophy: meaning and purpose of life</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=yucjFSm1ERQ"/>
  <author>
   <name>Protesilaos Stavrou</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC0uTPqBCFIpZxlz_Lv1tk_g</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-11-02T12:35:38+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-11-04T23:54:56+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Philosophy: meaning and purpose of life</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/yucjFSm1ERQ?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i2.ytimg.com/vi/yucjFSm1ERQ/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>Find all my publications on my website: https://protesilaos.com

* * *

I traversed the mountains and talked for about 1 hour and 10 minutes on matters of philosophy.  Outline:

* An explanation of what I mean when I claim that no-one is special: our shared humanity and co-existence with all forms of life.
* Why not being special makes life simpler.  We accept that not everything is a function of our volition.
* Explain how this affects the binary of reward and punishment and why our life becomes easier.
* Start with the point of what is purpose and what is meaning.  The former is the ulterior end for which something happens.  The latter is our evaluation of a state of affairs: how we feel about it.
* Discuss how I proceed from the little things.  How, for example, the colours I see and the warmth of the Sun engender certain emotions---I add meaning to those experiences.
* Elaborate why the purpose does not need to exist.  We then develop a transactional outlook of not actually caring about the experiences.  We only cater to them to the extend that they bring us closer the end goal.  We are not genuine.  Also see my talk about &quot;Forgiveness and hubris&quot;: https://protesilaos.com/books/2022-10-25-forgiveness-hubris/.
* The purpose denies us our presence.
* Comment on how the absence of purpose pertains to reward and punishment.  We do not need to ground reward and punishment in some greater authority for them to work.
* Remark how mere knowledge of ultimate reward/punishment (heaven and hell) does not instil in us a sense of doing what is right.
* Continue with the argument of not needing a purpose by using more examples of applied rules.
* Expound on the same argument, but in theistic terms.  Explain how omniscience precludes experimentation and that a perfect God does not need to test anything, for that contradicts omniscience.
* Propound the view that in the absence of consensus regarding theist matters, our only takeaways is that we are not sure.  So we should not project our perceived need for purpose as God's need for purpose.
* Connect those points to social matters: beauty, fame, power.  Also watch my presentation &quot;About 'sorry for being a burden'&quot;: https://protesilaos.com/books/2022-10-31-sorry-for-being-burden/.
* Talk about the experience of meeting a &quot;fabulous&quot; person at a restaurant and how their purpose was detracting from the meaning in their life.
* Tie it all together.</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="22" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="317"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:TCUPJHXMQkQ</id>
  <yt:videoId>TCUPJHXMQkQ</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UC0uTPqBCFIpZxlz_Lv1tk_g</yt:channelId>
  <title>Philosophy: &quot;sorry for being a burden!&quot;</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=TCUPJHXMQkQ"/>
  <author>
   <name>Protesilaos Stavrou</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC0uTPqBCFIpZxlz_Lv1tk_g</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-10-31T14:54:45+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-11-02T06:12:30+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Philosophy: &quot;sorry for being a burden!&quot;</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/TCUPJHXMQkQ?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i1.ytimg.com/vi/TCUPJHXMQkQ/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>Find all my publications on my website: https://protesilaos.com

* * *

I hiked and talked philosophy for a bit more than an hour.  I covered a broad set of topics related to the expression &quot;sorry for being a burden&quot;.  An overview:

* We start feeling like a burden when we are coping with some difficult situation.  We think that others are doing well, while we are not.
* We do not want to bring others to our misery, so we avoid them.
* Not wanting to externalise our negativity in this way comes from a good starting point: we consider the wellness of others.
* An explanation of how this apparent altruism is biased both against us and against the others.  We think we are worthless while they are impeccable.
* When we think we are a burden, we develop a sense of egocentrism even though we do not want to.  We do it by obsessing about our condition.
* Our obsession turns into a misplaced sense of exceptionalism as we think we are special in our agony: &quot;I am special because I am the only one who suffers&quot;.
* There is a &quot;transmission mechanism&quot; by which this ostensible burden can be distributed.  Explanation of how this relates to the communicative aspect of the human condition.
* We cannot opt out of our humanity.  To be sorry for being human is pointless.  We always communicate.
* When we communicate with others, we open ourselves to their positivity.  In general, we remove the obstacles that worsen our condition.
* Explanation of moderation, of finding a middle way between the extremes.
* More comments on the perversion of self-hatred that masquerades as altruism.
* Practical ways to gradually escape from the overthinking loop.  We break the cycle by acting.  Also comment on one's physical condition and how idle energy is contributing to the problem.
* We live in a world where we forget to be human sometimes and are absorbed in our little bubble---practical step to avoid that.
* Example with how we do not control how others perceive our messages and why we should not blame our self or them.
* Don't judge and be patient.</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="34" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="442"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:cc335wPXRlQ</id>
  <yt:videoId>cc335wPXRlQ</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UC0uTPqBCFIpZxlz_Lv1tk_g</yt:channelId>
  <title>Philosophy: discipline and self-restraint</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=cc335wPXRlQ"/>
  <author>
   <name>Protesilaos Stavrou</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC0uTPqBCFIpZxlz_Lv1tk_g</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-10-27T11:47:03+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-10-29T18:11:09+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Philosophy: discipline and self-restraint</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/cc335wPXRlQ?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i4.ytimg.com/vi/cc335wPXRlQ/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>Find all my publications on my website: https://protesilaos.com

* * *

I climbed the mountain and sat at its top, all while talking philosophy.  This video is about an hour long.  These are the main themes:

* Story about me when I was younger, which illustrates how I had the appearance of discipline without a solid grasp of the &quot;why&quot;
* Continuation of that story, delving into my bad habit with alcohol consumption.  The gist is that I overestimated my ability by believing in my own narrative of how disciplined I was---a mistake.
* How can we have self-restraint without a good understanding of our self and of our limits?
* Discussion on the introspection---the search for the &quot;why&quot;---that made me understand the reason I was behaving in that bad way (where alcohol was the facilitator and enabler of certain experiences).
* Tie it all together in an exposition about not talking big and not overestimating our abilities.
* Comment on three more stories that further explain these and related ideas.
* In short: be patient, take it slow, do not assume that you are special, do not talk big, have a sense of purpose that is consistent with your actuality, put yourself to the test in order to learn who you are (what you can and cannot do).

Related videos:

* Forgiveness and hubris: https://protesilaos.com/books/2022-10-25-forgiveness-hubris/
* On self-improvement: https://protesilaos.com/books/2022-10-21-self-improvement/
* Loss, entitlement, and presence: https://protesilaos.com/books/2022-10-17-loss-entitlement-presence/</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="40" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="468"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:EgDpc2Oh4LE</id>
  <yt:videoId>EgDpc2Oh4LE</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UC0uTPqBCFIpZxlz_Lv1tk_g</yt:channelId>
  <title>Philosophy: forgiveness and hubris</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=EgDpc2Oh4LE"/>
  <author>
   <name>Protesilaos Stavrou</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC0uTPqBCFIpZxlz_Lv1tk_g</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-10-25T15:15:15+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-10-29T06:45:26+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Philosophy: forgiveness and hubris</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/EgDpc2Oh4LE?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i2.ytimg.com/vi/EgDpc2Oh4LE/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>Find all my publications on my website: https://protesilaos.com

* * *

I walked and talked philosophy for an hour.  In this presentation, I talked about the substance of values, with forgiveness as a case in point.  To make the topic more relatable, I described what &quot;hubris&quot; is and offered some concrete examples.

The contents in brief:

* Real story of a person that would not let go of something trivial that happened more than 30 years ago.
* Link it to the mistake of appreciating forgiveness or anything pertaining to self-improvement only with regard to its ultimate rewards.  This also relates to the previous entry [on self-improvement](https://protesilaos.com/books/2022-10-21-self-improvement/).
* The practical aspect of forgiveness in the here-and-now is that we keep ourselves free from useless burdens, else garbage.  We can then focus our limited resources on something more useful.
* Talk about the myth of Sisyphus and how it essentially describes the struggles of the person who does not let go.
* Comment on the theme of non-ownership, though it is not the focus here.  I talked more about this in [loss, entitlement, and presence](https://protesilaos.com/books/2022-10-17-loss-entitlement-presence/).
* Explain another story of me not becoming a priest and how it relates to this case.
* Talk about the misplaced ritualistic view we have of certain precepts.  Basically, we miss the point as we cater to the appearances while disregarding the essential teachings.</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="26" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="311"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:EJOoBWcFdio</id>
  <yt:videoId>EJOoBWcFdio</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UC0uTPqBCFIpZxlz_Lv1tk_g</yt:channelId>
  <title>Philosophy: on  self-improvement</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=EJOoBWcFdio"/>
  <author>
   <name>Protesilaos Stavrou</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC0uTPqBCFIpZxlz_Lv1tk_g</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-10-21T16:29:50+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-10-22T14:56:59+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Philosophy: on  self-improvement</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/EJOoBWcFdio?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i2.ytimg.com/vi/EJOoBWcFdio/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>Find all my publications on my website: https://protesilaos.com

* * *

In this entry, I scaled a mountain to make a philosophical point pertinent to the titular topic.  This talk is a bit less than an hour long.  The main ideas:

* We sometimes think of self-improvement only as a means to an ulterior goal, such as money, fame, sex.
* Use the example of climbing to the top of the mountain in hope of finding those &quot;rewards&quot;.
* Elaborate on the connection between the transactional view of self-improvement and the concept of entitlement.  The latter was also covered in my previous talk about [loss, entitlement, and presence](https://protesilaos.com/books/2022-10-17-loss-entitlement-presence/).
* Explain that self-importance is okay but how it can go awry.  A relevant theme was covered in my talk about [On self-importance and elitism](https://protesilaos.com/books/2022-10-09-self-importance-elitism/).
* Discuss how philosophy helps us overcome the self-centric view.  We do not expect rewards.
* Talk about expectations and entitlement, with a view to how they can make a person turn their disappointment into a weapon that is used against others.
* Remark how philosophy helps us remain calm and not go to extremes.</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="45" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="572"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:_5xle0NYFFE</id>
  <yt:videoId>_5xle0NYFFE</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UC0uTPqBCFIpZxlz_Lv1tk_g</yt:channelId>
  <title>Philosophy: loss, entitlement, and presence</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_5xle0NYFFE"/>
  <author>
   <name>Protesilaos Stavrou</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC0uTPqBCFIpZxlz_Lv1tk_g</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-10-17T16:54:20+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-10-18T10:33:52+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Philosophy: loss, entitlement, and presence</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/_5xle0NYFFE?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i4.ytimg.com/vi/_5xle0NYFFE/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>Find all my publications on my website: https://protesilaos.com.

* * *

Thanks to Dmitry Matveyev for the 500 EUR donation that allowed me to buy the smartphone (Samsung A53) and selfie stick that I use to record these videos in the great outdoors.

* * *

In this entry, I walked in the mountains and talked about developing the right attitude for dealing with matters we do not control.  The main points:

- A story of mine about remaining open to new experiences after misfortune strikes.
- You do not control all the factors.  If you assume the blame, you imply that you do control those factors.
- If you think you are a god, you will always overestimate your abilities.  You will then desire to achieve that which you cannot.  The disconnect will make you suffer.
- An explanation of non-ownership with specific examples.
- Elaboration on the bad habit of dithering, delaying, and postponing.  You think you control time, again overestimating yourself.
- Overthinking and overanalysing is to your detriment.  Fundamentally, you make the mistake of assuming that the perfect is attainable.
- Thinking that the perfect is attainable means that you expect your actions to be perfect.  But to act is to do so in imperfect circumstances, with incomplete knowledge.
- To act is to perform a leap of faith.  There is faith in acting.
- More examples that tie it all together.</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="39" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="527"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:VOU443wsePA</id>
  <yt:videoId>VOU443wsePA</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UC0uTPqBCFIpZxlz_Lv1tk_g</yt:channelId>
  <title>Philosophy: showing off, demonstration, and overthinking (feat Chantara WATERFALL)</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VOU443wsePA"/>
  <author>
   <name>Protesilaos Stavrou</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC0uTPqBCFIpZxlz_Lv1tk_g</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-10-14T12:27:20+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-10-17T04:23:51+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Philosophy: showing off, demonstration, and overthinking (feat Chantara WATERFALL)</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/VOU443wsePA?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i3.ytimg.com/vi/VOU443wsePA/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>This is another video of mine where I do philosophy.  There is no transcript.  The part with the waterfall of Chantara at the Troodos mountain range (Cyprus) starts after the 15:00 mark.  I noticed that whenever I toggled between the front and rear cameras, there was an interruption or distortion to the audio.  I think nothing critical is lost, though I will try to find ways to improve this while still keeping it recording in one go.

Some of the other videos of mine that I mention here:

- On meditation, walking, and acceptance :: https://protesilaos.com/books/2022-10-07-meditation-walking-acceptance/
- On self-importance and elitism :: https://protesilaos.com/books/2022-10-09-self-importance-elitism/
- Practicality, honesty, and patience :: https://protesilaos.com/books/2022-10-13-practicality-honesty-patience/

The main points I covered:

- There is a distinction between showing off and demonstrating something, but in practice it is hard to draw clear lines.
- I am an Internet stranger to you (and you to me), which means that you have no means of verifying my claims.  This adds to the problem with the unclear lines.
- In turn, I cannot control how you perceive of what I consider &quot;demonstration&quot;---you may still think it is me &quot;showing off&quot;.
- Explanation of the perils of overthinking. Life is practical, not theoretical.
- My corpus of work---such as this video of me walking and talking---is a demonstration against overthinking.  It proves that I managed to overcome a major problem I had.</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="33" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="561"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:MhSzxhVibbc</id>
  <yt:videoId>MhSzxhVibbc</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UC0uTPqBCFIpZxlz_Lv1tk_g</yt:channelId>
  <title>Philosophy: practicality, honesty, and patience</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MhSzxhVibbc"/>
  <author>
   <name>Protesilaos Stavrou</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC0uTPqBCFIpZxlz_Lv1tk_g</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-10-13T13:46:44+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-10-17T03:58:42+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Philosophy: practicality, honesty, and patience</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/MhSzxhVibbc?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i2.ytimg.com/vi/MhSzxhVibbc/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>Find all my publications on my website: https://protesilaos.com</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="38" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="446"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:NBE82sy-kwU</id>
  <yt:videoId>NBE82sy-kwU</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UC0uTPqBCFIpZxlz_Lv1tk_g</yt:channelId>
  <title>Philosophy: video games, individuality, and tolerance</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=NBE82sy-kwU"/>
  <author>
   <name>Protesilaos Stavrou</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC0uTPqBCFIpZxlz_Lv1tk_g</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-10-11T07:41:35+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-10-11T18:48:40+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Philosophy: video games, individuality, and tolerance</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/NBE82sy-kwU?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i3.ytimg.com/vi/NBE82sy-kwU/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>Find all my publications on my website: https://protesilaos.com</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="62" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="1089"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:UKEyEMJs6fA</id>
  <yt:videoId>UKEyEMJs6fA</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UC0uTPqBCFIpZxlz_Lv1tk_g</yt:channelId>
  <title>Philosophy: self-importance and elitism</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=UKEyEMJs6fA"/>
  <author>
   <name>Protesilaos Stavrou</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC0uTPqBCFIpZxlz_Lv1tk_g</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-10-09T16:12:46+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-10-10T20:27:10+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Philosophy: self-importance and elitism</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/UKEyEMJs6fA?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i2.ytimg.com/vi/UKEyEMJs6fA/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>Find all my publications on my website: https://protesilaos.com

The previous video about &quot;meditation, walking, and acceptance&quot;: https://protesilaos.com/books/2022-10-07-meditation-walking-acceptance/</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="51" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="853"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:Tl0jgrh-5l8</id>
  <yt:videoId>Tl0jgrh-5l8</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UC0uTPqBCFIpZxlz_Lv1tk_g</yt:channelId>
  <title>Philosophy: meditation, walking, and acceptance</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Tl0jgrh-5l8"/>
  <author>
   <name>Protesilaos Stavrou</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC0uTPqBCFIpZxlz_Lv1tk_g</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-10-07T16:13:29+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-10-21T21:55:53+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Philosophy: meditation, walking, and acceptance</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/Tl0jgrh-5l8?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i1.ytimg.com/vi/Tl0jgrh-5l8/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>I am walking in nature and talking... Find all my publications on my website: https://protesilaos.com</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="125" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="1652"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:Rv6Y44V3G6c</id>
  <yt:videoId>Rv6Y44V3G6c</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UC0uTPqBCFIpZxlz_Lv1tk_g</yt:channelId>
  <title>Philosophy: being breakable and taking it slow</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Rv6Y44V3G6c"/>
  <author>
   <name>Protesilaos Stavrou</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC0uTPqBCFIpZxlz_Lv1tk_g</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-09-30T09:39:52+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-10-07T09:52:14+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Philosophy: being breakable and taking it slow</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/Rv6Y44V3G6c?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i3.ytimg.com/vi/Rv6Y44V3G6c/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>There is no transcript. Find all my publications on my website: https://protesilaos.com</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="59" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="836"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:Du0mYE1Uag0</id>
  <yt:videoId>Du0mYE1Uag0</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UC0uTPqBCFIpZxlz_Lv1tk_g</yt:channelId>
  <title>Philosophy: the fully fledged human being</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Du0mYE1Uag0"/>
  <author>
   <name>Protesilaos Stavrou</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC0uTPqBCFIpZxlz_Lv1tk_g</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-09-28T07:19:26+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-10-02T17:08:11+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Philosophy: the fully fledged human being</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/Du0mYE1Uag0?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i1.ytimg.com/vi/Du0mYE1Uag0/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>There is no transcript. Find all my publications on my website: https://protesilaos.com</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="31" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="529"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:fkSzJCYGj8c</id>
  <yt:videoId>fkSzJCYGj8c</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UC0uTPqBCFIpZxlz_Lv1tk_g</yt:channelId>
  <title>Philosophy: fast-paced life and magical solutions</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fkSzJCYGj8c"/>
  <author>
   <name>Protesilaos Stavrou</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC0uTPqBCFIpZxlz_Lv1tk_g</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-09-26T08:44:51+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-10-02T16:58:31+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Philosophy: fast-paced life and magical solutions</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/fkSzJCYGj8c?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i3.ytimg.com/vi/fkSzJCYGj8c/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>There is no transcript for this talk. You can find all my publications on my website: https://protesilaos.com</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="48" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="713"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
</feed>
