<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
>

<channel>
	<title>Asia 361</title>
	<atom:link href="https://asia361.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://asia361.com</link>
	<description>We cover Asia 360° and that added extra.</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 06:28:57 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.9.8</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">88101801</site>	<item>
		<title>Just the Thing for Coloured Asian Hair &#8211; Kim Robinson Cleansing Clay and Intensive Repair Treatment</title>
		<link>https://asia361.com/2022/10/27/just-the-thing-for-coloured-asian-hair-kim-robinson-cleansing-clay-and-intensive-repair-treatment/</link>
		<comments>https://asia361.com/2022/10/27/just-the-thing-for-coloured-asian-hair-kim-robinson-cleansing-clay-and-intensive-repair-treatment/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2022 14:34:22 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Marky Ramone Go]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Fashion & Beauty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Singapore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kim robinson]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kim robinson cleansing clay]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://asia361.com/?p=31874</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Coloured hair does not need to lose its vibrance, thanks to two new Kim Robinson&#8217;s products. Celebrity hair stylist to some of the world&#8217;s top stars, Kim Robinson, continues his quest to deliver the best care for all hair needs, made especially for Asian hair. The hair maven has launched two new products as part [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://asia361.com/2022/10/27/just-the-thing-for-coloured-asian-hair-kim-robinson-cleansing-clay-and-intensive-repair-treatment/">Just the Thing for Coloured Asian Hair &#8211; Kim Robinson Cleansing Clay and Intensive Repair Treatment</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://asia361.com">Asia 361</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;">Coloured hair does not need to lose its vibrance, thanks to two new Kim Robinson&#8217;s products. Celebrity hair stylist to some of the world&#8217;s top stars, Kim Robinson, continues his quest to deliver the best care for all hair needs, made especially for Asian hair. The hair maven has launched two new products as part of his salon&#8217;s Colour Range &#8211; Cleansing Clay and Intensive Repair Treatment, both of which have been created specifically for coloured Asian hair.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Over 90% of women use hair dye, therefore maintaining coloured hair is important. Dry, frizzy hair results from colouring&#8217;s damage to the hair&#8217;s structure and integrity. Cleansing Clay and Intensive Repair Treatment keeps colour-treated hair healthy, vibrant, and shiny</p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Cleansing Clay</strong></h3>
<p><a href="https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/bjS1sBuQ.jpeg"><img class="size-full wp-image-31876 aligncenter" src="https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/bjS1sBuQ.jpeg" alt="" width="800" height="524" srcset="https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/bjS1sBuQ.jpeg 800w, https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/bjS1sBuQ-300x197.jpeg 300w, https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/bjS1sBuQ-214x140.jpeg 214w, https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/bjS1sBuQ-300x197@2x.jpeg 600w, https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/bjS1sBuQ-214x140@2x.jpeg 428w" sizes="(max-width: 800px) 100vw, 800px" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">The Cleansing Clay is a one-of-a-kind non-foaming cleansing product that does not strip colour pigments from your hair.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">The Cleansing Clay can be used in place of shampoo to eliminate product buildup, detoxify the scalp, and restore its natural pH balance. Lemon and chamomile extracts &#8211; rich in vitamin C, vitamin B, and folic acid &#8211; prevent hair loss and promote hair growth. White kaolin clay&#8217;s anti-dandruff actions leave hair and the scalp clean, silky, and shiny for longer. The gentle cleanser strengthens and rejuvenate hair. The dye pigments are undamaged because it doesn&#8217;t froth.</p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Intensive Repair Treatment</strong></h3>
<p><a href="https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Intensive-Repair-Treatment-is-formulated-with-hydrolysed-elastin-to-improve-moisture-retention-and-elasticity-of-hair-giving-hair-bounce-body-improved-texture-and-a-satiny-finis.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-31875 aligncenter" src="https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Intensive-Repair-Treatment-is-formulated-with-hydrolysed-elastin-to-improve-moisture-retention-and-elasticity-of-hair-giving-hair-bounce-body-improved-texture-and-a-satiny-finis.jpg" alt="" width="800" height="606" srcset="https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Intensive-Repair-Treatment-is-formulated-with-hydrolysed-elastin-to-improve-moisture-retention-and-elasticity-of-hair-giving-hair-bounce-body-improved-texture-and-a-satiny-finis.jpg 800w, https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Intensive-Repair-Treatment-is-formulated-with-hydrolysed-elastin-to-improve-moisture-retention-and-elasticity-of-hair-giving-hair-bounce-body-improved-texture-and-a-satiny-finis-300x227.jpg 300w, https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Intensive-Repair-Treatment-is-formulated-with-hydrolysed-elastin-to-improve-moisture-retention-and-elasticity-of-hair-giving-hair-bounce-body-improved-texture-and-a-satiny-finis-300x227@2x.jpg 600w" sizes="(max-width: 800px) 100vw, 800px" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">The Intensive Repair Treatment is created specifically for coloured Asian hair to replenish hydration and nurture individual strands.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Hair that has been repeatedly dyed may become dry and brittle over time. The Intensive Repair Treatment is made with hydrolysed elastin to repair and nourish each hair strand, increasing the hair&#8217;s ability to retain moisture and elasticity, resulting in fuller, healthier hair with a satiny sheen. Olea europea derived from European olive fruit oil makes this hair mask rich in hydration to moisturise hair for increased elasticity and resistance, while the Ricinus communis seed oil and radish root ferment penetrate prevent the creation of split ends. Hair&#8217;s moisture balance is preserved, and frizz is kept under control, so the hair looks and feels healthy and luxurious.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Kim Robinson Colour Range Cleansing Clay and Intensive Repair Treatment are now available at Kim Robinson&#8217;s Orchard Road boutique.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://asia361.com/2022/10/27/just-the-thing-for-coloured-asian-hair-kim-robinson-cleansing-clay-and-intensive-repair-treatment/">Just the Thing for Coloured Asian Hair &#8211; Kim Robinson Cleansing Clay and Intensive Repair Treatment</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://asia361.com">Asia 361</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://asia361.com/2022/10/27/just-the-thing-for-coloured-asian-hair-kim-robinson-cleansing-clay-and-intensive-repair-treatment/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">31874</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Roborock G10: The Robot That Helped Me When I Was Down With COVID-19</title>
		<link>https://asia361.com/2022/10/27/roborock-g10-the-robot-that-helped-me-when-i-was-down-with-covid-19/</link>
		<comments>https://asia361.com/2022/10/27/roborock-g10-the-robot-that-helped-me-when-i-was-down-with-covid-19/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2022 11:17:38 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Katherine Goh]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Singapore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[roborock]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[roborock g10]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[robot vacuum cleaner]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://asia361.com/?p=31891</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Having COVID-19 sucks. Having to clean your home when you are extremely sick with COVID-19 sucks even more. I was recently down with the dreaded virus and never did I expect to have a robot help me during my period of illness. That very robot is the Roborock G10 – a robot vacuum/mop cleaner. For [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://asia361.com/2022/10/27/roborock-g10-the-robot-that-helped-me-when-i-was-down-with-covid-19/">Roborock G10: The Robot That Helped Me When I Was Down With COVID-19</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://asia361.com">Asia 361</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Having COVID-19 sucks. Having to clean your home when you are extremely sick with COVID-19 sucks even more. I was recently down with the dreaded virus and never did I expect to have a robot help me during my period of illness. That very robot is the Roborock G10 – a robot vacuum/mop cleaner.</p>
<p>For the uninitiated, Roborock is a technology company that is known for its range of intelligent robot vacuum cleaners and mops. The Roborock G10 is one of the latest innovations to come from the company.</p>
<div id="attachment_31898" style="width: 810px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img class="size-full wp-image-31898" src="https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/roborock.jpeg" alt="" width="800" height="676" srcset="https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/roborock.jpeg 800w, https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/roborock-300x254.jpeg 300w, https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/roborock-300x254@2x.jpeg 600w" sizes="(max-width: 800px) 100vw, 800px" /><p class="wp-caption-text">Photo © Roborock</p></div>
<p style="text-align: justify;">The arrival of the Roborock G10 at my doorstep could not have been timelier. I happened to come down with COVID-19. Of course, the two events got nothing to do with each other. Being sick means it’s all the more imperative that I keep the home clean. Yet, when one is sick, the last thing on your mind is having to do household chores. So yes, words cannot express how grateful I am to this inanimate object called Roborock G10, strange as it may sound.</p>
<h3><strong>Setting Up </strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Being a non-techie person and one who hates reading instruction manuals, getting the Roborock G10 up and running was surprisingly a breeze.</p>
<p>The Roborock G10 comes with a docking station, ramp and a cable. The vacuum unit weighs about 5kg. Upon unboxing, one will find a pictorial quick start guide that is very easy to read and understand. The instructions include how to pair your G10 with the app too. Within minutes, I got my G10 up and running.</p>
<div id="attachment_31892" style="width: 810px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img class="size-full wp-image-31892" src="https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/DC1B9632.jpg" alt="" width="800" height="533" srcset="https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/DC1B9632.jpg 800w, https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/DC1B9632-300x200.jpg 300w, https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/DC1B9632-300x200@2x.jpg 600w" sizes="(max-width: 800px) 100vw, 800px" /><p class="wp-caption-text">The big chart of instructions makes a set-up a breeze. Photo © Asia 361</p></div>
<p>In terms of design, I initially felt that the docking station is too big and takes up too much space but I got used to its size after a while. After all, the docking station needs to house the 2.9-litre clean water tank and the 2.5-litre dirty water tank. The former is for housing water to wash the mop while the latter is for housing the dirty water after washing the mop.</p>
<p>The vacuum unit itself is white in colour and sleek in design, reminiscent of a UFO to me. The docking station is a mix of black and white. The clean white design goes well with my predominantly white home décor.</p>
<p>Another small design feature that I appreciate is the cable management at the back of the docking station. I could coil the excess cable so that it looks neat.</p>
<p>Here’s a look at the specifications at a glance:</p>
<ul>
<li>Vacuum suction power: 2,500 Pa</li>
<li>Sonic mopping: 3,000 vibrations per minute</li>
<li>Water tank capacity of robot: 200 ml</li>
<li>Dustbin capacity of robot: 470 ml</li>
<li>Battery capacity: 5,200 mAh</li>
<li>Mop lifting height: 5 mm</li>
<li>Clean water tank capacity of docking station: 2.9 litres</li>
<li>Dirty water tank capacity of docking station: 2.5 litres</li>
<li>Docking station cleaning module: 600 rpm</li>
</ul>
<h3><strong>Ready, Get Set, Mop!</strong></h3>
<p>Once the set-up is done, the Roborock G10 is pretty ready to embark on its first journey – mapping of the home layout. The G10 has a mopping range of up to 300 sqm or 3,230 sq feet, a range that should suit most homes in Singapore.</p>
<p>The G10 works on common flooring such as marble, parquet and vinyl. Before starting the G10, I had to make sure that the floor area was clear of obstacles. I have no carpets at home but the G10 is supposedly able to surmount carpets up to 2cm thick to continue cleaning. The VibraRise technology allows the G10 to lift its mop when a carpet is detected.</p>
<p>Everything is controlled via the mobile app and the mobile phone pretty much acts like a remote control. I didn’t have to touch the G10 unit at all. All I had to do was tap the buttons on the app.</p>
<p>Once the G10 has scanned the layout of your house, you can view the layout on the app in three formats – 2D, 3D and Matrix.</p>
<div id="attachment_31894" style="width: 810px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img class="size-full wp-image-31894" src="https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/pp.jpg" alt="" width="800" height="771" srcset="https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/pp.jpg 800w, https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/pp-300x289.jpg 300w, https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/pp-300x289@2x.jpg 600w" sizes="(max-width: 800px) 100vw, 800px" /><p class="wp-caption-text">The app shows the scanning and cleaning area of the layout. Photo © Asia 361</p></div>
<p style="text-align: justify;">I am impressed by how intelligent the G10 is in detecting obstacles and navigating around them. The sensors and omni-directional wheel of the G10 helps it to slow down and avoid obstacles when necessary. If there are certain areas where you do not want the G10 to cover, it is possible to mark those no-go zones on the mobile app.</p>
<div id="attachment_31895" style="width: 810px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img class="size-full wp-image-31895" src="https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/DC1B9629.jpg" alt="" width="800" height="533" srcset="https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/DC1B9629.jpg 800w, https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/DC1B9629-300x200.jpg 300w, https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/DC1B9629-300x200@2x.jpg 600w" sizes="(max-width: 800px) 100vw, 800px" /><p class="wp-caption-text">The G10 navigates between rooms easily. Photo © Asia 361</p></div>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Between my living area and my toilet, there is a groove. I had expected the robot to get stuck there but the G10 skilfully navigated in and out of the toilet without my interference. I also loved how it moved under my sofa – a hard-to-reach area that I normally dislike having to mop usually. Splendid.</p>
<div id="attachment_31893" style="width: 810px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img class="size-full wp-image-31893" src="https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/DC1B9631.jpg" alt="" width="800" height="533" srcset="https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/DC1B9631.jpg 800w, https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/DC1B9631-300x200.jpg 300w, https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/DC1B9631-300x200@2x.jpg 600w" sizes="(max-width: 800px) 100vw, 800px" /><p class="wp-caption-text">The G10 can cover hard-to-reach areas such as under the sofa. Photo © Asia 361</p></div>
<p>Now the important question – did the Roborock G10 do a good job vacuuming and mopping the floor? Yes, it did. There was no place that the G10 did not conquer at my home, except the areas with furniture, of course. It swept all dust and debris in its way with its 2,500 Pa of suction power while the sonic mop vibrates at 3,000 vibrations per minute to loosen dirt and pick up stains from the floor.</p>
<p>The G10 also goes over each area more than once. For my cosy little abode, the G10 took 26 minutes to clean an area of 24 sqm. Once all cleaning is done, the G10 automatically returns to the docking station for the mop to be washed and cleaned – all without me lifting a finger or getting out of the bed, for that matter.</p>
<h3><strong>Takeaway</strong></h3>
<div id="attachment_31896" style="width: 810px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img class="size-full wp-image-31896" src="https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/DC1B9645.jpg" alt="" width="800" height="533" srcset="https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/DC1B9645.jpg 800w, https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/DC1B9645-300x200.jpg 300w, https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/DC1B9645-300x200@2x.jpg 600w" sizes="(max-width: 800px) 100vw, 800px" /><p class="wp-caption-text">The G10 is perfect for homes with furkids. Photo © Asia 361</p></div>
<p>Do I recommend the Roborock G10? As someone who does all the manual housework without help, the answer is a resounding yes. The Roborock is an immense help especially when you are busy or sick, in my case. Granted, it cannot be compared to elbow grease in cleaning out those stubborn stains, but for day-to-day cleaning, it does a very decent job. It warrants a &#8220;Domo arigato, Mr Roboto&#8221; from me.</p>
<p>The only downside I can think of is the price. At $1,699.90, the cost might be a bit prohibitive to some people. However, time is money and if you are the sort that values your time over money, I would say go get the Roborock G10 pronto.</p>
<p><em>You can now get the Roborock G10 at a promo price of S$959.90 on <a href="https://www.lazada.sg/products/new-launch-international-roborock-g10-self-washing-mop-robot-vacuum-cleaner-auto-lift-up-mop-smart-technology-sweep-i2396454588-s14079802907.html?clickTrackInfo=undefined&amp;search=1&amp;spm=a2o42.searchlist.list.3">Lazada</a>. </em></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://asia361.com/2022/10/27/roborock-g10-the-robot-that-helped-me-when-i-was-down-with-covid-19/">Roborock G10: The Robot That Helped Me When I Was Down With COVID-19</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://asia361.com">Asia 361</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://asia361.com/2022/10/27/roborock-g10-the-robot-that-helped-me-when-i-was-down-with-covid-19/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">31891</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>A5 Japanese Wagyu Specialty Butchery Gyu San Launches Premium Take-Home Yakiniku and Sukiyaki Sets</title>
		<link>https://asia361.com/2022/10/24/a5-japanese-wagyu-specialty-butchery-gyu-san-launches-premium-take-home-yakiniku-and-sukiyaki-sets/</link>
		<comments>https://asia361.com/2022/10/24/a5-japanese-wagyu-specialty-butchery-gyu-san-launches-premium-take-home-yakiniku-and-sukiyaki-sets/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 14:37:05 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Vanessa Chan]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Eat & Drink]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Singapore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[A5 Wagyu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dining]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gyu San]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Japanese cuisine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Japanese food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sandos]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sukiyaki]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Wagyu beef]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Yakiniku]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://asia361.com/?p=31807</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Dining at home can be just as luxurious as a meal in a restaurant when you&#8217;re cooking with fresh, quality ingredients. A5 Japanese Wagyu Specialty Butchery Gyu San aims to offer that experience with the launch of their new take-home Yakiniku and Sukiyaki in premium cuts. The butchery specialises in sought-after cuts like striploin, tenderloin [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://asia361.com/2022/10/24/a5-japanese-wagyu-specialty-butchery-gyu-san-launches-premium-take-home-yakiniku-and-sukiyaki-sets/">A5 Japanese Wagyu Specialty Butchery Gyu San Launches Premium Take-Home Yakiniku and Sukiyaki Sets</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://asia361.com">Asia 361</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Dining at home can be just as luxurious as a meal in a restaurant when you&#8217;re cooking with fresh, quality ingredients. A5 Japanese Wagyu Specialty Butchery Gyu San aims to offer that experience with the launch of their new take-home Yakiniku and Sukiyaki in premium cuts.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><a href="https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Sukiyaki-Take-Home-Sets.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-31814" src="https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Sukiyaki-Take-Home-Sets.jpg" alt="" width="1200" height="800" srcset="https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Sukiyaki-Take-Home-Sets.jpg 1200w, https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Sukiyaki-Take-Home-Sets-300x200.jpg 300w, https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Sukiyaki-Take-Home-Sets-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Sukiyaki-Take-Home-Sets-300x200@2x.jpg 600w" sizes="(max-width: 1200px) 100vw, 1200px" /></a> <a href="https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Striploin-2.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-31815" src="https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Striploin-2.jpg" alt="" width="912" height="800" srcset="https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Striploin-2.jpg 912w, https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Striploin-2-300x263.jpg 300w, https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Striploin-2-110x96.jpg 110w, https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Striploin-2-300x263@2x.jpg 600w, https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Striploin-2-110x96@2x.jpg 220w" sizes="(max-width: 912px) 100vw, 912px" /></a><br />
The butchery specialises in sought-after cuts like striploin, tenderloin and ribeye, as well as lesser known cuts such as flank, oyster blade and tri-tip. Gyu San offers an impressive range of over 55 wagyu cuts, sourced directly from farm to table from prefectures all over Japan.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><a href="https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Minced-Patty.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-31816" src="https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Minced-Patty.jpg" alt="" width="1200" height="800" srcset="https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Minced-Patty.jpg 1200w, https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Minced-Patty-300x200.jpg 300w, https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Minced-Patty-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Minced-Patty-300x200@2x.jpg 600w" sizes="(max-width: 1200px) 100vw, 1200px" /></a><br />
Now you can indulge in the comfort of your own home with their take-away Yakiniku and Sukiyaki sets, complete with all the ingredients you need and easy-to-follow instructions. Suitable for two to four pax, you’ll be able to easily whip up restaurant-worthy meals for yourself and your loved ones wherever you wish.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Kamichiku-4-Miracle-Gyu-Sukiyaki-Set1.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-31819 aligncenter" src="https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Kamichiku-4-Miracle-Gyu-Sukiyaki-Set1.jpg" alt="" width="800" height="800" srcset="https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Kamichiku-4-Miracle-Gyu-Sukiyaki-Set1.jpg 800w, https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Kamichiku-4-Miracle-Gyu-Sukiyaki-Set1-150x150.jpg 150w, https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Kamichiku-4-Miracle-Gyu-Sukiyaki-Set1-150x150@2x.jpg 300w, https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Kamichiku-4-Miracle-Gyu-Sukiyaki-Set1-300x300@2x.jpg 600w" sizes="(max-width: 800px) 100vw, 800px" /></a><br />
We sampled the Kamichiku 4% Miracle Gyu Sukiyaki set (S$88 for self-pick-up/S$98+ for delivery). Aside from the finely marbled Miracle Gyu, it was brimming with a generous portion of fresh ingredients like naba cabbage, shiitake mushrooms, golden enoki mushrooms, shirataki, tofu, and eggs. It made for a satisfying and hearty meal, with the natural sweetness of the meat and ingredients slowly seeping into the simmering sauce, adding another dimension of flavour that really hit the spot. We found ourselves reaching out for second and even third helpings again and again. Highly recommended for get-togethers, or if you simply want a fuss-free way to treat yourself and a companion to a healthy, quality Japanese meal at home.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br />
</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br />
These Yakiniku and Sukiyaki sets are for taking away only; you won’t be able to enjoy them at Gyu San itself. Instead, smaller bites such as decadent wagyu fat fried katsu sandos and chips are available for in-house dining.<br />
</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br />
</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Katsu-Sando-Ebi.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-31818" src="https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Katsu-Sando-Ebi.jpg" alt="" width="1200" height="800" srcset="https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Katsu-Sando-Ebi.jpg 1200w, https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Katsu-Sando-Ebi-300x200.jpg 300w, https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Katsu-Sando-Ebi-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Katsu-Sando-Ebi-300x200@2x.jpg 600w" sizes="(max-width: 1200px) 100vw, 1200px" /></a> <a href="https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Katsu-Sandos-Brussel-Chips-Mix-Salad-and-Chips.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-31817" src="https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Katsu-Sandos-Brussel-Chips-Mix-Salad-and-Chips.jpg" alt="" width="1200" height="800" srcset="https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Katsu-Sandos-Brussel-Chips-Mix-Salad-and-Chips.jpg 1200w, https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Katsu-Sandos-Brussel-Chips-Mix-Salad-and-Chips-300x200.jpg 300w, https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Katsu-Sandos-Brussel-Chips-Mix-Salad-and-Chips-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Katsu-Sandos-Brussel-Chips-Mix-Salad-and-Chips-300x200@2x.jpg 600w" sizes="(max-width: 1200px) 100vw, 1200px" /></a><br />
Here’s a list of the available sandos and sides you can look forward to:<br />
</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br />
</span><strong>Sandos</strong></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">A5 Gyu San Katsu Sando S$32 &#8211; House Cut</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">A5 Striploin Katsu Sando S$48</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">A5 Chateaubriand Katsu Sando S$62</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Tamagoyaki Katsu Sando (Fluffy Japanese Omelette, Wasabi Aioli) S$18</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Ebi Katsu Sando (Minced Shrimp Patty, Housemade Tartare Sauce) S$28</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Fresh Fruits Sando (Seasonal Fruit, Housemade Whipped Custard Cream) S$12</span></li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Sides</strong></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Wagyu Chips (Russet Potato, top-grade Japanese Wagyu Fat, Gyu San Furikake) S$8</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">A5 Yakiniku Salad (A5 Yakiniku, Gyu San Tare, Gyu San Dressing) S$18</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Green Salad (Gyu San Dressing) S$8</span></li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><b>Gyu San<br />
</b></span><span style="font-weight: 400;">7 Wallich Street,<br />
#01-03, Guoco Tower<br />
Singapore 078884</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br />
</span><b>Tel:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> +65 8313 6633</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br />
</span><b>Email:</b> <a href="mailto:moshimoshi@gyusan.sg"><span style="font-weight: 400;">moshimoshi@gyusan.sg</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br />
</span></a><b><br />
Operating Hours:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> 11.30 am–9 pm daily (last orders: 8.30 pm)</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br />
</span><b>Nearest MRT:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Tanjong Pagar</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br />
</span><b>Facebook:</b> <a href="https://www.facebook.com/gyusan.sg"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://www.facebook.com/gyusan.sg</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br />
</span></a><b>Instagram:</b> <a href="https://www.instagram.com/gyusan.sg"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://www.instagram.com/gyusan.sg</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://asia361.com/2022/10/24/a5-japanese-wagyu-specialty-butchery-gyu-san-launches-premium-take-home-yakiniku-and-sukiyaki-sets/">A5 Japanese Wagyu Specialty Butchery Gyu San Launches Premium Take-Home Yakiniku and Sukiyaki Sets</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://asia361.com">Asia 361</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://asia361.com/2022/10/24/a5-japanese-wagyu-specialty-butchery-gyu-san-launches-premium-take-home-yakiniku-and-sukiyaki-sets/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">31807</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Love, Bonito Launches New Activewear cheak and We Love It</title>
		<link>https://asia361.com/2022/10/21/cheak-activewear/</link>
		<comments>https://asia361.com/2022/10/21/cheak-activewear/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2022 15:18:32 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Marky Ramone Go]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Fashion & Beauty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Singapore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cheak]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Love Bonito]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://asia361.com/?p=31846</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Homegrown brand Love, Bonito is loved for its ready-to-wear collection and now it has launched cheak, adding sportswear to its repertoire. Love, Bonito has taken over butter, a Singaporean women-led sports brand and rebranded it as cheak. This demonstrates Love, Bonito&#8217;s commitment to developing a full female ecosystem by acquiring an enterprise created exclusively for the [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://asia361.com/2022/10/21/cheak-activewear/">Love, Bonito Launches New Activewear cheak and We Love It</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://asia361.com">Asia 361</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;">Homegrown brand Love, Bonito is loved for its ready-to-wear collection and now it has launched cheak, adding sportswear to its repertoire.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Love, Bonito has taken over butter, a Singaporean women-led sports brand and rebranded it as cheak. This demonstrates Love, Bonito&#8217;s commitment to developing a full female ecosystem by acquiring an enterprise created exclusively for the average Asian lady. Adding sportswear as a new category is part of the company&#8217;s long-term plan to fulfil the diverse needs of women.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Following the Series C fundraising, Dione Song, CEO of Love, Bonito, sees the launch of cheak as a pivotal moment for the company. Song noted that cheak will broaden the company&#8217;s long-held goal of becoming a true partner of the women&#8217;s fashion world, particularly in activewear.  &#8220;Merging forces with butter came at the right place and time&#8221;, she added.</p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;">Get cheak-y</h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;">The sportswear line has been renamed cheak to mark the beginning of a new era following the merger of the Love, Bonito, and butter brands. This marks an important turning point in the evolution of the company&#8217;s commitment to empowering women all across the world.</p>
<div id="attachment_31848" style="width: 810px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/BaseCore®-Sweetheart-Bra-and-Classic-Biker-Shorts-Baked-BaseCore®-Duo-Bra-and-Classic-Biker-Shorts-Baked.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-31848" src="https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/BaseCore®-Sweetheart-Bra-and-Classic-Biker-Shorts-Baked-BaseCore®-Duo-Bra-and-Classic-Biker-Shorts-Baked.jpg" alt="" width="800" height="676" srcset="https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/BaseCore®-Sweetheart-Bra-and-Classic-Biker-Shorts-Baked-BaseCore®-Duo-Bra-and-Classic-Biker-Shorts-Baked.jpg 800w, https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/BaseCore®-Sweetheart-Bra-and-Classic-Biker-Shorts-Baked-BaseCore®-Duo-Bra-and-Classic-Biker-Shorts-Baked-300x254.jpg 300w, https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/BaseCore®-Sweetheart-Bra-and-Classic-Biker-Shorts-Baked-BaseCore®-Duo-Bra-and-Classic-Biker-Shorts-Baked-300x254@2x.jpg 600w" sizes="(max-width: 800px) 100vw, 800px" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">BaseCore® Sweetheart Bra and Classic Biker Shorts (Baked); BaseCore® Duo Bra and Classic Biker Shorts (Baked)</p></div>
<p style="text-align: justify;">According to Tiffany Chng, co-founder of cheak, butter was renamed cheak, which is a play on the word &#8220;cheeky&#8221;, in hope that it will better capture the spirit of the new brand&#8217;s products. Everything about cheak was designed with the ambitious energetic girl in mind. A woman who is strong and self-assured, but also thoughtful and and exhibits a lively zest for life.</p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>From butter to cheak, it’s a perfect fit</strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Olivia Yiong and Tiffany Chng, founded butter in 2020 to solve a dearth of inexpensive Asian-fit sportswear. Since then, butter rapidly built respect among the local fitness scene with over 100 instructors onboarded on their teacher program.</p>
<div id="attachment_31850" style="width: 810px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/BaseFlex®-Invert-Bra-and-Flex-Leggings-Blush-BaseFlex®-Asymmetric-Bra-and-Flex-Shorts-Lettuce.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-31850" src="https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/BaseFlex®-Invert-Bra-and-Flex-Leggings-Blush-BaseFlex®-Asymmetric-Bra-and-Flex-Shorts-Lettuce.jpg" alt="" width="800" height="533" srcset="https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/BaseFlex®-Invert-Bra-and-Flex-Leggings-Blush-BaseFlex®-Asymmetric-Bra-and-Flex-Shorts-Lettuce.jpg 800w, https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/BaseFlex®-Invert-Bra-and-Flex-Leggings-Blush-BaseFlex®-Asymmetric-Bra-and-Flex-Shorts-Lettuce-300x200.jpg 300w, https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/BaseFlex®-Invert-Bra-and-Flex-Leggings-Blush-BaseFlex®-Asymmetric-Bra-and-Flex-Shorts-Lettuce-300x200@2x.jpg 600w" sizes="(max-width: 800px) 100vw, 800px" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">BaseFlex® Invert Bra and Flex Leggings (Blush); BaseFlex® Asymmetric Bra and Flex Shorts (Lettuce)</p></div>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Love, Bonito chose buuter because of their Asian sensibility and commitment to establishing a strong female community. Together, they are driven by an Asian-centric design philosophy and brand objective to empower everyday Asian women. Love, Bonito is excited to support another women-led Asian-centric firm as it grows across the region with this acquisition.</p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Active wear inspired by a distinctly Asian sensibility</strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;">cheak expands butter&#8217;s design ideas with activewear developed with Asian sensibilities in fit, colours, climate, and sports. The debut collection contains 12 styles, seven sizes and 13 colours, including eight on Love, Bonito.</p>
<div id="attachment_31849" style="width: 810px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/BaseFlex®-Asymmetric-Bra-and-Flex-Shorts-Sesame.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-31849" src="https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/BaseFlex®-Asymmetric-Bra-and-Flex-Shorts-Sesame.jpg" alt="" width="800" height="533" srcset="https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/BaseFlex®-Asymmetric-Bra-and-Flex-Shorts-Sesame.jpg 800w, https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/BaseFlex®-Asymmetric-Bra-and-Flex-Shorts-Sesame-300x200.jpg 300w, https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/BaseFlex®-Asymmetric-Bra-and-Flex-Shorts-Sesame-300x200@2x.jpg 600w" sizes="(max-width: 800px) 100vw, 800px" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">BaseFlex® Asymmetric Bra and Flex Shorts (Sesame)</p></div>
<p style="text-align: justify;">The activewear line includes distinctive upgraded essentials and stylish styles. Activewear apparels are available in two fabrics: BaseCore® and BaseFlex®.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">BaseCore® is designed for high-intensity exercises like HIIT, spinning, and running, giving improved support and sweat-wicking characteristics to keep you cool and dry. Compressive characteristics improve blood circulation, performance, and recovery.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">BaseFlex® is ultra-soft and silky smooth, great for low-intensity workouts like yoga, pilates, and barre. BaseFlex® products are soft and feminine, with low to mid compression and support.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">The range comes in 13 warm-to-cool skin-toned colours. Pickle, Truffle, Sesame, and Potion are earthy staples. Lighter, bolder colourways including Wink, Blush, Moon, and Green encourage women to make a bold statement in and outside the gym, reaching new personal bests with stunning confidence.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">The new cheak collections are available at all Love, Bonito outlets around Singapore. Prices range from S$50 to S$79. A brand-new collection will be available to shoppers this coming December.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://asia361.com/2022/10/21/cheak-activewear/">Love, Bonito Launches New Activewear cheak and We Love It</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://asia361.com">Asia 361</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://asia361.com/2022/10/21/cheak-activewear/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">31846</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Martell Singapore Introduces Curated &#8220;Perfect Pairing&#8221; Gastronomic Experiences</title>
		<link>https://asia361.com/2022/10/11/martell-singapore-introduces-curated-perfect-pairing-gastronomic-experiences/</link>
		<comments>https://asia361.com/2022/10/11/martell-singapore-introduces-curated-perfect-pairing-gastronomic-experiences/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2022 04:30:29 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Marky Ramone Go]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Eat & Drink]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Singapore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[martell]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[perfect pairing by martell]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://asia361.com/?p=31677</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Pairing delicious cuisine with a fine drink is essential for people with opulent tastes. Great news, Martell Singapore has made this whim for a superb gourmet experience a reality. Martell Singapore has just unveiled Perfect Pairing by Martell &#8211; an exclusive curated selection of gastronomic creations that will pair the iconic Martell Cordon Bleu as well as [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://asia361.com/2022/10/11/martell-singapore-introduces-curated-perfect-pairing-gastronomic-experiences/">Martell Singapore Introduces Curated &#8220;Perfect Pairing&#8221; Gastronomic Experiences</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://asia361.com">Asia 361</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;">Pairing delicious cuisine with a fine drink is essential for people with opulent tastes. Great news, Martell Singapore has made this whim for a superb gourmet experience a reality.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Martell Singapore has just unveiled <strong>Perfect Pairing by</strong> <strong>Martell</strong> &#8211; an exclusive curated selection of gastronomic creations that will pair the iconic <strong>Martell Cordon Bleu</strong> as well as other legendary blends of the storied cognac house with exquisite dining experiences at 11 dining partners in Singapore.</p>
<div id="attachment_31679" style="width: 810px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Angus-Beef-Flambé-with-Martell-Cordon-Bleu.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-31679" src="https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Angus-Beef-Flambé-with-Martell-Cordon-Bleu.jpg" alt="" width="800" height="622" srcset="https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Angus-Beef-Flambé-with-Martell-Cordon-Bleu.jpg 800w, https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Angus-Beef-Flambé-with-Martell-Cordon-Bleu-300x233.jpg 300w, https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Angus-Beef-Flambé-with-Martell-Cordon-Bleu-300x233@2x.jpg 600w" sizes="(max-width: 800px) 100vw, 800px" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Angus Beef Flambé with Martell Cordon Bleu at Chinoiserie</p></div>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Featuring a staggeringly varied range of dining partners, Perfect Pairing by Martell eloquently illustrates how Martell&#8217;s cognac range can complement exemplary flavours, working with renowned Chinese restaurants such as <strong>Taste Paradise</strong> and <strong>Yan&#8217;s Dining</strong>, Western restaurants such as the steakhouse <strong>The Feather Blade</strong>, the unconventional and visionary wine hall, <strong>Corduroy Palace</strong>, and more.</p>
<p>The Perfect Pairing by Martell dining partners are Avenue87, Corduroy Palace, Good Graces, Chonoiserie, Madame Fan, Mimi, Table65, Taste Paradise, Yan&#8217;s Dining, The Feather Blade and Table at 7.</p>
<div id="attachment_31680" style="width: 810px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Jiangnan-Appetizers-Served-with-Noblige-Coffee.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-31680" src="https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Jiangnan-Appetizers-Served-with-Noblige-Coffee.jpg" alt="" width="800" height="582" srcset="https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Jiangnan-Appetizers-Served-with-Noblige-Coffee.jpg 800w, https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Jiangnan-Appetizers-Served-with-Noblige-Coffee-300x218.jpg 300w, https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Jiangnan-Appetizers-Served-with-Noblige-Coffee-300x218@2x.jpg 600w" sizes="(max-width: 800px) 100vw, 800px" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Jiangnan Appetizers Served with Noblige &amp; Coffee at Yan&#8217;s Dining</p></div>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Perfect Pairing by Martell is happening from 14 October to 18 December 2022. Each Perfect Pairing by Martell experience will highlight the rich narratives that reinforce every delightful culinary creation. From unexpected new delights to re-imagined familiar classics, it shall provide diners with an unparalleled opportunity to discover the finesse and marvellous versatility of Martell cognacs to elevate taste and flavor across a diverse range of cuisines.</p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Martell Cordon Bleu Presents Fresh, Unexpected Recipe Ideas</strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;">The Perfect Pairing by Martell menu will showcase a number of dishes that feature Martell Cordon Bleu. A renowned brand that is both very emblematic of and an icon for the Martell brand.</p>
<div id="attachment_31681" style="width: 810px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Overall-Menu-Dishes.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-31681" src="https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Overall-Menu-Dishes.jpg" alt="" width="800" height="565" srcset="https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Overall-Menu-Dishes.jpg 800w, https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Overall-Menu-Dishes-300x212.jpg 300w, https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Overall-Menu-Dishes-300x212@2x.jpg 600w" sizes="(max-width: 800px) 100vw, 800px" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Perfect Pairing at Madame Fan</p></div>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Additionally, diners will be treated to special rites and ceremonies featuring Martell&#8217;s cognacs that will forever imprint these magical voyages of discovery in their minds and hearts, guaranteeing that these meals will be the subject of conversation for months and years to come.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">The Perfect Pairing by Martell cognac pairing culinary trips, which start at S$198 per person, are more than just gastronomic experiences. These painstakingly crafted gourmet options, inspired by Martell&#8217;s customary ambition and flair, are poised to convert the commonplace into audacious experiences that will engage not just diners&#8217; senses, but also their love for spontaneity and tales, at every meal time.</p>
<div id="attachment_31682" style="width: 810px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Fine-pairing.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-31682" src="https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Fine-pairing.jpg" alt="" width="800" height="686" srcset="https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Fine-pairing.jpg 800w, https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Fine-pairing-300x257.jpg 300w, https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Fine-pairing-300x257@2x.jpg 600w" sizes="(max-width: 800px) 100vw, 800px" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Fine food and drink pairing at Corduroy Place</p></div>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Bookings for Perfect Pairing by Martell&#8217;s tailored menus begin on 14 October 2022. Visit the Perfect Pairing by Martell <a href="https://www.martell.com/en-sg/perfectpairing/">website</a> for more information on how to reserve a seat and details on each dining partner and their tailored menus.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://asia361.com/2022/10/11/martell-singapore-introduces-curated-perfect-pairing-gastronomic-experiences/">Martell Singapore Introduces Curated &#8220;Perfect Pairing&#8221; Gastronomic Experiences</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://asia361.com">Asia 361</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://asia361.com/2022/10/11/martell-singapore-introduces-curated-perfect-pairing-gastronomic-experiences/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">31677</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bored of Tonkotsu Ramen? Enjoy Ramen Champion&#8217;s New Chicken Version From 10 to 21 October</title>
		<link>https://asia361.com/2022/10/10/bored-of-tonkotsu-ramen-enjoy-ramen-champions-new-chicken-version-from-10-to-21-october/</link>
		<comments>https://asia361.com/2022/10/10/bored-of-tonkotsu-ramen-enjoy-ramen-champions-new-chicken-version-from-10-to-21-october/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2022 04:11:45 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Fen Chia]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Eat & Drink]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Singapore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ramen champion]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://asia361.com/?p=31447</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Ramen fans can soon look forward to a limited edition chicken ramen from 10 to 21 October 2022. Multi-label ramen eatery Ramen Champion has launched the Tori Paitan Stamina Shio Ramen (S$18.80), its in-house creation that features a soup made wholly with chicken. This ramen features a collagen-rich soup base that takes over 12 hours of [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://asia361.com/2022/10/10/bored-of-tonkotsu-ramen-enjoy-ramen-champions-new-chicken-version-from-10-to-21-october/">Bored of Tonkotsu Ramen? Enjoy Ramen Champion&#8217;s New Chicken Version From 10 to 21 October</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://asia361.com">Asia 361</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Ramen fans can soon look forward to a limited edition chicken ramen from 10 to 21 October 2022. Multi-label ramen eatery <a href="https://ramenchampion.com.sg/">Ramen Champion</a> has launched the <strong>Tori Paitan Stamina Shio Ramen </strong>(S$18.80), its in-house creation that features a soup made wholly with chicken. This ramen features a collagen-rich soup base that takes over 12 hours of painstaking preparation, during which chicken, vegetables, three kinds of sea salt and garlic are simmered to bring out their essential flavours. </span></p>
<div id="attachment_31451" style="width: 1810px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img class="wp-image-31451 size-full" src="https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/IMG_3807-e1665461877994.jpg" alt="" width="1800" height="1219" srcset="https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/IMG_3807-e1665461877994.jpg 1800w, https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/IMG_3807-e1665461877994-300x203.jpg 300w, https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/IMG_3807-e1665461877994-1024x693.jpg 1024w, https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/IMG_3807-e1665461877994-768x520.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1800px) 100vw, 1800px" /><p class="wp-caption-text"><em>Tori Paitan Stamina Shio Ramen comes with a heap of vegetables. Photo © Fen Chia</em></p></div>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Each bowl comes with a bone-in whole chicken leg that is cooked in chicken broth for a half-hour before it is steeped in a rich sauce for another 30 minutes. This results in a fall-off-the-bone and deeply flavoured meat. For those with hearty appetites, you will be glad to note that this ramen is Jiro-style, which evolved from the need to feed hungry blue-collar workers and students during Tokyo’s redevelopment from the 1960s-70s with flavourful and reasonably-priced ramen that came in large portions. </span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Thick and chewy flat noodles are used in the Tori Paitan Stamina Shio Ramen, which is topped with a huge heap of beansprouts and cabbage that makes the bowl look mountainous. A flowy Ajitama (ramen egg) and ninniku (garlic) round out the dish.</span></p>
<div id="attachment_31452" style="width: 1930px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/IMG_3817.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-31452" src="https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/IMG_3817.jpg" alt="" width="1920" height="1280" srcset="https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/IMG_3817.jpg 1920w, https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/IMG_3817-300x200.jpg 300w, https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/IMG_3817-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/IMG_3817-300x200@2x.jpg 600w" sizes="(max-width: 1920px) 100vw, 1920px" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text"><em>Mr Koichi Horikawa, general manager and chef behind the new ramen version. Photo © Fen Chia</em></p></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Catch this limited-edition ramen only on weekdays from 10 to 21 October 2022. Only 30 bowls will be available each day. Not to worry about someone going hungry if you are heading there in a big group &#8211; the beauty of Ramen Champion’s concept is that it allows you to enjoy many types of ramen and even donburi from its other brands Tonkotsu Ikkyu, Don Meijin, Menya Ryu, Buta God and Taishoken under one roof.</span></p>
<div id="attachment_31449" style="width: 1930px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/IMG_3784.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-31449" src="https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/IMG_3784.jpg" alt="" width="1920" height="1280" srcset="https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/IMG_3784.jpg 1920w, https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/IMG_3784-300x200.jpg 300w, https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/IMG_3784-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/IMG_3784-300x200@2x.jpg 600w" sizes="(max-width: 1920px) 100vw, 1920px" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Ramen Champion offers many brands under one roof. Photo © Fen Chia</p></div>
<p><b>Ramen Champion<br />
</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">201 Victoria Street Bugis+<br />
</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">#04-07<br />
Singapore 188067</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><strong>Operating hours:</strong> 11am to 10 pm daily </span></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://asia361.com/2022/10/10/bored-of-tonkotsu-ramen-enjoy-ramen-champions-new-chicken-version-from-10-to-21-october/">Bored of Tonkotsu Ramen? Enjoy Ramen Champion&#8217;s New Chicken Version From 10 to 21 October</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://asia361.com">Asia 361</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://asia361.com/2022/10/10/bored-of-tonkotsu-ramen-enjoy-ramen-champions-new-chicken-version-from-10-to-21-october/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">31447</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Aigner Reopens a Gilded-Toned Flagship Store at Paragon in Singapore</title>
		<link>https://asia361.com/2022/10/10/aigner-reopens-a-gilded-toned-flagship-store-at-paragon-in-singapore/</link>
		<comments>https://asia361.com/2022/10/10/aigner-reopens-a-gilded-toned-flagship-store-at-paragon-in-singapore/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2022 02:46:50 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Marky Ramone Go]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Fashion & Beauty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Luxury]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Singapore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[aigner]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[etienne aigner]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://asia361.com/?p=31684</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Etienne Aigner in the year 2022 is taking the credo Time is Gold to heart. Making each passing moment worthwhile, the German luxury brand marks another milestone by returning to Paragon at Orchard Road, Singapore with a flagship store coated in brushed gold and white. The 54-square-metre store is the ideal setting for Aigner&#8217;s expertly [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://asia361.com/2022/10/10/aigner-reopens-a-gilded-toned-flagship-store-at-paragon-in-singapore/">Aigner Reopens a Gilded-Toned Flagship Store at Paragon in Singapore</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://asia361.com">Asia 361</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;">Etienne Aigner in the year 2022 is taking the credo <em>Time is Gold</em> to heart. Making each passing moment worthwhile, the German luxury brand marks another milestone by returning to Paragon at Orchard Road, Singapore with a flagship store coated in brushed gold and white.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">The 54-square-metre store is the ideal setting for Aigner&#8217;s expertly produced leather bags and accessories of unrivalled quality and timeless style.</p>
<p><a href="https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Store-interior-2.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-31686 aligncenter" src="https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Store-interior-2.jpg" alt="" width="800" height="534" srcset="https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Store-interior-2.jpg 800w, https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Store-interior-2-300x200.jpg 300w, https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Store-interior-2-300x200@2x.jpg 600w" sizes="(max-width: 800px) 100vw, 800px" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">The reopening symbolises Aigner&#8217;s successful return to Paragon, where it was formerly located until 2016. To commemorate the store&#8217;s opening, shoppers who sign up for the Aigner mailing list will receive 10% off storewide or 15% off a minimum purchase of $1800.</p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"><strong><em>Progress</em></strong><strong> with Kate Moss</strong></h3>
<div id="attachment_31696" style="width: 869px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img class="size-full wp-image-31696" src="https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/9dae2210-f69a-42ce-bad5-0537d201b364_Kampagnenstart-222-1.jpeg" alt="" width="859" height="1200" srcset="https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/9dae2210-f69a-42ce-bad5-0537d201b364_Kampagnenstart-222-1.jpeg 859w, https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/9dae2210-f69a-42ce-bad5-0537d201b364_Kampagnenstart-222-1-215x300.jpeg 215w, https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/9dae2210-f69a-42ce-bad5-0537d201b364_Kampagnenstart-222-1-733x1024.jpeg 733w, https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/9dae2210-f69a-42ce-bad5-0537d201b364_Kampagnenstart-222-1-215x300@2x.jpeg 430w" sizes="(max-width: 859px) 100vw, 859px" /><p class="wp-caption-text">Kate Moss is the new face of Etienne Aigner.</p></div>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Aigner will launch its most recent collection <em>Progress</em> at the flagship store. With Kate Moss, a renowned figure in the fashion industry serving as the face of the label, the Progress line embodies independence and strength. Through the release of Progress, Aigner has demonstrated its commitment to development, vitality, and advancement in its field. By adapting to ever-changing tastes of consumers, the brand experiments with fresh perspectives while remaining true to its signature aesthetic.</p>
<p>Kate Moss will be seen promoting the new &#8220;Progress&#8221; collection for the upcoming Fall/Winter 2022 season.</p>
<div id="attachment_31687" style="width: 810px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/CYBILL-BRILLANTE-MINI-BAG-S-COSMIC-BLUE-1642-SGD.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-31687" src="https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/CYBILL-BRILLANTE-MINI-BAG-S-COSMIC-BLUE-1642-SGD.jpg" alt="" width="800" height="692" srcset="https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/CYBILL-BRILLANTE-MINI-BAG-S-COSMIC-BLUE-1642-SGD.jpg 800w, https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/CYBILL-BRILLANTE-MINI-BAG-S-COSMIC-BLUE-1642-SGD-300x260.jpg 300w, https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/CYBILL-BRILLANTE-MINI-BAG-S-COSMIC-BLUE-1642-SGD-110x96.jpg 110w, https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/CYBILL-BRILLANTE-MINI-BAG-S-COSMIC-BLUE-1642-SGD-300x260@2x.jpg 600w, https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/CYBILL-BRILLANTE-MINI-BAG-S-COSMIC-BLUE-1642-SGD-110x96@2x.jpg 220w" sizes="(max-width: 800px) 100vw, 800px" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Cybill Mini Bag</p></div>
<div id="attachment_31688" style="width: 810px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/DELIA-HOBO-BAG-M-BURGUNDY-821-SGD-.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-31688" src="https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/DELIA-HOBO-BAG-M-BURGUNDY-821-SGD-.jpg" alt="" width="800" height="570" srcset="https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/DELIA-HOBO-BAG-M-BURGUNDY-821-SGD-.jpg 800w, https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/DELIA-HOBO-BAG-M-BURGUNDY-821-SGD--300x214.jpg 300w, https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/DELIA-HOBO-BAG-M-BURGUNDY-821-SGD--300x214@2x.jpg 600w" sizes="(max-width: 800px) 100vw, 800px" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Delia Hobo bag</p></div>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>A Progressive Collection</strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Aigner&#8217;s &#8220;Progress&#8221; collection is a personal take on a kind of futurism that values independence of expression in the arts, physical vitality, and male power.</p>
<div id="attachment_31689" style="width: 810px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/MAIA-SHOULDER-BAG-S-BURGUNDY-821-SGD-3.jpg"><img class="wp-image-31689 size-full" src="https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/MAIA-SHOULDER-BAG-S-BURGUNDY-821-SGD-3.jpg" alt="" width="800" height="532" srcset="https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/MAIA-SHOULDER-BAG-S-BURGUNDY-821-SGD-3.jpg 800w, https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/MAIA-SHOULDER-BAG-S-BURGUNDY-821-SGD-3-300x200.jpg 300w, https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/MAIA-SHOULDER-BAG-S-BURGUNDY-821-SGD-3-300x200@2x.jpg 600w" sizes="(max-width: 800px) 100vw, 800px" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Maia Shoulder bag</p></div>
<ul style="text-align: justify;">
<li><strong>Cybil Specials</strong>. The AIGNER trademark bag CYBILL adopts a futuristic twist this season. CYBILL GRAFICO features geometric embossing and metallic tones. The traditional CYBILL Bag will be offered in &#8220;Orchid Pink&#8221; and &#8220;Maple Brown&#8221; leather.</li>
<li><strong>Delia</strong>. The minimalist DELIA series reinterprets a 1990s design. Composed of sustainably produced smooth leather, it has a stylish style and light-gold metal pieces. The series&#8217; varied shapes and muted hues &#8220;Black&#8221;, &#8220;Maple Brown&#8221;, and &#8220;Burgundy&#8221; make it versatile.</li>
<li><strong>Filo</strong>. This series&#8217; delicate silhouette contrasts with the collection&#8217;s other strong-formed series.</li>
<li><strong>MAIA</strong>. It features a gold-twisted A logo. Textured leather and envelope design make the collection a cheerful companion.</li>
<li><strong>Nico and Torino</strong>. NICO and TORINO, two new series, broaden the options for male consumers. The NICO line stands for eco-friendly, laid-back style thanks to its Dadino print on recycled cloth. The TORINO collection is a perfect blend of urban chic and practicality thanks to its use of a variety of fabrics and leathers in its design.</li>
</ul>
<div id="attachment_31690" style="width: 810px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/FILO-HOBO-BAG-S-BLACK-913-SGD-3.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-31690" src="https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/FILO-HOBO-BAG-S-BLACK-913-SGD-3.jpg" alt="" width="800" height="708" srcset="https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/FILO-HOBO-BAG-S-BLACK-913-SGD-3.jpg 800w, https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/FILO-HOBO-BAG-S-BLACK-913-SGD-3-300x266.jpg 300w, https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/FILO-HOBO-BAG-S-BLACK-913-SGD-3-110x96.jpg 110w, https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/FILO-HOBO-BAG-S-BLACK-913-SGD-3-300x266@2x.jpg 600w, https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/FILO-HOBO-BAG-S-BLACK-913-SGD-3-110x96@2x.jpg 220w" sizes="(max-width: 800px) 100vw, 800px" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Filo Hobo bag</p></div>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Aigner is located at Paragon Shopping Mall (Flagship), 290 Orchard Road #02-11 Singapore 238859 and has a counter at Takashimaya Shopping Center Level 2.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://asia361.com/2022/10/10/aigner-reopens-a-gilded-toned-flagship-store-at-paragon-in-singapore/">Aigner Reopens a Gilded-Toned Flagship Store at Paragon in Singapore</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://asia361.com">Asia 361</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://asia361.com/2022/10/10/aigner-reopens-a-gilded-toned-flagship-store-at-paragon-in-singapore/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">31684</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Wagatomo: A Smokier Take on Contemporary Japanese Fare</title>
		<link>https://asia361.com/2022/10/07/wagatomo/</link>
		<comments>https://asia361.com/2022/10/07/wagatomo/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 07 Oct 2022 02:56:48 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Marky Ramone Go]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Eat & Drink]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Singapore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wagatomo]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://asia361.com/?p=31627</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Fans of Japanese food will find themselves spoilt for choice at Guoco Tower in the Tanjong Pagar area of Singapore. Japanese restaurants have been popping up in the area and the lastest to make the list is Wagatomo. Formerly from Akira Back, Chef Tomoyuki Kiga has taken his innovative kitchen skills to Wagatomo, his new [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://asia361.com/2022/10/07/wagatomo/">Wagatomo: A Smokier Take on Contemporary Japanese Fare</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://asia361.com">Asia 361</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;">Fans of Japanese food will find themselves spoilt for choice at Guoco Tower in the Tanjong Pagar area of Singapore. Japanese restaurants have been popping up in the area and the lastest to make the list is Wagatomo.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Formerly from Akira Back, Chef Tomoyuki Kiga has taken his innovative kitchen skills to Wagatomo, his new home. The restaurant deviates from the conventional concept of Japanese food and puts a bolder, smokier take on modern Japanese delicacies.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">The exterior of Wagatomo is understated. It did take us some time to find it on the first level of Guoco Tower. Upon entering the cosy restaurant, you will see Wagatomo&#8217;s lively kitchen at work, with its chefs working on grilling Japanese fare on an open grill heated with binchotan charcoal and oak wood.</p>
<div id="attachment_31629" style="width: 810px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img class="wp-image-31629 size-full" src="https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/V0912-Wagatomo1142.jpg" alt="" width="800" height="533" srcset="https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/V0912-Wagatomo1142.jpg 800w, https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/V0912-Wagatomo1142-300x200.jpg 300w, https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/V0912-Wagatomo1142-300x200@2x.jpg 600w" sizes="(max-width: 800px) 100vw, 800px" /><p class="wp-caption-text">Chef Tomoyuki Kiga showcases his innovative interpretations of Japanese food, from an open kitchen to an open grill. Photo © Wagatomo</p></div>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Wagatomo’s Flavorful Menu</strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Wagatomo offers an a la carte menu for both lunch and supper, emphasising the restaurant&#8217;s desire to serve only the finest and most exquisite cuisine. The A5 Wagyu Pizza (S$32) is a must-try. Don&#8217;t be deceived by the name though; it&#8217;s not exactly a pizza. Instead of a pizza crust, the dish features a crispy waffle-like base topped with slices of the restaurant&#8217;s famous A5 wagyu beef, ponzu mayo, pickled myoga, yuzu kosho cream, and a sprinkle of truffle oil.</p>
<div id="attachment_31630" style="width: 810px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/A5-WAGYU-PIZZA-03.jpg"><img class="wp-image-31630 size-full" src="https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/A5-WAGYU-PIZZA-03.jpg" alt="" width="800" height="533" srcset="https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/A5-WAGYU-PIZZA-03.jpg 800w, https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/A5-WAGYU-PIZZA-03-300x200.jpg 300w, https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/A5-WAGYU-PIZZA-03-300x200@2x.jpg 600w" sizes="(max-width: 800px) 100vw, 800px" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Wagyu Pizza. Photo © Wagatomo</p></div>
<p>Another cold dish, Hokkaido Scallop (S$27) is served raw with mango sambal, yuzu oroshi, and a delicious nanbanzu, a marriage of ponzu and amazu. The sweetness of the scallops permeates through and works perfectly with the flavours of the condiments.</p>
<div id="attachment_31699" style="width: 778px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img class=" wp-image-31699" src="https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/scallops.jpg" alt="" width="768" height="610" srcset="https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/scallops.jpg 1536w, https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/scallops-300x238.jpg 300w, https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/scallops-1024x813.jpg 1024w, https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/scallops-300x238@2x.jpg 600w" sizes="(max-width: 768px) 100vw, 768px" /><p class="wp-caption-text">Hokkaido Scallop. Photo © Asia 361</p></div>
<p style="text-align: justify;">For hot bites, Scampi Ochazuke (S$35) is Chef Tomoyuki&#8217;s take on the classic ochazuke green tea over rice. The ethereal-looking dish features Scampi dashi, caviar and smoked pickled daikon. It is a dish that works well on its own or with a side of well curated craft beer.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">For meat lovers, we would suggest going for the Pork Chop (S$42). The chef uses Duroc pork, which has a high degree of marbling, intense flavour and juiciness. The Pork Chop, coupled with yuzu miso glaze and apple fennel slaw, was hands-down the favourite dish among us at the table.</p>
<div id="attachment_31700" style="width: 810px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img class="size-full wp-image-31700" src="https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Pork-chop.jpg" alt="" width="800" height="673" srcset="https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Pork-chop.jpg 800w, https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Pork-chop-300x252.jpg 300w, https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Pork-chop-300x252@2x.jpg 600w" sizes="(max-width: 800px) 100vw, 800px" /><p class="wp-caption-text">The Pork Chop wins us over with its intense flavour and juiciness. Photo © Asia 361</p></div>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Beef lovers can opt for the A5 Tri Tip (S$98). Slow-cooked for six hours, the A5 Tri Tip is Kamichiku Satsuma Gyu that is seasoned with a sansho spice rub for flavour that penetrates right to the deepest centre. It comes with charred onion puree to round off the meal.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Also available for lunch are donburi packages perfect for on-the-go dining and come with a house salad and Monaka dessert. Evening meals, meanwhile, places an emphasis on specially chosen dishes prepared with both traditional and modern techniques. The beverage menu at Wagatomo is an integral component of the restaurant&#8217;s overall offering. It has a wide variety of sakes, umeshu, and Japanese craft beer carefully curated to pair with the restaurant&#8217;s food.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">One can be assured of the finest quality ingredients being used at Wagatomo. If we may have a gripe, we wish the portions are bigger because we left the restaurant wanting more. Or perhaps, the food is too good.</p>
<p><strong>Wagatomo </strong><br />
5 Wallich St<br />
#01-12 Guoco Tower<br />
Singapore 078883<br />
Tel: +65 <span aria-label="Call phone number 8313 6622">8313 6622</span></p>
<p><strong>Opening hours:</strong> Mon to Sat &#8211; 11.30am to 2.30pm and 5.30pm to 10.30pm; Closed on Sunday</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://asia361.com/2022/10/07/wagatomo/">Wagatomo: A Smokier Take on Contemporary Japanese Fare</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://asia361.com">Asia 361</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://asia361.com/2022/10/07/wagatomo/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">31627</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Get Ready for a Month-Long Food Fest at Singapore River</title>
		<link>https://asia361.com/2022/10/03/singapore-river-one-food-festival/</link>
		<comments>https://asia361.com/2022/10/03/singapore-river-one-food-festival/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2022 02:39:49 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Marky Ramone Go]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Eat & Drink]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Singapore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[boat quay]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[clarke quay]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[singapore river]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[singapore river restaurants]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://asia361.com/?p=31591</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Delicious meals and tempting deals are on the table this month at Singapore River One&#8217;s month-long culinary festival. With the launch of Singapore River Signatures (SRS) on 1 October 2022, SRO is calling for everyone to join in the celebration of Singapore&#8217;s re-opening through delectable meals and great conversations. With a theme &#8220;Feast of Joy”, [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://asia361.com/2022/10/03/singapore-river-one-food-festival/">Get Ready for a Month-Long Food Fest at Singapore River</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://asia361.com">Asia 361</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;">Delicious meals and tempting deals are on the table this month at Singapore River One&#8217;s month-long culinary festival. With the launch of Singapore River Signatures (SRS) on 1 October 2022, SRO is calling for everyone to join in the celebration of Singapore&#8217;s re-opening through delectable meals and great conversations.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">With a theme &#8220;Feast of Joy”, it aims to gather food aficionados while celebrating exceptional restaurants along the Singapore River. For the whole month of October, foodies will get coveted rewards, amazing promotions, and e-vouchers.</p>
<h4 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Best Eats</strong></h4>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Following the public nominations for Diner&#8217;s Choice in July, SRO&#8217;s eminent team of judges conducted a rigorous and exhaustive round of tasting sessions to select the best dishes along Boat Quay, Clarke Quay, and Robertson Quay.This year&#8217;s judges come from a variety of backgrounds, each with their own point of view, constituting an exceptional panel of renowned culinary specialists. The panel comprises Gayatri Singh, Professional Chef and Director of Operations at Terra Madre; Dr Aaron Nathanael Ho, Food Blogger at Rubbish Eat Rubbish Grow; Shawn Chua, Host at Hawkerpedia; and Clara Chua, Lifestyle and Food Blogger at Exploding Belly.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">The best restaurants were chosen and granted the distinction &#8216;Top 10 Signatures&#8217; after meeting tough criteria and impressing the discerning panel. Results will be revealed in an upcoming ceremony on 11 October.</p>
<h4 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>SRS e-Vouchers</strong></h4>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Singapore River One has filled this unique month with exceptional bargains and promotions for all culinary enthusiasts to commemorate Singapore River Signatures (SRS) 2022, which will officially open on 1 October 2022 and run the entire month. Up to S$3,600 in e-Vouchers that you may use at participating F&amp;B establishments are up for grabs.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Visit <a href="https://singapore-river.sg/where-to-redeem/">https://singapore-river.sg/where-to-redeem/</a> for a comprehensive list of promotions and participating food and beverage (F&amp;B) businesses.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://asia361.com/2022/10/03/singapore-river-one-food-festival/">Get Ready for a Month-Long Food Fest at Singapore River</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://asia361.com">Asia 361</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://asia361.com/2022/10/03/singapore-river-one-food-festival/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">31591</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Round Up Your Wellness Routine With Naked Blend</title>
		<link>https://asia361.com/2022/10/01/naked-blend/</link>
		<comments>https://asia361.com/2022/10/01/naked-blend/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2022 09:53:01 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Marky Ramone Go]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Fashion & Beauty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Singapore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[naked blend]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://asia361.com/?p=31514</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>There is no better time to achieve that healthy skin glow than now. Good thing, it’s not yet too late to start, thanks to Naked Blend&#8217;s new line of healthy, mostly plant-based beverages. Founded and manufactured in Singapore, Naked Blend aims to transform the wellness and beauty realms via the use of sustainably sourced, healthful, [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://asia361.com/2022/10/01/naked-blend/">Round Up Your Wellness Routine With Naked Blend</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://asia361.com">Asia 361</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;">There is no better time to achieve that healthy skin glow than now. Good thing, it’s not yet too late to start, thanks to Naked Blend&#8217;s new line of healthy, mostly plant-based beverages.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Founded and manufactured in Singapore, Naked Blend aims to transform the wellness and beauty realms via the use of sustainably sourced, healthful, and delightful beverages that are largely plant-based. A &#8220;me-first&#8221; regimen is made simple and natural with Naked Blend.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Vikki Tear, founder of Naked Blend, drew motivation from the market&#8217;s lack of plant-based supplements. Fuelled by the realisation that the body need delightful and healthy supplements, Tear came up with Naked Blend.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">&#8220;I wanted to offer something that provides not just a boost in Vitamins but also in maintaining beauty wellness like hair and skin, achieving a radiant glow from within, supplements to be enjoyed and be easily blended in daily routines,&#8221; Tear said.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Naked Blend&#8217;s products meet the highest quality requirements, with highly experienced R&amp;D specialists designing nutritious consumables to fit a variety of diets, including plant-based, halal, gluten-free, and even for nursing and pregnant women.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">&#8220;We strongly believe in staying au naturel in all our products, with flavoirings and ingredients that are derived from natural sources to keep them safe for ingestion,” adds Vikki Tear.</p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Milk Tea to Start Your Day</strong></h3>
<p><a href="https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/Original-Milk-Tea.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-31518 aligncenter" src="https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/Original-Milk-Tea.jpg" alt="" width="800" height="600" srcset="https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/Original-Milk-Tea.jpg 800w, https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/Original-Milk-Tea-300x225.jpg 300w, https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/Original-Milk-Tea-300x225@2x.jpg 600w" sizes="(max-width: 800px) 100vw, 800px" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Naked Blend’s Original Milk Tea is a healthier and better substitute to coffee and bubble tea. The beverage comprises plant-based milk best suited for all diets. It has been painstakingly curated with multiple premium tea blends. Pu&#8217;er tea, black tea, and green tea completes the delectable mixture. This creamy beverage is high in nutrients such as Vitamin A, Vitamin C, Vitamin D, Curcumin, Ginkgo, and Glutathione. All of these aid in skin regeneration and provide a healthy glow from inside. Especially in sunny Singapore, it helps slow down the effects of ageing and protects the skin from damaging UV radiation.</p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Nightly Wind Down with Peach Detox Glow</strong></h3>
<p><a href="https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/Peach-Detox-Glow.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-31517 aligncenter" src="https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/Peach-Detox-Glow.jpg" alt="" width="800" height="673" srcset="https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/Peach-Detox-Glow.jpg 800w, https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/Peach-Detox-Glow-300x252.jpg 300w, https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/Peach-Detox-Glow-300x252@2x.jpg 600w" sizes="(max-width: 800px) 100vw, 800px" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">This natural detox cleanse is an efficient drink that relieves constipation and bloating. It provides natural plant prebiotics, fibre, fruit enzymes and antioxidants. The drink promotes the body&#8217;s natural detoxification process and eventually enhances general well-being and skin by facilitating a moderate intestinal flush and developing a healthy gut. It also promotes a healthy immune system, increases natural collagen formation, maintains hormonal balance, and restores the skin&#8217;s natural radiance. The Peach Detox Glow is an easy-to-drink beverage ideal for a wind-down ritual or a self-pampering session of skincare regimen. It is best consumed before bedtime.</p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Tasty Treats for Health and Beauty</strong></h3>
<p><a href="https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/Skin-Booster.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-31516 aligncenter" src="https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/Skin-Booster.jpg" alt="" width="800" height="800" srcset="https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/Skin-Booster.jpg 800w, https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/Skin-Booster-150x150.jpg 150w, https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/Skin-Booster-150x150@2x.jpg 300w, https://asia361.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/Skin-Booster-300x300@2x.jpg 600w" sizes="(max-width: 800px) 100vw, 800px" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Naked Blend&#8217;s product line is continually evolving with new flavours. The Naked Combination Skin Booster, a premium blend of natural ingredients in one compact pack, was created in conjunction with Lalalostyou, an online beauty store maintained by a local beauty enthusiast. This drink comprises patented components from the United States and Japan. This includes the Hydrolysed Marine Collagen and Muscat White Grape, to combat environmental aggressors and indications of premature ageing.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Visit the official <a href="https://nakedblend.co/Home/">Naked Blend website</a> to discover more about their amazing entire line of goods, which includes anything from low-calorie milk teas like Matcha Milk Tea to detox jellies like the Berry Enzyme Cleanse Jelly. To enjoy a discount, make a one-time purchase or sign up for a monthly subscription box.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://asia361.com/2022/10/01/naked-blend/">Round Up Your Wellness Routine With Naked Blend</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://asia361.com">Asia 361</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://asia361.com/2022/10/01/naked-blend/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">31514</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
