<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns:yt="http://www.youtube.com/xml/schemas/2015" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
 <link rel="self" href="http://www.youtube.com/feeds/videos.xml?channel_id=UCG_nvdTLdijiAAuPKxtvBjA"/>
 <id>yt:channel:UCG_nvdTLdijiAAuPKxtvBjA</id>
 <yt:channelId>UCG_nvdTLdijiAAuPKxtvBjA</yt:channelId>
 <title>Filmento</title>
 <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCG_nvdTLdijiAAuPKxtvBjA"/>
 <author>
  <name>Filmento</name>
  <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCG_nvdTLdijiAAuPKxtvBjA</uri>
 </author>
 <published>2013-06-24T13:51:16+00:00</published>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:UFPrI2Vxg9s</id>
  <yt:videoId>UFPrI2Vxg9s</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCG_nvdTLdijiAAuPKxtvBjA</yt:channelId>
  <title>Halloween Ends — How to Ruin Horror | Anatomy Of A Failure</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=UFPrI2Vxg9s"/>
  <author>
   <name>Filmento</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCG_nvdTLdijiAAuPKxtvBjA</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-10-31T22:04:23+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-10-31T22:56:53+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Halloween Ends — How to Ruin Horror | Anatomy Of A Failure</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/UFPrI2Vxg9s?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i2.ytimg.com/vi/UFPrI2Vxg9s/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>Use FILMENTO to get 55% off your first month at Scentbird: https://sbird.co/3gMHGM1 

This month I received...
Aventus by The House of Creed https://sbird.co/3f6bXoo 
Percival by Parfums de Marly https://sbird.co/3zi4Ikd 
Colonia C.L.U.B. by Acqua di Parma https://sbird.co/3SDIEY7 

2022's Halloween Ends continues the return of Michael Myers from 2018's Halloween and 2021's Halloween Kills. They even used the Filmento idea all the way back from my video about first entry, in which Michael Myers shouldn't be only an old man in a mask but more of an idea that can spread and corrupt. Awesome! Unfortunately, that's not enough to save this movie, because it stumbles into a couple horror pitfalls which make it not scary. A horror movie where the horror doesn't work! In today's Anatomy of a Failure, let's see what those pitfalls are so that we can avoid them in our own horror scripts.

Filmento en Español: 
https://youtu.be/ViDZUofaZd8

Support:     https://patreon.com/filmento
Follow:        https://twitter.com/filmento


Music:
Where's my Mind - https://youtu.be/XcV3rLSbY8E

#halloweenends  #AnatomyOfAFailure #halloween 


-
Halloween Ends (2022)
This is Laurie Strode’s last stand. After 45 years, the most acclaimed, revered horror franchise in film history reaches its epic, terrifying conclusion as Laurie Strode faces off for the last time against the embodiment of evil, Michael Myers, in a final confrontation unlike any captured on-screen before. Only one of them will survive. Icon Jamie Lee Curtis returns for the last time as Laurie Strode, horror’s first “final girl” and the role that launched Curtis’ career. Curtis has portrayed Laurie for more than four decades now, one of the longest actor-character pairings in cinema history. When the franchise relaunched in 2018, Halloween shattered box office records, becoming the franchise’s highest-grossing chapter and set a new record for the biggest opening weekend for a horror film starring a woman. Four years after the events of last year’s Halloween Kills, Laurie is living with her granddaughter Allyson (Andi Matichak) and is finishing writing her memoir. Michael Myers death scene Halloween ends bad movie garbage movie everything wrong with halloween ends full movie watch online free 4k clip hd best moments halloween ends kill counter michael myers death laurie vs michael myers halloween ends explained ending all kills compilation honest trailer halloween ends box office flop reaction review mistakes  hasn’t been seen since. Laurie, after allowing the specter of Michael to determine and drive her reality for decades, has decided to liberate herself from fear and rage and embrace life. But when a young man, Corey Cunningham (Rohan Campbell; The Hardy Boys, Virgin River), is accused of killing a boy he was babysitting, it ignites a cascade of violence and terror that will force Laurie to finally confront the evil she can’t control, once and for all. 
-
Halloween (2018)
Director David Gordon Green’s slasher film is a direct sequel to the 1978 film of the same name. Four decades later, survivor Laurie Strode (Jamie Lee Curtis) braces herself for a final confrontation with serial killer Michael Myers (Nick Castle and James Jude Courtney) after he escapes from confinement while being transferred to a maximum-security prison.</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="14143" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="230880"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:z1KkFu-5bKc</id>
  <yt:videoId>z1KkFu-5bKc</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCG_nvdTLdijiAAuPKxtvBjA</yt:channelId>
  <title>Why Rings of Power Failed where House of the Dragon Worked | One v One</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=z1KkFu-5bKc"/>
  <author>
   <name>Filmento</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCG_nvdTLdijiAAuPKxtvBjA</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-10-17T18:35:56+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-11-02T01:29:25+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Why Rings of Power Failed where House of the Dragon Worked | One v One</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/z1KkFu-5bKc?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i3.ytimg.com/vi/z1KkFu-5bKc/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>Sponsored by Ridge Wallet. Get 10% off and free international shipping with code FILMENTO: https://ridge.com/FILMENTO

Amazon's Lord of the Rings: The Rings of Power is here to dethrone Game of Thrones: House of the Dragon as the new biggest show on TV. But did it? The seasons are still ongoing I guess, but based on the pilot episode, House of the Dragon comes on top.  Which is strange because both shows feature a lot of the fantasy elements. So in today's episode of One v One, let's compare these two shows with each other to see how the fantasy side of House of the Dragon is handled in such a way that it's much easier for casual audiences to get into the story... than compared to Rings of Power.

Filmento en Español: 
https://youtu.be/ViDZUofaZd8

Support:     https://patreon.com/filmento
Follow:        https://twitter.com/filmento

#ringsofpower   #houseofthedragon  #onevone 

Music:


-
The Lord of the Rings: The Rings of Power (2022)
Prime Video's The Lord of the Rings: The Rings of Power brings to screens for the very first time the heroic legends of the fabled Second Age of Middle-earth's history. This epic drama is set thousands of years before the events of J.R.R. Tolkien’s The Hobbit and The Lord of the Rings, and will take viewers back to an era in which great powers were forged, kingdoms rose to glory and fell to ruin, unlikely heroes were tested, hope hung by the finest of threads, and the greatest villain that ever flowed from Tolkien’s pen threatened to cover all the world in darkness. Beginning in a time of relative peace, the series follows an ensemble cast of characters, both familiar and new, as they confront the long-feared re-emergence rings of power vs house of the dragon rings of power bad show good show trash house of the dragon good show bad show trash rings of power watch free online free house of the dragon watch free online free shocking moments only action pilot episodes is house of  the dragon better than rings of power of evil to Middle-earth. From the darkest depths of the Misty Mountains, to the majestic forests of the elf-capital of Lindon, to the breathtaking island kingdom of Númenor, to the furthest reaches of the map, these kingdoms and characters will carve out legacies that live on long after they are gone.
-
Game of Thrones: House of the Dragon (2022)
An internal succession war within House Targaryen at the height of its power, 172 years before the birth of Daenerys Targaryen.  King Viserys I Targaryen,  Prince Daemon Targaryen,  Princess Rhaenyra Targaryen</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="18354" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="336287"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:SK-cZiHoAJE</id>
  <yt:videoId>SK-cZiHoAJE</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCG_nvdTLdijiAAuPKxtvBjA</yt:channelId>
  <title>Bullet Train — How to Elevate Action Spectacle | Film Perfection</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=SK-cZiHoAJE"/>
  <author>
   <name>Filmento</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCG_nvdTLdijiAAuPKxtvBjA</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-10-05T18:15:49+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-10-06T19:10:37+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Bullet Train — How to Elevate Action Spectacle | Film Perfection</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/SK-cZiHoAJE?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i4.ytimg.com/vi/SK-cZiHoAJE/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>Get Surfshark VPN at https://surfshark.deals/FILM and enter promo code FILM for 83% discount and 3 extra months for free!

Bullet Train is a new big-budget ensemble action movie starring Brad Pitt along with other big Avengers-level actors, directed by the co-director of John Wick. And despite being in danger of becoming just another John Wick clone, Bullet Train manages to stand on its own two legs, in terms of characters and story and action. So in today's Film Perfection, let's look at some of the ways it does that. Here's a couple ways to make more of your action movie.

Filmento en Español: 
https://youtu.be/ViDZUofaZd8

Support:     https://patreon.com/filmento
Follow:        https://twitter.com/filmento

#bullettrain #filmperfection  

Music:
Thomas the Tank Metal - https://youtu.be/3mpH9ijJuU8

-
Bullet Train (2022)
In Bullet Train, Brad Pitt stars as Ladybug, an unlucky assassin determined to do his job peacefully after one too many gigs gone off the rails. Fate, however, may have other plans, as Ladybug's latest mission puts him on a collision course with lethal adversaries from around the globe—all with connected, yet conflicting, objectives—on the world's fastest train. The end of the line is just the beginning in this non-stop thrill-ride through modern-day bullet train full movie watch online free 4k clip hd action moments bullet train explained bullet train ending train crash samurai fight bullet train honest trailer everything wrong with bullet train only action funny moments ryan reynolds Japan from David Leitch, the director of Deadpool 2. Directed by: David Leitch. Screenplay by: Zak Olkewicz. Based on the book by: Kotaro Isaka.  cast:  Brad Pitt Joey King AaronTaylor-Johnson Brian Tyree Henry Andrew Koji Hiroyuki Sanada Michael Shannon Benito A Martínez Ocasio and Sandra Bullock</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="19242" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="354481"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:D5ufCLB1Uq0</id>
  <yt:videoId>D5ufCLB1Uq0</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCG_nvdTLdijiAAuPKxtvBjA</yt:channelId>
  <title>Prey (Predator 2022) — When Is a Movie Too Simple? | Anatomy Of A Failure</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=D5ufCLB1Uq0"/>
  <author>
   <name>Filmento</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCG_nvdTLdijiAAuPKxtvBjA</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-09-24T17:00:06+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-09-27T04:48:52+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Prey (Predator 2022) — When Is a Movie Too Simple? | Anatomy Of A Failure</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/D5ufCLB1Uq0?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i1.ytimg.com/vi/D5ufCLB1Uq0/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>Get started with Brilliant for free at https://brilliant.org/FILMENTO -- the first 200 people also get 20% off the annual premium subscription.

2022's Prey is a new take on the Predator franchise, this time on streaming. It is a great example of what streaming movies should be: instead of putting 200 million dollar IP on streaming instead of theaters, make smaller movies with that IP you would never make for theaters and put that on streaming. One potential issue with the movie is that it could be too simple, to a point where it becomes almost too predictable. So in today's Anatomy of a Failure, let's see how to avoid making a movie that is too simple.

Filmento en Español: 
https://youtu.be/ViDZUofaZd8

Support:     https://patreon.com/filmento
Follow:        https://twitter.com/filmento

#Prey   #predator   #anatomyofafailure

Music:
Predator kill music - https://youtu.be/1m_qeAU0lKo
AC3 - https://youtu.be/ZhakHVnSA4w

-
Prey 2022
An all-new entry in the Predator franchise, set 300 years ago, tells the story of a young Comanche woman, a fierce and highly skilled warrior, who stalks, and ultimately confronts, a highly evolved alien predator with a technically advanced Prey predator scene fight scene bear attack everything wrong with Prey honest trailer Prey full movie watch online free 4k clip hd official trailer mistakes prey sequel prey ending explained arsenal. Prey 2022 All predator kills compilation 1080p hd prey predator kill counter  Starring: Amber Midthunder Dane Di Liegro Harlan Blayne Kytwayhat Dakota Beavers Michelle Thrush. Director: Dan Trachtenberg.</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="13902" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="204215"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:tghqgDo_k8k</id>
  <yt:videoId>tghqgDo_k8k</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCG_nvdTLdijiAAuPKxtvBjA</yt:channelId>
  <title>Thor: Love and Thunder — Why Marvel Villains Keep Flopping | Anatomy Of A Failure</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=tghqgDo_k8k"/>
  <author>
   <name>Filmento</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCG_nvdTLdijiAAuPKxtvBjA</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-09-16T18:00:19+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-09-19T18:45:02+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Thor: Love and Thunder — Why Marvel Villains Keep Flopping | Anatomy Of A Failure</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/tghqgDo_k8k?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i1.ytimg.com/vi/tghqgDo_k8k/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>Start speaking a new language in 3 weeks with Babbel 🎉. Get up to 60% OFF your subscription ➡️ here: https://go.babbel.com/t?bsc=1200m60-youtube-filmento-sept-2022&amp;btp=default&amp;utm_term=generic_v1&amp;utm_medium=paidsocial&amp;utm_source=YouTube&amp;utm_content=Influencer..filmento..USA..YouTube


Thor: Love and Thunder reunites Thor with Natalie Portman's Jane Foster, who has now become a Thor as well, to take down the evil Gorr played by Christian Bale. Obviously this movie overall is yet another 10/10 as you can always expect from Marvel, but there is one negative aspect here as well: the villain. For some reason Gorr becomes another bland and forgettable MCU villain that you're gonna forget as soon as the movie ends, even despite Christian Bale. We already touched on this topic with Wanda in Doctor Strange in the Multiverse of Madness, but let's look for a couple more reasons why Marvel villains suck and how to avoid those problems ourselves.

Filmento en Español: 
https://youtu.be/ViDZUofaZd8

Support:     https://patreon.com/filmento
Follow:        https://twitter.com/filmento

#thorloveandthunder #marvel    #anatomyofafailure 

Music:


-
Thor: Love and Thunder (2022)
The God of Thunder’s latest adventure—including a trek to Olympus where Zeus (Russell Crowe) reigns supreme. The film finds Thor (Chris Hemsworth) on a journey unlike anything he’s ever faced – a search for self-discovery. But his retirement is interrupted by a galactic killer known as Gorr the God Butcher (Christian Bale), who seeks the extinction of the gods. To combat the threat, Thor enlists the help of King Valkyrie (Tessa Thompson), Korg (Taika Waititi) and ex-girlfriend Jane Foster (Natalie Portman), who – to Thor’s surprise – inexplicably wields his magical hammer, Mjolnir, as the Mighty Thor. Together, everything wrong with Thor love and thunder honest trailer thor love and thunder bad movie thor vs gorr fight love and thunder zeus funny moments good movie thor love and thunder best moments only action black and white lady thor natalie portman thor explained thor love and thunder watch full movie online free 4k clips hd screenwriting thor vs zeus love and thunder post credits mistakes bad cgi terrible cgi doctor strange 2 multiverse of  madness the wanda problem of madness they embark upon a harrowing cosmic adventure to uncover the mystery of the God Butcher’s vengeance and stop him before it’s too late. Directed by Taika Waititi (“Thor: Ragnarok,” “Jojo Rabbit”) and produced by Kevin Feige and Brad Winderbaum, “Thor: Love and Thunder” opens in U.S. theaters July 8, 2022.</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="36458" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="690861"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:_z4J404skuU</id>
  <yt:videoId>_z4J404skuU</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCG_nvdTLdijiAAuPKxtvBjA</yt:channelId>
  <title>Top Gun Maverick — How to Make a Movie Without a Villain | Film Perfection</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_z4J404skuU"/>
  <author>
   <name>Filmento</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCG_nvdTLdijiAAuPKxtvBjA</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-09-03T18:18:51+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-09-05T04:36:55+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Top Gun Maverick — How to Make a Movie Without a Villain | Film Perfection</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/_z4J404skuU?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i4.ytimg.com/vi/_z4J404skuU/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>Step up your belt game with SlideBelts, use code FILMENTO for 20% off: https://slidebelts.com/
 
Filmento en Español: https://youtu.be/ViDZUofaZd8

Top Gun Maverick brings back Tom Cruise as Maverick to once more fly fighter jets in a visual marvel. The movie became the biggest box office success of the year, even more so than the MCU, and everybody seemed to like it. Which is crazy because this movie is missing a proper villain. Somehow it just manages to make things work without one. So in today's Film Perfection let's try to figure out what you can do when the villain is missing. Not to say you shouldn't include a villain, because unless you're Christopher McQuarrie it might go badly wrong, but more so what you can do on top of your villain.

Support:     https://patreon.com/filmento
Follow:        https://twitter.com/filmento

#topgunmaverick     #topgun   #filmperfection

Music:
https://www.youtube.com/c/WhiteBatAudio
https://youtu.be/dWibx_3s_mM

-
Top Gun: Maverick (2022)
After more than thirty years of service as one of the Navy’s top aviators, Pete “Maverick” Mitchell (Tom Cruise) is where he belongs, pushing the envelope as a courageous test pilot and dodging the advancement in rank that would ground him. When he finds himself training a detachment of Top Gun graduates for a specialized mission the likes of which no living pilot has ever seen, Maverick encounters Lt. Bradley Bradshaw (Miles Teller), call sign: “Rooster,” the son of Maverick’s late friend and Radar Intercept Officer Lt. Nick Bradshaw, Top gun maverick flying scenes top gun maverick mistakes top gun maverick dogfight scene enemy fighter ending fight ending battle lady gaga top gun maverick only action honest trailer best movie top gun maverick bad movie top gun maverick best moments funny moments live die repeat edge of tomorrow top gun maverick full movie watch online free 4k clip hd top gun maverick official trailer top gun maverick dog fight training aka “Goose.” Facing an uncertain future and confronting the ghosts of his past, Maverick is drawn into a confrontation with his own deepest fears, culminating in a mission that demands the ultimate sacrifice from those who will be chosen to fly it.</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="23673" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="403752"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:44lUj_UemoA</id>
  <yt:videoId>44lUj_UemoA</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCG_nvdTLdijiAAuPKxtvBjA</yt:channelId>
  <title>Jurassic World Dominion — How a Movie Ruined Itself | Anatomy Of A Failure</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=44lUj_UemoA"/>
  <author>
   <name>Filmento</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCG_nvdTLdijiAAuPKxtvBjA</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-08-20T16:00:04+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-09-29T02:00:08+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Jurassic World Dominion — How a Movie Ruined Itself | Anatomy Of A Failure</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/44lUj_UemoA?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i1.ytimg.com/vi/44lUj_UemoA/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>Sponsored by Ridge Wallet. Get 10% off and free international shipping with code FILMENTO: https://ridge.com/FILMENTO

Jurassic World Dominion is the latest entry in the Jurassic Park reboot franchise, which has some good stuff in it and made a bunch of money as per usual. But despite all the positives, the movie also harms itself with a second, very unentertaining plotline in addition to the Chris Pratt one that ultimately drags the entire experience down to the swamps. And so in today's Anatomy of a Failure, let's compare the two main plotlines of the movie to see why one of them doesn't work at all. Here's when you should cut your losses and focus on what actually works in your movie.

Filmento en Español:
https://youtu.be/Hd718nQbjt4

Support:     https://patreon.com/filmento
Follow:        https://twitter.com/filmento

#jurassicworlddominion    #anatomyofafailure   #jurassicworld 

Music:
https://www.youtube.com/c/WhiteBatAudio


-
Jurassic World Dominion
This summer, experience the epic conclusion to the Jurassic era as two generations unite for the first time. Chris Pratt and Bryce Dallas Howard are joined by Oscar®-winner Laura Dern, Jeff Goldblum and Sam Neill in Jurassic World Dominion, a bold, timely and breathtaking new adventure that spans the globe. From Jurassic World architect and director Colin Trevorrow, Dominion takes place four years after Isla Nublar has been destroyed. Dinosaurs now live—and hunt—alongside humans all over the world. This fragile balance will reshape the future and determine, once and for all, whether human beings are to remain the apex predators on a planet they now share with history’s most fearsome creatures. The film features new cast members DeWanda Wise (She’s Gotta Have It), Emmy nominee Mamoudou Athie (Archive 81), Dichen Lachman (Agents of S.H.I.E.L.D.), Scott Haze (Minari) and Campbell Scott (The Amazing Spider-Man 2). The film’s returning cast includes BD Wong as Dr. Henry Wu, Justice Smith as Franklin Webb, Daniella Pineda as Dr. Zia Rodriguez T-rex vs giganotosaurus everything wrong with jurassic world dominion honest trailer jurassic world dominion watch full movie online free best moments 4k clip hd ending fight all dinosaur moments dinosaur action jurassic world 4 jurassic world dominion trailer explained mistakes bad movie good movie box office flop jurassic world 3 clips hd 4k eand Omar Sy as Barry Sembenè.  Jurassic World Dominion is directed by Colin Trevorrow, who steered 2015’s Jurassic World to a record-shattering $1.7 billion global box office. The screenplay is by Emily Carmichael (Battle at Big Rock) &amp; Colin Trevorrow from a story by Derek Connolly (Jurassic World) &amp; Trevorrow, based on characters created by Michael Crichton. Jurassic World Dominion is produced by acclaimed franchise producers Frank Marshall p.g.a. and Patrick Crowley p.g.a. and is executive produced by legendary, Oscar®-winning franchise creator Steven Spielberg, Alexandra Derbyshire and Colin Trevorrow.</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="25830" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="578968"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:mDPvBt1Pc80</id>
  <yt:videoId>mDPvBt1Pc80</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCG_nvdTLdijiAAuPKxtvBjA</yt:channelId>
  <title>Ninja Turtles — How to Fail at Launching a Franchise | Anatomy Of A Failure</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=mDPvBt1Pc80"/>
  <author>
   <name>Filmento</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCG_nvdTLdijiAAuPKxtvBjA</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-08-10T16:00:26+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-08-16T04:05:45+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Ninja Turtles — How to Fail at Launching a Franchise | Anatomy Of A Failure</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/mDPvBt1Pc80?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i2.ytimg.com/vi/mDPvBt1Pc80/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>Get started with Brilliant for free at https://brilliant.org/FILMENTO -- the first 200 people also get 20% off the annual premium subscription.

2014's Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles was an effort from Paramount and Michael Bay to recapture the financial success of the Transformers franchise. Unfortunately it didn't exactly go as planned. The movie was pretty bad and forgettable to the point where the better sequel flopped at the box office badly and thus the franchise was buried before it even fully began. In today's Anatomy of a Failure, lets look at TMNT to see the pitfalls of starting a new blockbuster franchise.

Filmento en Español:
https://youtu.be/Hd718nQbjt4

Support:     https://patreon.com/filmento
Follow:        https://twitter.com/filmento

#teenagemutantninjaturtles   #anatomyofafailure   #tmnt 

Music:




-
Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles (2014)
Paramount Pictures and Michael Bay present this reboot of the Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles franchise with Wrath of the Titans' helmer Jonathan Liebesman directing. The sinister Shredder has seized control of New York City's police and politicians, leaving his ruthless Foot Clan to spread chaos in the streets. With no prospects for salvation in sight, mutant crime-fighters Raphael, Leonardo , Donatello, and Michaelangelo leap into action. They put up a fierce fight, too, though in order to truly defeat Shredder, the heroes in honest trailer teenage mutant ninja turtles cinemasins everything wrong with teenage mutant ninja turtles bad movie ninja turtles 3 mistakes movie mistakes teenage mutant ninja turtles tmnt only action action scenes teenage mutant ninja turtles watch full movie free online 4k clip hd half shell will need the help of box office flops biggest courageous reporter April O'Neil (Megan Fox) and her quick witted cameraman Vern Fenwick (Will Arnett) as well. With their help, Shredder's plan will quickly unravel, and this once-great city will rise again.</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="23447" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="430518"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:tZtbvJ97N48</id>
  <yt:videoId>tZtbvJ97N48</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCG_nvdTLdijiAAuPKxtvBjA</yt:channelId>
  <title>Why The Gray Man “Worked” where The 355 Failed | One v One</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=tZtbvJ97N48"/>
  <author>
   <name>Filmento</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCG_nvdTLdijiAAuPKxtvBjA</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-08-02T17:00:36+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-08-11T03:59:20+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Why The Gray Man “Worked” where The 355 Failed | One v One</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/tZtbvJ97N48?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i1.ytimg.com/vi/tZtbvJ97N48/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>Get Surfshark VPN at https://surfshark.deals/FILM and enter promo code FILM for 83% discount and 3 extra months for free!

The Gray Man is Netflix's new Bournelike action movie from the directors of Captain America and Avengers, starring Captain America Chris Evans and robot Ryan Gosling. Whether the movie overall is good or not is up for debate but as an action movie it is definitely an improvement over The 355, which tried and failed hard at the same earlier in 2022 as discussed in the video &quot;The 355 - Why Hollywood's Female Action Films Flop&quot;. So today, let's compare the Gray Man to the action weaknesses of The 355 and see how it improves upon them.

Filmento en Español:
https://youtu.be/Hd718nQbjt4

Support:     https://patreon.com/filmento
Follow:        https://twitter.com/filmento

#thegrayman  #onevone  #the355  

Music and inspiration:
www.youtube.com/c/WhiteBatAudio



-
The Gray Man (2022)
Ryan Gosling is THE GRAY MAN and Chris Evans is his psychopathic adversary in the Netflix/AGBO spy thriller directed by Anthony and Joe Russo - available globally July 22 on Netflix. Also starring Ana de Armas, with Regé-Jean Page, Billy Bob Thornton, Jessica Henwick, Dhanush, Wagner Moura and Alfre Woodard. Based on the novel The Gray Man by Mark Greaney, the screenplay is by Joe Russo, Christopher Markus and Stephen McFeely. THE GRAY MAN is CIA operative Court Gentry (Ryan Gosling), aka, Sierra Six. Plucked from a federal penitentiary and recruited by his handler, Donald Fitzroy (Billy Bob Thornton), Gentry was once a highly-skilled, Agency-sanctioned merchant of death. But The Gray Man watch full movie online free now bloopers ryan gosling v chris evans gray man prague fight scene shootout scene action scene only action gray man 2 gray man bad movie good movie fight scene gray man avengers everything wrong with the gray man now the tables have turned and Six is the target, hunted across the globe by Lloyd Hansen (Chris Evans), a former cohort at the CIA, who will stop at nothing to take him out. Agent Dani Miranda (Ana de Armas) has his back. He’ll need it.
-
The 355 (2022)
Directed by Simon Kinberg, this spy thriller features Mace (Jessica Chastain), a wildcard type of CIA agent who decides to join forces with other spies to retrieve a top-secret weapon stolen by mercenaries planning to unleash global trouble. Since the weapon involves cyberspace knowhow, Mace convinces former MI6 British agent Khadijah (Lupita Nyong’o) to help since she’s a computer specialist. She also recruits Colombian psychologist Graciela (Penélope Cruz) and even a rival agent from Germany named Marie (Diane Kruger) to join the espionage team.</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="15484" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="257332"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:KJhj-YbBkkI</id>
  <yt:videoId>KJhj-YbBkkI</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCG_nvdTLdijiAAuPKxtvBjA</yt:channelId>
  <title>Doctor Strange 2 — The Wanda Problem of Madness | Anatomy Of A Failure</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=KJhj-YbBkkI"/>
  <author>
   <name>Filmento</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCG_nvdTLdijiAAuPKxtvBjA</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-06-30T17:00:07+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-07-29T11:57:45+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Doctor Strange 2 — The Wanda Problem of Madness | Anatomy Of A Failure</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/KJhj-YbBkkI?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i4.ytimg.com/vi/KJhj-YbBkkI/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>Thanks MANSCAPED for sponsoring the video! Get 20% off + Free International Shipping with code “FILMENTO20” at https://mnscpd.com/Filmento

Doctor Strange in the Multiverse of Madness is Marvel's next step into the multiverse after Spider-Man No Way Home. It's visually great and also has a fresh feel of a Marvel horror movie thanks to Sam Raimi. The main issue with the movie seems to be the writing, especially in terms of the antagonist Wanda Maximoff/Scarlet Witch as well as with the exposition. So today let's look at the Wanda problem and the exposition problem to maybe learn something.

Filmento en Español:
https://youtu.be/xmLyqpc8C_U

Support:     https://patreon.com/filmento
Follow:        https://twitter.com/filmento

#doctorstrange  #multiverseofmadness   #anatomyofafailure  

Music and inspiration
man outta u - https://youtu.be/WCUHeNYOYpQ
ok wanda - https://youtu.be/bVa8lEuDcsc


-
Doctor Strange in the Multiverse of Madness (2022)
In Marvel Studios’ “Doctor Strange in the Multiverse of Madness,” the MCU unlocks the Multiverse and pushes its boundaries further than ever before. Journey into the unknown with Doctor Strange, who, with the help of mystical allies both old and new, traverses the mind-bending and dangerous alternate realities of the Multiverse to confront a mysterious new adversary. “Doctor Strange in the Multiverse of Madness” stars Benedict Cumberbatch, Chiwetel Ejiofor, Elizabeth Olsen, Benedict Wong, Xochitl Gomez, with Michael Stühlbarg, and multiverse of madness scene honest trailer multiverse of madness everything wrong with doctor strange in the multiverse of madness full movie online free watch clip 4k hd multiverse of madness after credits explained multiverse of madness wanda bad movie good movie multiverse of madness memes scene doctor strange vs doctor strange opening evil wanda kids explained boys smartest man alive wanda black bolt reed richards doctor strange 2 mistakes Rachel McAdams. The film is directed by Sam Raimi, and Kevin Feige is the producer. Louis D’Esposito, Victoria Alonso, Eric Hauserman Carroll and Jamie Christopher serve as executive producers. The screenplay was written by Michael Waldron.</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="70617" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="1403903"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:VFCaCe-Cnlg</id>
  <yt:videoId>VFCaCe-Cnlg</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCG_nvdTLdijiAAuPKxtvBjA</yt:channelId>
  <title>Ambulance (2022) — What is Bayhem? | Film Perfection</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VFCaCe-Cnlg"/>
  <author>
   <name>Filmento</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCG_nvdTLdijiAAuPKxtvBjA</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-06-21T17:00:11+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-10-30T09:27:08+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Ambulance (2022) — What is Bayhem? | Film Perfection</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/VFCaCe-Cnlg?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i3.ytimg.com/vi/VFCaCe-Cnlg/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>Get a Galaxy Projector 2.0 with 15% off by using code FILMENTO: https://galaxylamps.co/filmento

Ambulance is a new 2022 action movie from Filmento's biggest enemy/friend Michael Bay. A lot of negativity has been said about his Transformers movies here, but Ambulance is a return to form for him as well as a great showcase of his biggest strength: Bayhem. And that's not just explosions -- there is something about Michael Bay that allows him to pack his movies with incredible action if he only cares enough to try. And so today let's dive into what Bayhem means and how to use it in our own action scripts.

Support:     https://patreon.com/filmento
Follow:        https://twitter.com/filmento

Music:
https://www.youtube.com/c/WhiteBatAudio

#ambulance  #michaelbay #filmperfection


-
Ambulance (2022)
In this breakneck thriller from director-producer Michael Bay, decorated veteran Will Sharp (Yahya Abdul-Mateen II, The Matrix Resurrections), desperate for money to cover his wife’s medical bills, asks for help from the one person he knows he shouldn’t—his adoptive brother Danny (Jake Gyllenhaal, Zodiac, Spider-Man: Far From Home). A charismatic career criminal, Danny instead offers him a score: the biggest bank heist in Los Angeles history: $32 million. With his wife’s survival on the line, Will can’t say no. But when their getaway goes spectacularly wrong, the desperate brothers hijack an ambulance with a wounded cop clinging to life and ace EMT Cam Thompson (Eiza González, Fast &amp; Furious Presents: Hobbs &amp; Shaw) onboard. In a high-speed pursuit that never stops, Will and Danny ambulance only action ambulance honest trailer everything wrong with ambulance ending best moments michael bay bayhem ambulance full movie online free clip 4k hd ambulance flop ambulance great movie must evade a massive, city-wide law enforcement response, keep their hostages alive, and somehow try not to kill each other, all while executing the most insane escape L.A. has ever seen.</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="14735" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="219163"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:KHlWu9PNh5M</id>
  <yt:videoId>KHlWu9PNh5M</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCG_nvdTLdijiAAuPKxtvBjA</yt:channelId>
  <title>The Secrets of Dumbledore — Death by Author | Anatomy Of A Failure</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=KHlWu9PNh5M"/>
  <author>
   <name>Filmento</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCG_nvdTLdijiAAuPKxtvBjA</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-06-11T15:45:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-06-19T01:58:09+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>The Secrets of Dumbledore — Death by Author | Anatomy Of A Failure</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/KHlWu9PNh5M?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i4.ytimg.com/vi/KHlWu9PNh5M/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>Get 20% off your first Bespoke Post box at https://bespokepost.com/filmento by using code FILMENTO at checkout. Thanks to Bespoke Post for sponsoring the video.

Fantastic Beasts: The Secrets of Dumbledore is another not-Harry Potter movie from Warner Brothers that is much like its predecessor The Crimes of Grindelwald: amazing to look at but boring to watch because of bad writing. And as before, most of the narrative faults come from JK Rowling doing the writing despite not being a screenwriter. She has had success with books but she keeps doing book things that do not work on screen. We talked about this in the last video &quot;Crimes of Grindewald — Death by Author&quot; but let's do it more. Here are a few more dangers to avoid when writing a film as a book author.

Support:     https://patreon.com/filmento
Follow:       https://twitter.com/filmento


Music:
https://youtu.be/m0o5OwN4ab0

#FantasticBeasts #AnatomyOfAFailure #SecretsOfDumbledore



-
Fantastic Beasts: The Secrets of Dumbledore
Warner Bros. Pictures’ “Fantastic Beasts: The Secrets of Dumbledore” is the newest adventure in the Wizarding World created by J.K. Rowling. Professor Albus Dumbledore (Jude Law) knows the powerful Dark wizard Gellert Grindelwald (Mads Mikkelsen) is moving to seize control of the wizarding world.  Unable to stop him alone, he entrusts Magizoologist Newt Scamander (Eddie Redmayne) to lead an intrepid team of everything wrong with secrets of dumbledore honest trailer secrets of dumbledore ending explained after credits final fight dumbledore vs grindelwald fight secrets of dumbledore trailer official secrets of dumbledore full movie watch online free 4k clip hd best moments secrets of dumbledore fight scenes dungeon brother monster scene secrets of dumbledore bad movie box office flop great movie fantastic beasts 3 fantastic beasts 4 secrets of dumbledore funny moments mistakes movie dumbledore vs credence fight wizards, witches and one brave Muggle baker on a dangerous mission, where they encounter old and new beasts and clash with Grindelwald’s growing legion of followers.  But with the stakes so high, how long can Dumbledore remain on the sidelines?</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="32880" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="746037"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:cK_PS9HXE84</id>
  <yt:videoId>cK_PS9HXE84</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCG_nvdTLdijiAAuPKxtvBjA</yt:channelId>
  <title>Morbius — How to Get Bullied by the Internet | Anatomy Of A Failure</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=cK_PS9HXE84"/>
  <author>
   <name>Filmento</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCG_nvdTLdijiAAuPKxtvBjA</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-05-28T19:00:17+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-09-10T10:55:56+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Morbius — How to Get Bullied by the Internet | Anatomy Of A Failure</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/cK_PS9HXE84?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i4.ytimg.com/vi/cK_PS9HXE84/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>Get Surfshark VPN at https://surfshark.deals/FILM and enter promo code FILM for 83% discount and 3 extra months for free!

Morbius is a new sort-of MCU superhero origin movie from Sony, in which Doctor Michael Morbius played by Jared Leto transforms into Morbius. The movie did break all kinds of box office records and sold over 300 morbillion tickets, but the reception wasn't so great. The entire internet was mostly making fun of and memeing Morbius. So in today's Anatomy of a Failure, let's see what Morbius did and didn't do in order to become an easy target online. Let's see why Morbius is a bad movie and how it can avoid the same fate in the sequel.


Support:     https://patreon.com/filmento
Follow:       https://twitter.com/filmento


Music:

Morbin time:
https://youtu.be/ON_q39LIVlo

#Morbius #AnatomyOfAFailure #MorbiusSweep

-
Morbius (2022)
While attempting to find a cure for his terminal disease, Dr. Michael Morbius stumbles upon an experimental procedure that may improve his aliment. Although initially considered a success, Dr. Morbius starts to feel a darkness awaken inside of him. The Marvel Comic of the same name inspires this anti-hero's journey. One of the most compelling and conflicted characters in Sony Pictures Universe of Marvel Characters comes to the big screen as Oscar® winner Jared Leto transforms into the enigmatic antihero Michael Morbius. Dangerously ill with a rare blood disorder and determined to save others suffering his same fate, Dr. Morbius attempts a desperate gamble. While at first it seems to be a radical success, everything wrong with morbius honest trailer cinemasins morbius full movie online free morbius bad movie review good movie morbius after credits post credits scene morbius final fight morbius funny moments morbius ending explained morbius only action morbius vs bats morbius opening morbius mcu morbius terrible movie rant great movie morbius 2 morbius 2 clip 4k hd watch full mocie online free morbius reaction official trailer morbius memes morbius spider-man a darkness inside him is unleashed. Will good override evil – or will Morbius succumb to his mysterious new urges? Directed by: Daniel Espinosa
 Screen Story and Screenplay by: Matt Sazama &amp; Burk Sharpless  Based on the Marvel Comics Produced by: Avi Arad Matt Tolmach Lucas Foster Cast: Jared Leto Matt Smith Jared Harris with Tyrese Gibson
-</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="86283" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="1819716"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:630ssQ72pyA</id>
  <yt:videoId>630ssQ72pyA</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCG_nvdTLdijiAAuPKxtvBjA</yt:channelId>
  <title>Sonic 2 — How to Break the Video Game Movie Curse | Film Perfection</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=630ssQ72pyA"/>
  <author>
   <name>Filmento</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCG_nvdTLdijiAAuPKxtvBjA</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-05-18T17:15:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-05-20T07:23:12+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Sonic 2 — How to Break the Video Game Movie Curse | Film Perfection</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/630ssQ72pyA?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i3.ytimg.com/vi/630ssQ72pyA/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>Thanks to Established Titles for sponsoring this video! Use code Filmento to get 10% off on top of their big Memorial Day sale: https://establishedtitles.com/Filmento

2022's Sonic the Hedgehog 2 continues the story of 2020's surprise hit Sonic the Hedgehog. There's a lot to like in the sequel, from in-form Jim Carrey to new characters like Knuckles and Tails. But just like in the first movie, the most amazing thing about Sonic 2 is how it manages to feel like a proper movie despite being based on a video game. Just last week we talked about how Uncharted was affected by the video game movie stigma, and yet Sonic 2 passes all those problems easily. So in today's Film Perfection, let's see how the movie did it. Building on my video on the first Sonic movie, here's a few more ways to break the video game movie curse.

Support:     https://patreon.com/filmento
Follow:        https://twitter.com/filmento

Music:
https://youtu.be/5DwS72t1ky8
https://youtu.be/TT_b3YU8SRk
https://www.youtube.com/c/WhiteBatAudio

#Sonic2 #SonicTheHedgehog2 #FilmPerfection


-
Sonic the Hedgehog 2 (2022)
The world’s favorite blue hedgehog is back for a next-level adventure in SONIC THE HEDGEHOG 2. After settling in Green Hills, Sonic is eager to prove he has what it takes to be a true hero. His test comes when Dr. Robotnik returns, this time with a new partner, Knuckles, in search for an emerald that has the power to destroy civilizations. Sonic teams up with his own sidekick, Tails, and together they embark on a globe-trotting journey to find the emerald before it falls into the wrong hands. From the filmmakers behind The Fast and the Furious and Deadpool, SONIC THE HEDGEHOG 2 stars James Marsden, Ben Schwartz as the voice of Sonic, Tika Sumpter, Natasha Rothwell, Adam Pally, and Jim Carrey returning, alongside new additions Shemar Moore, with Idris Elba as the voice of Knuckles, and Colleen O'Shaughnessey as the voice of Tails.
-
Assassin's Creed (2016)
In this feature-film adaptation of the hugely popular video-game series, death-row convict Callum Lynch (Michael Fassbender) relives his ancestor's memories as an assassin in 15th century Spain. From this out-of-body experience, Lynch gains the training he needs to battle a conspiracy in the present day. Marion Cotillard, Jeremy Irons, everything wrong with Sonic the hedgehog 2 honest trailer Sonic 2 ending explained after credits scene sonic vs knuckles sonic vs robotnik eggman sonic 2 full movie online free clips 4k hd only action cinemasins sonic 2 best moments funniest moments sonic 2 tails knuckles sonic 2 great movie bad movie funny moments sonic 3 shadow sonic 2 easter eggs best moments sonic 2 golden sonic ending final battle temple battle sonic 2 snowboard mountain Michael Kenneth Williams, Brendan Gleeson, and Charlotte Rampling co-star. Directed by Justin Kurzel (The Snowtown Murders).</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="30585" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="443817"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:q6R7SyV9C8I</id>
  <yt:videoId>q6R7SyV9C8I</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCG_nvdTLdijiAAuPKxtvBjA</yt:channelId>
  <title>Uncharted — How to be Ruined by the Video Game Movie Curse | Anatomy Of A Failure</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=q6R7SyV9C8I"/>
  <author>
   <name>Filmento</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCG_nvdTLdijiAAuPKxtvBjA</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-05-05T19:15:02+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-09-02T04:42:16+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Uncharted — How to be Ruined by the Video Game Movie Curse | Anatomy Of A Failure</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/q6R7SyV9C8I?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i2.ytimg.com/vi/q6R7SyV9C8I/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>Become a Lord or Lady of Glencoe by buying land you can visit any time, and help create nature reserves in Scotland. 10% off with code FILMENTO: https://www.highlandtitles.com

2022's Uncharted is a film adaptation of Playstation's Uncharted video game franchise, with Tom Holland as Nathan Drake and Mark Wahlberg as Mark Wahlberg. And as much as I liked it personally, it is yet another victim of the infamous video game movie curse that also claimed other victims like Mortal Kombat and Tomb Raider. So like in the Moral Kombat video, lets see how being a video game movie has harmful effects on Uncharted and how to hopefully fix them for the future. As weird as it may seem... Sonic the Hedgehog might still be the best video game movie to date. I just hope they get Bioshock right, but then again it's Netflix so I dunno.

Support:     https://patreon.com/filmento
Follow:       https://twitter.com/filmento


Music:
#Uncharted #AnatomyOfAFailure

-
Uncharted (2022)
Intrepid twentysomething Nathan Drake (Tom Holland) desires a life of adventure. Upon crossing paths with the wry Victor Sullivan (Mark Wahlberg), the adventurous duo embarks on a high-stakes international quest to find the world's most elusive ancient treasure. Along the way, they encounter evidence that may lead to the whereabouts of Drake's estranged brother. Ruben Fleischer directs the prequel to the computer game of the same name. Co-starring Antonio Banderas and Tati Gabrielle.
-
Mortal Kombat (2021)
MMA fighter Cole Young (Lewis Tan) is unaware of his heritage - or why Outworld’s Emperor seeks to hunt him down. Cole finds sanctuary under Lord Raiden (Tadanobu Asano) and prepares to stand with Earth’s greatest champions against the enemies of Outworld in a high-stakes battle for the universe. Will Cole be able to unleash his arcana in time to stop the Outworld once and for all? Mortal Kombat is in theaters April 23 and streaming exclusively on HBO Max at 12:01 am PT/3:01 am ET. Available on HBO Max in the US only at no extra cost to subscribers for 31 days from its theatrical release. The Mortal Kombat movie everything wrong with Uncharted honest trailer uncharted watch full movie online free 4k clip hd uncharted sequel elena fisher uncharted movie funny moments best moments uncharted ending fight scene uncharted ending explained uncharted movie sequel 2 uncharted bad movie uncharted great movie uncharted failure box office flop reboot from director Simon McQuoid features the defenders of Earthrealm Liu Kang, Sonya Blade, Jax Briggs and more entering the Mortal Kombat tournament to save the world from Shang Tsung, Sub-Zero, Mileena and other supernatural kombatants. Hanzo Hasashi’s (Hiroyuki Sanada) life is forever changed when his compound is attacked by a few uninvited visitors.</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="26174" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="565693"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
</feed>
