<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns:yt="http://www.youtube.com/xml/schemas/2015" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
 <link rel="self" href="http://www.youtube.com/feeds/videos.xml?channel_id=UCbu2SsF-Or3Rsn3NxqODImw"/>
 <id>yt:channel:UCbu2SsF-Or3Rsn3NxqODImw</id>
 <yt:channelId>UCbu2SsF-Or3Rsn3NxqODImw</yt:channelId>
 <title>GameSpot</title>
 <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCbu2SsF-Or3Rsn3NxqODImw"/>
 <author>
  <name>GameSpot</name>
  <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCbu2SsF-Or3Rsn3NxqODImw</uri>
 </author>
 <published>2006-04-09T02:01:54+00:00</published>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:7MIMXFeKMVU</id>
  <yt:videoId>7MIMXFeKMVU</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCbu2SsF-Or3Rsn3NxqODImw</yt:channelId>
  <title>Firearms Expert Reacts To Call of Duty: Modern Warfare 2 (2022)’s Multiplayer Guns</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7MIMXFeKMVU"/>
  <author>
   <name>GameSpot</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCbu2SsF-Or3Rsn3NxqODImw</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-11-05T14:00:09+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-11-05T14:00:09+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Firearms Expert Reacts To Call of Duty: Modern Warfare 2 (2022)’s Multiplayer Guns</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/7MIMXFeKMVU?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i4.ytimg.com/vi/7MIMXFeKMVU/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>Jonathan Ferguson, a weapons expert and Keeper of Firearms &amp; Artillery at the Royal Armouries, breaks down more of the weaponry of Call of Duty: Modern Warfare 2 (2022), including the AKS-74U, a suppressed M4 shotgun, and Jonathan’s favourite, the MP5.

00:00 - Opening
00:38 - AKS-74U
02:14 - SA-B 50
03:27 - AR-57
05:06 - 556 Icarus
06:25 - Marlin Model 336
08:15 - Benelli M4 Super 90
09:45 - M16A3
10:29 - HK94A3
12:46 - Smith and Wesson Model 500 (with snake shot)
13:42 - Gepard GM6 Lynx
16:26 - Ending

In the latest video in the Firearm Expert Reacts series, Jonathan Ferguson--a weapons expert and Keeper of Firearms &amp; Artillery at the Royal Armouries--breaks down more of the guns of Call of Duty: Modern Warfare 2 (2022) and compares them to their real-life counterparts.

Firearms Expert Reacts playlist - https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=y4T78VQoWUs&amp;list=PLpg6WLs8kxGMgYb13XjPgOKbm5O-CDq7R

If you're interested in seeing more of Jonathan's work, you can check out more from the Royal Armouries right here. - https://www.youtube.com/user/RoyalArmouries

If you would like to support the Royal Armouries, you can make a charitable donation to the museum here. - https://royalarmouries.org/support-us/donations/

And if you would like to become a member of the Royal Armouries, you can get a membership here. - https://royalarmouries.org/support-us/membership/

You can either purchase Jonathan's book here. - https://www.headstamppublishing.com/bullpup-rifle-book

Or at the Royal Armouries shop here. - https://shop.royalarmouries.org/collections/thorneycroft-to-sa80-british-bullpup-firearms-1901-2020

You can subscribe to the Armax Journal that Jonathan Associate Edited here: https://www.armaxjournal.org/</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="3370" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="34984"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:f9JIpDJ8avg</id>
  <yt:videoId>f9JIpDJ8avg</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCbu2SsF-Or3Rsn3NxqODImw</yt:channelId>
  <title>Overwatch 2 Ramattra Official Reveal Trailer</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=f9JIpDJ8avg"/>
  <author>
   <name>GameSpot</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCbu2SsF-Or3Rsn3NxqODImw</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-11-05T02:12:20+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-11-05T02:12:20+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Overwatch 2 Ramattra Official Reveal Trailer</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/f9JIpDJ8avg?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i3.ytimg.com/vi/f9JIpDJ8avg/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>Ramattra’s story is complex and multifaceted, and his ultimate goal is to protect his people, but the cost of that goal is still to be determined.

Originally a war machine, Ramattra shed his munitions for a shield to protect his people by promoting peace and tranquility. His ideals weren’t far removed from his fellow Shambli monk, Zenyatta. However, Ramattra’s story is one of hardships, trauma, and a magnified view of humanity’s harsh realities.

Harmony was replaced by dissonance, and Ramattra began to approach his convictions from a more pragmatic angle—justifying any means necessary to defend his fellow omnics. As the leader of Null Sector, Ramattra boasts incredible support from his people, and he is primed to impose his philosophies on our world.

Ramattra will join the tank lineup at the beginning of Season Two, starting December 6. 

#overwatch2 #overwatch #gaming</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="1909" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="55508"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:9fLUxRsMJC8</id>
  <yt:videoId>9fLUxRsMJC8</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCbu2SsF-Or3Rsn3NxqODImw</yt:channelId>
  <title>Infinity Ward Fixes Modern Warfare 2 Vault Edition Confusion | GameSpot News</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9fLUxRsMJC8"/>
  <author>
   <name>GameSpot</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCbu2SsF-Or3Rsn3NxqODImw</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-11-04T21:30:02+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-11-05T07:24:57+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Infinity Ward Fixes Modern Warfare 2 Vault Edition Confusion | GameSpot News</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/9fLUxRsMJC8?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i2.ytimg.com/vi/9fLUxRsMJC8/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>MW2 Vault Edition players get a bonus, Marvel Snap will let you play with friends, and Final Fantasy XVI is almost finished.
#Gaming @ModernWarfare2 #MarvelSnap #FFXVI 

Did you pick up the Modern Warfare Vault Edition? Good news! You’re getting 10 hours of double xp and double weapons xp tokens.

Initially this offer was only available to purchasers of the Vault edition that picked up the game via one of the previous, recent Call of Duty titles: Modern Warfare 2019, Black Ops Cold War, or Vanguard.

However, since almost no one purchases a game in that manner, the vast majority of people that picked up the Vault edition were not eligible for these bonuses, leading to confusion amongst many of the players that picked up the more expensive version of the game

&quot;We understand there has been some confusion about an in-game store exclusive reward for the Vault Edition,&quot; reads an image Tweeted out by the official Call of Duty Twitter. “ Therefore, we've decided to reward all players that currently own or purchase any version of the MWII Vault Edition with 10 hours of double xp tokens and 10 hours of double weapon xp tokens. Current owners who have not already received the tokens should expect to see them in their account over the next 48 hours”

That means, even if you purchase the Vault Edition after this announcement was made via the means of your choosing, you’re still going to net yourself those double XP and double weapons XP tokens, which, yeah, you should get if you’re paying $100 for this game.

Now, if only there was double XP in Marvel Snap, the new hit mobile card game from former Hearthstone devs, and my personal latest obsession.

If you’ve been playing Marvel Snap, and you’ve wanted to absolutely wipe the floor with your friends that are also just as addicted, you won’t have to wait long. An update that is coming to the game before the end of the year will allow you to do just that.

As reported by The Washington Post, a new Battle mode will be coming to Marvel Snap before the end of 2022, and will allow players to challenge specific people, like friends, as opposed to using the game's current matchmaking system, but matches will work differently to the regular mode already in the game.

In the current mode, players play for ranked points, with the Snap mechanic effectively serving as a way to double down on the amount of ranked points on the line. As it wouldn't exactly be fair to bet ranked points on matches between friends, Battle mode will instead introduce a HP system. 

Each player will have 10 HP, with the number of points on the line for a given match instead affecting the losing player's HP pool as opposed to rank. Battle mode matches will consist of multiple rounds, and the first player to lose all their HP will lose the match.

Marvel Snap is currently the 5th most popular free-to-play game on the App Store, but can also be played via Steam. If you haven’t checked it out yet, I implore you do, unless you have responsibilities in your life you absolutely cannot neglect.</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="213" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="8722"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:cqlrMjlhvcc</id>
  <yt:videoId>cqlrMjlhvcc</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCbu2SsF-Or3Rsn3NxqODImw</yt:channelId>
  <title>God of War (2018) Full Story Recap</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=cqlrMjlhvcc"/>
  <author>
   <name>GameSpot</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCbu2SsF-Or3Rsn3NxqODImw</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-11-04T14:00:20+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-11-04T14:00:20+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>God of War (2018) Full Story Recap</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/cqlrMjlhvcc?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i4.ytimg.com/vi/cqlrMjlhvcc/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>2018’s God of War packed a lot of story into its 20 hour campaign. Not only did it have the Herculean task of reinventing the franchise’s central anti-hero, Kratos, but it had a whole new world of myths and legends to introduce. Whether you played the original back in 2018 and want a story recap, or you’re just jumping in to prep yourself for Ragnarok, let’s break down the story so far.

In the above video, we break down and recap the full story of Sony Santa Monica’s God of War (2018). The video goes through the story beats of the 20-hour campaign, from Kratos and Atreus’s journey to the highest peak in the Nine Realms through to their encounters with the many gods and monsters.

Timeline Playlist - https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3gaFRoP4RUA&amp;list=PLpg6WLs8kxGN7aotOq-B5tYZWpvTZ3KRS

00:00 - Opening 
00:29 - The Journey Begins
03:34 - The Light of Alfheim
04:23 - The Mountain
05:44 - Gods and Giants
06:58 - A Funny Thing Happened on the Way to Jotunheim
08:38 - Helheim and Back
09:43 - A God in the Family
11:25 - The Realm Between Realms
12:41 - The Belly of the Beast
14:07 - Jotunheim, Finally
16:25 - Ending</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="572" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="14903"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:YBIa99gulDM</id>
  <yt:videoId>YBIa99gulDM</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCbu2SsF-Or3Rsn3NxqODImw</yt:channelId>
  <title>Wo Long: Fallen Dynasty 8 Minutes of New Gameplay</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=YBIa99gulDM"/>
  <author>
   <name>GameSpot</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCbu2SsF-Or3Rsn3NxqODImw</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-11-04T13:00:19+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-11-04T13:00:19+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Wo Long: Fallen Dynasty 8 Minutes of New Gameplay</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/YBIa99gulDM?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i2.ytimg.com/vi/YBIa99gulDM/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>Set in a dark fantasy version of China during its warring Three Kingdoms period of history, Wo Long: Fallen Dynasty is aiming to be bigger in scale than Team Ninja's Nioh games and even more challenging.

While Wo-Long: Fallen Dynasty will launch on Xbox One and Xbox Series X|S as a day-one Game Pass title--it'll also be available on PC, PS5, and PS4 on March 3, 2023. 
#Gaming #WoLongFallenDynasty #Gamespot</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="496" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="28532"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:yf1uHJ-4iB0</id>
  <yt:videoId>yf1uHJ-4iB0</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCbu2SsF-Or3Rsn3NxqODImw</yt:channelId>
  <title>God Of War Ragnarok PS5 vs PS4 Comparison</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=yf1uHJ-4iB0"/>
  <author>
   <name>GameSpot</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCbu2SsF-Or3Rsn3NxqODImw</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-11-03T23:21:02+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-11-04T08:38:35+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>God Of War Ragnarok PS5 vs PS4 Comparison</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/yf1uHJ-4iB0?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i2.ytimg.com/vi/yf1uHJ-4iB0/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>We take a look at God Of War Ragnarok graphical differences on a base PS4 in 1080p, and compare it to PS5's 4K version with fidelity mode on.

0:00 Combat Side By Side
0:22 Top/Bottom Comparison
2:01 Wiped Comparison
3:05 Top/Bottom Comparison 2
3:41 PS5 Raw Gameplay
4:48 PS4 Raw Gameplay
5:38 Split Comparison


#godofwarragnarok #godofwar #gaming</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="708" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="55969"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:JTZNLwCOD6M</id>
  <yt:videoId>JTZNLwCOD6M</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCbu2SsF-Or3Rsn3NxqODImw</yt:channelId>
  <title>God of War Ragnarok Review Roundup | GameSpot News</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=JTZNLwCOD6M"/>
  <author>
   <name>GameSpot</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCbu2SsF-Or3Rsn3NxqODImw</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-11-03T21:30:05+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-11-04T09:06:43+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>God of War Ragnarok Review Roundup | GameSpot News</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/JTZNLwCOD6M?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i3.ytimg.com/vi/JTZNLwCOD6M/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>God of War Ragnarok reviews are here, a tease at a second Warzone 2.0 map, and Modern Warfare 2 gets its first post launch patch. All this on today’s GameSpot News.
#Gaming #GodOfWarRagnarok #Warzone2.0 

God of War Ragnarok reviews are here, a tease at a second Warzone 2.0 map, and Modern Warfare II gets its first post launch patch. All this on today’s GameSpot News.

Ragnarok Reviews are here, and it sounds like the game Ragnarocks. 

Look. I’m sorry. I tried to write this script and not make that joke, but I just couldn’t do it. I promise it’s the only one.

On Metacritic, which, full disclosure, is a sister site to GameSpot, the game at the time of recording has a 94 avg based on 112 reviews. That is the exact same score its 2018 predecessor has on the site as well based on 118 reviews.

Our own review from Tamoor Hussain states, “God of War Ragnarok is a lavish production with pristine visuals, jaw-dropping scale, crunchy combat that is as satisfying as it is brutal, and a world that begs to have its every corner and crevice explored.” Hussain’s singular gripe with the game stems from elements of its combat, noting, “ the mechanics can struggle under the pressure of the increased speed and aggression [as the game progresses]”

Leon Hurley at Games Radar has some light criticism of the game’s first half, saying, “I found God of War Ragnarok an oddly split experience overall. There's a light start that feels padded – still good but missing depth – which leads into a weighty finish that's every bit the equal of its predecessor.”

Game Informer’s Kyle Hilliard, who used to be GameSpot’s Kyle Hilliard — they won him over by saying he could review Ragnarok, I’m sure — writes, “God of War Ragnarök feels a lot like God of War (2018), which is a compliment considering how fantastic that game is. Sony Santa Monica was right to not break what wasn't broken and it has expertly continued the story threads that were left hanging from the previous game. Any complaints about the overall experience (familiar combat, collecting and leveling up equipment isn't particularly interesting) are quickly forgotten in the face of the compelling narrative, believable character relationships, and incredible visuals and animation.”

Not too Badnarok. 

TIMESTAMPS: 
00:14 - Ragnarok review roundup
02:15 - Warzone 2.0 map easter egg
03:15 - Modern Warfare 2 patch</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="368" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="14088"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:FWwgkfPtZks</id>
  <yt:videoId>FWwgkfPtZks</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCbu2SsF-Or3Rsn3NxqODImw</yt:channelId>
  <title>God of War Ragnarok: The Mythology Behind the End of the World</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=FWwgkfPtZks"/>
  <author>
   <name>GameSpot</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCbu2SsF-Or3Rsn3NxqODImw</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-11-03T19:00:15+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-11-04T09:05:52+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>God of War Ragnarok: The Mythology Behind the End of the World</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/FWwgkfPtZks?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i3.ytimg.com/vi/FWwgkfPtZks/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>Ragnarök is coming, and Kratos and Atreus will soon find themselves facing the end of the world itself. Yet, as the great battle with the most dangerous of Aesir approaches, let’s look at the history of behind the Norse apocalypse, Ragnarok itself, to see what that might mean for God of War Ragnarok.</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="306" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="6832"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:pLTfX838Bgs</id>
  <yt:videoId>pLTfX838Bgs</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCbu2SsF-Or3Rsn3NxqODImw</yt:channelId>
  <title>Day of the Devs Showcase 2022 Livestream</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=pLTfX838Bgs"/>
  <author>
   <name>GameSpot</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCbu2SsF-Or3Rsn3NxqODImw</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-11-03T18:17:48+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-11-04T09:05:15+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Day of the Devs Showcase 2022 Livestream</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/pLTfX838Bgs?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i1.ytimg.com/vi/pLTfX838Bgs/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>Tune in November 3rd at 10am PT for Day of the Devs! This digital showcase will feature amazing indie games and the passionate developers that make them.&#13;
&#13;
#gaming</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="119" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="4842"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:ciO7N6Y6frE</id>
  <yt:videoId>ciO7N6Y6frE</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCbu2SsF-Or3Rsn3NxqODImw</yt:channelId>
  <title>Sonic Frontiers Showdown Official Trailer</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ciO7N6Y6frE"/>
  <author>
   <name>GameSpot</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCbu2SsF-Or3Rsn3NxqODImw</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-11-03T16:37:03+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-11-04T11:21:53+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Sonic Frontiers Showdown Official Trailer</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/ciO7N6Y6frE?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i4.ytimg.com/vi/ciO7N6Y6frE/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>It's almost time. Explore the Starfall Islands, gather the Chaos Emeralds, and get ready for the showdown of a lifetime in Sonic Frontiers.

Sonic Frontiers releases on November 8th, 2022 on PlayStation 4, PlayStation 5, Xbox Series X and S, Nintendo Switch, and Steam!</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="1503" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="38759"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:veulTkE_QZE</id>
  <yt:videoId>veulTkE_QZE</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCbu2SsF-Or3Rsn3NxqODImw</yt:channelId>
  <title>God of War Ragnarok Review</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=veulTkE_QZE"/>
  <author>
   <name>GameSpot</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCbu2SsF-Or3Rsn3NxqODImw</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-11-03T16:00:38+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-11-04T08:53:13+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>God of War Ragnarok Review</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/veulTkE_QZE?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i3.ytimg.com/vi/veulTkE_QZE/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>Sony Santa Monica brings back what made the original God of War reboot great and delivers another fantastic story with exceptional writing.

#godofwarragnarok #gamespot #gaming</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="3930" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="143543"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:pVzaitdJKk0</id>
  <yt:videoId>pVzaitdJKk0</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCbu2SsF-Or3Rsn3NxqODImw</yt:channelId>
  <title>Sonic Frontiers Everything To Know</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=pVzaitdJKk0"/>
  <author>
   <name>GameSpot</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCbu2SsF-Or3Rsn3NxqODImw</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-11-02T23:30:06+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-11-04T18:28:48+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Sonic Frontiers Everything To Know</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/pVzaitdJKk0?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i1.ytimg.com/vi/pVzaitdJKk0/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>Sonic is back with a bold new direction in Sonic Frontiers. Sonic Frontiers takes cues from modern open world games to create something both familiar and all new for Sonic. So, here is everything you need to know about Sonic Frontiers.
#Gaming #SonicFrontiers #GameSpot

Brand new to Sonic with Sonic Frontiers is a skill tree. Fallen enemies now drop skill pieces Sonic can collect and use to upgrade his skills. Not only that, but Sonic will be able to upgrade his stats by collecting red seeds of power and blue seeds of defense. These seeds can be found by completing puzzles and sidequests in the open zones. These puzzles can also unlock new areas of the map.

Combat is another new feature to Sonic Frontiers. While Sonic will maintain his classic skill of a homing attack, he’ll also have a drop dash and stomp attack, be able to slide at any point, and boost his speed on ground or mid-air. Not only that, but Sonic can now attack with his fists in melee combat, perform combos, and use the brand new skill tree to level up these skills.

Cyloop sees you run in a circle around an enemy while activating this ability in order to break enemy’s shields and guards, then have an opening to get in attacks. Cyloop can also be used to quickly collect rings after getting hit by an enemy.

Sonic can also now both parry enemy attacks and dodge. Parrying allows Sonic to use this window to counter-attack. Meanwhile, dodging at the right time briefly slows down the time allowing Sonic to get in more attacks.

Included in Sonic’s new skillset is a meter that will fill up during combos, and when high enough, allows Sonic to perform a Phantom Rush - which boosts Sonic’s attack power until the meter drops back to 0.</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="1591" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="50259"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:mdUxpZKJJXM</id>
  <yt:videoId>mdUxpZKJJXM</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCbu2SsF-Or3Rsn3NxqODImw</yt:channelId>
  <title>PSVR 2 Is More Expensive Than A PS5 | GameSpot News</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=mdUxpZKJJXM"/>
  <author>
   <name>GameSpot</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCbu2SsF-Or3Rsn3NxqODImw</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-11-02T21:30:04+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-11-04T21:14:29+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>PSVR 2 Is More Expensive Than A PS5 | GameSpot News</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/mdUxpZKJJXM?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i2.ytimg.com/vi/mdUxpZKJJXM/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>PSVR 2 gets a massive price tag, Modern Warfare 2 runs into more issues, and It Takes Two developer teases the team’s next game. All this on today’s GameSpot News.
#Gaming #PlayStation #PS5 #ModernWarfare2 

PSVR 2 gets a massive price tag, Modern Warfare 2 runs into more issues, and It Takes Two developer teases the team’s next game. All this on today’s GameSpot News.

Sony has revealed the launch date and price of the upcoming PSVR 2. The good news is the device is releasing very soon. The bad news is that it will cost you more than a PS5.

On February 22 2023, the PSVR 2 will release for $550, which is $50 more than the PS5 with a disk drive and $150 more than the digital only PS5. Sony will also sell a Horizon Call of the Mountain bundle that comes with the system and the game for $600, while the PSVR 2 Sense controller charging station will be offered on its own for $50.

PSVR 2 will be available to preorder starting November 15 from Sony's online store at direct.playstation.com for shoppers in the US, UK, France, Germany, Belgium, Netherlands, and Luxembourg. Preorder registration opens today, November 2.

In addition to the release date and pricing announcement, Sony revealed a bunch more games you’ll be able to play on the system at launch.

In the vein of its previous VR title Until Dawn: Rush of Blood that came out for the first PS VR, developer Supermassive will be releasing a similar experience under its more recent Dark Pictures banner; a horror game subtitled Switchback VR that, like Rush of Blood, is a first person shooter on a rollercoaster.

In addition, shooter franchise Crossfire is coming to the device with Sierra Squad, the popular VR title Pistol Whip is being ported over, and the Cities series is getting a VR installment. For more info on all the titles announced, head to the link in the description.

On the PC side of gaming life, a Steam feature that was available at Modern Warfare 2’s launch has since been disabled. 

For the unfamiliar, family sharing is a Steam feature that lets family and friends have access to games on your account. Any account can share a game with up to five other accounts, but there are some restrictions. The digital copy is essentially shared between accounts, so two players cannot play at the same time on different PCs. The feature is activated at the discretion of the game publisher and there is an option to turn it off or on in the Steam backend.

While the game launched with this enabled, a listing on SteamDB states the feature was turned off on Halloween, preventing some players who had access to the game from playing further.

Activision has yet to make an official comment, but users have speculated that family sharing can enable cheaters to avoid bans. Regardless, members of the Call of Duty community are generally unhappy with the change, citing the high price tag of the game and the desire to let other members of their household or family play without buying a second copy.

TIMESTAMPS:
00:12 - PSVR 2 https://www.gamespot.com/articles/sony-reveals-a-bunch-of-new-psvr-2-games/1100-6508821/
01:42 - Modern Warfare 2 Steam family sharing disabled
02:51 - Josef Fares talks Hazelight's next game</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="363" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="12334"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:_H2rYcqyNqU</id>
  <yt:videoId>_H2rYcqyNqU</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCbu2SsF-Or3Rsn3NxqODImw</yt:channelId>
  <title>God of War Ragnarok Everything To Know</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_H2rYcqyNqU"/>
  <author>
   <name>GameSpot</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCbu2SsF-Or3Rsn3NxqODImw</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-11-02T14:00:21+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-11-04T18:10:23+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>God of War Ragnarok Everything To Know</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/_H2rYcqyNqU?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i4.ytimg.com/vi/_H2rYcqyNqU/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>Kratos and Atreus are back! And they’re ready to face the end of the world together, or at least I hope they are. Here’s everything you need to know about God of War Ragnarok.
#Gaming #GodofWarRagnarok #GameSpot

God of War Ragnarok takes place a few years after the events of God of War 2018. According to Sony, Atreus is desperately curious and “like most young people, he wants to understand who he is more than anything. In this case, he wants to understand who he could be. The mystery of Loki's role in the upcoming conflict is something that Atreus cannot let go of.”

That conflict is the looming threat of Ragnarok, a prophesied battle that will end the world and Sony continued by saying “Atreus also doesn't want to stand by and do nothing while conflict consumes the Nine Realms.

s for Kratos, Sony says he is intent on helping to spare Atreus from the &quot;bloody lessons he learned from his conflict with gods.&quot;

If you’ve never played the games that came before 2018’s release then let me just say, this man’s hands get VERY dirty. We have a complete God of War timeline video available to watch if you need a refresher. For now, back to Ragnarok. 

In order to find the answers they seek, Kratos and Atreus will journey to each of the Nine Realms facing off against a variety of Norse gods and monsters while exploring stunning mythical landscapes. 

Ragnarok will wrap up this Norse chapter of the franchise, as Sony Santa Monica wanted to avoid having this portion of the story from getting too unwieldy.</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="1932" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="83403"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:CQq3wm0GB7I</id>
  <yt:videoId>CQq3wm0GB7I</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCbu2SsF-Or3Rsn3NxqODImw</yt:channelId>
  <title>Call of Duty: Modern Warfare 2 Multiplayer Review</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=CQq3wm0GB7I"/>
  <author>
   <name>GameSpot</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCbu2SsF-Or3Rsn3NxqODImw</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-11-02T02:28:29+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-11-04T17:51:23+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Call of Duty: Modern Warfare 2 Multiplayer Review</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/CQq3wm0GB7I?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i4.ytimg.com/vi/CQq3wm0GB7I/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>Modern Warfare 2 dials back Call of Duty's multiplayer experience for a refreshing and more classic feel, but the overall package is incomplete.</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="1248" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="64525"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
</feed>
