<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<rdf:RDF
 xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
 xmlns="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/"
 xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
 xmlns:taxo="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/taxonomy/"
 xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
 xmlns:syn="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
 xmlns:admin="http://webns.net/mvcb/"
>

<channel rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/">
<title>econ updates on arXiv.org</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">Economics (econ) updates on the arXiv.org e-print archive</description>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:date>2022-11-03T20:30:00-05:00</dc:date>
<dc:publisher>www-admin@arxiv.org</dc:publisher>
<dc:subject>Economics</dc:subject>
<syn:updateBase>1901-01-01T00:00+00:00</syn:updateBase>
<syn:updateFrequency>1</syn:updateFrequency>
<syn:updatePeriod>daily</syn:updatePeriod>
<items>
 <rdf:Seq>
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01537" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01547" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01557" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01575" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01921" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01944" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2003.07545" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2010.01105" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2203.04065" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2203.17232" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2209.07330" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.10166" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.00131" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.00520" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.16547" />
 </rdf:Seq>
</items>
<image rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif" />
</channel>
<image rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif">
<title>arXiv.org</title>
<url>http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif</url>
<link>http://arxiv.org/</link>
</image>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01537">
<title>Stochastic Treatment Choice with Empirical Welfare Updating. (arXiv:2211.01537v1 [econ.EM])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01537</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;This paper proposes a novel method to estimate individualised treatment
assignment rules. The method is designed to find rules that are stochastic,
reflecting uncertainty in estimation of an assignment rule and about its
welfare performance. Our approach is to form a prior distribution over
assignment rules and to update this prior based upon an empirical welfare
criterion. The social planner then assigns treatment by drawing a policy from
the resulting posterior. We show analytically a welfare-optimal way of updating
the prior using empirical welfare. The posterior obtained by implementing the
optimal updating rule is not feasible to compute, so we propose a variational
Bayes approximation for the optimal posterior. We characterise the welfare
regret convergence of the assignment rule based upon this variational Bayes
approximation and show that it converges to zero at a rate of ln(n)/sqrt(n). We
apply our methods to experimental data from the Job Training Partnership Act
Study and extensive numerical simulations to illustrate the implementation of
our methods.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/econ/1/au:+Kitagawa_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Toru Kitagawa&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/econ/1/au:+Lopez_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Hugo Lopez&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/econ/1/au:+Rowley_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jeff Rowley&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01547">
<title>A Systematic Paradigm for Detecting, Surfacing, and Characterizing Heterogeneous Treatment Effects (HTE). (arXiv:2211.01547v1 [stat.ME])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01547</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;To effectively optimize and personalize treatments, it is necessary to
investigate the heterogeneity of treatment effects. With the wide range of
users being treated over many online controlled experiments, the typical
approach of manually investigating each dimension of heterogeneity becomes
overly cumbersome and prone to subjective human biases. We need an efficient
way to search through thousands of experiments with hundreds of target
covariates and hundreds of breakdown dimensions. In this paper, we propose a
systematic paradigm for detecting, surfacing and characterizing heterogeneous
treatment effects. First, we detect if treatment effect variation is present in
an experiment, prior to specifying any breakdowns. Second, we surface the most
relevant dimensions for heterogeneity. Finally, we characterize the
heterogeneity beyond just the conditional average treatment effects (CATE) by
studying the conditional distributions of the estimated individual treatment
effects. We show the effectiveness of our methods using simulated data and
empirical studies.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/stat/1/au:+Cai_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;John Cai&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/stat/1/au:+Wang_W/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Weinan Wang&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01557">
<title>Estimating interaction effects with panel data. (arXiv:2211.01557v1 [econ.EM])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01557</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;A common task in empirical economics is to estimate \emph{interaction
effects} that measure how the effect of one variable $X$ on another variable
$Y$ depends on a third variable $H$. This paper considers the estimation of
interaction effects in linear panel models with a fixed number of time periods.
There are at least two ways to estimate interaction effects in this setting,
both common in applied work. Our theoretical results show that these two
approaches are distinct, and only coincide under strong conditions on
unobserved effect heterogeneity. Our empirical results show that the difference
between the two approaches is large, leading to conflicting conclusions about
the sign of the interaction effect. Taken together, our findings may guide the
choice between the two approaches in empirical work.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/econ/1/au:+Muris_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Chris Muris&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/econ/1/au:+Wacker_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Konstantin Wacker&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01575">
<title>Are Synthetic Control Weights Balancing Score?. (arXiv:2211.01575v1 [stat.ME])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01575</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;In this short note, I outline conditions under which conditioning on
Synthetic Control (SC) weights emulates a randomized control trial where the
treatment status is independent of potential outcomes. Specifically, I
demonstrate that if there exist SC weights such that (i) the treatment effects
are exactly identified and (ii) these weights are uniformly and cumulatively
bounded, then SC weights are balancing scores.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/stat/1/au:+Parikh_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Harsh Parikh&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01921">
<title>On Estimation and Inference of Large Approximate Dynamic Factor Models via the Principal Component Analysis. (arXiv:2211.01921v1 [econ.EM])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01921</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;This paper revisits and provides an alternative derivation of the asymptotic
results for the Principal Components estimator of a large approximate factor
model as considered in Stock and Watson (2002), Bai (2003), and Forni et al.
(2009). Results are derived under a minimal set of assumptions with a special
focus on the time series setting, which is usually considered in almost all
recent empirical applications. Hence, $n$ and $T$ are not treated
symmetrically, the former being the dimension of the considered vector of time
series, while the latter being the sample size and, therefore, being relevant
only for estimation purposes, but not when it comes to just studying the
properties of the model at a population level. As a consequence, following
Stock and Watson (2002) and Forni et al. (2009), estimation is based on the
classical $n \times n$ sample covariance matrix. As expected, all asymptotic
results we derive are equivalent to those stated in Bai (2003), where, however,
a $T\times T$ covariance matrix is considered as a starting point. A series of
useful complementary results is also given. In particular, we give some
alternative sets of primitive conditions for mean-squared consistency of the
sample covariance matrix of the factors, of the idiosyncratic components, and
of the observed time series. We also give more intuitive asymptotic expansions
for the estimators showing that PCA is equivalent to OLS as long as
$\sqrt{T}/n\to 0$ and $\sqrt{n}/T\to 0$, that is loadings are estimated in a
time series regression as if the factors were known, while factors are
estimated in a cross-sectional regression as if the loadings were known. The
issue of testing multiple restrictions on the loadings as well as building
joint confidence intervals for the factors is discussed.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/econ/1/au:+Barigozzi_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Matteo Barigozzi&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01944">
<title>Carbon Monitor Europe, near-real-time daily CO$_2$ emissions for 27 EU countries and the United Kingdom. (arXiv:2211.01944v1 [physics.geo-ph])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01944</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;With the urgent need to implement the EU countries pledges and to monitor the
effectiveness of Green Deal plan, Monitoring Reporting and Verification tools
are needed to track how emissions are changing for all the sectors. Current
official inventories only provide annual estimates of national CO$_2$ emissions
with a lag of 1+ year which do not capture the variations of emissions due to
recent shocks including COVID lockdowns and economic rebounds, war in Ukraine.
Here we present a near-real-time country-level dataset of daily fossil fuel and
cement emissions from January 2019 through December 2021 for 27 EU countries
and UK, which called Carbon Monitor Europe. The data are calculated separately
for six sectors: power, industry, ground transportation, domestic aviation,
international aviation and residential. Daily CO$_2$ emissions are estimated
from a large set of activity data compiled from different sources. The goal of
this dataset is to improve the timeliness and temporal resolution of emissions
for European countries, to inform the public and decision makers about current
emissions changes in Europe.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Ke_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Piyu Ke&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Deng_Z/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Zhu Deng&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Zhu_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Biqing Zhu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Zheng_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Bo Zheng&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Wang_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yilong Wang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Boucher_O/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Olivier Boucher&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Arous_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Simon Ben Arous&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Zhou_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Chuanlong Zhou&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Dou_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xinyu Dou&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Sun_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Taochun Sun&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Li_Z/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Zhao Li&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Yan_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Feifan Yan&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Cui_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Duo Cui&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Hu_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yifan Hu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Huo_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Da Huo&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Pierre_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jean Pierre&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Engelen_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Richard Engelen&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Davis_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Steven J. Davis&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Ciais_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Philippe Ciais&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Liu_Z/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Zhu Liu&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2003.07545">
<title>Interpretable Personalization via Policy Learning with Linear Decision Boundaries. (arXiv:2003.07545v4 [cs.LG] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2003.07545</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;With the rise of the digital economy and an explosion of available
information about consumers, effective personalization of goods and services
has become a core business focus for companies to improve revenues and maintain
a competitive edge. This paper studies the personalization problem through the
lens of policy learning, where the goal is to learn a decision-making rule (a
policy) that maps from consumer and product characteristics (features) to
recommendations (actions) in order to optimize outcomes (rewards). We focus on
using available historical data for offline learning with unknown data
collection procedures, where a key challenge is the non-random assignment of
recommendations. Moreover, in many business and medical applications,
interpretability of a policy is essential. We study the class of policies with
linear decision boundaries to ensure interpretability, and propose learning
algorithms using tools from causal inference to address unbalanced treatments.
We study several optimization schemes to solve the associated non-convex,
non-smooth optimization problem, and find that a Bayesian optimization
algorithm is effective. We test our algorithm with extensive simulation studies
and apply it to an anonymized online marketplace customer purchase dataset,
where the learned policy outputs a personalized discount recommendation based
on customer and product features in order to maximize gross merchandise value
(GMV) for sellers. Our learned policy improves upon the platform&apos;s baseline by
88.2\% in net sales revenue, while also providing informative insights on which
features are important for the decision-making process. Our findings suggest
that our proposed policy learning framework using tools from causal inference
and Bayesian optimization provides a promising practical approach to
interpretable personalization across a wide range of applications.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Qu_Z/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Zhaonan Qu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Qian_I/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Isabella Qian&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zhou_Z/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Zhengyuan Zhou&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2010.01105">
<title>Policy evaluation of waste pricing programs using heterogeneous causal effect estimation. (arXiv:2010.01105v8 [econ.GN] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2010.01105</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Using machine learning methods in a quasi-experimental setting, I study the
heterogeneous effects of introducing waste prices - unit prices on household
unsorted waste disposal on - waste demands, municipal costs and pollution.
Using a unique panel of Italian municipalities with large variation in prices
and observables, I show that waste demands are nonlinear. I find evidence of
constant elasticities at low prices, and increasing elasticities at high prices
driven by income effects and waste habits before policy. The policy reduces
waste management costs and pollution in all municipalities after three years of
adoption, when prices cause significant waste avoidance.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/econ/1/au:+Valente_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Marica Valente&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2203.04065">
<title>Honest calibration assessment for binary outcome predictions. (arXiv:2203.04065v2 [math.ST] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2203.04065</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Probability predictions from binary regressions or machine learning methods
ought to be calibrated: If an event is predicted to occur with probability $x$,
it should materialize with approximately that frequency, which means that the
so-called calibration curve $p(\cdot)$ should equal the identity, $p(x) = x$
for all $x$ in the unit interval. We propose honest calibration assessment
based on novel confidence bands for the calibration curve, which are valid only
subject to the natural assumption of isotonicity. Besides testing the classical
goodness-of-fit null hypothesis of perfect calibration, our bands facilitate
inverted goodness-of-fit tests whose rejection allows for the sought-after
conclusion of a sufficiently well specified model. We show that our bands have
a finite sample coverage guarantee, are narrower than existing approaches, and
adapt to the local smoothness of the calibration curve $p$ and the local
variance of the binary observations. In an application to model predictions of
an infant having a low birth weight, the bounds give informative insights on
model calibration.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Dimitriadis_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Timo Dimitriadis&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Duembgen_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Lutz Duembgen&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Henzi_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Alexander Henzi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Puke_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Marius Puke&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Ziegel_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Johanna Ziegel&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2203.17232">
<title>Performative Power. (arXiv:2203.17232v2 [cs.LG] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2203.17232</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We introduce the notion of performative power, which measures the ability of
a firm operating an algorithmic system, such as a digital content
recommendation platform, to cause change in a population of participants. We
relate performative power to the economic study of competition in digital
economies. Traditional economic concepts struggle with identifying
anti-competitive patterns in digital platforms not least due to the complexity
of market definition. In contrast, performative power is a causal notion that
is identifiable with minimal knowledge of the market, its internals,
participants, products, or prices.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Low performative power implies that a firm can do no better than to optimize
their objective on current data. In contrast, firms of high performative power
stand to benefit from steering the population towards more profitable behavior.
We confirm in a simple theoretical model that monopolies maximize performative
power. A firm&apos;s ability to personalize increases performative power, while
competition and outside options decrease performative power. On the empirical
side, we propose an observational causal design to identify performative power
from discontinuities in how digital platforms display content. This allows to
repurpose causal effects from various studies about digital platforms as lower
bounds on performative power. Finally, we speculate about the role that
performative power might play in competition policy and antitrust enforcement
in digital marketplaces.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Hardt_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Moritz Hardt&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Jagadeesan_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Meena Jagadeesan&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Mendler_Dunner_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Celestine Mendler-D&amp;#xfc;nner&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2209.07330">
<title>Semiparametric Best Arm Identification with Contextual Information. (arXiv:2209.07330v3 [cs.LG] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2209.07330</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We study best-arm identification with a fixed budget and contextual
(covariate) information in stochastic multi-armed bandit problems. In each
round, after observing contextual information, we choose a treatment arm using
past observations and current context. Our goal is to identify the best
treatment arm, a treatment arm with the maximal expected reward marginalized
over the contextual distribution, with a minimal probability of
misidentification. First, we derive semiparametric lower bounds of the
misidentification probability for this problem, where we regard the gaps
between the expected rewards of the best and suboptimal treatment arms as
parameters of interest, and all other parameters, such as the expected rewards
conditioned on contexts, as the nuisance parameters. We then develop the
``Contextual RS-AIPW strategy,&apos;&apos; which consists of the random sampling (RS)
rule tracking a target allocation ratio and the recommendation rule using the
augmented inverse probability weighting (AIPW) estimator. Our proposed
Contextual RS-AIPW strategy is optimal because the upper bound for the
probability of misidentification by the strategy matches the semiparametric
lower bound, when the budget goes to infinity and the gaps converge to zero.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Kato_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Masahiro Kato&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Imaizumi_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Masaaki Imaizumi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Ishihara_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Takuya Ishihara&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Kitagawa_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Toru Kitagawa&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.10166">
<title>How (Not) to Reform India&apos;s Affirmative Action Policies for its Economically Weaker Segments. (arXiv:2210.10166v2 [econ.GN] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.10166</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Various groups in India are protected with a vertical reservation (VR)
policy, which sets aside a share of public positions for these groups.
VR-protected positions are processed by law after those open to all, assuring
that they are awarded to individuals who do not merit open positions.
Historically, VR protections were exclusive to groups who suffered
discrimination due to their caste identities. This structure means that no
individual can belong to multiple VR-protected groups, which implies that the
processing sequence of VR-protected groups is immaterial. A Constitutional
Amendment in 2019 granted economically weaker sections (EWS) VR protections,
but limited its eligibility to members of upper castes who are ineligible for
caste-based VR protections. The amendment was immediately brought to court, and
the exclusion of caste-based VR-protected groups was challenged due to its
violation of Right to Equality. A compromise that emerged at the Supreme Court
involves maintaining the amendment, but expanding its scope to include the
excluded groups. If this policy is adopted, individuals can belong to multiple
VR-protected groups. We show that a major loophole will emerge, if the Supreme
Court only expands the scope of EWS without specifying how its positions are
processed. Depending on which normative objective the court wants to promote,
we formulate and characterize three plausible specifications. If EWS is
processed simultaneously with other VR-protected groups, then the outcome is
one that selects the most meritorious individuals subject to the Court&apos;s
mandates. If EWS is processed before other VR-protected groups, then the
outcome maintains the elevated status of caste-based VR protections. If EWS is
processed after other VR-protected groups, then the outcome is the smallest
possible change from the contested amendment that escapes a violation of Right
to Equality.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/econ/1/au:+Sonmez_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Tayfun S&amp;#xf6;nmez&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/econ/1/au:+Unver_U/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Utku &amp;#xdc;nver&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.00131">
<title>A New Concept of the Value Function. (arXiv:2211.00131v2 [econ.GN] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.00131</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The prospect theory&apos;s value function is usually concave for gains, commonly
convex for losses, and generally steeper for losses than for gains. The neural
system is quite different from the loss and gains sides. Four new studies on
neurons related to this issue have examined neuronal responses to losses,
gains, and reference points, respectively. The value function with a neuronal
cusp could have variations and behavior cusps with catastrophe where a trader
closes her position.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/econ/1/au:+Sano_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Kazuo Sano&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.00520">
<title>Distortion risk measures in random environments: construction and axiomatic characterization. (arXiv:2211.00520v2 [econ.TH] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.00520</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The risk of a financial position shines through by means of the fluctuation
of its market price. The factors affecting the price of a financial position
include not only market internal factors, but also other various market
external factors. The latter can be understood as sorts of environments to
which financial positions have to expose. Motivated by this observation, this
paper aims to design a novel axiomatic approach to risk measures in random
environments. We construct a new distortion-type risk measure, which can
appropriately evaluate the risk of financial positions in the presence of
environments. After having studied its fundamental properties, we also
axiomatically characterize it. Furthermore, its coherence and dual
representation are investigated. The new class of risk measures in random
environments is large enough, for example, it not only can recover some known
risk measures such as the common weighted value at risk and range value at
risk, but also can induce other new specific risk measures such as risk
measures in the presence of background risk. Examples are given to illustrate
the new framework of risk measures. This paper gives some theoretical results
about risk measures in random environments, helping one to have an insight look
at the potential impact of environments on risk measures of positions.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/econ/1/au:+Gong_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Shuo Gong&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/econ/1/au:+Hu_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yijun Hu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/econ/1/au:+Wei_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Linxiao Wei&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.16547">
<title>Flexible machine learning estimation of conditional average treatment effects: a blessing and a curse. (arXiv:2210.16547v1 [stat.ME] CROSS LISTED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.16547</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Causal inference from observational data requires untestable assumptions. If
these assumptions apply, machine learning (ML) methods can be used to study
complex forms of causal-effect heterogeneity. Several ML methods were developed
recently to estimate the conditional average treatment effect (CATE). If the
features at hand cannot explain all heterogeneity, the individual treatment
effects (ITEs) can seriously deviate from the CATE. In this work, we
demonstrate how the distributions of the ITE and the estimated CATE can differ
when a causal random forest (CRF) is applied. We extend the CRF to estimate the
difference in conditional variance between treated and controls. If the ITE
distribution equals the CATE distribution, this difference in variance should
be small. If they differ, an additional causal assumption is necessary to
quantify the heterogeneity not captured by the CATE distribution. The
conditional variance of the ITE can be identified when the individual effect is
independent of the outcome under no treatment given the measured features.
Then, in the cases where the ITE and CATE distributions differ, the extended
CRF can appropriately estimate the characteristics of the ITE distribution
while the CRF fails to do so.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/stat/1/au:+Post_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Richard Post&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/stat/1/au:+Heuvel_I/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Isabel van den Heuvel&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/stat/1/au:+Petkovic_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Marko Petkovic&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/stat/1/au:+Heuvel_E/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Edwin van den Heuvel&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
</rdf:RDF>