<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<rdf:RDF
 xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
 xmlns="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/"
 xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
 xmlns:taxo="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/taxonomy/"
 xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
 xmlns:syn="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
 xmlns:admin="http://webns.net/mvcb/"
>

<channel rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/">
<title>physics.optics updates on arXiv.org</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">Physics -- Optics (physics.optics) updates on the arXiv.org e-print archive</description>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:date>2022-11-03T20:30:00-05:00</dc:date>
<dc:publisher>help@arxiv.org</dc:publisher>
<dc:subject>Physics -- Optics</dc:subject>
<syn:updateBase>1901-01-01T00:00+00:00</syn:updateBase>
<syn:updateFrequency>1</syn:updateFrequency>
<syn:updatePeriod>daily</syn:updatePeriod>
<items>
 <rdf:Seq>
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01368" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01408" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01433" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01437" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01476" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01489" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01680" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01734" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01735" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01811" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01823" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01997" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2111.08760" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2202.12615" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2205.14511" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2206.07103" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2206.10410" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2208.00899" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2208.07454" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.08504" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.13844" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01075" />
 </rdf:Seq>
</items>
<image rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif" />
</channel>
<image rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif">
<title>arXiv.org</title>
<url>http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif</url>
<link>http://arxiv.org/</link>
</image>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01368">
<title>Coherently averaged dual-comb spectroscopy with a low-noise and high-power free-running gigahertz dual-comb laser. (arXiv:2211.01368v1 [physics.optics])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01368</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We present a new type of dual optical frequency comb source capable of
scaling applications to high measurement speeds while combining high average
power, ultra-low noise operation, and a compact setup. Our approach is based on
a diode-pumped solid-state laser cavity which includes an intracavity biprism
operated at Brewster angle to generate two spatially-separated modes with
highly correlated properties. The 15-cm-long cavity uses an Yb:CALGO crystal
and a SESAM as an end mirror to generate more than 3 W average power per comb,
below 80 fs pulse duration, a repetition rate of 1.03 GHz, and a continuously
tunable repetition rate difference up to 27 kHz. We carefully investigate the
coherence properties of the dual-comb by a series of heterodyne measurements,
revealing several important features: (1) ultra-low jitter on the uncorrelated
part of the timing noise; (2) the radio frequency comb lines of the
interferograms are fully resolved in free-running operation; (3) we validate
that through a simple measurement of the interferograms we can determine the
fluctuations of the phase of all the radio frequency comb lines; (4) this phase
information is used in a post-processing routine to perform coherently averaged
dual-comb spectroscopy of acetylene (C2H2) over long timescales. Our results
represent a powerful and general approach to dual-comb applications by
combining low noise and high power operation directly from a highly compact
laser oscillator.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Phillips_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;C. R. Phillips&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Willenberg_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;B. Willenberg&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Nussbaum_Lapping_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;A. Nussbaum-Lapping&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Callegari_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;F. Callegari&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Camenzind_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;S. L. Camenzind&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Pupeikis_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;J. Pupeikis&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Keller_U/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;U. Keller&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01408">
<title>Design of a Modified Coupled Resonators Optical Waveguide Supporting a Frozen Mode. (arXiv:2211.01408v1 [physics.optics])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01408</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We design a three-way silicon optical waveguide with the Bloch dispersion
relation supporting a stationary inflection point (SIP). The SIP is a third
order exceptional point of degeneracy (EPD) where three Bloch modes coalesce
forming the frozen mode with greatly enhanced amplitude. The proposed design
consists of a coupled resonators optical waveguide (CROW) coupled to a parallel
straight waveguide. At any given frequency, this structure supports three pairs
of reciprocal Bloch eigenmodes, propagating and/or evanescent. In addition to
full-wave simulations, we also employ a so-called &apos;&apos;hybrid model&apos;&apos; that uses
transfer matrices obtained from full-wave simulations of sub-blocks of the unit
cell. This allows us to account for radiation losses and enables a design
procedure based on minimizing the eigenmodes&apos; coalescence parameter. The
proposed finite-length CROW displays almost unitary transfer function at the
SIP frequency, implying a nearly perfect conversion of the input light into the
frozen mode. The group delay and the effective quality factor at the SIP
frequency show an $N^{3}$ scaling, where $N$ is the number of unit cells in the
cavity. The frozen mode in the CROW can be utilized in various applications
like sensors, lasers and optical delay lines.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Nada_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Mohamed Y. Nada&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Mealy_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Tarek Mealy&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Islam_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Md Shafiqul Islam&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Vitebskiy_I/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ilya Vitebskiy&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Gibson_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ricky Gibson&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Bedford_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Robert Bedford&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Boyraz_O/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ozdal Boyraz&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Capolino_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Filippo Capolino&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01433">
<title>Testing highly nonlinear fiber for squeezed-light generation. (arXiv:2211.01433v1 [physics.optics])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01433</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Squeezed light, which is easily degraded by loss, could benefit from
generation directly in optical fiber. Furthermore, highly nonlinear fiber could
offer more efficient generation with lower pump power and shorter fiber lengths
than standard single-mode fiber. We investigate non-polarization-maintaining
highly nonlinear fiber (HNLF) for squeezed-light generation by characterizing
possible sources of excess noise, including its zero-dispersion wavelength
(ZDW) variation and polarization noise. We find significant ZDW variation and
excess polarization noise. We believe the polarization noise is from non-linear
polarization-mode dispersion. These findings are indicative of excess noise
that would reduce and potentially completely overtake any squeezing generated,
except possibly using intensity difference detection.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Chapman_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Joseph C. Chapman&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Peters_N/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Nicholas A. Peters&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01437">
<title>Multi-photon polymerization using upconversion nanoparticles for tunable feature-size printing. (arXiv:2211.01437v1 [physics.optics])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01437</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The recent development of light-based 3D printing technologies has marked a
turning point in additive manufacturing. Through photopolymerization, liquid
resins can be solidified into complex objects. Usually, the polymerization is
triggered by exciting a photoinitiator with ultraviolet (UV) or blue light. In
two-photon printing (TPP), the excitation is done through the non-linear
absorption of two photons; it enables printing 100-nm voxels but requires
expensive femtosecond lasers which strongly limits their broad dissemination.
Upconversion nanoparticles (UCNPs) have recently been proposed as an
alternative to TPP for photopolymerization but using continuous-wave lasers.
UCNPs convert near-infrared (NIR) into visible/UV light to initiate the
polymerization locally as in TPP. Here we provide a study of this multi-photon
mechanism and demonstrate how the non-linearity impacts the printing process.
In particular, we report on the possibility of fine-tuning the size of the
printed voxel by adjusting the NIR excitation intensity. Using gelatin-based
hydrogel, we are able to vary the transverse voxel size from 1.3 to 2.8 {\mu}m
and the axial size from 7.7 to 59 {\mu}m by adjusting the NIR power without
changing the degree of polymerization. This work opens up new opportunities for
speeding up the fabrication while preserving the minimum feature size with
cheap light sources.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Zhang_Q/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Qianyi Zhang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Boniface_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Antoine Boniface&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Parashar_V/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Virendra K. Parashar&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Gijs_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Martin A. M. Gijs&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Moser_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Christophe Moser&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01476">
<title>Integrated Photonic Tensor Processing Unit for a Matrix Multiply: a Review. (arXiv:2211.01476v1 [cs.ET])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01476</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The explosion of artificial intelligence and machine-learning algorithms,
connected to the exponential growth of the exchanged data, is driving a search
for novel application-specific hardware accelerators. Among the many, the
photonics field appears to be in the perfect spotlight for this global data
explosion, thanks to its almost infinite bandwidth capacity associated with
limited energy consumption. In this review, we will overview the major
advantages that photonics has over electronics for hardware accelerators,
followed by a comparison between the major architectures implemented on
Photonics Integrated Circuits (PIC) for both the linear and nonlinear parts of
Neural Networks. By the end, we will highlight the main driving forces for the
next generation of photonic accelerators, as well as the main limits that must
be overcome.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Peserico_N/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Nicola Peserico&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Shastri_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Bhavin J. Shastri&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Sorger_V/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Volker J. Sorger&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01489">
<title>Chip-scale Simulations in a Quantum-correlated Synthetic Space. (arXiv:2211.01489v1 [physics.optics])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01489</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;An efficient simulator for quantum systems is one of the original goals for
the efforts to develop a quantum computer [1]. In recent years, synthetic
dimension in photonics [2] have emerged as a potentially powerful approach for
simulation that is free from the constraint of geometric dimensionality. Here
we demonstrate a quantum-correlated synthetic crystal, based upon a
coherently-controlled broadband quantum frequency comb produced in a chip-scale
dynamically modulated lithium niobate microresonator. The time-frequency
entanglement inherent with the comb modes significantly extends the
dimensionality of the synthetic space, creating a massive nearly 400 x 400
synthetic lattice with electrically-controlled tunability. With such a system,
we are able to utilize the evolution of quantum correlations between entangled
photons to perform a series of simulations, demonstrating quantum random walks,
Bloch oscillations, and multi-level Rabi oscillations in the time and frequency
correlation space. The device combines the simplicity of monolithic
nanophotonic architecture, high dimensionality of a quantum-correlated
synthetic space, and on-chip coherent control, which opens up an avenue towards
chip-scale implementation of large-scale analog quantum simulation and
computation [1,3,4] in the time-frequency domain.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Javid_U/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Usman A. Javid&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Lopez_Rios_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Raymond Lopez-Rios&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Ling_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jingwei Ling&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Graf_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Austin Graf&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Staffa_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jeremy Staffa&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Lin_Q/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Qiang Lin&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01680">
<title>Electrically controlling vortices in a neutral exciton polariton condensate at room temperature. (arXiv:2211.01680v1 [physics.optics])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01680</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Manipulating bosonic condensates with electric fields is very challenging as
the electric fields do not directly interact with the neutral particles of the
condensate. Here we demonstrate a simple electric method to tune the vorticity
of exciton polariton condensates in a strong coupling liquid crystal (LC)
microcavity with CsPbBr$_3$ microplates as active material at room temperature.
In such a microcavity, the LC molecular director can be electrically modulated
giving control over the polariton condensation in different modes. For
isotropic non-resonant optical pumping we demonstrate the spontaneous formation
of vortices with topological charges of -2, -1, +1, and +2. The topological
vortex charge is controlled by a voltage in the range of 1 to 10 V applied to
the microcavity sample. This control is achieved by the interplay of a built-in
potential gradient, the anisotropy of the optically active perovskite
microplates, and the electrically controllable LC molecular director in our
system with intentionally broken rotational symmetry. Besides the fundamental
interest in the achieved electric polariton vortex control at room temperature,
our work paves the way to micron-sized emitters with electric control over the
emitted light&apos;s phase profile and quantized orbital angular momentum for
information processing and integration into photonic circuits.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Zhai_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xiaokun Zhai&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Ma_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xuekai Ma&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Gao_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ying Gao&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Xing_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Chunzi Xing&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Gao_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Meini Gao&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Dai_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Haitao Dai&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Wang_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xiao Wang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Pan_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Anlian Pan&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Schumacher_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Stefan Schumacher&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Gao_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Tingge Gao&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01734">
<title>Tunable Chiral Bound States in a Dimer Chain of Coupled Resonators. (arXiv:2211.01734v1 [physics.optics])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01734</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We study the chiral feature in a system composed of one two-level emitter
(TLE) and a one dimensional (1D) dimer chain of coupled resonators with the
alternate single-photon energies. In the single-excitation subspace, this
system not only possesses two energy bands with propagating states, but also
possesses chiral bound states. The number of chiral bound states depends on the
coupling forms between the TLE and the dimer chain. It is found that when the
TLE is locally coupled to one resonator of the dimer chain, the bound-state
that has mirror reflection symmetry is not a chiral one. When the TLE is
nonlocally coupled to two adjacent resonators, three chiral bound states arise
due to the mirror symmetry breaking. The chirality of these bound states can be
tuned by changing the energy differences of single photon in the adjacent
resonators, the coupling strengths and the transition energy of the TLE. The
chirality behaviour of the ordinary two bound states outside the energy bands
is quite different from the one of the emerging bound state inside the energy
gap. The almost perfect chiral bound states can be achieved at certain
parameters as a result of completely destructive interference.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Li_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jing Li&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Lu_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jing Lu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Gong_Z/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Z.R.Gong&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Zhou_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Lan Zhou&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01735">
<title>Electronic Coherent Control of an Insulator-to-Metal Mott Transition. (arXiv:2211.01735v1 [cond-mat.str-el])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01735</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Managing light-matter interaction on timescales faster than the loss of
electronic coherence is key for achieving the full quantum control of final
products in solid-solid transformations. In this work, we demonstrate coherent
electronic control of the photoinduced insulator-to-metal transition in the
prototypical Mott insulator V$_2$O$_3$. Selective excitation of a specific
interband transition with two phase-locked light pulses manipulates the orbital
occupation of the correlated bands in a way that depends on the coherent
evolution of the photoinduced superposition of states. Comparison between
experimental results and numerical solutions of the optical Bloch equations
provides an electronic coherence time on the order of 5 fs. Temperature
dependent experiments suggest that the electronic coherence time is enhanced in
the vicinity of the insulator-to-metal transition critical temperature, thus
highlighting the role of fluctuations in determining the electronic coherence.
These results open new routes to selectively switch functionalities of quantum
materials and coherently control solid-solid electronic transformations.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Franceschini_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Paolo Franceschini&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Policht_V/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Veronica R.Policht&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Milloch_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Alessandra Milloch&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Ronchi_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Andrea Ronchi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Mor_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Selene Mor&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Mellaerts_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Simon Mellaerts&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Hsu_W/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Wei-Fan Hsu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Pagliara_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Stefania Pagliara&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Ferrini_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Gabriele Ferrini&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Banfi_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Francesco Banfi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Fabrizio_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Michele Fabrizio&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Menghini_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Mariela Menghini&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Locquet_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jean-Pierre Locquet&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Conte_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Stefano Dal Conte&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Cerullo_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Giulio Cerullo&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Giannetti_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Claudio Giannetti&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01811">
<title>Photonic Elementary Cellular Automata for Simulation of Complex Phenomena. (arXiv:2211.01811v1 [cs.ET])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01811</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Cellular automata are a class of computational models based on simple rules
and algorithms that can simulate a wide range of complex phenomena. However,
when using conventional computers, these &apos;simple&apos; rules are only encapsulated
at the level of software. This can be taken one step further by simplifying the
underlying physical hardware. Here, we propose and implement a simple photonic
hardware platform for simulating complex phenomena based on cellular automata.
Using this special-purpose computer, we experimentally demonstrate complex
phenomena including fractals, chaos, and solitons, which are typically
associated with much more complex physical systems. The flexibility and
programmability of our photonic computer presents new opportunities to simulate
and harness complexity for efficient, robust, and decentralized information
processing schemes using light.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Li_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Gordon H. Y. Li&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Leefmans_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Christian R. Leefmans&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Williams_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;James Williams&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Marandi_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Alireza Marandi&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01823">
<title>Doubly resonant photonic crystal cavity using merged bound states in the continuum. (arXiv:2211.01823v1 [physics.optics])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01823</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;In this work, a doubly resonant photonic crystal (PhC) cavity using the
merged bound states in the continuum (BICs) is proposed to obtain a higher
second harmonic generation (SHG) efficiency. Firstly by scanning geometry
parameters the accidental BICs and a band-edge mode outside the light cone can
be obtained. Then as the lattice constant or the thickness of the slab is
adjusted the accidental BICs will merge. A supercell with large and small holes
is constructed and the band-edge mode outside the light cone can be
mode-matched with the merged BICs mode. Finally the heterostructure PhC cavity
is designed. The merged BICs show a high quality factor for the photonic
crystal with finite size. Consequently, the SHG efficiency of the lattice
constant near merged BICs of ~6000% W-1 is higher than the one of the isolated
BIC.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Ge_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Rui Ge&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Liu_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xiangmin Liu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Yan_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xiongshuo Yan&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Chen_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xianfeng Chen&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Chen_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yuping Chen&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01997">
<title>Extremely Narrow, Sharp-Peaked Resonances at the Edge of the Continuum. (arXiv:2211.01997v1 [physics.optics])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01997</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We report a critical narrowing of resonances of a driven potential well, when
their eigenfrequencies approach the edge of the continuum. The resonances also
obtain unusual sharp-peak shapes at the continuum boundary. The situation can
be realized for the electromagnetic wave propagating across the dielectric thin
films with a periodically modulated interface(s). We show the general
phenomenon semi-analytically on a simplified model of a driven quantum
potential well, also by rigorous numerical analysis of Maxwell equations for
the wave propagation across the thin film with a modulated interface(s). We
justify the phenomenon experimentally, by the measurements of light reflection
from the dielectric thin film deposited on a periodically modulated surface.
The narrow and sharp-peak resonances can be used for an efficient narrow-band
frequency- and spatial filtering of light.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Lukosiunas_I/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ignas Lukosiunas&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Grineviciute_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Lina Grineviciute&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Nikitina_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Julianija Nikitina&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Gailevicius_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Darius Gailevicius&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Staliunas_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Kestutis Staliunas&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2111.08760">
<title>Field Synthesis with Azimuthally-Varying, Cascaded, Cylindrical Metasurfaces using a Wave Matrix Approach. (arXiv:2111.08760v2 [physics.app-ph] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2111.08760</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;In recent years, there has been extensive research on planar metasurfaces
capable of arbitrarily controlling scattered fields. However, rigorous studies
on conformal metasurfaces, such as those that are cylindrical, have been few in
number likely due to their more complex geometry. Here, wave propagation in
cascaded cylindrical structures consisting of layers of dielectric spacers and
azimuthally-varying metasurfaces (subwavelength patterned metallic claddings)
is investigated. A wave matrix approach, which incorporates the advantages of
both ABCD matrices and scattering matrices (S matrices), is adopted. Wave
matrices are used to model the higher order coupling between metasurface
layers, overcoming fabrication difficulties associated with previous works. The
proposed framework provides an efficient approach to synthesize the
inhomogeneous sheet admittances that realize a desired cylindrical field
transformation. Design examples are reported to illustrate the power and
potential applications of the proposed method in antenna design and stealth
technology.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Lin_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Chun-Wen Lin&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Grbic_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Anthony Grbic&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2202.12615">
<title>Fall of a Particle to the Center of a Singular Potential: Classical vs. Quantum Exact Solutions. (arXiv:2202.12615v3 [quant-ph] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2202.12615</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Exact solutions describing a fall of a particle to the center of a singular
potential (collapse) in classical and quantum cases are obtained, inspected,
and compared. The quantum and classical solutions exhibit striking
similarities. In particular, at zero energy of the particle, both are
self-similar, and their characteristic spatial scales obey the same temporal
dependence. In addition to collapsing, exact expanding solutions, corresponding
to the escape of the particle from the singularity, exist for both problems.
The collapse and escape are independent and not linked to each other through
the singularity. In the quantum collapse, the wave functions of the exact
solutions have time-depended norms. This case requires reconsidering and
generalizing the continuity equations and rules for mean value calculations. It
has also been done. The analysis sheds new light on the fundamentals of quantum
mechanics.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Tribelsky_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Michael I. Tribelsky&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2205.14511">
<title>Multiphase nonlinear electron plasma waves. (arXiv:2205.14511v2 [physics.plasm-ph] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2205.14511</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We present a method for constructing multiphase excitations in the generally
non-integrable system of warm fluid equations describing plasma oscillations.
It is based on autoresonant excitation of nonlinear electron plasma waves by
phase locking with small amplitude chirped-frequency ponderomotive drives. We
demonstrate the excitation of these multiphase waves by performing fully
nonlinear numerical simulations of the fluid equations. We develop a simplified
model based on a weakly nonlinear analytical theory by applying Whitham&apos;s
averaged Lagrangian procedure. The simplified model predictions are in good
agreement with the results from the warm fluid simulations. Such autoresonantly
excited multiphase waves form coherent quasicrystalline structures, which can
potentially be used as plasma photonic or accelerating devices. Finally, we
discuss the laser parameters required for the autoresonant excitation of
nonlinear waves in a plasma.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Munirov_V/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Vadim R. Munirov&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Friedland_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Lazar Friedland&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Wurtele_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jonathan S. Wurtele&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2206.07103">
<title>Efficient and compact source of tuneable ultrafast deep ultraviolet laser pulses at 50 kHz repetition rate. (arXiv:2206.07103v2 [physics.optics] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2206.07103</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Deep ultraviolet (DUV) laser pulses with tuneable wavelength and very short
duration are a key enabling technology for next-generation technology and
ultrafast science. Their generation has been the subject of extensive
experimental effort, but no technique demonstrated thus far has been able to
meet all requirements in one light source. Here we demonstrate a bright,
efficient, and compact source of tuneable deep ultraviolet ultrafast laser
pulses based on resonant dispersive wave emission in hollow capillary fibre. In
a total footprint of only 120 $\times$ 75 cm, including the Yb-based drive
laser, we generate pulses between 208 and 363 nm at 50 kHz repetition rate with
a total efficiency of up to 3.6%. Down-scaling of the DUV generation reduces
the required energy sufficiently to enable the generation of two-colour
few-femtosecond DUV pulses.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Brahms_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Christian Brahms&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Travers_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;John C. Travers&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2206.10410">
<title>Soliton Pulses in Photonic Crystal Fabry-Perot Microresonators. (arXiv:2206.10410v3 [physics.optics] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2206.10410</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Dissipative Kerr solitons (DKSs) in high-Q microresonators enable
applications in sensing, communication, and signal processing. Until now, DKSs
driven by continuous-wave (CW) lasers are exclusively generated in ring-type
resonators. Complementary to ring-type resonators, Fabry-Perot resonators could
enable new approaches to dispersion engineering, addressing a key challenge of
DKS technology. However, DKS generation in a CW-driven Fabry-Perot
microresonator has not yet been achieved. Here, we demonstrate for the first
time CW-driven DKSs in a high-Q Fabry-Perot microresonator. Fabricated in a
wafer-level process, two photonic crystal reflectors in a waveguide form the
chip-integrated resonator and define its dispersion. The intrinsic Q-factor of
4 million is propagation-loss limited. In principle, each cell of the photonic
crystal reflector can be tailored, opening a design space beyond traditional
dispersion engineering, with potential for future extension of DKSs to visible
and other currently inaccessible wavelengths. Beyond DKSs, this creates
opportunities for filter-driven pulse formation, engineered spectra and
broadband phase-matching in microresonators.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Wildi_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Thibault Wildi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Gaafar_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Mahmoud A. Gaafar&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Voumard_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Thibault Voumard&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Ludwig_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Markus Ludwig&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Herr_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Tobias Herr&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2208.00899">
<title>Parametric Waveform Synthesis: a scalable approach to generate sub-cycle optical transients. (arXiv:2208.00899v2 [physics.optics] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2208.00899</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The availability of electromagnetic pulses with controllable field waveform
and extremely short duration, even below a single optical cycle, is imperative
to fully harness strong-field processes and to gain insight into ultrafast
light-driven mechanisms occurring in the attosecond time-domain. The recently
demonstrated parametric waveform synthesis (PWS) introduces an energy-, power-
and spectrum-scalable method to generate non-sinusoidal sub-cycle optical
waveforms by coherently combining different phase-stable pulses attained via
optical parametric amplifiers. Significant technological developments have been
addressed to overcome the stability issues related to PWS and to obtain an
effective and reliable waveform control system. Here we present the main
ingredients enabling PWS technology. The design choices concerning the optical,
mechanical and electronic setups are justified by analytical/numerical modeling
and benchmarked by experimental observations. In its present incarnation, the
PWS technology enables the generation of field-controllable mJ-level
few-femtosecond pulses spanning the visible to infrared range.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Mainz_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Roland E. Mainz&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Rossi_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Giulio Maria Rossi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Scheiba_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Fabian Scheiba&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Silva_Toledo_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Miguel A. Silva-Toledo&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Cirmi_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Giovanni Cirmi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Kartner_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Franz X. K&amp;#xe4;rtner&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2208.07454">
<title>High frequency torsional motion transduction using optomechanical coupled oscillators. (arXiv:2208.07454v2 [physics.optics] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2208.07454</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Using light to measure an object&apos;s motion is central to operating mechanical
sensors that probe forces and fields. Cavity optomechanical systems embed
mechanical resonators inside optical resonators. This enhances the sensitivity
of optomechanical measurements, but only if the mechanical resonator does not
spoil the properties of the optical cavity. For example, cavity optomechanical
detection of resonators made from optically absorbing materials, or whose
geometry does not possess suitable spatial symmetry, is challenging. Here we
demonstrate a system that overcomes challenges in measuring high-frequency
twisting motion of a nanodisk by converting them to vibrations of a photonic
crystal cavity. Optomechanical readout of the cavity then enables measurement
of the nanodisk&apos;s torsional resonances with sensitivity $5.1\times
10^{-21}-1.2\times 10^{-19}\,\text{Nm}/\sqrt{\text{Hz}}$ for a mechanical
frequency range of 5--800 MHz. The nanodisk can be outfitted with magnetic
nanostructures or metasurfaces without affecting the optical properties of the
cavity, making the system suitable for torque magnetometry and structured light
sensing.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Kaviani_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Hamidreza Kaviani&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Behera_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Bishnupada Behera&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Hajisalem_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ghazal Hajisalem&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Luiz_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Gustavo de Oliveira Luiz&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Lake_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;David P. Lake&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Barclay_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Paul E. Barclay&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.08504">
<title>An electronic-based model of the optical nonlinearity of low-density Drude materials. (arXiv:2210.08504v2 [physics.optics] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.08504</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Low electron density Drude (LEDD) materials such as indium tin oxide (ITO)
are receiving considerable attention because of their combination of CMOS
compatibility, unique epsilon-near-zero (ENZ) behavior, and giant ultrafast
nonlinear thermo-optic response. However, the understanding of the electronic
and optical response of LEDD materials is so far based on simplistic extensions
of known models of noble metals, frequently without the inclusion of the
interplay among the lower electron density, relatively high Debye energy, and
the non-parabolic band structure. To bridge this knowledge gap, this work
provides a complete understanding of the nonlinear electronic-thermal-optical
response of LEDD materials. In particular, we rely on state-of-the-art electron
dynamics modeling, as well as the newly derived time-dependent permittivity
model for LEDD materials under optical pumping within the adiabatic
approximation. We find that unlike noble metals, the electron temperatures can
reach the Fermi temperature, in which case the effective chemical potential
dramatically decreases and even becomes negative, thus, transiently converting
the Drude metal into a semiconductor. We further show that the nonlinear
optical response of LEDD materials originating from the changes to the real
part of the permittivity is due to the generation of non-thermal electrons.
This resolves the argument about the rise time of the permittivity and shows
that it is instantaneous. In this vein, we show that referring to the LEDD
permittivity as having a ``saturable&apos;&apos; nonlinearity is unsuitable since its
permittivity dynamics does not originate from population inversion. Finally, we
analyze the probe pulse dynamics and unlike previous work, we obtain a
quantitative agreement with the results of recent experiments.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Un_I/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ieng Wai Un&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Sarkar_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Subhajit Sarkar&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Sivan_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yonatan Sivan&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.13844">
<title>Topological Robust Corner States of a Two-Dimensional Square Lattice with $\mathbf C_{\mathbf 4}$ Symmetry in Fully Coupled Dipolar Arrays. (arXiv:2210.13844v2 [physics.optics] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.13844</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Higher-order topological insulators(HOTIs) is an exciting topic. We
constructed a square lattice dipole arrays, it supports out-of-plane and
in-plane modes by going beyond conventional scalar coupling. In-plane modes
naturally break $\mathrm C_{4}$ symmetry, we only studied the out-of-plane
modes that maintain $\mathrm C_{4}$ symmetry. Due to the slowly decaying
long-range coupling, we consider its fully coupled interactions by using the
lattice sums technique and combined with the coupled dipole method (CDM) to
study its topological properties in detail. Interestingly, even when the full
coupling is considered, the topological properties of the system remain similar
to those of the 2D Su-Schrieffer-Heeger(SSH) model, but very differently, it
supports robust zero-energy corner states (ZECSs) with $\mathrm C_{4}$
symmetry, we calculate the bulk polarization and discuss in detail the
topological origin of the ZECSs. The lattice sums technique in the article can
be applied to arbitrary fully coupled 2D dipole arrays. The materials we used
can be able to confine light into the deep subwavelength scale, it has a great
potential in enhancing light-matter interactions in the terahertz (THz) range.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Luo_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Chen Luo&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Zhou_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xiang Zhou&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Li_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Hui-Chang Li&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Zhang_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Tai-Lin Zhang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Shen_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yun Shen&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Deng_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xiao-Hua Deng&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01075">
<title>Electromagnetic wave propagation in a nonlinear hyperbolic medium. (arXiv:2211.01075v2 [nlin.PS] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01075</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The propagation of a quasi-harmonic electromagnetic wave in a bulk hyperbolic
dielectric metamaterial is considered. If the group velocities dispersion is
not taken into account, then wave propagation can be described either by the
hyperbolic nonlinear Schrodinger equation or by the hyperbolic Manakov
equations. It is shown that the region in the space of wave vectors in which
the modulation instability of a spatially homogeneous wave is possible is not
limited, in contrast to the case of ordinary media.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/nlin/1/au:+Maimistov_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;A.I. Maimistov&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
</rdf:RDF>