<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:cc="http://web.resource.org/cc/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:googleplay="http://www.google.com/schemas/play-podcasts/1.0" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:podcast="https://podcastindex.org/namespace/1.0" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" version="2.0">
	<channel>
		<atom:link href="https://thejimmydoreshow.libsyn.com/rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
		<title>The Jimmy Dore Show</title>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2022 05:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2022 05:38:29 +0000</lastBuildDate>
		<generator>Libsyn WebEngine 2.0</generator>
		<link>http://www.jimmydorecomedy.com/show/jimmy-dore-show</link>
		<language>en</language>
		<copyright><![CDATA[Jimmy Dore]]></copyright>
		<docs>http://www.jimmydorecomedy.com/show/jimmy-dore-show</docs>
		<managingEditor>malcolm@jimmydorecomedy.com (malcolm@jimmydorecomedy.com)</managingEditor>
		<itunes:summary>Hosted by award winning comedian Jimmy Dore, This is an irreverent and humorous take on todays headlines and hypocrites. This program skewers politicians as well as the corporate mouthpieces which are todays main stream "news media". Interviews with todays top comedians and comedy writers, and gets their take on all things newsy. It is a show that provides the unvarnished truth with a twist of funny.&#13;
</itunes:summary>
		<image>
			<url>https://ssl-static.libsyn.com/p/assets/a/7/5/6/a756a3fe5cfb3d10/JDPodLogo.jpg</url>
			<title>The Jimmy Dore Show</title>
			<link><![CDATA[http://www.jimmydorecomedy.com/show/jimmy-dore-show]]></link>
		</image>
		<itunes:author>Jimmy Dore</itunes:author>
		<itunes:keywords>Politics,debate,dore,humor,jimmy,sketches</itunes:keywords>
		
		
		<itunes:image href="http://29.media.tumblr.com/tumblr_l7sinil0nY1qz5n8po1_400.jpg "/>
		<itunes:explicit>yes</itunes:explicit>
		
		<description><![CDATA[“ Jimmy Dore is outrageous and outraged, bothersome and bothered, a crucial, profane, passionate voice for progressives and freethinkers in 21st century America.” -Patton Oswalt]]></description>
		<itunes:subtitle>Hosted by award winning comedian Jimmy Dore, This is an irreverent and humorous take on todays headlines and hypocrites. This program skewers politicians as well as the corporate mouthpieces which are todays main stream "news media". Interviews with today</itunes:subtitle>
		<itunes:type>episodic</itunes:type>
		


		<podcast:locked owner="malcolm@jimmydorecomedy.com">no</podcast:locked>
		
		<itunes:category text="News &amp; Politics"/><itunes:owner><itunes:email>malcolm@jimmydorecomedy.com</itunes:email></itunes:owner><item>
			<title>COVID Smear Artists Want “Amnesty” For Their Lies</title>
			<itunes:title>COVID Smear Artists Want “Amnesty” For Their Lies</itunes:title>
			<pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2022 05:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false"><![CDATA[25dd9642-4e42-4bf6-9c92-9298458157d7]]></guid>
			<link><![CDATA[https://thejimmydoreshow.libsyn.com/covid-smear-artists-want-amnesty-for-their-lies]]></link>
			<itunes:image href="https://ssl-static.libsyn.com/p/assets/e/c/b/5/ecb59d549db2725fe55e3c100dce7605/Screen_Shot_2022-11-03_at_8.07.11_PM.png"/>
			<description><![CDATA[<p>Writing in The Atlantic, economist Emily Oster announced that it’s time for the COVID wars to end, and for aggrieved parties who may or may not have been “right” in challenging the dominant narrative about vaccines, masks, transmission and related topics to give their antagonists a pass so that we can all move on together. But is that how it works – thousands lose their jobs, while countless more are demonized on a grand scale and everyone’s supposed to just take a mulligan?</p> <p>Jimmy and Americans’ Comedian Kurt Metzger discuss the importance of expressions of contrition if there is to be any “amnesty” for the likes of Noam Chomsky, Piers Morgan and Jimmy Kimmel who did everything they could to smear COVID narrative skeptics.<br /> <br /> Plus a segment on President Obama getting heckled at a campaign rally over Democrats' support for the march to nuclear war over Ukraine.</p> <p>Also featuring Stef Zamorano, Kurt Metzger and Mike MacRae! And phone calls from Alec Baldwin and Benjamin Netanyahu!</p>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Writing in The Atlantic, economist Emily Oster announced that it’s time for the COVID wars to end, and for aggrieved parties who may or may not have been “right” in challenging the dominant narrative about vaccines, masks, transmission and related topics to give their antagonists a pass so that we can all move on together. But is that how it works – thousands lose their jobs, while countless more are demonized on a grand scale and everyone’s supposed to just take a mulligan?</p> <p>Jimmy and Americans’ Comedian Kurt Metzger discuss the importance of expressions of contrition if there is to be any “amnesty” for the likes of Noam Chomsky, Piers Morgan and Jimmy Kimmel who did everything they could to smear COVID narrative skeptics.  Plus a segment on President Obama getting heckled at a campaign rally over Democrats' support for the march to nuclear war over Ukraine.</p> <p>Also featuring Stef Zamorano, Kurt Metzger and Mike MacRae! And phone calls from Alec Baldwin and Benjamin Netanyahu!</p>]]></content:encoded>
			<enclosure length="59799432" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/thejimmydoreshow/TJDS_20221104_Podcast_-_11322_7.33_PM.mp3?dest-id=19460"/>
			<itunes:duration>01:01:54</itunes:duration>
			<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
			<itunes:keywords/>
			<itunes:subtitle><![CDATA[Writing in The Atlantic, economist Emily Oster announced that it’s time for the COVID wars to end, and for aggrieved parties who may or may not have been “right” in challenging the dominant narrative about vaccines, masks, transmission and...]]></itunes:subtitle>
			<itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
		<itunes:summary>Writing in The Atlantic, economist Emily Oster announced that it’s time for the COVID wars to end, and for aggrieved parties who may or may not have been “right” in challenging the dominant narrative about vaccines, masks, transmission and related topics to give their antagonists a pass so that we can all move on together. But is that how it works – thousands lose their jobs, while countless more are demonized on a grand scale and everyone’s supposed to just take a mulligan? Jimmy and Americans’ Comedian Kurt Metzger discuss the importance of expressions of contrition if there is to be any “amnesty” for the likes of Noam Chomsky, Piers Morgan and Jimmy Kimmel who did everything they could to smear COVID narrative skeptics. Plus a segment on President Obama getting heckled at a campaign rally over Democrats' support for the march to nuclear war over Ukraine. Also featuring Stef Zamorano, Kurt Metzger and Mike MacRae! And phone calls from Alec Baldwin and Benjamin Netanyahu!</itunes:summary></item>
		<item>
			<title>Fired Anti-Mandate Professor Now VINDICATED!</title>
			<itunes:title>Fired Anti-Mandate Professor Now VINDICATED!</itunes:title>
			<pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2022 05:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false"><![CDATA[bb0ba6ab-a5cd-438c-871d-80379039cb7d]]></guid>
			<link><![CDATA[https://thejimmydoreshow.libsyn.com/fired-anti-mandate-professor-now-vindicated]]></link>
			<itunes:image href="https://ssl-static.libsyn.com/p/assets/5/6/5/6/5656296ca9bc33a4d959afa2a1bf1c87/Screen_Shot_2022-10-27_at_9.36.21_AM.png"/>
			<description><![CDATA[<p>University of California-Irvine professor and physician Dr. Aaron Kheriaty (http://aaronkheriaty.substack.com) was fired earlier this year after refusing to get the COVID vaccine since he’d already had COVID and developed natural immunity. Since then he’s become an outspoken advocate against vaccine mandates and the torrent of disinformation and misinformation spread by very powerful interests pushing vaccines and mandates while downplaying natural immunity and possible preventive measures.</p> <p>Jimmy speaks with Dr. Kheriaty about his experience opposing COVID protocols and the lawsuit underway that will force government officials like Anthony Fauci to defend the strictures imposed on the public during the pandemic.<br /> <br /> <span style= "font-family: -apple-system, BlinkMacSystemFont, 'Segoe UI', Roboto, Oxygen, Ubuntu, Cantarell, 'Open Sans', 'Helvetica Neue', sans-serif;"> Plus a segment on an international democracy forum silencing Dr. Jeffrey Sachs for sharing the truth about U.S. imperialism and violence across the globe since 1950.</span></p> <p>Also featuring Stef Zamorano, Aaron Maté and Mike MacRae! And phone calls from Joe Biden and Vince Vaughn!</p>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>University of California-Irvine professor and physician Dr. Aaron Kheriaty (http://aaronkheriaty.substack.com) was fired earlier this year after refusing to get the COVID vaccine since he’d already had COVID and developed natural immunity. Since then he’s become an outspoken advocate against vaccine mandates and the torrent of disinformation and misinformation spread by very powerful interests pushing vaccines and mandates while downplaying natural immunity and possible preventive measures.</p> <p>Jimmy speaks with Dr. Kheriaty about his experience opposing COVID protocols and the lawsuit underway that will force government officials like Anthony Fauci to defend the strictures imposed on the public during the pandemic.   Plus a segment on an international democracy forum silencing Dr. Jeffrey Sachs for sharing the truth about U.S. imperialism and violence across the globe since 1950.</p> <p>Also featuring Stef Zamorano, Aaron Maté and Mike MacRae! And phone calls from Joe Biden and Vince Vaughn!</p>]]></content:encoded>
			<enclosure length="62180462" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/thejimmydoreshow/TJDS_20221028_Podcast_-_102722_9.27_AM.mp3?dest-id=19460"/>
			<itunes:duration>01:04:32</itunes:duration>
			<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
			<itunes:keywords/>
			<itunes:subtitle><![CDATA[University of California-Irvine professor and physician Dr. Aaron Kheriaty (http://aaronkheriaty.substack.com) was fired earlier this year after refusing to get the COVID vaccine since he’d already had COVID and developed natural immunity. Since...]]></itunes:subtitle>
			<itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
		<itunes:summary>University of California-Irvine professor and physician Dr. Aaron Kheriaty (http://aaronkheriaty.substack.com) was fired earlier this year after refusing to get the COVID vaccine since he’d already had COVID and developed natural immunity. Since then he’s become an outspoken advocate against vaccine mandates and the torrent of disinformation and misinformation spread by very powerful interests pushing vaccines and mandates while downplaying natural immunity and possible preventive measures. Jimmy speaks with Dr. Kheriaty about his experience opposing COVID protocols and the lawsuit underway that will force government officials like Anthony Fauci to defend the strictures imposed on the public during the pandemic. Plus a segment on an international democracy forum silencing Dr. Jeffrey Sachs for sharing the truth about U.S. imperialism and violence across the globe since 1950. Also featuring Stef Zamorano, Aaron Maté and Mike MacRae! And phone calls from Joe Biden and Vince Vaughn!</itunes:summary></item>
		<item>
			<title>AOC HUMILIATED Over Funding Nuclear War</title>
			<itunes:title>AOC HUMILIATED Over Funding Nuclear War</itunes:title>
			<pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2022 05:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false"><![CDATA[c560f84e-59ec-4983-9cfa-bad596cdcfec]]></guid>
			<link><![CDATA[https://thejimmydoreshow.libsyn.com/aoc-humiliated-over-funding-nuclear-war]]></link>
			<itunes:image href="https://ssl-static.libsyn.com/p/assets/1/8/1/2/1812268cb4776e01e55e3c100dce7605/Screen_Shot_2022-10-20_at_3.01.19_PM.png"/>
			<description><![CDATA[<p>During a recent sparsely attended town hall event, Congresswoman Alexandria Ocasio-Cortez was confronted by anti-war activists who demanded that AOC stop supporting the war in Ukraine that is rapidly leading the US and Russia to the brink of nuclear war. Instead of engaging with her critics, Congresswoman Ocasio-Cortez called the activists “rude,” insisted they wait their turn in line and later upbraided them for shouting over a deaf constituent who she alleged had been trying to speak.</p> <p>Jimmy and America’s Comedian Kurt Metzger discuss AOC’s rank hypocrisy and how she used to emphasize the importance of activists holding the powerful to account even if it means making them uncomfortable.<br /> <br /> Plus a segment on a Pfizer executive's admission to the European Parliament that the company's COVID vaccine was not tested for transmissibility before gaining approval for distribution.<br /> <br /> Also featuring Stef Zamorano, Kurt Metzger and Mike MacRae! And phone calls from Harrison Ford and the duo of Barack Obama and James Carville!</p>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>During a recent sparsely attended town hall event, Congresswoman Alexandria Ocasio-Cortez was confronted by anti-war activists who demanded that AOC stop supporting the war in Ukraine that is rapidly leading the US and Russia to the brink of nuclear war. Instead of engaging with her critics, Congresswoman Ocasio-Cortez called the activists “rude,” insisted they wait their turn in line and later upbraided them for shouting over a deaf constituent who she alleged had been trying to speak.</p> <p>Jimmy and America’s Comedian Kurt Metzger discuss AOC’s rank hypocrisy and how she used to emphasize the importance of activists holding the powerful to account even if it means making them uncomfortable.  Plus a segment on a Pfizer executive's admission to the European Parliament that the company's COVID vaccine was not tested for transmissibility before gaining approval for distribution.  Also featuring Stef Zamorano, Kurt Metzger and Mike MacRae! And phone calls from Harrison Ford and the duo of Barack Obama and James Carville!</p>]]></content:encoded>
			<enclosure length="61227139" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/thejimmydoreshow/TJDS_20221021_Podcast_-_102022_2.13_PM.mp3?dest-id=19460"/>
			<itunes:duration>01:03:32</itunes:duration>
			<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
			<itunes:keywords/>
			<itunes:subtitle><![CDATA[During a recent sparsely attended town hall event, Congresswoman Alexandria Ocasio-Cortez was confronted by anti-war activists who demanded that AOC stop supporting the war in Ukraine that is rapidly leading the US and Russia to the brink of nuclear...]]></itunes:subtitle>
			<itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
		<itunes:summary>During a recent sparsely attended town hall event, Congresswoman Alexandria Ocasio-Cortez was confronted by anti-war activists who demanded that AOC stop supporting the war in Ukraine that is rapidly leading the US and Russia to the brink of nuclear war. Instead of engaging with her critics, Congresswoman Ocasio-Cortez called the activists “rude,” insisted they wait their turn in line and later upbraided them for shouting over a deaf constituent who she alleged had been trying to speak. Jimmy and America’s Comedian Kurt Metzger discuss AOC’s rank hypocrisy and how she used to emphasize the importance of activists holding the powerful to account even if it means making them uncomfortable. Plus a segment on a Pfizer executive's admission to the European Parliament that the company's COVID vaccine was not tested for transmissibility before gaining approval for distribution. Also featuring Stef Zamorano, Kurt Metzger and Mike MacRae! And phone calls from Harrison Ford and the duo of Barack Obama and James Carville!</itunes:summary></item>
		<item>
			<title>Rogan DISMANTLES Rolling Stone Founder On Censorship</title>
			<itunes:title>Rogan DISMANTLES Rolling Stone Founder On Censorship</itunes:title>
			<pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 17:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false"><![CDATA[3845e96b-7e43-4794-be31-f223bc447332]]></guid>
			<link><![CDATA[https://thejimmydoreshow.libsyn.com/rogan-dismantles-rolling-stone-founder-on-censorship]]></link>
			<itunes:image href="https://ssl-static.libsyn.com/p/assets/7/1/6/8/716837025864847abafc7308ab683e82/Screen_Shot_2022-10-14_at_9.52.26_AM.png"/>
			<description><![CDATA[<p>During a recent episode of the Joe Rogan Experience podcast, the titular host welcomed Rolling Stone Magazine founder Jann Wenner, and the conversation quickly turned to online censorship. Wenner expressed support for the tech industry and government regulating speech since government does so well regulating the food supply and the pharmaceutical industry. At which point Rogan stepped in and set Wenner straight in a gentle but nevertheless devastating way.</p> <p>Jimmy and America’s Comedian Kurt Metzger wonder at the founder of an iconically countercultural publication like Rolling Stone turning into such a neoliberal shill for the establishment.<br /> <br /> Plus segments on the escalating war in Ukraine, a former Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff calling for NATO to negotiate a settlement to the Ukraine War, Joe Biden lying about codifying Roe v Wade into law and a Wired Magazine article with the dumbest work-related advice ever.<br /> <br /> Also featuring Stef Zamorano!</p>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>During a recent episode of the Joe Rogan Experience podcast, the titular host welcomed Rolling Stone Magazine founder Jann Wenner, and the conversation quickly turned to online censorship. Wenner expressed support for the tech industry and government regulating speech since government does so well regulating the food supply and the pharmaceutical industry. At which point Rogan stepped in and set Wenner straight in a gentle but nevertheless devastating way.</p> <p>Jimmy and America’s Comedian Kurt Metzger wonder at the founder of an iconically countercultural publication like Rolling Stone turning into such a neoliberal shill for the establishment.  Plus segments on the escalating war in Ukraine, a former Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff calling for NATO to negotiate a settlement to the Ukraine War, Joe Biden lying about codifying Roe v Wade into law and a Wired Magazine article with the dumbest work-related advice ever.  Also featuring Stef Zamorano!</p>]]></content:encoded>
			<enclosure length="63454004" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/thejimmydoreshow/TJDS_20221014_Podcast_-_101422_9.38_AM.mp3?dest-id=19460"/>
			<itunes:duration>01:05:43</itunes:duration>
			<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
			<itunes:keywords/>
			<itunes:subtitle><![CDATA[During a recent episode of the Joe Rogan Experience podcast, the titular host welcomed Rolling Stone Magazine founder Jann Wenner, and the conversation quickly turned to online censorship. Wenner expressed support for the tech industry and government...]]></itunes:subtitle>
			<itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
		<itunes:summary>During a recent episode of the Joe Rogan Experience podcast, the titular host welcomed Rolling Stone Magazine founder Jann Wenner, and the conversation quickly turned to online censorship. Wenner expressed support for the tech industry and government regulating speech since government does so well regulating the food supply and the pharmaceutical industry. At which point Rogan stepped in and set Wenner straight in a gentle but nevertheless devastating way. Jimmy and America’s Comedian Kurt Metzger wonder at the founder of an iconically countercultural publication like Rolling Stone turning into such a neoliberal shill for the establishment. Plus segments on the escalating war in Ukraine, a former Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff calling for NATO to negotiate a settlement to the Ukraine War, Joe Biden lying about codifying Roe v Wade into law and a Wired Magazine article with the dumbest work-related advice ever. Also featuring Stef Zamorano!</itunes:summary></item>
		<item>
			<title>Your Democracy Was Stolen Long Before January 6</title>
			<itunes:title>Your Democracy Was Stolen Long Before January 6</itunes:title>
			<pubDate>Fri, 07 Oct 2022 05:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false"><![CDATA[93c4517f-1fb1-4751-bab5-5cf56decf0c3]]></guid>
			<link><![CDATA[https://thejimmydoreshow.libsyn.com/your-democracy-was-stolen-long-before-january-6]]></link>
			<itunes:image href="https://ssl-static.libsyn.com/p/assets/2/a/4/b/2a4b127f435b4cbf88c4a68c3ddbc4f2/Screen_Shot_2022-10-06_at_5.47.40_PM.png"/>
			<description><![CDATA[<p>Chris Hedges is among the most incisive, trenchant analysts of the social, economic and political factors influencing the world for the past 30 years. And he’s here to tell you that the January 6th riots were not the great threat to American democracy they’re cracked up to be. American democracy has been steadily eroding since the Reagan administration, Hedges says, and if you think Donald Trump’s arrival on the political scene is what killed democracy you have not been paying attention.<br /> <br /> Jimmy and his panel of Hedges and America’s comedian Kurt Metzger discuss the myriad ways Wall Street, Big Pharma, weapons manufacturers, Big Ag and other powerful sectors snatched away the reins of power from the American people decades ago.<br /> <br /> Plus a segment on news that the Nord Stream 2 was not, in fact, permanenly disabled by the recent sabotage attempt, and may be operational again very soon.<br /> <br /> Also featuring Stef Zamorano, Aaron Maté and Mike MacRae! And phone calls from Alec Baldwin and Joe Biden!</p>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Chris Hedges is among the most incisive, trenchant analysts of the social, economic and political factors influencing the world for the past 30 years. And he’s here to tell you that the January 6th riots were not the great threat to American democracy they’re cracked up to be. American democracy has been steadily eroding since the Reagan administration, Hedges says, and if you think Donald Trump’s arrival on the political scene is what killed democracy you have not been paying attention.  Jimmy and his panel of Hedges and America’s comedian Kurt Metzger discuss the myriad ways Wall Street, Big Pharma, weapons manufacturers, Big Ag and other powerful sectors snatched away the reins of power from the American people decades ago.  Plus a segment on news that the Nord Stream 2 was not, in fact, permanenly disabled by the recent sabotage attempt, and may be operational again very soon.  Also featuring Stef Zamorano, Aaron Maté and Mike MacRae! And phone calls from Alec Baldwin and Joe Biden!</p>]]></content:encoded>
			<enclosure length="54147140" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/thejimmydoreshow/TJDS_20221007_Podcast_-_10622_3.29_PM.mp3?dest-id=19460"/>
			<itunes:duration>56:12</itunes:duration>
			<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
			<itunes:keywords/>
			<itunes:subtitle><![CDATA[Chris Hedges is among the most incisive, trenchant analysts of the social, economic and political factors influencing the world for the past 30 years. And he’s here to tell you that the January 6th riots were not the great threat to American...]]></itunes:subtitle>
			<itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
		<itunes:summary>Chris Hedges is among the most incisive, trenchant analysts of the social, economic and political factors influencing the world for the past 30 years. And he’s here to tell you that the January 6th riots were not the great threat to American democracy they’re cracked up to be. American democracy has been steadily eroding since the Reagan administration, Hedges says, and if you think Donald Trump’s arrival on the political scene is what killed democracy you have not been paying attention. Jimmy and his panel of Hedges and America’s comedian Kurt Metzger discuss the myriad ways Wall Street, Big Pharma, weapons manufacturers, Big Ag and other powerful sectors snatched away the reins of power from the American people decades ago. Plus a segment on news that the Nord Stream 2 was not, in fact, permanenly disabled by the recent sabotage attempt, and may be operational again very soon. Also featuring Stef Zamorano, Aaron Maté and Mike MacRae! And phone calls from Alec Baldwin and Joe Biden!</itunes:summary></item>
		<item>
			<title>No, Russia Didn’t Blow Up Their Own Pipeline</title>
			<itunes:title>No, Russia Didn’t Blow Up Their Own Pipeline</itunes:title>
			<pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2022 05:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false"><![CDATA[baff0ecb-5c34-4ddb-9e4e-fc458c42bef8]]></guid>
			<link><![CDATA[https://thejimmydoreshow.libsyn.com/no-russia-didnt-blow-up-their-own-pipeline]]></link>
			<itunes:image href="https://ssl-static.libsyn.com/p/assets/e/9/4/b/e94b3db8aed38a97d959afa2a1bf1c87/Screen_Shot_2022-09-29_at_1.28.51_PM.png"/>
			<description><![CDATA[<p>On Tuesday it was revealed that the Nord Stream 1 & 2 pipelines that carry liquefied natural gas under Northern Europe’s Baltic Sea had been sabotaged, rendering them inoperable, possibly permanently. And almost as quickly the finger-pointing began, with many in the West alleging that Russia had intentionally damaged its own pipeline while others claimed that a more logical explanation would pin the blame on the U.S., likely acting to eliminate any possibility that European countries will revert to relying on Russia as a source of gas.<br /> <br /> Jimmy and his panel of The Dive’s Jackson Hinkle and America’s comedian Kurt Metzger discuss the competing theories and possible motives behind the Nordstream attacks.<br /> <br /> Plus segments on how the mainstream media silences internal voices attempting to tell the truth about war and Bill Gates' ongoing effort to blame the pandemic's devastating impact on regular people instead of the oligarchs and their minions in the government who actually make all the decisions.<br /> <br /> Also featuring Stef Zamorano, Kit Cabello and Mike MacRae! And phone calls from Joe Biden and Vince Vaughn!</p>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>On Tuesday it was revealed that the Nord Stream 1 & 2 pipelines that carry liquefied natural gas under Northern Europe’s Baltic Sea had been sabotaged, rendering them inoperable, possibly permanently. And almost as quickly the finger-pointing began, with many in the West alleging that Russia had intentionally damaged its own pipeline while others claimed that a more logical explanation would pin the blame on the U.S., likely acting to eliminate any possibility that European countries will revert to relying on Russia as a source of gas.  Jimmy and his panel of The Dive’s Jackson Hinkle and America’s comedian Kurt Metzger discuss the competing theories and possible motives behind the Nordstream attacks.  Plus segments on how the mainstream media silences internal voices attempting to tell the truth about war and Bill Gates' ongoing effort to blame the pandemic's devastating impact on regular people instead of the oligarchs and their minions in the government who actually make all the decisions.  Also featuring Stef Zamorano, Kit Cabello and Mike MacRae! And phone calls from Joe Biden and Vince Vaughn!</p>]]></content:encoded>
			<enclosure length="57481242" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/thejimmydoreshow/TJDS_20220930_Podcast_-_92922_12.28_PM.mp3?dest-id=19460"/>
			<itunes:duration>59:35</itunes:duration>
			<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
			<itunes:keywords/>
			<itunes:subtitle><![CDATA[On Tuesday it was revealed that the Nord Stream 1 & 2 pipelines that carry liquefied natural gas under Northern Europe’s Baltic Sea had been sabotaged, rendering them inoperable, possibly permanently. And almost as quickly the finger-pointing began,...]]></itunes:subtitle>
			<itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
		<itunes:summary>On Tuesday it was revealed that the Nord Stream 1 &amp; 2 pipelines that carry liquefied natural gas under Northern Europe’s Baltic Sea had been sabotaged, rendering them inoperable, possibly permanently. And almost as quickly the finger-pointing began, with many in the West alleging that Russia had intentionally damaged its own pipeline while others claimed that a more logical explanation would pin the blame on the U.S., likely acting to eliminate any possibility that European countries will revert to relying on Russia as a source of gas. Jimmy and his panel of The Dive’s Jackson Hinkle and America’s comedian Kurt Metzger discuss the competing theories and possible motives behind the Nordstream attacks. Plus segments on how the mainstream media silences internal voices attempting to tell the truth about war and Bill Gates' ongoing effort to blame the pandemic's devastating impact on regular people instead of the oligarchs and their minions in the government who actually make all the decisions. Also featuring Stef Zamorano, Kit Cabello and Mike MacRae! And phone calls from Joe Biden and Vince Vaughn!</itunes:summary></item>
		<item>
			<title>“Pandemic Is Over!” Declares President Biden</title>
			<itunes:title>“Pandemic Is Over!” Declares President Biden</itunes:title>
			<pubDate>Fri, 23 Sep 2022 16:15:41 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false"><![CDATA[c9d658b9-c091-4d2c-ba4d-4cdcf4787594]]></guid>
			<link><![CDATA[https://thejimmydoreshow.libsyn.com/pandemic-is-over-declares-president-biden]]></link>
			<itunes:image href="https://ssl-static.libsyn.com/p/assets/c/0/5/0/c0504c8d852cb675bafc7308ab683e82/Screen_Shot_2022-09-22_at_8.36.46_PM.png"/>
			<description><![CDATA[<p>At the Detroit Auto Show for an appearance on 60 Minutes, President Joe Biden declared that the pandemic is over. Not surprisingly, handlers immediately started walking back the President’s comments, but the impromptu announcement nevertheless caused a great deal of controversy and heated reactions, both from COVID skeptics and COVID alarmists.</p> <p>Jimmy and his panel of The Dive’s Jackson Hinkle and Convo Couch’s Craig “Pasta” Jardula discuss whether the pandemic really is “over” and what that even means.<br /> <br /> Plus segments on the arrival of 50 Venezuelan migrants to Martha's Vineyard and the media freakout over Ben Shapiro allegedly grooming a new generation of incels online.<br /> <br /> Also featuring Stef Zamorano and Mike MacRae! And phone calls from  Jeff Bridges and Joe Biden!</p>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>At the Detroit Auto Show for an appearance on 60 Minutes, President Joe Biden declared that the pandemic is over. Not surprisingly, handlers immediately started walking back the President’s comments, but the impromptu announcement nevertheless caused a great deal of controversy and heated reactions, both from COVID skeptics and COVID alarmists.</p> <p>Jimmy and his panel of The Dive’s Jackson Hinkle and Convo Couch’s Craig “Pasta” Jardula discuss whether the pandemic really is “over” and what that even means.  Plus segments on the arrival of 50 Venezuelan migrants to Martha's Vineyard and the media freakout over Ben Shapiro allegedly grooming a new generation of incels online.  Also featuring Stef Zamorano and Mike MacRae! And phone calls from  Jeff Bridges and Joe Biden!</p>]]></content:encoded>
			<enclosure length="68306197" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/thejimmydoreshow/TJDS_20220923_Podcast_-_92222_5.39_PM.mp3?dest-id=19460"/>
			<itunes:duration>01:10:45</itunes:duration>
			<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
			<itunes:keywords/>
			<itunes:subtitle><![CDATA[At the Detroit Auto Show for an appearance on 60 Minutes, President Joe Biden declared that the pandemic is over. Not surprisingly, handlers immediately started walking back the President’s comments, but the impromptu announcement nevertheless...]]></itunes:subtitle>
			<itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
		<itunes:summary>At the Detroit Auto Show for an appearance on 60 Minutes, President Joe Biden declared that the pandemic is over. Not surprisingly, handlers immediately started walking back the President’s comments, but the impromptu announcement nevertheless caused a great deal of controversy and heated reactions, both from COVID skeptics and COVID alarmists. Jimmy and his panel of The Dive’s Jackson Hinkle and Convo Couch’s Craig “Pasta” Jardula discuss whether the pandemic really is “over” and what that even means. Plus segments on the arrival of 50 Venezuelan migrants to Martha's Vineyard and the media freakout over Ben Shapiro allegedly grooming a new generation of incels online. Also featuring Stef Zamorano and Mike MacRae! And phone calls from  Jeff Bridges and Joe Biden!</itunes:summary></item>
		<item>
			<title>Ukraine Wins Back Territory From Russia!</title>
			<itunes:title>Ukraine Wins Back Territory From Russia!</itunes:title>
			<pubDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2022 05:00:09 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false"><![CDATA[8765dc1c-7892-434b-bafb-b887106eb934]]></guid>
			<link><![CDATA[https://thejimmydoreshow.libsyn.com/ukraine-wins-back-territory-from-russia]]></link>
			<itunes:image href="https://ssl-static.libsyn.com/p/assets/0/9/5/3/095360681b92b73840be95ea3302a6a1/Screen_Shot_2022-09-13_at_6.36.10_PM.png"/>
			<description><![CDATA[<p>The news networks have brimmed with stories lately of the stunning Kharkiv counter-offensive that has seen Ukraine recapture vast swathes of territory from the invading Russians. Have we reached a turning point in the war? Is the handwriting on the wall for Putin and his marauding Russian hordes? Or is this a mere blip, a short-term stumble for the Russian Bear before he continues his inexorable march across all of the Donbass, and possibly all of Ukraine?<br /> <br /> Jimmy and his panel of America’s comedian Kurt Metzger and The Dive’s Jackson Hinkle discuss this surprising turn of events in the Ukraine War and their larger significance.<br /> <br /> Plus segments on the latest round of booster misinformation from America's top health officials and the DNC's epic snub of progressives over dark money.<br /> <br /> Also featuring Stef Zamorano and Mike MacRae! And phone calls from King Charles III and Joe Biden!</p>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The news networks have brimmed with stories lately of the stunning Kharkiv counter-offensive that has seen Ukraine recapture vast swathes of territory from the invading Russians. Have we reached a turning point in the war? Is the handwriting on the wall for Putin and his marauding Russian hordes? Or is this a mere blip, a short-term stumble for the Russian Bear before he continues his inexorable march across all of the Donbass, and possibly all of Ukraine?  Jimmy and his panel of America’s comedian Kurt Metzger and The Dive’s Jackson Hinkle discuss this surprising turn of events in the Ukraine War and their larger significance.  Plus segments on the latest round of booster misinformation from America's top health officials and the DNC's epic snub of progressives over dark money.  Also featuring Stef Zamorano and Mike MacRae! And phone calls from King Charles III and Joe Biden!</p>]]></content:encoded>
			<enclosure length="62277177" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/thejimmydoreshow/TJDS_20220916_Podcast_-_91322_6.23_PM.mp3?dest-id=19460"/>
			<itunes:duration>01:04:42</itunes:duration>
			<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
			<itunes:keywords/>
			<itunes:subtitle><![CDATA[The news networks have brimmed with stories lately of the stunning Kharkiv counter-offensive that has seen Ukraine recapture vast swathes of territory from the invading Russians. Have we reached a turning point in the war? Is the handwriting on the...]]></itunes:subtitle>
			<itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
		<itunes:summary>The news networks have brimmed with stories lately of the stunning Kharkiv counter-offensive that has seen Ukraine recapture vast swathes of territory from the invading Russians. Have we reached a turning point in the war? Is the handwriting on the wall for Putin and his marauding Russian hordes? Or is this a mere blip, a short-term stumble for the Russian Bear before he continues his inexorable march across all of the Donbass, and possibly all of Ukraine? Jimmy and his panel of America’s comedian Kurt Metzger and The Dive’s Jackson Hinkle discuss this surprising turn of events in the Ukraine War and their larger significance. Plus segments on the latest round of booster misinformation from America's top health officials and the DNC's epic snub of progressives over dark money. Also featuring Stef Zamorano and Mike MacRae! And phone calls from King Charles III and Joe Biden!</itunes:summary></item>
		<item>
			<title>Debate: Are Democrats REALLY Any Better Than Republicans?</title>
			<itunes:title>Debate: Are Democrats REALLY Any Better Than Republicans?</itunes:title>
			<pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2022 05:00:49 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false"><![CDATA[a69b7d41-33ad-4114-bfbb-9499fe95233e]]></guid>
			<link><![CDATA[https://thejimmydoreshow.libsyn.com/debate-are-democrats-really-any-better-than-republicans]]></link>
			<itunes:image href="https://ssl-static.libsyn.com/p/assets/0/2/c/f/02cf4d20116d9d0fe55e3c100dce7605/Screen_Shot_2022-09-08_at_10.38.41_AM.png"/>
			<description><![CDATA[<p>Standup comedian, game show host and erstwhile Presidential candidate Ben Gleib stopped by The Jimmy Dore Show studio for a segment discussing his new special on YouTube, the state of comedy in the era of wokeness, the Trump phenomenon and whether there are any substantive differences between the two major American political parties.<br /> <br /> Jimmy and America’s comedian Kurt Metzger engage in a predominantly civil but sometimes heated exchange of ideas with Gleib.<br /> <br /> Plus a segment on progressives' latest opportunity to use their leverage to stop Joe Manchin's bad climate bill - and why they won't do it.<br /> <br /> Also featuring Stef Zamorano and Mike MacRae! And a phone call from George Clooney!</p>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Standup comedian, game show host and erstwhile Presidential candidate Ben Gleib stopped by The Jimmy Dore Show studio for a segment discussing his new special on YouTube, the state of comedy in the era of wokeness, the Trump phenomenon and whether there are any substantive differences between the two major American political parties.  Jimmy and America’s comedian Kurt Metzger engage in a predominantly civil but sometimes heated exchange of ideas with Gleib.  Plus a segment on progressives' latest opportunity to use their leverage to stop Joe Manchin's bad climate bill - and why they won't do it.  Also featuring Stef Zamorano and Mike MacRae! And a phone call from George Clooney!</p>]]></content:encoded>
			<enclosure length="61355410" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/thejimmydoreshow/TJDS_20220909_Podcast_-_9822_10.37_AM.mp3?dest-id=19460"/>
			<itunes:duration>01:03:34</itunes:duration>
			<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
			<itunes:keywords/>
			<itunes:subtitle><![CDATA[Standup comedian, game show host and erstwhile Presidential candidate Ben Gleib stopped by The Jimmy Dore Show studio for a segment discussing his new special on YouTube, the state of comedy in the era of wokeness, the Trump phenomenon and whether...]]></itunes:subtitle>
			<itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
		<itunes:summary>Standup comedian, game show host and erstwhile Presidential candidate Ben Gleib stopped by The Jimmy Dore Show studio for a segment discussing his new special on YouTube, the state of comedy in the era of wokeness, the Trump phenomenon and whether there are any substantive differences between the two major American political parties. Jimmy and America’s comedian Kurt Metzger engage in a predominantly civil but sometimes heated exchange of ideas with Gleib. Plus a segment on progressives' latest opportunity to use their leverage to stop Joe Manchin's bad climate bill - and why they won't do it. Also featuring Stef Zamorano and Mike MacRae! And a phone call from George Clooney!</itunes:summary></item>
		<item>
			<title>COVID Booster Approved Despite ZERO Human Testing</title>
			<itunes:title>COVID Booster Approved Despite ZERO Human Testing</itunes:title>
			<pubDate>Fri, 02 Sep 2022 05:00:55 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false"><![CDATA[e90ccc56-806b-4b1f-ba61-9abb9132ea34]]></guid>
			<link><![CDATA[https://thejimmydoreshow.libsyn.com/covid-booster-approved-despite-zero-human-testing]]></link>
			<itunes:image href="https://ssl-static.libsyn.com/p/assets/3/1/d/a/31dac517ada95ddb27a2322813b393ee/Screen_Shot_2022-09-01_at_7.00.41_PM.png"/>
			<description><![CDATA[<p>The FDA has announced emergency use authorization of a booster shot that targets the omicron BA.5 COVID variant. How the current state of the pandemic qualifies as an “emergency” is anyone’s guess. As is the likely effect on anyone given the booster since the authorization process did not involve any actual human testing. In fact, the little information Pfizer has made available to the public involves tests performed on eight mice. And that’s it!<br /> <br /> Jimmy and America’s comedian Kurt Metzger discuss the public’s dwindling interest in boosters and the skepticism from knowledgeable experts over the value of endless COVID boosters<br /> <br /> Plus segments on the FBI's role in Facebook censoring the Hunter Biden laptop story and Dr. Fauci's latest lie about COVID lockdowns.<br /> <br /> Also featuring Stef Zamorano and Mike MacRae! And phone calls from Joe Biden and Ozzy Osbourne!</p> <p> </p>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The FDA has announced emergency use authorization of a booster shot that targets the omicron BA.5 COVID variant. How the current state of the pandemic qualifies as an “emergency” is anyone’s guess. As is the likely effect on anyone given the booster since the authorization process did not involve any actual human testing. In fact, the little information Pfizer has made available to the public involves tests performed on eight mice. And that’s it!  Jimmy and America’s comedian Kurt Metzger discuss the public’s dwindling interest in boosters and the skepticism from knowledgeable experts over the value of endless COVID boosters  Plus segments on the FBI's role in Facebook censoring the Hunter Biden laptop story and Dr. Fauci's latest lie about COVID lockdowns.  Also featuring Stef Zamorano and Mike MacRae! And phone calls from Joe Biden and Ozzy Osbourne!</p> <p> </p>]]></content:encoded>
			<enclosure length="65105194" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/thejimmydoreshow/TJDS_20220902_Podcast_-_9122_4.08_PM.mp3?dest-id=19460"/>
			<itunes:duration>01:07:36</itunes:duration>
			<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
			<itunes:keywords/>
			<itunes:subtitle><![CDATA[The FDA has announced emergency use authorization of a booster shot that targets the omicron BA.5 COVID variant. How the current state of the pandemic qualifies as an “emergency” is anyone’s guess. As is the likely effect on anyone given the...]]></itunes:subtitle>
			<itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
		<itunes:summary>The FDA has announced emergency use authorization of a booster shot that targets the omicron BA.5 COVID variant. How the current state of the pandemic qualifies as an “emergency” is anyone’s guess. As is the likely effect on anyone given the booster since the authorization process did not involve any actual human testing. In fact, the little information Pfizer has made available to the public involves tests performed on eight mice. And that’s it! Jimmy and America’s comedian Kurt Metzger discuss the public’s dwindling interest in boosters and the skepticism from knowledgeable experts over the value of endless COVID boosters Plus segments on the FBI's role in Facebook censoring the Hunter Biden laptop story and Dr. Fauci's latest lie about COVID lockdowns. Also featuring Stef Zamorano and Mike MacRae! And phone calls from Joe Biden and Ozzy Osbourne!  </itunes:summary></item>
		<item>
			<title>George W. Bush To Teach “MasterClass” In Leadership?</title>
			<itunes:title>George W. Bush To Teach “MasterClass” In Leadership?</itunes:title>
			<pubDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2022 05:00:15 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false"><![CDATA[f17e5ce4-6107-48dd-8811-2401aac4d72a]]></guid>
			<link><![CDATA[https://thejimmydoreshow.libsyn.com/george-w-bush-to-teach-masterclass-in-leadership]]></link>
			<itunes:image href="https://ssl-static.libsyn.com/p/assets/5/5/7/7/55776f54d444f1c0a04421dee9605cbd/Screen_Shot_2022-08-25_at_2.39.52_PM.png"/>
			<description><![CDATA[<p>If you can believe it, ex-President George W. Bush has announced that he will be teaching a “MasterClass” in leadership that you and anyone else willing to pony up the money can take to learn what Bush has to say on the topic. Whether students will learn the ins and outs of committing war crimes, ignoring the suffering of hurricane victims and overseeing a torture program that continues to this day remains unclear.<br /> <br /> Jimmy and America’s comedian Kurt Metzger discuss the curious choice of a colossal f*ckup like George W. Bush to teach a class in leadership<br /> <br /> Plus segments on bringing MAGA and communism together and Joe Biden's meager student debt assistance program.<br /> <br /> Also featuring Stef Zamorano and Mike MacRae! And phone calls from Vince Vaughn and Jake Tapper!</p>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>If you can believe it, ex-President George W. Bush has announced that he will be teaching a “MasterClass” in leadership that you and anyone else willing to pony up the money can take to learn what Bush has to say on the topic. Whether students will learn the ins and outs of committing war crimes, ignoring the suffering of hurricane victims and overseeing a torture program that continues to this day remains unclear.  Jimmy and America’s comedian Kurt Metzger discuss the curious choice of a colossal f*ckup like George W. Bush to teach a class in leadership  Plus segments on bringing MAGA and communism together and Joe Biden's meager student debt assistance program.  Also featuring Stef Zamorano and Mike MacRae! And phone calls from Vince Vaughn and Jake Tapper!</p>]]></content:encoded>
			<enclosure length="56791609" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/thejimmydoreshow/TJDS_20220826_Podcast_-_82522_12.47_PM.mp3?dest-id=19460"/>
			<itunes:duration>58:51</itunes:duration>
			<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
			<itunes:keywords/>
			<itunes:subtitle><![CDATA[If you can believe it, ex-President George W. Bush has announced that he will be teaching a “MasterClass” in leadership that you and anyone else willing to pony up the money can take to learn what Bush has to say on the topic. Whether students...]]></itunes:subtitle>
			<itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
		<itunes:summary>If you can believe it, ex-President George W. Bush has announced that he will be teaching a “MasterClass” in leadership that you and anyone else willing to pony up the money can take to learn what Bush has to say on the topic. Whether students will learn the ins and outs of committing war crimes, ignoring the suffering of hurricane victims and overseeing a torture program that continues to this day remains unclear. Jimmy and America’s comedian Kurt Metzger discuss the curious choice of a colossal f*ckup like George W. Bush to teach a class in leadership Plus segments on bringing MAGA and communism together and Joe Biden's meager student debt assistance program. Also featuring Stef Zamorano and Mike MacRae! And phone calls from Vince Vaughn and Jake Tapper!</itunes:summary></item>
		<item>
			<title>Desperate Dems Cheer FBI &amp; Raid On Mar-A-Lago</title>
			<itunes:title>Desperate Dems Cheer FBI &amp; Raid On Mar-A-Lago</itunes:title>
			<pubDate>Fri, 19 Aug 2022 05:00:45 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false"><![CDATA[e6d54828-3520-4029-abed-de4a97dbd361]]></guid>
			<link><![CDATA[https://thejimmydoreshow.libsyn.com/desperate-dems-cheer-fbi-raid-on-mar-a-lago]]></link>
			<itunes:image href="https://ssl-static.libsyn.com/p/assets/2/d/9/4/2d94feea014f81e4bafc7308ab683e82/Screen_Shot_2022-08-18_at_1.31.44_PM.png"/>
			<description><![CDATA[<p>The political world was rocked last week when FBI agents descended on Mar-a-Lago, Donald Trump’s Florida estate, and scoured the former president’s home, making off with boxes and boxes of documents. Later reports emerged that Trump may have held on to highly sensitive classified materials relating to the nation’s nuclear program and will be accused of violating the Espionage Act. Democrats cheered the FBI raid while Trump supporters accused the Justice Department of engaging in a partisan witch hunt.<br /> <br /> Jimmy and his panel of The Grayzone’s Max Blumenthal and America’s comedian Kurt Metzger discuss what might have really motivated this unprecedented raid on a former president’s home.<br /> <br /> Plus a segment on Andrew Yang's inability to defend his new third party effort under wilting questioning from CNN's Jim Acosta.<br /> <br /> Also featuring Stef Zamorano and Mike MacRae! And phone calls from Chuck Schumer and Andrew Cuomo!</p>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The political world was rocked last week when FBI agents descended on Mar-a-Lago, Donald Trump’s Florida estate, and scoured the former president’s home, making off with boxes and boxes of documents. Later reports emerged that Trump may have held on to highly sensitive classified materials relating to the nation’s nuclear program and will be accused of violating the Espionage Act. Democrats cheered the FBI raid while Trump supporters accused the Justice Department of engaging in a partisan witch hunt.  Jimmy and his panel of The Grayzone’s Max Blumenthal and America’s comedian Kurt Metzger discuss what might have really motivated this unprecedented raid on a former president’s home.  Plus a segment on Andrew Yang's inability to defend his new third party effort under wilting questioning from CNN's Jim Acosta.  Also featuring Stef Zamorano and Mike MacRae! And phone calls from Chuck Schumer and Andrew Cuomo!</p>]]></content:encoded>
			<enclosure length="63362534" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/thejimmydoreshow/TJDS_20220819_Podcast_-_81822_1.27_PM.mp3?dest-id=19460"/>
			<itunes:duration>01:05:36</itunes:duration>
			<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
			<itunes:keywords/>
			<itunes:subtitle><![CDATA[The political world was rocked last week when FBI agents descended on Mar-a-Lago, Donald Trump’s Florida estate, and scoured the former president’s home, making off with boxes and boxes of documents. Later reports emerged that Trump may have held...]]></itunes:subtitle>
			<itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
		<itunes:summary>The political world was rocked last week when FBI agents descended on Mar-a-Lago, Donald Trump’s Florida estate, and scoured the former president’s home, making off with boxes and boxes of documents. Later reports emerged that Trump may have held on to highly sensitive classified materials relating to the nation’s nuclear program and will be accused of violating the Espionage Act. Democrats cheered the FBI raid while Trump supporters accused the Justice Department of engaging in a partisan witch hunt. Jimmy and his panel of The Grayzone’s Max Blumenthal and America’s comedian Kurt Metzger discuss what might have really motivated this unprecedented raid on a former president’s home. Plus a segment on Andrew Yang's inability to defend his new third party effort under wilting questioning from CNN's Jim Acosta. Also featuring Stef Zamorano and Mike MacRae! And phone calls from Chuck Schumer and Andrew Cuomo!</itunes:summary></item>
		<item>
			<title>Roger Waters Destroys CNN Host Over Ukraine &amp; Taiwan</title>
			<itunes:title>Roger Waters Destroys CNN Host Over Ukraine &amp; Taiwan</itunes:title>
			<pubDate>Fri, 12 Aug 2022 05:00:35 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false"><![CDATA[0ba51412-6ade-4bac-a739-b4438ee7f713]]></guid>
			<link><![CDATA[https://thejimmydoreshow.libsyn.com/roger-waters-destroys-cnn-host-over-ukraine-taiwan]]></link>
			<itunes:image href="https://ssl-static.libsyn.com/p/assets/f/3/a/3/f3a3f886446ec15188c4a68c3ddbc4f2/Screen_Shot_2022-08-11_at_9.31.59_PM.png"/>
			<description><![CDATA[<p>Pink Floyd founding member and outspoken activist Roger Waters appeared on CNN recently and took advantage of the opportunity to school host Michael Smerconish on a range of topics, including the truth about the Ukraine War’s origins, Russia’s role in winning World War II against the Nazis and Taiwan’s relationship to China.<br /> <br /> Jimmy and his panel of The Dive’s Jackson Hinkle and America’s comedian Kurt Metzger discuss Waters’ teachable moment and Smerconish’s phony-baloney claims to even-handedness.<br /> <br /> Plus segments on CBS News furiously backpedaling after mistakenly telling the truth about Ukraine and a California county sending police thousands of miles away to harass a small business owner as a favor for a wealthy friend of the sheriff.</p> <p dir="ltr" data-test-bidi="">Also featuring Stef Zamorano and Mike MacRae! And phone calls from Kevin Spacey and the duo of Chuck Schumer and Bernie Sanders!</p>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Pink Floyd founding member and outspoken activist Roger Waters appeared on CNN recently and took advantage of the opportunity to school host Michael Smerconish on a range of topics, including the truth about the Ukraine War’s origins, Russia’s role in winning World War II against the Nazis and Taiwan’s relationship to China.  Jimmy and his panel of The Dive’s Jackson Hinkle and America’s comedian Kurt Metzger discuss Waters’ teachable moment and Smerconish’s phony-baloney claims to even-handedness.  Plus segments on CBS News furiously backpedaling after mistakenly telling the truth about Ukraine and a California county sending police thousands of miles away to harass a small business owner as a favor for a wealthy friend of the sheriff.</p> <p dir="ltr" data-test-bidi="">Also featuring Stef Zamorano and Mike MacRae! And phone calls from Kevin Spacey and the duo of Chuck Schumer and Bernie Sanders!</p>]]></content:encoded>
			<enclosure length="58177687" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/thejimmydoreshow/TJDS_20220812_Podcast_-_81122_9.16_PM.mp3?dest-id=19460"/>
			<itunes:duration>01:00:24</itunes:duration>
			<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
			<itunes:keywords/>
			<itunes:subtitle><![CDATA[Pink Floyd founding member and outspoken activist Roger Waters appeared on CNN recently and took advantage of the opportunity to school host Michael Smerconish on a range of topics, including the truth about the Ukraine War’s origins, Russia’s...]]></itunes:subtitle>
			<itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
		<itunes:summary>Pink Floyd founding member and outspoken activist Roger Waters appeared on CNN recently and took advantage of the opportunity to school host Michael Smerconish on a range of topics, including the truth about the Ukraine War’s origins, Russia’s role in winning World War II against the Nazis and Taiwan’s relationship to China. Jimmy and his panel of The Dive’s Jackson Hinkle and America’s comedian Kurt Metzger discuss Waters’ teachable moment and Smerconish’s phony-baloney claims to even-handedness. Plus segments on CBS News furiously backpedaling after mistakenly telling the truth about Ukraine and a California county sending police thousands of miles away to harass a small business owner as a favor for a wealthy friend of the sheriff. Also featuring Stef Zamorano and Mike MacRae! And phone calls from Kevin Spacey and the duo of Chuck Schumer and Bernie Sanders!</itunes:summary></item>
		<item>
			<title>CNN Denies We’re In A Recession To Boost Biden</title>
			<itunes:title>CNN Denies We’re In A Recession To Boost Biden</itunes:title>
			<pubDate>Fri, 05 Aug 2022 05:00:20 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false"><![CDATA[d68626a1-ed33-44e7-aa92-f59291423b31]]></guid>
			<link><![CDATA[https://thejimmydoreshow.libsyn.com/cnn-denies-were-in-a-recession-to-boost-biden]]></link>
			<itunes:image href="https://ssl-static.libsyn.com/p/assets/b/0/1/3/b0130232d7b8b1a5bafc7308ab683e82/Screen_Shot_2022-08-04_at_12.56.10_PM.png"/>
			<description><![CDATA[<p>New York Times opinion writer Paul Krugman won a Nobel Prize for Economics, but lately it seems like he’s gunning for a new prize – that of Biggest Apologist for the Biden administration. And in that role most recently Krugman has been downplaying the prospect that the United States economy is in recession, even though by all traditional definitions of the term we most certainly are. CNN’s Brian Stelter helps further the cause by giggling along as Krugman twists the language and the truth to suit the needs of his masters in the Democratic Party.<br /> <br /> Jimmy and his panel of The Dive’s Jackson Hinkle and America’s comedian Kurt Metzger discuss the contortions Krugman engages in to try to persuade us that the economy is doing super duper.<br /> <br /> Plus segments on Nancy Pelosi's word salad speech in Taiwan, the collapse of CNN's ratings and profits, and Colorado Senator Michael Bennet's "oops" moment revealing he may engage in insider trading.</p> <p>Also featuring Stef Zamorano and Black Agenda Report's Danny Haiphong!</p>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>New York Times opinion writer Paul Krugman won a Nobel Prize for Economics, but lately it seems like he’s gunning for a new prize – that of Biggest Apologist for the Biden administration. And in that role most recently Krugman has been downplaying the prospect that the United States economy is in recession, even though by all traditional definitions of the term we most certainly are. CNN’s Brian Stelter helps further the cause by giggling along as Krugman twists the language and the truth to suit the needs of his masters in the Democratic Party.  Jimmy and his panel of The Dive’s Jackson Hinkle and America’s comedian Kurt Metzger discuss the contortions Krugman engages in to try to persuade us that the economy is doing super duper.  Plus segments on Nancy Pelosi's word salad speech in Taiwan, the collapse of CNN's ratings and profits, and Colorado Senator Michael Bennet's "oops" moment revealing he may engage in insider trading.</p> <p>Also featuring Stef Zamorano and Black Agenda Report's Danny Haiphong!</p>]]></content:encoded>
			<enclosure length="55462938" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/thejimmydoreshow/TJDS_20220804_Podcast_-_8422_11.42_AM.mp3?dest-id=19460"/>
			<itunes:duration>57:25</itunes:duration>
			<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
			<itunes:keywords/>
			<itunes:subtitle><![CDATA[New York Times opinion writer Paul Krugman won a Nobel Prize for Economics, but lately it seems like he’s gunning for a new prize – that of Biggest Apologist for the Biden administration. And in that role most recently Krugman has been downplaying...]]></itunes:subtitle>
			<itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
		<itunes:summary>New York Times opinion writer Paul Krugman won a Nobel Prize for Economics, but lately it seems like he’s gunning for a new prize – that of Biggest Apologist for the Biden administration. And in that role most recently Krugman has been downplaying the prospect that the United States economy is in recession, even though by all traditional definitions of the term we most certainly are. CNN’s Brian Stelter helps further the cause by giggling along as Krugman twists the language and the truth to suit the needs of his masters in the Democratic Party. Jimmy and his panel of The Dive’s Jackson Hinkle and America’s comedian Kurt Metzger discuss the contortions Krugman engages in to try to persuade us that the economy is doing super duper. Plus segments on Nancy Pelosi's word salad speech in Taiwan, the collapse of CNN's ratings and profits, and Colorado Senator Michael Bennet's "oops" moment revealing he may engage in insider trading. Also featuring Stef Zamorano and Black Agenda Report's Danny Haiphong!</itunes:summary></item>
		<item>
			<title>Tom Cruise VINDICATED For Viral Rant Against Big Pharma – New Study</title>
			<itunes:title>Tom Cruise VINDICATED For Viral Rant Against Big Pharma – New Study</itunes:title>
			<pubDate>Fri, 29 Jul 2022 23:00:23 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false"><![CDATA[3297c4a2-73a6-4931-8494-280b856688df]]></guid>
			<link><![CDATA[https://thejimmydoreshow.libsyn.com/tom-cruise-vindicated-for-viral-rant-against-big-pharma-new-study]]></link>
			<itunes:image href="https://ssl-static.libsyn.com/p/assets/4/5/0/7/45071838d2e8589d27a2322813b393ee/Screen_Shot_2022-07-29_at_3.17.26_PM.png"/>
			<description><![CDATA[<p>In 2005 Tom Cruise was widely mocked, derided and accused of being a lunatic after appearing on the Today Show and expressing controversial views about the ineffectiveness of antidepressants and the widespread practice of prescribing Ritalin and Adderall to children. Now 17 years later Cruise is being vindicated by a comprehensive study questioning the science behind “chemical imbalances” in the brain and demonstrating that antidepressants do not work as advertised. Jimmy and America’s comedian Kurt Metzger discuss their recollection of the infamous interview and how the march of scientific advancement has now caught up with… Tom Cruise.<br /> <br /> Plus a segment speaking with The Grayzone's Aaron Maté about confronting the writer who smeared him in the pages of The Guardian.<br /> <br /> Also featuring Stef Zamorano, Kurt Metzger and Mike MacRae! And phone calls from Joe Biden and Al Pacino!</p> <p><br /> <br /> <br /></p>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In 2005 Tom Cruise was widely mocked, derided and accused of being a lunatic after appearing on the Today Show and expressing controversial views about the ineffectiveness of antidepressants and the widespread practice of prescribing Ritalin and Adderall to children. Now 17 years later Cruise is being vindicated by a comprehensive study questioning the science behind “chemical imbalances” in the brain and demonstrating that antidepressants do not work as advertised. Jimmy and America’s comedian Kurt Metzger discuss their recollection of the infamous interview and how the march of scientific advancement has now caught up with… Tom Cruise.  Plus a segment speaking with The Grayzone's Aaron Maté about confronting the writer who smeared him in the pages of The Guardian.  Also featuring Stef Zamorano, Kurt Metzger and Mike MacRae! And phone calls from Joe Biden and Al Pacino!</p> <p>  </p>]]></content:encoded>
			<enclosure length="55026212" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/thejimmydoreshow/TJDS_20220729_Podcast_-_72922_3.03_PM.mp3?dest-id=19460"/>
			<itunes:duration>56:56</itunes:duration>
			<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
			<itunes:keywords/>
			<itunes:subtitle><![CDATA[In 2005 Tom Cruise was widely mocked, derided and accused of being a lunatic after appearing on the Today Show and expressing controversial views about the ineffectiveness of antidepressants and the widespread practice of prescribing Ritalin and...]]></itunes:subtitle>
			<itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
		<itunes:summary>In 2005 Tom Cruise was widely mocked, derided and accused of being a lunatic after appearing on the Today Show and expressing controversial views about the ineffectiveness of antidepressants and the widespread practice of prescribing Ritalin and Adderall to children. Now 17 years later Cruise is being vindicated by a comprehensive study questioning the science behind “chemical imbalances” in the brain and demonstrating that antidepressants do not work as advertised. Jimmy and America’s comedian Kurt Metzger discuss their recollection of the infamous interview and how the march of scientific advancement has now caught up with… Tom Cruise. Plus a segment speaking with The Grayzone's Aaron Maté about confronting the writer who smeared him in the pages of The Guardian. Also featuring Stef Zamorano, Kurt Metzger and Mike MacRae! And phone calls from Joe Biden and Al Pacino!</itunes:summary></item>
		<item>
			<title>Actual Journalists Slam Corporate Media To Their Faces</title>
			<itunes:title>Actual Journalists Slam Corporate Media To Their Faces</itunes:title>
			<pubDate>Fri, 22 Jul 2022 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false"><![CDATA[993978b6-6583-49cb-974e-c3468392e91e]]></guid>
			<link><![CDATA[https://thejimmydoreshow.libsyn.com/actual-journalists-slam-corporate-media-to-their-faces]]></link>
			<itunes:image href="https://ssl-static.libsyn.com/p/assets/6/c/1/1/6c11d1722e8dd54cbafc7308ab683e82/Screen_Shot_2022-07-21_at_11.48.42_AM.png"/>
			<description><![CDATA[<p>The Grayzone journalists Max Blumenthal and Aaron Maté recently traveled to Canada to attend Collision Toronto, "North America's fastest growing tech conference," and sat for an interview where they described an audience filled with representatives of the mainstream media as duplicitous, fake news-spreading propagandists. Jimmy speaks with Aaron and Max about the experience, and how it felt to tell the truth about the malign influence of the corporate media right to their glaring faces.<br /> <br /> Plus a segment on The Guardian newspaper's call for an immediate escalation in Ukraine that will likely lead to World War III.<br /> <br /> Also featuring Stef Zamorano and Mike MacRae! And phone calls from Brad Pitt as well as Joe Biden and Joe Manchin!</p>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Grayzone journalists Max Blumenthal and Aaron Maté recently traveled to Canada to attend Collision Toronto, "North America's fastest growing tech conference," and sat for an interview where they described an audience filled with representatives of the mainstream media as duplicitous, fake news-spreading propagandists. Jimmy speaks with Aaron and Max about the experience, and how it felt to tell the truth about the malign influence of the corporate media right to their glaring faces.  Plus a segment on The Guardian newspaper's call for an immediate escalation in Ukraine that will likely lead to World War III.  Also featuring Stef Zamorano and Mike MacRae! And phone calls from Brad Pitt as well as Joe Biden and Joe Manchin!</p>]]></content:encoded>
			<enclosure length="61285590" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/thejimmydoreshow/TJDS_20220722_Podcast_-_72122_11.32_AM.mp3?dest-id=19460"/>
			<itunes:duration>01:03:25</itunes:duration>
			<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
			<itunes:keywords/>
			<itunes:subtitle><![CDATA[The Grayzone journalists Max Blumenthal and Aaron Maté recently traveled to Canada to attend Collision Toronto, "North America's fastest growing tech conference," and sat for an interview where they described an audience filled with representatives...]]></itunes:subtitle>
			<itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
		<itunes:summary>The Grayzone journalists Max Blumenthal and Aaron Maté recently traveled to Canada to attend Collision Toronto, "North America's fastest growing tech conference," and sat for an interview where they described an audience filled with representatives of the mainstream media as duplicitous, fake news-spreading propagandists. Jimmy speaks with Aaron and Max about the experience, and how it felt to tell the truth about the malign influence of the corporate media right to their glaring faces. Plus a segment on The Guardian newspaper's call for an immediate escalation in Ukraine that will likely lead to World War III. Also featuring Stef Zamorano and Mike MacRae! And phone calls from Brad Pitt as well as Joe Biden and Joe Manchin!</itunes:summary></item>
		<item>
			<title>Hunter Biden “Should Be In Prison!” Says Joe Biden</title>
			<itunes:title>Hunter Biden “Should Be In Prison!” Says Joe Biden</itunes:title>
			<pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2022 05:11:36 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false"><![CDATA[8bd02bcf-e717-4f54-94e3-dfacaab8770d]]></guid>
			<link><![CDATA[https://thejimmydoreshow.libsyn.com/hunter-biden-should-be-in-prison-says-joe-biden]]></link>
			<itunes:image href="https://ssl-static.libsyn.com/p/assets/7/d/7/f/7d7f2bb5f7906095e55e3c100dce7605/Screen_Shot_2022-07-14_at_4.12.26_PM.png"/>
			<description><![CDATA[<p>Hunter Biden is back in the news, this time as the victim of a hack revealing photos, videos and texts on his phone, and it’s all pretty damning. Biden is shown weighing his crack, smoking crack and engaging in other decidedly prurient acts. So what does Hunter’s father, President Joe Biden, think about all of this? There’s no comment from the White House after this most recent hack, but as Jimmy reveals, back in his Senate days Joe had plenty to say about what kind of punishment people like Hunter should face.<br /> <br /> Plus a segment on CNN's COVID fearmongering, labeling BA.5 the "worst variant ever."<br /> <br /> Also featuring Stef Zamorano, Kurt Metzger, Malcolm Fleschner and Mike MacRae! And phone calls from Joe Biden and the World Economic Forum's Klaus Schwab!</p>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hunter Biden is back in the news, this time as the victim of a hack revealing photos, videos and texts on his phone, and it’s all pretty damning. Biden is shown weighing his crack, smoking crack and engaging in other decidedly prurient acts. So what does Hunter’s father, President Joe Biden, think about all of this? There’s no comment from the White House after this most recent hack, but as Jimmy reveals, back in his Senate days Joe had plenty to say about what kind of punishment people like Hunter should face.  Plus a segment on CNN's COVID fearmongering, labeling BA.5 the "worst variant ever."  Also featuring Stef Zamorano, Kurt Metzger, Malcolm Fleschner and Mike MacRae! And phone calls from Joe Biden and the World Economic Forum's Klaus Schwab!</p>]]></content:encoded>
			<enclosure length="55042784" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/thejimmydoreshow/TJDS_20220715_Podcast_-_71422_12.40_PM.mp3?dest-id=19460"/>
			<itunes:duration>57:04</itunes:duration>
			<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
			<itunes:keywords/>
			<itunes:subtitle><![CDATA[Hunter Biden is back in the news, this time as the victim of a hack revealing photos, videos and texts on his phone, and it’s all pretty damning. Biden is shown weighing his crack, smoking crack and engaging in other decidedly prurient acts. So what...]]></itunes:subtitle>
			<itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
		<itunes:summary>Hunter Biden is back in the news, this time as the victim of a hack revealing photos, videos and texts on his phone, and it’s all pretty damning. Biden is shown weighing his crack, smoking crack and engaging in other decidedly prurient acts. So what does Hunter’s father, President Joe Biden, think about all of this? There’s no comment from the White House after this most recent hack, but as Jimmy reveals, back in his Senate days Joe had plenty to say about what kind of punishment people like Hunter should face. Plus a segment on CNN's COVID fearmongering, labeling BA.5 the "worst variant ever." Also featuring Stef Zamorano, Kurt Metzger, Malcolm Fleschner and Mike MacRae! And phone calls from Joe Biden and the World Economic Forum's Klaus Schwab!</itunes:summary></item>
		<item>
			<title>Dems Illegally Kick 3rd Party Off Ballot In North Carolina</title>
			<itunes:title>Dems Illegally Kick 3rd Party Off Ballot In North Carolina</itunes:title>
			<pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2022 05:30:38 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false"><![CDATA[42eca59b-7101-4a53-8ab9-61cb4089ef9b]]></guid>
			<link><![CDATA[https://thejimmydoreshow.libsyn.com/dems-illegally-kick-3rd-party-off-ballot-in-north-carolina]]></link>
			<itunes:image href="https://ssl-static.libsyn.com/p/assets/7/1/1/7/71178718980c7242a04421dee9605cbd/Screen_Shot_2022-07-07_at_1.56.16_PM.png"/>
			<description><![CDATA[<p dir="ltr" data-test-bidi="">While Democrats continue rigging elections against 3rd parties, Matthew Hoh - U.S. Senate candidate to represent North Carolina on the Green Party ticket - is fighting back to claim his rightfully earned place on the ballot.</p> <p dir="ltr" data-test-bidi="">Plus, a segment revealing how Democrats fund radical Republicans.</p> <p dir="ltr" data-test-bidi="">Featuring Stef Zamorano, Kurt Metzger, Matthew Hoh and Mike MacRae! And phone calls from Vince Vaughn and Willem the Dutch Farmer!</p>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="ltr" data-test-bidi="">While Democrats continue rigging elections against 3rd parties, Matthew Hoh - U.S. Senate candidate to represent North Carolina on the Green Party ticket - is fighting back to claim his rightfully earned place on the ballot.</p> <p dir="ltr" data-test-bidi="">Plus, a segment revealing how Democrats fund radical Republicans.</p> <p dir="ltr" data-test-bidi="">Featuring Stef Zamorano, Kurt Metzger, Matthew Hoh and Mike MacRae! And phone calls from Vince Vaughn and Willem the Dutch Farmer!</p>]]></content:encoded>
			<enclosure length="87600610" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/thejimmydoreshow/TJDS_20220708_Podcast.mp3?dest-id=19460"/>
			<itunes:duration>01:00:50</itunes:duration>
			<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
			<itunes:keywords/>
			<itunes:subtitle><![CDATA[While Democrats continue rigging elections against 3rd parties, Matthew Hoh - U.S. Senate candidate to represent North Carolina on the Green Party ticket - is fighting back to claim his rightfully earned place on the ballot. Plus, a segment revealing...]]></itunes:subtitle>
			<itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
		<itunes:summary>While Democrats continue rigging elections against 3rd parties, Matthew Hoh - U.S. Senate candidate to represent North Carolina on the Green Party ticket - is fighting back to claim his rightfully earned place on the ballot. Plus, a segment revealing how Democrats fund radical Republicans. Featuring Stef Zamorano, Kurt Metzger, Matthew Hoh and Mike MacRae! And phone calls from Vince Vaughn and Willem the Dutch Farmer!</itunes:summary></item>
		<item>
			<title>Trump Never “Lunged” For Steering Wheel Say Secret Service</title>
			<itunes:title>Trump Never “Lunged” For Steering Wheel Say Secret Service</itunes:title>
			<pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2022 05:30:08 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false"><![CDATA[b8bda576-6a23-4a52-817f-5397599b86fe]]></guid>
			<link><![CDATA[https://thejimmydoreshow.libsyn.com/trump-never-lunged-for-steering-wheel-say-secret-service]]></link>
			<itunes:image href="https://ssl-static.libsyn.com/p/assets/2/7/8/d/278dabe3e556cd165f2e77a3093c12a1/Screen_Shot_2022-06-30_at_1.08.51_PM.png"/>
			<description><![CDATA[<div class= "product-hero-desc product-hero-desc--spacer-bottom-large"> <section class= "section section--no-padding-bottom product-hero-desc__section"> <p class="p1">Despite the testimony of former White House aide, Cassidy Hutchinson, the Secret Service says Trump never "lunged" for the steering wheel on January 6. </p> <p dir="ltr" data-test-bidi="">Plus a segment on a secret and undercover force created by the Pentagon and tasked with manipulating and influencing social media sites in order to spread Amercian propaganda.</p> <p dir="ltr" data-test-bidi="">Featuring Stef Zamorano, Kurt Metzger, Anya Parampil and Mike MacRae! And phone calls from Al Pacino and Hillary Supporter!</p> </section> </div>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[  <p class="p1">Despite the testimony of former White House aide, Cassidy Hutchinson, the Secret Service says Trump never "lunged" for the steering wheel on January 6. </p> <p dir="ltr" data-test-bidi="">Plus a segment on a secret and undercover force created by the Pentagon and tasked with manipulating and influencing social media sites in order to spread Amercian propaganda.</p> <p dir="ltr" data-test-bidi="">Featuring Stef Zamorano, Kurt Metzger, Anya Parampil and Mike MacRae! And phone calls from Al Pacino and Hillary Supporter!</p>  ]]></content:encoded>
			<enclosure length="92665648" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/thejimmydoreshow/TJDS_20220701_Podcast.mp3?dest-id=19460"/>
			<itunes:duration>01:04:21</itunes:duration>
			<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
			<itunes:keywords/>
			<itunes:subtitle><![CDATA[Despite the testimony of former White House aide, Cassidy Hutchinson, the Secret Service says Trump never "lunged" for the steering wheel on January 6.  Plus a segment on a secret and undercover force created by the Pentagon and tasked with...]]></itunes:subtitle>
			<itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
		<itunes:summary>Despite the testimony of former White House aide, Cassidy Hutchinson, the Secret Service says Trump never "lunged" for the steering wheel on January 6.  Plus a segment on a secret and undercover force created by the Pentagon and tasked with manipulating and influencing social media sites in order to spread Amercian propaganda. Featuring Stef Zamorano, Kurt Metzger, Anya Parampil and Mike MacRae! And phone calls from Al Pacino and Hillary Supporter!</itunes:summary></item>
		<item>
			<title>Lockdowns Actually Saved SHOCKINGLY Few Lives – Fake Fact Checkers DEBUNKED</title>
			<itunes:title>Lockdowns Actually Saved SHOCKINGLY Few Lives – Fake Fact Checkers DEBUNKED</itunes:title>
			<pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2022 05:30:32 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false"><![CDATA[2e147352-3404-4151-b81d-63adc6aed6db]]></guid>
			<link><![CDATA[https://thejimmydoreshow.libsyn.com/lockdowns-actually-saved-shockingly-few-lives-fake-fact-checkers-debunked]]></link>
			<itunes:image href="https://ssl-static.libsyn.com/p/assets/1/d/b/6/1db633ef1f1c365a5f2e77a3093c12a1/Screen_Shot_2022-06-23_at_3.33.42_PM.png"/>
			<description><![CDATA[<p>When Johns Hopkins Economics Professor Steve Hanke released a metastudy indicating that COVID lockdowns had only saved a small number of lives compared to the astronomical figure that had been reported by an Imperial College study, the backlash was quick and fevered. The Imperial College researchers, along with "fact checkers" like Snopes sought to refute the claims Hanke and his co-authors made. Jimmy interviews Professor Hanke about the failure of lockdowns and the backlash his study received.<br /> <br /> Plus a segment on Krystal Ball's dismantling of Bill Maher over widespread misinformation about the causes of runaway inflation.<br /> <br /> Also featuring Stef Zamorano, Kurt Metzger and Mike MacRae! And phone calls from Joe Biden and Vince Vaughn!</p>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>When Johns Hopkins Economics Professor Steve Hanke released a metastudy indicating that COVID lockdowns had only saved a small number of lives compared to the astronomical figure that had been reported by an Imperial College study, the backlash was quick and fevered. The Imperial College researchers, along with "fact checkers" like Snopes sought to refute the claims Hanke and his co-authors made. Jimmy interviews Professor Hanke about the failure of lockdowns and the backlash his study received.  Plus a segment on Krystal Ball's dismantling of Bill Maher over widespread misinformation about the causes of runaway inflation.  Also featuring Stef Zamorano, Kurt Metzger and Mike MacRae! And phone calls from Joe Biden and Vince Vaughn!</p>]]></content:encoded>
			<enclosure length="64292908" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/thejimmydoreshow/TJDS_20220624_Podcast_-_12.23.21_7.19_PM_-_62322_3.23_PM.mp3?dest-id=19460"/>
			<itunes:duration>01:06:59</itunes:duration>
			<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
			<itunes:keywords/>
			<itunes:subtitle><![CDATA[When Johns Hopkins Economics Professor Steve Hanke released a metastudy indicating that COVID lockdowns had only saved a small number of lives compared to the astronomical figure that had been reported by an Imperial College study, the backlash was...]]></itunes:subtitle>
			<itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
		<itunes:summary>When Johns Hopkins Economics Professor Steve Hanke released a metastudy indicating that COVID lockdowns had only saved a small number of lives compared to the astronomical figure that had been reported by an Imperial College study, the backlash was quick and fevered. The Imperial College researchers, along with "fact checkers" like Snopes sought to refute the claims Hanke and his co-authors made. Jimmy interviews Professor Hanke about the failure of lockdowns and the backlash his study received. Plus a segment on Krystal Ball's dismantling of Bill Maher over widespread misinformation about the causes of runaway inflation. Also featuring Stef Zamorano, Kurt Metzger and Mike MacRae! And phone calls from Joe Biden and Vince Vaughn!</itunes:summary></item>
		<item>
			<title>Leaked Emails Prove U.K. Gov’t Ordered Censoring Of YouTube Videos</title>
			<itunes:title>Leaked Emails Prove U.K. Gov’t Ordered Censoring Of YouTube Videos</itunes:title>
			<pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2022 05:36:09 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false"><![CDATA[920f3552-7ee5-493a-a3f0-567fdf8638e1]]></guid>
			<link><![CDATA[https://thejimmydoreshow.libsyn.com/leaked-emails-prove-uk-govt-ordered-censoring-of-youtube-videos]]></link>
			<itunes:image href="https://ssl-static.libsyn.com/p/assets/9/0/4/6/904645ddd3dfb8a827a2322813b393ee/Screen_Shot_2022-06-16_at_12.40.34_PM.png"/>
			<description><![CDATA[<p>Leaked emails have revealed the extent to which celebrity British journalist Paul Mason has been colluding with members of U.K. intelligence to smear, deplatform and bankrupt left-wing and anti-war journalistic outlets like The Grayzone. Mason has even generated a bizarre “mindmap” connecting Russian psyops to Jeremy Corbyn, the Muslim community, trade unions and black people. Jimmy discusses the bombshell report with The Grayzone's Max Blumenthal and American comedian Kurt Metzger.<br /> <br /> Plus a segment on a Ukraine boxer who celebrated her silver medal by unfolding a neo-Nazi Azov Battalion flag on the medal stand.<br /> <br /> Also featuring Stef Zamorano and Mike MacRae! And phone calls from Alec Baldwin, Kevin Spacey and Joe Biden!</p>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Leaked emails have revealed the extent to which celebrity British journalist Paul Mason has been colluding with members of U.K. intelligence to smear, deplatform and bankrupt left-wing and anti-war journalistic outlets like The Grayzone. Mason has even generated a bizarre “mindmap” connecting Russian psyops to Jeremy Corbyn, the Muslim community, trade unions and black people. Jimmy discusses the bombshell report with The Grayzone's Max Blumenthal and American comedian Kurt Metzger.  Plus a segment on a Ukraine boxer who celebrated her silver medal by unfolding a neo-Nazi Azov Battalion flag on the medal stand.  Also featuring Stef Zamorano and Mike MacRae! And phone calls from Alec Baldwin, Kevin Spacey and Joe Biden!</p>]]></content:encoded>
			<enclosure length="63818715" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/thejimmydoreshow/TJDS_20220617_Podcast_-_61622_12.29_PM.mp3?dest-id=19460"/>
			<itunes:duration>01:06:05</itunes:duration>
			<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
			<itunes:keywords/>
			<itunes:subtitle><![CDATA[Leaked emails have revealed the extent to which celebrity British journalist Paul Mason has been colluding with members of U.K. intelligence to smear, deplatform and bankrupt left-wing and anti-war journalistic outlets like The Grayzone. Mason has...]]></itunes:subtitle>
			<itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
		<itunes:summary>Leaked emails have revealed the extent to which celebrity British journalist Paul Mason has been colluding with members of U.K. intelligence to smear, deplatform and bankrupt left-wing and anti-war journalistic outlets like The Grayzone. Mason has even generated a bizarre “mindmap” connecting Russian psyops to Jeremy Corbyn, the Muslim community, trade unions and black people. Jimmy discusses the bombshell report with The Grayzone's Max Blumenthal and American comedian Kurt Metzger. Plus a segment on a Ukraine boxer who celebrated her silver medal by unfolding a neo-Nazi Azov Battalion flag on the medal stand. Also featuring Stef Zamorano and Mike MacRae! And phone calls from Alec Baldwin, Kevin Spacey and Joe Biden!</itunes:summary></item>
		<item>
			<title>“Epic Clusterf*ck” Unfolds At The Washington Post Following Dave Weigel Retweet</title>
			<itunes:title>“Epic Clusterf*ck” Unfolds At The Washington Post Following Dave Weigel Retweet</itunes:title>
			<pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2022 05:10:16 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false"><![CDATA[fc18bc0f-8ef0-4d56-baf1-03d388e6f45a]]></guid>
			<link><![CDATA[https://thejimmydoreshow.libsyn.com/epic-clusterfck-unfolds-at-the-washington-post-following-dave-weigel-retweet]]></link>
			<itunes:image href="https://ssl-static.libsyn.com/p/assets/e/4/4/3/e443c653d986ce885f2e77a3093c12a1/Screen_Shot_2022-06-09_at_1.22.36_PM.png"/>
			<description><![CDATA[<p>It was the retweet heard round the world — Washington Post reporter Dave Weigel’s ill-advised retweet of a mildly sexist joke that led not only to his suspension without pay, but to a wider conflagration at the Post centered around his fellow reporter, Felicia Sonmez. Jimmy and friends discuss the maelstrom of accusations, recrimination and distinct lack of collegiality on display in the “clusterfuck” underway at the Post.<br /> <br /> Plus a segment on British celebrity reporter Paul Mason's email leak revealing a plot to bring down the anti-war journalists at The Grayzone.<br /> <br /> Also featuring Stef Zamorano, Kurt Metzger, Max Blumenthal and Mike MacRae! And phone calls from Brad Pitt and Joe Biden!</p>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It was the retweet heard round the world — Washington Post reporter Dave Weigel’s ill-advised retweet of a mildly sexist joke that led not only to his suspension without pay, but to a wider conflagration at the Post centered around his fellow reporter, Felicia Sonmez. Jimmy and friends discuss the maelstrom of accusations, recrimination and distinct lack of collegiality on display in the “clusterfuck” underway at the Post.  Plus a segment on British celebrity reporter Paul Mason's email leak revealing a plot to bring down the anti-war journalists at The Grayzone.  Also featuring Stef Zamorano, Kurt Metzger, Max Blumenthal and Mike MacRae! And phone calls from Brad Pitt and Joe Biden!</p>]]></content:encoded>
			<enclosure length="55711456" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/thejimmydoreshow/TJDS_20220610_Podcast_-_6922_1.16_PM.mp3?dest-id=19460"/>
			<itunes:duration>57:51</itunes:duration>
			<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
			<itunes:keywords/>
			<itunes:subtitle><![CDATA[It was the retweet heard round the world — Washington Post reporter Dave Weigel’s ill-advised retweet of a mildly sexist joke that led not only to his suspension without pay, but to a wider conflagration at the Post centered around his fellow...]]></itunes:subtitle>
			<itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
		<itunes:summary>It was the retweet heard round the world — Washington Post reporter Dave Weigel’s ill-advised retweet of a mildly sexist joke that led not only to his suspension without pay, but to a wider conflagration at the Post centered around his fellow reporter, Felicia Sonmez. Jimmy and friends discuss the maelstrom of accusations, recrimination and distinct lack of collegiality on display in the “clusterfuck” underway at the Post. Plus a segment on British celebrity reporter Paul Mason's email leak revealing a plot to bring down the anti-war journalists at The Grayzone. Also featuring Stef Zamorano, Kurt Metzger, Max Blumenthal and Mike MacRae! And phone calls from Brad Pitt and Joe Biden!</itunes:summary></item>
		<item>
			<title>Biden’s “Plan” To Fix Inflation Is Insulting To Your Intelligence</title>
			<itunes:title>Biden’s “Plan” To Fix Inflation Is Insulting To Your Intelligence</itunes:title>
			<pubDate>Fri, 03 Jun 2022 05:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false"><![CDATA[05b48f67-3ec6-4b77-8020-8596f867d9ec]]></guid>
			<link><![CDATA[https://thejimmydoreshow.libsyn.com/bidens-plan-to-fix-inflation-is-insulting-to-your-intelligence]]></link>
			<itunes:image href="https://ssl-static.libsyn.com/p/assets/a/f/d/a/afda83a3b399fb5127a2322813b393ee/Screen_Shot_2022-06-02_at_2.34.59_PM.png"/>
			<description><![CDATA[Joe Biden recently published an opinion piece in the Wall Street Journal detailing his plan, to the extent he has one, to deal with the inflation crisis. What the opinion piece reveals, more than anything else, is that Biden not only has no real conception of what is causing prices to rise, but he also is woefully short on ideas for what to do about the problem.  Jimmy and Professor Richard Wolff discuss the spiraling down of the Biden presidency as prices skyrocket.<br /> <br /> Plus a segment on certain municipalities in the United States ending minor traffic stops to prevent police from escalating conflicts with motorists and possibly killing them.<br /> <br /> Also featuring Stef Zamorano, Kurt Metzger, Jackson Hinkle and Mike MacRae! And phone calls from David Axelrod and Prince Charles!]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[Joe Biden recently published an opinion piece in the Wall Street Journal detailing his plan, to the extent he has one, to deal with the inflation crisis. What the opinion piece reveals, more than anything else, is that Biden not only has no real conception of what is causing prices to rise, but he also is woefully short on ideas for what to do about the problem.  Jimmy and Professor Richard Wolff discuss the spiraling down of the Biden presidency as prices skyrocket.  Plus a segment on certain municipalities in the United States ending minor traffic stops to prevent police from escalating conflicts with motorists and possibly killing them.  Also featuring Stef Zamorano, Kurt Metzger, Jackson Hinkle and Mike MacRae! And phone calls from David Axelrod and Prince Charles!]]></content:encoded>
			<enclosure length="56657068" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/thejimmydoreshow/TJDS_20220603_Podcast_-_6222_11.57_AM.mp3?dest-id=19460"/>
			<itunes:duration>58:47</itunes:duration>
			<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
			<itunes:keywords/>
			<itunes:subtitle><![CDATA[Joe Biden recently published an opinion piece in the Wall Street Journal detailing his plan, to the extent he has one, to deal with the inflation crisis. What the opinion piece reveals, more than anything else, is that Biden not only has no real...]]></itunes:subtitle>
			<itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
		<itunes:summary>Joe Biden recently published an opinion piece in the Wall Street Journal detailing his plan, to the extent he has one, to deal with the inflation crisis. What the opinion piece reveals, more than anything else, is that Biden not only has no real conception of what is causing prices to rise, but he also is woefully short on ideas for what to do about the problem.  Jimmy and Professor Richard Wolff discuss the spiraling down of the Biden presidency as prices skyrocket. Plus a segment on certain municipalities in the United States ending minor traffic stops to prevent police from escalating conflicts with motorists and possibly killing them. Also featuring Stef Zamorano, Kurt Metzger, Jackson Hinkle and Mike MacRae! And phone calls from David Axelrod and Prince Charles!</itunes:summary></item>
		<item>
			<title>The End of the American Empire Is Here</title>
			<itunes:title>The End of the American Empire Is Here</itunes:title>
			<pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2022 05:11:30 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false"><![CDATA[4fab3b17-c13b-4309-a7fa-0375c329b296]]></guid>
			<link><![CDATA[https://thejimmydoreshow.libsyn.com/the-end-of-the-american-empire-is-here]]></link>
			<itunes:image href="https://ssl-static.libsyn.com/p/assets/5/7/b/9/57b96503ac5150595f2e77a3093c12a1/Screen_Shot_2022-05-26_at_12.10.24_PM.png"/>
			<description><![CDATA[<p>While the US Government continues to write blank checks for the war in Ukraine and bloats the Pentagon budget to an obscene degree, the collapse at home continues as homelessness, inflation, poverty, addiction and other serious problems grow worse every day. Jimmy and Pulitzer Prize-winning journalist Chris Hedges discuss the rapidly approaching collapse of US hegemony across the globe.<br /> <br /> Plus a segment on Henry Kissinger's controversial recent acknowledgment that Ukraine will have to trade territory for peace.<br /> <br /> Also featuring Stef Zamorano, Kurt Metzger, and Mike MacRae! And phone calls from Barack Obama and George Bush, and Rick Perry!</p>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>While the US Government continues to write blank checks for the war in Ukraine and bloats the Pentagon budget to an obscene degree, the collapse at home continues as homelessness, inflation, poverty, addiction and other serious problems grow worse every day. Jimmy and Pulitzer Prize-winning journalist Chris Hedges discuss the rapidly approaching collapse of US hegemony across the globe.  Plus a segment on Henry Kissinger's controversial recent acknowledgment that Ukraine will have to trade territory for peace.  Also featuring Stef Zamorano, Kurt Metzger, and Mike MacRae! And phone calls from Barack Obama and George Bush, and Rick Perry!</p>]]></content:encoded>
			<enclosure length="61203587" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/thejimmydoreshow/TJDS_20220527_Podcast_-_52622_12.08_PM.mp3?dest-id=19460"/>
			<itunes:duration>01:03:32</itunes:duration>
			<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
			<itunes:keywords/>
			<itunes:subtitle><![CDATA[While the US Government continues to write blank checks for the war in Ukraine and bloats the Pentagon budget to an obscene degree, the collapse at home continues as homelessness, inflation, poverty, addiction and other serious problems grow worse...]]></itunes:subtitle>
			<itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
		<itunes:summary>While the US Government continues to write blank checks for the war in Ukraine and bloats the Pentagon budget to an obscene degree, the collapse at home continues as homelessness, inflation, poverty, addiction and other serious problems grow worse every day. Jimmy and Pulitzer Prize-winning journalist Chris Hedges discuss the rapidly approaching collapse of US hegemony across the globe. Plus a segment on Henry Kissinger's controversial recent acknowledgment that Ukraine will have to trade territory for peace. Also featuring Stef Zamorano, Kurt Metzger, and Mike MacRae! And phone calls from Barack Obama and George Bush, and Rick Perry!</itunes:summary></item>
		<item>
			<title>Washington Post Reporter Freaks Out Over Disinformation Board’s Closure</title>
			<itunes:title>Washington Post Reporter Freaks Out Over Disinformation Board’s Closure</itunes:title>
			<pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2022 05:03:03 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false"><![CDATA[7ba98ea2-0e54-412b-afdd-31ebe71ffe13]]></guid>
			<link><![CDATA[https://thejimmydoreshow.libsyn.com/washington-post-reporter-freaks-out-over-disinformation-boards-closure]]></link>
			<itunes:image href="https://ssl-static.libsyn.com/p/assets/4/2/f/5/42f541846dbaebfd40be95ea3302a6a1/Screen_Shot_2022-05-19_at_3.03.47_PM.png"/>
			<description><![CDATA[<p>Washington Post reporter/mainstream media crybully Taylor Lorenz is upset at the announcement that the Department of Homeland Security would be shelving the so-called “Disinformation Governance Board” intended to police online speech. <br /> <br /> Plus a segment on former Fox News political correspondent Carl Cameron calling for current Fox News hosts to be imprisoned for their "dangerous" speech.<br /> <br /> Also featuring Stef Zamorano, Kurt Metzger, Max Blumenthal and Mike MacRae! And phone calls from Chuck Schumer and Al Pacino!</p>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Washington Post reporter/mainstream media crybully Taylor Lorenz is upset at the announcement that the Department of Homeland Security would be shelving the so-called “Disinformation Governance Board” intended to police online speech.   Plus a segment on former Fox News political correspondent Carl Cameron calling for current Fox News hosts to be imprisoned for their "dangerous" speech.  Also featuring Stef Zamorano, Kurt Metzger, Max Blumenthal and Mike MacRae! And phone calls from Chuck Schumer and Al Pacino!</p>]]></content:encoded>
			<enclosure length="64478840" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/thejimmydoreshow/TJDS_20220520_Podcast_-_51922_2.59_PM.mp3?dest-id=19460"/>
			<itunes:duration>01:06:57</itunes:duration>
			<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
			<itunes:keywords/>
			<itunes:subtitle><![CDATA[Washington Post reporter/mainstream media crybully Taylor Lorenz is upset at the announcement that the Department of Homeland Security would be shelving the so-called “Disinformation Governance Board” intended to police online speech.   Plus...]]></itunes:subtitle>
			<itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
		<itunes:summary>Washington Post reporter/mainstream media crybully Taylor Lorenz is upset at the announcement that the Department of Homeland Security would be shelving the so-called “Disinformation Governance Board” intended to police online speech.  Plus a segment on former Fox News political correspondent Carl Cameron calling for current Fox News hosts to be imprisoned for their "dangerous" speech. Also featuring Stef Zamorano, Kurt Metzger, Max Blumenthal and Mike MacRae! And phone calls from Chuck Schumer and Al Pacino!</itunes:summary></item>
		<item>
			<title>Trevor Noah Kisses Up To The WHCD Crowd</title>
			<itunes:title>Trevor Noah Kisses Up To The WHCD Crowd</itunes:title>
			<pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 06:20:34 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false"><![CDATA[1d263015-3027-4c05-bb57-124745e67327]]></guid>
			<link><![CDATA[https://thejimmydoreshow.libsyn.com/trevor-noah-kisses-up-to-the-whcd-crowd]]></link>
			<itunes:image href="https://ssl-static.libsyn.com/p/assets/8/8/3/1/88314777ab1cd15e88c4a68c3ddbc4f2/Screen_Shot_2022-05-05_at_4.02.17_PM.png"/>
			<description><![CDATA[<p>The Daily Show's Trevor Noah headlined this year's White House Correspondents Dinner, and the South African-born comedian delivered what he was paid for -- some mild criticism of the luminaries in the room and then an epic tongue bath for the fourth estate and all the alleged "journalism" the media bigwigs in the room produce.<br /> <br /> Plus a segment on Dave Chappelle's recent attack while on stage at the Hollywood Bowl.<br /> <br /> Also featuring Stef Zamorano, Kurt Metzger and Mike MacRae! And phone calls from Vince Vaughn and CNN stars Jake Tapper and Jeffrey Toobin!</p>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Daily Show's Trevor Noah headlined this year's White House Correspondents Dinner, and the South African-born comedian delivered what he was paid for -- some mild criticism of the luminaries in the room and then an epic tongue bath for the fourth estate and all the alleged "journalism" the media bigwigs in the room produce.  Plus a segment on Dave Chappelle's recent attack while on stage at the Hollywood Bowl.  Also featuring Stef Zamorano, Kurt Metzger and Mike MacRae! And phone calls from Vince Vaughn and CNN stars Jake Tapper and Jeffrey Toobin!</p>]]></content:encoded>
			<enclosure length="65705404" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/thejimmydoreshow/TJDS_20220506_Podcast_-_5522_2.51_PM.mp3?dest-id=19460"/>
			<itunes:duration>01:08:12</itunes:duration>
			<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
			<itunes:keywords/>
			<itunes:subtitle><![CDATA[The Daily Show's Trevor Noah headlined this year's White House Correspondents Dinner, and the South African-born comedian delivered what he was paid for -- some mild criticism of the luminaries in the room and then an epic tongue bath for the fourth...]]></itunes:subtitle>
			<itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
		<itunes:summary>The Daily Show's Trevor Noah headlined this year's White House Correspondents Dinner, and the South African-born comedian delivered what he was paid for -- some mild criticism of the luminaries in the room and then an epic tongue bath for the fourth estate and all the alleged "journalism" the media bigwigs in the room produce. Plus a segment on Dave Chappelle's recent attack while on stage at the Hollywood Bowl. Also featuring Stef Zamorano, Kurt Metzger and Mike MacRae! And phone calls from Vince Vaughn and CNN stars Jake Tapper and Jeffrey Toobin!</itunes:summary></item>
		<item>
			<title>MSNBC Freaks Out About Elon Musk Buying Twitter</title>
			<itunes:title>MSNBC Freaks Out About Elon Musk Buying Twitter</itunes:title>
			<pubDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2022 04:49:43 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false"><![CDATA[103c07e0-488d-4f26-9f5a-5116237b787a]]></guid>
			<link><![CDATA[https://thejimmydoreshow.libsyn.com/msnbc-freaks-out-about-elon-musk-buying-twitter]]></link>
			<itunes:image href="https://ssl-static.libsyn.com/p/assets/f/3/1/7/f31745b55aa7ef9816c3140a3186d450/Screen_Shot_2022-04-28_at_8.56.36_PM.png"/>
			<description><![CDATA[<p>On a recent episode of her MSNBC show "The ReidOut" Joy-Ann Reid and guest Anand Giridiharadis expressed dismay at the prospect of an Elon Musk-owned Twitter and the thought that unsavories might be welcomed back on the platform just to make trouble for the "regular" people who typically interact there. Jimmy and guest Max Blumenthal discuss the freakout over Musk underway at a number of MSNBC shows.<br /> <br /> Plus a segment on candidate Nina Turner's excessive response to a critical tweet from Jimmy. <br /> <br /> Also featuring Stef Zamorano, Sabby Sabs and Mike MacRae! And phone calls from Chuck Schumer and Joe Biden!</p>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>On a recent episode of her MSNBC show "The ReidOut" Joy-Ann Reid and guest Anand Giridiharadis expressed dismay at the prospect of an Elon Musk-owned Twitter and the thought that unsavories might be welcomed back on the platform just to make trouble for the "regular" people who typically interact there. Jimmy and guest Max Blumenthal discuss the freakout over Musk underway at a number of MSNBC shows.  Plus a segment on candidate Nina Turner's excessive response to a critical tweet from Jimmy.   Also featuring Stef Zamorano, Sabby Sabs and Mike MacRae! And phone calls from Chuck Schumer and Joe Biden!</p>]]></content:encoded>
			<enclosure length="57238094" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/thejimmydoreshow/TJDS_20220429_Podcast_-_42822_6.56_PM.mp3?dest-id=19460"/>
			<itunes:duration>59:24</itunes:duration>
			<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
			<itunes:keywords/>
			<itunes:subtitle><![CDATA[On a recent episode of her MSNBC show "The ReidOut" Joy-Ann Reid and guest Anand Giridiharadis expressed dismay at the prospect of an Elon Musk-owned Twitter and the thought that unsavories might be welcomed back on the platform just to make trouble...]]></itunes:subtitle>
			<itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
		<itunes:summary>On a recent episode of her MSNBC show "The ReidOut" Joy-Ann Reid and guest Anand Giridiharadis expressed dismay at the prospect of an Elon Musk-owned Twitter and the thought that unsavories might be welcomed back on the platform just to make trouble for the "regular" people who typically interact there. Jimmy and guest Max Blumenthal discuss the freakout over Musk underway at a number of MSNBC shows. Plus a segment on candidate Nina Turner's excessive response to a critical tweet from Jimmy.  Also featuring Stef Zamorano, Sabby Sabs and Mike MacRae! And phone calls from Chuck Schumer and Joe Biden!</itunes:summary></item>
		<item>
			<title>Amazon Union Organizer Hits Back At Critics!</title>
			<itunes:title>Amazon Union Organizer Hits Back At Critics!</itunes:title>
			<pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2022 05:04:16 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false"><![CDATA[e6aa1148-e2c6-4fae-969c-0a38a977ce91]]></guid>
			<link><![CDATA[https://thejimmydoreshow.libsyn.com/amazon-union-organizer-hits-back-at-critics]]></link>
			<itunes:image href="https://ssl-static.libsyn.com/p/assets/5/0/e/9/50e9d4184b9cbbc716c3140a3186d450/Screen_Shot_2022-04-21_at_2.09.45_PM.png"/>
			<description><![CDATA[<p>Christian Smalls, the fired Amazon worker who beat the odds to successfully win a union vote at the company's Staten Island fulfillment center, spoke to Jimmy about why his efforts succeeded, what it takes to organize workers from diverse backgrounds and his recent appearance on Tucker Carlson's show.<br /> <br /> Plus segments on the plummeting price of the first ever Twitter tweet NFT and Nina Turner's snubbing by the Congressional Progressive Caucus.<br /> <br /> Also featuring Stef Zamorano, Kurt Metzger and Mike MacRae! And a phone calls from Al Pacino!</p>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Christian Smalls, the fired Amazon worker who beat the odds to successfully win a union vote at the company's Staten Island fulfillment center, spoke to Jimmy about why his efforts succeeded, what it takes to organize workers from diverse backgrounds and his recent appearance on Tucker Carlson's show.  Plus segments on the plummeting price of the first ever Twitter tweet NFT and Nina Turner's snubbing by the Congressional Progressive Caucus.  Also featuring Stef Zamorano, Kurt Metzger and Mike MacRae! And a phone calls from Al Pacino!</p>]]></content:encoded>
			<enclosure length="54714937" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/thejimmydoreshow/TJDS_20220422_Podcast_-_42122_1.35_PM.mp3?dest-id=19460"/>
			<itunes:duration>56:42</itunes:duration>
			<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
			<itunes:keywords/>
			<itunes:subtitle><![CDATA[Christian Smalls, the fired Amazon worker who beat the odds to successfully win a union vote at the company's Staten Island fulfillment center, spoke to Jimmy about why his efforts succeeded, what it takes to organize workers from diverse backgrounds...]]></itunes:subtitle>
			<itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
		<itunes:summary>Christian Smalls, the fired Amazon worker who beat the odds to successfully win a union vote at the company's Staten Island fulfillment center, spoke to Jimmy about why his efforts succeeded, what it takes to organize workers from diverse backgrounds and his recent appearance on Tucker Carlson's show. Plus segments on the plummeting price of the first ever Twitter tweet NFT and Nina Turner's snubbing by the Congressional Progressive Caucus. Also featuring Stef Zamorano, Kurt Metzger and Mike MacRae! And a phone calls from Al Pacino!</itunes:summary></item>
		<item>
			<title>FBI Foils Its Own Plot To Kidnap MI Gov Whitmer</title>
			<itunes:title>FBI Foils Its Own Plot To Kidnap MI Gov Whitmer</itunes:title>
			<pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2022 05:00:57 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false"><![CDATA[75cd721a-ff3e-4227-a6a7-2cd5c9bc9ae3]]></guid>
			<link><![CDATA[https://thejimmydoreshow.libsyn.com/fbi-foils-its-own-plot-to-kidnap-mi-gov-whitmer]]></link>
			<itunes:image href="https://ssl-static.libsyn.com/p/assets/4/3/8/f/438f7fa23e9a5a5fe5bbc093207a2619/Screen_Shot_2022-04-14_at_9.34.18_PM.png"/>
			<description><![CDATA[<p>Two of the defendents involved in the alleged plot to kidnap Michigan Governor Gretchen Whitmer have been acquitted after a jury heard testimony indicating that the FBI and its informants entrapped the two into participating in the plot, and that the FBI was much more instrumental in planning the kidnapping than the accused. Jimmy and The Grayzone's Max Blumenthal discuss the FBI's practice of enticing marginal individuals into terrorist schemes, then blowing their own horn after "thwarting" the plots.<br /> <br /> Plus segments on the New York Times using the recent subway shooting to push pro-cop propaganda and the not-so surprising story of California cities funneling COVID relief money into police departments.<br /> <br /> Also featuring Stef Zamorano, Anya Parampil and Mike MacRae! And phone calls from Andrew Cuomo and Alec Baldwin!</p>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Two of the defendents involved in the alleged plot to kidnap Michigan Governor Gretchen Whitmer have been acquitted after a jury heard testimony indicating that the FBI and its informants entrapped the two into participating in the plot, and that the FBI was much more instrumental in planning the kidnapping than the accused. Jimmy and The Grayzone's Max Blumenthal discuss the FBI's practice of enticing marginal individuals into terrorist schemes, then blowing their own horn after "thwarting" the plots.  Plus segments on the New York Times using the recent subway shooting to push pro-cop propaganda and the not-so surprising story of California cities funneling COVID relief money into police departments.  Also featuring Stef Zamorano, Anya Parampil and Mike MacRae! And phone calls from Andrew Cuomo and Alec Baldwin!</p>]]></content:encoded>
			<enclosure length="64335292" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/thejimmydoreshow/TJDS_20220415_Podcast_-_41422_7.09_PM.mp3?dest-id=19460"/>
			<itunes:duration>01:06:49</itunes:duration>
			<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
			<itunes:keywords/>
			<itunes:subtitle><![CDATA[Two of the defendents involved in the alleged plot to kidnap Michigan Governor Gretchen Whitmer have been acquitted after a jury heard testimony indicating that the FBI and its informants entrapped the two into participating in the plot, and that the...]]></itunes:subtitle>
			<itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
		<itunes:summary>Two of the defendents involved in the alleged plot to kidnap Michigan Governor Gretchen Whitmer have been acquitted after a jury heard testimony indicating that the FBI and its informants entrapped the two into participating in the plot, and that the FBI was much more instrumental in planning the kidnapping than the accused. Jimmy and The Grayzone's Max Blumenthal discuss the FBI's practice of enticing marginal individuals into terrorist schemes, then blowing their own horn after "thwarting" the plots. Plus segments on the New York Times using the recent subway shooting to push pro-cop propaganda and the not-so surprising story of California cities funneling COVID relief money into police departments. Also featuring Stef Zamorano, Anya Parampil and Mike MacRae! And phone calls from Andrew Cuomo and Alec Baldwin!</itunes:summary></item>
		<item>
			<title>Authoritarian Left EXPOSED By Covid!</title>
			<itunes:title>Authoritarian Left EXPOSED By Covid!</itunes:title>
			<pubDate>Fri, 08 Apr 2022 03:03:48 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false"><![CDATA[f223066c-945f-4122-9c83-0fb40bebcd27]]></guid>
			<link><![CDATA[https://thejimmydoreshow.libsyn.com/authoritarian-left-exposed-by-covid]]></link>
			<itunes:image href="https://ssl-static.libsyn.com/p/assets/4/5/a/6/45a6289b846ec1755f2e77a3093c12a1/Screen_Shot_2022-04-07_at_12.09.23_PM.png"/>
			<description><![CDATA[<p>Jimmy speaks with John Jay College economics professor Christian Parenti about all the ways the coronavirus pandemic has revealed the authoritarian streak in so-called "leftists" in the United States, whether supporting mandates and vaccine passports or paying fealty to corrupt government agencies and the rapacious pharmaceutical industry.<br /> <br /> Plus a segment on how Ukrainian President Zelenskyy could have avoided war but chose to risk a Russian invasion instead.<br /> <br /> Also featuring Stef Zamorano, Aaron Maté and Mike MacRae! And phone calls from Vince Vaughn and David Axelrod!</p>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Jimmy speaks with John Jay College economics professor Christian Parenti about all the ways the coronavirus pandemic has revealed the authoritarian streak in so-called "leftists" in the United States, whether supporting mandates and vaccine passports or paying fealty to corrupt government agencies and the rapacious pharmaceutical industry.  Plus a segment on how Ukrainian President Zelenskyy could have avoided war but chose to risk a Russian invasion instead.  Also featuring Stef Zamorano, Aaron Maté and Mike MacRae! And phone calls from Vince Vaughn and David Axelrod!</p>]]></content:encoded>
			<enclosure length="65916348" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/thejimmydoreshow/TJDS_20220408_Podcast_-_4722_11.55_AM.mp3?dest-id=19460"/>
			<itunes:duration>01:08:12</itunes:duration>
			<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
			<itunes:keywords/>
			<itunes:subtitle><![CDATA[Jimmy speaks with John Jay College economics professor Christian Parenti about all the ways the coronavirus pandemic has revealed the authoritarian streak in so-called "leftists" in the United States, whether supporting mandates and vaccine passports...]]></itunes:subtitle>
			<itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
		<itunes:summary>Jimmy speaks with John Jay College economics professor Christian Parenti about all the ways the coronavirus pandemic has revealed the authoritarian streak in so-called "leftists" in the United States, whether supporting mandates and vaccine passports or paying fealty to corrupt government agencies and the rapacious pharmaceutical industry. Plus a segment on how Ukrainian President Zelenskyy could have avoided war but chose to risk a Russian invasion instead. Also featuring Stef Zamorano, Aaron Maté and Mike MacRae! And phone calls from Vince Vaughn and David Axelrod!</itunes:summary></item>
		<item>
			<title>Censored! Journalist Chris Hedges Erased From YouTube!</title>
			<itunes:title>Censored! Journalist Chris Hedges Erased From YouTube!</itunes:title>
			<pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 03:54:06 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false"><![CDATA[99de4049-62f7-4c9c-a8a5-cea311834787]]></guid>
			<link><![CDATA[https://thejimmydoreshow.libsyn.com/censored-journalist-chris-hedges-erased-from-youtube]]></link>
			<itunes:image href="https://ssl-static.libsyn.com/p/assets/b/0/d/e/b0de92e2253c00f4e5bbc093207a2619/Screen_Shot_2022-03-31_at_6.55.42_PM.png"/>
			<description><![CDATA[<p>Award-winning journalist and bestselling author Chris Hedges talks to Jimmy about his effective silencing by YouTube, with six years’ worth of Hedges’ show, ​​”On Contact,” deleted from the platform simply because the program appeared on the Russian-affiliated network RT. As a result, hundreds of episodes featuring interviews with a wide range of guests, the vast majority of which had nothing to do with Russia, have been removed from public view.</p> <p>Plus a segment on the curious case of the Anti-Defamation League downplaying concerns about the neo-Nazi Azov Battalion in Ukraine.<br /> <br /> Also featuring Stef Zamorano, Howard Skora and Mike MacRae! And phone calls from Al Pacino and Joe Biden!</p>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Award-winning journalist and bestselling author Chris Hedges talks to Jimmy about his effective silencing by YouTube, with six years’ worth of Hedges’ show, ​​”On Contact,” deleted from the platform simply because the program appeared on the Russian-affiliated network RT. As a result, hundreds of episodes featuring interviews with a wide range of guests, the vast majority of which had nothing to do with Russia, have been removed from public view.</p> <p>Plus a segment on the curious case of the Anti-Defamation League downplaying concerns about the neo-Nazi Azov Battalion in Ukraine.  Also featuring Stef Zamorano, Howard Skora and Mike MacRae! And phone calls from Al Pacino and Joe Biden!</p>]]></content:encoded>
			<enclosure length="60285894" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/thejimmydoreshow/TJDS_20220401_Podcast_-_33122_6.58_PM.mp3?dest-id=19460"/>
			<itunes:duration>01:02:37</itunes:duration>
			<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
			<itunes:keywords/>
			<itunes:subtitle><![CDATA[Award-winning journalist and bestselling author Chris Hedges talks to Jimmy about his effective silencing by YouTube, with six years’ worth of Hedges’ show, ​​”On Contact,” deleted from the platform simply because the program appeared on...]]></itunes:subtitle>
			<itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
		<itunes:summary>Award-winning journalist and bestselling author Chris Hedges talks to Jimmy about his effective silencing by YouTube, with six years’ worth of Hedges’ show, ​​”On Contact,” deleted from the platform simply because the program appeared on the Russian-affiliated network RT. As a result, hundreds of episodes featuring interviews with a wide range of guests, the vast majority of which had nothing to do with Russia, have been removed from public view. Plus a segment on the curious case of the Anti-Defamation League downplaying concerns about the neo-Nazi Azov Battalion in Ukraine. Also featuring Stef Zamorano, Howard Skora and Mike MacRae! And phone calls from Al Pacino and Joe Biden!</itunes:summary></item>
		<item>
			<title>Twitter Bans the Babylon Bee Over Hacky Trans Joke</title>
			<itunes:title>Twitter Bans the Babylon Bee Over Hacky Trans Joke</itunes:title>
			<pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2022 19:25:22 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false"><![CDATA[a8522ac4-4cff-4808-ba1c-1c830db25c67]]></guid>
			<link><![CDATA[https://thejimmydoreshow.libsyn.com/twitter-bans-the-babylon-bee-over-hacky-trans-joke]]></link>
			<itunes:image href="https://ssl-static.libsyn.com/p/assets/3/3/e/3/33e32e37cca2369216c3140a3186d450/Screen_Shot_2022-03-25_at_12.18.35_PM.png"/>
			<description><![CDATA[<p class="p1">Those Twitter censors are at it again, this time suspending the account belonging to the conservative satirical site The Babylon Bee, over a tweet misgendering trans Health Secretary Rachel Levine as a man.<span class= "Apple-converted-space"> </span></p> <p class="p1">Plus segments detailing the blood on the US and NATO’s hands over Ukraine, an obnoxious CBS host berating the Chinese ambassador, Ukrainian president Zelensky cracking down on opposition parties and Jake Tapper floating the possibility of a false flag chemical attack in Ukraine.</p> <p class="p1">Also featuring Stef Zamorano and Kurt Metzger!</p>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p class="p1">Those Twitter censors are at it again, this time suspending the account belonging to the conservative satirical site The Babylon Bee, over a tweet misgendering trans Health Secretary Rachel Levine as a man. </p> <p class="p1">Plus segments detailing the blood on the US and NATO’s hands over Ukraine, an obnoxious CBS host berating the Chinese ambassador, Ukrainian president Zelensky cracking down on opposition parties and Jake Tapper floating the possibility of a false flag chemical attack in Ukraine.</p> <p class="p1">Also featuring Stef Zamorano and Kurt Metzger!</p>]]></content:encoded>
			<enclosure length="59689237" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/thejimmydoreshow/TJDS_20220325_Podcast_-_32522_12.08_PM.mp3?dest-id=19460"/>
			<itunes:duration>01:01:59</itunes:duration>
			<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
			<itunes:keywords/>
			<itunes:subtitle><![CDATA[Those Twitter censors are at it again, this time suspending the account belonging to the conservative satirical site The Babylon Bee, over a tweet misgendering trans Health Secretary Rachel Levine as a man.  Plus segments detailing the blood on...]]></itunes:subtitle>
			<itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
		<itunes:summary>Those Twitter censors are at it again, this time suspending the account belonging to the conservative satirical site The Babylon Bee, over a tweet misgendering trans Health Secretary Rachel Levine as a man.  Plus segments detailing the blood on the US and NATO’s hands over Ukraine, an obnoxious CBS host berating the Chinese ambassador, Ukrainian president Zelensky cracking down on opposition parties and Jake Tapper floating the possibility of a false flag chemical attack in Ukraine. Also featuring Stef Zamorano and Kurt Metzger!</itunes:summary></item>
		<item>
			<title>"The View" Hosts Spew McCarthyite Propaganda</title>
			<itunes:title>"The View" Hosts Spew McCarthyite Propaganda</itunes:title>
			<pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2022 05:55:29 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false"><![CDATA[6b4bf7f7-ee23-4304-974c-b9aa242caca4]]></guid>
			<link><![CDATA[https://thejimmydoreshow.libsyn.com/the-view-hosts-spew-mccarthyite-propaganda]]></link>
			<itunes:image href="https://ssl-static.libsyn.com/p/assets/e/5/b/3/e5b397af9625d96fa04421dee9605cbd/Screen_Shot_2022-03-17_at_10.46.01_PM.png"/>
			<description><![CDATA[<p dir="ltr" data-test-bidi="">The View's Whoopi Goldberg, Joy Behar, Ana Navarro and Sunny Hostin dedicated a full segment to calling Ukraine war critics Tulsi Gabbard and Tucker Carlson as traitors who should be investigated and possibly arrested for questioning the dominant media and government narrative about the conflict.</p> <p dir="ltr" data-test-bidi="">Plus a segment on mainstream journalists' efforts to smear actor, comedian and podcaster Russell Brand for allegedly spreading conspiracies and misinformation on his way to becoming "The next Joe Rogan."<br /> <br /> Also featuring Stef Zamorano, Max Blumenthal, Kurt Metzger and Mike MacRae! And phone calls from Al Pacino and Bernie Sanders!</p>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="ltr" data-test-bidi="">The View's Whoopi Goldberg, Joy Behar, Ana Navarro and Sunny Hostin dedicated a full segment to calling Ukraine war critics Tulsi Gabbard and Tucker Carlson as traitors who should be investigated and possibly arrested for questioning the dominant media and government narrative about the conflict.</p> <p dir="ltr" data-test-bidi="">Plus a segment on mainstream journalists' efforts to smear actor, comedian and podcaster Russell Brand for allegedly spreading conspiracies and misinformation on his way to becoming "The next Joe Rogan."  Also featuring Stef Zamorano, Max Blumenthal, Kurt Metzger and Mike MacRae! And phone calls from Al Pacino and Bernie Sanders!</p>]]></content:encoded>
			<enclosure length="75084346" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/thejimmydoreshow/TJDS_20220318_Podcast_-_31722_8.50_PM.mp3?dest-id=19460"/>
			<itunes:duration>01:17:47</itunes:duration>
			<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
			<itunes:keywords/>
			<itunes:subtitle><![CDATA[The View's Whoopi Goldberg, Joy Behar, Ana Navarro and Sunny Hostin dedicated a full segment to calling Ukraine war critics Tulsi Gabbard and Tucker Carlson as traitors who should be investigated and possibly arrested for questioning the dominant...]]></itunes:subtitle>
			<itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
		<itunes:summary>The View's Whoopi Goldberg, Joy Behar, Ana Navarro and Sunny Hostin dedicated a full segment to calling Ukraine war critics Tulsi Gabbard and Tucker Carlson as traitors who should be investigated and possibly arrested for questioning the dominant media and government narrative about the conflict. Plus a segment on mainstream journalists' efforts to smear actor, comedian and podcaster Russell Brand for allegedly spreading conspiracies and misinformation on his way to becoming "The next Joe Rogan." Also featuring Stef Zamorano, Max Blumenthal, Kurt Metzger and Mike MacRae! And phone calls from Al Pacino and Bernie Sanders!</itunes:summary></item>
		<item>
			<title>Ukraine Military Officially Adopts Nazi Slogan</title>
			<itunes:title>Ukraine Military Officially Adopts Nazi Slogan</itunes:title>
			<pubDate>Fri, 11 Mar 2022 09:16:19 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false"><![CDATA[d9f36762-cf0a-4a69-8a18-9bda6e156cf8]]></guid>
			<link><![CDATA[https://thejimmydoreshow.libsyn.com/ukraine-military-officially-adopts-nazi-slogan]]></link>
			<itunes:image href="https://ssl-static.libsyn.com/p/assets/2/2/2/a/222a614c06e9e14ce55e3c100dce7605/Screen_Shot_2022-03-10_at_12.30.44_PM.png"/>
			<description><![CDATA[NATO apologists have sought to portray the Ukrainian military as free of neo-Nazis, but one point undermining the argument is the fact that the nation's armed forces adopted as its official slogan "Slava Ukraini!" or "Glory to Ukraine!" which was first popularized during World War II by a Nazi-affiliated nationalist militia.<br /> <br /> Plus segments on the Biden administration's humiliating efforts to persuade the "dictatorial" Venezuelan government to sell us oil and sad examples of high-minded liberals like Larry Summers, George Takei and Stephen Colbert explaining that paying higher gas prices is YOUR moral duty to support Ukraine.<br /> <br /> Also featuring Stef Zamorano, Lee Camp, Kurt Metzger and Mike MacRae! And phone calls from George Clooney and Andrew Cuomo!]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[NATO apologists have sought to portray the Ukrainian military as free of neo-Nazis, but one point undermining the argument is the fact that the nation's armed forces adopted as its official slogan "Slava Ukraini!" or "Glory to Ukraine!" which was first popularized during World War II by a Nazi-affiliated nationalist militia.  Plus segments on the Biden administration's humiliating efforts to persuade the "dictatorial" Venezuelan government to sell us oil and sad examples of high-minded liberals like Larry Summers, George Takei and Stephen Colbert explaining that paying higher gas prices is YOUR moral duty to support Ukraine.  Also featuring Stef Zamorano, Lee Camp, Kurt Metzger and Mike MacRae! And phone calls from George Clooney and Andrew Cuomo!]]></content:encoded>
			<enclosure length="59649175" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/thejimmydoreshow/TJDS_20220311_Podcast_-_31022_12.10_PM.mp3?dest-id=19460"/>
			<itunes:duration>01:01:10</itunes:duration>
			<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
			<itunes:keywords/>
			<itunes:subtitle><![CDATA[NATO apologists have sought to portray the Ukrainian military as free of neo-Nazis, but one point undermining the argument is the fact that the nation's armed forces adopted as its official slogan "Slava Ukraini!" or "Glory to Ukraine!" which was...]]></itunes:subtitle>
			<itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
		<itunes:summary>NATO apologists have sought to portray the Ukrainian military as free of neo-Nazis, but one point undermining the argument is the fact that the nation's armed forces adopted as its official slogan "Slava Ukraini!" or "Glory to Ukraine!" which was first popularized during World War II by a Nazi-affiliated nationalist militia. Plus segments on the Biden administration's humiliating efforts to persuade the "dictatorial" Venezuelan government to sell us oil and sad examples of high-minded liberals like Larry Summers, George Takei and Stephen Colbert explaining that paying higher gas prices is YOUR moral duty to support Ukraine. Also featuring Stef Zamorano, Lee Camp, Kurt Metzger and Mike MacRae! And phone calls from George Clooney and Andrew Cuomo!</itunes:summary></item>
		<item>
			<title>NATO Pushed Russia Into War, Experts Say</title>
			<itunes:title>NATO Pushed Russia Into War, Experts Say</itunes:title>
			<pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2022 20:12:37 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false"><![CDATA[1be64940-6d1c-492e-acb6-d9ed49e9f350]]></guid>
			<link><![CDATA[https://thejimmydoreshow.libsyn.com/nato-pushed-russia-into-war-experts-say]]></link>
			<itunes:image href="https://ssl-static.libsyn.com/p/assets/5/c/a/7/5ca7cc2c89e404b25f2e77a3093c12a1/Screen_Shot_2022-03-04_at_12.20.16_PM.png"/>
			<description><![CDATA[<p>Longtime foreign policy observers ranging from Noam Chomsky and Stephen Cohen to Pat Buchanan and Henry Kissinger have long warned that NATO actions would push Russia into a military response in Ukraine, and now that's precisely what's happened.<br /> <br /> Plus a segment describing all the myriad ways neo-Nazi groups have infiltrated the Ukrainian government and military, and how neo-Nazi militias operate freely in wide swaths of the country.<br /> <br /> Also featuring Stef Zamorano, Max Blumenthal and Mike MacRae! And phone calls from Liam Neeson and Joe Biden!</p>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Longtime foreign policy observers ranging from Noam Chomsky and Stephen Cohen to Pat Buchanan and Henry Kissinger have long warned that NATO actions would push Russia into a military response in Ukraine, and now that's precisely what's happened.  Plus a segment describing all the myriad ways neo-Nazi groups have infiltrated the Ukrainian government and military, and how neo-Nazi militias operate freely in wide swaths of the country.  Also featuring Stef Zamorano, Max Blumenthal and Mike MacRae! And phone calls from Liam Neeson and Joe Biden!</p>]]></content:encoded>
			<enclosure length="65781180" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/thejimmydoreshow/TJDS_20220304_Podcast_-_3422_11.28_AM.mp3?dest-id=19460"/>
			<itunes:duration>01:08:12</itunes:duration>
			<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
			<itunes:keywords/>
			<itunes:subtitle><![CDATA[Longtime foreign policy observers ranging from Noam Chomsky and Stephen Cohen to Pat Buchanan and Henry Kissinger have long warned that NATO actions would push Russia into a military response in Ukraine, and now that's precisely what's happened.  Plus...]]></itunes:subtitle>
			<itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
		<itunes:summary>Longtime foreign policy observers ranging from Noam Chomsky and Stephen Cohen to Pat Buchanan and Henry Kissinger have long warned that NATO actions would push Russia into a military response in Ukraine, and now that's precisely what's happened. Plus a segment describing all the myriad ways neo-Nazi groups have infiltrated the Ukrainian government and military, and how neo-Nazi militias operate freely in wide swaths of the country. Also featuring Stef Zamorano, Max Blumenthal and Mike MacRae! And phone calls from Liam Neeson and Joe Biden!</itunes:summary></item>
		<item>
			<title>Trudeau Revokes Emergency Powers Authorization</title>
			<itunes:title>Trudeau Revokes Emergency Powers Authorization</itunes:title>
			<pubDate>Fri, 25 Feb 2022 20:06:41 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false"><![CDATA[6524ba00-9075-436e-aecc-f9ca68f13add]]></guid>
			<link><![CDATA[https://thejimmydoreshow.libsyn.com/trudeau-revokes-emergency-powers-authorization]]></link>
			<itunes:image href="https://ssl-static.libsyn.com/p/assets/1/a/0/d/1a0d97cc060bfb66a04421dee9605cbd/Screen_Shot_2022-02-24_at_5.40.55_PM.png"/>
			<description><![CDATA[Canadian Prime Minister Justin Trudeau has reversed himself, and announced that the emergency powers he invoked to deal with the trucker protest, will be revoked. Some had feared that Trudeau would extend the powers in a decidedly authoritarian manner.<br /> <br /> Plus segments about plans in place by global officials to institute digital IDs and the CDC's recent announcement that data about booster effectiveness will not be released for fear the information will be "misinterpreted."<br /> <br /> Also featuring Stef Zamorano, Max Blumenthal and Mike MacRae! And phone calls from Vince Vaughn and Mitt Romney!]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[Canadian Prime Minister Justin Trudeau has reversed himself, and announced that the emergency powers he invoked to deal with the trucker protest, will be revoked. Some had feared that Trudeau would extend the powers in a decidedly authoritarian manner.  Plus segments about plans in place by global officials to institute digital IDs and the CDC's recent announcement that data about booster effectiveness will not be released for fear the information will be "misinterpreted."  Also featuring Stef Zamorano, Max Blumenthal and Mike MacRae! And phone calls from Vince Vaughn and Mitt Romney!]]></content:encoded>
			<enclosure length="61419630" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/thejimmydoreshow/TJDS_20220224_Podcast_-_22522_11.15_AM.mp3?dest-id=19460"/>
			<itunes:duration>01:03:46</itunes:duration>
			<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
			<itunes:keywords/>
			<itunes:subtitle><![CDATA[Canadian Prime Minister Justin Trudeau has reversed himself, and announced that the emergency powers he invoked to deal with the trucker protest, will be revoked. Some had feared that Trudeau would extend the powers in a decidedly authoritarian...]]></itunes:subtitle>
			<itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
		<itunes:summary>Canadian Prime Minister Justin Trudeau has reversed himself, and announced that the emergency powers he invoked to deal with the trucker protest, will be revoked. Some had feared that Trudeau would extend the powers in a decidedly authoritarian manner. Plus segments about plans in place by global officials to institute digital IDs and the CDC's recent announcement that data about booster effectiveness will not be released for fear the information will be "misinterpreted." Also featuring Stef Zamorano, Max Blumenthal and Mike MacRae! And phone calls from Vince Vaughn and Mitt Romney!</itunes:summary></item>
		<item>
			<title>Joy Behar's Mask Is NEVER Coming Off!</title>
			<itunes:title>Joy Behar's Mask Is NEVER Coming Off!</itunes:title>
			<pubDate>Sat, 19 Feb 2022 04:18:32 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false"><![CDATA[ecf4b369-c7a1-4c34-bd73-6098aa6c92df]]></guid>
			<link><![CDATA[https://thejimmydoreshow.libsyn.com/joy-behars-mask-is-never-coming-off]]></link>
			<itunes:image href="https://ssl-static.libsyn.com/p/assets/7/5/0/0/75003b713ec44e2ba04421dee9605cbd/Screen_Shot_2022-02-18_at_7.53.06_PM.png"/>
			<description><![CDATA[<p>The View host Joy Behar has revealed that she plans to continue wearing a mask in public and indoors whenever away from home for, well, the rest of her life, it seems. So that's it, just masked up forever for Joy Behar.</p> <p>Plus segments on Canadian Prime Minister Justin Trudeau telling a Jewish MP she's supporting Nazis and the hacker who admitted to exposing the names of donors to the fundraising campaign for Canadian truckers.</p> <p>Also featuring Stef Zamorano, Kurt Metzger, Jackson Hinkle and Mike MacRae! And phone calls from Jake Tapper and Joe Biden!</p>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The View host Joy Behar has revealed that she plans to continue wearing a mask in public and indoors whenever away from home for, well, the rest of her life, it seems. So that's it, just masked up forever for Joy Behar.</p> <p>Plus segments on Canadian Prime Minister Justin Trudeau telling a Jewish MP she's supporting Nazis and the hacker who admitted to exposing the names of donors to the fundraising campaign for Canadian truckers.</p> <p>Also featuring Stef Zamorano, Kurt Metzger, Jackson Hinkle and Mike MacRae! And phone calls from Jake Tapper and Joe Biden!</p>]]></content:encoded>
			<enclosure length="64016786" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/thejimmydoreshow/TJDS_20220218_Podcast_-_21822_6.48_PM.mp3?dest-id=19460"/>
			<itunes:duration>01:06:29</itunes:duration>
			<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
			<itunes:keywords/>
			<itunes:subtitle><![CDATA[The View host Joy Behar has revealed that she plans to continue wearing a mask in public and indoors whenever away from home for, well, the rest of her life, it seems. So that's it, just masked up forever for Joy Behar. Plus segments on Canadian Prime...]]></itunes:subtitle>
			<itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
		<itunes:summary>The View host Joy Behar has revealed that she plans to continue wearing a mask in public and indoors whenever away from home for, well, the rest of her life, it seems. So that's it, just masked up forever for Joy Behar. Plus segments on Canadian Prime Minister Justin Trudeau telling a Jewish MP she's supporting Nazis and the hacker who admitted to exposing the names of donors to the fundraising campaign for Canadian truckers. Also featuring Stef Zamorano, Kurt Metzger, Jackson Hinkle and Mike MacRae! And phone calls from Jake Tapper and Joe Biden!</itunes:summary></item>
		<item>
			<title>Dem SuperPAC Behind Joe Rogan Smear Campaign</title>
			<itunes:title>Dem SuperPAC Behind Joe Rogan Smear Campaign</itunes:title>
			<pubDate>Fri, 11 Feb 2022 07:44:55 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false"><![CDATA[271fd80d-736a-421a-a125-b43ca92284aa]]></guid>
			<link><![CDATA[https://thejimmydoreshow.libsyn.com/dem-superpac-behind-joe-rogan-smear-campaign]]></link>
			<itunes:image href="https://ssl-static.libsyn.com/p/assets/7/b/e/3/7be365018d20333c40be95ea3302a6a1/Screen_Shot_2022-02-11_at_12.24.08_AM.png"/>
			<description><![CDATA[<p>It's been revealed that Meidas Touch, a Democratically-affiliated SuperPAC, has been the driving force behind the campaign to smear Joe Rogan as a racist, anti-trans spreader of vaccine misinformation. Aided, of course, by a compliant media eager to take down a successful podcaster who's not part of their "club."<br /> <br /> Plus segments on "Rising" host Ryan Grim's attack on the Canadian truckers and a new report revealing that Tucker Carlson is the most watched cable news host among Democrats</p> <p>Also featuring Stef Zamorano, Kurt Metzger and Mike MacRae! And phone calls from Joe Biden and Al Pacino!</p>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It's been revealed that Meidas Touch, a Democratically-affiliated SuperPAC, has been the driving force behind the campaign to smear Joe Rogan as a racist, anti-trans spreader of vaccine misinformation. Aided, of course, by a compliant media eager to take down a successful podcaster who's not part of their "club."  Plus segments on "Rising" host Ryan Grim's attack on the Canadian truckers and a new report revealing that Tucker Carlson is the most watched cable news host among Democrats</p> <p>Also featuring Stef Zamorano, Kurt Metzger and Mike MacRae! And phone calls from Joe Biden and Al Pacino!</p>]]></content:encoded>
			<enclosure length="62990090" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/thejimmydoreshow/TJDS_20220210_Podcast_-_21022_11.31_PM.mp3?dest-id=19460"/>
			<itunes:duration>01:05:24</itunes:duration>
			<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
			<itunes:keywords/>
			<itunes:subtitle><![CDATA[It's been revealed that Meidas Touch, a Democratically-affiliated SuperPAC, has been the driving force behind the campaign to smear Joe Rogan as a racist, anti-trans spreader of vaccine misinformation. Aided, of course, by a compliant media eager to...]]></itunes:subtitle>
			<itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
		<itunes:summary>It's been revealed that Meidas Touch, a Democratically-affiliated SuperPAC, has been the driving force behind the campaign to smear Joe Rogan as a racist, anti-trans spreader of vaccine misinformation. Aided, of course, by a compliant media eager to take down a successful podcaster who's not part of their "club." Plus segments on "Rising" host Ryan Grim's attack on the Canadian truckers and a new report revealing that Tucker Carlson is the most watched cable news host among Democrats Also featuring Stef Zamorano, Kurt Metzger and Mike MacRae! And phone calls from Joe Biden and Al Pacino!</itunes:summary></item>
		<item>
			<title>CNN Caught Constantly Lying, Unlike Joe Rogan</title>
			<itunes:title>CNN Caught Constantly Lying, Unlike Joe Rogan</itunes:title>
			<pubDate>Fri, 04 Feb 2022 07:00:49 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false"><![CDATA[bd9e01a0-d5d5-4f0d-b538-afa2f60c8106]]></guid>
			<link><![CDATA[https://thejimmydoreshow.libsyn.com/cnn-caught-constantly-lying-unlike-joe-rogan]]></link>
			<itunes:image href="https://ssl-static.libsyn.com/p/assets/f/0/0/4/f004b2243971ea08bafc7308ab683e82/Screen_Shot_2022-02-03_at_10.55.04_PM.png"/>
			<description><![CDATA[CNN's Brian Stelter lamented that people are increasingly turning to Joe Rogan for information instead of the truth-tellers in the mainstream, corporate media with their large staffs and newsrooms. Except as Jimmy points out CNN's record of truth-telling is spotty, at best.  <p>Plus a segment on CNN host Jim Acosta's unhinged warmongering over Ukraine and Russia.</p> <p>Also featuring Stef Zamorano, Kurt Metzger and Mike MacRae! And phone calls from Joe Biden and Alec Baldwin!</p>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[CNN's Brian Stelter lamented that people are increasingly turning to Joe Rogan for information instead of the truth-tellers in the mainstream, corporate media with their large staffs and newsrooms. Except as Jimmy points out CNN's record of truth-telling is spotty, at best.  <p>Plus a segment on CNN host Jim Acosta's unhinged warmongering over Ukraine and Russia.</p> <p>Also featuring Stef Zamorano, Kurt Metzger and Mike MacRae! And phone calls from Joe Biden and Alec Baldwin!</p>]]></content:encoded>
			<enclosure length="60410969" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/thejimmydoreshow/TJDS_20220203_Podcast_-_2322_7.51_PM.mp3?dest-id=19460"/>
			<itunes:duration>01:02:36</itunes:duration>
			<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
			<itunes:keywords/>
			<itunes:subtitle><![CDATA[CNN's Brian Stelter lamented that people are increasingly turning to Joe Rogan for information instead of the truth-tellers in the mainstream, corporate media with their large staffs and newsrooms. Except as Jimmy points out CNN's record of...]]></itunes:subtitle>
			<itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
		<itunes:summary>CNN's Brian Stelter lamented that people are increasingly turning to Joe Rogan for information instead of the truth-tellers in the mainstream, corporate media with their large staffs and newsrooms. Except as Jimmy points out CNN's record of truth-telling is spotty, at best.  Plus a segment on CNN host Jim Acosta's unhinged warmongering over Ukraine and Russia. Also featuring Stef Zamorano, Kurt Metzger and Mike MacRae! And phone calls from Joe Biden and Alec Baldwin!</itunes:summary></item>
		<item>
			<title>Left &amp; Right Unite for DC Anti-Vax Mandate Rally</title>
			<itunes:title>Left &amp; Right Unite for DC Anti-Vax Mandate Rally</itunes:title>
			<pubDate>Fri, 28 Jan 2022 07:50:52 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false"><![CDATA[b95d2923-2eb2-412b-9c33-6f97752cb261]]></guid>
			<link><![CDATA[https://thejimmydoreshow.libsyn.com/left-right-unite-for-dc-anti-vax-mandate-rally]]></link>
			<itunes:image href="https://ssl-static.libsyn.com/p/assets/a/4/9/c/a49c26ab3f1ec71be5bbc093207a2619/Screen_Shot_2022-01-27_at_11.16.54_PM.png"/>
			<description><![CDATA[<p dir="ltr" data-test-bidi="">Last weekend witnessed a rare coming together of those on the left and the right, united in opposition to vaccine mandates. Jimmy and comedian The Greyzone's Max Blumenthal discuss the event and Max delivers the speech he had hoped to make at the rally but couldn't.</p> <p dir="ltr" data-test-bidi="">Plus segments on Whoopi Goldberg's attacks on Bill Maher over COVID restrictions and news that the UK and Ireland will soon be lifting those restrictions.</p> <p dir="ltr" data-test-bidi="">Also featuring Stef Zamorano, Kurt Metzger and Mike MacRae! And phone calls from Vladimir Putin and George Clooney!</p>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="ltr" data-test-bidi="">Last weekend witnessed a rare coming together of those on the left and the right, united in opposition to vaccine mandates. Jimmy and comedian The Greyzone's Max Blumenthal discuss the event and Max delivers the speech he had hoped to make at the rally but couldn't.</p> <p dir="ltr" data-test-bidi="">Plus segments on Whoopi Goldberg's attacks on Bill Maher over COVID restrictions and news that the UK and Ireland will soon be lifting those restrictions.</p> <p dir="ltr" data-test-bidi="">Also featuring Stef Zamorano, Kurt Metzger and Mike MacRae! And phone calls from Vladimir Putin and George Clooney!</p>]]></content:encoded>
			<enclosure length="63843208" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/thejimmydoreshow/TJDS_20220127_Podcast_-_12722_9.30_PM.mp3?dest-id=19460"/>
			<itunes:duration>01:06:13</itunes:duration>
			<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
			<itunes:keywords/>
			<itunes:subtitle><![CDATA[Last weekend witnessed a rare coming together of those on the left and the right, united in opposition to vaccine mandates. Jimmy and comedian The Greyzone's Max Blumenthal discuss the event and Max delivers the speech he had hoped to make at the...]]></itunes:subtitle>
			<itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
		<itunes:summary>Last weekend witnessed a rare coming together of those on the left and the right, united in opposition to vaccine mandates. Jimmy and comedian The Greyzone's Max Blumenthal discuss the event and Max delivers the speech he had hoped to make at the rally but couldn't. Plus segments on Whoopi Goldberg's attacks on Bill Maher over COVID restrictions and news that the UK and Ireland will soon be lifting those restrictions. Also featuring Stef Zamorano, Kurt Metzger and Mike MacRae! And phone calls from Vladimir Putin and George Clooney!</itunes:summary></item>
		<item>
			<title>Debunking the 270 "Doctors" Who Criticized Joe Rogan</title>
			<itunes:title>Debunking the 270 "Doctors" Who Criticized Joe Rogan</itunes:title>
			<pubDate>Fri, 21 Jan 2022 17:03:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false"><![CDATA[8992c0f9-544b-49ab-b253-e50a6c4f34ac]]></guid>
			<link><![CDATA[https://thejimmydoreshow.libsyn.com/debunking-the-270-doctors-who-criticized-joe-rogan]]></link>
			<itunes:image href="https://ssl-static.libsyn.com/p/assets/5/0/f/4/50f4e57ac7a2d4e6a04421dee9605cbd/Screen_Shot_2022-01-21_at_8.56.49_AM.png"/>
			<description><![CDATA[Turns out that the story about 270 "doctors" criticizing Joe Rogan's "misinformation" that was widely touted by the mainstream media was itself misinformation. Jimmy and comedian Kurt Metzger discuss this epic swing and a miss from the corporate media and many others.<br /> <br /> Plus a segment on Dr. Fauci admitting that Jimmy's been right about the spread of coronavirus since August.<br /> <br /> <div class= "product-hero-desc product-hero-desc--spacer-bottom-large"> <section class= "section section--no-padding-bottom product-hero-desc__section"> <p dir="ltr" data-test-bidi="">Also featuring Stef Zamorano and Mike MacRae! A phone call from Joe Biden!</p> </section> </div>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[Turns out that the story about 270 "doctors" criticizing Joe Rogan's "misinformation" that was widely touted by the mainstream media was itself misinformation. Jimmy and comedian Kurt Metzger discuss this epic swing and a miss from the corporate media and many others.  Plus a segment on Dr. Fauci admitting that Jimmy's been right about the spread of coronavirus since August.    <p dir="ltr" data-test-bidi="">Also featuring Stef Zamorano and Mike MacRae! A phone call from Joe Biden!</p>  ]]></content:encoded>
			<enclosure length="57688508" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/thejimmydoreshow/TJDS_20220120_Podcast_-_12022_8.55_PM.mp3?dest-id=19460"/>
			<itunes:duration>58:49</itunes:duration>
			<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
			<itunes:keywords/>
			<itunes:subtitle><![CDATA[Turns out that the story about 270 "doctors" criticizing Joe Rogan's "misinformation" that was widely touted by the mainstream media was itself misinformation. Jimmy and comedian Kurt Metzger discuss this epic swing and a miss from the corporate media...]]></itunes:subtitle>
			<itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
		<itunes:summary>Turns out that the story about 270 "doctors" criticizing Joe Rogan's "misinformation" that was widely touted by the mainstream media was itself misinformation. Jimmy and comedian Kurt Metzger discuss this epic swing and a miss from the corporate media and many others. Plus a segment on Dr. Fauci admitting that Jimmy's been right about the spread of coronavirus since August. Also featuring Stef Zamorano and Mike MacRae! A phone call from Joe Biden!</itunes:summary></item>
		<item>
			<title>One Year Anniversary of #ForceTheVote!</title>
			<itunes:title>One Year Anniversary of #ForceTheVote!</itunes:title>
			<pubDate>Thu, 13 Jan 2022 08:47:12 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false"><![CDATA[4d00eece-af39-48e5-ab37-c4b02e99f9d5]]></guid>
			<link><![CDATA[https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/thejimmydoreshow/TJDS_20220113_Podcast_-_11222_8.22_PM.mp3]]></link>
			<itunes:image href="https://ssl-static.libsyn.com/p/assets/3/8/a/c/38ace666d55fb4f3e5bbc093207a2619/Screen_Shot_2022-01-13_at_12.38.20_AM.png"/>
			<description><![CDATA[<p>It's been a year since the #ForceTheVote campaign to pressure progressive Democrats in the House to deny their vote for Speaker from Nancy Pelosi unless she agreed to bring up a Medicare for All vote on the House Floor. Jimmy and comedian Kurt Metzger reflect on what happened to #ForceTheVote.<br /> <br /> Plus Slate smears Supreme Court members as "anti-vaxx."<br /> <br /> Also featuring Stef Zamorano! </p>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It's been a year since the #ForceTheVote campaign to pressure progressive Democrats in the House to deny their vote for Speaker from Nancy Pelosi unless she agreed to bring up a Medicare for All vote on the House Floor. Jimmy and comedian Kurt Metzger reflect on what happened to #ForceTheVote.  Plus Slate smears Supreme Court members as "anti-vaxx."  Also featuring Stef Zamorano! </p>]]></content:encoded>
			<enclosure length="67593577" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/thejimmydoreshow/TJDS_20220113_Podcast_-_11222_8.22_PM.mp3?dest-id=19460"/>
			<itunes:duration>01:09:51</itunes:duration>
			<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
			<itunes:keywords/>
			<itunes:subtitle><![CDATA[It's been a year since the #ForceTheVote campaign to pressure progressive Democrats in the House to deny their vote for Speaker from Nancy Pelosi unless she agreed to bring up a Medicare for All vote on the House Floor. Jimmy and comedian Kurt Metzger...]]></itunes:subtitle>
			<itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
		<itunes:summary>It's been a year since the #ForceTheVote campaign to pressure progressive Democrats in the House to deny their vote for Speaker from Nancy Pelosi unless she agreed to bring up a Medicare for All vote on the House Floor. Jimmy and comedian Kurt Metzger reflect on what happened to #ForceTheVote. Plus Slate smears Supreme Court members as "anti-vaxx." Also featuring Stef Zamorano! </itunes:summary></item>
		<item>
			<title>Patton Oswalt DRAGGED for Taking Photo w/ Dave Chappelle</title>
			<itunes:title>Patton Oswalt DRAGGED for Taking Photo w/ Dave Chappelle</itunes:title>
			<pubDate>Fri, 07 Jan 2022 04:43:08 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false"><![CDATA[420e445e-ca91-4109-9478-ebc93dfdca06]]></guid>
			<link><![CDATA[https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/thejimmydoreshow/TJDS_20220106_Podcast_-_1622_7.59_PM.mp3]]></link>
			<itunes:image href="https://ssl-static.libsyn.com/p/assets/b/c/5/a/bc5ae7d5981ede55e55e3c100dce7605/Screen_Shot_2022-01-06_at_8.23.01_PM.png"/>
			<description><![CDATA[<p>Patton Oswalt committed the cardinal sin of... taking a photo with his friend of 34 years, Dave Chappelle. In response Oswalt was raked over the social media coals, and delivered a groveling apology, promising to do better and expressing regret for all the harm he caused. Jimmy and comedian Kurt Metzger discuss Patton's humiliating cave to the social media mob.</p> <p>Plus segments on the censoring of mRNA vaccine technology developer Dr. Robert Malone and Howard Stern's bizarre attack on Oprah for hosting holiday parties.<br /> <br /> Also featuring Stef Zamorano and Mike MacRae! Phone calls from Andrew Cuomo and Vince Vaughn!</p>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Patton Oswalt committed the cardinal sin of... taking a photo with his friend of 34 years, Dave Chappelle. In response Oswalt was raked over the social media coals, and delivered a groveling apology, promising to do better and expressing regret for all the harm he caused. Jimmy and comedian Kurt Metzger discuss Patton's humiliating cave to the social media mob.</p> <p>Plus segments on the censoring of mRNA vaccine technology developer Dr. Robert Malone and Howard Stern's bizarre attack on Oprah for hosting holiday parties.  Also featuring Stef Zamorano and Mike MacRae! Phone calls from Andrew Cuomo and Vince Vaughn!</p>]]></content:encoded>
			<enclosure length="61665787" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/thejimmydoreshow/TJDS_20220106_Podcast_-_1622_7.59_PM.mp3?dest-id=19460"/>
			<itunes:duration>01:03:13</itunes:duration>
			<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
			<itunes:keywords/>
			<itunes:subtitle><![CDATA[Patton Oswalt committed the cardinal sin of... taking a photo with his friend of 34 years, Dave Chappelle. In response Oswalt was raked over the social media coals, and delivered a groveling apology, promising to do better and expressing regret for...]]></itunes:subtitle>
			<itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
		<itunes:summary>Patton Oswalt committed the cardinal sin of... taking a photo with his friend of 34 years, Dave Chappelle. In response Oswalt was raked over the social media coals, and delivered a groveling apology, promising to do better and expressing regret for all the harm he caused. Jimmy and comedian Kurt Metzger discuss Patton's humiliating cave to the social media mob. Plus segments on the censoring of mRNA vaccine technology developer Dr. Robert Malone and Howard Stern's bizarre attack on Oprah for hosting holiday parties. Also featuring Stef Zamorano and Mike MacRae! Phone calls from Andrew Cuomo and Vince Vaughn!</itunes:summary></item>
		<item>
			<title>Brian Williams' Cringeworthy Retirement Speech</title>
			<itunes:title>Brian Williams' Cringeworthy Retirement Speech</itunes:title>
			<pubDate>Fri, 31 Dec 2021 06:25:38 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false"><![CDATA[2e4fe623-75f1-4083-9d5d-b857d0341391]]></guid>
			<link><![CDATA[https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/thejimmydoreshow/TJDS_20211231_Podcast_-_123021_9.23_PM.mp3]]></link>
			<itunes:image href="https://ssl-static.libsyn.com/p/assets/b/f/2/f/bf2f98da718e0cd4e5bbc093207a2619/Screen_Shot_2021-12-30_at_9.53.34_PM.png"/>
			<description><![CDATA[<p>MSNBC anchor and noted stolen valor aficionado Brian Williams is leaving his show, 11th Hour, and his farewell announcement was equal parts self-aggrandizing, terrifying and elite-fluffing. Jimmy and comedian Kurt Metzger discuss the story.<br /> <br /> Plus a segment on the corporate capture of purported leftists on "BreadTube" with The Grayzone's Max Bluementhal.</p> <p>Also featuring Stef Zamorano and Mike MacRae! Phone calls from Joe Biden and Al Pacino!</p>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>MSNBC anchor and noted stolen valor aficionado Brian Williams is leaving his show, 11th Hour, and his farewell announcement was equal parts self-aggrandizing, terrifying and elite-fluffing. Jimmy and comedian Kurt Metzger discuss the story.  Plus a segment on the corporate capture of purported leftists on "BreadTube" with The Grayzone's Max Bluementhal.</p> <p>Also featuring Stef Zamorano and Mike MacRae! Phone calls from Joe Biden and Al Pacino!</p>]]></content:encoded>
			<enclosure length="65943160" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/thejimmydoreshow/TJDS_20211231_Podcast_-_123021_9.23_PM.mp3?dest-id=19460"/>
			<itunes:duration>01:06:57</itunes:duration>
			<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
			<itunes:keywords/>
			<itunes:subtitle><![CDATA[MSNBC anchor and noted stolen valor aficionado Brian Williams is leaving his show, 11th Hour, and his farewell announcement was equal parts self-aggrandizing, terrifying and elite-fluffing. Jimmy and comedian Kurt Metzger discuss the story.  Plus a...]]></itunes:subtitle>
			<itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
		<itunes:summary>MSNBC anchor and noted stolen valor aficionado Brian Williams is leaving his show, 11th Hour, and his farewell announcement was equal parts self-aggrandizing, terrifying and elite-fluffing. Jimmy and comedian Kurt Metzger discuss the story. Plus a segment on the corporate capture of purported leftists on "BreadTube" with The Grayzone's Max Bluementhal. Also featuring Stef Zamorano and Mike MacRae! Phone calls from Joe Biden and Al Pacino!</itunes:summary></item>
		<item>
			<title>What's the Story Behind Japan's COVID "Miracle?"</title>
			<itunes:title>What's the Story Behind Japan's COVID "Miracle?"</itunes:title>
			<pubDate>Fri, 24 Dec 2021 05:58:43 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false"><![CDATA[4f0960af-fe33-47c3-b5ba-7e11b656437c]]></guid>
			<link><![CDATA[https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/thejimmydoreshow/TJDS_20211224_Podcast_-_122321_7.19_PM.mp3]]></link>
			<itunes:image href="https://ssl-static.libsyn.com/p/assets/0/d/6/a/0d6a1dfcb803b89988c4a68c3ddbc4f2/Screen_Shot_2021-12-23_at_9.43.41_PM.png"/>
			<description><![CDATA[<p>Japan has recently seen coronavirus cases plummet, yet no one seems entirely sure why (although Jimmy has a theory). Jimmy and comedian Kurt Metzger discuss the story, as well as recent news suggesting that burgers made of bugs are right around the corner, and the unsettling reality of corporate capture of the FDA.<br /> <br /> Also featuring Stef Zamorano and Mike MacRae! Phone call from Noam Chomsky and holiday voicemail messages to Jimmy from a range of celebrities!</p>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Japan has recently seen coronavirus cases plummet, yet no one seems entirely sure why (although Jimmy has a theory). Jimmy and comedian Kurt Metzger discuss the story, as well as recent news suggesting that burgers made of bugs are right around the corner, and the unsettling reality of corporate capture of the FDA.  Also featuring Stef Zamorano and Mike MacRae! Phone call from Noam Chomsky and holiday voicemail messages to Jimmy from a range of celebrities!</p>]]></content:encoded>
			<enclosure length="70849500" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/thejimmydoreshow/TJDS_20211224_Podcast_-_122321_7.19_PM.mp3?dest-id=19460"/>
			<itunes:duration>01:13:19</itunes:duration>
			<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
			<itunes:keywords/>
			<itunes:subtitle><![CDATA[Japan has recently seen coronavirus cases plummet, yet no one seems entirely sure why (although Jimmy has a theory). Jimmy and comedian Kurt Metzger discuss the story, as well as recent news suggesting that burgers made of bugs are right around the...]]></itunes:subtitle>
			<itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
		<itunes:summary>Japan has recently seen coronavirus cases plummet, yet no one seems entirely sure why (although Jimmy has a theory). Jimmy and comedian Kurt Metzger discuss the story, as well as recent news suggesting that burgers made of bugs are right around the corner, and the unsettling reality of corporate capture of the FDA. Also featuring Stef Zamorano and Mike MacRae! Phone call from Noam Chomsky and holiday voicemail messages to Jimmy from a range of celebrities!</itunes:summary></item>
		<item>
			<title>MSNBC Blatantly LIES About Julian Assange Case</title>
			<itunes:title>MSNBC Blatantly LIES About Julian Assange Case</itunes:title>
			<pubDate>Fri, 17 Dec 2021 05:05:48 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false"><![CDATA[3907a71d-1fcb-4d9b-afe0-2a240530f6da]]></guid>
			<link><![CDATA[https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/thejimmydoreshow/TJDS_20211217_Podcast_-_121621_1.01_PM.mp3]]></link>
			<itunes:image href="https://ssl-static.libsyn.com/p/assets/c/7/f/e/c7fe743d9bb39e8188c4a68c3ddbc4f2/Screen_Shot_2021-12-16_at_9.04.41_PM.png"/>
			<description><![CDATA[<p>Julian Assange moved one step closer to extradition to the United States to face trumped-up Espionage Act charges. Jimmy and Glenn Greenwald discuss the case and the savage indictment of the U.S. and U.K. media the Assange case represents as alleged "journalists" cheer on the erosion of the free press.<br /> <br /> Also featuring Stef Zamorano and Mike MacRae! Phone calls from Bernie Sanders and Anthony Fauci!</p>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Julian Assange moved one step closer to extradition to the United States to face trumped-up Espionage Act charges. Jimmy and Glenn Greenwald discuss the case and the savage indictment of the U.S. and U.K. media the Assange case represents as alleged "journalists" cheer on the erosion of the free press.  Also featuring Stef Zamorano and Mike MacRae! Phone calls from Bernie Sanders and Anthony Fauci!</p>]]></content:encoded>
			<enclosure length="66728610" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/thejimmydoreshow/TJDS_20211217_Podcast_-_121621_1.01_PM.mp3?dest-id=19460"/>
			<itunes:duration>01:09:26</itunes:duration>
			<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
			<itunes:keywords/>
			<itunes:subtitle><![CDATA[Julian Assange moved one step closer to extradition to the United States to face trumped-up Espionage Act charges. Jimmy and Glenn Greenwald discuss the case and the savage indictment of the U.S. and U.K. media the Assange case represents as alleged...]]></itunes:subtitle>
			<itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
		<itunes:summary>Julian Assange moved one step closer to extradition to the United States to face trumped-up Espionage Act charges. Jimmy and Glenn Greenwald discuss the case and the savage indictment of the U.S. and U.K. media the Assange case represents as alleged "journalists" cheer on the erosion of the free press. Also featuring Stef Zamorano and Mike MacRae! Phone calls from Bernie Sanders and Anthony Fauci!</itunes:summary></item>
		<item>
			<title>Omicron Variant: Born to Be Mild?</title>
			<itunes:title>Omicron Variant: Born to Be Mild?</itunes:title>
			<pubDate>Fri, 10 Dec 2021 05:58:38 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false"><![CDATA[0c7dec8e-bc9d-40a6-ad23-82e052b668fc]]></guid>
			<link><![CDATA[https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/thejimmydoreshow/TJDS_20211210_Podcast_-_12921_3.05_PM.mp3]]></link>
			<itunes:image href="https://ssl-static.libsyn.com/p/assets/e/e/6/e/ee6e960d631dea9116c3140a3186d450/Screen_Shot_2021-12-09_at_9.57.26_PM.png"/>
			<description><![CDATA[<p>Nancy Pelosi's bewildering word salad press conference, the War on Christmas comes for Fox News' tree. Featuring Max Blumenthal, Mike MacRae and Stef Zamorano. Phone calls from Andrew Cuomo and Joe Biden!</p>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Nancy Pelosi's bewildering word salad press conference, the War on Christmas comes for Fox News' tree. Featuring Max Blumenthal, Mike MacRae and Stef Zamorano. Phone calls from Andrew Cuomo and Joe Biden!</p>]]></content:encoded>
			<enclosure length="58553370" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/thejimmydoreshow/TJDS_20211210_Podcast_-_12921_3.05_PM.mp3?dest-id=19460"/>
			<itunes:duration>01:00:21</itunes:duration>
			<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
			<itunes:keywords/>
			<itunes:subtitle><![CDATA[Nancy Pelosi's bewildering word salad press conference, the War on Christmas comes for Fox News' tree. Featuring Max Blumenthal, Mike MacRae and Stef Zamorano. Phone calls from Andrew Cuomo and Joe Biden!]]></itunes:subtitle>
			<itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
		<itunes:summary>Nancy Pelosi's bewildering word salad press conference, the War on Christmas comes for Fox News' tree. Featuring Max Blumenthal, Mike MacRae and Stef Zamorano. Phone calls from Andrew Cuomo and Joe Biden!</itunes:summary></item>
		<item>
			<title>CNN FINALLY Suspends Chris Cuomo!</title>
			<itunes:title>CNN FINALLY Suspends Chris Cuomo!</itunes:title>
			<pubDate>Fri, 03 Dec 2021 05:18:32 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false"><![CDATA[7a7e170a-67ae-42af-89fd-19588503a5f9]]></guid>
			<link><![CDATA[https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/thejimmydoreshow/TJDS_20211203_Podcast_-_12221_6.30_PM.mp3]]></link>
			<itunes:image href="https://ssl-static.libsyn.com/p/assets/0/f/2/0/0f209b711901fd8abafc7308ab683e82/Screen_Shot_2021-12-02_at_9.17.16_PM.png"/>
			<description><![CDATA[<p>Democrats TURN on Merrick Garland Over Jan 6 Investigation, Fauci Uses “Science” As Defense for His Lies<br /> <br /> Featuring Mike MacRae, and Stef Zamorano!<br /> <br /> Phone calls from Dr. Fauci and Jake Tapper!</p>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Democrats TURN on Merrick Garland Over Jan 6 Investigation, Fauci Uses “Science” As Defense for His Lies  Featuring Mike MacRae, and Stef Zamorano!  Phone calls from Dr. Fauci and Jake Tapper!</p>]]></content:encoded>
			<enclosure length="65083961" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/thejimmydoreshow/TJDS_20211203_Podcast_-_12221_6.30_PM.mp3?dest-id=19460"/>
			<itunes:duration>01:05:28</itunes:duration>
			<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
			<itunes:keywords/>
			<itunes:subtitle><![CDATA[Democrats TURN on Merrick Garland Over Jan 6 Investigation, Fauci Uses “Science” As Defense for His Lies  Featuring Mike MacRae, and Stef Zamorano!  Phone calls from Dr. Fauci and Jake Tapper!]]></itunes:subtitle>
			<itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
		<itunes:summary>Democrats TURN on Merrick Garland Over Jan 6 Investigation, Fauci Uses “Science” As Defense for His Lies Featuring Mike MacRae, and Stef Zamorano! Phone calls from Dr. Fauci and Jake Tapper!</itunes:summary></item>
		<item>
			<title>Bill Gates Caught Buying Positive News Coverage!</title>
			<itunes:title>Bill Gates Caught Buying Positive News Coverage!</itunes:title>
			<pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 17:21:22 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false"><![CDATA[0d418d57-5692-43e8-bf03-a56a2a94954f]]></guid>
			<link><![CDATA[https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/thejimmydoreshow/TJDS_20211124_Podcast.mp3]]></link>
			<itunes:image href="https://ssl-static.libsyn.com/p/assets/8/a/b/3/8ab38894eead9aa788c4a68c3ddbc4f2/123ascqdqw.jpg"/>
			<description><![CDATA[<p>Media Pushes Meaningless “State Lines” Talking Point In Kyle Rittenhouse Coverage!</p> <p>Featuring Max Blumenthal, Mike MacRae, and Stef Zamorano!</p> <p>Phone calls from Al Pacino and Andrew Cuomo!</p>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Media Pushes Meaningless “State Lines” Talking Point In Kyle Rittenhouse Coverage!</p> <p>Featuring Max Blumenthal, Mike MacRae, and Stef Zamorano!</p> <p>Phone calls from Al Pacino and Andrew Cuomo!</p>]]></content:encoded>
			<enclosure length="63624513" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/thejimmydoreshow/TJDS_20211124_Podcast.mp3?dest-id=19460"/>
			<itunes:duration>01:05:55</itunes:duration>
			<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
			<itunes:keywords/>
			<itunes:subtitle><![CDATA[Media Pushes Meaningless “State Lines” Talking Point In Kyle Rittenhouse Coverage! Featuring Max Blumenthal, Mike MacRae, and Stef Zamorano! Phone calls from Al Pacino and Andrew Cuomo!]]></itunes:subtitle>
			<itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
		<itunes:summary>Media Pushes Meaningless “State Lines” Talking Point In Kyle Rittenhouse Coverage! Featuring Max Blumenthal, Mike MacRae, and Stef Zamorano! Phone calls from Al Pacino and Andrew Cuomo!</itunes:summary></item>
		<item>
			<title>Pelosi Confronted!</title>
			<itunes:title>Pelosi Confronted!</itunes:title>
			<pubDate>Thu, 18 Nov 2021 07:36:32 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false"><![CDATA[c0eaaa8b-b7a2-4c80-ba98-aca5626739fe]]></guid>
			<link><![CDATA[https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/thejimmydoreshow/TJDS_20211117_Podcast.mp3]]></link>
			<itunes:image href="https://ssl-static.libsyn.com/p/assets/9/5/5/6/955621c05a4c10a8d959afa2a1bf1c87/2121wasassad.jpg"/>
			<description><![CDATA[<p>Vaxx Booster Reactions Forces School Closings!  Gavin Newsom Reappears!  U.S. Sanctions Nicaragua Over “Sham” Election!</p> <p>Featuring Mike MacRae, <span class= "css-901oao css-16my406 r-poiln3 r-bcqeeo r-qvutc0">Craig Pasta Jardula,</span> <span class= "css-901oao css-16my406 r-poiln3 r-bcqeeo r-qvutc0">Fiorella Isabel, and Stef Zamorano!  </span> <span class= "css-901oao css-16my406 r-poiln3 r-bcqeeo r-qvutc0">Phone calls from Dr. Fauci and Joe Biden!</span></p>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Vaxx Booster Reactions Forces School Closings!  Gavin Newsom Reappears!  U.S. Sanctions Nicaragua Over “Sham” Election!</p> <p>Featuring Mike MacRae, Craig Pasta Jardula, Fiorella Isabel, and Stef Zamorano!   Phone calls from Dr. Fauci and Joe Biden!</p>]]></content:encoded>
			<enclosure length="58879782" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/thejimmydoreshow/TJDS_20211117_Podcast.mp3?dest-id=19460"/>
			<itunes:duration>01:01:13</itunes:duration>
			<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
			<itunes:keywords/>
			<itunes:subtitle><![CDATA[Vaxx Booster Reactions Forces School Closings!  Gavin Newsom Reappears!  U.S. Sanctions Nicaragua Over “Sham” Election! Featuring Mike MacRae, Craig Pasta Jardula, Fiorella Isabel, and Stef Zamorano!   Phone calls from Dr....]]></itunes:subtitle>
			<itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
		<itunes:summary>Vaxx Booster Reactions Forces School Closings!  Gavin Newsom Reappears!  U.S. Sanctions Nicaragua Over “Sham” Election! Featuring Mike MacRae, Craig Pasta Jardula, Fiorella Isabel, and Stef Zamorano!   Phone calls from Dr. Fauci and Joe Biden!</itunes:summary></item>
		<item>
			<title>Pfizer Whistleblower Exposes Vaccine Research!</title>
			<pubDate>Thu, 11 Nov 2021 05:04:38 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false"><![CDATA[58c2eb6d-5cab-4794-bdeb-ec11c583f18d]]></guid>
			<link><![CDATA[https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/thejimmydoreshow/TJDS_11102021_PODCAST.mp3]]></link>
			<itunes:image href="https://ssl-static.libsyn.com/p/assets/1/d/7/e/1d7e1b07361cfb90a04421dee9605cbd/saddasqwsdwqxazx.jpg"/>
			<description><![CDATA[<p><span class= "css-901oao css-16my406 r-poiln3 r-bcqeeo r-qvutc0">Establishment Fear Mongers Covid Risk in Children!</span></p> <p>Featuring Max Blumenthal (The Grayzone), Nick Cruse (Fred Hampton Leftist Network), Mike MacRae, and Stef Zamorano!</p> <p>Phone calls from Al Pacino and Joe Biden!</p>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Establishment Fear Mongers Covid Risk in Children!</p> <p>Featuring Max Blumenthal (The Grayzone), Nick Cruse (Fred Hampton Leftist Network), Mike MacRae, and Stef Zamorano!</p> <p>Phone calls from Al Pacino and Joe Biden!</p>]]></content:encoded>
			<enclosure length="60161783" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/thejimmydoreshow/TJDS_11102021_PODCAST.mp3?dest-id=19460"/>
			<itunes:duration>01:02:35</itunes:duration>
			<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
			<itunes:keywords/>
			<itunes:subtitle><![CDATA[Establishment Fear Mongers Covid Risk in Children! Featuring Max Blumenthal (The Grayzone), Nick Cruse (Fred Hampton Leftist Network), Mike MacRae, and Stef Zamorano! Phone calls from Al Pacino and Joe Biden!]]></itunes:subtitle>
			<itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
		<itunes:summary>Establishment Fear Mongers Covid Risk in Children! Featuring Max Blumenthal (The Grayzone), Nick Cruse (Fred Hampton Leftist Network), Mike MacRae, and Stef Zamorano! Phone calls from Al Pacino and Joe Biden!</itunes:summary></item>
		<item>
			<title>Workers Rebelling Against Vaxx Mandates!</title>
			<itunes:title>Workers Rebelling Against Vaxx Mandates!</itunes:title>
			<pubDate>Thu, 04 Nov 2021 05:04:42 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false"><![CDATA[9ae5e5b1-f2f3-45f0-b703-dc9cacf88871]]></guid>
			<link><![CDATA[https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/thejimmydoreshow/TJDS_20211103_Podcast.mp3]]></link>
			<itunes:image href="https://ssl-static.libsyn.com/p/assets/a/7/7/3/a773d61d8e46b30c88c4a68c3ddbc4f2/dsfxzcefew.jpg"/>
			<description><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: left;">Real Reasons Dems Lost Virginia!</p> <p style="text-align: left;">Progressives Completely Cave To Establishment!</p> <p style="text-align: left;">Featuring Professor Richard Wolff, Nick Cruse, Mike MacRae, and Stef Zamorano!</p>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: left;">Real Reasons Dems Lost Virginia!</p> <p style="text-align: left;">Progressives Completely Cave To Establishment!</p> <p style="text-align: left;">Featuring Professor Richard Wolff, Nick Cruse, Mike MacRae, and Stef Zamorano!</p>]]></content:encoded>
			<enclosure length="75232530" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/thejimmydoreshow/TJDS_20211103_Podcast.mp3?dest-id=19460"/>
			<itunes:duration>01:18:13</itunes:duration>
			<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
			<itunes:keywords/>
			<itunes:subtitle><![CDATA[Real Reasons Dems Lost Virginia! Progressives Completely Cave To Establishment! Featuring Professor Richard Wolff, Nick Cruse, Mike MacRae, and Stef Zamorano!]]></itunes:subtitle>
			<itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
		<itunes:summary>Real Reasons Dems Lost Virginia! Progressives Completely Cave To Establishment! Featuring Professor Richard Wolff, Nick Cruse, Mike MacRae, and Stef Zamorano!</itunes:summary></item>
		<item>
			<title>The End Of Fauci!</title>
			<itunes:title>The End Of Fauci!</itunes:title>
			<pubDate>Thu, 28 Oct 2021 05:59:09 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false"><![CDATA[a9bd30ee-e521-4e44-a80e-03db5084ad5c]]></guid>
			<link><![CDATA[https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/thejimmydoreshow/TJDS_20211027_Podcast.mp3]]></link>
			<itunes:image href="https://ssl-static.libsyn.com/p/assets/f/9/5/0/f9502db6da7ece855f2e77a3093c12a1/cascassadadFAUCI_TWO.jpg"/>
			<description><![CDATA[<p>Fauci Funded Horrific Experiment on Dogs!</p> <p>Bill Gates's Diabolical Digital ID Will Control Your Life!</p> <p>Featuring Max Blumenthal, Mike MacRae, and Stef Zamorano!</p> <p>Phone calls from Noam Chomsky & Joe Biden!</p>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Fauci Funded Horrific Experiment on Dogs!</p> <p>Bill Gates's Diabolical Digital ID Will Control Your Life!</p> <p>Featuring Max Blumenthal, Mike MacRae, and Stef Zamorano!</p> <p>Phone calls from Noam Chomsky & Joe Biden!</p>]]></content:encoded>
			<enclosure length="65708520" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/thejimmydoreshow/TJDS_20211027_Podcast.mp3?dest-id=19460"/>
			<itunes:duration>01:07:45</itunes:duration>
			<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
			<itunes:keywords/>
			<itunes:subtitle><![CDATA[Fauci Funded Horrific Experiment on Dogs! Bill Gates's Diabolical Digital ID Will Control Your Life! Featuring Max Blumenthal, Mike MacRae, and Stef Zamorano! Phone calls from Noam Chomsky & Joe Biden!]]></itunes:subtitle>
			<itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
		<itunes:summary>Fauci Funded Horrific Experiment on Dogs! Bill Gates's Diabolical Digital ID Will Control Your Life! Featuring Max Blumenthal, Mike MacRae, and Stef Zamorano! Phone calls from Noam Chomsky &amp; Joe Biden!</itunes:summary></item>
		<item>
			<title>Colin Powell, War Criminal</title>
			<itunes:title>Colin Powell, War Criminal</itunes:title>
			<pubDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2021 04:51:02 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false"><![CDATA[14880400-56f2-4401-a9cb-b4856a546497]]></guid>
			<link><![CDATA[https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/thejimmydoreshow/TJDS_20211020_Podcast.mp3]]></link>
			<itunes:image href="https://ssl-static.libsyn.com/p/assets/7/b/1/2/7b1283f1864bf00ae55e3c100dce7605/dsjdfewwqfqf.jpg"/>
			<description><![CDATA[<p>Should We Vaxx Children?</p> <p>Secret Recordings Expose How Politicians Are Bought!</p> <p>Featuring Stef Zamorano, Mike MacRae, and Max Blumenthal, editor of The Grayzone.</p> <p>Phone calls from Joe Biden and Noam Chomsky!</p>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Should We Vaxx Children?</p> <p>Secret Recordings Expose How Politicians Are Bought!</p> <p>Featuring Stef Zamorano, Mike MacRae, and Max Blumenthal, editor of The Grayzone.</p> <p>Phone calls from Joe Biden and Noam Chomsky!</p>]]></content:encoded>
			<enclosure length="67478764" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/thejimmydoreshow/TJDS_20211020_Podcast.mp3?dest-id=19460"/>
			<itunes:duration>01:10:07</itunes:duration>
			<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
			<itunes:keywords/>
			<itunes:subtitle><![CDATA[Should We Vaxx Children? Secret Recordings Expose How Politicians Are Bought! Featuring Stef Zamorano, Mike MacRae, and Max Blumenthal, editor of The Grayzone. Phone calls from Joe Biden and Noam Chomsky!]]></itunes:subtitle>
			<itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
		<itunes:summary>Should We Vaxx Children? Secret Recordings Expose How Politicians Are Bought! Featuring Stef Zamorano, Mike MacRae, and Max Blumenthal, editor of The Grayzone. Phone calls from Joe Biden and Noam Chomsky!</itunes:summary></item>
		<item>
			<title>Biden's Approval Ratings Plummet!</title>
			<itunes:title>Biden's Approval Ratings Plummet!</itunes:title>
			<pubDate>Thu, 14 Oct 2021 04:15:43 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false"><![CDATA[27e2c677-8698-4554-a0a5-141656de6586]]></guid>
			<link><![CDATA[https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/thejimmydoreshow/TJDS_20211013_Podcast.mp3]]></link>
			<itunes:image href="https://ssl-static.libsyn.com/p/assets/7/f/c/c/7fcc8cd6cb907a22e5bbc093207a2619/dsawq21asd12e2e1e2.jpg"/>
			<description><![CDATA[<p>More AOC Word Salad Excuses! Facebook "WhistleBlower" Pushes For Censorship! Unvaxxed Patient Denied Kidney Transplant!</p> <p>Featuring Nick Cruse (Fred Hampton Leftists Network), Mike MacRae and Stef Zamorano!</p> <p>Phone Calls from Al Pacino, Barrack Obama, and Bernie Sanders!</p>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>More AOC Word Salad Excuses! Facebook "WhistleBlower" Pushes For Censorship! Unvaxxed Patient Denied Kidney Transplant!</p> <p>Featuring Nick Cruse (Fred Hampton Leftists Network), Mike MacRae and Stef Zamorano!</p> <p>Phone Calls from Al Pacino, Barrack Obama, and Bernie Sanders!</p>]]></content:encoded>
			<enclosure length="64002816" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/thejimmydoreshow/TJDS_20211013_Podcast.mp3?dest-id=19460"/>
			<itunes:duration>01:06:18</itunes:duration>
			<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
			<itunes:keywords/>
			<itunes:subtitle><![CDATA[More AOC Word Salad Excuses! Facebook "WhistleBlower" Pushes For Censorship! Unvaxxed Patient Denied Kidney Transplant! Featuring Nick Cruse (Fred Hampton Leftists Network), Mike MacRae and Stef Zamorano! Phone Calls from Al Pacino, Barrack Obama, and...]]></itunes:subtitle>
			<itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
		<itunes:summary>More AOC Word Salad Excuses! Facebook "WhistleBlower" Pushes For Censorship! Unvaxxed Patient Denied Kidney Transplant! Featuring Nick Cruse (Fred Hampton Leftists Network), Mike MacRae and Stef Zamorano! Phone Calls from Al Pacino, Barrack Obama, and Bernie Sanders!</itunes:summary></item>
		<item>
			<title>EXPLOSIVE Truth About Vaccines &amp; Covid!</title>
			<itunes:title>EXPLOSIVE Truth About Vaccines &amp; Covid!</itunes:title>
			<pubDate>Thu, 07 Oct 2021 05:48:39 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false"><![CDATA[d4385f36-26e6-4736-ba9c-e7c49e5654c3]]></guid>
			<link><![CDATA[https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/thejimmydoreshow/TJDS_20211006_Podcast.mp3]]></link>
			<itunes:image href="https://ssl-static.libsyn.com/p/assets/6/1/d/1/61d1cd62dd55721e27a2322813b393ee/assaddsfsgw.jpg"/>
			<description><![CDATA[<p>Special Guest: Dr. Robert Malone, inventor of the mRNA vaccine technology.</p> <p>Featuring Stef Zamorano and Mike MacRae!</p>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Special Guest: Dr. Robert Malone, inventor of the mRNA vaccine technology.</p> <p>Featuring Stef Zamorano and Mike MacRae!</p>]]></content:encoded>
			<enclosure length="70455174" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/thejimmydoreshow/TJDS_20211006_Podcast.mp3?dest-id=19460"/>
			<itunes:duration>01:13:17</itunes:duration>
			<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
			<itunes:keywords/>
			<itunes:subtitle><![CDATA[Special Guest: Dr. Robert Malone, inventor of the mRNA vaccine technology. Featuring Stef Zamorano and Mike MacRae!]]></itunes:subtitle>
			<itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
		<itunes:summary>Special Guest: Dr. Robert Malone, inventor of the mRNA vaccine technology. Featuring Stef Zamorano and Mike MacRae!</itunes:summary></item>
		<item>
			<title>Russell Brand and CIA's Assassination Plots</title>
			<itunes:title>Russell Brand &amp; CIA's Assassination Plots</itunes:title>
			<pubDate>Thu, 30 Sep 2021 13:55:35 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false"><![CDATA[1edaf5a0-8c97-45c5-a10a-a79c959a6913]]></guid>
			<link><![CDATA[https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/thejimmydoreshow/TJDS_20210929_Podcast.mp3]]></link>
			<itunes:image href="https://ssl-static.libsyn.com/p/assets/3/7/0/0/3700c47c33823370a04421dee9605cbd/qdasdhjggj.jpg"/>
			<description><![CDATA[<p>Guests:  GLENN GREENWALD, Pulitzer Prize winning journalist.</p> <p>MAX BLUMENTHAL, editor of The Grayzone.</p> <p>Featuring Stef Zamorano & Mike MacRae.</p> <p>Phone calls from Joe Biden, Mitt Romney, Barack Obama.</p>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Guests:  GLENN GREENWALD, Pulitzer Prize winning journalist.</p> <p>MAX BLUMENTHAL, editor of The Grayzone.</p> <p>Featuring Stef Zamorano & Mike MacRae.</p> <p>Phone calls from Joe Biden, Mitt Romney, Barack Obama.</p>]]></content:encoded>
			<enclosure length="53535570" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/thejimmydoreshow/TJDS_20210929_Podcast.mp3?dest-id=19460"/>
			<itunes:duration>55:20</itunes:duration>
			<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
			<itunes:keywords/>
			<itunes:subtitle><![CDATA[Guests:  GLENN GREENWALD, Pulitzer Prize winning journalist. MAX BLUMENTHAL, editor of The Grayzone. Featuring Stef Zamorano & Mike MacRae. Phone calls from Joe Biden, Mitt Romney, Barack Obama.]]></itunes:subtitle>
			<itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
		<itunes:summary>Guests:  GLENN GREENWALD, Pulitzer Prize winning journalist. MAX BLUMENTHAL, editor of The Grayzone. Featuring Stef Zamorano &amp; Mike MacRae. Phone calls from Joe Biden, Mitt Romney, Barack Obama.</itunes:summary></item>
		<item>
			<title>Hillary Clinton Lawyer Indicted For RussiaGate Lying!</title>
			<itunes:title>Hillary Clinton Lawyer Indicted For RussiaGate Lying!</itunes:title>
			<pubDate>Thu, 23 Sep 2021 04:28:15 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false"><![CDATA[be1f9b96-d0de-4afa-9488-4f39af764718]]></guid>
			<link><![CDATA[https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/thejimmydoreshow/TJDS_20210921_Podcast.mp3]]></link>
			<itunes:image href="https://ssl-static.libsyn.com/p/assets/f/4/9/2/f49252b12ae8c39c40be95ea3302a6a1/2eqwdqwd3re23wfsd.jpg"/>
			<description><![CDATA[<p>Bill Gates squirms over Jeffrey Epstein questions!</p> <p>Guest: award-winning journalist Aaron Mate!</p> <p>Featuring Mike MacRae and Stef Zamorano!</p> <p>Phone calls from Matthew McConaughey, Joe Biden, Barack Obama!</p>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Bill Gates squirms over Jeffrey Epstein questions!</p> <p>Guest: award-winning journalist Aaron Mate!</p> <p>Featuring Mike MacRae and Stef Zamorano!</p> <p>Phone calls from Matthew McConaughey, Joe Biden, Barack Obama!</p>]]></content:encoded>
			<enclosure length="64929436" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/thejimmydoreshow/TJDS_20210921_Podcast.mp3?dest-id=19460"/>
			<itunes:duration>01:07:25</itunes:duration>
			<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
			<itunes:keywords/>
			<itunes:subtitle><![CDATA[Bill Gates squirms over Jeffrey Epstein questions! Guest: award-winning journalist Aaron Mate! Featuring Mike MacRae and Stef Zamorano! Phone calls from Matthew McConaughey, Joe Biden, Barack Obama!]]></itunes:subtitle>
			<itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
		<itunes:summary>Bill Gates squirms over Jeffrey Epstein questions! Guest: award-winning journalist Aaron Mate! Featuring Mike MacRae and Stef Zamorano! Phone calls from Matthew McConaughey, Joe Biden, Barack Obama!</itunes:summary></item>
		<item>
			<title>AOC's Stunts Are No Threat To Estsablishment</title>
			<itunes:title>AOC's Stunts Are No Threat To Estsablishment</itunes:title>
			<pubDate>Thu, 16 Sep 2021 05:47:38 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false"><![CDATA[fc6e4ad0-3269-4cb8-9806-6088de1ae202]]></guid>
			<link><![CDATA[https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/thejimmydoreshow/TJDS_20210916_Podcast.mp3]]></link>
			<itunes:image href="https://ssl-static.libsyn.com/p/assets/c/0/b/5/c0b5d709b7a86aa7e55e3c100dce7605/2e1easaswqdwq.jpg"/>
			<description><![CDATA[<p>Special Guests:  GLENN GREENWALD, Pulitzer Prize winning journalist.   NICK CRUSE, co-founder of the Fred Hampton Leftist Network.</p> <p>Featuring Stef Zamorano and Mike MacRae.   Phone calls from Vince Vaughn, Joe Biden, Noam Chomsky, and Barack Obama.</p> <p> </p>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Special Guests:  GLENN GREENWALD, Pulitzer Prize winning journalist.   NICK CRUSE, co-founder of the Fred Hampton Leftist Network.</p> <p>Featuring Stef Zamorano and Mike MacRae.   Phone calls from Vince Vaughn, Joe Biden, Noam Chomsky, and Barack Obama.</p> <p> </p>]]></content:encoded>
			<enclosure length="57943474" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/thejimmydoreshow/TJDS_20210916_Podcast.mp3?dest-id=19460"/>
			<itunes:duration>01:00:03</itunes:duration>
			<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
			<itunes:keywords/>
			<itunes:subtitle><![CDATA[Special Guests:  GLENN GREENWALD, Pulitzer Prize winning journalist.   NICK CRUSE, co-founder of the Fred Hampton Leftist Network. Featuring Stef Zamorano and Mike MacRae.   Phone calls from Vince Vaughn, Joe Biden, Noam...]]></itunes:subtitle>
			<itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
		<itunes:summary>Special Guests:  GLENN GREENWALD, Pulitzer Prize winning journalist.   NICK CRUSE, co-founder of the Fred Hampton Leftist Network. Featuring Stef Zamorano and Mike MacRae.   Phone calls from Vince Vaughn, Joe Biden, Noam Chomsky, and Barack Obama.  </itunes:summary></item>
		<item>
			<title>Bill Maher's Dumbest Rant Yet!</title>
			<itunes:title>Bill Maher's Dumbest Rant Yet!</itunes:title>
			<pubDate>Thu, 09 Sep 2021 05:04:11 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false"><![CDATA[6f2aa7d7-52d3-4bc1-8625-94390360b8cb]]></guid>
			<link><![CDATA[https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/thejimmydoreshow/TJDS_20210908_Podcast.mp3]]></link>
			<itunes:image href="https://ssl-static.libsyn.com/p/assets/3/c/8/8/3c8836d903d026b45f2e77a3093c12a1/asdasBILL_MAHEREED.jpg"/>
			<description><![CDATA[<p>Bernie Kicks Host Off Podcast and Embarrasses Himself!</p> <p>Obama's Presidential Library Screws Over Chicago!</p> <p>Phone calls from Joe Biden, Noam Chomsky, Bernie Sanders!</p> <p>Featuring Aaron Mate, Mike MacRae, and Stef Zamorano!</p>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Bernie Kicks Host Off Podcast and Embarrasses Himself!</p> <p>Obama's Presidential Library Screws Over Chicago!</p> <p>Phone calls from Joe Biden, Noam Chomsky, Bernie Sanders!</p> <p>Featuring Aaron Mate, Mike MacRae, and Stef Zamorano!</p>]]></content:encoded>
			<enclosure length="65886245" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/thejimmydoreshow/TJDS_20210908_Podcast.mp3?dest-id=19460"/>
			<itunes:duration>01:08:38</itunes:duration>
			<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
			<itunes:keywords/>
			<itunes:subtitle><![CDATA[Bernie Kicks Host Off Podcast and Embarrasses Himself! Obama's Presidential Library Screws Over Chicago! Phone calls from Joe Biden, Noam Chomsky, Bernie Sanders! Featuring Aaron Mate, Mike MacRae, and Stef Zamorano!]]></itunes:subtitle>
			<itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
		<itunes:summary>Bernie Kicks Host Off Podcast and Embarrasses Himself! Obama's Presidential Library Screws Over Chicago! Phone calls from Joe Biden, Noam Chomsky, Bernie Sanders! Featuring Aaron Mate, Mike MacRae, and Stef Zamorano!</itunes:summary></item>
		<item>
			<title>Dems Still Blaming Susan Sarandon!</title>
			<itunes:title>Dems Still Blaming Susan Sarandon!</itunes:title>
			<pubDate>Thu, 02 Sep 2021 12:53:04 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false"><![CDATA[ebdfd0be-262f-4e73-9135-98d64c1b1c59]]></guid>
			<link><![CDATA[https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/thejimmydoreshow/TJDS_20210901_Podcast.mp3]]></link>
			<itunes:image href="https://ssl-static.libsyn.com/p/assets/a/0/f/4/a0f4c37beca15df8a04421dee9605cbd/hgfr56.jpg"/>
			<description><![CDATA[<p>The Squad's Grandstanding Flops! JusticeDems Dark Money!</p> <p>Phone calls from Joe Biden, Liam Neeson, and Mitt Romney!</p> <p>Featuring Mike MacRae and Stef Zamorano!</p>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Squad's Grandstanding Flops! JusticeDems Dark Money!</p> <p>Phone calls from Joe Biden, Liam Neeson, and Mitt Romney!</p> <p>Featuring Mike MacRae and Stef Zamorano!</p>]]></content:encoded>
			<enclosure length="63253723" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/thejimmydoreshow/TJDS_20210901_Podcast.mp3?dest-id=19460"/>
			<itunes:duration>01:05:38</itunes:duration>
			<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
			<itunes:keywords/>
			<itunes:subtitle><![CDATA[The Squad's Grandstanding Flops! JusticeDems Dark Money! Phone calls from Joe Biden, Liam Neeson, and Mitt Romney! Featuring Mike MacRae and Stef Zamorano!]]></itunes:subtitle>
			<itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
		<itunes:summary>The Squad's Grandstanding Flops! JusticeDems Dark Money! Phone calls from Joe Biden, Liam Neeson, and Mitt Romney! Featuring Mike MacRae and Stef Zamorano!</itunes:summary></item>
		<item>
			<title>Truth, Censorship, and America</title>
			<itunes:title>Truth, Censorship, and America</itunes:title>
			<pubDate>Thu, 26 Aug 2021 03:25:29 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false"><![CDATA[d9cec55b-c345-4e74-b49e-5e5a380a7a3f]]></guid>
			<link><![CDATA[https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/thejimmydoreshow/TJDS_20210825_Podcast.mp3]]></link>
			<itunes:image href="https://ssl-static.libsyn.com/p/assets/4/5/e/f/45ef0d18b7fd70f8e5bbc093207a2619/live_stresmeddd.jpg"/>
			<description><![CDATA[<p>Guest: CHRIS HEDGES, Pulitzer Prize winning journalist!</p> <p>Featuring Mike MacRae and Stef Zamorano.</p> <p>Phone calls from Andrew Cuomo, Bernie Sanders, and Joe Biden.</p>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Guest: CHRIS HEDGES, Pulitzer Prize winning journalist!</p> <p>Featuring Mike MacRae and Stef Zamorano.</p> <p>Phone calls from Andrew Cuomo, Bernie Sanders, and Joe Biden.</p>]]></content:encoded>
			<enclosure length="60260252" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/thejimmydoreshow/TJDS_20210825_Podcast.mp3?dest-id=19460"/>
			<itunes:duration>01:02:38</itunes:duration>
			<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
			<itunes:keywords/>
			<itunes:subtitle><![CDATA[Guest: CHRIS HEDGES, Pulitzer Prize winning journalist! Featuring Mike MacRae and Stef Zamorano. Phone calls from Andrew Cuomo, Bernie Sanders, and Joe Biden.]]></itunes:subtitle>
			<itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
		<itunes:summary>Guest: CHRIS HEDGES, Pulitzer Prize winning journalist! Featuring Mike MacRae and Stef Zamorano. Phone calls from Andrew Cuomo, Bernie Sanders, and Joe Biden.</itunes:summary></item>
		<item>
			<title>Secret Documents Predicted Afghan Disaster</title>
			<itunes:title>Secret Documents Predicted Afghan Disaster</itunes:title>
			<pubDate>Thu, 19 Aug 2021 05:08:38 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false"><![CDATA[534e78a0-c8cf-4eef-b471-e94d992974e5]]></guid>
			<link><![CDATA[https://thejimmydoreshow.libsyn.com/secret-documents-predicted-afghan-disaster]]></link>
			<itunes:image href="https://ssl-static.libsyn.com/p/assets/2/7/9/7/27976580a7a32019e5bbc093207a2619/ihuhhhi.jpg"/>
			<description><![CDATA[<p>"Not My Fault" Says Biden & Kamala On Afghanistan!</p> <p>War Mongers Cynically Use "Protecting Women" To Extend War!</p> <p>Featuring Stef Zamorano, Ron Placone, and Mike MacRae!</p> <p>Phone calls from Barack Obama, Noam Chomsky, Joe Biden, and David Axelrod!</p>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>"Not My Fault" Says Biden & Kamala On Afghanistan!</p> <p>War Mongers Cynically Use "Protecting Women" To Extend War!</p> <p>Featuring Stef Zamorano, Ron Placone, and Mike MacRae!</p> <p>Phone calls from Barack Obama, Noam Chomsky, Joe Biden, and David Axelrod!</p>]]></content:encoded>
			<enclosure length="68482622" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/thejimmydoreshow/TJDS_20210818_Podcast.mp3?dest-id=19460"/>
			<itunes:duration>01:11:01</itunes:duration>
			<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
			<itunes:keywords/>
			<itunes:subtitle><![CDATA["Not My Fault" Says Biden & Kamala On Afghanistan! War Mongers Cynically Use "Protecting Women" To Extend War! Featuring Stef Zamorano, Ron Placone, and Mike MacRae! Phone calls from Barack Obama, Noam Chomsky, Joe Biden, and David Axelrod!]]></itunes:subtitle>
			<itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
		<itunes:summary>"Not My Fault" Says Biden &amp; Kamala On Afghanistan! War Mongers Cynically Use "Protecting Women" To Extend War! Featuring Stef Zamorano, Ron Placone, and Mike MacRae! Phone calls from Barack Obama, Noam Chomsky, Joe Biden, and David Axelrod!</itunes:summary></item>
		<item>
			<title>Olbermann Wants Jimmy Censored!</title>
			<itunes:title>Olbermann Wants Jimmy Censored!</itunes:title>
			<pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2021 04:45:50 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false"><![CDATA[a53502cd-e613-4df9-afdf-e9b32a50b0e2]]></guid>
			<link><![CDATA[https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/thejimmydoreshow/TJDS_20210811_Podcast.mp3]]></link>
			<itunes:image href="https://ssl-static.libsyn.com/p/assets/5/4/f/2/54f2641db3f6fb38bafc7308ab683e82/sdsdffweolbermann_thumb.jpg"/>
			<description><![CDATA[<p>Biden Drilling More Than Trump!</p> <p>Daniel Hale, American Hero!</p> <p>Featuring Aaron Mate, Ron Placone, Mike MacRae, and Stef Zamorano!</p>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Biden Drilling More Than Trump!</p> <p>Daniel Hale, American Hero!</p> <p>Featuring Aaron Mate, Ron Placone, Mike MacRae, and Stef Zamorano!</p>]]></content:encoded>
			<enclosure length="53262227" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/thejimmydoreshow/TJDS_20210811_Podcast.mp3?dest-id=19460"/>
			<itunes:duration>55:16</itunes:duration>
			<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
			<itunes:keywords/>
			<itunes:subtitle><![CDATA[Biden Drilling More Than Trump! Daniel Hale, American Hero! Featuring Aaron Mate, Ron Placone, Mike MacRae, and Stef Zamorano!]]></itunes:subtitle>
			<itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
		<itunes:summary>Biden Drilling More Than Trump! Daniel Hale, American Hero! Featuring Aaron Mate, Ron Placone, Mike MacRae, and Stef Zamorano!</itunes:summary></item>
		<item>
			<title>Report Shows Cuomo Guilty!</title>
			<itunes:title>Report Shows Cuomo Guilty!</itunes:title>
			<pubDate>Thu, 05 Aug 2021 20:33:33 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false"><![CDATA[148db9c0-fb5c-4168-85b2-ba018b13cee6]]></guid>
			<link><![CDATA[https://thejimmydoreshow.libsyn.com/report-shows-cuomo-guilty]]></link>
			<itunes:image href="https://ssl-static.libsyn.com/p/assets/5/4/9/5/54952447d1019fc127a2322813b393ee/eqweqwqdwasc.jpg"/>
			<description><![CDATA[<p>War Monger Confronted by Reporter!</p> <p>Independent Media Targeted!</p> <p>Featuring journalist Max Blumenthal, Mike MacRae, and Stef Zamorano!</p>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>War Monger Confronted by Reporter!</p> <p>Independent Media Targeted!</p> <p>Featuring journalist Max Blumenthal, Mike MacRae, and Stef Zamorano!</p>]]></content:encoded>
			<enclosure length="61094166" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/thejimmydoreshow/TJDS_20210805_Podcast.mp3?dest-id=19460"/>
			<itunes:duration>01:03:32</itunes:duration>
			<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
			<itunes:keywords/>
			<itunes:subtitle><![CDATA[War Monger Confronted by Reporter! Independent Media Targeted! Featuring journalist Max Blumenthal, Mike MacRae, and Stef Zamorano!]]></itunes:subtitle>
			<itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
		<itunes:summary>War Monger Confronted by Reporter! Independent Media Targeted! Featuring journalist Max Blumenthal, Mike MacRae, and Stef Zamorano!</itunes:summary></item>
		<item>
			<title>Biden's Bizarre Town Hall!</title>
			<itunes:title>Biden's Bizarre Town Hall!</itunes:title>
			<pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 05:51:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false"><![CDATA[489b2ed2-5b94-4643-b213-769e2296a671]]></guid>
			<link><![CDATA[https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/thejimmydoreshow/TJDS_20210728_Podcast.mp3]]></link>
			<itunes:image href="https://ssl-static.libsyn.com/p/assets/d/9/f/8/d9f8d5bf2df3fd40e5bbc093207a2619/2dqwwdq.jpg"/>
			<description><![CDATA[<p>FBI Instigated Kidnapping Plot Of Michigan Governor!</p> <p>Special Guest: Paula Jean Swearengin, Justice Democrat!</p> <p>Featuring Stef Zamorano, Ron Placone, and Graham Elwood!</p> <p>Phone calls from Noam Chomsky, Bernie Sanders, and Joe Biden!</p>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>FBI Instigated Kidnapping Plot Of Michigan Governor!</p> <p>Special Guest: Paula Jean Swearengin, Justice Democrat!</p> <p>Featuring Stef Zamorano, Ron Placone, and Graham Elwood!</p> <p>Phone calls from Noam Chomsky, Bernie Sanders, and Joe Biden!</p>]]></content:encoded>
			<enclosure length="57648790" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/thejimmydoreshow/TJDS_20210728_Podcast.mp3?dest-id=19460"/>
			<itunes:duration>59:57</itunes:duration>
			<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
			<itunes:keywords/>
			<itunes:subtitle><![CDATA[FBI Instigated Kidnapping Plot Of Michigan Governor! Special Guest: Paula Jean Swearengin, Justice Democrat! Featuring Stef Zamorano, Ron Placone, and Graham Elwood! Phone calls from Noam Chomsky, Bernie Sanders, and Joe Biden!]]></itunes:subtitle>
			<itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
		<itunes:summary>FBI Instigated Kidnapping Plot Of Michigan Governor! Special Guest: Paula Jean Swearengin, Justice Democrat! Featuring Stef Zamorano, Ron Placone, and Graham Elwood! Phone calls from Noam Chomsky, Bernie Sanders, and Joe Biden!</itunes:summary></item>
		<item>
			<title>Biden Drug Hypocrisy! </title>
			<itunes:title>Biden Drug Hypocrisy! </itunes:title>
			<pubDate>Thu, 22 Jul 2021 06:18:08 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false"><![CDATA[d503b9b6-d0e6-4bd1-ab2b-3f444cbda9aa]]></guid>
			<link><![CDATA[https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/thejimmydoreshow/TJDS_20210722_Podcast.mp3]]></link>
			<itunes:image href="https://ssl-static.libsyn.com/p/assets/0/9/2/b/092ba7f855031e8e16c3140a3186d450/2wqdsdq.jpg"/>
			<description><![CDATA[<p>Biden Orders Air Strikes On Somalia!</p> <p>The Truth About Cuba!</p> <p>Phone calls from Al Pacino, Joe Biden, Bernie Sanders, and Joe Manchin!</p> <p>Featuring Graham Elwood, Max Blumenthal, Mike MacRae, and Stef Zamorano!</p>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Biden Orders Air Strikes On Somalia!</p> <p>The Truth About Cuba!</p> <p>Phone calls from Al Pacino, Joe Biden, Bernie Sanders, and Joe Manchin!</p> <p>Featuring Graham Elwood, Max Blumenthal, Mike MacRae, and Stef Zamorano!</p>]]></content:encoded>
			<enclosure length="67408270" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/thejimmydoreshow/TJDS_20210722_Podcast.mp3?dest-id=19460"/>
			<itunes:duration>01:09:55</itunes:duration>
			<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
			<itunes:keywords/>
			<itunes:subtitle><![CDATA[Biden Orders Air Strikes On Somalia! The Truth About Cuba! Phone calls from Al Pacino, Joe Biden, Bernie Sanders, and Joe Manchin! Featuring Graham Elwood, Max Blumenthal, Mike MacRae, and Stef Zamorano!]]></itunes:subtitle>
			<itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
		<itunes:summary>Biden Orders Air Strikes On Somalia! The Truth About Cuba! Phone calls from Al Pacino, Joe Biden, Bernie Sanders, and Joe Manchin! Featuring Graham Elwood, Max Blumenthal, Mike MacRae, and Stef Zamorano!</itunes:summary></item>
		<item>
			<title>Blackmailers Contradict Each Other!</title>
			<itunes:title>Blackmailers Contradict Each Other!</itunes:title>
			<pubDate>Thu, 15 Jul 2021 16:09:40 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false"><![CDATA[c973fb72-52f5-4ba4-8c23-ef35307c563c]]></guid>
			<link><![CDATA[https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/thejimmydoreshow/TJDS_20210715_Podcast.mp3]]></link>
			<itunes:image href="https://ssl-static.libsyn.com/p/assets/a/6/8/b/a68b8d69dc2d8c2b5f2e77a3093c12a1/qwdsac.jpg"/>
			<description><![CDATA[<p>The Young Turks attack the foremost journalists of our era!</p> <p>Special guest: award winning journalist "BuzzSaw" Aaron Maté!</p> <p>Phone calls from Joe Biden, Vladimir Putin, and Harrison Ford!</p> <p>Featuring Stef Zamorano and Mike MacRae!</p>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Young Turks attack the foremost journalists of our era!</p> <p>Special guest: award winning journalist "BuzzSaw" Aaron Maté!</p> <p>Phone calls from Joe Biden, Vladimir Putin, and Harrison Ford!</p> <p>Featuring Stef Zamorano and Mike MacRae!</p>]]></content:encoded>
			<enclosure length="64063152" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/thejimmydoreshow/TJDS_20210715_Podcast.mp3?dest-id=19460"/>
			<itunes:duration>01:06:34</itunes:duration>
			<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
			<itunes:keywords/>
			<itunes:subtitle><![CDATA[The Young Turks attack the foremost journalists of our era! Special guest: award winning journalist "BuzzSaw" Aaron Maté! Phone calls from Joe Biden, Vladimir Putin, and Harrison Ford! Featuring Stef Zamorano and Mike MacRae!]]></itunes:subtitle>
			<itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
		<itunes:summary>The Young Turks attack the foremost journalists of our era! Special guest: award winning journalist "BuzzSaw" Aaron Maté! Phone calls from Joe Biden, Vladimir Putin, and Harrison Ford! Featuring Stef Zamorano and Mike MacRae!</itunes:summary></item>
		<item>
			<title>Biden Wants You To Snitch On Family &amp; Friends!</title>
			<itunes:title>Biden Wants You To Snitch On Family &amp; Friends!</itunes:title>
			<pubDate>Thu, 08 Jul 2021 21:31:14 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false"><![CDATA[88030e8e-c0de-4d4a-a794-3db28df83c04]]></guid>
			<link><![CDATA[https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/thejimmydoreshow/TJDS_20210708_podcast.mp3]]></link>
			<itunes:image href="https://ssl-static.libsyn.com/p/assets/e/e/2/b/ee2baae7e9bdef0e16c3140a3186d450/amosm22.jpg"/>
			<description><![CDATA[<p>Jimmy truth bombs TYT about Syria!</p> <p>Case against Julian Assange collapses!</p> <p>Biden illegally bombs Middle East again!</p> <p>Phone calls from Noam Chomsky, Joe Biden, and Barack Obama!</p> <p>Featuring Stef Zamorano, Ron Placone, and Mike MacRae!</p>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Jimmy truth bombs TYT about Syria!</p> <p>Case against Julian Assange collapses!</p> <p>Biden illegally bombs Middle East again!</p> <p>Phone calls from Noam Chomsky, Joe Biden, and Barack Obama!</p> <p>Featuring Stef Zamorano, Ron Placone, and Mike MacRae!</p>]]></content:encoded>
			<enclosure length="63583356" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/thejimmydoreshow/TJDS_20210708_podcast.mp3?dest-id=19460"/>
			<itunes:duration>01:05:56</itunes:duration>
			<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
			<itunes:keywords/>
			<itunes:subtitle><![CDATA[Jimmy truth bombs TYT about Syria! Case against Julian Assange collapses! Biden illegally bombs Middle East again! Phone calls from Noam Chomsky, Joe Biden, and Barack Obama! Featuring Stef Zamorano, Ron Placone, and Mike MacRae!]]></itunes:subtitle>
			<itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
		<itunes:summary>Jimmy truth bombs TYT about Syria! Case against Julian Assange collapses! Biden illegally bombs Middle East again! Phone calls from Noam Chomsky, Joe Biden, and Barack Obama! Featuring Stef Zamorano, Ron Placone, and Mike MacRae!</itunes:summary></item>
		<item>
			<title>GLENN GREENWALD - Rachel Maddow Court Ruling!</title>
			<itunes:title>GLENN GREENWALD - Rachel Maddow Court Ruling!</itunes:title>
			<pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2021 08:17:56 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false"><![CDATA[1eb10c16-84df-4417-8206-fce0d0826050]]></guid>
			<link><![CDATA[https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/thejimmydoreshow/TJDS_20210701_Podcast.mp3]]></link>
			<itunes:image href="https://ssl-static.libsyn.com/p/assets/7/0/0/9/70098b08af2811c9e5bbc093207a2619/qwwfdsc.jpg"/>
			<description><![CDATA[<p>Special Guest: Glenn Greenwald, Pulitzer Prize winning journalist!</p> <p>Keith Olbermann Is Bonkers!</p> <p>Court Ruling:  Rachel Maddow Is Not News!</p> <p>Phone calls from Vince Vaughn, Mitt Romney, and Joe Biden!</p> <p>Featuring Mike MacRae and Stef Zamorano!</p>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Special Guest: Glenn Greenwald, Pulitzer Prize winning journalist!</p> <p>Keith Olbermann Is Bonkers!</p> <p>Court Ruling:  Rachel Maddow Is Not News!</p> <p>Phone calls from Vince Vaughn, Mitt Romney, and Joe Biden!</p> <p>Featuring Mike MacRae and Stef Zamorano!</p>]]></content:encoded>
			<enclosure length="53563089" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/thejimmydoreshow/TJDS_20210701_Podcast.mp3?dest-id=19460"/>
			<itunes:duration>55:33</itunes:duration>
			<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
			<itunes:keywords/>
			<itunes:subtitle><![CDATA[Special Guest: Glenn Greenwald, Pulitzer Prize winning journalist! Keith Olbermann Is Bonkers! Court Ruling:  Rachel Maddow Is Not News! Phone calls from Vince Vaughn, Mitt Romney, and Joe Biden! Featuring Mike MacRae and Stef Zamorano!]]></itunes:subtitle>
			<itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
		<itunes:summary>Special Guest: Glenn Greenwald, Pulitzer Prize winning journalist! Keith Olbermann Is Bonkers! Court Ruling:  Rachel Maddow Is Not News! Phone calls from Vince Vaughn, Mitt Romney, and Joe Biden! Featuring Mike MacRae and Stef Zamorano!</itunes:summary></item>
		<item>
			<title>"BuzzSaw" Aaron Mate Strikes Again!</title>
			<itunes:title>"BuzzSaw" Aaron Mate Strikes Again!</itunes:title>
			<pubDate>Thu, 24 Jun 2021 18:27:10 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false"><![CDATA[acea757a-3b6e-4820-86d7-ca21e7a71ae5]]></guid>
			<link><![CDATA[https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/thejimmydoreshow/TJDS_20210624_Podcast.mp3]]></link>
			<itunes:image href="https://ssl-static.libsyn.com/p/assets/2/c/f/5/2cf51359007203295f2e77a3093c12a1/21ewssdf.jpg"/>
			<description><![CDATA[<p>Guest: award winning journalist Aaron Mate!</p> <p>Featuring Mike MacRae and Stef Zamorano!</p> <p>Phone calls from Harrison Ford, Joe Manchin, and Chuck Schumer!</p>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Guest: award winning journalist Aaron Mate!</p> <p>Featuring Mike MacRae and Stef Zamorano!</p> <p>Phone calls from Harrison Ford, Joe Manchin, and Chuck Schumer!</p>]]></content:encoded>
			<enclosure length="67315425" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/thejimmydoreshow/TJDS_20210624_Podcast.mp3?dest-id=19460"/>
			<itunes:duration>46:33</itunes:duration>
			<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
			<itunes:keywords/>
			<itunes:subtitle><![CDATA[Guest: award winning journalist Aaron Mate! Featuring Mike MacRae and Stef Zamorano! Phone calls from Harrison Ford, Joe Manchin, and Chuck Schumer!]]></itunes:subtitle>
			<itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
		<itunes:summary>Guest: award winning journalist Aaron Mate! Featuring Mike MacRae and Stef Zamorano! Phone calls from Harrison Ford, Joe Manchin, and Chuck Schumer!</itunes:summary></item>
		<item>
			<title>The Young Turks EXPOSED!</title>
			<itunes:title>The Young Turks EXPOSED!</itunes:title>
			<pubDate>Thu, 17 Jun 2021 03:05:01 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false"><![CDATA[46d8969f-81ff-42e1-be28-59744891f9c3]]></guid>
			<link><![CDATA[https://thejimmydoreshow.libsyn.com/the-young-turks-exposed]]></link>
			<itunes:image href="https://ssl-static.libsyn.com/p/assets/3/4/e/2/34e20dc0356dd90ee55e3c100dce7605/dsflsdkfwe.jpg"/>
			<description><![CDATA[<p>TYT's Disgusting Misogyny, Hypocrisy, & Their False Accusations EXPOSED!</p> <p>Special Guest: foreign policy journalist Anya Parampil!</p> <p>Phone calls from Jeffrey Toobin! Bernie Sanders! Joe Biden!</p> <p>Featuring Stef Zamorano and Mike MacRae!</p>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>TYT's Disgusting Misogyny, Hypocrisy, & Their False Accusations EXPOSED!</p> <p>Special Guest: foreign policy journalist Anya Parampil!</p> <p>Phone calls from Jeffrey Toobin! Bernie Sanders! Joe Biden!</p> <p>Featuring Stef Zamorano and Mike MacRae!</p>]]></content:encoded>
			<enclosure length="81633115" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/thejimmydoreshow/TJDS_20210617_Podcast.mp3?dest-id=19460"/>
			<itunes:duration>01:24:49</itunes:duration>
			<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
			<itunes:keywords/>
			<itunes:subtitle><![CDATA[TYT's Disgusting Misogyny, Hypocrisy, & Their False Accusations EXPOSED! Special Guest: foreign policy journalist Anya Parampil! Phone calls from Jeffrey Toobin! Bernie Sanders! Joe Biden! Featuring Stef Zamorano and Mike MacRae!]]></itunes:subtitle>
			<itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
		<itunes:summary>TYT's Disgusting Misogyny, Hypocrisy, &amp; Their False Accusations EXPOSED! Special Guest: foreign policy journalist Anya Parampil! Phone calls from Jeffrey Toobin! Bernie Sanders! Joe Biden! Featuring Stef Zamorano and Mike MacRae!</itunes:summary></item>
		<item>
			<title>Creepy Biden Does It Again!</title>
			<itunes:title>Creepy Biden Does It Again!</itunes:title>
			<pubDate>Thu, 10 Jun 2021 05:47:54 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false"><![CDATA[986616d5-27f2-4327-aa41-f79a22b59188]]></guid>
			<link><![CDATA[https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/thejimmydoreshow/TJDS_20210609_Podcast.mp3]]></link>
			<itunes:image href="https://ssl-static.libsyn.com/p/assets/4/d/5/7/4d579291c61125d0e55e3c100dce7605/wjsnksdfs.jpg"/>
			<description><![CDATA[<p>Kamala Harris sounds exactly like Trump!</p> <p>Biden defends discriminating against LGBTQ students!</p> <p>Rep. Jayapal opposes voting on her own bill!</p> <p>Phone calls from Senator Joe Manchin, Barack Obama, and Joe Biden!</p> <p>Featuring Stef Zamorano, Ron Placone, and Mike MacRae!</p> <p> </p> <p> </p>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Kamala Harris sounds exactly like Trump!</p> <p>Biden defends discriminating against LGBTQ students!</p> <p>Rep. Jayapal opposes voting on her own bill!</p> <p>Phone calls from Senator Joe Manchin, Barack Obama, and Joe Biden!</p> <p>Featuring Stef Zamorano, Ron Placone, and Mike MacRae!</p> <p> </p> <p> </p>]]></content:encoded>
			<enclosure length="57582009" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/thejimmydoreshow/TJDS_20210609_Podcast.mp3?dest-id=19460"/>
			<itunes:duration>59:36</itunes:duration>
			<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
			<itunes:keywords/>
			<itunes:subtitle><![CDATA[Kamala Harris sounds exactly like Trump! Biden defends discriminating against LGBTQ students! Rep. Jayapal opposes voting on her own bill! Phone calls from Senator Joe Manchin, Barack Obama, and Joe Biden! Featuring Stef Zamorano, Ron Placone, and...]]></itunes:subtitle>
			<itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
		<itunes:summary>Kamala Harris sounds exactly like Trump! Biden defends discriminating against LGBTQ students! Rep. Jayapal opposes voting on her own bill! Phone calls from Senator Joe Manchin, Barack Obama, and Joe Biden! Featuring Stef Zamorano, Ron Placone, and Mike MacRae!    </itunes:summary></item>
		<item>
			<title>TYT Slanders Real Journalists!</title>
			<itunes:title>TYT Slanders Real Journalists!</itunes:title>
			<pubDate>Thu, 03 Jun 2021 10:37:31 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false"><![CDATA[fd7c0658-87a4-432b-8e5f-7697eccf1bfc]]></guid>
			<link><![CDATA[https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/thejimmydoreshow/TJDS_20210603_Podcast.mp3]]></link>
			<itunes:image href="https://ssl-static.libsyn.com/p/assets/8/d/7/b/8d7b9e7919e53562e55e3c100dce7605/4ddfsds.jpg"/>
			<description><![CDATA[<p>Special Guest:  award winning journalist <span class= "css-901oao css-16my406 r-poiln3 r-bcqeeo r-qvutc0">Aaron Maté, live from Syria!</span></p> <p>The Young Turks Unhinged!</p> <p>Phone calls from Bernie Sanders, Jake Tapper, Vladimir Putin!</p> <p>Featuring Mike MacRae, Ron Placone, and Stef Zamorano!</p>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Special Guest:  award winning journalist Aaron Maté, live from Syria!</p> <p>The Young Turks Unhinged!</p> <p>Phone calls from Bernie Sanders, Jake Tapper, Vladimir Putin!</p> <p>Featuring Mike MacRae, Ron Placone, and Stef Zamorano!</p>]]></content:encoded>
			<enclosure length="61029232" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/thejimmydoreshow/TJDS_20210603_Podcast.mp3?dest-id=19460"/>
			<itunes:duration>01:03:08</itunes:duration>
			<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
			<itunes:keywords/>
			<itunes:subtitle><![CDATA[Special Guest:  award winning journalist Aaron Maté, live from Syria! The Young Turks Unhinged! Phone calls from Bernie Sanders, Jake Tapper, Vladimir Putin! Featuring Mike MacRae, Ron Placone, and Stef Zamorano!]]></itunes:subtitle>
			<itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
		<itunes:summary>Special Guest:  award winning journalist Aaron Maté, live from Syria! The Young Turks Unhinged! Phone calls from Bernie Sanders, Jake Tapper, Vladimir Putin! Featuring Mike MacRae, Ron Placone, and Stef Zamorano!</itunes:summary></item>
		<item>
			<title>COVID Fact Checkers Wrong Again!</title>
			<itunes:title>COVID Fact Checkers Wrong Again!</itunes:title>
			<pubDate>Thu, 27 May 2021 05:52:21 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false"><![CDATA[bf2e69be-059f-452d-89d8-112d172c1d18]]></guid>
			<link><![CDATA[https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/thejimmydoreshow/TJDS_20210526_Podcast.mp3]]></link>
			<itunes:image href="https://ssl-static.libsyn.com/p/assets/2/3/d/6/23d6ca122eefff7c40be95ea3302a6a1/238sdsdd.jpg"/>
			<description><![CDATA[<p>The Squad Votes Strategically!</p> <p>Special Guest:  Matt Taibbi, contributing editor for Rolling Stone Magazine!</p> <p>Phone calls from Al Pacino! Chuck Schumer! Joe Biden!</p> <p>Featuring Mike MacRae, Ron Placone, and Stef Zamorano!</p>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Squad Votes Strategically!</p> <p>Special Guest:  Matt Taibbi, contributing editor for Rolling Stone Magazine!</p> <p>Phone calls from Al Pacino! Chuck Schumer! Joe Biden!</p> <p>Featuring Mike MacRae, Ron Placone, and Stef Zamorano!</p>]]></content:encoded>
			<enclosure length="66379026" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/thejimmydoreshow/TJDS_20210526_Podcast.mp3?dest-id=19460"/>
			<itunes:duration>01:08:43</itunes:duration>
			<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
			<itunes:keywords/>
			<itunes:subtitle><![CDATA[The Squad Votes Strategically! Special Guest:  Matt Taibbi, contributing editor for Rolling Stone Magazine! Phone calls from Al Pacino! Chuck Schumer! Joe Biden! Featuring Mike MacRae, Ron Placone, and Stef Zamorano!]]></itunes:subtitle>
			<itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
		<itunes:summary>The Squad Votes Strategically! Special Guest:  Matt Taibbi, contributing editor for Rolling Stone Magazine! Phone calls from Al Pacino! Chuck Schumer! Joe Biden! Featuring Mike MacRae, Ron Placone, and Stef Zamorano!</itunes:summary></item>
		<item>
			<title>Delay &amp; Distract</title>
			<itunes:title>Delay &amp; Distract!</itunes:title>
			<pubDate>Thu, 20 May 2021 06:22:14 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false"><![CDATA[8e77fd08-1242-44d7-a858-1dc528ad6632]]></guid>
			<link><![CDATA[https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/thejimmydoreshow/TJDS_20210520_Podcast.mp3]]></link>
			<itunes:image href="https://ssl-static.libsyn.com/p/assets/c/2/5/a/c25aa6031c9e09b85f2e77a3093c12a1/dsfnsdj.jpg"/>
			<description><![CDATA[<p>Is Biden A Putin Puppet?</p> <p>Dumbest Conspiracy Theory Just Got Dumber! </p> <p>Phone calls from Al Pacino, Bibi Netanyahu, Barack Obama, and Bernie Sanders!</p> <p>Featuring award winning journalist Aaron Maté, Mike MacRae, Ron Placone, and Stef Zamorano!</p>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Is Biden A Putin Puppet?</p> <p>Dumbest Conspiracy Theory Just Got Dumber! </p> <p>Phone calls from Al Pacino, Bibi Netanyahu, Barack Obama, and Bernie Sanders!</p> <p>Featuring award winning journalist Aaron Maté, Mike MacRae, Ron Placone, and Stef Zamorano!</p>]]></content:encoded>
			<enclosure length="59234014" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/thejimmydoreshow/TJDS_20210520_Podcast.mp3?dest-id=19460"/>
			<itunes:duration>01:01:26</itunes:duration>
			<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
			<itunes:keywords/>
			<itunes:subtitle><![CDATA[Is Biden A Putin Puppet? Dumbest Conspiracy Theory Just Got Dumber!  Phone calls from Al Pacino, Bibi Netanyahu, Barack Obama, and Bernie Sanders! Featuring award winning journalist Aaron Maté, Mike MacRae, Ron Placone, and Stef Zamorano!]]></itunes:subtitle>
			<itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
		<itunes:summary>Is Biden A Putin Puppet? Dumbest Conspiracy Theory Just Got Dumber!  Phone calls from Al Pacino, Bibi Netanyahu, Barack Obama, and Bernie Sanders! Featuring award winning journalist Aaron Maté, Mike MacRae, Ron Placone, and Stef Zamorano!</itunes:summary></item>
		<item>
			<title>Biden Administration Neutral On Child Murder</title>
			<itunes:title>Biden Administration Neutral On Child Murder</itunes:title>
			<pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 04:10:48 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false"><![CDATA[a6180c53-18d5-432e-8924-eb58e73f15f8]]></guid>
			<link><![CDATA[https://thejimmydoreshow.libsyn.com/biden-administration-neutral-on-child-murder]]></link>
			<itunes:image href="https://ssl-static.libsyn.com/p/assets/a/2/9/f/a29f46a445e44b1927a2322813b393ee/dfefwersd.jpg"/>
			<description><![CDATA[<p>Special Guest:  journalist Max Blumenthal, editor of The Grayzone.</p> <p>What Is Really Happening In Israel?</p> <p>Phone calls from Vince Vaughn! David Axelrod! Joe Biden!</p> <p>Featuring Stef Zamorano & Mike MacRae!</p> <p> </p>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Special Guest:  journalist Max Blumenthal, editor of The Grayzone.</p> <p>What Is Really Happening In Israel?</p> <p>Phone calls from Vince Vaughn! David Axelrod! Joe Biden!</p> <p>Featuring Stef Zamorano & Mike MacRae!</p> <p> </p>]]></content:encoded>
			<enclosure length="61973548" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/thejimmydoreshow/TJDS_20210512_Podcast.mp3?dest-id=19460"/>
			<itunes:duration>01:04:12</itunes:duration>
			<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
			<itunes:keywords/>
			<itunes:subtitle><![CDATA[Special Guest:  journalist Max Blumenthal, editor of The Grayzone. What Is Really Happening In Israel? Phone calls from Vince Vaughn! David Axelrod! Joe Biden! Featuring Stef Zamorano & Mike MacRae!  ]]></itunes:subtitle>
			<itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
		<itunes:summary>Special Guest:  journalist Max Blumenthal, editor of The Grayzone. What Is Really Happening In Israel? Phone calls from Vince Vaughn! David Axelrod! Joe Biden! Featuring Stef Zamorano &amp; Mike MacRae!  </itunes:summary></item>
		<item>
			<title>AOC Swindles Her Own Donors!</title>
			<itunes:title>AOC Swindles Her Own Donors!</itunes:title>
			<pubDate>Thu, 06 May 2021 06:14:44 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false"><![CDATA[63717996-58c2-4e48-be38-ad41ad7fb97c]]></guid>
			<link><![CDATA[https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/thejimmydoreshow/TJDS_20210505_Podcast.mp3]]></link>
			<itunes:image href="https://ssl-static.libsyn.com/p/assets/3/a/7/0/3a701835dde0d172e55e3c100dce7605/sdkfjnsdfsd.jpg"/>
			<description><![CDATA[<p>U.S. Coast Guard discovers Persians in the Persian Gulf!</p> <p>Hilarious CIA "Woke" Recruitment Video!</p> <p>Featuring Stef Zamorano, Ron Placone, and Mike MacRae!</p> <p>Phone calls from Bill Gates! Chuck Schumer! Mitt Romney! Joe Biden!</p>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>U.S. Coast Guard discovers Persians in the Persian Gulf!</p> <p>Hilarious CIA "Woke" Recruitment Video!</p> <p>Featuring Stef Zamorano, Ron Placone, and Mike MacRae!</p> <p>Phone calls from Bill Gates! Chuck Schumer! Mitt Romney! Joe Biden!</p>]]></content:encoded>
			<enclosure length="58511655" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/thejimmydoreshow/TJDS_20210505_Podcast.mp3?dest-id=19460"/>
			<itunes:duration>01:00:35</itunes:duration>
			<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
			<itunes:keywords/>
			<itunes:subtitle><![CDATA[U.S. Coast Guard discovers Persians in the Persian Gulf! Hilarious CIA "Woke" Recruitment Video! Featuring Stef Zamorano, Ron Placone, and Mike MacRae! Phone calls from Bill Gates! Chuck Schumer! Mitt Romney! Joe Biden!]]></itunes:subtitle>
			<itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
		<itunes:summary>U.S. Coast Guard discovers Persians in the Persian Gulf! Hilarious CIA "Woke" Recruitment Video! Featuring Stef Zamorano, Ron Placone, and Mike MacRae! Phone calls from Bill Gates! Chuck Schumer! Mitt Romney! Joe Biden!</itunes:summary></item>
		<item>
			<title>AOC Gaslights Progressives Defending Biden</title>
			<itunes:title>AOC Gaslights Progressives Defending Biden</itunes:title>
			<pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 05:16:32 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false"><![CDATA[814bc386-eeb4-4451-8948-8cf8eaf6623b]]></guid>
			<link><![CDATA[https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/thejimmydoreshow/TJDS_20210429_Podcast.mp3]]></link>
			<itunes:image href="https://ssl-static.libsyn.com/p/assets/6/c/b/6/6cb6f1eb51404ef1e55e3c100dce7605/dsjfsdhwewe.jpg"/>
			<description><![CDATA[<p>George Bush, War Criminal!   Even CNN Ask Squad To Use Their Leverage!   Professor Shuts Down BBC's Propganda!</p> <p>Featuring Justin Jackson, Stef Zamorano, Ron Placone, and Mike MacRae!</p> <p>Phone calls from Noam Chomsky, Joe Biden, and Harrison Ford!</p>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>George Bush, War Criminal!   Even CNN Ask Squad To Use Their Leverage!   Professor Shuts Down BBC's Propganda!</p> <p>Featuring Justin Jackson, Stef Zamorano, Ron Placone, and Mike MacRae!</p> <p>Phone calls from Noam Chomsky, Joe Biden, and Harrison Ford!</p>]]></content:encoded>
			<enclosure length="64354933" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/thejimmydoreshow/TJDS_20210429_Podcast.mp3?dest-id=19460"/>
			<itunes:duration>01:06:40</itunes:duration>
			<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
			<itunes:keywords/>
			<itunes:subtitle><![CDATA[George Bush, War Criminal!   Even CNN Ask Squad To Use Their Leverage!   Professor Shuts Down BBC's Propganda! Featuring Justin Jackson, Stef Zamorano, Ron Placone, and Mike MacRae! Phone calls from Noam Chomsky, Joe Biden, and...]]></itunes:subtitle>
			<itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
		<itunes:summary>George Bush, War Criminal!   Even CNN Ask Squad To Use Their Leverage!   Professor Shuts Down BBC's Propganda! Featuring Justin Jackson, Stef Zamorano, Ron Placone, and Mike MacRae! Phone calls from Noam Chomsky, Joe Biden, and Harrison Ford!</itunes:summary></item>
		<item>
			<title>Nancy Pelosi's Human Sacrifices!</title>
			<itunes:title>Nancy Pelosi's Human Sacrifices!</itunes:title>
			<pubDate>Thu, 22 Apr 2021 06:19:20 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false"><![CDATA[78acf81f-9d27-4582-854b-b6791163f687]]></guid>
			<link><![CDATA[https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/thejimmydoreshow/TJDS_20210422_Podcast.mp3]]></link>
			<itunes:image href="https://ssl-static.libsyn.com/p/assets/1/d/7/3/1d73df593bbe19dae55e3c100dce7605/podcast.jpg"/>
			<description><![CDATA[<p>Biden's Afghan "Withdrawal" Revealed!</p> <p>Dr. Fauci Caught Lying Again!</p> <p>Featuring Stef Zamorano, Ron Placone, and Mike MacRae!</p> <p>Phone calls from Joe Biden, Chuck Schumer, and Jeb Bush!</p>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Biden's Afghan "Withdrawal" Revealed!</p> <p>Dr. Fauci Caught Lying Again!</p> <p>Featuring Stef Zamorano, Ron Placone, and Mike MacRae!</p> <p>Phone calls from Joe Biden, Chuck Schumer, and Jeb Bush!</p>]]></content:encoded>
			<enclosure length="58813024" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/thejimmydoreshow/TJDS_20210422_Podcast.mp3?dest-id=19460"/>
			<itunes:duration>59:59</itunes:duration>
			<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
			<itunes:keywords/>
			<itunes:subtitle><![CDATA[Biden's Afghan "Withdrawal" Revealed! Dr. Fauci Caught Lying Again! Featuring Stef Zamorano, Ron Placone, and Mike MacRae! Phone calls from Joe Biden, Chuck Schumer, and Jeb Bush!]]></itunes:subtitle>
			<itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
		<itunes:summary>Biden's Afghan "Withdrawal" Revealed! Dr. Fauci Caught Lying Again! Featuring Stef Zamorano, Ron Placone, and Mike MacRae! Phone calls from Joe Biden, Chuck Schumer, and Jeb Bush!</itunes:summary></item>
		<item>
			<title>Biden Re-Hires Trump's Ambassador to RUSSIA!</title>
			<itunes:title>Biden Re-Hires Trump's Ambassador to RUSSIA!</itunes:title>
			<pubDate>Thu, 15 Apr 2021 06:24:09 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false"><![CDATA[d5e7c899-5940-4fce-9138-15b17a48c6a8]]></guid>
			<link><![CDATA[https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/thejimmydoreshow/TJDS_20210415_Podcast.mp3]]></link>
			<itunes:image href="https://ssl-static.libsyn.com/p/assets/e/e/5/4/ee5440e433743bb4d959afa2a1bf1c87/dcsdswer233r.jpg"/>
			<description><![CDATA[<p>Special Guest:  award winning journalist Aaron Maté!</p> <p>Is Biden Bluffing About Ending Afghan War?</p> <p>Featuring Stef Zamorano and Ron Placone!</p> <p>Phone calls from Al Pacino, Brad Pitt, Rick Perry, and Mitt Romney!</p>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Special Guest:  award winning journalist Aaron Maté!</p> <p>Is Biden Bluffing About Ending Afghan War?</p> <p>Featuring Stef Zamorano and Ron Placone!</p> <p>Phone calls from Al Pacino, Brad Pitt, Rick Perry, and Mitt Romney!</p>]]></content:encoded>
			<enclosure length="71674360" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/thejimmydoreshow/TJDS_20210415_Podcast.mp3?dest-id=19460"/>
			<itunes:duration>01:14:37</itunes:duration>
			<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
			<itunes:keywords/>
			<itunes:subtitle><![CDATA[Special Guest:  award winning journalist Aaron Maté! Is Biden Bluffing About Ending Afghan War? Featuring Stef Zamorano and Ron Placone! Phone calls from Al Pacino, Brad Pitt, Rick Perry, and Mitt Romney!]]></itunes:subtitle>
			<itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
		<itunes:summary>Special Guest:  award winning journalist Aaron Maté! Is Biden Bluffing About Ending Afghan War? Featuring Stef Zamorano and Ron Placone! Phone calls from Al Pacino, Brad Pitt, Rick Perry, and Mitt Romney!</itunes:summary></item>
		<item>
			<title>Bernie Is A Bust!</title>
			<itunes:title>Bernie Is A Bust!</itunes:title>
			<pubDate>Thu, 08 Apr 2021 05:02:42 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false"><![CDATA[cf773b65-6cb2-484f-b78b-982c3dee223d]]></guid>
			<link><![CDATA[https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/thejimmydoreshow/TJDS_20210407_Podcast.mp3]]></link>
			<itunes:image href="https://ssl-static.libsyn.com/p/assets/8/f/9/4/8f94cc06f38f140840be95ea3302a6a1/weesdf.jpg"/>
			<description><![CDATA[<p>Biden continues building Trump's Wall!</p> <p>AOC Betrays Supporters By Funding Anti-Progressives!</p> <p>Rigged System - The Richest Corporations Paid ZERO in Taxes!</p> <p>Featuring Stef Zamorano, Ron Placone, and Mike MacRae!</p> <p>Phone calls from Bernie Sanders, John Boehner, David Axelrod, and Matthew McConaughey!</p>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Biden continues building Trump's Wall!</p> <p>AOC Betrays Supporters By Funding Anti-Progressives!</p> <p>Rigged System - The Richest Corporations Paid ZERO in Taxes!</p> <p>Featuring Stef Zamorano, Ron Placone, and Mike MacRae!</p> <p>Phone calls from Bernie Sanders, John Boehner, David Axelrod, and Matthew McConaughey!</p>]]></content:encoded>
			<enclosure length="55224594" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/thejimmydoreshow/TJDS_20210407_Podcast.mp3?dest-id=19460"/>
			<itunes:duration>57:12</itunes:duration>
			<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
			<itunes:keywords/>
			<itunes:subtitle><![CDATA[Biden continues building Trump's Wall! AOC Betrays Supporters By Funding Anti-Progressives! Rigged System - The Richest Corporations Paid ZERO in Taxes! Featuring Stef Zamorano, Ron Placone, and Mike MacRae! Phone calls from Bernie Sanders, John...]]></itunes:subtitle>
			<itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
		<itunes:summary>Biden continues building Trump's Wall! AOC Betrays Supporters By Funding Anti-Progressives! Rigged System - The Richest Corporations Paid ZERO in Taxes! Featuring Stef Zamorano, Ron Placone, and Mike MacRae! Phone calls from Bernie Sanders, John Boehner, David Axelrod, and Matthew McConaughey!</itunes:summary></item>
		<item>
			<title>AOC Calls Biden Critics "Bad Faith Actors"!</title>
			<itunes:title>AOC Calls Biden Critics "Bad Faith Actors"!</itunes:title>
			<pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2021 06:22:23 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false"><![CDATA[e472abc0-8174-4f83-bc81-75d51b24ec60]]></guid>
			<link><![CDATA[https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/thejimmydoreshow/TJDS_20210331_Podcast.mp3]]></link>
			<itunes:image href="https://ssl-static.libsyn.com/p/assets/4/e/2/9/4e2901bb89a6c7a6/qdjnqwdq.jpg"/>
			<description><![CDATA[<p>Bernie says You're Already Fooled about the Stimulus Bill!</p> <p>Ilhan Omar's Word Salad when Challenged about Strategy!</p> <p>Phone calls from Vince Vaughn!  George Clooney!  Joe Biden! Noam Chomsky!</p> <p>Featuring Mike MacRae & Stef Zamorano!</p>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Bernie says You're Already Fooled about the Stimulus Bill!</p> <p>Ilhan Omar's Word Salad when Challenged about Strategy!</p> <p>Phone calls from Vince Vaughn!  George Clooney!  Joe Biden! Noam Chomsky!</p> <p>Featuring Mike MacRae & Stef Zamorano!</p>]]></content:encoded>
			<enclosure length="67033842" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/thejimmydoreshow/TJDS_20210331_Podcast.mp3?dest-id=19460"/>
			<itunes:duration>01:09:22</itunes:duration>
			<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
			<itunes:keywords/>
			<itunes:subtitle><![CDATA[with Justin Jackson, LA Chargers & host of The TakeOver!]]></itunes:subtitle>
			<itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
		<itunes:summary>Bernie says You're Already Fooled about the Stimulus Bill! Ilhan Omar's Word Salad when Challenged about Strategy! Phone calls from Vince Vaughn!  George Clooney!  Joe Biden! Noam Chomsky! Featuring Mike MacRae &amp; Stef Zamorano!</itunes:summary></item>
		<item>
			<title>Biden Fires Staffers For Using Pot!</title>
			<itunes:title>Biden Fires Staffers For Using Pot!</itunes:title>
			<pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2021 22:48:52 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false"><![CDATA[dd443271-6c2f-4da6-a42d-5a3f6f82ffae]]></guid>
			<link><![CDATA[https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/thejimmydoreshow/TJDS_20210324_Podcast.mp3]]></link>
			<itunes:image href="https://ssl-static.libsyn.com/p/assets/d/6/0/3/d6031329355a33f3/askasdj.jpg"/>
			<description><![CDATA[<p>Rachel Maddow's Nutty Stuff!</p> <p>Andrew Yang Gets Smeared by Politico!</p> <p>Syria Cover-Up Exposed!</p> <p>Guest: award winning journalist Aaron Mate!</p> <p>Phone calls from Joe Biden, Noam Chomsky, Vladimir Putin, and Al Pacino!</p> <p>Featuring Stef Zamorano, Graham Elwood, and Mike MacRae!</p>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Rachel Maddow's Nutty Stuff!</p> <p>Andrew Yang Gets Smeared by Politico!</p> <p>Syria Cover-Up Exposed!</p> <p>Guest: award winning journalist Aaron Mate!</p> <p>Phone calls from Joe Biden, Noam Chomsky, Vladimir Putin, and Al Pacino!</p> <p>Featuring Stef Zamorano, Graham Elwood, and Mike MacRae!</p>]]></content:encoded>
			<enclosure length="75091657" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/thejimmydoreshow/TJDS_20210324_Podcast.mp3?dest-id=19460"/>
			<itunes:duration>01:17:40</itunes:duration>
			<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
			<itunes:keywords/>
			<itunes:subtitle><![CDATA[Rachel Maddow's Nutty Stuff! Andrew Yang Gets Smeared by Politico! Syria Cover-Up Exposed! Guest: award winning journalist Aaron Mate! Phone calls from Joe Biden, Noam Chomsky, Vladimir Putin, and Al Pacino! Featuring Stef Zamorano, Graham Elwood, and...]]></itunes:subtitle>
			<itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
		<itunes:summary>Rachel Maddow's Nutty Stuff! Andrew Yang Gets Smeared by Politico! Syria Cover-Up Exposed! Guest: award winning journalist Aaron Mate! Phone calls from Joe Biden, Noam Chomsky, Vladimir Putin, and Al Pacino! Featuring Stef Zamorano, Graham Elwood, and Mike MacRae!</itunes:summary></item>
		<item>
			<title>AOC's Epic Gaslighting Session</title>
			<itunes:title>AOC's Epic Gaslighting Session</itunes:title>
			<pubDate>Thu, 18 Mar 2021 07:10:28 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false"><![CDATA[0747e291-43ed-4d48-889a-71c961352b7b]]></guid>
			<link><![CDATA[https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/thejimmydoreshow/TJDS_20210317_Podcast.mp3]]></link>
			<itunes:image href="https://ssl-static.libsyn.com/p/assets/f/2/3/2/f232dca4ada534da/dr24f.jpg"/>
			<description><![CDATA[<p>Biden Unironically Calls Putin "A Killer".</p> <p>RussiaGate on life support by Corporate Media & Intelligence Complex!</p> <p>Phone Calls from Liam Neeson, David Axelrod, Chuck Schumer, and Joe Biden.</p> <p>Featuring Stef Zamorano, Ron Placone, and Mike MacRae!</p>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Biden Unironically Calls Putin "A Killer".</p> <p>RussiaGate on life support by Corporate Media & Intelligence Complex!</p> <p>Phone Calls from Liam Neeson, David Axelrod, Chuck Schumer, and Joe Biden.</p> <p>Featuring Stef Zamorano, Ron Placone, and Mike MacRae!</p>]]></content:encoded>
			<enclosure length="59804340" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/thejimmydoreshow/TJDS_20210317_Podcast.mp3?dest-id=19460"/>
			<itunes:duration>01:01:56</itunes:duration>
			<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
			<itunes:keywords/>
			<itunes:subtitle><![CDATA[Biden Unironically Calls Putin "A Killer". RussiaGate on life support by Corporate Media & Intelligence Complex! Phone Calls from Liam Neeson, David Axelrod, Chuck Schumer, and Joe Biden. Featuring Stef Zamorano, Ron Placone, and Mike MacRae!]]></itunes:subtitle>
			<itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
		<itunes:summary>Biden Unironically Calls Putin "A Killer". RussiaGate on life support by Corporate Media &amp; Intelligence Complex! Phone Calls from Liam Neeson, David Axelrod, Chuck Schumer, and Joe Biden. Featuring Stef Zamorano, Ron Placone, and Mike MacRae!</itunes:summary></item>
		<item>
			<title>Squad Tweets Rather Than Fight For Workers!</title>
			<itunes:title>Squad Tweets Rather Than Fight For Workers!</itunes:title>
			<pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 06:45:13 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false"><![CDATA[dbd9079b-2c57-44ab-a1e8-b456a083bcd1]]></guid>
			<link><![CDATA[https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/thejimmydoreshow/TJDS_20210311_Podcast.mp3]]></link>
			<itunes:image href="https://ssl-static.libsyn.com/p/assets/0/b/f/9/0bf918c7b24f217e/sdjasndas.jpg"/>
			<description><![CDATA[<p>Special Guest:  Justin Jackson, LA Chargers Running Back and Progressive Activist.</p> <p>Featuring Stef Zamorano and Mike MacRae!</p> <p>Phone calls from Barack Obama, Mitt Romney, and Joe Biden!</p>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Special Guest:  Justin Jackson, LA Chargers Running Back and Progressive Activist.</p> <p>Featuring Stef Zamorano and Mike MacRae!</p> <p>Phone calls from Barack Obama, Mitt Romney, and Joe Biden!</p>]]></content:encoded>
			<enclosure length="63522442" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/thejimmydoreshow/TJDS_20210311_Podcast.mp3?dest-id=19460"/>
			<itunes:duration>01:05:38</itunes:duration>
			<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
			<itunes:keywords/>
			<itunes:subtitle><![CDATA[Special Guest:  Justin Jackson, LA Chargers Running Back and Progressive Activist. Featuring Stef Zamorano and Mike MacRae! Phone calls from Barack Obama, Mitt Romney, and Joe Biden!]]></itunes:subtitle>
			<itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
		<itunes:summary>Special Guest:  Justin Jackson, LA Chargers Running Back and Progressive Activist. Featuring Stef Zamorano and Mike MacRae! Phone calls from Barack Obama, Mitt Romney, and Joe Biden!</itunes:summary></item>
		<item>
			<title>Democrats Fail On Purpose!</title>
			<itunes:title>Democrats Fail On Purpose!</itunes:title>
			<pubDate>Thu, 04 Mar 2021 06:36:08 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false"><![CDATA[65bd183b-c041-4719-8cc0-0f6f181ea1a5]]></guid>
			<link><![CDATA[https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/thejimmydoreshow/TJDS_20210303_Podcast.mp3]]></link>
			<itunes:image href="https://ssl-static.libsyn.com/p/assets/6/a/b/a/6abadfa64a320a41/ewfw3.jpg"/>
			<description><![CDATA[<p>Progressives Sell Out Workers on $15 Minimum Wage</p> <p>Neera Tanden Denied Confirmation -- Justice Democrats Weep!</p> <p>Phone Calls from Noam Chomsky, Vince Vaughn, Joe Biden, and Andrew Cuomo!</p> <p>Featuring Stef Zamorano, Ron Placone, and Mike MacRae!</p>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Progressives Sell Out Workers on $15 Minimum Wage</p> <p>Neera Tanden Denied Confirmation -- Justice Democrats Weep!</p> <p>Phone Calls from Noam Chomsky, Vince Vaughn, Joe Biden, and Andrew Cuomo!</p> <p>Featuring Stef Zamorano, Ron Placone, and Mike MacRae!</p>]]></content:encoded>
			<enclosure length="61586936" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/thejimmydoreshow/TJDS_20210303_Podcast.mp3?dest-id=19460"/>
			<itunes:duration>01:03:35</itunes:duration>
			<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
			<itunes:keywords/>
			<itunes:subtitle><![CDATA[Progressives Sell Out Workers on $15 Minimum Wage Neera Tanden Denied Confirmation -- Justice Democrats Weep! Phone Calls from Noam Chomsky, Vince Vaughn, Joe Biden, and Andrew Cuomo! Featuring Stef Zamorano, Ron Placone, and Mike MacRae!]]></itunes:subtitle>
			<itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
		<itunes:summary>Progressives Sell Out Workers on $15 Minimum Wage Neera Tanden Denied Confirmation -- Justice Democrats Weep! Phone Calls from Noam Chomsky, Vince Vaughn, Joe Biden, and Andrew Cuomo! Featuring Stef Zamorano, Ron Placone, and Mike MacRae!</itunes:summary></item>
		<item>
			<title>Biden's Weapon Deals!</title>
			<itunes:title>Biden's Weapon Deals!</itunes:title>
			<pubDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2021 07:51:33 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false"><![CDATA[60e65acd-e44c-4654-87f1-daad3cc55656]]></guid>
			<link><![CDATA[https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/thejimmydoreshow/TJDS_20210224_Podcast.mp3]]></link>
			<itunes:image href="https://ssl-static.libsyn.com/p/assets/d/f/8/f/df8f25620d7afdb8/bidens.jpg"/>
			<description><![CDATA[<p>Justice Democrats Protecting Neera Tanden!</p> <p>Cuomo Says Don't Trust "Experts" on Covid To Distract From Scandal!</p> <p>Featuring Stef Zamorano, Ron Placone, and Mike MacRae!</p> <p>Phone Calls from Vladimir Putin, Rick Perry, Joe Biden, and Bernie Sanders.</p>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Justice Democrats Protecting Neera Tanden!</p> <p>Cuomo Says Don't Trust "Experts" on Covid To Distract From Scandal!</p> <p>Featuring Stef Zamorano, Ron Placone, and Mike MacRae!</p> <p>Phone Calls from Vladimir Putin, Rick Perry, Joe Biden, and Bernie Sanders.</p>]]></content:encoded>
			<enclosure length="68466168" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/thejimmydoreshow/TJDS_20210224_Podcast.mp3?dest-id=19460"/>
			<itunes:duration>01:10:59</itunes:duration>
			<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
			<itunes:keywords/>
			<itunes:subtitle><![CDATA[Justice Democrats Protecting Neera Tanden! Cuomo Says Don't Trust "Experts" on Covid To Distract From Scandal! Featuring Stef Zamorano, Ron Placone, and Mike MacRae! Phone Calls from Vladimir Putin, Rick Perry, Joe Biden, and Bernie Sanders.]]></itunes:subtitle>
			<itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
		<itunes:summary>Justice Democrats Protecting Neera Tanden! Cuomo Says Don't Trust "Experts" on Covid To Distract From Scandal! Featuring Stef Zamorano, Ron Placone, and Mike MacRae! Phone Calls from Vladimir Putin, Rick Perry, Joe Biden, and Bernie Sanders.</itunes:summary></item>
		<item>
			<title>Capitol Protests &amp; Economic Despair.</title>
			<itunes:title>Capitol Protests &amp; Economic Despair.</itunes:title>
			<pubDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2021 15:49:44 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false"><![CDATA[c710f74a-d122-419b-bf07-8834eea398a0]]></guid>
			<link><![CDATA[https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/thejimmydoreshow/TJDS_20210218_Podcast.mp3]]></link>
			<itunes:image href="https://ssl-static.libsyn.com/p/assets/e/1/9/7/e197c03f217d3bed/asjnascwefq.jpg"/>
			<description><![CDATA[<p>Biden Continues Persecution of Julian Assange!</p> <p>Big Tech Governments To Be Created in Nevada! WTF!</p> <p>Washington Post Blames Capitol Protest On Economic Despair.</p> <p>Special Guest: Max Blumenthal, editor of The Grayzone.</p> <p>Phone calls from Hillary Supporter, Barack Obama, and Noam Chomsky!   Featuring Stef Zamorano & Mike MacRae!</p>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Biden Continues Persecution of Julian Assange!</p> <p>Big Tech Governments To Be Created in Nevada! WTF!</p> <p>Washington Post Blames Capitol Protest On Economic Despair.</p> <p>Special Guest: Max Blumenthal, editor of The Grayzone.</p> <p>Phone calls from Hillary Supporter, Barack Obama, and Noam Chomsky!   Featuring Stef Zamorano & Mike MacRae!</p>]]></content:encoded>
			<enclosure length="60448227" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/thejimmydoreshow/TJDS_20210218_Podcast.mp3?dest-id=19460"/>
			<itunes:duration>01:02:26</itunes:duration>
			<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
			<itunes:keywords/>
			<itunes:subtitle><![CDATA[Biden Continues Persecution of Julian Assange! Big Tech Governments To Be Created in Nevada! WTF! Washington Post Blames Capitol Protest On Economic Despair. Special Guest: Max Blumenthal, editor of The Grayzone. Phone calls from Hillary Supporter,...]]></itunes:subtitle>
			<itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
		<itunes:summary>Biden Continues Persecution of Julian Assange! Big Tech Governments To Be Created in Nevada! WTF! Washington Post Blames Capitol Protest On Economic Despair. Special Guest: Max Blumenthal, editor of The Grayzone. Phone calls from Hillary Supporter, Barack Obama, and Noam Chomsky!   Featuring Stef Zamorano &amp; Mike MacRae!</itunes:summary></item>
		<item>
			<title>Will Bernie Confirm Enemy of Progressives?</title>
			<itunes:title>Will Bernie Confirm Enemy of Progressives?</itunes:title>
			<pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2021 16:37:19 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false"><![CDATA[45f3fe2b-8d34-4d58-a6f9-a0291230de07]]></guid>
			<link><![CDATA[https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/thejimmydoreshow/TJDS_20210211_Podcast.mp3]]></link>
			<itunes:image href="https://ssl-static.libsyn.com/p/assets/e/3/1/8/e3186a34dcb1d558/confirm.jpg"/>
			<description><![CDATA[<p>Special Guest:  Max Blumenthal, editor of The Grayzone.</p> <p>Biden Won't Withdraw Troops From Afghanistan!</p> <p>Corporate News Ratings PLUMMET Post-Trump!</p> <p>Phone calls from</p> <p>Featuring Stef Zamorano and Mike MacRae!</p>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Special Guest:  Max Blumenthal, editor of The Grayzone.</p> <p>Biden Won't Withdraw Troops From Afghanistan!</p> <p>Corporate News Ratings PLUMMET Post-Trump!</p> <p>Phone calls from</p> <p>Featuring Stef Zamorano and Mike MacRae!</p>]]></content:encoded>
			<enclosure length="61226007" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/thejimmydoreshow/TJDS_20210211_Podcast.mp3?dest-id=19460"/>
			<itunes:duration>01:03:26</itunes:duration>
			<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
			<itunes:keywords/>
			<itunes:subtitle><![CDATA[Special Guest:  Max Blumenthal, editor of The Grayzone. Biden Won't Withdraw Troops From Afghanistan! Corporate News Ratings PLUMMET Post-Trump! Phone calls from Featuring Stef Zamorano and Mike MacRae!]]></itunes:subtitle>
			<itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
		<itunes:summary>Special Guest:  Max Blumenthal, editor of The Grayzone. Biden Won't Withdraw Troops From Afghanistan! Corporate News Ratings PLUMMET Post-Trump! Phone calls from Featuring Stef Zamorano and Mike MacRae!</itunes:summary></item>
		<item>
			<title>Glenn Greenwald on Free Speech &amp; The Left!</title>
			<itunes:title>Glenn Greenwald on Free Speech &amp; The Left!</itunes:title>
			<pubDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2021 18:51:22 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false"><![CDATA[fa59fa23-1e09-419d-ad00-62f42f9148b2]]></guid>
			<link><![CDATA[https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/thejimmydoreshow/TJDS_20210203_Podcast.mp3]]></link>
			<itunes:image href="https://ssl-static.libsyn.com/p/assets/c/a/6/f/ca6f2dbe96e9c14c/amskjdhvn_.jpg"/>
			<description><![CDATA[<p>Biden Already War-Mongering Iran!</p> <p>Special Guest: Glenn Greenwald, Pulitzer Prize winning journalist</p> <p>Featuring Stef Zamorano, Graham Elwood, and Mike MacRae!</p> <p>Phone Calls from Noam Chomsky, Bernie Sanders, chuck Schumer, and Joe Biden!</p> <p> </p>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Biden Already War-Mongering Iran!</p> <p>Special Guest: Glenn Greenwald, Pulitzer Prize winning journalist</p> <p>Featuring Stef Zamorano, Graham Elwood, and Mike MacRae!</p> <p>Phone Calls from Noam Chomsky, Bernie Sanders, chuck Schumer, and Joe Biden!</p> <p> </p>]]></content:encoded>
			<enclosure length="78480449" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/thejimmydoreshow/TJDS_20210203_Podcast.mp3?dest-id=19460"/>
			<itunes:duration>01:21:22</itunes:duration>
			<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
			<itunes:keywords/>
			<itunes:subtitle><![CDATA[Biden Already War-Mongering Iran! Special Guest: Glenn Greenwald, Pulitzer Prize winning journalist Featuring Stef Zamorano, Graham Elwood, and Mike MacRae! Phone Calls from Noam Chomsky, Bernie Sanders, chuck Schumer, and Joe Biden!  ]]></itunes:subtitle>
			<itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
		<itunes:summary>Biden Already War-Mongering Iran! Special Guest: Glenn Greenwald, Pulitzer Prize winning journalist Featuring Stef Zamorano, Graham Elwood, and Mike MacRae! Phone Calls from Noam Chomsky, Bernie Sanders, chuck Schumer, and Joe Biden!  </itunes:summary></item>
		<item>
			<title>Facebook Censors The Left!</title>
			<itunes:title>Facebook Censors The Left!</itunes:title>
			<pubDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2021 03:26:11 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false"><![CDATA[1e194b19-2720-4864-b84d-385640d7d7ad]]></guid>
			<link><![CDATA[https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/thejimmydoreshow/TJDS_20210127_Podcast.mp3]]></link>
			<itunes:image href="https://ssl-static.libsyn.com/p/assets/0/a/2/6/0a26fa0b45dca1c5/dsfwer3.jpg"/>
			<description><![CDATA[<p>Special Guest:  Daryl Davis, famous R&B musician who converted KKK members out of the Klan!</p> <p>Phone calls from Vince Vaughn and Harrison Ford!</p> <p>Featuring Stef Zamorano, Graham Elwood, and Mike MacRae!</p>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Special Guest:  Daryl Davis, famous R&B musician who converted KKK members out of the Klan!</p> <p>Phone calls from Vince Vaughn and Harrison Ford!</p> <p>Featuring Stef Zamorano, Graham Elwood, and Mike MacRae!</p>]]></content:encoded>
			<enclosure length="61342639" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/thejimmydoreshow/TJDS_20210127_Podcast.mp3?dest-id=19460"/>
			<itunes:duration>01:03:44</itunes:duration>
			<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
			<itunes:keywords/>
			<itunes:subtitle><![CDATA[Special Guest:  Daryl Davis, famous R&B musician who converted KKK members out of the Klan! Phone calls from Vince Vaughn and Harrison Ford! Featuring Stef Zamorano, Graham Elwood, and Mike MacRae!]]></itunes:subtitle>
			<itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
		<itunes:summary>Special Guest:  Daryl Davis, famous R&amp;B musician who converted KKK members out of the Klan! Phone calls from Vince Vaughn and Harrison Ford! Featuring Stef Zamorano, Graham Elwood, and Mike MacRae!</itunes:summary></item>
		<item>
			<title>INAUGURATION DAY -- The Biden Era Begins</title>
			<itunes:title>INAUGURATION DAY -- The Biden Era Begins</itunes:title>
			<pubDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2021 14:58:34 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false"><![CDATA[fceaeb8e-19b2-45e7-988b-1f67d79366a6]]></guid>
			<link><![CDATA[https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/thejimmydoreshow/TJDS_20210121_Podcast.mp3]]></link>
			<itunes:image href="https://ssl-static.libsyn.com/p/assets/f/4/4/1/f441a72734a44935/DCEQWD.jpg"/>
			<description><![CDATA[<p>Georgia Betrayal!</p> <p>Biden's Healthcare Plan Written By Insurance Lobbyists!</p> <p>NYC Workers Strike In World's Largest Food Market!</p> <p>Phone Calls from CNN's Jake Tapper, Bernie Sanders, Barack Obama, and Joe Biden.</p> <p>Featuring Stef Zamorano and Mike MacRae!</p>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Georgia Betrayal!</p> <p>Biden's Healthcare Plan Written By Insurance Lobbyists!</p> <p>NYC Workers Strike In World's Largest Food Market!</p> <p>Phone Calls from CNN's Jake Tapper, Bernie Sanders, Barack Obama, and Joe Biden.</p> <p>Featuring Stef Zamorano and Mike MacRae!</p>]]></content:encoded>
			<enclosure length="63732926" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/thejimmydoreshow/TJDS_20210121_Podcast.mp3?dest-id=19460"/>
			<itunes:duration>01:06:02</itunes:duration>
			<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
			<itunes:keywords/>
			<itunes:subtitle><![CDATA[Georgia Betrayal! Biden's Healthcare Plan Written By Insurance Lobbyists! NYC Workers Strike In World's Largest Food Market! Phone Calls from CNN's Jake Tapper, Bernie Sanders, Barack Obama, and Joe Biden. Featuring Stef Zamorano and Mike MacRae!]]></itunes:subtitle>
			<itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
		<itunes:summary>Georgia Betrayal! Biden's Healthcare Plan Written By Insurance Lobbyists! NYC Workers Strike In World's Largest Food Market! Phone Calls from CNN's Jake Tapper, Bernie Sanders, Barack Obama, and Joe Biden. Featuring Stef Zamorano and Mike MacRae!</itunes:summary></item>
		<item>
			<title>AOC Endorses #ForceTheVote!</title>
			<itunes:title>AOC Endorses #ForceTheVote!</itunes:title>
			<pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2021 09:00:29 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false"><![CDATA[2ccac8da-64a4-460b-a119-9704bcfa5a68]]></guid>
			<link><![CDATA[https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/thejimmydoreshow/TJDS_20210113_Podcast.mp3]]></link>
			<itunes:image href="https://ssl-static.libsyn.com/p/assets/3/6/d/b/36dbe403b6affd5f/dfgergergssd.jpg"/>
			<description><![CDATA[<p>Special Guest:  Professor Richard Wolff,  on the Capitol insurrection!</p> <p>Phone calls from Mike Pompeo, David Axelrod, Barack Obama, and Noam Chomsky.</p> <p>Featuring Stef Zamorano and Mike MacRae!</p>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Special Guest:  Professor Richard Wolff,  on the Capitol insurrection!</p> <p>Phone calls from Mike Pompeo, David Axelrod, Barack Obama, and Noam Chomsky.</p> <p>Featuring Stef Zamorano and Mike MacRae!</p>]]></content:encoded>
			<enclosure length="69516625" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/thejimmydoreshow/TJDS_20210113_Podcast.mp3?dest-id=19460"/>
			<itunes:duration>01:11:52</itunes:duration>
			<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
			<itunes:keywords/>
			<itunes:subtitle><![CDATA[Special Guest:  Professor Richard Wolff,  on the Capitol insurrection! Phone calls from Mike Pompeo, David Axelrod, Barack Obama, and Noam Chomsky. Featuring Stef Zamorano and Mike MacRae!]]></itunes:subtitle>
			<itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
		<itunes:summary>Special Guest:  Professor Richard Wolff,  on the Capitol insurrection! Phone calls from Mike Pompeo, David Axelrod, Barack Obama, and Noam Chomsky. Featuring Stef Zamorano and Mike MacRae!</itunes:summary></item>
		<item>
			<title>Fraud Squad!</title>
			<itunes:title>Fraud Squad!</itunes:title>
			<pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2021 09:25:35 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false"><![CDATA[e9dc5afe-6b93-4fb8-b5f4-a7fdecf68bd2]]></guid>
			<link><![CDATA[https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/thejimmydoreshow/TJDS_20210107_Podcast.mp3]]></link>
			<itunes:image href="https://ssl-static.libsyn.com/p/assets/7/7/c/5/77c584a4e6b7713a/dfsdjfnw.jpg"/>
			<description><![CDATA[<p>Julian Assange's Extradition Trial!</p> <p>Democrats Win Senate but won't become the Party for the People!</p> <p>Featuring Stef Zamorano & Mike MacRae!</p> <p>Phone calls from Al Pacino, Mitt Romney, Joe Biden, and Noam Chomsky!</p>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Julian Assange's Extradition Trial!</p> <p>Democrats Win Senate but won't become the Party for the People!</p> <p>Featuring Stef Zamorano & Mike MacRae!</p> <p>Phone calls from Al Pacino, Mitt Romney, Joe Biden, and Noam Chomsky!</p>]]></content:encoded>
			<enclosure length="72135954" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/thejimmydoreshow/TJDS_20210107_Podcast.mp3?dest-id=19460"/>
			<itunes:duration>01:14:47</itunes:duration>
			<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
			<itunes:keywords/>
			<itunes:subtitle><![CDATA[Julian Assange's Extradition Trial! Democrats Win Senate but won't become the Party for the People! Featuring Stef Zamorano & Mike MacRae! Phone calls from Al Pacino, Mitt Romney, Joe Biden, and Noam Chomsky!]]></itunes:subtitle>
			<itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
		<itunes:summary>Julian Assange's Extradition Trial! Democrats Win Senate but won't become the Party for the People! Featuring Stef Zamorano &amp; Mike MacRae! Phone calls from Al Pacino, Mitt Romney, Joe Biden, and Noam Chomsky!</itunes:summary></item>
		<item>
			<title>Force The Vote is Now or Never!</title>
			<itunes:title>Force The Vote is Now or Never!</itunes:title>
			<pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 08:25:12 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false"><![CDATA[806f714a-b394-4e28-bf87-2139d24c1b8d]]></guid>
			<link><![CDATA[https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/thejimmydoreshow/TJDS_12312020_Podcast.mp3]]></link>
			<itunes:image href="https://ssl-static.libsyn.com/p/assets/b/7/8/3/b7836a0373984e57/sddwe.jpg"/>
			<description><![CDATA[<p>When AOC Wanted Pelosi Replaced!</p> <p>Trump Pardons War Criminals But Not Whistle Blowers!</p> <p>DNC Election Meddling -- New Revelations!</p> <p>Featuring Stef Zamorano & Mike MacRae!</p> <p>Calls from Bernie Sanders, Joe Biden, and George Clooney!</p>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>When AOC Wanted Pelosi Replaced!</p> <p>Trump Pardons War Criminals But Not Whistle Blowers!</p> <p>DNC Election Meddling -- New Revelations!</p> <p>Featuring Stef Zamorano & Mike MacRae!</p> <p>Calls from Bernie Sanders, Joe Biden, and George Clooney!</p>]]></content:encoded>
			<enclosure length="63374150" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/thejimmydoreshow/TJDS_12312020_Podcast.mp3?dest-id=19460"/>
			<itunes:duration>01:05:52</itunes:duration>
			<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
			<itunes:keywords/>
			<itunes:subtitle><![CDATA[When AOC Wanted Pelosi Replaced! Trump Pardons War Criminals But Not Whistle Blowers! DNC Election Meddling -- New Revelations! Featuring Stef Zamorano & Mike MacRae! Calls from Bernie Sanders, Joe Biden, and George Clooney!]]></itunes:subtitle>
			<itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
		<itunes:summary>When AOC Wanted Pelosi Replaced! Trump Pardons War Criminals But Not Whistle Blowers! DNC Election Meddling -- New Revelations! Featuring Stef Zamorano &amp; Mike MacRae! Calls from Bernie Sanders, Joe Biden, and George Clooney!</itunes:summary></item>
		<item>
			<title>Dr. Cornel West -- Xmas Podcast!</title>
			<itunes:title>Dr. Cornel West -- Xmas Podcast!</itunes:title>
			<pubDate>Thu, 24 Dec 2020 15:59:32 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false"><![CDATA[195c421c-9f57-404d-b8b5-6012b479b45b]]></guid>
			<link><![CDATA[https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/thejimmydoreshow/TJDS_20201225_XmasPodcast.mp3]]></link>
			<itunes:image href="https://ssl-static.libsyn.com/p/assets/d/2/b/f/d2bff5097a800f02/cxsd.jpg"/>
			<description><![CDATA[<p>Dr. Cornel West on Force The Vote!</p> <p>Steve Grumbine, modern economics educator!</p> <p>Featuring Stef Zamorano and Mike MacRae!</p> <p>Phone calls from Brad Pitt, Joe Biden, Chuck Schumer, Harrison Ford, and Noam Chomsky!</p>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Dr. Cornel West on Force The Vote!</p> <p>Steve Grumbine, modern economics educator!</p> <p>Featuring Stef Zamorano and Mike MacRae!</p> <p>Phone calls from Brad Pitt, Joe Biden, Chuck Schumer, Harrison Ford, and Noam Chomsky!</p>]]></content:encoded>
			<enclosure length="85718185" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/thejimmydoreshow/TJDS_20201225_XmasPodcast.mp3?dest-id=19460"/>
			<itunes:duration>01:29:10</itunes:duration>
			<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
			<itunes:keywords/>
			<itunes:subtitle><![CDATA[Dr. Cornel West on Force The Vote! Steve Grumbine, modern economics educator! Featuring Stef Zamorano and Mike MacRae! Phone calls from Brad Pitt, Joe Biden, Chuck Schumer, Harrison Ford, and Noam Chomsky!]]></itunes:subtitle>
			<itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
		<itunes:summary>Dr. Cornel West on Force The Vote! Steve Grumbine, modern economics educator! Featuring Stef Zamorano and Mike MacRae! Phone calls from Brad Pitt, Joe Biden, Chuck Schumer, Harrison Ford, and Noam Chomsky!</itunes:summary></item>
		<item>
			<title>Jimmy Responds To AOC!</title>
			<itunes:title>Jimmy Responds To AOC!</itunes:title>
			<pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2020 08:55:22 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false"><![CDATA[66b1118b-4841-4a72-a6b3-184533be83e1]]></guid>
			<link><![CDATA[https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/thejimmydoreshow/TJDS_20201216_Podcast.mp3]]></link>
			<itunes:image href="https://ssl-static.libsyn.com/p/assets/1/6/8/7/16876c4cc94422f8/dsdfwe23e3aasdf33ed.jpg"/>
			<description><![CDATA[<p>Leaked audio exposes Joe Biden's contempt for the Democratic Party base!</p> <p>AOC is schooled by the NFL's Justin Jackson of the L.A.Rangers over not fighting for Medicare For All!</p> <p>Phone calls from Bernie Sanders, Chris Christie, Joe Biden, and Al Pacino!</p> <p>Featuring Stef Zamorano, Ron Placone, and Mike MacRae!</p>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Leaked audio exposes Joe Biden's contempt for the Democratic Party base!</p> <p>AOC is schooled by the NFL's Justin Jackson of the L.A.Rangers over not fighting for Medicare For All!</p> <p>Phone calls from Bernie Sanders, Chris Christie, Joe Biden, and Al Pacino!</p> <p>Featuring Stef Zamorano, Ron Placone, and Mike MacRae!</p>]]></content:encoded>
			<enclosure length="69448142" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/thejimmydoreshow/TJDS_20201216_Podcast.mp3?dest-id=19460"/>
			<itunes:duration>01:12:00</itunes:duration>
			<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
			<itunes:keywords/>
			<itunes:subtitle><![CDATA[Leaked audio exposes Joe Biden's contempt for the Democratic Party base! AOC is schooled by the NFL's Justin Jackson of the L.A.Rangers over not fighting for Medicare For All! Phone calls from Bernie Sanders, Chris Christie, Joe Biden, and Al Pacino!...]]></itunes:subtitle>
			<itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
		<itunes:summary>Leaked audio exposes Joe Biden's contempt for the Democratic Party base! AOC is schooled by the NFL's Justin Jackson of the L.A.Rangers over not fighting for Medicare For All! Phone calls from Bernie Sanders, Chris Christie, Joe Biden, and Al Pacino! Featuring Stef Zamorano, Ron Placone, and Mike MacRae!</itunes:summary></item>
		<item>
			<title>Hunter Biden Under Investigation!</title>
			<itunes:title>Hunter Biden Under Investigation!</itunes:title>
			<pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2020 15:10:05 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false"><![CDATA[12b0f2c4-89d9-4810-847b-acd214089aef]]></guid>
			<link><![CDATA[https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/thejimmydoreshow/TJDS_20201210_Podcast.mp3]]></link>
			<itunes:image href="https://ssl-static.libsyn.com/p/assets/9/c/d/e/9cded0d31181cbb8/aded3.jpg"/>
			<description><![CDATA[<p>Biden's Conflict Of Interest Cabinet!</p> <p>Stimulus Bill With No Stimulus!</p> <p>Always Money For War!</p> <p>Featuring Stef Zamorano, Lee Camp, and Mike MacRae!</p> <p>Phone Calls from Matthew McConaughey, Joe Biden, and Pete Buttigieg!</p>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Biden's Conflict Of Interest Cabinet!</p> <p>Stimulus Bill With No Stimulus!</p> <p>Always Money For War!</p> <p>Featuring Stef Zamorano, Lee Camp, and Mike MacRae!</p> <p>Phone Calls from Matthew McConaughey, Joe Biden, and Pete Buttigieg!</p>]]></content:encoded>
			<enclosure length="58918433" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/thejimmydoreshow/TJDS_20201210_Podcast.mp3?dest-id=19460"/>
			<itunes:duration>01:01:00</itunes:duration>
			<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
			<itunes:keywords/>
			<itunes:subtitle><![CDATA[Biden's Conflict Of Interest Cabinet! Stimulus Bill With No Stimulus! Always Money For War! Featuring Stef Zamorano, Lee Camp, and Mike MacRae! Phone Calls from Matthew McConaughey, Joe Biden, and Pete Buttigieg!]]></itunes:subtitle>
			<itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
		<itunes:summary>Biden's Conflict Of Interest Cabinet! Stimulus Bill With No Stimulus! Always Money For War! Featuring Stef Zamorano, Lee Camp, and Mike MacRae! Phone Calls from Matthew McConaughey, Joe Biden, and Pete Buttigieg!</itunes:summary></item>
		<item>
			<title>NEERA TANDEN: Perfect Choice For BIDEN Administration!</title>
			<itunes:title>NEERA TANDEN: Perfect Choice For BIDEN Administration!</itunes:title>
			<pubDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2020 08:35:11 +0000</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false"><![CDATA[fbbe7955-d19e-41c2-a1f8-48674b95614a]]></guid>
			<link><![CDATA[https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/thejimmydoreshow/TJDS_20201203_Podcast.mp3]]></link>
			<itunes:image href="https://ssl-static.libsyn.com/p/assets/6/e/3/7/6e371813ec423e22/arCalt_DCADQWdcdsd.jpg"/>
			<description><![CDATA[<p>Progressives Can Force A Vote on Medicare-For-All!</p> <p>Pelosi's Stimulus Half The Size of Trump's!</p> <p>Featuring Stef Zamorano & Mike MacRae!</p> <p>Phone Calls from Hillary Supporter! Joe Biden! Chuck Schumer! Bernie Sanders!</p>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Progressives Can Force A Vote on Medicare-For-All!</p> <p>Pelosi's Stimulus Half The Size of Trump's!</p> <p>Featuring Stef Zamorano & Mike MacRae!</p> <p>Phone Calls from Hillary Supporter! Joe Biden! Chuck Schumer! Bernie Sanders!</p>]]></content:encoded>
			<enclosure length="65118545" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/thejimmydoreshow/TJDS_20201203_Podcast.mp3?dest-id=19460"/>
			<itunes:duration>01:07:30</itunes:duration>
			<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
			<itunes:keywords/>
			<itunes:subtitle><![CDATA[Progressives Can Force A Vote on Medicare-For-All! Pelosi's Stimulus Half The Size of Trump's! Featuring Stef Zamorano & Mike MacRae! Phone Calls from Hillary Supporter! Joe Biden! Chuck Schumer! Bernie Sanders!]]></itunes:subtitle>
			<itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
		<itunes:summary>Progressives Can Force A Vote on Medicare-For-All! Pelosi's Stimulus Half The Size of Trump's! Featuring Stef Zamorano &amp; Mike MacRae! Phone Calls from Hillary Supporter! Joe Biden! Chuck Schumer! Bernie Sanders!</itunes:summary></item>
	
	</channel>
</rss>