<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<rdf:RDF
 xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
 xmlns="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/"
 xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
 xmlns:taxo="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/taxonomy/"
 xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
 xmlns:syn="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
 xmlns:admin="http://webns.net/mvcb/"
>

<channel rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/">
<title>physics.soc-ph updates on arXiv.org</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">Physics -- Physics and Society (physics.soc-ph) updates on the arXiv.org e-print archive</description>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:date>2022-11-03T20:30:00-05:00</dc:date>
<dc:publisher>help@arxiv.org</dc:publisher>
<dc:subject>Physics -- Physics and Society</dc:subject>
<syn:updateBase>1901-01-01T00:00+00:00</syn:updateBase>
<syn:updateFrequency>1</syn:updateFrequency>
<syn:updatePeriod>daily</syn:updatePeriod>
<items>
 <rdf:Seq>
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01425" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01545" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01936" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01955" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.02023" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.02040" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.15555" />
 </rdf:Seq>
</items>
<image rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif" />
</channel>
<image rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif">
<title>arXiv.org</title>
<url>http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif</url>
<link>http://arxiv.org/</link>
</image>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01425">
<title>Mesoscopic analytical approach in a three state opinion model with continuous internal variable. (arXiv:2211.01425v1 [physics.soc-ph])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01425</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Analytical approaches in models of opinion formation have been extensively
studied either for an opinion represented as a discrete or a continuous
variable. In this paper, we analyze a model which combines both approaches. The
state of an agent is represented with an internal continuous variable (the
leaning or propensity), that leads to a discrete public opinion: pro, against
or neutral. This model can be described by a set of master equations which are
a nonlinear coupled system of first order differential equations of hyperbolic
type including non-local terms and non-local boundary conditions, which can&apos;t
be solved analytically. We developed an approximation to tackle this difficulty
by deriving a set of master equations for the dynamics of the average leaning
of agents with the same opinion, under the hypothesis of a time scale
separation in the dynamics of the variables. We show that this simplified model
accurately predicts the expected transition between a neutral consensus and a
bi-polarized state, and also gives an excellent approximation for the dynamics
of the average leaning of agents with the same opinion, even when the time
separation scale hypothesis is not completely fulfilled.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Pedraza_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Luc&amp;#xed;a Pedraza&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Pinasco_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Juan Pablo Pinasco&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Semeshenko_V/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Viktoriya Semeshenko&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Balenzuela_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Pablo Balenzuela&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01545">
<title>Extracting Spatial Interaction Patterns between Urban Road Networks and Mixed Functions. (arXiv:2211.01545v1 [physics.soc-ph])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01545</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;In the field of urban planning, road network system planning is often the
first step and the main purpose of urban planning is to create a spatial
configuration of different functions such as residence, education, business,
etc. Generally speaking, the more mixed the functions of an area has, the more
possible its vitality may be. Therefore, in this article, we propose a new
framework to study the specific spatial influence patterns of the overall
structure and different sub-structures of road networks on the mixed functions.
Taking road segment as the basic unit, we characterize mixed functions
aggregation of road networks with the number of POIs categories within 100
meters around every road segment. At the same time, on the basis of centrality
measurement in graph theory, we use 4 indexes to reflect the characteristics of
the urban road network structure, including degree, closeness, betweenness, and
length. We conduct our methods and experiments using the road networks and POI
data within the 5th ring road of Beijing. The results demonstrate that urban
road networks inherently influence the aggregation of urban mixed functions in
various patterns and the patterns of road network sub-structures is also quite
different. Our study shows that the higher the degree of the road network
structure has, the more likely it will attract functions&apos; aggregation. It also
reveals that diversified local degree will help gather urban functions. In
addition to those, the analysis as well validates the importance of small-grids
typology of urban road networks and the closeness to the center of cities.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Xiao_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Huidan Xiao&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Yang_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Tao Yang&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01936">
<title>Differences in collaboration structures and impact among prominent researchers in Europe and North America. (arXiv:2211.01936v1 [physics.soc-ph])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01936</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Scientists collaborate through intricate networks, which impact the quality
and scope of their research. At the same time, funding and institutional
arrangements, as well as scientific and political cultures, affect the
structure of collaboration networks. Since such arrangements and cultures
differ across regions in the world in systematic ways, we surmise that
collaboration networks and impact should also differ systematically across
regions. To test this, we compare the structure of collaboration networks among
prominent researchers in North America and Europe. We find that prominent
researchers in Europe establish denser collaboration networks, whereas those in
North-America establish more decentralized networks. We also find that the
impact of the publications of prominent researchers in North America is
significantly higher than for those in Europe, both when they collaborate with
other prominent researchers and when they do not. Although Europeans
collaborate with other prominent researchers more often, which increases their
impact, we also find that repeated collaboration among prominent researchers
decreases the synergistic effect of collaborating.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Danus_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Lluis Danus&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Muntaner_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Carles Muntaner&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Krauss_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Alexander Krauss&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Sales_Pardo_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Marta Sales-Pardo&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Guimera_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Roger Guimera&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01955">
<title>Quantifying the `end of history&apos; through a Bayesian Markov-chain approach. (arXiv:2211.01955v1 [physics.soc-ph])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01955</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Political regimes have been changing throughout human history. After the
apparent triumph of liberal democracies at the end of the twentieth century,
Francis Fukuyama and others have been arguing that humankind is approaching an
`end of history&apos; (EoH) in the form of a universality of liberal democracies.
This view has been challenged by recent developments that seem to indicate the
rise of defective democracies across the globe. There has been no attempt to
quantify the expected EoH with a statistical approach. In this study, we model
the transition between political regimes as a Markov process and -- using a
Bayesian inference approach -- we estimate the transition probabilities between
political regimes from time-series data describing the evolution of political
regimes from 1800--2018. We then compute the steady state for this Markov
process which represents a mathematical abstraction of the EoH and predicts
that approximately 46 % of countries will be full democracies. Furthermore, we
find that, under our model, the fraction of autocracies in the world is
expected to increase for the next half-century before it declines. Using
random-walk theory, we then estimate survival curves of different types of
regimes and estimate characteristic lifetimes of democracies and autocracies of
244 years and 69 years, respectively. Quantifying the expected EoH allows us to
challenge common beliefs about the nature of political equilibria.
Specifically, we find no statistical evidence that the EoH constitutes a fixed,
complete omnipresence of democratic regimes.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Klimm_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Florian Klimm&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.02023">
<title>Research on the impact of asteroid mining on global equity. (arXiv:2211.02023v1 [physics.soc-ph])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.02023</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;In the future situation, aiming to seek more resources, human beings decided
to march towards the mysterious and bright starry sky, which opened the era of
great interstellar exploration. According to the Outer Space Treaty, any
exploration of celestial bodies should be aimed at promoting global equality
and for the benefit of all nations. Firstly, we defined global equity and set a
Unified Equity Index (UEI) model to measure it. We merge the factors with
greater correlation, and finally, get 6 elements, and then use the entropy
method (TEM) to find the dispersion of these elements in different countries.
Then use principal component analysis (PCA) to reduce the dimensionality of the
dispersion, and then use the scandalized index to obtain the global equity.
Secondly, we simulated a future with asteroid mining and evaluated its impact
on Unified Equity Index (UEI). Then, we divided the mineable asteroids into
three classes with different mining difficulties and values, identified 28
mining entities including private companies, national and international
organizations. We considered changes in the asteroid classes, mining
capabilities and mining scales to determine the changes in the value of
minerals mined between 2025 and 2085. We convert mining output value into
mineral transaction value through allocation matrix. Based on grey relational
analysis (GRA). Finally, we presented three possible versions of the future of
asteroid mining by changing the conditions. We propose two sets of
corresponding policies for changes in future trends in global fairness with
asteroid mining. We test the separate and combined effects of these policies
and find that they are positive, strongly supporting the effectiveness of our
model.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Sun_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;He Sun&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Zhu_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Junfeng Zhu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Xu_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yipeng Xu&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.02040">
<title>Barcelona, The Innovation District: between vulnerability and social equity. (arXiv:2211.02040v1 [physics.soc-ph])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.02040</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The municipal actors of the Catalan capital wish to obtain a reversal of the
negative representations concerning the lack of attractiveness of the district
of Poblenou considered as one of the poorest and most marginalized districts of
the city while having as identity the expression of &quot;Manchester southern
Europe&quot;, recalling its role as a factory for Spain and an emblem of the
Industrial Revolution for the Iberian Peninsula. Conceptualization, programming
and construction of a new image of the city through this large urban wasteland
are made concrete thanks to an urban marketing operation. The specifications
allow the construction of innovative buildings, with resolutely contemporary
architecture, breaking with the regulations in force on the limitation of the
height of skyscrapers in order to make this pericentral territory visible and
attractive. Catalan society in the 21st century has produced a fragmented and
dominating neo-capitalist space through a thoughtless real estate frenzy and
complex land games. Walking through the streets of Poblenou, one is forced to
think of the work of Henri Lefebvre on the production of space and the three
orders of understanding the design of an urban composition. Here, the city has
become a stake and the place of economic growth based on innovation. Finally,
neighborhood life is in complete mutation which seems for this territory to
leave a chance for a long time on the sidelines. We present an economic
analysis grid of a cluster with graphs and statistics.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Ballester_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;P. Ballester&lt;/a&gt; (GEODE, UPPA, AMU)</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.15555">
<title>A note on &quot;Goals, constraints, and transparently fair assignments: A field study of randomization design in the UEFA Champions League&apos;&apos;. (arXiv:2210.15555v2 [physics.soc-ph] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.15555</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;A paper published on 2 September 2022 in Management Science (Boczo\&apos;n, M. and
Wilson, A. J.: Goals, constraints, and transparently fair assignments: A field
study of randomization design in the UEFA Champions League) contains
substantial omissions and inaccuracies. This note attempts to correct them.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Csato_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;L&amp;#xe1;szl&amp;#xf3; Csat&amp;#xf3;&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
</rdf:RDF>