<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns:yt="http://www.youtube.com/xml/schemas/2015" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
 <link rel="self" href="http://www.youtube.com/feeds/videos.xml?channel_id=UCP3alkHEJhoxTpy3iVON-lg"/>
 <id>yt:channel:UCP3alkHEJhoxTpy3iVON-lg</id>
 <yt:channelId>UCP3alkHEJhoxTpy3iVON-lg</yt:channelId>
 <title>Physics with Elliot</title>
 <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCP3alkHEJhoxTpy3iVON-lg"/>
 <author>
  <name>Physics with Elliot</name>
  <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCP3alkHEJhoxTpy3iVON-lg</uri>
 </author>
 <published>2021-08-16T19:55:51+00:00</published>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:V8fSYnY9Bj0</id>
  <yt:videoId>V8fSYnY9Bj0</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCP3alkHEJhoxTpy3iVON-lg</yt:channelId>
  <title>How General Relativity Reshaped the Universe!</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=V8fSYnY9Bj0"/>
  <author>
   <name>Physics with Elliot</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCP3alkHEJhoxTpy3iVON-lg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-05-17T21:15:22+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-06-27T23:03:50+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>How General Relativity Reshaped the Universe!</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/V8fSYnY9Bj0?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i3.ytimg.com/vi/V8fSYnY9Bj0/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>Discover how Einstein's general theory of relativity spans the cosmic spectrum from planetary orbits to black holes! Sponsored by Babbel 🎉: Start speaking a new language in 3 weeks. Get up to 65% OFF your subscription ▶️ HERE: https://go.babbel.com/12m65-youtube-physicswithelliot-may-2022/default

Get the notes for free here: https://courses.physicswithelliot.com/notes-sign-up

Einstein's theory of gravity---general relativity---was the last great pillar of pre-quantum physics. Gravity, he says, results from the curvature of spacetime in the presence of massive objects like stars. Then lighter particles moving nearby just travel along the straightest possible routes that they can through this curved geometry, called geodesics. And yet over 200 years earlier  Newton wrote down a vastly simpler force law for gravity  and used it to derive the orbits of the planets in our solar system to remarkable accuracy. So how is it that these two radically different descriptions of gravity fit together? And how does Einstein's theory go beyond Newton's, to predict the existence of black holes? (Like the Sagittarius A* supermassive black hole at the center of our galaxy that the Event Horizon Telescope collaboration released the first ever picture of just last week!) We'll explore it all in this video. We'll learn about geodesics, gravitational time dilation, the Schwarzschild solution of Einstein's equations, and the black hole geometries that emerge when you squish a star into a ball smaller than its Schwarzschild radius. You'll come away with an appreciation for how Einstein's theory can capture the same physics as Newton's inverse square law in the limit when gravity is weak, and at the same time describe black holes in the opposite limit when gravity is strong.

Related videos:

How Newton derived the orbit of our home planet: https://youtu.be/wLYZsO6lk0E

The life of a particle in special relativity: https://youtu.be/KVk1QNTWBxQ

The life of a particle in general relativity and the geodesic equation: https://youtu.be/h2SEK6Jjv3Y

Field theory fundamentals: https://youtu.be/13hCkUiu_mI

The principle of least action: https://youtu.be/sUk9y23FPHk


If you find the content I’m creating valuable and would like to help make it possible for me to continue sharing more, please consider supporting me! You can make a recurring contribution at https://www.Patreon.com/PhysicsWithElliot, or make a one time contribution at https://www.physicswithelliot.com/support-me. Thank you so much!

About physics mini lessons:
In these intermediate-level physics lessons, I'll try to give you a self-contained introduction to some fascinating physics topics. If you're just getting started on your physics journey, you might not understand every single detail in every video---that's totally fine! What I'm really hoping is that you'll be inspired to go off and keep learning more on your own.

About me:
I’m Dr. Elliot Schneider. I love physics, and I want to help others learn (and learn to love) physics, too. Whether you’re a beginner just starting out with your physics studies, a more advanced student, or a lifelong learner, I hope you’ll find resources here that enable you to deepen your understanding of the laws of nature. For more cool physics stuff, visit me at https://www.physicswithelliot.com.</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="1173" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="25017"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:I4CjewbJgRQ</id>
  <yt:videoId>I4CjewbJgRQ</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCP3alkHEJhoxTpy3iVON-lg</yt:channelId>
  <title>Particle Physics is Founded on This Principle!</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=I4CjewbJgRQ"/>
  <author>
   <name>Physics with Elliot</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCP3alkHEJhoxTpy3iVON-lg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-04-14T20:50:37+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-06-27T23:03:18+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Particle Physics is Founded on This Principle!</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/I4CjewbJgRQ?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i2.ytimg.com/vi/I4CjewbJgRQ/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>Take your first steps toward understanding gauge field theory, which underlies everything we know about particle physics! Sponsored by Blinkist: Start your free trial and get 25% off! https://www.blinkist.com/elliot

Get the notes for free here: https://courses.physicswithelliot.com/notes-sign-up

Conservation laws, symmetries, and in particular gauge symmetries are fundamental to the construction of the standard model of particle physics. And as we've seen in past videos, the link that connects symmetries and conservation laws is Noether's theorem. In this video, we'll see how it all extends to field theories. We'll learn to formulate a local conservation law by writing down its continuity equation, which describes how charge is conserved in any region of space. Then we'll see how these conservation laws appear any time we have a field theory with a continuous symmetry. We'll learn about the symmetry of electromagnetism, called U(1), that leads to the conservation of electric charge. And finally, we'll see how to write down the simplest example of a gauge theory by coupling to the electromagnetic potential. The global U(1) symmetry becomes a local symmetry thanks to the covariant derivative, and we arrive at a U(1) gauge theory! The standard model is a generalization of all this.

Field theory fundamentals: https://youtu.be/13hCkUiu_mI

Intro to Noether's theorem: https://youtu.be/O0NYaO_OnH4

The principle of least action: https://youtu.be/sUk9y23FPHk

The Lagrangian for a special relativistic particle: https://youtu.be/KVk1QNTWBxQ

The Lagrangian for a general relativistic particle: https://youtu.be/h2SEK6Jjv3Y

Tutoring  inquiries: https://www.physicswithelliot.com/tutoring

If you find the content I’m creating valuable and would like to help make it possible for me to continue sharing more, please consider supporting me! You can make a recurring contribution at https://www.Patreon.com/PhysicsWithElliot, or make a one time contribution at https://www.physicswithelliot.com/support-me. Thank you so much!

About physics mini lessons:
In these intermediate-level physics lessons, I'll try to give you a self-contained introduction to some fascinating physics topics. If you're just getting started on your physics journey, you might not understand every single detail in every video---that's totally fine! What I'm really hoping is that you'll be inspired to go off and keep learning more on your own.

About me:
I’m Dr. Elliot Schneider. I love physics, and I want to help others learn (and learn to love) physics, too. Whether you’re a beginner just starting out with your physics studies, a more advanced student, or a lifelong learner, I hope you’ll find resources here that enable you to deepen your understanding of the laws of nature. For more cool physics stuff, visit me at https://www.physicswithelliot.com.</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="2520" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="60893"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:HQsZG8Yxb7w</id>
  <yt:videoId>HQsZG8Yxb7w</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCP3alkHEJhoxTpy3iVON-lg</yt:channelId>
  <title>The Most Important Math Formula For Understanding Physics</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=HQsZG8Yxb7w"/>
  <author>
   <name>Physics with Elliot</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCP3alkHEJhoxTpy3iVON-lg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-03-08T22:49:05+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-06-27T23:02:46+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>The Most Important Math Formula For Understanding Physics</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/HQsZG8Yxb7w?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i1.ytimg.com/vi/HQsZG8Yxb7w/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>Math is the language of physics, and there's one formula that you'll encounter time and again in your study of physics: the Taylor series. Get the notes for free here: https://courses.physicswithelliot.com/notes-sign-up

If I had to name one mathematical theorem that's the most essential for understanding physics, it would be Taylor's formula. It shows up in virtually everything we do in physics. In this video, I'll teach you the basics of Taylor series, and show you a few applications in different corners of physics. In the first part, we'll go through the math, including how to write Taylor's formula in a particularly beautiful way that also makes the generalization to the multi-variable case straightforward. In the second half, we'll look at three physics applications. First, we'll discuss how to linearize complicated F = ma equations to simplify them in special limits. Then we'll learn to take the non-relativistic limit of Einstein's energy formula, and see how it's related to the fine-structure correction to the binding energy of a hydrogen atom. And third we'll look at the definition of the momentum operator in quantum mechanics.

All about pendulums: https://youtu.be/0q0L7Fj4dk8

Taylor expanding the potential energy and discovering the harmonic oscillator: https://youtu.be/bmGqhM-tUk4

Dimensional analysis and the binding energy of hydrogen: https://youtu.be/kC6U900CvwY

Defining the momentum operator in quantum mechanics: https://youtu.be/_lz1VfI6Wxk

Tutoring inquiries: https://www.physicswithelliot.com/tutoring

If you find the content I’m creating valuable and would like to help make it possible for me to continue sharing more, please consider supporting me! You can make a recurring contribution at https://www.Patreon.com/PhysicsWithElliot, or make a one time contribution at https://www.physicswithelliot.com/support-me. Thank you so much!

About physics help room videos:
These are intro-level physics videos aimed at students taking their first physics classes. In each video, I'll teach you the fundamentals of a particular physics topic you're likely to meet in your first classes on mechanics and electromagnetism.

About me:
I’m Dr. Elliot Schneider. I love physics, and I want to help others learn (and learn to love) physics, too. Whether you’re a beginner just starting out with your physics studies, a more advanced student, or a lifelong learner, I hope you’ll find resources here that enable you to deepen your understanding of the laws of nature. For more cool physics stuff, visit me at https://www.physicswithelliot.com.</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="3957" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="100776"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:13hCkUiu_mI</id>
  <yt:videoId>13hCkUiu_mI</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCP3alkHEJhoxTpy3iVON-lg</yt:channelId>
  <title>Field Theory Fundamentals in 20 Minutes!</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=13hCkUiu_mI"/>
  <author>
   <name>Physics with Elliot</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCP3alkHEJhoxTpy3iVON-lg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-02-11T20:27:03+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-06-27T23:02:01+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Field Theory Fundamentals in 20 Minutes!</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/13hCkUiu_mI?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i2.ytimg.com/vi/13hCkUiu_mI/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>Field theory is the mathematical language that we use to describe the deepest theories of physics. I'll teach you the basics in about 20 minutes. Get the notes for free here: https://courses.physicswithelliot.com/notes-sign-up

The most fundamental laws of nature that human beings have understood---the standard model of particle physics and Einstein's theory of gravity---are written in the language of field theory; quantum in the first case and classical in the second. The first field theory that you're likely to meet in your physics classes is electromagnetism, which describes the electric and magnetic fields through which light waves ripple all around us. But electromagnetism is actually fairly complicated; to learn field theory, it's better to start with a simpler example, and that's what I do in this video. I'll teach you the fundamentals using the Klein-Gordon theory of a real, scalar field. We'll see how to write down the Lagrangian, apply the principle of least action to obtain the Klein-Gordon field equation, how to solve it using plane waves, and how relativity is built in from the beginning.
We'll also take a peek at quantum field theory along the way.

Get all the links here: https://www.physicswithelliot.com/fields-mini

The principle of least action: https://youtu.be/sUk9y23FPHk

The Lagrangian for a special relativistic particle: https://youtu.be/KVk1QNTWBxQ

The Lagrangian for a general relativistic particle: https://youtu.be/h2SEK6Jjv3Y

Tutoring  inquiries: https://www.physicswithelliot.com/tutoring

If you find the content I’m creating valuable and would like to help make it possible for me to continue sharing more, please consider supporting me! You can make a recurring contribution at https://www.Patreon.com/PhysicsWithElliot, or make a one time contribution at https://www.physicswithelliot.com/support-me. Thank you so much!

About physics mini lessons:
In these intermediate-level physics lessons, I'll try to give you a self-contained introduction to some fascinating physics topics. If you're just getting started on your physics journey, you might not understand every single detail in every video---that's totally fine! What I'm really hoping is that you'll be inspired to go off and keep learning more on your own.

About me:
I’m Dr. Elliot Schneider. I love physics, and I want to help others learn (and learn to love) physics, too. Whether you’re a beginner just starting out with your physics studies, a more advanced student, or a lifelong learner, I hope you’ll find resources here that enable you to deepen your understanding of the laws of nature. For more cool physics stuff, visit me at https://www.physicswithelliot.com.</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="8882" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="213461"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:bmGqhM-tUk4</id>
  <yt:videoId>bmGqhM-tUk4</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCP3alkHEJhoxTpy3iVON-lg</yt:channelId>
  <title>To Master Physics, First Master the Harmonic Oscillator</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=bmGqhM-tUk4"/>
  <author>
   <name>Physics with Elliot</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCP3alkHEJhoxTpy3iVON-lg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-01-25T22:09:37+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-08-19T15:35:43+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>To Master Physics, First Master the Harmonic Oscillator</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/bmGqhM-tUk4?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i3.ytimg.com/vi/bmGqhM-tUk4/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>It's hard to overstate how important the simple harmonic oscillator is in so many areas of physics. Almost every system is an oscillator near a stable equilibrium! Get the notes for free here: https://courses.physicswithelliot.com/notes-sign-up

Of all the systems you'll study in your first physics class, the oscillations of a block attached to a spring are a subject you'll meet again and again throughout your physics education. The spring exerts a force on the block (sometimes called Hooke's law) that tries to push it back toward equilibrium, and the result is that the block oscillates around equilibrium in simple harmonic motion. But why is this simple system so prevalent throughout physics? The basic reason is that you can Taylor expand any potential energy function near a stable equilibrium point, and it will almost always look like the parabola of the simple harmonic oscillator potential energy!

Play with the animations: https://www.physicswithelliot.com/oscillator-help-room

How to think of the potential energy like a hill: https://youtu.be/NvOvmgHSFx0

All about pendulums: https://youtu.be/0q0L7Fj4dk8

Tutoring inquiries: https://www.physicswithelliot.com/tutoring

If you find the content I’m creating valuable and would like to help make it possible for me to continue sharing more, please consider supporting me! You can make a recurring contribution at https://www.Patreon.com/PhysicsWithElliot, or make a one time contribution at https://www.physicswithelliot.com/support-me. Thank you so much!

About physics help room videos:
These are intro-level physics videos aimed at students taking their first physics classes. In each video, I'll teach you the fundamentals of a particular physics topic you're likely to meet in your first classes on mechanics and electromagnetism.

About me:
I’m Dr. Elliot Schneider. I love physics, and I want to help others learn (and learn to love) physics, too. Whether you’re a beginner just starting out with your physics studies, a more advanced student, or a lifelong learner, I hope you’ll find resources here that enable you to deepen your understanding of the laws of nature. For more cool physics stuff, visit me at https://www.physicswithelliot.com.</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="5243" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="111341"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:_lz1VfI6Wxk</id>
  <yt:videoId>_lz1VfI6Wxk</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCP3alkHEJhoxTpy3iVON-lg</yt:channelId>
  <title>The Symmetry at the Heart of the Canonical Commutation Relation</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_lz1VfI6Wxk"/>
  <author>
   <name>Physics with Elliot</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCP3alkHEJhoxTpy3iVON-lg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-01-11T23:13:55+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-09-26T17:29:03+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>The Symmetry at the Heart of the Canonical Commutation Relation</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/_lz1VfI6Wxk?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i4.ytimg.com/vi/_lz1VfI6Wxk/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>The canonical commutator is one of the most fundamental equations of quantum mechanics. But where does it come from? I'll show you how symmetry leads straight to it! Get the notes for free here: https://courses.physicswithelliot.com/notes-sign-up

The canonical commutation relation between the position operator and momentum operator is one of the defining equations of quantum mechanics. It's what leads to the Heisenberg uncertainty principle, that even if you know the quantum state (or wavefunction) of a particle, you can't precisely determine its position and momentum at the same time. In this video, I'll show how the CCR follows by defining the momentum as the generator of spatial translation symmetry. Along the way, we'll take a crash course in the fundamentals of quantum mechanics.

Get all the links here: https://www.physicswithelliot.com/ccr-mini

Related earlier videos:

- Poisson brackets demystified: https://youtu.be/Nd4b0_vJZUk

- Hamiltonian Noether theorem: https://youtu.be/uncm8DChdhc


Tutoring  inquiries: https://www.physicswithelliot.com/tutoring

If you find the content I’m creating valuable and would like to help make it possible for me to continue sharing more, please consider supporting me! You can make a recurring contribution at https://www.Patreon.com/PhysicsWithElliot, or make a one time contribution at https://www.physicswithelliot.com/support-me. Thank you so much!

About physics mini lessons:
In these intermediate-level physics lessons, I'll try to give you a self-contained introduction to some fascinating physics topics. If you're just getting started on your physics journey, you might not understand every single detail in every video---that's totally fine! What I'm really hoping is that you'll be inspired to go off and keep learning more on your own.

About me:
I’m Dr. Elliot Schneider. I love physics, and I want to help others learn (and learn to love) physics, too. Whether you’re a beginner just starting out with your physics studies, a more advanced student, or a lifelong learner, I hope you’ll find resources here that enable you to deepen your understanding of the laws of nature. For more cool physics stuff, visit me at https://www.physicswithelliot.com.</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="1261" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="21067"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:uncm8DChdhc</id>
  <yt:videoId>uncm8DChdhc</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCP3alkHEJhoxTpy3iVON-lg</yt:channelId>
  <title>The Most Beautiful Result in Classical Mechanics</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=uncm8DChdhc"/>
  <author>
   <name>Physics with Elliot</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCP3alkHEJhoxTpy3iVON-lg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-01-01T20:41:13+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-08-19T15:50:16+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>The Most Beautiful Result in Classical Mechanics</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/uncm8DChdhc?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i2.ytimg.com/vi/uncm8DChdhc/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>Noether's theorem says that a symmetry of a Lagrangian implies a conservation law. But to fully appreciate the connection we need to go to Hamiltonian mechanics and see how symmetries act on phase space! Get the notes for free here: https://courses.physicswithelliot.com/notes-sign-up

The connection between symmetries and conservation laws is one of the deepest relationships in physics. Noether's theorem says that for every continuous symmetry of a Lagrangian, you'll find a corresponding conserved quantity. But to fully understand the connection between the two, we need to investigate their relationship in Hamiltonian mechanics. Any function on phase space generates a &quot;flow,&quot; similar to how the Hamiltonian generates time evolution. Then the rate of change of any other function along the flow is given by its Poisson bracket with the generator. A quantity will be conserved if and only if the flow that it generates leaves the Hamiltonian invariant!

Get all the links here: https://www.physicswithelliot.com/hamiltonian-noether-mini

Watch these first!:

- The principle of least action: https://youtu.be/sUk9y23FPHk

- Noether's theorem: https://youtu.be/O0NYaO_OnH4

- Poisson brackets: https://youtu.be/Nd4b0_vJZUk

Also check out:

A 20 minute intro to Lagrangian and Hamiltonian mechanics: https://youtu.be/0DHNGtsmmH8

The relativistic action: https://youtu.be/KVk1QNTWBxQ

Tutoring  inquiries: https://www.physicswithelliot.com/tutoring

If you find the content I’m creating valuable and would like to help make it possible for me to continue sharing more, please consider supporting me! You can make a recurring contribution at https://www.Patreon.com/PhysicsWithElliot, or make a one time contribution at https://www.physicswithelliot.com/support-me. Thank you so much!

About physics mini lessons:
In these intermediate-level physics lessons, I'll try to give you a self-contained introduction to some fascinating physics topics. If you're just getting started on your physics journey, you might not understand every single detail in every video---that's totally fine! What I'm really hoping is that you'll be inspired to go off and keep learning more on your own.

About me:
I’m Dr. Elliot Schneider. I love physics, and I want to help others learn (and learn to love) physics, too. Whether you’re a beginner just starting out with your physics studies, a more advanced student, or a lifelong learner, I hope you’ll find resources here that enable you to deepen your understanding of the laws of nature. For more cool physics stuff, visit me at https://www.physicswithelliot.com.</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="1671" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="28705"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:kC6U900CvwY</id>
  <yt:videoId>kC6U900CvwY</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCP3alkHEJhoxTpy3iVON-lg</yt:channelId>
  <title>How to Succeed at Physics Without Really Trying</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=kC6U900CvwY"/>
  <author>
   <name>Physics with Elliot</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCP3alkHEJhoxTpy3iVON-lg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2021-12-22T22:11:32+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-09-28T00:15:49+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>How to Succeed at Physics Without Really Trying</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/kC6U900CvwY?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i4.ytimg.com/vi/kC6U900CvwY/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>Units are your physics superpower! With dimensional analysis, you can get 90% of the way to the answer for many physics problems with next to no work! Get the notes for free here: https://courses.physicswithelliot.com/notes-sign-up

In any given physics problem, you have a certain list of parameters at your disposal: masses, charges, lengths, and so on, and fundamental constants like G and c. And you're looking for an answer with some particular units. Dimensional analysis is a strategy to figure out how you can combine the given parameters to get the correct units of the answer you want. And often times this approach can get you 90% of the answer with minimal effort. I'll show you how to apply it to three very different problems: the period of a pendulum, the binding energy of a hydrogen atom, and the event horizon radius of a black hole.

Get the links here: https://www.physicswithelliot.com/dimensional-analysis-help-room

More about the pendulum period: https://youtu.be/NvOvmgHSFx0

How to catch your own mistakes by checking units: https://youtu.be/iDVaoU8MmVw

All about pendulums: https://youtu.be/0q0L7Fj4dk8

Tutoring inquiries: https://www.physicswithelliot.com/tutoring

If you find the content I’m creating valuable and would like to help make it possible for me to continue sharing more, please consider supporting me! You can make a recurring contribution at https://www.Patreon.com/PhysicsWithElliot, or make a one time contribution at https://www.physicswithelliot.com/support-me. Thank you so much!

About physics help room videos:
These are intro-level physics videos aimed at students taking their first physics classes. In each video, I'll teach you the fundamentals of a particular physics topic you're likely to meet in your first classes on mechanics and electromagnetism.

About me:
I’m Dr. Elliot Schneider. I love physics, and I want to help others learn (and learn to love) physics, too. Whether you’re a beginner just starting out with your physics studies, a more advanced student, or a lifelong learner, I hope you’ll find resources here that enable you to deepen your understanding of the laws of nature. For more cool physics stuff, visit me at https://www.physicswithelliot.com.</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="940" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="15494"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:Nd4b0_vJZUk</id>
  <yt:videoId>Nd4b0_vJZUk</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCP3alkHEJhoxTpy3iVON-lg</yt:channelId>
  <title>Before You Start On Quantum Mechanics, Learn This</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Nd4b0_vJZUk"/>
  <author>
   <name>Physics with Elliot</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCP3alkHEJhoxTpy3iVON-lg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2021-12-16T23:02:37+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-06-27T23:00:07+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Before You Start On Quantum Mechanics, Learn This</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/Nd4b0_vJZUk?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i3.ytimg.com/vi/Nd4b0_vJZUk/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>Quantum mechanics is mysterious---but not as mysterious as it has to be. Most quantum equations have close parallels in classical mechanics, where quantum commutators are replaced by Poisson brackets. Get the notes for free here: https://courses.physicswithelliot.com/notes-sign-up

You can't derive quantum mechanics from classical laws like F = ma, but there are close parallels between many classical and quantum equations. Many fundamental quantum equations are expressed as a commutator of operators, such as the canonical commutation relation and the Heisenberg equation of motion. These equations have classical parallels where the quantum commutator is replaced by a classical operation called the Poisson bracket, up to a factor of i hbar. I'll show how Poisson brackets work, and how they mirror these key quantum equations.

Get all the links here: https://www.physicswithelliot.com/poisson-mini

Intro to Lagrangian and Hamiltonian mechanics: https://youtu.be/0DHNGtsmmH8

Introduction to the principle of least action: https://youtu.be/sUk9y23FPHk

Noether's theorem: https://youtu.be/O0NYaO_OnH4

Tutoring  inquiries: https://www.physicswithelliot.com/tutoring

If you find the content I’m creating valuable and would like to help make it possible for me to continue sharing more, please consider supporting me! You can make a recurring contribution at https://www.Patreon.com/PhysicsWithElliot, or make a one time contribution at https://www.physicswithelliot.com/support-me. Thank you so much!

About physics mini lessons:
In these intermediate-level physics lessons, I'll try to give you a self-contained introduction to some fascinating physics topics. If you're just getting started on your physics journey, you might not understand every single detail in every video---that's totally fine! What I'm really hoping is that you'll be inspired to go off and keep learning more on your own.

About me:
I’m Dr. Elliot Schneider. I love physics, and I want to help others learn (and learn to love) physics, too. Whether you’re a beginner just starting out with your physics studies, a more advanced student, or a lifelong learner, I hope you’ll find resources here that enable you to deepen your understanding of the laws of nature. For more cool physics stuff, visit me at https://www.physicswithelliot.com.</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="3410" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="59259"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:A_79m5x0ucY</id>
  <yt:videoId>A_79m5x0ucY</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCP3alkHEJhoxTpy3iVON-lg</yt:channelId>
  <title>Why Newton's 3rd Law is Conservation of Momentum in Disguise</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=A_79m5x0ucY"/>
  <author>
   <name>Physics with Elliot</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCP3alkHEJhoxTpy3iVON-lg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2021-12-09T19:04:14+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-09-27T16:02:10+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Why Newton's 3rd Law is Conservation of Momentum in Disguise</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/A_79m5x0ucY?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i2.ytimg.com/vi/A_79m5x0ucY/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>Newton's third law says that for every action there's an equal-but-opposite reaction. Hidden inside it is a deep principle of physics: conservation of momentum! Get the notes for free here: https://courses.physicswithelliot.com/notes-sign-up

Newton's third law looks a little strange the first time you see it: all forces between particles come in equal-but-opposite pairs. But it's really all about a more intuitive physical principle: the conservation of momentum. It implies that in an isolated system---meaning one where there are no outside forces acting on it---the total momentum will be conserved. I'll explain why in this video. But there's a catch: Newton's third law isn't always true!

Get the links here: https://www.physicswithelliot.com/third-law-help-room

A more advanced video about Noether's theorem: https://youtu.be/O0NYaO_OnH4

Tutoring inquiries: https://www.physicswithelliot.com/tutoring

If you find the content I’m creating valuable and would like to help make it possible for me to continue sharing more, please consider supporting me! You can make a recurring contribution at https://www.Patreon.com/PhysicsWithElliot, or make a one time contribution at https://www.physicswithelliot.com/support-me. Thank you so much!

About physics help room videos:
These are intro-level physics videos aimed at students taking their first physics classes. In each video, I'll teach you the fundamentals of a particular physics topic you're likely to meet in your first classes on mechanics and electromagnetism.

About me:
I’m Dr. Elliot Schneider. I love physics, and I want to help others learn (and learn to love) physics, too. Whether you’re a beginner just starting out with your physics studies, a more advanced student, or a lifelong learner, I hope you’ll find resources here that enable you to deepen your understanding of the laws of nature. For more cool physics stuff, visit me at https://www.physicswithelliot.com.</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="612" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="8882"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:O0NYaO_OnH4</id>
  <yt:videoId>O0NYaO_OnH4</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCP3alkHEJhoxTpy3iVON-lg</yt:channelId>
  <title>Symmetries &amp; Conservation Laws: A (Physics) Love Story</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=O0NYaO_OnH4"/>
  <author>
   <name>Physics with Elliot</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCP3alkHEJhoxTpy3iVON-lg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2021-12-02T23:24:46+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-06-27T22:58:02+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Symmetries &amp; Conservation Laws: A (Physics) Love Story</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/O0NYaO_OnH4?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i4.ytimg.com/vi/O0NYaO_OnH4/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>There is a deep connection in physics between symmetries of nature and conservation laws, called Noether's theorem. In this physics lesson I'll show you how it works. Get the notes for free here: https://courses.physicswithelliot.com/notes-sign-up

The relationship between symmetries and conservation laws is one of the most profound and far-reaching connections in physics. The central result is called Noether's theorem, and it says that for every continuous symmetry of the Lagrangian or action for a system, you'll find a corresponding conserved quantity. Momentum conservation, for example, follows from a symmetry called spatial translation invariance, meaning that you can pick up your system and slide it over without changing anything about the physics. Likewise, angular momentum conservation follows from rotation invariance, and energy conservation from time translation invariance.

Get all the links here: https://www.physicswithelliot.com/noether-mini

Introduction to the principle of least action: https://youtu.be/sUk9y23FPHk

Intro to Lagrangian (and Hamiltonian) mechanics: https://youtu.be/0DHNGtsmmH8

The Hamiltonian version of Noether's theorem: https://youtu.be/uncm8DChdhc

Tutoring  inquiries: https://www.physicswithelliot.com/tutoring

If you find the content I’m creating valuable and would like to help make it possible for me to continue sharing more, please consider supporting me! You can make a recurring contribution at https://www.Patreon.com/PhysicsWithElliot, or make a one time contribution at https://www.physicswithelliot.com/support-me. Thank you so much!

About physics mini lessons:
In these intermediate-level physics lessons, I'll try to give you a self-contained introduction to some fascinating physics topics. If you're just getting started on your physics journey, you might not understand every single detail in every video---that's totally fine! What I'm really hoping is that you'll be inspired to go off and keep learning more on your own.

About me:
I’m Dr. Elliot Schneider. I love physics, and I want to help others learn (and learn to love) physics, too. Whether you’re a beginner just starting out with your physics studies, a more advanced student, or a lifelong learner, I hope you’ll find resources here that enable you to deepen your understanding of the laws of nature. For more cool physics stuff, visit me at https://www.physicswithelliot.com.</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="2266" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="42562"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:KpIaWiWvuRs</id>
  <yt:videoId>KpIaWiWvuRs</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCP3alkHEJhoxTpy3iVON-lg</yt:channelId>
  <title>The First Thing You'll Learn in a String Theory Class</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=KpIaWiWvuRs"/>
  <author>
   <name>Physics with Elliot</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCP3alkHEJhoxTpy3iVON-lg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2021-11-22T19:32:11+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-09-27T18:46:06+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>The First Thing You'll Learn in a String Theory Class</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/KpIaWiWvuRs?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i4.ytimg.com/vi/KpIaWiWvuRs/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>As a string moves through spacetime, it sweeps out a surface called its worldsheet. The starting point for string theory sets the action equal to the area of this worldsheet. Get the notes for free here: https://courses.physicswithelliot.com/notes-sign-up

Get all the links here: https://www.physicswithelliot.com/string-action-mini

This video is part 4 of the series I've been sharing with you about the principle of least action. The first video was about a particle in Newtonian mechanics, the second was about a particle in special relativity, and the third about a particle in general relativity. In this video, we'll learn about the principle of least action for string theory. It's called the Nambu-Goto action, and it's given by the area of the worldsheet that the string sweeps out as it moves through spacetime.

Part 1 Introduction to the principle of least action: https://youtu.be/sUk9y23FPHk

Part 2 The action in special relativity: https://youtu.be/KVk1QNTWBxQ

Part 3 The action in general relativity: https://youtu.be/h2SEK6Jjv3Y

Tutoring  inquiries: https://www.physicswithelliot.com/tutoring

If you find the content I’m creating valuable and would like to help make it possible for me to continue sharing more, please consider supporting me! You can make a recurring contribution at https://www.Patreon.com/PhysicsWithElliot, or make a one time contribution at https://www.physicswithelliot.com/support-me. Thank you so much!

About physics mini lessons:
In these intermediate-level physics lessons, I'll try to give you a self-contained introduction to some fascinating physics topics. If you're just getting started on your physics journey, you might not understand every single detail in every video---that's totally fine! What I'm really hoping is that you'll be inspired to go off and keep learning more on your own.

About me:
I’m Dr. Elliot Schneider. I love physics, and I want to help others learn (and learn to love) physics, too. Whether you’re a beginner just starting out with your physics studies, a more advanced student, or a lifelong learner, I hope you’ll find resources here that enable you to deepen your understanding of the laws of nature. For more cool physics stuff, visit me at https://www.physicswithelliot.com.</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="1289" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="21933"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:iDVaoU8MmVw</id>
  <yt:videoId>iDVaoU8MmVw</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCP3alkHEJhoxTpy3iVON-lg</yt:channelId>
  <title>What I Wish I'd Known As A Beginning Physics Student</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=iDVaoU8MmVw"/>
  <author>
   <name>Physics with Elliot</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCP3alkHEJhoxTpy3iVON-lg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2021-11-17T00:41:23+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-01-01T16:46:07+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>What I Wish I'd Known As A Beginning Physics Student</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/iDVaoU8MmVw?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i2.ytimg.com/vi/iDVaoU8MmVw/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>Experienced physics students always do the same thing whenever they write down an answer to a question: check the units. If the units are wrong, you know you've made a mistake! That way, you can catch your own errors and elevate your grade.

Dimensional analysis is your physics superpower: https://youtu.be/kC6U900CvwY 

More physics help room videos: https://www.physicswithelliot.com/help-room-all

Tutoring inquiries: https://www.physicswithelliot.com/tutoring

If you find the content I’m creating valuable and would like to help make it possible for me to continue sharing more, please consider supporting me! You can make a recurring contribution at https://www.Patreon.com/PhysicsWithElliot, or make a one time contribution at https://www.physicswithelliot.com/support-me. Thank you so much!

About physics help room videos:
These are intro-level physics videos aimed at students taking their first physics classes. In each video, I'll teach you the fundamentals of a particular physics topic you're likely to meet in your first classes on mechanics and electromagnetism.

About me:
I’m Dr. Elliot Schneider. I love physics, and I want to help others learn (and learn to love) physics, too. Whether you’re a beginner just starting out with your physics studies, a more advanced student, or a lifelong learner, I hope you’ll find resources here that enable you to deepen your understanding of the laws of nature. For more cool physics stuff, visit me at https://www.physicswithelliot.com.</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="923" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="20451"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:RtWQYhWlqQ0</id>
  <yt:videoId>RtWQYhWlqQ0</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCP3alkHEJhoxTpy3iVON-lg</yt:channelId>
  <title>How Einstein Changed the Way We Look at the Universe #shorts</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=RtWQYhWlqQ0"/>
  <author>
   <name>Physics with Elliot</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCP3alkHEJhoxTpy3iVON-lg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2021-11-11T03:40:07+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-01-09T12:39:13+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>How Einstein Changed the Way We Look at the Universe #shorts</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/RtWQYhWlqQ0?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i3.ytimg.com/vi/RtWQYhWlqQ0/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>Einstein literally reshaped our understanding of the universe when he published his theory of gravity: general relativity. For more physics videos, subscribe to Physics with Elliot or visit https://www.physicswithelliot.com</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="527" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="6899"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:h2SEK6Jjv3Y</id>
  <yt:videoId>h2SEK6Jjv3Y</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCP3alkHEJhoxTpy3iVON-lg</yt:channelId>
  <title>How Einstein Uncovered the Path a Particle Traces Through Spacetime!</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=h2SEK6Jjv3Y"/>
  <author>
   <name>Physics with Elliot</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCP3alkHEJhoxTpy3iVON-lg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2021-11-10T04:32:34+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-09-27T11:20:03+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>How Einstein Uncovered the Path a Particle Traces Through Spacetime!</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/h2SEK6Jjv3Y?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i1.ytimg.com/vi/h2SEK6Jjv3Y/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>In Einstein's theory of gravity, general relativity, massive objects like stars warp the geometry of spacetime. Then a particle travels along the straightest and shortest path that it can through spacetime, called a geodesic. Get the notes for free here: https://courses.physicswithelliot.com/notes-sign-up

Get all the links here: https://www.physicswithelliot.com/gr-action-mini

This video is part 3 of the series I've been sharing with you about the principle of least action. The first video was about a particle in Newtonian mechanics, and the second was about a particle in special relativity. In this video, we'll learn about the principle of least action for a particle in general relativity. The action is just the length of the particle's worldline through spacetime, and it picks the straightest and shortest path that it can. The fourth video is about a string in string theory.

Part 1 Introduction to the principle of least action: https://youtu.be/sUk9y23FPHk

Part 2 The action in special relativity: https://youtu.be/KVk1QNTWBxQ

Part 4 The action for string theory: https://youtu.be/KpIaWiWvuRs

Tutoring  inquiries: https://www.physicswithelliot.com/tutoring

If you find the content I’m creating valuable and would like to help make it possible for me to continue sharing more, please consider supporting me! You can make a recurring contribution at https://www.Patreon.com/PhysicsWithElliot, or make a one time contribution at https://www.physicswithelliot.com/support-me. Thank you so much!

About physics mini lessons:
In these intermediate-level physics lessons, I'll try to give you a self-contained introduction to some fascinating physics topics. If you're just getting started on your physics journey, you might not understand every single detail in every video---that's totally fine! What I'm really hoping is that you'll be inspired to go off and keep learning more on your own.

About me:
I’m Dr. Elliot Schneider. I love physics, and I want to help others learn (and learn to love) physics, too. Whether you’re a beginner just starting out with your physics studies, a more advanced student, or a lifelong learner, I hope you’ll find resources here that enable you to deepen your understanding of the laws of nature. For more cool physics stuff, visit me at https://www.physicswithelliot.com.</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="1202" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="26924"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
</feed>
