<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<rdf:RDF
 xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
 xmlns="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/"
 xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
 xmlns:taxo="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/taxonomy/"
 xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
 xmlns:syn="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
 xmlns:admin="http://webns.net/mvcb/"
>

<channel rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/">
<title>eess.SP updates on arXiv.org</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">Electrical Engineering and Systems Science -- Signal Processing (eess.SP) updates on the arXiv.org e-print archive</description>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:date>2022-11-03T20:30:00-05:00</dc:date>
<dc:publisher>help@arxiv.org</dc:publisher>
<dc:subject>Electrical Engineering and Systems Science -- Signal Processing</dc:subject>
<syn:updateBase>1901-01-01T00:00+00:00</syn:updateBase>
<syn:updateFrequency>1</syn:updateFrequency>
<syn:updatePeriod>daily</syn:updatePeriod>
<items>
 <rdf:Seq>
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01411" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01573" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01603" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01640" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01659" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01669" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01684" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01704" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01716" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01717" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01730" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01731" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01738" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01849" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01856" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01943" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.02005" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.02012" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.02017" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2010.11114" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2111.02229" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2202.13526" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2205.03770" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2207.09340" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.17177" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.00230" />
 </rdf:Seq>
</items>
<image rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif" />
</channel>
<image rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif">
<title>arXiv.org</title>
<url>http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif</url>
<link>http://arxiv.org/</link>
</image>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01411">
<title>A Distributed Adaptive Algorithm for Node-Specific Signal Fusion Problems in Wireless Sensor Networks. (arXiv:2211.01411v1 [eess.SP])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01411</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Wireless sensor networks consist of sensor nodes that are physically
distributed over different locations. Spatial filtering procedures exploit the
spatial correlation across these sensor signals to fuse them into a filtered
signal satisfying some optimality condition. However, gathering the raw sensor
data in a fusion center to solve the problem in a centralized way would lead to
high energy and communication costs. The distributed adaptive signal fusion
(DASF) framework has been proposed as a generic method to solve these signal
fusion problems in a distributed fashion, which reduces the communication and
energy costs in the network. The DASF framework assumes that there is a common
goal across the nodes, i.e., the optimal filter is shared across the network.
However, many applications require a node-specific objective, while all these
node-specific objectives are still related via a common latent data model. In
this work, we propose the DANSF algorithm which builds upon the DASF framework,
and extends it to allow for node-specific spatial filtering problems.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/eess/1/au:+Musluoglu_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Cem Ates Musluoglu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/eess/1/au:+Bertrand_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Alexander Bertrand&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01573">
<title>Resource Allocation in MIMO setup. (arXiv:2211.01573v1 [cs.IT])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01573</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;In a multi-input multi-output (MIMO) setup, where one side of the link
comprises a linear antenna array, data can be transmitted over the direction of
incident rays. Channel capacity for this setup is studied in this paper. We
define two different setups; one when the energy is constant and equal over all
rays, and one when available energy is evenly distributed over rays. For the
latter, we show that there is an upper bound for channel capacity, regardless
of the number of rays and antennas. Also, we have compared this setup with the
legacy single-input single-output (SISO) AWGN channel.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Yun_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Felix Ma Yun&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Nabi_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jordan Nabi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Hassani_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Mitra Hassani&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01603">
<title>Using Signal Processing in Tandem With Adapted Mixture Models for Classifying Genomic Signals. (arXiv:2211.01603v1 [q-bio.GN])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01603</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Genomic signal processing has been used successfully in bioinformatics to
analyze biomolecular sequences and gain varied insights into DNA structure,
gene organization, protein binding, sequence evolution, etc. But challenges
remain in finding the appropriate spectral representation of a biomolecular
sequence, especially when multiple variable-length sequences need to be handled
consistently. In this study, we address this challenge in the context of the
well-studied problem of classifying genomic sequences into different taxonomic
units (strain, phyla, order, etc.). We propose a novel technique that employs
signal processing in tandem with Gaussian mixture models to improve the
spectral representation of a sequence and subsequently the taxonomic
classification accuracies. The sequences are first transformed into spectra,
and projected to a subspace, where sequences belonging to different taxons are
better distinguishable. Our method outperforms a similar state-of-the-art
method on established benchmark datasets by an absolute margin of 6.06%
accuracy.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/q-bio/1/au:+Jaiswal_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Saish Jaiswal&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/q-bio/1/au:+Nema_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Shreya Nema&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/q-bio/1/au:+Murthy_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Hema A Murthy&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/q-bio/1/au:+Narayanan_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Manikandan Narayanan&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01640">
<title>Joint Beamforming Design and 3D DoA Estimation for RIS-aided Communication System. (arXiv:2211.01640v1 [eess.SP])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01640</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;In this paper, we consider a reconfigurable intelligent surface
(RIS)-assisted 3D direction-of-arrival (DoA) estimation system, in which a
uniform planar array (UPA) RIS is deployed to provide virtual line-of-sight
(LOS) links and reflect the uplink pilot signal to sensors. To overcome the
mutually coupled problem between the beamforming design at the RIS and DoA
estimation, we explore the separable sparse representation structure and
propose an alternating optimization algorithm. The grid-based DoA estimation is
modeled as a joint-sparse recovery problem considering the grid bias, and the
Joint-2D-OMP method is used to estimate both on-grid and off-grid parts. The
corresponding Cram\&apos;er-Rao lower bound (CRLB) is derived to evaluate the
estimation. Then, the beampattern at the RIS is optimized to maximize the
signal-to-noise (SNR) at sensors according to the estimated angles. Numerical
results show that the proposed alternating optimization algorithm can achieve
lower estimation error compared to benchmarks of random beamforming design.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/eess/1/au:+Wang_Z/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Zhengyu Wang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/eess/1/au:+Yang_W/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Wei Yang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/eess/1/au:+Mi_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Tiebin Mi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/eess/1/au:+Qiu_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Robert Caiming Qiu&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01659">
<title>An Open Platform for Simulating the Physical Layer of 6G Communication Systems with Multiple Intelligent Surfaces. (arXiv:2211.01659v1 [cs.ET])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01659</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Reconfigurable Intelligent Surfaces (RIS) constitute a promising technology
that could fulfill the extreme performance and capacity needs of the upcoming
6G wireless networks, by offering software-defined control over wireless
propagation phenomena. Despite the existence of many theoretical models
describing various aspects of RIS from the signal processing perspective (e.g.,
channel fading models), there is no open platform to simulate and study their
actual physical-layer behavior, especially in the multi-RIS case. In this
paper, we develop an open simulation platform, aimed at modeling the
physical-layer electromagnetic coupling and propagation between RIS pairs. We
present the platform by initially designing a basic unit cell, and then
proceeding to progressively model and simulate multiple and larger RISs. The
platform can be used for producing verifiable stochastic models for wireless
communication in multi-RIS deployments, such as vehicle-to-everything (V2X)
communications in autonomous vehicles and cybersecurity schemes, while its code
is freely available to the public.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Papadopoulos_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Alexandros Papadopoulos&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Lalas_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Antonios Lalas&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Votis_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Konstantinos Votis&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Tyrovolas_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Dimitrios Tyrovolas&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Karagiannidis_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;George K. Karagiannidis&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Ioannidis_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Sotiris Ioannidis&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Liaskos_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Christos Liaskos&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01669">
<title>Channel-Aware Pretraining of Joint Encoder-Decoder Self-Supervised Model for Telephonic-Speech ASR. (arXiv:2211.01669v1 [eess.AS])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01669</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;This paper proposes a novel technique to obtain better downstream ASR
performance from a joint encoder-decoder self-supervised model when trained
with speech pooled from two different channels (narrow and wide band). The
joint encoder-decoder self-supervised model extends the HuBERT model with a
Transformer decoder. HuBERT performs clustering of features and predicts the
class of every input frame. In simple pooling, which is our baseline, there is
no way to identify the channel information. To incorporate channel information,
we have proposed non-overlapping cluster IDs for speech from different
channels. Our method gives a relative improvement of ~ 5% over the joint
encoder-decoder self-supervised model built with simple pooling of data, which
serves as our baseline.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/eess/1/au:+Sukhadia_V/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Vrunda N. Sukhadia&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/eess/1/au:+Arunkumar_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;A. Arunkumar&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/eess/1/au:+Umesh_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;S. Umesh&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01684">
<title>Indefinite causal order for quantum metrology with quantum thermal noise. (arXiv:2211.01684v1 [quant-ph])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01684</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;A switched quantum channel with indefinite causal order is studied for the
fundamental metrological task of phase estimation on a qubit unitary operator
affected by quantum thermal noise. Specific capabilities are reported in the
switched channel with indefinite order, not accessible with conventional
estimation approaches with definite order. Phase estimation can be performed by
measuring the control qubit alone, although it does not actively interact with
the unitary process -- only the probe qubit doing so. Also, phase estimation
becomes possible with a fully depolarized input probe or with an input probe
aligned with the rotation axis of the unitary, while this is never possible
with conventional approaches. The present study extends to thermal noise,
investigations previously carried out with the more symmetric and isotropic
qubit depolarizing noise, and it contributes to the timely exploration of
properties of quantum channels with indefinite causal order relevant to quantum
signal and information processing.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Chapeau_Blondeau_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Francois Chapeau-Blondeau&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01704">
<title>Cutting Through the Noise: An Empirical Comparison of Psychoacoustic and Envelope-based Features for Machinery Fault Detection. (arXiv:2211.01704v1 [eess.SP])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01704</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Acoustic-based fault detection has a high potential to monitor the health
condition of mechanical parts. However, the background noise of an industrial
environment may negatively influence the performance of fault detection.
Limited attention has been paid to improving the robustness of fault detection
against industrial environmental noise. Therefore, we present the Lenze
production background-noise (LPBN) real-world dataset and an automated and
noise-robust auditory inspection (ARAI) system for the end-of-line inspection
of geared motors. An acoustic array is used to acquire data from motors with a
minor fault, major fault, or which are healthy. A benchmark is provided to
compare the psychoacoustic features with different types of envelope features
based on expert knowledge of the gearbox. To the best of our knowledge, we are
the first to apply time-varying psychoacoustic features for fault detection. We
train a state-of-the-art one-class-classifier, on samples from healthy motors
and separate the faulty ones for fault detection using a threshold. The
best-performing approaches achieve an area under curve of 0.87 (logarithm
envelope), 0.86 (time-varying psychoacoustics), and 0.91 (combination of both).
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/eess/1/au:+Wissbrock_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Peter Wi&amp;#xdf;brock&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/eess/1/au:+Richter_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yvonne Richter&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/eess/1/au:+Pelkmann_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;David Pelkmann&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/eess/1/au:+Ren_Z/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Zhao Ren&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/eess/1/au:+Palmer_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Gregory Palmer&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01716">
<title>Discussion of Features for Acoustic Anomaly Detection under Industrial Disturbing Noise in an End-of-Line Test of Geared Motors. (arXiv:2211.01716v1 [eess.AS])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01716</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;In the end-of-line test of geared motors, the evaluation of product qual-ity
is important. Due to time constraints and the high diversity of variants,
acous-tic measurements are more economical than vibration measurements.
However, the acoustic data is affected by industrial disturbing noise.
Therefore, the aim of this study is to investigate the robustness of features
used for anomaly detection in geared motor end-of-line testing. A real-world
dataset with typical faults and acoustic disturbances is recorded by an
acoustic array. This includes industrial noise from the production and
systematically produced disturbances, used to compare the robustness. Overall,
it is proposed to apply features extracted from a log-envelope spectrum
together with psychoacoustic features. The anomaly de-tection is done by using
the isolation forest or the more universal bagging random miner. Most
disturbances can be circumvented, while the use of a hammer or air pressure
often causes problems. In general, these results are important for condi-tion
monitoring tasks that are based on acoustic or vibration measurements.
Fur-thermore, a real-world problem description is presented to improve common
sig-nal processing and machine learning tasks.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/eess/1/au:+Wissbrock_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Peter Wissbrock&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/eess/1/au:+Pelkmann_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;David Pelkmann&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/eess/1/au:+Richter_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yvonne Richter&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01717">
<title>Learning Hypergraphs From Signals With Dual Smoothness Prior. (arXiv:2211.01717v1 [cs.LG])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01717</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The construction of a meaningful hypergraph topology is the key to processing
signals with high-order relationships that involve more than two entities.
Learning the hypergraph structure from the observed signals to capture the
intrinsic relationships among the entities becomes crucial when a hypergraph
topology is not readily available in the datasets. There are two challenges
that lie at the heart of this problem: 1) how to handle the huge search space
of potential hyperedges, and 2) how to define meaningful criteria to measure
the relationship between the signals observed on nodes and the hypergraph
structure. In this paper, to address the first challenge, we adopt the
assumption that the ideal hypergraph structure can be derived from a learnable
graph structure that captures the pairwise relations within signals. Further,
we propose a hypergraph learning framework with a novel dual smoothness prior
that reveals a mapping between the observed node signals and the hypergraph
structure, whereby each hyperedge corresponds to a subgraph with both node
signal smoothness and edge signal smoothness in the learnable graph structure.
Finally, we conduct extensive experiments to evaluate the proposed framework on
both synthetic and real world datasets. Experiments show that our proposed
framework can efficiently infer meaningful hypergraph topologies from observed
signals.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Tang_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Bohan Tang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Chen_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Siheng Chen&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Dong_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xiaowen Dong&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01730">
<title>Feedback is Good, Active Feedback is Better: Block Attention Active Feedback Codes. (arXiv:2211.01730v1 [cs.IT])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01730</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Deep neural network (DNN)-assisted channel coding designs, such as
low-complexity neural decoders for existing codes, or end-to-end
neural-network-based auto-encoder designs are gaining interest recently due to
their improved performance and flexibility; particularly for communication
scenarios in which high-performing structured code designs do not exist.
Communication in the presence of feedback is one such communication scenario,
and practical code design for feedback channels has remained an open challenge
in coding theory for many decades. Recently, DNN-based designs have shown
impressive results in exploiting feedback. In particular, generalized block
attention feedback (GBAF) codes, which utilizes the popular transformer
architecture, achieved significant improvement in terms of the block error rate
(BLER) performance. However, previous works have focused mainly on passive
feedback, where the transmitter observes a noisy version of the signal at the
receiver. In this work, we show that GBAF codes can also be used for channels
with active feedback. We implement a pair of transformer architectures, at the
transmitter and the receiver, which interact with each other sequentially, and
achieve a new state-of-the-art BLER performance, especially in the low SNR
regime.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Ozfatura_E/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Emre Ozfatura&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Shao_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yulin Shao&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Ghazanfari_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Amin Ghazanfari&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Perotti_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Alberto Perotti&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Popovic_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Branislav Popovic&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Gunduz_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Deniz Gunduz&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01731">
<title>Data Converter Design Space Exploration for IoT Applications: An Overview of Challenges and Future Directions. (arXiv:2211.01731v1 [eess.SP])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01731</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Human lives are improving with the widespread use of cutting-edge digital
technology like the Internet of Things (IoT). Recently, the pandemic has shown
the demand for more digitally advanced IoT-based devices. International Data
Corporation (IDC) forecasts that by 2025, there will be approximately 42
billion of these devices in use, capable of producing around 80 ZB (zettabytes)
of data. So data acquisition, processing, communication, and visualization are
necessary from a functional standpoint. Indicating sensors &amp;amp; data converters
are the key components for IoT-based applications. The efficiency of such
applications is truly measured in terms of latency, power, and resolution of
data converters motivating designers to perform efficiently. Sensors capture
and covert physical features from their chosen environment into detectable
quantities. Data converter gives meaningful information and connects the real
analog world to the digital component of the devices. The received data is
interpreted and analyzed with the digital processing circuitry. Ultimately, it
is used as information by a network of internet-connected smart devices.
Because IoT technologies are adaptable to nearly any technology that may
provide its operational activity and environmental conditions. But the
challenges occur with power consumption as the complete IoT framework is
battery operated and replacing a battery is a daunting task. So the goal of
this chapter is to unveil the requirements to design energy-efficient data
converters for IoT applications.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/eess/1/au:+Sharma_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Buddhi Prakash Sharma&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/eess/1/au:+Gupta_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Anu Gupta&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/eess/1/au:+Shekhar_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Chandra Shekhar&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01738">
<title>Analysis of a Deep Learning Model for 12-Lead ECG Classification Reveals Learned Features Similar to Diagnostic Criteria. (arXiv:2211.01738v1 [eess.SP])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01738</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Despite their remarkable performance, deep neural networks remain unadopted
in clinical practice, which is considered to be partially due to their lack in
explainability. In this work, we apply attribution methods to a pre-trained
deep neural network (DNN) for 12-lead electrocardiography classification to
open this &quot;black box&quot; and understand the relationship between model prediction
and learned features. We classify data from a public data set and the
attribution methods assign a &quot;relevance score&quot; to each sample of the classified
signals. This allows analyzing what the network learned during training, for
which we propose quantitative methods: average relevance scores over a)
classes, b) leads, and c) average beats. The analyses of relevance scores for
atrial fibrillation (AF) and left bundle branch block (LBBB) compared to
healthy controls show that their mean values a) increase with higher
classification probability and correspond to false classifications when around
zero, and b) correspond to clinical recommendations regarding which lead to
consider. Furthermore, c) visible P-waves and concordant T-waves result in
clearly negative relevance scores in AF and LBBB classification, respectively.
In summary, our analysis suggests that the DNN learned features similar to
cardiology textbook knowledge.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/eess/1/au:+Bender_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Theresa Bender&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/eess/1/au:+Beinecke_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jacqueline Michelle Beinecke&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/eess/1/au:+Krefting_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Dagmar Krefting&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/eess/1/au:+Muller_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Carolin M&amp;#xfc;ller&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/eess/1/au:+Dathe_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Henning Dathe&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/eess/1/au:+Seidler_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Tim Seidler&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/eess/1/au:+Spicher_N/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Nicolai Spicher&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/eess/1/au:+Hauschild_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Anne-Christin Hauschild&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01849">
<title>Unsupervised Parameter Estimation using Model-based Decoder. (arXiv:2211.01849v1 [eess.SP])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01849</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;In this work, we consider the use of a model-based decoder in combination
with an unsupervised learning strategy for direction-of-arrival (DoA)
estimation. Relying only on unlabeled training data we show in our analysis
that we can outperform existing unsupervised machine learning methods and
classical methods. This is done by introducing a model-based decoder in an
autoencoder architecture with leads to a meaningful representation of the
statistical model in the latent space. Our numerical simulation show that the
performance of the presented approach is not affected by correlated signals but
rather improves slightly. This is due to the fact, that we propose the
estimation of the correlation parameters simultaneously to the DoA estimation.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/eess/1/au:+Weisser_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Franz Wei&amp;#xdf;er&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/eess/1/au:+Baur_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Michael Baur&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/eess/1/au:+Utschick_W/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Wolfgang Utschick&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01856">
<title>Human Biophysics as Network Weights: Conditional Generative Models for Ultra-fast Simulation. (arXiv:2211.01856v1 [cs.LG])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01856</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Simulations of biophysical systems have provided a huge contribution to our
fundamental understanding of human physiology and remain a central pillar for
developments in medical devices and human machine interfaces. However, despite
their successes, such simulations usually rely on highly computationally
expensive numerical modelling, which is often inefficient to adapt to new
simulation parameters. This limits their use in dynamic models of human
behavior, for example in modelling the electric fields generated by muscles in
a moving arm. We propose the alternative approach to use conditional generative
models, which can learn complex relationships between the underlying generative
conditions whilst remaining inexpensive to sample from. As a demonstration of
this concept, we present BioMime, a hybrid architecture that combines elements
of deep latent variable models and conditional adversarial training to
construct a generative model that can both transform existing data samples to
reflect new modelling assumptions and sample new data from a conditioned
distribution. We demonstrate that BioMime can learn to accurately mimic a
complex numerical model of human muscle biophysics and then use this knowledge
to continuously sample from a dynamically changing system in real-time. We
argue that transfer learning approaches with conditional generative models are
a viable solution for dynamic simulation with any numerical model.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Ma_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Shihan Ma&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Clarke_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Alexander Kenneth Clarke&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Maksymenko_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Kostiantyn Maksymenko&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Deslauriers_Gauthier_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Samuel Deslauriers-Gauthier&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Sheng_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xinjun Sheng&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zhu_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xiangyang Zhu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Farina_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Dario Farina&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01943">
<title>Quantized Precoding and RIS-Assisted Modulation for Integrated Sensing and Communications Systems. (arXiv:2211.01943v1 [eess.SP])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01943</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;In this paper, we present a novel reconfigurable intelligent surface
(RIS)-assisted integrated sensing and communication (ISAC) system with 1-bit
quantization at the ISAC base station. An RIS is introduced in the ISAC system
to mitigate the effects of coarse quantization and to enable the co-existence
between sensing and communication functionalities. Specifically, we design
transmit precoder to obtain 1-bit sensing waveforms having a desired radiation
pattern. The RIS phase shifts are then designed to modulate the 1-bit sensing
waveform to transmit M-ary phase shift keying symbols to users. Through
numerical simulations, we show that the proposed method offers significantly
improved symbol error probabilities when compared to MIMO communication systems
having quantized linear precoders, while still offering comparable sensing
performance as that of unquantized sensing systems.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/eess/1/au:+Sankar_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;R.S. Prasobh Sankar&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/eess/1/au:+Chepuri_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Sundeep Prabhakar Chepuri&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.02005">
<title>Robust Dependence Measure using RKHS based Uncertainty Moments and Optimal Transport. (arXiv:2211.02005v1 [eess.SP])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.02005</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Reliable measurement of dependence between variables is essential in many
applications of statistics and machine learning. Current approaches for
dependence estimation, especially density-based approaches, lack in precision,
robustness and/or interpretability (in terms of the type of dependence being
estimated). We propose a two-step approach for dependence quantification
between random variables: 1) We first decompose the probability density
functions (PDF) of the variables involved in terms of multiple local moments of
uncertainty that systematically and precisely identify the different regions of
the PDF (with special emphasis on the tail-regions). 2) We then compute an
optimal transport map to measure the geometric similarity between the
corresponding sets of decomposed local uncertainty moments of the variables.
Dependence is then determined by the degree of one-to-one correspondence
between the respective uncertainty moments of the variables in the optimal
transport map. We utilize a recently introduced Gaussian reproducing kernel
Hilbert space (RKHS) based framework for multi-moment uncertainty decomposition
of the variables. Being based on the Gaussian RKHS, our approach is robust
towards outliers and monotone transformations of data, while the multiple
moments of uncertainty provide high resolution and interpretability of the type
of dependence being quantified. We support these claims through some
preliminary results using simulated data.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/eess/1/au:+Singh_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Rishabh Singh&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/eess/1/au:+Principe_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jose C. Principe&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.02012">
<title>Optimal Compression for Minimizing Classification Error Probability: an Information-Theoretic Approach. (arXiv:2211.02012v1 [eess.SP])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.02012</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We formulate the problem of performing optimal data compression under the
constraints that compressed data can be used for accurate classification in
machine learning. We show that this translates to a problem of minimizing the
mutual information between data and its compressed version under the constraint
on error probability of classification is small when using the compressed data
for machine learning. We then provide analytical and computational methods to
characterize the optimal trade-off between data compression and classification
error probability. First, we provide an analytical characterization for the
optimal compression strategy for data with binary labels. Second, for data with
multiple labels, we formulate a set of convex optimization problems to
characterize the optimal tradeoff, from which the optimal trade-off between the
classification error and compression efficiency can be obtained by numerically
solving the formulated optimization problems. We further show the improvements
of our formulations over the information-bottleneck methods in classification
performance.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/eess/1/au:+Gao_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jingchao Gao&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/eess/1/au:+Tang_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ao Tang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/eess/1/au:+Xu_W/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Weiyu Xu&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.02017">
<title>A cryogenic SRAM based arbitrary waveform generator in 14 nm for spin qubit control. (arXiv:2211.02017v1 [quant-ph])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.02017</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Realization of qubit gate sequences require coherent microwave control pulses
with programmable amplitude, duration, spacing and phase. We propose an SRAM
based arbitrary waveform generator for cryogenic control of spin qubits. We
demonstrate in this work, the cryogenic operation of a fully programmable radio
frequency arbitrary waveform generator in 14 nm FinFET technology. The waveform
sequence from a control processor can be stored in an SRAM memory array, which
can be programmed in real time. The waveform pattern is converted to microwave
pulses by a source-series-terminated digital to analog converter. The chip is
operational at 4 K, capable of generating an arbitrary envelope shape at the
desired carrier frequency. Total power consumption of the AWG is 40-140mW at 4
K, depending upon the baud rate. A wide signal band of 1-17 GHz is measured at
4 K, while multiple qubit control can be achieved using frequency division
multiplexing at an average spurious free dynamic range of 40 dB. This work
paves the way to optimal qubit control and closed loop feedback control, which
is necessary to achieve low latency error mitigation
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Prathapan_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Mridula Prathapan&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Mueller_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Peter Mueller&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Menolfi_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Christian Menolfi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Braendli_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Matthias Braendli&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Kossel_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Marcel Kossel&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Francese_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Pier Andrea Francese&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Heim_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;David Heim&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Oropallo_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Maria Vittoria Oropallo&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Ruffino_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Andrea Ruffino&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Zota_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Cezar Zota&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Morf_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Thomas Morf&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2010.11114">
<title>Model Selection for Signal Processing: a Minimum Error Approach and a General Performance Analysis. (arXiv:2010.11114v6 [eess.SP] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2010.11114</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Estimation of the number of signals in the presence of noise is an important
problem in several areas of statistical signal processing. There are a number
of modern works on the design of an optimal solution to this problem in terms
of some criteria. Each criterion generates a model order selection (MOS)
algorithm. However, the minimum error probability criterion has not received
significant attention, although errors in the estimation of the number of
signals might directly affect the performance of the signal processing system
as a whole. In this paper, we propose a new approach to the design of MOS
algorithms partially based on the minimum error probability criterion. Also, we
pay a lot of attention to the performance and consistency analysis of the MOS
algorithms. In this study, an abridged error probability is used as a universal
performance measure of the MOS algorithms. We propose a theoretical framework
that makes it possible to provide a parametric consistency analysis and to
obtain closed-form expressions for the abridged error probabilities of a wide
range of MOS algorithms. As an example, we applied this framework to the
consistency and performance analysis of several MOS algorithms. Using the
obtained results, we provide a parametric optimization of the presented MOS
algorithms. Finally, we examinate a quasilikelihood (QL) approach to the design
and analysis of the MOS algorithms. The proposed theoretical framework is used
to obtain the abridged error probabilities as functions of the unknown signal
parameter. These functions, in turn, allow us to find the scope of the QL
approach.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/eess/1/au:+Kharin_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Aleksandr Kharin&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2111.02229">
<title>Cram\&apos;er-Rao Bounds for Holographic Positioning. (arXiv:2111.02229v2 [eess.SP] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2111.02229</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Multiple antennas arrays play a key role in wireless networks for
communications but also for localization and sensing applications. The use of
large antenna arrays at high carrier frequencies (in the mmWave range) pushes
towards a propagation regime in which the wavefront is no longer plane but
spherical. This allows to infer the position and orientation of a transmitting
source from the received signal without the need of using multiple anchor
nodes, located in known positions. To understand the fundamental limits of
large antenna arrays for localization, this paper combines wave propagation
theory with estimation theory, and computes the Cram\&apos;er-Rao Bound (CRB) for
the estimation of the source position on the basis of the three Cartesian
components of the electric field, observed over a rectangular surface area. The
problem is referred to as holographic positioning and is formulated by taking
into account the radiation angular pattern of the transmitting source, which is
typically ignored in standard signal processing models. We assume that the
source is a Hertzian dipole, and address the holographic positioning problem in
both cases, that is, with and without a priori knowledge of its orientation. To
simplify the analysis and gain further insights, we also consider the case in
which the dipole is located on the line perpendicular to the surface center.
Numerical and asymptotic results are given to quantify the CRBs, and to
quantify the effect of various system parameters on the ultimate estimation
accuracy. It turns out that surfaces of practical size may guarantee a
centimeter-level accuracy in the mmWave bands.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/eess/1/au:+DAmico_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Antonio A. D&amp;#x27;Amico&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/eess/1/au:+Torres_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Andrea de Jesus Torres&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/eess/1/au:+Sanguinetti_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Luca Sanguinetti&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/eess/1/au:+Win_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Moe Win&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2202.13526">
<title>Sparse Graph Learning with Spectrum Prior for Deep Graph Convolutional Networks. (arXiv:2202.13526v2 [cs.LG] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2202.13526</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;A graph convolutional network (GCN) employs a graph filtering kernel tailored
for data with irregular structures. However, simply stacking more GCN layers
does not improve performance; instead, the output converges to an uninformative
low-dimensional subspace, where the convergence rate is characterized by the
graph spectrum -- this is the known over-smoothing problem in GCN. In this
paper, we propose a sparse graph learning algorithm incorporating a new
spectrum prior to compute a graph topology that circumvents over-smoothing
while preserving pairwise correlations inherent in data. Specifically, based on
a spectral analysis of multilayer GCN output, we derive a spectrum prior for
the graph Laplacian matrix $\mathbf{L}$ to robustify the model expressiveness
against over-smoothing. Then, we formulate a sparse graph learning problem with
the spectrum prior, solved efficiently via block coordinate descent (BCD).
Moreover, we optimize the weight parameter trading off the fidelity term with
the spectrum prior, based on data smoothness on the original graph learned
without spectrum manipulation. The output $\mathbf{L}$ is then normalized for
supervised GCN training. Experiments show that our proposal produced deeper
GCNs and higher prediction accuracy for regression and classification tasks
compared to competing schemes.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zeng_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jin Zeng&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Liu_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yang Liu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Cheung_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Gene Cheung&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Hu_W/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Wei Hu&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2205.03770">
<title>Transformer-Empowered 6G Intelligent Networks: From Massive MIMO Processing to Semantic Communication. (arXiv:2205.03770v4 [cs.IT] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2205.03770</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;It is anticipated that 6G wireless networks will accelerate the convergence
of the physical and cyber worlds and enable a paradigm-shift in the way we
deploy and exploit communication networks. Machine learning, in particular deep
learning (DL), is expected to be one of the key technological enablers of 6G by
offering a new paradigm for the design and optimization of networks with a high
level of intelligence. In this article, we introduce an emerging DL
architecture, known as the transformer, and discuss its potential impact on 6G
network design. We first discuss the differences between the transformer and
classical DL architectures, and emphasize the transformer&apos;s self-attention
mechanism and strong representation capabilities, which make it particularly
appealing for tackling various challenges in wireless network design.
Specifically, we propose transformer-based solutions for various massive
multiple-input multiple-output (MIMO) and semantic communication problems, and
show their superiority compared to other architectures. Finally, we discuss key
challenges and open issues in transformer-based solutions, and identify future
research directions for their deployment in intelligent 6G networks.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Wang_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yang Wang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Gao_Z/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Zhen Gao&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zheng_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Dezhi Zheng&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Chen_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Sheng Chen&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Gunduz_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Deniz G&amp;#xfc;nd&amp;#xfc;z&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Poor_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;H. Vincent Poor&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2207.09340">
<title>A coherence parameter characterizing generative compressed sensing with Fourier measurements. (arXiv:2207.09340v4 [cs.IT] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2207.09340</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;In Bora et al. (2017), a mathematical framework was developed for compressed
sensing guarantees in the setting where the measurement matrix is Gaussian and
the signal structure is the range of a generative neural network (GNN). The
problem of compressed sensing with GNNs has since been extensively analyzed
when the measurement matrix and/or network weights follow a subgaussian
distribution. We move beyond the subgaussian assumption, to measurement
matrices that are derived by sampling uniformly at random rows of a unitary
matrix (including subsampled Fourier measurements as a special case).
Specifically, we prove the first known restricted isometry guarantee for
generative compressed sensing with subsampled isometries, and provide recovery
bounds with nearly order-optimal sample complexity, addressing an open problem
of Scarlett et al. (2022, p. 10). Recovery efficacy is characterized by the
coherence, a new parameter, which measures the interplay between the range of
the network and the measurement matrix. Our approach relies on subspace
counting arguments and ideas central to high-dimensional probability.
Furthermore, we propose a regularization strategy for training GNNs to have
favourable coherence with the measurement operator. We provide compelling
numerical simulations that support this regularized training strategy: our
strategy yields low coherence networks that require fewer measurements for
signal recovery. This, together with our theoretical results, supports
coherence as a natural quantity for characterizing generative compressed
sensing with subsampled isometries.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Berk_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Aaron Berk&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Brugiapaglia_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Simone Brugiapaglia&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Joshi_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Babhru Joshi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Plan_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yaniv Plan&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Scott_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Matthew Scott&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Yilmaz_O/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;&amp;#xd6;zg&amp;#xfc;r Yilmaz&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.17177">
<title>Variational Inference Aided Estimation of Time Varying Channels. (arXiv:2210.17177v2 [eess.SP] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.17177</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;One way to improve the estimation of time varying channels is to incorporate
knowledge of previous observations. In this context, Dynamical VAEs (DVAEs)
build a promising deep learning (DL) framework which is well suited to learn
the distribution of time series data. We introduce a new DVAE architecture,
called k-MemoryMarkovVAE (k-MMVAE), whose sparsity can be controlled by an
additional memory parameter. Following the approach in [1] we derive a k-MMVAE
aided channel estimator which takes temporal correlations of successive
observations into account. The results are evaluated on simulated channels by
QuaDRiGa and show that the k-MMVAE aided channel estimator clearly outperforms
other machine learning (ML) aided estimators which are either memoryless or
naively extended to time varying channels without major adaptions.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/eess/1/au:+Bock_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Benedikt B&amp;#xf6;ck&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/eess/1/au:+Baur_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Michael Baur&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/eess/1/au:+Rizzello_V/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Valentina Rizzello&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/eess/1/au:+Utschick_W/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Wolfgang Utschick&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.00230">
<title>Survey on Source-coding technique. (arXiv:2211.00230v2 [cs.IT] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.00230</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Shannon separation theorem lays the foundation for traditional image
compression and transmission schemes, which consist of JPEG type image
compression methods and the usual channel coding schemes such as Turbo and LDPC
codes. One of the advantages of the separate design is that each of the two
components, channel coding and source coding can be handled independently
without considering the other, which is the base of decades-long technologies.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Wang_W/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Weida Wang&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
</rdf:RDF>