<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
<title>Review</title>
<description>Review</description>
<link>https://research.stlouisfed.org/publications/review/</link>
<atom:link href="https://research.stlouisfed.org/publications/review/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2022 11:47:40 -0500</pubDate>
<item>
<title>Full Issue</title>
<link>https://research.stlouisfed.org/publications/review/2022/10/21/full-issue</link>
<pubDate>2022-10-21</pubDate>
<guid>https://research.stlouisfed.org/publications/review/2022/10/21/full-issue</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Disparities in COVID-19’s Impact on Employment and Household Consumption</title>
<link>https://research.stlouisfed.org/publications/review/2022/09/29/disparities-in-covid-19s-impact-on-employment-and-household-consumption</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[This article investigates the socio-demographic differences in household responses to the COVID-19 pandemic regarding employment and consumption. We find that the significant racial disparities in employment observed during the pandemic can be explained, in part, by differences in household income, composition, education, and occupational sorting.]]>
</description>
<pubDate>2022-10-21</pubDate>
<guid>https://research.stlouisfed.org/publications/review/2022/09/29/disparities-in-covid-19s-impact-on-employment-and-household-consumption</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Financial Market Reactions to the Russian Invasion of Ukraine</title>
<link>https://research.stlouisfed.org/publications/review/2022/10/21/financial-market-reactions-to-the-russian-invasion-of-ukraine</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[This article analyzes financial market reactions to the Russia-Ukraine war with a focus on the opening weeks. Markets did not completely anticipate the war, and asset price reactions strengthened from the first week&mdash;when there were hopes for a quick resolution&mdash;to the second week, when prices generally peaked and began to partially revert to prewar values.]]>
</description>
<pubDate>2022-10-21</pubDate>
<guid>https://research.stlouisfed.org/publications/review/2022/10/21/financial-market-reactions-to-the-russian-invasion-of-ukraine</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Credit Expansion and Markups</title>
<link>https://research.stlouisfed.org/publications/review/2022/08/10/credit-expansion-and-markups</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[This article documents new empirical facts about the effects of credit expansion on the aggregate markup and markup dispersion in the United States. We use U.S. macroeconomic data and Jordà’s local projection and single-equation estimation methods.&nbsp;]]>
</description>
<pubDate>2022-10-21</pubDate>
<guid>https://research.stlouisfed.org/publications/review/2022/08/10/credit-expansion-and-markups</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>1960s Interstate Highways and Homeowner Wealth Distribution</title>
<link>https://research.stlouisfed.org/publications/review/2022/09/14/1960s-interstate-highways-and-homeowner-wealth-distribution</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[This article studies house-level real estate wealth distribution changes nearby a major interstate highway, comparing values before the announcement of the highway’s construction (1940) with those during and shortly after the construction period (1961-74). We also develop Lorenz curves to examine the distribution of housing wealth among various demographic groups of homeowners.&nbsp;]]>
</description>
<pubDate>2022-10-21</pubDate>
<guid>https://research.stlouisfed.org/publications/review/2022/09/14/1960s-interstate-highways-and-homeowner-wealth-distribution</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Full Issue</title>
<link>https://research.stlouisfed.org/publications/review/2022/07/14/full-issue</link>
<pubDate>2022-07-14</pubDate>
<guid>https://research.stlouisfed.org/publications/review/2022/07/14/full-issue</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Full Issue</title>
<link>https://research.stlouisfed.org/publications/review/2022/07/14/full-issue</link>
<pubDate>2022-07-14</pubDate>
<guid>https://research.stlouisfed.org/publications/review/2022/07/14/full-issue</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Blockchain Revolution: Decoding Digital Currencies</title>
<link>https://research.stlouisfed.org/publications/review/2022/07/14/the-blockchain-revolution-decoding-digital-currencies</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[Cryptocurrencies and decentralized finance have grown considerably since the publication of the white paper on bitcoin in 2009. This article presents an overview of cryptocurrencies, blockchain technology, and their applications, explaining the spirit of the enterprise and how it compares with traditional operations.]]>
</description>
<pubDate>2022-07-14</pubDate>
<guid>https://research.stlouisfed.org/publications/review/2022/07/14/the-blockchain-revolution-decoding-digital-currencies</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Increasing Employment by Halting Pandemic Unemployment Benefits</title>
<link>https://research.stlouisfed.org/publications/review/2022/06/23/increasing-employment-by-halting-pandemic-unemployment-benefits</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[In mid-2021, 26 states halted participation in all or some federal emergency unemployment benefits (EUB) programs before those programs' federal funding lapsed. This article uses this asynchronous EUB cessation between early- and late-halting states to estimate the causal impact of benefit cessation on employment.&nbsp;]]>
</description>
<pubDate>2022-07-14</pubDate>
<guid>https://research.stlouisfed.org/publications/review/2022/06/23/increasing-employment-by-halting-pandemic-unemployment-benefits</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Murky Future of Monetary Policy</title>
<link>https://research.stlouisfed.org/publications/review/2022/05/24/the-murky-future-of-monetary-policy</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[In August 2020, the Federal Reserve unveiled its new strategic framework. One major objective of the Fed was to address its concerns over the potential consequences for the conduct of monetary policy when the policy rate was constrained by its effective lower bound.&nbsp;]]>
</description>
<pubDate>2022-07-14</pubDate>
<guid>https://research.stlouisfed.org/publications/review/2022/05/24/the-murky-future-of-monetary-policy</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Turbulent Years for U.S. Banks: 2000-20</title>
<link>https://research.stlouisfed.org/publications/review/2022/05/13/turbulent-years-for-u-s-banks-2000-20</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[The first 20 years of the twenty-first century have presented U.S. banks with three recessions, long periods of very low interest rates, and increased regulation. The number of commercial banks operating in the United States declined by 51 percent during this period.&nbsp;]]>
</description>
<pubDate>2022-07-14</pubDate>
<guid>https://research.stlouisfed.org/publications/review/2022/05/13/turbulent-years-for-u-s-banks-2000-20</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Subjective Assessment of Managerial Performance and Decisionmaking in Banking</title>
<link>https://research.stlouisfed.org/publications/review/2022/05/10/subjective-assessment-of-managerial-performance-and-decisionmaking-in-banking</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[We examine subjective supervisory assessments of managerial performance in the banking industry. Results of empirical tests show that better assessments are (i) positively associated with decisions made by examiners to upgrade relatively objective bank performance ratings; (ii) negatively associated with decisions made by examiners to downgrade relatively objective bank performance ratings; and (iii) positively associated with decisions made by bank holding company managers to distribute resources among subsidiary banks.&nbsp;]]>
</description>
<pubDate>2022-07-14</pubDate>
<guid>https://research.stlouisfed.org/publications/review/2022/05/10/subjective-assessment-of-managerial-performance-and-decisionmaking-in-banking</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Full Issue</title>
<link>https://research.stlouisfed.org/publications/review/2022/04/21/full-issue</link>
<pubDate>2022-04-21</pubDate>
<guid>https://research.stlouisfed.org/publications/review/2022/04/21/full-issue</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Full Issue</title>
<link>https://research.stlouisfed.org/publications/review/2022/04/21/full-issue</link>
<pubDate>2022-04-21</pubDate>
<guid>https://research.stlouisfed.org/publications/review/2022/04/21/full-issue</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Global Supply Chain Disruptions and Inflation During the COVID-19 Pandemic</title>
<link>https://research.stlouisfed.org/publications/review/2022/02/07/global-supply-chain-disruptions-and-inflation-during-the-covid-19-pandemic</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[We investigate the role supply chain disruptions during the COVID-19 pandemic played in U.S. producer price index (PPI) inflation. We exploit pre-pandemic cross-industry variation in sourcing patterns across countries and interact it with measures of international supply chain bottlenecks during the pandemic.]]>
</description>
<pubDate>2022-04-21</pubDate>
<guid>https://research.stlouisfed.org/publications/review/2022/02/07/global-supply-chain-disruptions-and-inflation-during-the-covid-19-pandemic</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Who Should Work from Home During a Pandemic? The Wage-Infection Trade-off</title>
<link>https://research.stlouisfed.org/publications/review/2022/01/24/who-should-work-from-home-during-a-pandemic-the-wage-infection-trade-off</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[Shutting down the workplace is an effective means of reducing contagion but can induce large economic losses. We harmonize the American Time Use Survey and O*NET data to construct a measure of infection risk (exposure index) and a measure of the ease with which a job can be performed remotely (work-from-home index) across both industries and occupations.]]>
</description>
<pubDate>2022-04-21</pubDate>
<guid>https://research.stlouisfed.org/publications/review/2022/01/24/who-should-work-from-home-during-a-pandemic-the-wage-infection-trade-off</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Failing to Provide Public Goods: Why the Afghan Army Did Not Fight</title>
<link>https://research.stlouisfed.org/publications/review/2022/03/14/failing-to-provide-public-goods-why-the-afghan-army-did-not-fight</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[The theory of public goods is mainly about the difficulty in paying for them. Our question here is this: Why might public goods not be provided, even if funding is available?]]>
</description>
<pubDate>2022-04-21</pubDate>
<guid>https://research.stlouisfed.org/publications/review/2022/03/14/failing-to-provide-public-goods-why-the-afghan-army-did-not-fight</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Venture Capital: A Catalyst for Innovation and Growth</title>
<link>https://research.stlouisfed.org/publications/review/2022/04/06/venture-capital-a-catalyst-for-innovation-and-growth</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[This article studies the development of the venture capital (VC) industry in the United States and assesses how VC financing affects firm innovation and growth. The results highlight the essential role of VC financing for U.S. innovation and growth and suggest that VC development in other countries could promote their economic growth.]]>
</description>
<pubDate>2022-04-21</pubDate>
<guid>https://research.stlouisfed.org/publications/review/2022/04/06/venture-capital-a-catalyst-for-innovation-and-growth</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>On the Relative Performance of Inflation Forecasts</title>
<link>https://research.stlouisfed.org/publications/review/2022/04/05/on-the-relative-performance-of-inflation-forecasts</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[Inflation expectations constitute important components of macroeconomic models and monetary policy rules. We investigate the relative performance of consumer, professional, market-based, and model-based inflation forecasts.]]>
</description>
<pubDate>2022-04-21</pubDate>
<guid>https://research.stlouisfed.org/publications/review/2022/04/05/on-the-relative-performance-of-inflation-forecasts</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Full Issue</title>
<link>https://research.stlouisfed.org/publications/review/2022/01/14/full-issue</link>
<pubDate>2022-01-14</pubDate>
<guid>https://research.stlouisfed.org/publications/review/2022/01/14/full-issue</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Economic Activity during the COVID-19 Pandemic: A Model with “Acquired Immunity”</title>
<link>https://research.stlouisfed.org/publications/review/2021/11/05/economic-activity-during-the-covid-19-pandemic-a-model-with-acquired-immunity</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[We calibrate a macroeconomic model with epidemiological restrictions using Colombian data. The key feature of our model is that a portion of the population is immune and cannot transmit the virus, which improves substantially the fit of the model to the observed contagion and economic activity data.]]>
</description>
<pubDate>2022-01-14</pubDate>
<guid>https://research.stlouisfed.org/publications/review/2021/11/05/economic-activity-during-the-covid-19-pandemic-a-model-with-acquired-immunity</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Sectoral Impacts of Trade Wars</title>
<link>https://research.stlouisfed.org/publications/review/2021/12/17/sectoral-impacts-of-trade-wars</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[In recent years, we have witnessed rising trade protectionism with broad ranges of tariffs imposed on intermediate products. In this article, we develop an accounting framework to evaluate the sectoral impacts of the current U.S.-China trade war.]]>
</description>
<pubDate>2022-01-14</pubDate>
<guid>https://research.stlouisfed.org/publications/review/2021/12/17/sectoral-impacts-of-trade-wars</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Impact of Juvenile Conviction on Human Capital and Labor Market Outcomes</title>
<link>https://research.stlouisfed.org/publications/review/2022/01/14/the-impact-of-juvenile-conviction-on-human-capital-and-labor-market-outcomes</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[This article documents the long-term relationship among juvenile conviction, occupational choices, employment, wages, and recidivism. Using data from the National Longitudinal Survey of Youth 1997 (NLSY97), we document that youth convicted at or before age 17 have a lower full-time employment rate and lower wage growth rate even after 10 years in the labor market.]]>
</description>
<pubDate>2022-01-14</pubDate>
<guid>https://research.stlouisfed.org/publications/review/2022/01/14/the-impact-of-juvenile-conviction-on-human-capital-and-labor-market-outcomes</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Further Evidence on Greenspan’s Conundrum</title>
<link>https://research.stlouisfed.org/publications/review/2021/11/16/further-evidence-on-greenspans-conundrum</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[During his February 2005 congressional testimony, Alan Greenspan identified what he termed a conundrum. Despite the fact that the Federal Open Market Committee (FOMC) had increased the federal funds rate 150 basis points since June 2004, the 10-year Treasury yield remained essentially unchanged.]]>
</description>
<pubDate>2022-01-14</pubDate>
<guid>https://research.stlouisfed.org/publications/review/2021/11/16/further-evidence-on-greenspans-conundrum</guid>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>