<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<rdf:RDF
 xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
 xmlns="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/"
 xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
 xmlns:taxo="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/taxonomy/"
 xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
 xmlns:syn="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
 xmlns:admin="http://webns.net/mvcb/"
>

<channel rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/">
<title>nlin.CD updates on arXiv.org</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">Nonlinear Sciences -- Chaotic Dynamics (nlin.CD) updates on the arXiv.org e-print archive</description>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:date>2022-11-03T20:30:00-05:00</dc:date>
<dc:publisher>help@arxiv.org</dc:publisher>
<dc:subject>Nonlinear Sciences -- Chaotic Dynamics</dc:subject>
<syn:updateBase>1901-01-01T00:00+00:00</syn:updateBase>
<syn:updateFrequency>1</syn:updateFrequency>
<syn:updatePeriod>daily</syn:updatePeriod>
<items>
 <rdf:Seq>
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01394" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01721" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01887" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2205.05704" />
 </rdf:Seq>
</items>
<image rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif" />
</channel>
<image rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif">
<title>arXiv.org</title>
<url>http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif</url>
<link>http://arxiv.org/</link>
</image>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01394">
<title>Self-Similar Gravitational Dynamics, Singularities and Criticality in 2D. (arXiv:2211.01394v1 [hep-th])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01394</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We initiate a systematic study of continuously self-similar (CSS)
gravitational dynamics in two dimensions, motivated by critical phenomena
observed in higher dimensional gravitational theories. We consider CSS
spacetimes admitting a homothetic Killing vector (HKV) field. For a general
two-dimensional gravitational theory coupled to a dilaton field and Maxwell
field, we find that the assumption of continuous self-similarity determines the
form of the dilaton coupling to the curvature. Certain limits produce two
important classes of models, one of which is closely related to two-dimensional
target space string theory and the other being Liouville gravity. The gauge
field is shown to produce a shift in the dilaton potential strength. We
consider static black hole solutions and find spacetimes with uncommon
asymptotic behaviour. We show the vacuum self-similar spacetimes to be special
limits of the static solutions. We add matter fields consistent with
self-similarity (including a certain model of semi-classical gravity) and write
down the autonomous ordinary differential equations governing the gravitational
dynamics. Based on the phenomenon of finite-time blow-up in ODEs, we argue that
spacetime singularities are generic in our models. We present qualitatively
diverse results from analytical and numerical investigations regarding matter
field collapse and singularities. We find interesting hints of a Choptuik-like
scaling law.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Moitra_U/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Upamanyu Moitra&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01721">
<title>Chaos in multiplanetary extrasolar systems. (arXiv:2211.01721v1 [astro-ph.EP])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01721</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Here we present an initial look at the dynamics and stability of 178
multiplanetary systems which are already confirmed and listed in the NASA
Exoplanet Archive. To distinguish between the chaotic and regular nature of a
system, the value of the MEGNO indicator for each system was determined. Almost
three-quarters of them could be labelled as long-term stable. Only 45 studied
systems show chaotic behaviour. We consequently investigated the effects of the
number of planets and their parameters on the system stability. A comparison of
results obtained using the MEGNO indicator and machine-learning algorithm SPOCK
suggests that the SPOCK could be used as an effective tool for reviewing the
stability of multiplanetary systems. A similar study was already published by
Laskar and Petit in 2017. We compared their analysis based on the AMD criterion
with our results. The possible discrepancies are discussed.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Gajdos_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Pavol Gajdo&amp;#x161;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Vanko_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Martin Va&amp;#x148;ko&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01887">
<title>Thermalization of Classical Weakly Nonintegrable Many-Body Systems. (arXiv:2211.01887v1 [nlin.CD])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01887</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We devote our studies to the subject of weakly nonintegrable dynamics of
systems with a macroscopic number of degrees of freedom. Our main points of
interest are the relations between the timescales of thermalization and the
timescales of chaotization; the choice of appropriate observables and the
structure of equations coupling them; identifying the classes of weakly
nonintegrable dynamics and developing tools to diagnose the properties specific
to such classes. We discuss the traditional in the field methods for
thermalization timescale computation and employ them to study the scaling the
timescale with the proximity to the integrable limit. We then elaborate on a
novel framework based on the full Lyapunov spectra computation for large
systems as a powerful tool for the characterization of weak nonintegrability.
In particular, the Lyapunov spectrum scaling offers a quantitative description
allowing us to infer the structure of the underlying network of observables.
Proximity to integrable limit is associated with the rapid growth of
thermalization timescales and, thus, potential numerical challenges. We solve
these challenges by performing numerical tests using computationally efficient
model - unitary maps. The great advantage of unitary maps for numerical
applications is time-discrete error-free evolution. We use these advantages to
perform large timescale and system size computations in extreme proximity to
the integrable limit. To demonstrate the scope of obtained results we report on
the application of the developed framework to Hamiltonian systems.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/nlin/1/au:+Malishava_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Merab Malishava&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2205.05704">
<title>Dynamical quantum ergodicity from energy level statistics. (arXiv:2205.05704v2 [quant-ph] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2205.05704</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Ergodic theory provides a rigorous mathematical description of classical
dynamical systems including a formal definition of the ergodic hierarchy.
Closely related to this hierarchy is a less-known notion of cyclic approximate
periodic transformations [see, e.g., I. Cornfield, S. Fomin, and Y. Sinai,
Ergodic theory (Springer-Verlag New York, 1982)], which maps any &quot;ergodic&quot;
dynamical system to a cyclic permutation on a circle and arguably represents
the most elementary notion of ergodicity. This paper shows that cyclic
ergodicity generalizes to quantum dynamical systems, and this generalization is
proposed here as the basic rigorous definition of quantum ergodicity. It
implies the ability to construct an orthonormal basis, where quantum dynamics
transports an initial basis vector to all other basis vectors one by one, while
maintaining a sufficiently large overlap between the time-evolved initial state
and a given basis state. It is proven that the basis, maximizing the overlap
over all cyclic permutations, is obtained via the discrete Fourier transform of
the energy eigenstates. This relates quantum cyclic ergodicity to level
statistics. We then show that the near-universal Wigner-Dyson level statistics
implies quantum cyclic ergodicity, but the reverse is not necessarily true. For
the latter, we study irrational flows on a 2D torus and prove that both the
classical and quantum flows are cyclic ergodic. However, the corresponding
level statistics is neither Wigner-Dyson nor Poisson. Finally, we use the
cyclic construction to motivate a quantum ergodic hierarchy of operators and
argue that under the additional assumption of Poincare recurrences, cyclic
ergodicity is a necessary condition for such operators to satisfy the
eigenstate thermalization hypothesis. This work provides a general framework
for transplanting some rigorous concepts of ergodic theory to quantum dynamical
systems.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Vikram_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Amit Vikram&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Galitski_V/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Victor Galitski&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
</rdf:RDF>