<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns:yt="http://www.youtube.com/xml/schemas/2015" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
 <link rel="self" href="http://www.youtube.com/feeds/videos.xml?channel_id=UCddem5RlB3bQe99wyY49g0g"/>
 <id>yt:channel:UCddem5RlB3bQe99wyY49g0g</id>
 <yt:channelId>UCddem5RlB3bQe99wyY49g0g</yt:channelId>
 <title>PeriscopeFilm</title>
 <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCddem5RlB3bQe99wyY49g0g"/>
 <author>
  <name>PeriscopeFilm</name>
  <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCddem5RlB3bQe99wyY49g0g</uri>
 </author>
 <published>2009-11-03T03:49:10+00:00</published>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:ZuY2_RBl0fw</id>
  <yt:videoId>ZuY2_RBl0fw</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCddem5RlB3bQe99wyY49g0g</yt:channelId>
  <title>1950S ”PAY DIRT”  J.I. CASE CO. TRACTOR &amp; AGRICULTURAL MACHINERY PROMO FILM  XD60594</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ZuY2_RBl0fw"/>
  <author>
   <name>PeriscopeFilm</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCddem5RlB3bQe99wyY49g0g</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-11-05T16:29:48+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-11-05T16:29:48+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>1950S ”PAY DIRT”  J.I. CASE CO. TRACTOR &amp; AGRICULTURAL MACHINERY PROMO FILM  XD60594</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/ZuY2_RBl0fw?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i3.ytimg.com/vi/ZuY2_RBl0fw/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>Join this channel to get access to perks:
https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCddem5RlB3bQe99wyY49g0g/join

Want to learn more about Periscope Film and get access to exclusive swag? Join us on Patreon. Visit https://www.patreon.com/PeriscopeFilm
Visit our website www.PeriscopeFilm.com

This longform advertising film (which includes an intermission) from the 1950s is an educational film presented by the J. I. Case Co. about agriculture and machinery. The Case Company was founded in 1842 and manufactured agricultural and construction equipment. It eventually merged with International Harvester and is now part of the entity known as CNH Global. The film is parted into two sections, first covering the seeding and cultivation of crops, followed by the harvesting all whilst using the farming equipment and machinery from J. I. Case Co. The tractor shown appears to be a Case 430 or 530, but it's not identified by model #. 

An animation of space to introduce the film (00:24). J. I. Case Co. presents “Pay Dirt” part one (00:38). A farmer walks with two donkeys (01:02). A man sieving water and dirt for gold, silver, and other precious metals (01:21). He holds a small piece of gold between his fingers (01:30). He digs through soil using his hands (01:41). Grass fields and farm crops (01:58). Informational text about farming (02:14). Fertilizer is spread across fields using a tractor with a dispersion attachment (02:39). A farmer drives a moldboard plow (05:11). Informational text about tractor machines (09:16). Soil is harrowed using a wide disc harrow (09:32). Informational text about farming in difficult weather conditions (10:13). A farmer looks up at the cloudy sky (10:38). A Case 430 tractor drives across the fields to disperse seeds and fertilizer (10:50). An illustration of the infrastructure inside the seed and fertilizer dispenser (11:14). A farmer is seeding his fields (11:34). A sectional duplicate of the seeding-function (11:48). A 60-foot-wide seed spreader (12:54). A row crop planter for narrow seeding (13:14). Seeds are manually filled into hills (13:39) Sectional duplicate of a platter for precise seed spreading (13:54). Fertilizer is added to a different hill (15:10). An illustration of the mechanic functionality of the platter (15:25). Informational text about seed and fertilizer dispensing (15:42). A rotary hoe used for cultivating growing crops (15:55). Rich and healthy crops on a field (19:13). J. I. Case Co. presents “Pay Harvest” part two (19:32). Large fields of corn crops (21:18), and informational text about corn fields (21:37). A side-mounted tractor mower is cutting crops (21:47). A tractor with chopping-attachment shreds the cut crops evenly, and a baler tractor makes different sized bales after the harvest (24:02). The harvest of beans, nuts, rice, and other grains is powered by a tractor with a harvest-attachment (27:50). Bean crops are filled into sacks (32:30). Informational text about corn harvest (32:52): A machine is chopping corn crops into shreds (33:16). A corn-picker is mounted on a tractor (35:49), and they separate the whole corns from the crops during harvest (36:36). A farmer wins a corn-picking contest using J. I. Case Co. corn-picking equipment (38:10). 

We encourage viewers to add comments and, especially, to provide additional information about our videos by adding a comment!  See something interesting?  Tell people what it is and what they can see by writing something for example: &quot;01:00:12:00 -- President Roosevelt is seen meeting with Winston Churchill at the Quebec Conference.&quot;

This film is part of the Periscope Film LLC archive, one of the largest historic military, transportation, and aviation stock footage collections in the USA. Entirely film backed, this material is available for licensing in 24p HD, 2k and 4k. For more information visit http://www.PeriscopeFilm.com</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="22" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="240"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:ECeLlEjQmJI</id>
  <yt:videoId>ECeLlEjQmJI</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCddem5RlB3bQe99wyY49g0g</yt:channelId>
  <title>CASS SCENIC RAILROAD  WEST VIRGINIA    SHAY STEAM LOCOMOTIVE #6 &amp; MEADOW RIVER DIESEL #9   XD39054</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ECeLlEjQmJI"/>
  <author>
   <name>PeriscopeFilm</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCddem5RlB3bQe99wyY49g0g</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-11-04T16:29:46+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-11-04T16:29:46+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>CASS SCENIC RAILROAD  WEST VIRGINIA    SHAY STEAM LOCOMOTIVE #6 &amp; MEADOW RIVER DIESEL #9   XD39054</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/ECeLlEjQmJI?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i2.ytimg.com/vi/ECeLlEjQmJI/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>Want to support this channel and help us preserve old films? Visit https://www.patreon.com/PeriscopeFilm
Visit our website www.PeriscopeFilm.com

This film contains footage of the Cass Scenic Railroad State Park, an 11-mile heritage railroad located in Cass, Pocahontas County, West Virginia. The park also includes the town of Cass and part of the summit of Back Allegheny Mountain's Bald Knob. The film begins with shots of Meadow River Lumber Company diesel locomotive #9 moving a caboose. This locomotive was a General Electric 70 Ton Switcher, Production Roster - SN 32816. The film then shows extensive footage of Cass steam locomotive #6. The film was shot in the winter, with Cass' locomotive #6 operating in a light snowfall. Built in 1945, this engine is the last Shay locomotive built and the largest Shay locomotive in existence. It was formerly from the Western Maryland Railway. The engine is shown moving its tender and a caboose.  

West Virginia Pulp &amp; Paper Company (WVP&amp;P) built the sawmill, railroad and town at Cass. Its huge logging operation used Shay locomotives almost exclusively. Today the Cass Railroad owns eight Shay locomotives, one Heisler locomotive, and one Climax locomotive.

The Meadow River Lumber Company operated in Rainelle, West Virginia from 1906 to 1975, and was the largest hardwood sawmill in the world.


We encourage viewers to add comments and, especially, to provide additional information about our videos by adding a comment!  See something interesting?  Tell people what it is and what they can see by writing something for example: &quot;01:00:12:00 -- President Roosevelt is seen meeting with Winston Churchill at the Quebec Conference.&quot;

This film is part of the Periscope Film LLC archive, one of the largest historic military, transportation, and aviation stock footage collections in the USA. Entirely film backed, this material is available for licensing in 24p HD, 2k and 4k. For more information visit http://www.PeriscopeFilm.com</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="144" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="3501"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:lblK3tdRnew</id>
  <yt:videoId>lblK3tdRnew</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCddem5RlB3bQe99wyY49g0g</yt:channelId>
  <title>1972 R.A.C. RALLY RACE   WALES RALLY GB  KLEBER RADIAL TIRES PROMO FILM  96134</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=lblK3tdRnew"/>
  <author>
   <name>PeriscopeFilm</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCddem5RlB3bQe99wyY49g0g</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-11-03T19:29:47+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-11-03T19:29:48+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>1972 R.A.C. RALLY RACE   WALES RALLY GB  KLEBER RADIAL TIRES PROMO FILM  96134</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/lblK3tdRnew?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i1.ytimg.com/vi/lblK3tdRnew/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>Join this channel to get access to perks:
https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCddem5RlB3bQe99wyY49g0g/join

Want to learn more about Periscope Film and get access to exclusive swag? Join us on Patreon. Visit https://www.patreon.com/PeriscopeFilm
Visit our website www.PeriscopeFilm.com

This promotional film for Kleber Radial Tires covers the Daily Mirror R.A.C. Rally in 1972 with three different race tracks in Wales, England, and Scotland during three days of rallying. The film is directed and edited by Brian Llewelyn and produced by Barrie Hinchliffe, who also worked cameras with Keith Taylor and Bill Marshall.  This race was initiated in 1932, and later known as the Wales Rally GB, and was the largest and most high-profile motor rally in the United Kingdom. It was a round of the FIA World Rally Championship until 2019 and was also formerly a round of the MSA British Rally Championship. Up until 1997 it was known as the RAC Rally until adopting its current name in 2003 (except in 2009 when it was called the Rally of Great Britain).

The film begins with branches filmed up-close (00:08), and the camera zooms out to reveal a campsite (00:18). Two people are sitting in a rally car, and they drive (00:19). A man presents the Daily Mirror R.A.C. Rally to the camera (00:29). The rally cars are parked inside an enclosure, while mechanics perform service on the cars (00:50). One rally car drives down a ramp onto the racetrack with onlookers along the sides (02:22). The rally cars are speeding through muddy tracks (02:37). Car nr. 43 is stuck in the mud, and Ncrowd members rush to assist in releasing (03:14). The car is freed and continues rallying (03:43). Mechanics are changing tires and checking engines (05:20). A scoreboard shows the leading positions with Roger Clark and Tony Mason in the first place, driving a Ford Escort RS 1600 MKI (05:52). It is dark early morning at Severn Bridge, and the drivers make payments before driving across (06:07). Mechanics, racers, and bystanders are gathered around the track in preparation for the second race (06:46). Racers are interviewed about the weather conditions and the extremely muddy racetrack (07:38). Shifting scenery-footage of a tall stone beam with a statue and a large castle, interceded by footage from the cars rallying, dramatized with classical music (09:47). A race begins at morning-time at Yorkshire Moors National Park in England (15:30). A car has been dented heavily from the front and is towed away (19:37). A man is interviewed about the conditions of the mud-covered track (19:58). Drivers are getting ready inside their car (21:01), and they drive away in darkness (22:04). An assistant is wiping the soles clean on a driver’s shoes before entering the car (23:54). At Dalbeattie Forest in Scotland (24:37). A scoreboard shows the rankings with Roger Clark and Tony Mason continuously in the lead (24:43). Gas tanks are being filled and car tires are changes in preparation for the final race (24:46). Mechanics are working below the cars to ensure safety and functionality (25:30). Strong winds are blowing through the trees and on  bystanders (27:22). The race has begun, and the cars are rallying in the muddy track (27:36). Roger Clark and Tony Mason has won, and they pop champagne to drink and spray on each other in celebration of their victory (31:00). Stig Blomqvist and Arne Hertz finish in second place, driving a Saab 96 V4 (31:36). Third place goes to Anders Kulläng and Donald Karlsson in an Opel Ascona 1.9 SR (31:56). The checkered flag is waved at the last car cross the finish line, driven by Tony Fall and Wood Mike in a Datsun 240Z (32:39). 

The film is a United Motion Picture production presented by “Kleber Radial Tyres” with assistance from Cibie, Ferodo LTD., W.D., and H.O. Wills, and Ford Motor Company LTD. With sound by John Hayes, Paul Corfield, and Martin Sawyer, Dubbing by Roger Goodall, Aerial camera by Bob Lomas, and Alan Ross as 2nd unit director, the newsreel aired in 1972. Howard Everitt was assistant editor and Roger Edmunds was production assistant. 

We encourage viewers to add comments and, especially, to provide additional information about our videos by adding a comment!  See something interesting?  Tell people what it is and what they can see by writing something for example: &quot;01:00:12:00 -- President Roosevelt is seen meeting with Winston Churchill at the Quebec Conference.&quot;

This film is part of the Periscope Film LLC archive, one of the largest historic military, transportation, and aviation stock footage collections in the USA. Entirely film backed, this material is available for licensing in 24p HD, 2k and 4k. For more information visit http://www.PeriscopeFilm.com</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="202" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="4473"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:Oyps21ItfOk</id>
  <yt:videoId>Oyps21ItfOk</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCddem5RlB3bQe99wyY49g0g</yt:channelId>
  <title>&quot; GRAND PRIX DE FRANCE&quot; 1959 GRAND PRIX MOTORCYCLE RACE  CASTROL OIL PROMO FILM  XD60664</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Oyps21ItfOk"/>
  <author>
   <name>PeriscopeFilm</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCddem5RlB3bQe99wyY49g0g</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-11-03T16:29:46+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-11-03T16:29:47+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>&quot; GRAND PRIX DE FRANCE&quot; 1959 GRAND PRIX MOTORCYCLE RACE  CASTROL OIL PROMO FILM  XD60664</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/Oyps21ItfOk?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i4.ytimg.com/vi/Oyps21ItfOk/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>Join this channel to get access to perks:
https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCddem5RlB3bQe99wyY49g0g/join

Want to learn more about Periscope Film and get access to exclusive swag? Join us on Patreon. Visit https://www.patreon.com/PeriscopeFilm
Visit our website www.PeriscopeFilm.com

Created in 1959 as a promo for Castrol Oil, this film &quot;Grand Prix De France&quot; was produced by Kinocrat Films Limited, made in cooperation with Le Moto Club D’ Auvergne. It covers the French Grand Prix Race on May 17th, 1959, on the Charade Circuit in France. With commentary by Harry Louis, spoken by Raymond Baxter, this film reports on the first race day of the season 1959 with three classes of bikes: 350cc, 500cc, and sidecars 500cc. The 1959 Grand Prix motorcycle racing season was the 11th F.I.M. Road Racing World Championship Grand Prix season, with the Grand Prix De France the opening event in the nine race season. The bikes seen in the film were made by MV Agusta, Norton, BMW, and Matchless. 

The film begins with a motorcycle riding down a mountain road (00:06). At the Claremore Fair south of Paris (00:51). An officer directs traffic with hand gestures and a whistle (01:03). Narrow streets and tall cathedral spikes depict a typical French scene (01:08). Café Universe is the headquarters for Moto club D’ Auvergne (01:21). The sign of the five-mile circuit “Circuit De Montagne D’ Auvergne” (01:39). Footage of the racetrack from the point of view of a motorcycle rider (01:47). The highest point of the circuit near the village of Shahad (02:11) with voiceover comments from drivers Cyril Smith, Dickie Dale (riding an AJS), Gary Hocking (on a Norton), and Florian Camathias. A police helicopter flies over the track (03:27) and communicates with police officers on the ground via radio (03:33), followed by the Marshal’s office (03:38), the loudspeakers at the grandstands and vantage points (03:42), and the on-site ambulance (03:48). The motorcycle riders’ accommodation at a campsite (03:55). Cyril Smith and John Surtees talk at the campsite (04:22). Florian Camathias performs an oil-check (04:31). Mechanics are inspecting the bikes in the pit (04:38). People seated inside the race control office (05:05). Mechanics filling the motorcycle tanks before the 350cc race (05:19). The racers wheel their bikes into the circuit enclosure (05:25). John Hempleman, Bob Brown, and Dickie Dale are preparing at the starting line (05:59). John Surtees moves onto his MV Agusta (06:32). A checkered flag is waved, and the race begins (06:41). Watchers are seated on the sides of the racetrack (07:24). John Surtees wins the class 350cc race (12:34). Racers are preparing for the sidecars 500cc race (12:59). All motorcycles with sidecars are lined up along the starting line (13:34). The race begins (13:36). The victors are stood on a podium (19:04). The riders are drinking and eating after the race (19:05). The motorcycles are wheeled in for the final class 500cc race (19:15). The line up at the starting line (19:19). The checkered flag is waved, and the final race begins (19:52). John Surtees triumphs again (24:57). He steps onto the hood of a car, while a crowd applaud him, and he accepts flowers (25:05). The French and English flag is waving in the wind (25:34). The loudspeakers are silent (25:35). The camp-site area has been cleared out (25:43). A couple is sitting on a patch of grass kissing (25:50). A small village with a fountain where two cows pull a loaded carriage (25:53). 

We encourage viewers to add comments and, especially, to provide additional information about our videos by adding a comment!  See something interesting?  Tell people what it is and what they can see by writing something for example: &quot;01:00:12:00 -- President Roosevelt is seen meeting with Winston Churchill at the Quebec Conference.&quot;

This film is part of the Periscope Film LLC archive, one of the largest historic military, transportation, and aviation stock footage collections in the USA. Entirely film backed, this material is available for licensing in 24p HD, 2k and 4k. For more information visit http://www.PeriscopeFilm.com</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="113" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="2877"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:0NHu2_BOGW0</id>
  <yt:videoId>0NHu2_BOGW0</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCddem5RlB3bQe99wyY49g0g</yt:channelId>
  <title>“ BADEN-POWELL CHIEF SCOUT OF THE WORLD ” 1957 BOY SCOUTS ASSOCIATION DOCUMENTARY FILM   XD51864</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0NHu2_BOGW0"/>
  <author>
   <name>PeriscopeFilm</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCddem5RlB3bQe99wyY49g0g</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-11-02T19:29:46+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-11-02T19:29:47+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>“ BADEN-POWELL CHIEF SCOUT OF THE WORLD ” 1957 BOY SCOUTS ASSOCIATION DOCUMENTARY FILM   XD51864</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/0NHu2_BOGW0?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i1.ytimg.com/vi/0NHu2_BOGW0/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>Join this channel to get access to perks:
https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCddem5RlB3bQe99wyY49g0g/join

Want to learn more about Periscope Film and get access to exclusive swag? Join us on Patreon. Visit https://www.patreon.com/PeriscopeFilm
Visit our website www.PeriscopeFilm.com

This British documentary entitled “Baden-Powell Chief Scout of The World” was made in 1957 by The Boy Scouts Association. It is about the life and history of Baden Powell, the founder of The Boy Scouts. The film details his history working as a scout for the British Army and his undercover missions to disrupt rebellions in British colonies in India and Africa. The film illustrates the evolution of the Boy Scouts from a military movement to a force of unity and good will.  (Note: the USA version of The Boy Scouts Association is the Boy Scouts of America or BSA.) 

Film opens with hundreds of boys running through a field and introduces the founder, Baden Powell (1:54). Narration accompanies illustrations and photographs by and of Powell. Describes his childhood in England and his love of hunting and nature, accompanied by Powell’s sketches. Powell pictured as a teenager joined the army at age 19 and was sent to the regiment in India in 1876. Sketch of him on a horse shows his first scout mission to Natal, India in 1884 (3:35). Sketch of Powell undercover as a butterfly hunter (4:56). Map shows the gold coast of West Africa where Powell was sent in 1895 to command African scouts and pioneers (5:17). Sketches show ceremonies performing human sacrifices by the Ashanti tribe (5:30).  Was coined “he of the big hat” by the Africans. Picture of him in said hat which became part of the boy scout uniform (6:16). Map shows Matabeleland, a region in Zimbabwe, Where Powell was sent to repress the growing rebellion (6:28). Picture of him blowing a Kudu horn, which was incorporated as a tradition of the boy scouts (7:07). Map shows Meerut, India where Powell was sent after being promoted to Colonel (07:22). Sketches show soldiers he trained with scout skills in order to be more independent, and their badges. He then wrote a book called “Aids to Scouting for N. -C.Os. and Men” (8:15). Sketches show Mafeking in South Africa (8:50). More sketches show technology and tactics developed by Powell to bluff the regiment’s power and size (9:19) Sketches show the cadette core of boys who were trained to fill in for soldiers sent to the front line (11:31). Sketch of Sir William Smith, founder of the boy’s brigade (13:02). Pictures of boys from all over England participating in the first Boy Scout Camp in Brownsea Island in 1907 (13:33). Powell’s first appearance on motion picture film in 1911 inspecting boy scout rallies all over the country (15:28). Photo shows King George V, a boy scout enthusiast (16:40). Picture of Powell with his new wife, Olave St Clair Baden-Powell and their new car. Sketches show Powell and the boy scouts aiding in the efforts during WWI (17:39). Photos of the first permanent boy scout camp with Duke of Connaught, president of the boy scouts for 30 years (18:19). Photos of the first jamboree in Olympia London. King George inspects the scouts. Clips of the second jamboree in Denmark. The King of Denmark inspects the boys. More footage of Scout Jamborees all over the world. Pictures show a reunion of the Powell with the first campers from Brownsea Island (20:06). The Prince of Wales gives a speech during a jamboree (20:44). Footage of Powell giving speeches and traveling all over the world. Powell speaks from Sydney, Australia of the evolution of the boy scouts from a military movement to a movement of peace and good will among men intended to unite the world (25:15). Powell gives a speech in 1932 at a Jamboree in England (26:17). Footage of the Jamboree in Hungry. 77 year old Powell goes on another world tour. Footage shows Stockholm in 1935. Film from Powell’s daughter Betty’s wedding in 1936. Powell returns to India in 1937 for the countries first jamboree (29:47). The royal family speaks with Powell in front of Windsor Castle. Speech plays over photos from Powell address to the boy scouts encouraging them to be their best in celebration of his 80th birthday. Powell strolls the ship he took to Kenya where he retired in 1938. Pictures taken by Powell show game hunting tree houses. Powell dies in 1941 in Kenya, footage of his grand funeral possession (33:55). 

This film is part of the Periscope Film LLC archive, one of the largest historic military, transportation, and aviation stock footage collections in the USA. Entirely film backed, this material is available for licensing in 24p HD, 2k and 4k. For more information visit http://www.PeriscopeFilm.com</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="241" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="7691"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:m0G-0VRRu24</id>
  <yt:videoId>m0G-0VRRu24</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCddem5RlB3bQe99wyY49g0g</yt:channelId>
  <title>MERCURY-REDSTONE 4 SPLASHDOWN &amp; LOSS OF LIBERTY BELL 7 CAPSULE  GUS GRISSOM JULY 21, 1961  XD48204</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=m0G-0VRRu24"/>
  <author>
   <name>PeriscopeFilm</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCddem5RlB3bQe99wyY49g0g</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-11-02T16:29:48+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-11-04T17:24:52+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>MERCURY-REDSTONE 4 SPLASHDOWN &amp; LOSS OF LIBERTY BELL 7 CAPSULE  GUS GRISSOM JULY 21, 1961  XD48204</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/m0G-0VRRu24?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i2.ytimg.com/vi/m0G-0VRRu24/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>Want to support this channel and help us preserve old films? Visit https://www.patreon.com/PeriscopeFilm
Visit our website www.PeriscopeFilm.com

This television feed shows the splashdown, attempted recovery and loss of the Mercury-Redstone 4's Liberty Bell 7 capsule. The loss occurred as a result of the accidental deployment of the capsule's hatch, which was equipped with an emergency explosive release system. Astronaut Virgil &quot;Gus&quot; Grissom was rescued without injury and flown to the aircraft carrier USS Randolph for evaluation. Commentary in the film is provided by Jules Bergman, ABC's science editor, as well as correspondent Robert Lodge. 

Mercury-Redstone 4 was the second United States human spaceflight, on July 21, 1961. The flight was suborbital and lasted 15 minutes 30 seconds, reached an altitude of more than 102.8 nautical miles (190.4 km), and flew 262.5 nautical miles (486.2 km) downrange, landing in the Atlantic Ocean. The capsule was recovered in 1999. Grissom later flew in Gemini III, and then tragically died in the Apollo 1 fire in 1967.

We encourage viewers to add comments and, especially, to provide additional information about our videos by adding a comment!  See something interesting?  Tell people what it is and what they can see by writing something for example: &quot;01:00:12:00 -- President Roosevelt is seen meeting with Winston Churchill at the Quebec Conference.&quot;

This film is part of the Periscope Film LLC archive, one of the largest historic military, transportation, and aviation stock footage collections in the USA. Entirely film backed, this material is available for licensing in 24p HD, 2k and 4k. For more information visit http://www.PeriscopeFilm.com</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="73" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="1678"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:J_6tnx-SuN8</id>
  <yt:videoId>J_6tnx-SuN8</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCddem5RlB3bQe99wyY49g0g</yt:channelId>
  <title>”CHALLENGE OF CHAMPIONS”  1974 INDIANAPOLIS 500 RACE   JOHNNY RUTHERFORD  XD60674</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=J_6tnx-SuN8"/>
  <author>
   <name>PeriscopeFilm</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCddem5RlB3bQe99wyY49g0g</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-11-01T19:29:54+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-11-01T19:29:54+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>”CHALLENGE OF CHAMPIONS”  1974 INDIANAPOLIS 500 RACE   JOHNNY RUTHERFORD  XD60674</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/J_6tnx-SuN8?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i3.ytimg.com/vi/J_6tnx-SuN8/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>Join this channel to get access to perks:
https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCddem5RlB3bQe99wyY49g0g/join

Want to learn more about Periscope Film and get access to exclusive swag? Join us on Patreon. Visit https://www.patreon.com/PeriscopeFilm
Visit our website www.PeriscopeFilm.com

This promotional film for Valvoline covers the 58th Running of the Indianapolis 500 held on May 26th, 1974, at the Indianapolis Motor Speedway. Throughout the film, race drivers and team managers are interviewed, and highlights of the 115-lap 500-mile race are shown. In 1974, 33 drivers competed for a prize of over one million dollars.

The film begins with shots showing the over 300.000 fans attending the motorsport event (00:08). An overview reveals the impressive size of the crowd and stadium (00:16). McLaren team manager George Bignotti is interviewed (01:24), followed by Parnelli Jones (01:36), team manager Dan Gurney (01:45), Teddy Mayor of the McLaren team (01:52), and chief mechanic A. J. Watson (01:56). Gordon Johncock, winner of Indianapolis 500 in 1973 (02:24), 1969 winner; Mario Andretti (02:27), and 1968 winner; Bobby Unser (02:31). Mike Mosley puts on his glasses (02:34). Bill Vukovich II in his racecar (02:37), and Lloyd Ruby in his racecar (02:41). Three-time winner A. J. Foyt is interviewed about his results during trials (02:46). Footage from the qualification rounds (03:28). Johnny Rutherford is interviewed about the race from the 25th position (04:04), followed by Wally Dallenbach Sr. about starting from the front row (04:13). Clips of Mike Hiss (04:32), two-time winner Al Unser (04:36), Gary Bettenhausen (04:39), Pancho Carter (04:45), and Bill Simpson (04:57). Various fans are interviewed about their favorite driver (05:12). Tony Hulman is the starting command (05:38). Many balloons are released into the sky as a celebratory measure (05:49). 11 rows with 33 cars are lining up for the start of the race (06:14). The green flag is in, and the Indianapolis 500 begins (08:12). Mike Mosley is out on Lap four (11:15). Rutherford is in the pit on lap 23 (13:30), followed by A. J. Floyd on lap 24 (14:06), and Unser on lap 28 (14:14). Unser’s team manager Dan Gurney (14:28) and George Bignotti (15:07) comments on the race. On lap 59, 10 cars are out of the race (15:33). Jan Opperman has an accident on the track (16:01), and the yellow flag is out for caution laps (16:15). A. J. Floyd's pit crew is having problems inside the pit (17:13). The green flag is out (17:34). Jerry Grant hits a wall causing an accident on the racetrack (18:34), and the yellow flag is out again (18:43). Team-members attend to the damaged car to clean up the raceway (18:54). The green flag is out (19:45). At the 150-mile mark, half of the drivers are out of the race (20:18). Salt Walter is out (20:37). His father is interviewed about Walter’s near fatal accident in the 1973 race (20:44). A. J. Floyd is having unfixable problems with his car in the pit (22:06) and he withdraws from the race (22:24). Pancho Carter’s car is bumped and turned, and he is forced to drive off the track (23:17). Johnny Rutherford wins the race (26:45). Bobby Unser finishes second 22 behind (26:54). Fans are expressing their joy over the results of the race (27:07). Rutherford drives on the checkered victory lane (27:21). His team manager comments on the success (27:50). Rutherford comments on his victory and accepts several embraces and congratulations (28:05). 

We encourage viewers to add comments and, especially, to provide additional information about our videos by adding a comment!  See something interesting?  Tell people what it is and what they can see by writing something for example: &quot;01:00:12:00 -- President Roosevelt is seen meeting with Winston Churchill at the Quebec Conference.&quot;

This film is part of the Periscope Film LLC archive, one of the largest historic military, transportation, and aviation stock footage collections in the USA. Entirely film backed, this material is available for licensing in 24p HD, 2k and 4k. For more information visit http://www.PeriscopeFilm.com</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="94" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="2786"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:1Dq0VGnEMjI</id>
  <yt:videoId>1Dq0VGnEMjI</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCddem5RlB3bQe99wyY49g0g</yt:channelId>
  <title>&quot;DOWN THE AMAZON TO BELEM”   1958 BOLD JOURNEY TV SHOW  BRAZIL RAIN FOREST TRAVELOGUE   96764</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1Dq0VGnEMjI"/>
  <author>
   <name>PeriscopeFilm</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCddem5RlB3bQe99wyY49g0g</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-11-01T16:29:49+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-11-01T16:29:49+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>&quot;DOWN THE AMAZON TO BELEM”   1958 BOLD JOURNEY TV SHOW  BRAZIL RAIN FOREST TRAVELOGUE   96764</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/1Dq0VGnEMjI?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i2.ytimg.com/vi/1Dq0VGnEMjI/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>Join this channel to get access to perks:
https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCddem5RlB3bQe99wyY49g0g/join

Want to learn more about Periscope Film and get access to exclusive swag? Join us on Patreon. Visit https://www.patreon.com/PeriscopeFilm
Visit our website www.PeriscopeFilm.com

This black and white adventure film is part of the “Bold Journey” program broadcast by ABC Television in the late 1950s. This episode titled “Amazon to Belem” covers an epic journey made by adventurer Eric Pavel and his wife from the Andes in Argentina, down the Amazon River through Brazil.  The episode was released on October 6, 1958. Belém is the capital of the Brazilian state of Pará, and is a port city and gateway to Brazil’s lower Amazon region. Eric Pavel was a filmmaker best known for his movie &quot;Three Worlds of Peru.&quot; 

The film begins with actor Jack Douglas introducing the program featuring Eric Pavel, who made the journey across the Amazon River with his wife (00:06). The start of the river in the Andes Mountain range (00:18). Jaguars swimming through the river (00:24). The flesh-eating Piranha fish (00:27). Primitive tribes of Hebrew Indians live along the Amazon River (00:29). Jack Douglas interviews Eric Pavel about the upcoming episode in a studio (00:31). Pavel and his wife aboard an Argentine Air Force Plane, and they fly over the jungle (02:19). They land high in the Andes Mountains (02:53) and continue their journey in a four-wheel drive (03:17). They start the sail across the river in dugout canoes (03:29). The nature alongside the Amazon River is inhabited by many exotic animals such as macaw parrots (03:40), poisonous rattlesnakes (03:55), flat-headed snakes (04:05), leafcutter ants (04:17), centipedes (04:38), and two-toed sloths (04:43). The canoe travels up smaller tributaries (04:54), and people of a Hebrew Indian tribe greets them on the riverbank (05:14). The people of the tribe wear unique face paint and sticks through their ears and chins (05:32). The elder council discusses to make a discussion (06:05). The journey down the river continues (06:21) decorated by special trees, plants, and flower only found in this jungle (06:30). They pass through a small town, and local women wash their clothes in the river while conversing and smoking cigars (07:14). Local men wash gold found in the river (07:30). Rubber is tapped from rubber trees (08:03) and coagulated to form rubber balls (08:22), and finally it is transported by canoes (08:42). A tribe member catches a crocodile by hand (09:00) and catches Piranha fish using a spear (09:48). They pass by a trading post for crocodile skin, fish, sugar, and alcohol, built on a raft on the river (10:26). The children of the tribes sail in smaller dugout canoes (11:28). The canoes are built by burning out a wooden log (11:40). Cattle can cross the river during dry season (12:40). Piranhas eat dead cattle and left behind is only the skeleton (12:46). Some tribes fish for Piranha using bow and arrow (14:07), and they grill them over a fire before eating them (14:18). An American missionary is living with a Hebrew Indian tribe with his wife and children (14:26). In the area lives emus, (14:36), monkeys (14:48), iguanas (15:03), spotted leopards (15:14), and tarantulas (15:46). Pavel and his wife continue their journey on horses (16:23). Another Indian tribe use macaw parrots as watchdogs (16:48), and owls as a pet (17:03). The women of the tribe comb their hair and wash themselves and their children (17:22). They work with an Amazon spinning wheel and homegrown cotton to make clothes and decorations (17:44). With tied hair, lower-lip piercings, body paint and feathers, the people of the tribe are ready for a celebration (18:17). Two men wrestle wearing duck feather stuck to their arms and legs using tar (19:10). They eat special celebratory foods like maniac and mango soup (19:58). Carved figures present the people of the tribe (20:24). A Garza bird stands in water (20:36). They pass through the city of Manaus (21:08) where traders sell bread, milk, and meat from canoes (21:08), and a boat functions as a floating coffee shop (21:20). The Amazon Theatre is the Opera House in Manaus (21:24). In the zoological garden, Pavel is holding non-poisonous snakes (21:31). They arrive to their final destination, the city of Belem (21:51). Jack Douglas interviews Pavel in the studio to summarize the journey across the Amazon River (22:09). Scenes from the following episode of the Bold Journey Program covering Siberia (24:14). Jack Douglas makes an outro (24:55). 

The film was produced by Julian Lesser and edited by Bill O’Hara with Leon Barsha as editorial supervisor. 
 
This film is part of the Periscope Film LLC archive, one of the largest historic military, transportation, and aviation stock footage collections in the USA. Entirely film backed, this material is available for licensing in 24p HD, 2k and 4k. For more information visit http://www.PeriscopeFilm.com</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="70" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="1389"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:Sx9YhjiXdQg</id>
  <yt:videoId>Sx9YhjiXdQg</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCddem5RlB3bQe99wyY49g0g</yt:channelId>
  <title>“ONE WAY TICKET TO HELL” 1955 DRUG ADDICTION SCARE FILM   PART ONE    XD49854</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Sx9YhjiXdQg"/>
  <author>
   <name>PeriscopeFilm</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCddem5RlB3bQe99wyY49g0g</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-10-31T19:30:03+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-10-31T19:30:03+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>“ONE WAY TICKET TO HELL” 1955 DRUG ADDICTION SCARE FILM   PART ONE    XD49854</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/Sx9YhjiXdQg?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i4.ytimg.com/vi/Sx9YhjiXdQg/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>Want to support this channel and help us preserve old films? Visit https://www.patreon.com/PeriscopeFilm
Visit our website www.PeriscopeFilm.com

Part 2: https://youtu.be/pM6lK4OQ4pM

This black and white, mono-sound fictional film is the first half of “One Way Ticket to Hell”, a drug addiction scare film that was apparently first released in late 1955 under the title &quot;Teenage Devil Dolls&quot;.  It was made on a shoestring budget of $4000. The storyline spans from 1949-1952 and portrays a young girl named Cassandra Lee, who makes friends with the wrong crowd and becomes addicted to drugs. And as the story proceeds, she is caught in a downward spiral of addiction and crime. The film is directed, written, edited, and presented by B. Lawrence Price, Jr. (aka Bamlet Lawrence Price Jr. ) with photography by William R. Lieb and S. David Saxon, and is narrated by Kurt Martell. One critic described the film as &quot;an obscure, anti-drug, anti-juvenile delinquent anti-rebellion morality story, all told in not-so-glorious Dragnet style narration&quot;.

The film begins with a written disclaimer on screen (00:09). A city view with buildings (00:34), and a hospital zone (00:54). A man named Chola Martinez is sitting inside a parked car outside the hospital (01:01). Cassandra Lee exits the hospital with her family and narcotics police officer David Jason (01:11). The family and officer Jason drives away, and Martinez follows (01:57). “One Way Ticket” title banner (02:34). The family arrives at the Southern Pacific train station, and Martinez continues following them on foot (04:55). People are waiting on the perron as the “Eastbound Limited” train arrives (05:44). *Three years earlier* Cassandra is driving on the back of Russel Packard’s motorcycle alongside a group of other riders with passengers (06:23). Cassandra is working as a stock girl (06:41) across from a motorcycle shop where she meets Russel and his friends (06:45). Cassandra’s mother yells when she sees Cassandra talking to Russel (07:02), and Cassandra escaped with Russel on his motorcycle (07:37). The group of friends sit down, and they smoke marijuana (07:48). Cassandra is sitting against a rock laughing and smoking marijuana (09:26). Cassandra’s old friend Johnny Adams waits for her outside of their high school campus, but she never shows up (09:59). The group of motorcycle riders driving (10:30). Cassandra waves goodbye to them, and runs towards Johnny, who was still waiting at nightfall (11:02). Johnny and Cassandra exit a church after getting married (11:35). To depict Cassandra’s discontentment with her new life, she angrily rips down clothing from a drying rack while drying (12:03). Johnny brings home a dog to make his wife happier (12:31). Cassandra arrives with a bus in town and meets with Russel (14:18). She drives with the group on motorcycles and smokes marijuana (14:42). She is fights with her husband (15:30). Russel and his friends bring Cassandra to a cocktail bar (15:54). Johnny is sleeping alone, as Cassandra arrives drunkenly in the middle of the night (16:29). Johnny finds and overturned trash can outside their home and discovers numerous empty pill bottles, and Cassandra is nearly unconscious in the backyard (18:00). Johnny calls for help, meanwhile Cassandra attempts to drive away and collides with a car outside their house (20:09). A police car drives Cassandra to her parents’ house after her arrest (21:10). She walks through town carrying a suitcase (21:50). Police officer David Jason follows her (22:16). Officer Jason and Cassandra are driving around town, helping each other look for Russel (23:50). Cassandra is working as a waitress at a drive-in restaurant, which also sells marijuana in secret (25:57). To police officers surveil the drive-in restaurant from an apartment (26:48). Cassandra is caught doing drugs she was supposed to sell (27:08). Police raids an apartments and arrest Cassandra and other youngsters (28:27). She is interrogated at the police station (29:10). Other groups of young criminals are arrested (30:31). 

The film was shot in California. The music is composed and conducted by Robert Jackson Drasnin. Edith Gross is the script and screenplay supervisor, and Anthony Gorsline, Raymond Pearson, and Perry Grey were production assistants.  The cast consists of Barbara Marks as Cassandra Lee, Robert A. Sherry as Officer Jason, Robert Norman as Johnny Adams, William Kendell as Russel Packard, further including Elaine Lindenbaum, Joel Climenhaga, Lucille Price, B. L. Price, Sr., Victor Schwartz, Anthony Gorsline, B. Lawrence Prince, Jr., and Joe Popavich. 

This film is part of the Periscope Film LLC archive, one of the largest historic military, transportation, and aviation stock footage collections in the USA. Entirely film backed, this material is available for licensing in 24p HD, 2k and 4k. For more information visit http://www.PeriscopeFilm.com</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="68" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="1544"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:pM6lK4OQ4pM</id>
  <yt:videoId>pM6lK4OQ4pM</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCddem5RlB3bQe99wyY49g0g</yt:channelId>
  <title>“ONE WAY TICKET TO HELL” 1955 DRUG ADDICTION SCARE FILM   PART TWO   XD49864</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=pM6lK4OQ4pM"/>
  <author>
   <name>PeriscopeFilm</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCddem5RlB3bQe99wyY49g0g</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-10-31T19:30:03+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-10-31T19:30:03+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>“ONE WAY TICKET TO HELL” 1955 DRUG ADDICTION SCARE FILM   PART TWO   XD49864</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/pM6lK4OQ4pM?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i1.ytimg.com/vi/pM6lK4OQ4pM/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>Want to support this channel and help us preserve old films? Visit https://www.patreon.com/PeriscopeFilm
Visit our website www.PeriscopeFilm.com

Part One: https://youtu.be/Sx9YhjiXdQg

This black and white, mono-sound fictional film is the second half of “One Way Ticket to Hell”, a drug addiction scare film that was apparently first released in late 1955 under the title &quot;Teenage Devil Dolls&quot;.  It was made on a shoestring budget of $4000. The storyline spans from 1949-1952 and portrays a young girl named Cassandra Lee, who makes friends with the wrong crowd and becomes addicted to drugs. And as the story proceeds, she is caught in a downward spiral of addiction and crime. The film is directed, written, edited, and presented by B. Lawrence Price, Jr. (aka Bamlet Lawrence Price Jr. ) with photography by William R. Lieb and S. David Saxon, and is narrated by Kurt Martell. One critic described the film as &quot;an obscure, anti-drug, anti-juvenile delinquent anti-rebellion morality story, all told in not-so-glorious Dragnet style narration&quot;.

Part two begins with Cassandra walking through town during her probation period (00:08). She notices a woman, named Margo Rossi, in an alley suffering from narcotic withdrawal, and she tends to her (00:53). Margo and Cassandra are selling marijuana to a man on a street corner (02:02). Cassandra sells marijuana to another man (02:46) Drug dealer, Sven Bergman arrives in a car, and he attacks Cassandra (03:07). Margo rushes to help Cassandra, and they are both forced into Sven’s car (03:33). Now inside a bedroom, Sven is injecting Margo and Cassandra with heroin to make them his subjects (03:43). Cassandra gets escorted by a nurse and a police officer into a hospital ward for mental illness (06:15). She cries out in pain laying in her hospital bed (06:46). Policemen are chasing and arresting multiple drug dealers in town (07:29), resulting in numerous addicts suffering from withdrawal around the town (09:14). The police discover the dead body of an addict (09:45). Sven Bergman is chased by the police but manages to escape through a storm-drain tunnel (09:52). Cassandra sneaks past a nurse and meets with Margo Rossi by the fence of the hospital, where Margo bring her heroin (10:15). Margo is caught by Sven, and she is pushed out of a moving car into a ditch, where she dies (11:37). Footage of the city buildings (11:52). Officer Jason and other narcotic policemen are surveilling a parking lot (12:15). Cassandra enters the parking lot with her accomplice Martinez and another young man (12:49). Martinez and the young man steal a car from the parking lot, while Cassandra distracts the parking lot attendee by asking for directions (13:52). They drive on a highway through the desert toward Mexico (14:36). Patrol officers guarding checkpoints along the highway (15:16). Martinez makes a stop at a gas station to refuel the stolen car (15:56). The police arrives and Cassandra and Martinez escape in the car, leaving the other young man to be arrested (16:12). Martinez drives the car off-road, to avoid the checkpoints along the highway (17:36). All patrol officers enter their cars to search for Martinez and Cassandra (18:05). They stop the cars to continue their search on foot (19:02). They locate the stolen car abandoned by a cliff (20:50). Cassandra and Martinez are running through the desert (21:15). They enter a cave in search of shade and rest, both crying from withdrawal sickness (22:25). Police and patrol officers continue their search (22:36), and they discover Cassandra nearly dead on the ground (27:10). Cassandra is walking with officer Jason, her mother, and her father at the Southern Pacific train station, where Martinez is hiding (27:44). Police officers arrive and arrest Martinez (28:12). Cassandra and her mother aboard the train (28:44). Informational text on screen concerning the extent of the addiction problem today (29:59). “The End” on screen (30:53). 

The film footage is shot in California. The music is composed and conducted by Robert Jackson Drasnin. Edith Gross is the script and screenplay supervisor, and Anthony Gorsline, Raymond Pearson, and Perry Grey were production assistants. 
The cast consists of Barbara Marks as Cassandra Lee, Robert A. Sherry as Officer Jason, Elaine Lindenbaum as Margo Rossi, B. Lawrence Price, Jr. as “Cholo” Martinez further including Robert Norman, William Kendell, Joel Climenhaga, Lucille Price, B. L. Price, Sr., Victor Schwartz, Anthony Gorsline, and Joe Popavich. 

This film is part of the Periscope Film LLC archive, one of the largest historic military, transportation, and aviation stock footage collections in the USA. Entirely film backed, this material is available for licensing in 24p HD, 2k and 4k. For more information visit http://www.PeriscopeFilm.com</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="39" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="716"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:kAi3sSgGp9w</id>
  <yt:videoId>kAi3sSgGp9w</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCddem5RlB3bQe99wyY49g0g</yt:channelId>
  <title>&quot;THE HAUNTED MOUTH&quot;  1974 AMERICAN DENTAL ASSOCIATION EDUCATIONAL FILM  w/ CESAR ROMERO XD72304</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=kAi3sSgGp9w"/>
  <author>
   <name>PeriscopeFilm</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCddem5RlB3bQe99wyY49g0g</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-10-31T19:00:19+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-10-31T19:00:20+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>&quot;THE HAUNTED MOUTH&quot;  1974 AMERICAN DENTAL ASSOCIATION EDUCATIONAL FILM  w/ CESAR ROMERO XD72304</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/kAi3sSgGp9w?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i4.ytimg.com/vi/kAi3sSgGp9w/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>Join this channel to get access to perks:
https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCddem5RlB3bQe99wyY49g0g/join

Want to learn more about Periscope Film and get access to exclusive swag? Join us on Patreon. Visit https://www.patreon.com/PeriscopeFilm
Visit our website www.PeriscopeFilm.com

Produced by the American Dental Association courtesy of a grant from Colgate-Palmolive in 1974, &quot;The Haunted Mouth&quot;. It features actor Cesar Romero as the narrator, &quot;B. Plaque&quot;.  This &quot;scary movie&quot; is actually all about dental hygiene and preventing cavities, and in it the invisible spirit of plaque (Romero) warns children against the dangers of not brushing and flossing. The film shows the enemies of plaque including toothpaste, toothbrushes, and dental floss (7:25), and discusses the proper method for brushing and flossing.  

Cesar Julio Romero Jr. was an American actor and activist, known for his portrayal of the Joker in the Batman TV show, but also for a wide range of screen roles including Latin lovers, historical figures in costume dramas, and characters in light domestic comedies.

We encourage viewers to add comments and, especially, to provide additional information about our videos by adding a comment!  See something interesting?  Tell people what it is and what they can see by writing something for example: &quot;01:00:12:00 -- President Roosevelt is seen meeting with Winston Churchill at the Quebec Conference.&quot;

This film is part of the Periscope Film LLC archive, one of the largest historic military, transportation, and aviation stock footage collections in the USA. Entirely film backed, this material is available for licensing in 24p HD, 2k and 4k. For more information visit http://www.PeriscopeFilm.com</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="72" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="1705"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:Pvc8m5Nno7g</id>
  <yt:videoId>Pvc8m5Nno7g</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCddem5RlB3bQe99wyY49g0g</yt:channelId>
  <title>&quot; RAT ATTACK &quot;  BIZARRE RAT &amp; RODENT CONTROL EDUCATIONAL FILM    XD42144</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Pvc8m5Nno7g"/>
  <author>
   <name>PeriscopeFilm</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCddem5RlB3bQe99wyY49g0g</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-10-31T17:30:05+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-10-31T17:30:05+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>&quot; RAT ATTACK &quot;  BIZARRE RAT &amp; RODENT CONTROL EDUCATIONAL FILM    XD42144</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/Pvc8m5Nno7g?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i1.ytimg.com/vi/Pvc8m5Nno7g/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>Join this channel to get access to perks:
https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCddem5RlB3bQe99wyY49g0g/join

Want to learn more about Periscope Film and get access to exclusive swag? Join us on Patreon. Visit https://www.patreon.com/PeriscopeFilm
Visit our website www.PeriscopeFilm.com

WARNING: This film has numerous scenes of rats crawling everywhere, which may be triggering for those who have musophobia. 

This bizarre educational film &quot;Rat Attack&quot; vividly shows the effects of a rodent infestation, and describes how an infestation is caused, as well as delving into the history of rats and humans. It also offers solutions for how to keep rats out of your home or apartment. The film was made by  Ucom Educational Inc., which specialized in films for schools and industrial and medical training programs.

The film starts with rats crawling on the floor of a man’s bedroom at 0:50. Then, it jump cuts (our print has damage) to police cars, and the man who says “there’s rats in here!” then, shows a fire in the man’s apartment -- apparently caused by something the man did to try to kill the rats. The man is seen being carted into an ambulance at 1:47. Police investigate the incident and the neighbors are seen talking about it at 2:05. An old man is then shown who appears to be the narrator of the film at 2:03. The man says “rats kill more people than all the wars in history” at 2:41. A man is shown being bitten by a rat and blood drips from his finger at 3:03. This scene may be graphic for viewers. A rat is filmed eating leftovers of a sandwich at 3:42. At 4:09 a rat is shown drinking water. A broken glass window is shown and the narrator says buildings with holes and openings give rats a nice warm place to live and have babies at 4:32. The narrator then says “rats have 12 babies every 8 weeks” at 4:42. Rat droppings are shown at 5:07. Rat teeth inside a live rat are shown at 5:30. Rat tracks are shown at 5:44. A rat eating poison is shown at 6:08. A rat corpse is shown at 6:15. A man setting a rat trap is shown at 7:37. The film shows a rat being snared by the trap at 7:51– graphic. A rat is shown eating another rat at 9:23– extremely graphic. The film ends shortly after. 

A UCOM Presentation.

Acknowledgements to Albany County Department of Health, State of New York Department of Health, Bureau of Rodent, Insect and Weed Control, the Board of Education of the City of Albany, New York. Film was made in Albany, NY, in 1970. 


We encourage viewers to add comments and, especially, to provide additional information about our videos by adding a comment!  See something interesting?  Tell people what it is and what they can see by writing something for example: &quot;01:00:12:00 -- President Roosevelt is seen meeting with Winston Churchill at the Quebec Conference.&quot;

This film is part of the Periscope Film LLC archive, one of the largest historic military, transportation, and aviation stock footage collections in the USA. Entirely film backed, this material is available for licensing in 24p HD, 2k and 4k. For more information visit http://www.PeriscopeFilm.com</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="101" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="3000"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:_TBwZFifZk8</id>
  <yt:videoId>_TBwZFifZk8</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCddem5RlB3bQe99wyY49g0g</yt:channelId>
  <title>&quot;TIMES 25&quot;  1969 TRAFFIC SAFETY FOUNDATION   DRUNK DRIVING AWARENESS FILM W/ RONALD REAGAN   XD50924</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_TBwZFifZk8"/>
  <author>
   <name>PeriscopeFilm</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCddem5RlB3bQe99wyY49g0g</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-10-31T17:00:21+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-10-31T17:00:22+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>&quot;TIMES 25&quot;  1969 TRAFFIC SAFETY FOUNDATION   DRUNK DRIVING AWARENESS FILM W/ RONALD REAGAN   XD50924</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/_TBwZFifZk8?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i4.ytimg.com/vi/_TBwZFifZk8/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>Join this channel to get access to perks:
https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCddem5RlB3bQe99wyY49g0g/join

Want to learn more about Periscope Film and get access to exclusive swag? Join us on Patreon. Visit https://www.patreon.com/PeriscopeFilm
Visit our website www.PeriscopeFilm.com

This PSA-style film from the late 1970s titled “Times 25” warns of the dangers of alcoholism, how to recognize the problem, and how the issue affects driving and leads to fatal accidents. Produced by KGO-TV in association with The California Traffic Safety Foundation, the film features clips of real-life accidents as well as staged scenes of profiles of people who can be characterized as “alcoholics.” Additionally there was collaboration with the California Highway Patrol, General Motors Corporation, International Driving School, Western Laboratories Inc, and The San Francisco Police Department in the making of the film. Narrated by John Edwards, the film is additionally a series of interviews with doctors, experts, and employees of the California Traffic Safety Foundation and even includes opening and closing segments by former president and then Governor of California, Ronald Reagan. The film was directed by Gordon Waldear and the script was written by both Sharon Tresnon and Gordon Waldear.

Scene of a car crash (0:11). Ronald Reagan addresses chronic alcoholism and its link to a rise in fatal car crashes (0:22-2:22). Scene of another car crash (2:24). Interior of morgue with white sheets draped over bodies (2:50). Casket at a funeral in Christian church (3:12). Aerial view of busy city street (3:29). What is perhaps a Lincoln Town Car driving on the road (4:22). Aerial view of pedestrians on busy sidewalk (4:24). Person stirs their drink at a bar (5:01). Royal A. Neilson, from the California Traffic Safety Foundation, discussing statistics (5:18). Lab running blood alcohol studies (6:05). Interview with Dr. Henry Turkel, a coroner from San Francisco (6:38). Scientists in a lab (8:22). Interview with Harold Sullivan, then commissioner of the California Highway Patrol (8:29). Interview with Dr. William Haddon of the Insurance Institute for Highway Safety (9:15). Summary of points discussed thus far using diorama with mini toy cars (10:04). Interview with Dr. Charles Hine of the University of California Medical School to discuss how alcohol affects the body (10:54). Who is the problem drinker? Business man pulls out mug and whiskey from desk drawer (12:49). Housewife takes out a hidden alcohol bottle from the bathroom cabinet (13:06). Man sits in living room smoking and drinking (13:19). Bar counter (13:34). Perspective of a problem drinker from behind the wheel of a car with stitched scenes from the coroner's office (14:14). Highway sign for Los Angeles International Airport (LAX) (15:45). Studies of drunk drivers done at the driving simulator at The University of Los Angeles (UCLA) (15:55). Cinerama-type motion picture screen and real car used to simulate real traffic situations, study supervised by Dr. Slade Hulbert (16:00). Court sentencing for drunk driver (17:20). More of interview with Dr. Charles Hine of the University of California Medical School discussing reasons for excessive drinking (17:38). Interview with Dr. Fred Hudson of Presbyterian Hospital (18:38). More of interview with Dr. Henry Turkel (19:28). More of interview with Harold Sullivan. Interview with Dr. Seymour Pollock, then project director at the University fo Southern California USC (20:36). More of interview with Interview with Dr. William Haddon (21:22). Film returns to Ronald Regan and scene of the original car crash (22:10). Closing credits (24:15). 

We encourage viewers to add comments and, especially, to provide additional information about our videos by adding a comment!  See something interesting?  Tell people what it is and what they can see by writing something for example: &quot;01:00:12:00 -- President Roosevelt is seen meeting with Winston Churchill at the Quebec Conference.&quot;

This film is part of the Periscope Film LLC archive, one of the largest historic military, transportation, and aviation stock footage collections in the USA. Entirely film backed, this material is available for licensing in 24p HD, 2k and 4k. For more information visit http://www.PeriscopeFilm.com</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="66" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="1893"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:phK2pUZI0I4</id>
  <yt:videoId>phK2pUZI0I4</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCddem5RlB3bQe99wyY49g0g</yt:channelId>
  <title>&quot; THE CHILD MOLESTER &quot;  1964 PUBLIC SERVICE EDUCATION &amp; SAFETY FILM FOR PARENTS  XD60504</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=phK2pUZI0I4"/>
  <author>
   <name>PeriscopeFilm</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCddem5RlB3bQe99wyY49g0g</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-10-31T16:30:10+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-10-31T16:30:11+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>&quot; THE CHILD MOLESTER &quot;  1964 PUBLIC SERVICE EDUCATION &amp; SAFETY FILM FOR PARENTS  XD60504</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/phK2pUZI0I4?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i1.ytimg.com/vi/phK2pUZI0I4/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>Join this channel to get access to perks:
https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCddem5RlB3bQe99wyY49g0g/join

Want to learn more about Periscope Film and get access to exclusive swag? Join us on Patreon. Visit https://www.patreon.com/PeriscopeFilm
Visit our website www.PeriscopeFilm.com

WARNING: The end of this film contains graphic imagery. Viewer discretion is advised.

The “Child Molester” presented by The Highway Safety Foundation is a public service announcement intended to scare parents into teaching their children about the dangers of child molesters and how they can teach their children to stay safe. The film was directed and written by Herbert J. Leder, who served as a film professor at Jersey City State College's Media Arts Department and who wrote and/or directed several features including the 1969 crime pic &quot;The Candy Man&quot;.

A little girl plays hopscotch on a playground. A shadow of a man appears as she draws with chalk. He pours a bag of jelly beans into her hands. Her friend joins them for some jelly beans. A third little girl appears and says she has to go home. He leads both girls to his car. A woman on a bench watches them get into his car. She shakes her head in worry then in acceptance (1:50). A woman calls her friend to see if her daughter is there. Montage of the normal places her daughter could be. The little girl who didn’t get into the man’s car is looking at a doll in a store window. Two dolls are poised for a tea party. A rabbit jumps out of a baby stroller (4:15). The man pulls his car onto a remote patch of grass. He grabs one girl by the arm while the other girl jumps out of the car and runs away. He chases the girl with the other girl in tow. They run through a wooded area. The girl breaks free from him and runs while the other girl hides behind a tree. Two cops walk into a brick house. They take statements from both sets of parents. A woman in a sleep cap describes her daughter (6:45). The two cops cruise the streets. The woman from the bench drinks tea in her living room. She answers her phone and hears of the missing girls. She peers across the street at the cop car. She runs across the street. The third girl is shown a bag of jelly beans by her mother in their kitchen. The man continues to look for the girls in the woods. The little girl cowards and screams as he approaches. The parents cry at the police station. The missing little girl’s mother recollects memories of her daughter: picking up her baby sibling, watching a chick hatch and two newlyweds getting into a car (12:03). They stand on the sidewalk as a man and a young girl are escorted past them by cops. Close up of her crying. The third girl’s family plays croquet. The family walks down the street while a man on a bench stares. Two men light a cigarette. A girl jumps rope while a man pulls up next to her in a car. The man approaches the girl. A family crosses the street. A man in a suit grabs the arm of a girl and she pulls away. A man puts his hand on the thigh of a young boy in a theatre (15:50). The boy gets up and tells the usher. A man offers a boy money and he refuses. A man in a car asks a girl for directions. A man in a pencil tie and sunglasses approaches a boy outside of his school. The teacher interrupts them. A man finishes a bottle of booze in an alley. He grabs a little boy. A woman gestures to a drawing of a fetus in the womb on a chalk board (17:58). A boy nods. Parents tuck their children into bed. A cop escorts a crying couple out of their house. A girl lies face down in what looks like snow. Very graphic police footage of murdered children. A dirty shoe floats down a river.

We encourage viewers to add comments and, especially, to provide additional information about our videos by adding a comment!  See something interesting?  Tell people what it is and what they can see by writing something for example: &quot;01:00:12:00 -- President Roosevelt is seen meeting with Winston Churchill at the Quebec Conference.&quot;

This film is part of the Periscope Film LLC archive, one of the largest historic military, transportation, and aviation stock footage collections in the USA. Entirely film backed, this material is available for licensing in 24p HD, 2k and 4k. For more information visit http://www.PeriscopeFilm.com</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="109" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="2144"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:wZiULZzTuJY</id>
  <yt:videoId>wZiULZzTuJY</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCddem5RlB3bQe99wyY49g0g</yt:channelId>
  <title>“HALLOWEEN” 1960S ENGLISH LANGUAGE TEACHING FILM     TRICK OR TREAT  XD50184</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wZiULZzTuJY"/>
  <author>
   <name>PeriscopeFilm</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCddem5RlB3bQe99wyY49g0g</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-10-31T16:30:08+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-10-31T16:30:08+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>“HALLOWEEN” 1960S ENGLISH LANGUAGE TEACHING FILM     TRICK OR TREAT  XD50184</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/wZiULZzTuJY?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i4.ytimg.com/vi/wZiULZzTuJY/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>Want to support this channel and help us preserve old films? Visit https://www.patreon.com/PeriscopeFilm
Visit our website www.PeriscopeFilm.com

This short film from 1966 is a scripted educational film that seeks to improve command of the English language for special needs students or students who do not speak English as a first language. Presented by United World Films, inc. as part of the Living Language series this film titled “Halowe’en” uses narration in simple language and subtitles to chronicle the story of elementary school-aged children enjoying the customs and traditions specific to Halloween. The film utilized the expertise of educational consultants of language arts education (ELA) specialists Judit Horvath and Sheila Lowenbraun and was produced and directed by Leonard Peck. It is worth mentioning that the executive producer for the project is John .D. Desmond and the project director is Harold M. Weiner. 

Illuminated jack-o-lantern with overlaid text (0:12). Elementary school-aged children doing halloween crafts at a classroom table on Halloween Day, October 31st (0:21). Young boy presenting paper jack-o-lantern to his teacher (0:59). Little girl shows her drawing of an owl (1:19). Another girl holds up a drawing of a witch on a broomstick (1:27). Teacher gives feedback on the students’ pictures (1:34). Students help each other put on their Halloween costumes (2:20). Students play the game “Pin the Nose on the Jack-o-Lantern” (3:13). Teacher pours out apple cider and students take apple cider donuts and jelly apples (4:02). Positive reactions of students as they eat and drink the refreshments and snacks (6:12). Mother of one of the students, Mary, in her home kitchen taking a freshly-baked pumpkin pie out of the oven (6:35). Mary greets her mother in the kitchen (6:57). Mary and her brothers discussing their costumes for trick or treating later (7:56). Mary’s father comes home carrying two pumpkins (8:22). Mary, her dad, and her siblings carve a jack-o-lantern (9:12). Illuminated jack-o-lantern in windowsill (12:25). Mary dressed as a witch and her brothers dressed as a skeleton and a pirate walking down their driveway in their costumes (12:30). Mary and her brothers pass other trick or treaters and knock on a door for some candy (13:37). 

We encourage viewers to add comments and, especially, to provide additional information about our videos by adding a comment!  See something interesting?  Tell people what it is and what they can see by writing something for example: &quot;01:00:12:00 -- President Roosevelt is seen meeting with Winston Churchill at the Quebec Conference.&quot;

This film is part of the Periscope Film LLC archive, one of the largest historic military, transportation, and aviation stock footage collections in the USA. Entirely film backed, this material is available for licensing in 24p HD, 2k and 4k. For more information visit http://www.PeriscopeFilm.com</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="90" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="2341"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
</feed>
