<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:rdau="http://rdaregistry.info/Elements/u/#" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:swpo="http://sw-portal.deri.org/ontologies/swportal#" xmlns:identifiers="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/identifiers/" xmlns:ebucore="http://www.ebu.ch/metadata/ontologies/ebucore/ebucore#">
<channel>
<title>Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System (U.S.) publications</title>
<description>Economic research and commentary from Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System (U.S.)</description>
<link>https://fedinprint.org/search?facets[]=provider_literal_array:Board+of+Governors+of+the+Federal+Reserve+System+%28U.S.%29</link>
<atom:link href="https://fedinprint.org/search?facets[]=provider_literal_array:Board+of+Governors+of+the+Federal+Reserve+System+%28U.S.%29" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2022 16:29:17 +0000</pubDate>
<item>
<title>Excess Savings during the COVID-19 Pandemic</title>
<link>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedgfn/94961</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[Over the pandemic, historic levels of government transfers boosted household income while household spending was severely curtailed by social distancing. This led the personal saving rate to soar (Figure 1), and we estimate that U.S. households accumulated about $2.3 trillion in savings in 2020 and through the summer of 2021, above and beyond what they would have saved if income and spending components had grown at recent, pre-pandemic trends.]]>
</description>
<guid>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedgfn/94961</guid>
<dc:creator>Feiveson, Laura J.; Cho, David; Aladangady, Aditya; Pinto, Eugénio</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2022-10-21</dc:date>
<swpo:hasNumber>2022-10-21</swpo:hasNumber>
<identifiers:doi>10.17016/2380-7172.3223</identifiers:doi>
<bibo:series>FEDS Notes</bibo:series>
</item>
<item>
<title>Geopolitics and the U.S. Dollar's Future as a Reserve Currency</title>
<link>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedgif/94957/original</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[	I survey the role of geopolitics and sanctions risk in shaping the U.S. dollar's status as the primary currency used for international reserves. Without changes in the economic incentives for holding FX reserves in U.S. dollar assets, an increased threat of sanctions is unlikely to drastically reduce the dollar share of FX reserves. Currently, around three-quarters of foreign government holdings of safe U.S. assets are by countries with some military tie to the U.S. Even a reduced reliance on the U.S. dollar for trade invoicing and debt denomination by a large bloc of countries less geopolitically aligned with the U.S. would be unlikely to end U.S. dollar dominance.]]>
</description>
<guid>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedgif/94957/original</guid>
<dc:creator>Weiss, Colin</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2022-10</dc:date>
<dc:subject>Foreign Exchange Reserves; Sanctions; Security Alliances</dc:subject>
<swpo:hasNumber>1359</swpo:hasNumber>
<identifiers:doi>10.17016/IFDP.2022.1359</identifiers:doi>
<bibo:series>International Finance Discussion Papers</bibo:series>
</item>
<item>
<title>Non-bank financial institutions and the slope of the yield curve</title>
<link>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedgfn/94909</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[In this note, we examine how changes in the yield curve slope affect the provision of credit and intermediation services by non-bank financial institutions (NBFIs), including broker-dealers and hedge funds. Although these NBFIs typically do not lend directly to the non-financial sector, they indirectly support the flow of credit by investing in debt securities and extending financing to investors who own such securities.]]>
</description>
<guid>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedgfn/94909</guid>
<dc:creator>Monin, Phillip J.; Infante, Sebastian; Tian, Mary; Petrasek, Lubomir</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2022-10-11</dc:date>
<swpo:hasNumber>2022-10-11</swpo:hasNumber>
<identifiers:doi>10.17016/2380-7172.3185</identifiers:doi>
<bibo:series>FEDS Notes</bibo:series>
</item>
<item>
<title>Dealer Intermediation in the Primary Market of Commercial Paper</title>
<link>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedgfn/94893</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[The commercial paper (CP) market is an important source of short-term funding for highly-rated financial and nonfinancial firms, with over $1 trillion in outstanding assets. The Global Financial Crisis in 2008 and the COVID-19 crisis in March 2020 both demonstrated the fragility of the CP market, which seized up in both crises and only recovered following interventions from the Federal Reserve in the form of several liquidity facilities.]]>
</description>
<guid>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedgfn/94893</guid>
<dc:creator>Gross, Max; Wang, Ashley W.; Li, Yi</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2022-10-07</dc:date>
<swpo:hasNumber>2022-10-07</swpo:hasNumber>
<identifiers:doi>10.17016/2380-7172.3213</identifiers:doi>
<bibo:series>FEDS Notes</bibo:series>
</item>
<item>
<title>Market Effects of Central Bank Credit Markets Support Programs in Europe</title>
<link>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedgif/94813/original</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[Using responses of credit default swap indexes to ECB monetary policy announcements, we isolate a novel credit policy component of monetary policy surprises. We examine how such unconventional monetary policy surprises affect investor perceptions of credit risk and the functioning of primary corporate debt markets. Favorable credit surprises cause declines in uncertainty about credit risk and suggest a more stable outlook on its dynamics over the following months. Both net and gross corporate bond issuance increase as a result of favorable credit surprises, with the largest response in investment grade issuance. We argue that this provides evidence for the efficacy of a local channel of unconventional monetary policy.]]>
</description>
<guid>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedgif/94813/original</guid>
<dc:creator>Kitsul, Yuriy; Wright, Jonathan H.; Sokolinskiy, Oleg</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2022-08-30</dc:date>
<dc:subject>CDS; Central banks; Credit derivatives; Credit programs; Debt issuance; Uncertainty</dc:subject>
<swpo:hasNumber>1357</swpo:hasNumber>
<identifiers:doi>10.17016/IFDP.2022.1357</identifiers:doi>
<bibo:series>International Finance Discussion Papers</bibo:series>
</item>
<item>
<title>The impact of risk cycles on business cycles: a historical view</title>
<link>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedgif/94806/original</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[We investigate the effects of financial risk cycles on business cycles, using a panel spanning 73 countries since 1900. Agents use a Bayesian learning model to form their beliefs on risk. We construct a proxy of these beliefs and show that perceived low risk encourages risk-taking, augmenting growth at the cost of accumulating financial vulnerabilities, and therefore, a reversal in growth follows. The reversal is particularly pronounced when the low-risk environment persists and credit growth is excessive. Global-risk cycles have a stronger effect on growth than local-risk cycles via their impact on capital flows, investment, and debt-issuer quality.]]>
</description>
<guid>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedgif/94806/original</guid>
<dc:creator>Valenzuela, Marcela; Daníelsson, Jón; Zer, Ilknur</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2022-09-09</dc:date>
<dc:subject>Stock market volatility; Uncertainty; Monetary policy independence; Financial instability; Risk-taking; Global financial cycles</dc:subject>
<swpo:hasNumber>1358</swpo:hasNumber>
<identifiers:doi>10.17016/IFDP.2022.1358</identifiers:doi>
<bibo:series>International Finance Discussion Papers</bibo:series>
</item>
<item>
<title>The coming long-run slowdown in corporate profit growth and stock returns</title>
<link>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedgfn/94797</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[Over the past two decades, the corporate profits of stock market listed firms have been substantially boosted by declining interest rate expenses and lower corporate tax rates. This note's key finding is that the reduction in interest and tax expenses is responsible for a full one-third of all profit growth for S&P 500 nonfinancial firms over the prior two-decade period.]]>
</description>
<guid>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedgfn/94797</guid>
<dc:creator>Smolyansky, Michael</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2022-09-06</dc:date>
<swpo:hasNumber>2022-09-06</swpo:hasNumber>
<identifiers:doi>10.17016/2380-7172.3167</identifiers:doi>
<bibo:series>FEDS Notes</bibo:series>
</item>
<item>
<title>Credit Card Profitability</title>
<link>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedgfn/94794</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[Credit cards are one of the most ubiquitous consumer financial products in the United States, with more than 75 percent of households owning at least one general purpose credit card in 2019. According to the G.19 Consumer Credit Statistical release, revolving consumer credit, which mainly consists of credit cards and related plans, stood at over one trillion dollars at the end of 2021.]]>
</description>
<guid>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedgfn/94794</guid>
<dc:creator>Bord, Vitaly M.; Katcher, Bradley; Adams, Robert M.</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2022-09-09</dc:date>
<swpo:hasNumber>2022-09-09</swpo:hasNumber>
<identifiers:doi>10.17016/2380-7172.3100</identifiers:doi>
<bibo:series>FEDS Notes</bibo:series>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Rise of Nonbanks and the Quality of Financial Services: Evidence from Consumer Complaints</title>
<link>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedgfe/94792/original</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[We show that as nonbanks' market share increases in a local residential mortgage market, the quality of mortgage services in the market improves. Two instrumental variable analyses exploiting (1) stress tests conducted by the Federal Reserve, and (2) mortgage industry surety bonds required by each state confirm this finding. We find evidence that as nonbanks grow their market share, they develop a specialty in servicing lower-income borrowers and increase investment in technology, leading to improved service quality. This improvement in service quality is more salient in counties with a higher percentage of minority populations.]]>
</description>
<guid>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedgfe/94792/original</guid>
<dc:creator>Degerli, Ahmet; Wang, Jing</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2022-09-01</dc:date>
<rdau:hasExtent>66 p.</rdau:hasExtent>
<dc:subject>Product quality; Mortgage lending; Banks; Nonbanks</dc:subject>
<swpo:hasNumber>2022-059</swpo:hasNumber>
<identifiers:doi>10.17016/FEDS.2022.059</identifiers:doi>
<bibo:series>Finance and Economics Discussion Series</bibo:series>
</item>
<item>
<title>Information Externalities, Funding Liquidity, and Fire Sales</title>
<link>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedgfe/94731/original</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[We develop a theory of learning in a model of fire sales and collateralized debt to study how beliefs about fundamentals are shaped by market conditions. Agents exchange short-term debt contracts to invest in a long-term risky asset, and receive shocks to the opportunity cost of funds (cost shocks) and news about the fundamental of the asset, both of which are private information. Asset prices play a dual role of clearing markets and conveying agents' private information, but markets are informationally inefficient: Agents can partially, but never fully, infer their counterparties' private information from asset prices. The informational inefficiency of markets is more acute when liquidity conditions are especially tight or loose, as this impairs ability of prices to reveal private information about fundamentals. As a result, beliefs about fundamentals are shaped endogenously by cost shocks which are orthogonal to fundamentals, leading to socially costly booms and busts in asset prices. The equilibrium is constrained inefficient due to an information externality in which agents do not internalize how their choices affect the information set of other agents. Interventions in funding markets can stabilize asset prices by altering perceptions of risk.]]>
</description>
<guid>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedgfe/94731/original</guid>
<dc:creator>Chang, Jin-Wook; Altinoglu, Levent</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2022-08-15</dc:date>
<rdau:hasExtent>82 p.</rdau:hasExtent>
<dc:subject>Beliefs; Learning; Fire sales; Liquidity; Asset prices; Information asymmetry</dc:subject>
<swpo:hasNumber>2022-052</swpo:hasNumber>
<identifiers:doi>10.17016/FEDS.2022.052</identifiers:doi>
<bibo:series>Finance and Economics Discussion Series</bibo:series>
</item>
<item>
<title>Inflation Measured Every Day Keeps Adverse Responses Away: Temporal Aggregation and Monetary Policy Transmission</title>
<link>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedgfe/94726/original</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[Using daily inflation data from the Billion Prices Project [Cavallo and Rigobon (2016)], we show how temporal aggregation biases estimates of monetary policy transmission. We argue that the information mismatch between private agents and the econometrician —the source of temporal aggregation bias —is equally important as the more studied mismatch between private agents and the central bank (the “Fed information effect”). We find that the adverse response of daily inflation to high-frequency monetary policy shocks is short-lived, if present at all, in impulse responses from both local projections and an unobserved components model of inflation dynamics. To reconcile how one can obtain a sizable adverse response with monthly or quarterly data when only a limited adverse response exists at a higher frequency, we appeal to a simple monetary policy model and show how temporal aggregation bias can exacerbate initial impulse response functions. Because our modeling results are generic and macroeconomic indicators are published with a lag, we argue that temporal aggregation bias will be a key feature of the nascent field of high-frequency macroeconomics.]]>
</description>
<guid>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedgfe/94726/original</guid>
<dc:creator>Matthes, Christian; Walker, Todd B.; Jacobson, Margaret M.</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2022-08-16</dc:date>
<rdau:hasExtent>48 p.</rdau:hasExtent>
<dc:subject>Disaggregated inflation; Billion prices project; High-frequency macroeconomics; Monetary policy transmission; Temporal aggregation bias</dc:subject>
<swpo:hasNumber>2022-054</swpo:hasNumber>
<identifiers:doi>10.17016/FEDS.2022.054</identifiers:doi>
<bibo:series>Finance and Economics Discussion Series</bibo:series>
</item>
<item>
<title>LINVER: The Linear Version of FRB/US</title>
<link>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedgfe/94725/original</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[FRB/US, a large-scale, nonlinear macroeconomic model of the U.S., has been in use at the Federal Reserve Board for 25 years. For nearly as long, the FRB/US “project” has included a linear version of the model known as LINVER. A key reason that LINVER exists is the vast reduction in the computational costs that linearity confers when running experiments requiring large numbers of simulations under the assumption that expectations are model-consistent (MC). The public has been able to download FRB/US simulation code, documentation, and data from the Federal Reserve Board’s website since 2014. To further expand access to and understanding of the FRB/US project, a package devoted to LINVER is now available on the website. In this paper, we provide both a general introduction to LINVER and an overview of the contents and capabilities of its package. We review the ways that LINVER has been used in past research to study key policy issues; describe the package’s comprehensive set of programs for running simulations with MC expectations, with or without imposing the effective lower bound (ELB) on the federal funds rate and other nonlinear constraints; and illustrate how LINVER deterministic and stochastic simulations can be used to gauge the implications of the ELB for macroeconomic performance and to assess different strategies for mitigating its adverse effects.]]>
</description>
<guid>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedgfe/94725/original</guid>
<dc:creator>Brayton, Flint; Reifschneider, David L.</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2022-08-16</dc:date>
<rdau:hasExtent>41 p.</rdau:hasExtent>
<dc:subject>Interest rates; Simulation; Econometric modeling; Monetary policy; Effective lower bound</dc:subject>
<swpo:hasNumber>2022-053</swpo:hasNumber>
<identifiers:doi>10.17016/FEDS.2022.053</identifiers:doi>
<bibo:series>Finance and Economics Discussion Series</bibo:series>
</item>
<item>
<title>How Do U.S. Life Insurers Manage Liquidity in Times of Stress?</title>
<link>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedgfn/94700</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[In this note, we describe U.S. life insurers’ liquidity management when the COVID-19 pandemic broke. We show that life insurance companies immediately created cash buffers to manage potential liquidity shocks.]]>
</description>
<guid>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedgfn/94700</guid>
<dc:creator>Foley-Fisher, Nathan; Heinrich, Nathan; Verani, Stéphane</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2022-08-23</dc:date>
<swpo:hasNumber>2022-08-23</swpo:hasNumber>
<identifiers:doi>10.17016/2380-7172.3161</identifiers:doi>
<bibo:series>FEDS Notes</bibo:series>
</item>
<item>
<title>Debt Overhang and the Retail Apocalypse</title>
<link>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedgif/94699/original</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[Debt overhang is central for theories of capital structure, yet credible empirical estimates of its effects remain elusive. We study the consequences and mechanisms of debt overhang using exogenous changes in the leverage of commercial retail properties. Identification comes from changes in property values occurring after pre-determined debt rollover dates. We show that debt reduces profitability by impairing property owners' response to negative shocks, reducing the business activity of their remaining retail tenants. For the median property, a 10 percentage point leverage increase causes 22% lower employment, mostly in large retail stores, and overall 15% lower operating income.]]>
</description>
<guid>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedgif/94699/original</guid>
<dc:creator>Correa, Ricardo; Liebersohn, Jack; Sicilian, Martin</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2022-08</dc:date>
<dc:subject>commercial real estate; debt overhang; capital structure; commercial mortgage-backed securities; retail properties</dc:subject>
<swpo:hasNumber>1356</swpo:hasNumber>
<identifiers:doi>10.17016/IFDP.2022.1356</identifiers:doi>
<bibo:series>International Finance Discussion Papers</bibo:series>
</item>
<item>
<title>Are Stocks Pricing in Recession Risks? Evidence from Dividend Futures</title>
<link>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedgfn/94670</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[Since the beginning of this year, broad equity price indexes around the world have declined significantly. In interpreting the declines, market commentaries have highlighted the risks to the economic outlook in the United States and other advanced economies.]]>
</description>
<guid>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedgfn/94670</guid>
<dc:creator>Knox, Benjamin; Ibert, Markus F.; Vazquez-Grande, Francisco</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2022-08-18</dc:date>
<swpo:hasNumber>2022-08-18</swpo:hasNumber>
<identifiers:doi>10.17016/2380-7172.3176</identifiers:doi>
<bibo:series>FEDS Notes</bibo:series>
</item>
<item>
<title>Search Frictions, Labor Supply, and the Asymmetric Business Cycle </title>
<link>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedgif/94669/original</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[We develop a business cycle model with search frictions in the labor market and a labor supply decision along the extensive margin that yields cyclical asymmetry between peaks and troughs of the unemployment rate and symmetric fluctuations of the labor force participation rate as in the U.S. data. We calibrate the model and find that cyclical changes in the extent of search frictions are solely responsible for the peak-trough asymmetry. Participation decisions do not generate asymmetry but contribute to the fluctuations in search frictions by changing the size and composition of the pool of job seekers, which in turn affects the tightness ratio and thereby slack in the labor market. The participation rate would be counterfactually asymmetric absent labor supply responses to shocks.]]>
</description>
<guid>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedgif/94669/original</guid>
<dc:creator>Fiori, Giuseppe; Ferraro, Domenico</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2022-08-16</dc:date>
<dc:subject>Asymmetric business cycles; Labor supply; Search frictions; Employment; Unemployment rate; Labor force participation rate</dc:subject>
<swpo:hasNumber>1355</swpo:hasNumber>
<identifiers:doi>10.17016/IFDP.2022.1355</identifiers:doi>
<bibo:series>International Finance Discussion Papers</bibo:series>
</item>
<item>
<title>Working Women in the Pandemic Era: a speech at Arkansas Women's Commission Meeting, Russellville, Arkansas, August 17, 2022</title>
<link>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedgsq/94655</link>
<guid>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedgsq/94655</guid>
<dc:creator>Bowman, Michelle W.</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2022-08-17</dc:date>
<rdau:hasExtent>11</rdau:hasExtent>
<bibo:series>Speech</bibo:series>
</item>
<item>
<title>Technology, Innovation, and Financial Services: a speech at the VenCent Fintech Conference, Little Rock, Arkansas, August 17, 2022</title>
<link>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedgsq/94654</link>
<guid>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedgsq/94654</guid>
<dc:creator>Bowman, Michelle W.</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2022-08-17</dc:date>
<rdau:hasExtent>9</rdau:hasExtent>
<bibo:series>Speech</bibo:series>
</item>
<item>
<title>Long COVID, Cognitive Impairment, and the Stalled Decline in Disability Rates</title>
<link>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedgfn/94653</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[Long COVID encompasses a suite of long-term symptoms that commonly include fatigue, shortness of breath, and so-called brain fog, along with many others. Individuals with long-term symptoms may be unable to work (or work full-time) as a result of their condition, and there is growing speculation that long COVID may be restraining labor supply.]]>
</description>
<guid>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedgfn/94653</guid>
<dc:creator>Price, Brendan M.</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2022-08-05</dc:date>
<swpo:hasNumber>2022-08-05-2</swpo:hasNumber>
<identifiers:doi>10.17016/2380-7172.3189</identifiers:doi>
<bibo:series>FEDS Notes</bibo:series>
</item>
<item>
<title>Loan Modifications and the Commercial Real Estate Market</title>
<link>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedgfe/94622/original</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[Banks modify more CRE loans than CMBS, contributing to better loan performance when property incomes decline. However, banks have higher delinquency rates for less-stressed loans, consistent with modification policies encouraging strategic default. Motivated by these facts, we develop a tradeoff theory model in which lenders vary in their modification technologies. Modification frictions discourage strategic renegotiation, enabling CMBS to offer higher LTV loans and attract borrowers seeking higher leverage. The model produces cross-lender differences in LTVs and spreads consistent with the data. Reducing modification frictions at CMBS decreases welfare by restricting debt capacity for the borrowers that value it most.]]>
</description>
<guid>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedgfe/94622/original</guid>
<dc:creator>Kurtzman, Robert J.; Loewenstein, Lara; Glancy, David P.</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2022-08-08</dc:date>
<rdau:hasExtent>71 p.</rdau:hasExtent>
<dc:subject>Commercial real estate; Modifications; LTV</dc:subject>
<swpo:hasNumber>2022-050</swpo:hasNumber>
<identifiers:doi>10.17016/FEDS.2022.050</identifiers:doi>
<bibo:series>Finance and Economics Discussion Series</bibo:series>
</item>
<item>
<title>Pre-Positioning and Cross-Border Financial Intermediation</title>
<link>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedgfe/94619/original</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[The benefits of cross-border financial activity are wide-ranging, from greater competition and more efficient markets to broader and more stable access to capital. During normal economic times, the official sector and private sector share an incentive to foster such cross-border financial activities. During a financial crisis, however, the short-term alignment of official- and private-sector incentives can divergeâ€”sometimes significantly. We present a game-theoretic model of the underlying trade-offs and discuss lessons for international financial regulators, placing them in the context of the 2008 financial crisis, when challenges in cross-border cooperation both channeled and amplified financial stress. We also discuss the critical unfinished business of post-crisis regulatory measures to improve oversight of internationally active financial institutions.]]>
</description>
<guid>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedgfe/94619/original</guid>
<dc:creator>Zhang, Jeffery Y.; Tabor, Nicholas K.</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2022-08-09</dc:date>
<rdau:hasExtent>22 p.</rdau:hasExtent>
<dc:subject>Bank Capital; Bank Liquidity; Cross-Border Finance; Market Fragmentation; Pre-Positioning</dc:subject>
<swpo:hasNumber>2022-051</swpo:hasNumber>
<identifiers:doi>10.17016/FEDS.2022.051</identifiers:doi>
<bibo:series>Finance and Economics Discussion Series</bibo:series>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Economics of Sovereign Debt, Bailouts and the Eurozone Crisis</title>
<link>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedgif/94615/original</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[Despite a formal 'no-bailout clause; we estimate significant net present value transfers from the European Union to Cyprus, Greece, Ireland, Portugal, and Spain, ranging from roughly 0.5% (Ireland) to a whopping 43% (Greece) of2010 output during the Eurozone crisis. We propose a model to analyze and understand bailouts in a monetary union, and the large observed differences across countries. We characterize bailout size and likelihood as a function of the economic fundamentals (economic activity, debt-to-gdp ratio, default costs). Our model embeds a 'Southern view' of the crisis (transfers did not help) and a 'Northern view' (transfers weaken fiscal discipline). While a stronger no-bailout commitment reduces risk-shifting, it may not be optimal from the perspective of the creditor country, even ex-ante, if it increases the risk of immediate insolvency for high debt countries. Hence, the model provides a potential justification for the often decried policy of 'kicking the can down the road.' Mapping the model to the estimated transfers, we find that the main purpose of the outsized Greek bailout was to prevent an exit from the eurozone and possible contagion. Bailouts to avoid sovereign default were comparatively modest.]]>
</description>
<guid>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedgif/94615/original</guid>
<dc:creator>Martin, Philippe; Gourinchas, Pierre-Olivier; Messer, Todd</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2022-08-03</dc:date>
<dc:subject>Euro area; Monetary union; Sovereign debt; Sovereign default; Debt monetization</dc:subject>
<swpo:hasNumber>1351</swpo:hasNumber>
<identifiers:doi>10.17016/IFDP.2022.1351</identifiers:doi>
<bibo:series>International Finance Discussion Papers</bibo:series>
</item>
<item>
<title>Financial Failure and Depositor Quality: Evidence from Building and Loan Associations in California</title>
<link>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedgif/94614/original</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[Flightiness, or depositor sensitivity to liquidity needs, can be an important determinant of financial distress. I leverage institutional differences that attract depositors with varying flightiness across building and loan associations in California during the Great Depression. A new type of plan, the Dayton plan, involved less restrictive savings plans and lower withdrawal penalties. Dayton plans in California were more likely to close during the Great Depression. Archival evidence on lending rates and returns supports the flightiness mechanism.]]>
</description>
<guid>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedgif/94614/original</guid>
<dc:creator>Messer, Todd</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2022-08-08</dc:date>
<dc:subject>Bank Failures; Banks, credit unions, and other financial institutions; Building and Loan; Great Depression</dc:subject>
<swpo:hasNumber>1354</swpo:hasNumber>
<identifiers:doi>10.17016/IFDP.2022.1354</identifiers:doi>
<bibo:series>International Finance Discussion Papers</bibo:series>
</item>
<item>
<title>Pandemic Priors</title>
<link>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedgif/94587/original</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[The onset of the COVID-19 pandemic and the great lockdown caused macroeconomic variables to display complex patterns that hardly follow any historical behavior. In the context of Bayesian VARs, an off-the-shelf exercise demonstrates how a very low number of extreme pandemic observations bias the estimated persistence of the variables, affecting forecasts and giving a myopic view of the economic effects after a structural shock. I propose an easy and straightforward solution to deal with these extreme episodes, as an extension of the Minnesota Prior with dummy observations by allowing for time dummies. The Pandemic Priors succeed in recovering these historical relationships and the proper identification and propagation of structural shocks.]]>
</description>
<guid>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedgif/94587/original</guid>
<dc:creator>Cascaldi-Garcia, Danilo</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2022-08-03</dc:date>
<dc:subject>Bayesian VAR; Minnesota Prior; COVID-19; Structural shocks</dc:subject>
<swpo:hasNumber>1352</swpo:hasNumber>
<identifiers:doi>10.17016/IFDP.2022.1352</identifiers:doi>
<bibo:series>International Finance Discussion Papers</bibo:series>
</item>
<item>
<title>Insights from revised Form FR2004 into primary dealer securities financing and MBS activity</title>
<link>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedgfn/94578</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[The Primary Government Securities Dealers Reports (Form FR 2004) collect information at a weekly frequency on daily positions, cumulative transactions, financing, and fails of primary dealers in U.S. government and other fixed-income securities. The reports have been revised as of January 5, 2022 to increase the granularity of reporting. ]]>
</description>
<guid>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedgfn/94578</guid>
<dc:creator>Infante, Sebastian; Petrasek, Lubomir; Tian, Mary; Saravay, Zack</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2022-08-05</dc:date>
<swpo:hasNumber>2022-08-05-1</swpo:hasNumber>
<identifiers:doi>10.17016/2380-7172.3182</identifiers:doi>
<bibo:series>FEDS Notes</bibo:series>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>