<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:rdau="http://rdaregistry.info/Elements/u/#" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:swpo="http://sw-portal.deri.org/ontologies/swportal#" xmlns:identifiers="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/identifiers/" xmlns:ebucore="http://www.ebu.ch/metadata/ontologies/ebucore/ebucore#">
<channel>
<title>Federal Reserve Bank of Minneapolis publications</title>
<description>Economic research and commentary from Federal Reserve Bank of Minneapolis</description>
<link>https://fedinprint.org/search?facets[]=provider_literal_array:Federal+Reserve+Bank+of+Minneapolis</link>
<atom:link href="https://fedinprint.org/search?facets[]=provider_literal_array:Federal+Reserve+Bank+of+Minneapolis" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2022 16:27:56 +0000</pubDate>
<item>
<title>The Distributional Impact of the Minimum Wage in the Short and Long Run</title>
<link>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedmsr/94531</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[We develop a framework with rich worker heterogeneity, firm monopsony power, and putty-clay technology to study the distributional impact of the minimum wage in the short and long run. Our production technology is disciplined to be consistent with the small estimated employment effects of the minimum wage in the short run and the large estimated elasticities of substitution across inputs in the long run. We find that in the short run, a large increase in the minimum wage has a small effect on employment and therefore increases the labor income of the workers who were earning less than the new minimum wage. In the long run, however, the minimum wage has perverse distributional implications in that it reduces the employment, income, and welfare of precisely the low-income workers it is meant to help. Nonetheless, these long-run effects take time to fully materialize because firms slowly adjust their mix of inputs. Existing transfer programs, such as the earned income tax credit (EITC), are more effective at improving long-run outcomes for workers at the low end of the wage distribution. But combining existing programs with a modest increase in the minimum wage generates even larger welfare gains for low-earning workers.]]>
</description>
<guid>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedmsr/94531</guid>
<dc:creator>Kehoe, Patrick J.; Hurst, Erik; Pastorino, Elena; Winberry, Thomas</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2022-07-14</dc:date>
<dc:subject>Employment; Earned income tax credit; Progressive tax and transfer system; Monopsony; Putty-clay capital; Inequality; Unemployment; Labor market participation; Labor income; Redistribution; Monopsonistic competition; Wages; Search frictions</dc:subject>
<swpo:hasNumber>640</swpo:hasNumber>
<identifiers:doi>10.21034/sr.640</identifiers:doi>
<bibo:series>Staff Report</bibo:series>
</item>
<item>
<title>Minimum Wages and Labor Markets in the Twin Cities</title>
<link>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedmwp/94530/original</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[Using merged administrative datasets from Minnesota, we bring new evidence on the labor market effects of large minimum wage increases by examining the policy changes implemented by Minneapolis and Saint Paul. We begin by using synthetic difference-in-differences methods to estimate counterfactual outcomes at the zip code level from Minnesota and at the city level from the rest of the country. The minimum wage did not affect employment in most industries but exerted a negative impact on restaurants' employment, with an elasticity of -0.8. Next, using variation in exposure to the minimum wage across establishments and workers within the Twin Cities, we find employment effects that are half as large as those from the time series. The cross-sectional estimates difference out employment effects from the pandemic or civil unrest that could confound the time series comparisons, but they do not include potential effects of the minimum wage operating through equilibrium adjustments such as entry. We quantify a model of establishment dynamics to reconcile the different estimates and argue that they plausibly reflect lower and upper bounds of employment losses. We use the model to show that our estimates are consistent with an establishment elasticity of labor demand of -1 and illustrate how they can inform deeper parameters characterizing product and labor market competition, factor substitution, and establishment dynamics.]]>
</description>
<guid>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedmwp/94530/original</guid>
<dc:creator>Nath, Anusha; Karabarbounis, Loukas; Lise, Jeremy</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2022-07-07</dc:date>
<dc:subject>Wages; Hours; Jobs; Minimum wage</dc:subject>
<swpo:hasNumber>793</swpo:hasNumber>
<identifiers:doi>10.21034/wp.793</identifiers:doi>
<bibo:series>Working Papers</bibo:series>
</item>
<item>
<title>Long-Haulers and Labor Market Outcomes</title>
<link>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedmoi/94528/original</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[There have been growing concerns about long-haulers or individuals with long-term COVID-19 health complications (long-haul COVID). While the medical field has been investigating the health complications, there has been limited research on the relationship between long-haul COVID and labor market outcomes. To investigate this relationship, I used the University of Southern California Understanding America Study COVID-19 longitudinal survey to provide a snapshot of mid-2021. I first find about 24.1% of individuals who have had COVID are long-haulers and 25.9% of long-haulers reported that their long-haul COVID affected employment or work hours. I then find that a majority of these affected long-haulers remained employed and in same employment type. But I find that their mean change in work hours and paycheck declined. Afterwards, I tested whether long-haul COVID is associated with negative changes in labor market outcomes. When I combined long-haulers who reported that their health complications did or did not affect work, I failed to find that long-haulers are less likely to be employed relative to individuals without prior COVID infection. But, when I discern long-haulers by whether long-haul COVID affected work, I find that long-haulers who reported long-haul COVID affected work are 10 percentage points less likely to be employed and, on average, work 50% fewer hours than individuals without prior COVID infection. In contrast, I failed to find evidence that affected long-haulers receive a lower paycheck earning relative to individuals without prior COVID infection. Lastly, when comparing these affected long-haulers against similar individuals, I find evidence that they are more impacted in their employed status and work hours. Due to limitations, future data collection and research would provide a more robust picture.]]>
</description>
<guid>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedmoi/94528/original</guid>
<dc:creator>Ham, Dasom I.</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2022-07-07</dc:date>
<dc:subject>Labor market outcomes; Long-COVID</dc:subject>
<swpo:hasNumber>060</swpo:hasNumber>
<identifiers:doi>10.21034/iwp.60</identifiers:doi>
<bibo:series>Opportunity and Inclusive Growth Institute Working Papers</bibo:series>
</item>
<item>
<title>The End of Privilege: A Reexamination of the Net Foreign Asset Position of the United States</title>
<link>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedmsr/94111</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[The US net foreign asset position has deteriorated sharply since 2007 and is currently negative 65 percent of US GDP. This deterioration primarily reflects changes in the relative values of large gross international equity positions, as opposed to net new borrowing. In particular, a sharp increase in equity prices that has been US-specific has inflated the value of US foreign liabilities. We develop an international macro finance model to interpret these trends, and we argue that the rise in equity prices in the United States likely reflects rising profitability of domestic firms rather than a substantial accumulation of unmeasured capital by those firms. Under that interpretation, the revaluation effects that have driven down the US net foreign asset position are associated with large, unanticipated transfers of US output to foreign investors.]]>
</description>
<guid>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedmsr/94111</guid>
<dc:creator>Atkeson, Andrew; Heathcote, Jonathan; Perri, Fabrizio</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2022-04-25</dc:date>
<dc:subject>Global imbalances; Current account; Equity markets</dc:subject>
<swpo:hasNumber>639</swpo:hasNumber>
<identifiers:doi>10.21034/sr.639</identifiers:doi>
<bibo:series>Staff Report</bibo:series>
</item>
<item>
<title>On Wars, Sanctions and Sovereign Default</title>
<link>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedmwp/94110/original</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[This paper explores the role of restrictions on the use of international reserves as economic sanctions. We develop a simple model of the strategic game between a sanctioning (creditor) country and a sanctioned (debtor) country. We show how the sanctioning country should impose restrictions optimally, internalizing the geopolitical benefits and the financial costs of a potential default from the sanctioned country.]]>
</description>
<guid>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedmwp/94110/original</guid>
<dc:creator>Sosa-Padilla, César; Bianchi, Javier</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2022-04-26</dc:date>
<dc:subject>Wars; International reserves; Financial sanctions; Sovereign default</dc:subject>
<swpo:hasNumber>792</swpo:hasNumber>
<identifiers:doi>10.21034/wp.792</identifiers:doi>
<bibo:series>Working Papers</bibo:series>
</item>
<item>
<title>Minimum Wages, Efficiency and Welfare</title>
<link>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedmoi/93936/original</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[It has long been argued that a minimum wage could alleviate efficiency losses from monopsony power. In a general equilibrium framework that quantitatively replicates results from recent empirical studies, we find higher minimum wages can improve welfare, but most welfare gains stem from redistribution rather than efficiency. Our model features oligopsonistic labor markets with heterogeneous workers and firms and yields analytical expressions that characterize the mechanisms by which minimum wages can improve efficiency, and how these deteriorate at higher minimum wages. We provide a method to separate welfare gains into two channels: efficiency and redistribution. Under both channels and Utilitarian social welfare weights the optimal minimum wage is $15, but alternative weights can rationalize anything from $0 to $31. Under only the efficiency channel, the optimal minimum wage is narrowly around $8, robust to social welfare weights, and generates small welfare gains that recover only 2 percent of the efficiency losses from monopsony power.]]>
</description>
<guid>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedmoi/93936/original</guid>
<dc:creator>Mongey, Simon; Berger, David W.; Herkenhoff, Kyle F.</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2022-04-06</dc:date>
<dc:subject>minimum wages; Oligopsony; Labor markets; Market structure</dc:subject>
<swpo:hasNumber>058</swpo:hasNumber>
<identifiers:doi>10.21034/iwp.58</identifiers:doi>
<bibo:series>Opportunity and Inclusive Growth Institute Working Papers</bibo:series>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Global Distribution of College Graduate Quality</title>
<link>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedmwp/93935/original</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[We measure college graduate quality — the average human capital of a college’s graduates—using the average earnings of the college’s graduates adjusted to a common labor market. Our implementation uses the database of the website Glassdoor, which has the necessary information on earnings and education for non-migrants and migrants who graduate from roughly 3,300 colleges in 66 countries. Graduates of colleges in the richest countries have 50 percent more human capital than graduates of colleges in the poorest countries. Migration reinforces these differences. Poorer countries do not just lose a higher share of their skilled workers; their emigrants are highly positively selected on human capital. Finally, we show that these stocks and flows matter for growth and development by showing that college graduate quality predicts the share of a college’s students who become inventors, engage in entrepreneurship, and become top executives, both within and across countries.]]>
</description>
<guid>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedmwp/93935/original</guid>
<dc:creator>Martellini, Paolo; Sockin, Jason A.; Schoellman, Todd</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2022-03-07</dc:date>
<dc:subject>Human capital; Entrepreneurship; Migration; Development; Innovation; College quality</dc:subject>
<swpo:hasNumber>791</swpo:hasNumber>
<identifiers:doi>10.21034/wp.791</identifiers:doi>
<bibo:series>Working Papers</bibo:series>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Incredible Taylor Principle</title>
<link>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedmwp/93934/original</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[This note addresses the role of the Taylor principle to solve the indeterminacy of equilibria in economies in which the monetary authority follows an interest rate rule. We first study the role of imposing two additional ad-hoc restrictions on the definition of equilibrium. Imposing the equilibrium to be locally unique never delivers a unique outcome. Imposing the equilibrium to be bounded, renders the outcome unique only if the inflation target is the Friedman rule. Second, we show that the Taylor principle is strongly time inconsistent - in a sense we make very precise - and that policies that implement the Friedman rule are the only sustainable policies.]]>
</description>
<guid>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedmwp/93934/original</guid>
<dc:creator>Nicolini, Juan Pablo; Neumeyer, Pablo Andrés</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2022-01-28</dc:date>
<dc:subject>Taylor principle; Uniqueness of equilibrium; Time consistency</dc:subject>
<swpo:hasNumber>790</swpo:hasNumber>
<identifiers:doi>10.21034/wp.790</identifiers:doi>
<bibo:series>Working Papers</bibo:series>
</item>
<item>
<title>Online Appendix for: How Do Voters Respond to Welfare vis-à-vis Public Good Programs? An Empirical Test for Clientelism</title>
<link>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedmsr/93933</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[This appendix accompanies Staff Report 605: How Do Voters Respond to Welfare vis-à-vis Public Good Programs? An Empirical Test for Clientelism.]]>
</description>
<guid>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedmsr/93933</guid>
<dc:creator>Mitra, Sandip; Nath, Anusha; Mookherjee, Dilip; Bardhan, Pranab</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2022-03-17</dc:date>
<dc:subject>Public goods; Voting; Clientelism; Welfare programs</dc:subject>
<swpo:hasNumber>638</swpo:hasNumber>
<identifiers:doi>10.21034/sr.638</identifiers:doi>
<bibo:series>Staff Report</bibo:series>
</item>
<item>
<title>Appendix for: Optimal Cooperative Taxation in the Global Economy</title>
<link>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedmsr/93932</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[This appendix accompanies Staff Report 581: Optimal Cooperative Taxation in the Global Economy.]]>
</description>
<guid>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedmsr/93932</guid>
<dc:creator>Teles, Pedro; Nicolini, Juan Pablo; Chari, V. V.</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2022-03-07</dc:date>
<dc:subject>Capital income tax; Border adjustment; Origin- and destination-based taxation; Value-added taxes; Production efficiency; Free trade</dc:subject>
<swpo:hasNumber>637</swpo:hasNumber>
<identifiers:doi>10.21034/sr.637</identifiers:doi>
<bibo:series>Staff Report</bibo:series>
</item>
<item>
<title>When Do Informational Interventions Work? Experimental Evidence from New York City High School Choice</title>
<link>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedmoi/93794/original</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[This paper reports the results of a large, school-level randomized controlled trial evaluating a set of three informational interventions for young people choosing high schools in 473 middle schools, serving over 115,000 8th graders. The interventions differed in their level of customization to the student and their mode of delivery (paper or online); all treated schools received identical materials to scaffold the decision-making process. Every intervention reduced likelihood of application to and enrollment in schools with graduation rates below the city median (75 percent). An important channel is their effect on reducing nonoptimal first choice application strategies. Providing a simplified, middle-school specific list of relatively high graduation rate schools had the largest impacts, causing students to enroll in high schools with 1.5-percentage point higher graduation rates. Providing the same information online, however, did not alter students’ choices or enrollment. This appears to be due to low utilization. Online interventions with individual customization, including a recommendation tool and search engine, induced students to enroll in high schools with 1-percentage point higher graduation rates, but with more variance in impact. Together, these results show that successful informational interventions must generate engagement with the material, and this is possible through multiple channels.]]>
</description>
<guid>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedmoi/93794/original</guid>
<dc:creator>Sattin-Bajaj, Carolyn; Corcoran, Sean P.; Jennings, Jennifer; Cohodes, Sarah</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2022-02-01</dc:date>
<dc:subject>Informational interventions; Inequality; Decision-making; School choice</dc:subject>
<swpo:hasNumber>057</swpo:hasNumber>
<identifiers:doi>10.21034/iwp.57</identifiers:doi>
<bibo:series>Opportunity and Inclusive Growth Institute Working Papers</bibo:series>
</item>
<item>
<title>Changing Stability in U.S. Employment Relationships: A Tale of Two Tails</title>
<link>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedmoi/93792/original</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[We examine how the distribution of employment tenure has changed in aggregate and for various demographic groups, drawing links to trends in job stability and satisfaction. The fraction of workers with short tenure (less than a year) has been falling since at least the mid-1990s, consistent with the decline in job changing documented over this period. The decline in short-tenure was widespread across demographic groups, industry, and occupation. It appears to be associated with fewer workers cycling among briefly-held jobs and coincides with an increase in perceived job security among short tenure workers. Meanwhile, the fraction of workers with long tenure (20 years or more) has been rising modestly since the early 1980s owing to an increase in long tenure for women and the ageing of the population. The rise in long tenure for women was broad-based across industries and occupations but limited to married women. By contrast, long tenure has declined markedly among older men. This is only partly explained by changing demographics and employment patterns such as the decline in manufacturing and unionization. In addition, an increase in mid-career separations during the 1970s and 1980s appears to have reduced the likelihood of reaching long-tenure for men. Survey evidence indicates that – despite these substantive changes over time – longer-tenure workers report no greater concern about job insecurity or decreases in job satisfaction than four decades ago.]]>
</description>
<guid>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedmoi/93792/original</guid>
<dc:creator>Smith, Christopher L.; Molloy, Raven S.; Wozniak, Abigail</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2022-01-28</dc:date>
<dc:subject>Tenure distribution; New hires; Turnover; Retention; Long tenure; Job tenure</dc:subject>
<swpo:hasNumber>056</swpo:hasNumber>
<identifiers:doi>10.21034/iwp.56</identifiers:doi>
<bibo:series>Opportunity and Inclusive Growth Institute Working Papers</bibo:series>
</item>
<item>
<title>Optimal Age-Based Vaccination and Economic Mitigation Policies for the Second Phase of the Covid-19 Pandemic</title>
<link>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedmsr/93646</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[In this paper, we ask how to best allocate a given time-varying supply of vaccines across individuals of different ages during the second phase of the Covid-19 pandemic . Building on our previous heterogeneous household model of optimal economic mitigation and redistribution (Glover et al., 2021), we contrast the actual vaccine deployment path, which prioritized older, retired individuals, with one that first vaccinates younger workers. Vaccinating the old first saves more lives but slows the economic recovery, relative to inoculating the young first. Vaccines deliver large welfare benefits in both scenarios (relative to a world without vaccines), but the old-first policy is optimal under a utilitarian social welfare function. The welfare gains from having vaccinated the old first are especially significant once the economy is hit by a more infectious Delta variant in the summer of 2021.]]>
</description>
<guid>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedmsr/93646</guid>
<dc:creator>Heathcote, Jonathan; Krueger, Dirk; Glover, Andrew</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2022-01-18</dc:date>
<dc:subject>COVID-19; Vaccination paths</dc:subject>
<swpo:hasNumber>636</swpo:hasNumber>
<identifiers:doi>10.21034/sr.636</identifiers:doi>
<bibo:series>Staff Report</bibo:series>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Welfare Effects of Encouraging Rural-Urban Migration</title>
<link>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedmsr/93606</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[This paper studies the welfare effects of encouraging rural-urban migration in the developing world. To do so, we build and analyze a dynamic general-equilibrium model of migration that features a rich set of migration motives. We estimate the model to replicate the results of a field experiment that subsidized seasonal migration in rural Bangladesh, leading to significant increases in migration and consumption. We show that the welfare gains from migration subsidies come from providing better insurance for vulnerable rural households rather than correcting spatial misallocation by relaxing credit constraints for those with high productivity in urban areas that are stuck in rural areas.]]>
</description>
<guid>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedmsr/93606</guid>
<dc:creator>Mobarak, Mushfiq; Waugh, Michael E.; Lagakos, David</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2022-01-04</dc:date>
<dc:subject>Risk; Insurance; Rural-urban gaps; Field experiment; Rural-urban migration; Spatial misallocation</dc:subject>
<swpo:hasNumber>635</swpo:hasNumber>
<identifiers:doi>10.21034/sr.635</identifiers:doi>
<bibo:series>Staff Report</bibo:series>
</item>
<item>
<title>Dynamic Urn-Ball Discovery</title>
<link>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedmwp/93520/original</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[Under certain assumptions, monopolistic competition with CES preferences is efficient, as first discovered by Dixit and Stiglitz. One assumption, invariably left implicit, is that there are, at any given point in time, no bounds on the number of products that can be discovered. But square wheels do not work, and round wheels keep getting rediscovered. Giving away patents to entrepreneurs who happen to be the first to discover a product generates an inefficiently large amount of variety. The stock of undiscovered products is a commons that can attract too many discovery attempts. Perpetual patents can be efficient, but only when combined with just the right tax on patent-protected monopoly profits. Such a tax is, however, too crude an instrument in an economy with even the least amount of heterogeneity.]]>
</description>
<guid>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedmwp/93520/original</guid>
<dc:creator>Luttmer, Erzo G. J.</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2021-12-20</dc:date>
<rdau:hasExtent>35</rdau:hasExtent>
<dc:subject>Gains from variety; Long-run growth; Patents</dc:subject>
<swpo:hasNumber>789</swpo:hasNumber>
<identifiers:doi>10.21034/wp.789</identifiers:doi>
<bibo:series>Working Papers</bibo:series>
</item>
<item>
<title>Online Appendix for: Two Illustrations of the Quantity Theory of Money Reloaded</title>
<link>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedmsr/93496</link>
<guid>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedmsr/93496</guid>
<dc:creator>Nicolini, Juan Pablo; Gao, Han; Kulish, Mariano</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2021-12-17</dc:date>
<rdau:hasExtent>22</rdau:hasExtent>
<dc:subject>Monetary policy; Monetary aggregates; Money demand</dc:subject>
<swpo:hasNumber>634</swpo:hasNumber>
<identifiers:doi>10.21034/sr.634</identifiers:doi>
<bibo:series>Staff Report</bibo:series>
</item>
<item>
<title>Two Illustrations of the Quantity Theory of Money Reloaded</title>
<link>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedmsr/93495</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[In this paper, we review the relationship between inflation rates, nominal interest rates, and rates of growth of monetary aggregates for a large group of OECD countries. If persistent changes in the monetary policy regime are accounted for, the behavior of these series maintains the close relationship predicted by standard quantity theory models. With an estimated model, we show those relationships to be relatively invariant to alternative frictions that can deliver quite different high-frequency dynamics. We also show that the low-frequency component of the data derived from statistical filters does reasonably well in capturing these regime changes. We conclude that the quantity theory relationships are alive and well, and thus they are useful for policy design aimed at controlling inflation.]]>
</description>
<guid>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedmsr/93495</guid>
<dc:creator>Kulish, Mariano; Gao, Han; Nicolini, Juan Pablo</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2021-12-17</dc:date>
<rdau:hasExtent>50</rdau:hasExtent>
<dc:subject>Money demand; Monetary aggregates; Monetary policy</dc:subject>
<swpo:hasNumber>633</swpo:hasNumber>
<identifiers:doi>10.21034/sr.633</identifiers:doi>
<bibo:series>Staff Report</bibo:series>
</item>
<item>
<title>COVID-19 Vaccination and Financial Frictions</title>
<link>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedmsr/93491</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[We study the COVID-19 epidemic in emerging markets that face financial frictions and its mitigation through social distancing and vaccination. We find that restricted vaccine availability in emerging markets, as captured by limited quantities and high prices, renders the pandemic exceptionally costly compared to economies without financial frictions. Improved access to financial markets enables better response to the delay in vaccine supplies, as it supports more stringent social distancing measures prior to wider vaccine availability. We show that financial assistance programs to such financially constrained countries can increase vaccinations and lower fatalities, at no present-value cost to the international community.]]>
</description>
<guid>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedmsr/93491</guid>
<dc:creator>Arellano, Cristina; Mihalache, Gabriel; Bai, Yan</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2021-12-15</dc:date>
<dc:subject>Fiscal space; Vaccination; Financial market conditions; COVID-19</dc:subject>
<swpo:hasNumber>632</swpo:hasNumber>
<identifiers:doi>10.21034/sr.632</identifiers:doi>
<bibo:series>Staff Report</bibo:series>
</item>
<item>
<title>Constructing Pure-Exchange Economies with Many Equilibria</title>
<link>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedmsr/93490</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[We develop a restart algorithm based on Scarf’s (1973) algorithm for computing approximate Brouwer fixed points. We use the algorithm to compute all of the equilibria of a general equilibrium pure-exchange model with four consumers, four goods, and 15 equilibria. The mathematical result that motivates the algorithm is a fixed-point index theorem that provides a sufficient condition for uniqueness of equilibrium and a necessary condition for multiplicity of equilibria. Examining the structure of the model with 15 equilibria provides us with a method for constructing higher dimensional models with even more equilibria. For example, using our method, we can construct a pure-exchange economy with eight consumers and eight goods that has (at least) 255 equilibria.]]>
</description>
<guid>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedmsr/93490</guid>
<dc:creator>Quintin, Erwan; Kehoe, Timothy J.; Gauthier, Pascal</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2021-12-13</dc:date>
<dc:subject>Uniqueness of equilibrium; Multiplicity of equilibrium; Computation of equilibrium</dc:subject>
<swpo:hasNumber>631</swpo:hasNumber>
<identifiers:doi>10.21034/sr.631</identifiers:doi>
<bibo:series>Staff Report</bibo:series>
</item>
<item>
<title>Changing Income Risk across the US Skill Distribution: Evidence from a Generalized Kalman Filter</title>
<link>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedmoi/93489/original</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[For whom has earnings risk changed, and why? To answer these questions, we develop a filtering method that estimates parameters of an income process and recovers persistent and temporary earnings for every individual at every point in time. Our estimation flexibly allows for first and second moments of shocks to depend upon observables as well as spells of zero earnings (i.e., unemployment) and easily integrates into theoretical models. We apply our filter to a unique linkage of 23.5m SSA-CPS records. We first demonstrate that our earnings-based filter successfully captures observable shocks in the SSA-CPS data, such as job switching and layoffs. We then show that despite a decline in overall earnings risk since the 1980s, persistent earnings risk has risen for both employed and unemployed workers, while temporary earnings risk declined. Furthermore, the size of persistent earnings losses associated with full year unemployment has increased by 50%. Using geography, education, and occupation information in the SSA-CPS records, we refute hypotheses related to declining employment prospects among routine and low-skill workers as well as spatial theories related to the decline of the Rust-Belt. We show that rising persistent earnings risk is concentrated among high-skill workers and related to technology adoption. Lastly, we find that rising persistent earnings risk while employed (unemployed) leads to welfare losses equivalent to 1.8% (0.7%) of lifetime consumption, and larger persistent earnings losses while unemployed lead to a 3.3% welfare loss.]]>
</description>
<guid>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedmoi/93489/original</guid>
<dc:creator>Braxton, John Carter; Herkenhoff, Kyle F.; Rothbaum, Jonathan; Schmidt, Lawrence</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2021-12-15</dc:date>
<dc:subject>Earnings risk; Transitory risk; Persistent risk; Technology adoption; Unemployment</dc:subject>
<swpo:hasNumber>55</swpo:hasNumber>
<identifiers:doi>10.21034/iwp.55</identifiers:doi>
<bibo:series>Opportunity and Inclusive Growth Institute Working Papers</bibo:series>
</item>
<item>
<title>Social Transfers and Spatial Distortions</title>
<link>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedmoi/93474/original</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[US social transfer programs vary substantially across states, incentivizing households to locate in states with more generous transfer programs. Further, transfer formulas often decrease in income, therefore rewarding low-income households for living in low-paying cities. We quantify these distortions by combining a spatial equilibrium model with a detailed model of transfer programs in the US. The current system leads to locational inefficiency of 4.38% of total transfer spending. A reform that both harmonizes transfer policies across states and indexes household income to local average earnings reduces this inefficiency by over 85 percent while still preserving the programs' means-tested nature.]]>
</description>
<guid>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedmoi/93474/original</guid>
<dc:creator>McDonough, Robert; Colas, Mark</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2021-11-17</dc:date>
<rdau:hasExtent>81</rdau:hasExtent>
<dc:subject>Social transfers; Local labor markets; Spatial equilibrium</dc:subject>
<swpo:hasNumber>54</swpo:hasNumber>
<identifiers:doi>10.21034/iwp.54</identifiers:doi>
<bibo:series>Opportunity and Inclusive Growth Institute Working Papers</bibo:series>
</item>
<item>
<title>Disparate Impacts of Job Loss by Parental Income and Implications for Intergenerational Mobility</title>
<link>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedmoi/93473/original</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[Does job loss cause less economic damage if your parents are higher-income, and what are the implications for intergenerational mobility? In this paper we show that following a layoff, adult children born to parents in the bottom 20% of the income distribution have almost double the unemployment compared with those born to parents in the top 20%, with 118% higher present discounted value losses in earnings. Next, we show that these disparate impacts of job loss have important implications for inequality and intergenerational mobility. They increase the 80:20 income inequality ratio for those impacted by 8% and increase the rank-rank coefficient by 34%, implying large reductions in intergenerational mobility. In a simulation based on our main results, we show that the age 40 rank-rank correlation is 3.9% higher due to the disparate impact and incidence of job loss over the preceding decade. In the last part of the paper, we explore mechanisms and show that "baked in" advantages play an important role in explaining these differences.]]>
</description>
<guid>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedmoi/93473/original</guid>
<dc:creator>Riukula, Krista; Nix, Emily; Kaila, Martti</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2021-09-13</dc:date>
<rdau:hasExtent>74</rdau:hasExtent>
<dc:subject>Intergenerational mobility; Job loss</dc:subject>
<swpo:hasNumber>53</swpo:hasNumber>
<identifiers:doi>10.21034/iwp.53</identifiers:doi>
<bibo:series>Opportunity and Inclusive Growth Institute Working Papers</bibo:series>
</item>
<item>
<title>Telework, Childcare, and Mothers’ Labor Supply</title>
<link>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedmoi/93472/original</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[We study the impact of increased pandemic-related childcare responsibilities on custodial mothers by telework compatibility of their job. We estimate changes in employment outcomes of these mothers in a difference-in-difference framework relative to prime-age women without children and a triple-difference framework relative to prime-age custodial fathers. Mothers' labor force participation decreased between 0.1 to 1.5 percentage points (ppts) relative to women without dependent children and 0.3 to 2.0 ppts compared to custodial fathers. Conditional on being in the labor force, the probability of being unemployed fell by 0.7 ppts relative to childless women. Conditional on being employed, leave take-up increased by 0.7 ppts. These patterns were especially prominent among custodial mothers with a college degree or higher in telework-compatible jobs. Compared to women without children, mothers working as teachers and white-collar workers disproportionately left the labor market at the end of the 2020-2021 virtual school year. These mothers likely struggled balancing remote work while simultaneously supporting their children's virtual schooling needs. The disparity between mothers and fathers widened over time, indicating the prevalence of inequality in sharing household duties even today. By the start of the 2021-2022 school year, eighteen months after the pandemic began, mothers' employment was still adversely impacted by childcare disruptions. Our findings emphasize that while flexible work has been shown to increase women's labor supply, it is not sufficient to ensure continued and increasing levels of women's labor force participation if accessible and affordable childcare is unavailable while they work for pay.]]>
</description>
<guid>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedmoi/93472/original</guid>
<dc:creator>Heggeness, Misty; Suri, Palak</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2021-11-16</dc:date>
<rdau:hasExtent>53</rdau:hasExtent>
<dc:subject>Labor supply; Gender telework; Difference-in-difference</dc:subject>
<swpo:hasNumber>52</swpo:hasNumber>
<identifiers:doi>10.21034/iwp.52</identifiers:doi>
<bibo:series>Opportunity and Inclusive Growth Institute Working Papers</bibo:series>
</item>
<item>
<title>Doves for the Rich, Hawks for the Poor? Distributional Consequences of Systematic Monetary Policy</title>
<link>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedmoi/93471/original</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[We build a New Keynesian business-cycle model with rich household heterogeneity. In the model, systematic monetary stabilization policy affects the distribution of income, income risks, and the demand for funds and supply of assets: the demand, because matching frictions render idiosyncratic labor-market risk endogenous; the supply, because markups, adjustment costs, and the tax system mean that the average profitability of firms is endogenous. Disagreement about systematic monetary stabilization policy is pronounced. The wealth-rich or retired tend to favor inflation targeting. The wealth-poor working class, instead, favors unemployment-centric policy. One- and two-agent alternatives can show unanimous disapproval of inflation-centric policy, instead. We highlight how the political support for inflation-centric policy depends on wage setting, the tax system, and the portfolio that households have.]]>
</description>
<guid>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedmoi/93471/original</guid>
<dc:creator>Gornemann, Nils; Kuester, Keith; Nakajima, Makoto</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2021-06-29</dc:date>
<rdau:hasExtent>122</rdau:hasExtent>
<dc:subject>Monetary policy; Unemployment; Search and matching; Heterogeneous agents; General equilibrium; Dual mandate</dc:subject>
<swpo:hasNumber>50</swpo:hasNumber>
<identifiers:doi>10.21034/iwp.50</identifiers:doi>
<bibo:series>Opportunity and Inclusive Growth Institute Working Papers</bibo:series>
</item>
<item>
<title>Monetary/Fiscal Interactions with Forty Budget Constraints</title>
<link>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedmwp/93470/original</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[It is well known that monetary and fiscal policy are connected by a common budget constraint. In this paper, we study how this manifests itself in the context of the Eurozone, where that connection links the European Central Bank, the 19 national central banks, the Treasuries of 19 countries, and the European Union. Our goal is twofold. First, we wish to clarify how seigniorage flows from the monetary authority to the budget of each country. Second, we seek to answer the question of how the taxpayers of each country are affected by a default of one of the participants to the union. In answering this question, we analyze the mechanisms that ensure (or do not ensure) that net liabilities across countries stay bounded, and we establish how the answer depends on the liquidity premium that each category of assets commands (cash, excess reserves within the Eurosystem, and government bonds). We find that the official risk-sharing provisions of the policy of quantitative easing (QE), whereby national central banks retain 90% of the risk intrinsic in bonds of their own country, only holds under restrictive assumptions; under plausible scenarios, a significantly larger fraction of the risk is mutualized.]]>
</description>
<guid>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedmwp/93470/original</guid>
<dc:creator>Gennaro Caracciolo, Gherardo; Bassetto, Marco</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2021-12-02</dc:date>
<rdau:hasExtent>23</rdau:hasExtent>
<dc:subject>Monetary/fiscal interaction; Fiscal theory of the price level; Eurozone; TARGET2; Monetary union</dc:subject>
<swpo:hasNumber>788</swpo:hasNumber>
<identifiers:doi>10.21034/wp.788</identifiers:doi>
<bibo:series>Working Papers</bibo:series>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>