<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"><channel><title><![CDATA[Coding Horror]]></title><description><![CDATA[programming and human factors]]></description><link>https://blog.codinghorror.com/</link><image><url>https://blog.codinghorror.com/favicon.png</url><title>Coding Horror</title><link>https://blog.codinghorror.com/</link></image><generator>Ghost 4.48</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2022 00:40:27 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.codinghorror.com/rss/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><ttl>60</ttl><item><title><![CDATA[The 2030 Self-Driving Car Bet]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>It&apos;s my honor to announce that <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/John_Carmack">John Carmack</a> and I have initiated a friendly bet of $10,000* to the 501(c)(3) charity of the winner&#x2019;s choice:</p><blockquote><strong>By January 1st, 2030, completely autonomous self-driving cars meeting <a href="https://www.sae.org/binaries/content/assets/cm/content/blog/sae-j3016-visual-chart_5.3.21.pdf">SAE J3016 level 5</a> will be commercially available for</strong></blockquote>]]></description><link>https://blog.codinghorror.com/the-2030-self-driving-car-bet/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">62225c0cca10de003db5e1f7</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Jeff Atwood]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2022 18:53:32 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It&apos;s my honor to announce that <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/John_Carmack">John Carmack</a> and I have initiated a friendly bet of $10,000* to the 501(c)(3) charity of the winner&#x2019;s choice:</p><blockquote><strong>By January 1st, 2030, completely autonomous self-driving cars meeting <a href="https://www.sae.org/binaries/content/assets/cm/content/blog/sae-j3016-visual-chart_5.3.21.pdf">SAE J3016 level 5</a> will be commercially available for passenger use in major cities.</strong></blockquote><p>I am betting <em>against</em>, and John is betting <em>for</em>.</p><figure class="kg-card kg-embed-card"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">I have another long-term bet:<br>I bet <a href="https://twitter.com/codinghorror?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@codinghorror</a> $10k that by January 1st, 2030, completely autonomous self-driving cars meeting SAE J3016 level 5 will be commercially available for passenger use in major cities. \</p>&#x2014; John Carmack (@ID_AA_Carmack) <a href="https://twitter.com/ID_AA_Carmack/status/1499803694522589187?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">March 4, 2022</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>
</figure><p>By &#x201C;completely autonomous&#x201D;, per the <a href="https://www.sae.org/binaries/content/assets/cm/content/blog/sae-j3016-visual-chart_5.3.21.pdf">SAE level 5 definition</a>, we mean the vehicle performs all driving tasks under all conditions &#x2013; except in the case of natural disasters or emergencies. A human passenger enters the vehicle and selects a destination. Zero human attention or interaction is required during the journey. </p><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"><a href="https://www.sae.org/binaries/content/assets/cm/content/blog/sae-j3016-visual-chart_5.3.21.pdf"><img src="https://blog.codinghorror.com/content/images/2022/03/image.png" class="kg-image" alt loading="lazy" width="1440" height="1101" srcset="https://blog.codinghorror.com/content/images/size/w600/2022/03/image.png 600w, https://blog.codinghorror.com/content/images/size/w1000/2022/03/image.png 1000w, https://blog.codinghorror.com/content/images/2022/03/image.png 1440w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></a></figure><p>By &quot;major cities&quot; we mean any of the top 10 most populous cities in the United States of America.</p><p>To be clear, I am betting <em>against</em> because I think everyone is <strong>underestimating how difficult fully autonomous driving really is</strong>. I am by no means against self driving vehicles in any way! I&apos;d much rather spend my time in a vehicle reading, watching videos, or talking to my family and friends &#x2026; anything, really, instead of driving. I also think fully autonomous vehicles are a fascinating, incredibly challenging computer science problem, and I want everyone reading this to take it as just that, a <em>challenge</em>. Prove me wrong! Make it happen by 2030, and I&apos;ll be popping champagne along with you and everyone else!</p><p>(My take on VR is <a href="https://blog.codinghorror.com/i-tried-vr-and-it-was-just-ok/">far more pessimistic</a>. VR just&#x2026; isn&apos;t going to happen, in any &quot;changing the world&quot; form, in our lifetimes. This is a subject for a different blog post, but I think AR and projection will do much more for us, far sooner.)</p><p>I&apos;d like to thank John for suggesting this friendly wager as a fun way to generate STEM publicity. He is, and always will be, <a href="https://blog.codinghorror.com/you-dont-need-millions-of-dollars/">one of my biggest heroes</a>. Go read <a href="https://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/0812972155/codihorr-20">Masters of Doom</a> if you haven&apos;t, already!</p><p>And while I have you, we&apos;re still looking for code contributions in our project to <a href="https://blog.codinghorror.com/updating-the-single-most-influential-book-of-the-basic-era/">update the most famous programming book of the BASIC era</a>. Proceeds from that project will also go to charity. &#x1F60E;</p><p>* We may adjust the amount up or down to adjust for inflation as mutually agreed upon in 2030, so the money has the desired impact.</p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Updating The Single Most Influential Book of the BASIC Era]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>In a way, these two books are <a href="https://blog.codinghorror.com/everything-i-needed-to-know-about-programming-i-learned-from-basic/">responsible for my entire professional career</a>.</p><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"><img src="https://blog.codinghorror.com/content/images/2022/01/image.png" class="kg-image" alt loading="lazy" width="1446" height="960" srcset="https://blog.codinghorror.com/content/images/size/w600/2022/01/image.png 600w, https://blog.codinghorror.com/content/images/size/w1000/2022/01/image.png 1000w, https://blog.codinghorror.com/content/images/2022/01/image.png 1446w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></figure><p>With early computers, you didn&apos;t boot up to a fancy schmancy desktop, or a screen full of apps you could easily poke and prod with your finger. No, <strong>those computers booted up to the command</strong></p>]]></description><link>https://blog.codinghorror.com/updating-the-single-most-influential-book-of-the-basic-era/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">61cfb0fa34500c00482dc601</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Jeff Atwood]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 31 Dec 2021 23:49:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In a way, these two books are <a href="https://blog.codinghorror.com/everything-i-needed-to-know-about-programming-i-learned-from-basic/">responsible for my entire professional career</a>.</p><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"><img src="https://blog.codinghorror.com/content/images/2022/01/image.png" class="kg-image" alt loading="lazy" width="1446" height="960" srcset="https://blog.codinghorror.com/content/images/size/w600/2022/01/image.png 600w, https://blog.codinghorror.com/content/images/size/w1000/2022/01/image.png 1000w, https://blog.codinghorror.com/content/images/2022/01/image.png 1446w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></figure><p>With early computers, you didn&apos;t boot up to a fancy schmancy desktop, or a screen full of apps you could easily poke and prod with your finger. No, <strong>those computers booted up to the command line.</strong></p><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"><img src="https://blog.codinghorror.com/content/images/2022/01/image-1.png" class="kg-image" alt loading="lazy" width="562" height="127"></figure><p>From here, if you were lucky, you might have a cassette tape drive. If you knew the right commands, you could type them in to load programs from cassette tape. But that was an expensive add-on option with early personal computers. For many of us, if we wanted the computer to do anything, we had to type in entire programs from books like <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/BASIC_Computer_Games">101 Basic Computer Games</a>, by hand... <a href="https://www.atariarchives.org/basicgames/showpage.php?page=2">like so</a>.</p><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"><img src="https://blog.codinghorror.com/content/images/2022/01/image-2.png" class="kg-image" alt loading="lazy" width="784" height="1049" srcset="https://blog.codinghorror.com/content/images/size/w600/2022/01/image-2.png 600w, https://blog.codinghorror.com/content/images/2022/01/image-2.png 784w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></figure><p>Yep, believe it or not, circa 1983, <em>this was our idea of a good time</em>. No, we didn&apos;t get out much. The book itself was a sort of greatest hits compilation of games collected from Ahl&apos;s seminal <a href="https://www.atarimagazines.com/creative/v10n11/66_Dave_tells_Ahl__the_hist.php">Creative Computing magazine in the 1970s</a>:</p><blockquote>As soon as Ahl made up his mind to leave DEC, he started laying the groundwork for Creative Computing. He announced intentions to publish the magazine at NCC in June 1974 and over the next few months contacted prospective authors, got mailing lists, arranged for typesetting and printing, and started organizing hundreds of other details.<br><br>In addition, he also moved his family to Morristown, NJ, and settled into his new job at AT&amp;T. He had little spare capital, so he substituted for it with &quot;sweat equity.&quot; He edited submitted articles and wrote others. He specified type, took photos, got books of &quot;clip art,&quot; drew illustrations, and laid out boards. He wrote and laid out circulation flyers, pasted on labels, sorted and bundled mailings.<br><br>By October 1974, when it was time to specify the first print run, he had just 600 subscribers. But Ahl had no intention of running off just 600 issues. He took all the money he had received, divided it in half, and printed 8000 copies with it. These rolled off the presses October 31, 1974. Ahl recounts the feeling of euphoria on the drive to the printer replaced by dismay when he saw two skids of magazines and wondered how he would ever get them off the premises. Three trips later, his basement and garage were filled with 320 bundles of 25 magazines each. He delivered the 600 subscriber copies to the post office the next day, but it took nearly three weeks to paste labels by hand onto the other 7400 copies and send them, unsolicited, to libraries and school systems throughout the country.</blockquote><p>I also <a href="https://blog.codinghorror.com/the-best-of-creative-computing/">loved Creative Computing</a>, but it was a little before my time:</p><ul><li>1971 &#x2013; Ahl ports the programs from FOCAL to BASIC.</li><li>1973 &#x2013; <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/BASIC_Computer_Games">101 BASIC Computer Games</a> is first published by DEC.</li><li>1974 &#x2013; Ahl founds <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Creative_Computing_(magazine)">Creative Computing</a> magazine and acquires the rights to the book from DEC.</li><li>1977 &#x2013; the &#x201C;trinity&#x201D; of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Apple_II">Apple II</a> &#x1F5A5;&#xFE0F;, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Commodore_PET">PET </a> &#xFE0F;&#x1F5A5;&#xFE0F;, and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/TRS-80">TRS-80 </a> &#x1F5A5;&#xFE0F; microcomputers are released to the public, all with BASIC built in, at prices regular people could mostly afford &#x1F64C;</li><li>1978 &#x2013; a second edition of BASIC Computer Games is released, this time published by Ahl himself.</li></ul><p>As you can see, there&#x2019;s no way average people in 1973-1976 were doing a whole lot with BASIC programs, as <em>they had no microcomputers capable of running BASIC to buy! </em>It took a while for inexpensive personal computers to trickle down to the mainstream, which brings us to roughly 1984 when the sequels started appearing.</p><p>There was a <a href="https://social.technet.microsoft.com/wiki/contents/articles/16765.basic-computer-games-small-basic-edition.aspx">half-hearted attempt to modernize these early BASIC programs in 2010 with SmallBasic</a>, but I didn&apos;t feel these ports did much to bring the code up to date, and overall had little relevance to modern code practices. You can compare <a href="https://pastebin.com/j4jzGd4V">the original 1973 BASIC Civil War</a> with <a href="https://pastebin.com/5q1B0t2C">the 2010 SmallBasic port</a> to see what I mean:</p><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"><img src="https://blog.codinghorror.com/content/images/2022/01/image-3.png" class="kg-image" alt loading="lazy" width="2000" height="1083" srcset="https://blog.codinghorror.com/content/images/size/w600/2022/01/image-3.png 600w, https://blog.codinghorror.com/content/images/size/w1000/2022/01/image-3.png 1000w, https://blog.codinghorror.com/content/images/size/w1600/2022/01/image-3.png 1600w, https://blog.codinghorror.com/content/images/size/w2400/2022/01/image-3.png 2400w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></figure><p>Certainly we can do a bit better than merely removing the line numbers? What about <a href="https://blog.codinghorror.com/the-greatest-invention-in-computer-science/">our old buddy the subroutine, </a><em><a href="https://blog.codinghorror.com/the-greatest-invention-in-computer-science/">merely the greatest invention in computer science</a></em><a href="https://blog.codinghorror.com/the-greatest-invention-in-computer-science/">?</a> It&apos;s nowhere to be seen. &#x1F914;</p><p>So it was with considerable enthusiasm that I contacted <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/David_H._Ahl">David H. Ahl</a>, the author, and asked for permission to create a website that attempted to truly update all these ancient BASIC programs.</p><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"><img src="https://blog.codinghorror.com/content/images/2022/01/basic-computer-games-signed-david-ahl.jpg" class="kg-image" alt loading="lazy" width="2000" height="1210" srcset="https://blog.codinghorror.com/content/images/size/w600/2022/01/basic-computer-games-signed-david-ahl.jpg 600w, https://blog.codinghorror.com/content/images/size/w1000/2022/01/basic-computer-games-signed-david-ahl.jpg 1000w, https://blog.codinghorror.com/content/images/size/w1600/2022/01/basic-computer-games-signed-david-ahl.jpg 1600w, https://blog.codinghorror.com/content/images/size/w2400/2022/01/basic-computer-games-signed-david-ahl.jpg 2400w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></figure><p>Thankfully, permission was granted. It&apos;s hard to understate <a href="https://time.com/69316/basic/">how important this book was to an entire generation of programmers</a>. At one point, <strong>there were more copies of this book in print than there were personal computers, period!</strong></p><blockquote>... in 1973, DEC published an anthology, <em>101 BASIC Computer Games</em>. The book quickly went into a second printing, for a total of 10,000 copies sold. &#x201C;That was far more books than there were computers around, so people were buying three, four, five of them for each computer.&#x201D;</blockquote><p>It went on to be the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/BASIC_Computer_Games#Reception">first computer book to sell a million copies</a>. Quite a legacy.</p><p>I think we owe it to the world to bring this book up to date using <strong>modern, memory safe languages that embody the original spirit of BASIC, </strong>and modern programming practices including subroutines.</p><p>So let&apos;s do this. <strong>Please <a href="https://github.com/coding-horror/basic-computer-games">join us on GitHub</a></strong>, where we&apos;re updating those original 101 BASIC games in 10 memory safe, general purpose scripting languages:</p><ul><li>Java / Kotlin</li><li>Python</li><li>C#</li><li>VB.NET</li><li>JavaScript</li><li>Ruby</li><li>Perl</li><li>Lua</li></ul><p>(Edit: as of March 2022, we&apos;ve a) offered Kotlin as an alternative to Java, b) removed Pascal since we can&apos;t guarantee memory safety there, and replaced it with Rust, which very much can, and c) added Lua which <em>just</em> cracked the top 20 in TIOBE and strongly meets the scripting and memory safe criteria.)</p><p>Now, bear in mind these are <em>very</em> primitive games from the 1970s. They aren&apos;t going to win any awards for gameplay, or programming sophistication. But they <em>are </em><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Early_mainframe_games">precious artifacts of early computing</a> that deserve to be preserved for future generations, including the wonderful <a href="http://www.bekerbots.com/botbooks.htm">original art by George Beker</a>.</p><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"><img src="https://blog.codinghorror.com/content/images/2022/01/Chomperanimated2.gif" class="kg-image" alt loading="lazy" width="300" height="318"></figure><p><strong>We need your help to do this right</strong>, and <em>collaboratively together</em>, as with all modern programming projects. Imagine we&apos;re all typing these programs in simultaneously together online, all over the world, instead of being isolated alone in our room in 1984, cursing at the inevitable typo we made somewhere when typing the code in by hand out of the book&#x1F92C;.</p><figure class="kg-card kg-embed-card"><iframe width="200" height="113" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/I3lhtcGzhkc?start=349&amp;feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe></figure><p>Thanks Mr. Ahl. And a <em>big</em> thanks to everyone who contributed to this project when it was in beta, announced only on Twitter:</p><ul><li>Oscar Toledo (<a href="https://github.com/nanochess">nanochess</a>)</li><li>Tim Buchalka (<a href="https://github.com/journich">journich</a>)</li><li>Dave LeCompte (<a href="https://github.com/tsmaster">tsmaster</a>)</li><li>Nezumi Ronin (<a href="https://github.com/NezumiRonin">NezumiRonin</a>)</li><li>Daniel Piron (<a href="https://github.com/danielpiron">danielpiron</a>)</li><li>Darren Cardenas (<a href="https://github.com/darrencardenas">darrencardenas</a>)</li><li>Alvaro Frias (<a href="https://github.com/qequ">qequ</a>)</li><li>Jamie McCarthy (<a href="https://github.com/jamiemccarthy">jamiemccarthy</a>)</li><li>Roger Bamforth (<a href="https://github.com/rbamforth">rbamforth</a>)</li><li>Peter Ruderman (<a href="https://github.com/pgruderman">pgruderman</a>)</li><li>Piotr Czajkowski (<a href="https://github.com/pczajkowski">pczajkowski</a>)</li><li>Jack Boyce (<a href="https://github.com/jkboyce">jkboyce</a>)</li><li><a href="https://github.com/epvanhouten">epvanhouten</a></li><li>Topher Lamey (<a href="https://github.com/clamey">clamey</a>)</li><li><a href="https://github.com/kt--">kt--</a></li><li>Tom Armitage (<a href="https://github.com/infovore">infovore</a>)</li><li>Richard Nienaber (<a href="https://github.com/rjnienaber">rjneinaber</a>)</li><li><a href="https://github.com/marvin826">marvin826</a></li><li>Aldrin Misquitta (<a href="https://github.com/aldrinm">aldrinm</a>)</li><li><a href="https://github.com/olliehcrook">olliehcrook</a></li><li>Gustavo &apos;Gus&apos; Carreno (<a href="https://github.com/gcarreno">gcarreno</a>)</li><li>Nahid Mondol (<a href="https://github.com/NahidMondol">NahidMondol</a>)</li></ul><p>To encourage new contributions, by the end of 2022,<strong> for every functioning program submitted in each of the 10 indicated languages, I&apos;ll donate $5 to <a href="https://girlswhocode.com/">Girls Who Code</a></strong>. Before beginning, please <a href="https://github.com/coding-horror/basic-computer-games/blob/main/README.md">read the guidelines in the readme</a>, and if you have questions, <a href="https://discourse.codinghorror.com/t/updating-101-basic-computer-games-for-2022-and-beyond/7927">scan through this discussion topic</a>. And most of all, remember, <a href="https://blog.codinghorror.com/remember-this-stuff-is-supposed-to-be-fun/">this stuff is supposed to be fun</a>.</p><p>(I don&apos;t want to be &quot;that one guy&quot;, so I&apos;m also looking for project co-owners who can help own and organize this effort. If this is a project that <em>really</em> appeals to you, show me what you can do and let&apos;s work together as a team.)</p><p>Perhaps as your new year&apos;s resolution you can see fit to carve off some time to take part in <a href="https://github.com/coding-horror/basic-computer-games"><strong>our project to update a classic programming book</strong></a> &#x2013; <em>one of the most influential books in computing history</em> &#x2013; for 2022 and beyond! &#x1F389;</p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Building a PC, Part IX: Downsizing]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Hard to believe that I&apos;ve had the same PC case since 2011, and my last serious upgrade was in 2015. I guess that&apos;s yet another sign that <a href="https://blog.codinghorror.com/the-pc-is-over/">the PC is over</a>, because PC upgrades have gotten <em>really boring</em>. It took 5 years for me to muster</p>]]></description><link>https://blog.codinghorror.com/building-a-pc-part-ix-downsizing/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5e9cd090c3c8fd0038b12a3f</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Jeff Atwood]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2020 23:56:03 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hard to believe that I&apos;ve had the same PC case since 2011, and my last serious upgrade was in 2015. I guess that&apos;s yet another sign that <a href="https://blog.codinghorror.com/the-pc-is-over/">the PC is over</a>, because PC upgrades have gotten <em>really boring</em>. It took 5 years for me to muster up the initiative to get my system fully upgraded! &#x1F971;</p><p>I&apos;ve been slogging away at this for quite some time now. My PC build blog entry series spans 13 glorious years:</p><ul><li><a href="https://blog.codinghorror.com/building-a-pc-part-viii-iterating/">Building a PC, Part VIII: Iterating</a> (2015)</li><li><a href="https://blog.codinghorror.com/building-a-pc-part-vii-rebooting/">Building a PC, Part VII: Rebooting</a> (2011)</li><li><a href="http://www.codinghorror.com/blog/2009/12/building-a-pc-part-vi-rebuilding.html">Building a PC, Part VI: Rebuilding</a> (2009)</li><li><a href="http://www.codinghorror.com/blog/2008/04/building-a-pc-part-v-upgrading.html">Building a PC, Part V: Upgrading</a> (2008)</li><li><a href="http://www.codinghorror.com/blog/2007/07/building-a-pc-part-iv-now-its-your-turn.html">Building a PC, Part IV: Now It&apos;s Your Turn</a> (2007)</li><li><a href="http://www.codinghorror.com/blog/2007/07/building-a-pc-part-iii-overclocking.html">Building a PC, Part III: Overclocking</a> (2007)</li><li><a href="http://www.codinghorror.com/blog/2007/07/building-a-pc-part-ii.html">Building a PC, Part II: Burn in</a> (2007)</li><li><a href="http://www.codinghorror.com/blog/2007/07/building-a-pc-part-i.html">Building a PC, Part I: Minimal boot</a> (2007)</li></ul><p>The future of PCs may not necessarily be <strong>more speed</strong> (though there is some of that, if you read on), but in <strong>smaller builds</strong>. For this iteration, my go-to cases are the <a href="https://www.dan-cases.com/dana4.php">Dan A4 SFX</a> ...</p><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"><img src="https://blog.codinghorror.com/content/images/2020/04/dan-a4-sfx-v2-build-pc-side.jpg" class="kg-image" alt loading="lazy"></figure><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"><img src="https://blog.codinghorror.com/content/images/2020/04/dan-a4-sfx-v2-build-gpu-side.jpg" class="kg-image" alt loading="lazy"></figure><p>And the <a href="https://streacom.com/products/da2-chassis/">Streacom DA2</a> ...</p><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"><img src="https://blog.codinghorror.com/content/images/2020/04/IMG_0545.jpg" class="kg-image" alt loading="lazy"></figure><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"><img src="https://blog.codinghorror.com/content/images/2020/04/IMG_0532.jpg" class="kg-image" alt loading="lazy"></figure><p>The attraction here is <strong>maximum power in minimum size</strong>. Note that <a href="http://i.imgur.com/odoYjle.jpg">each of these cases are <em>just </em>large enough</a> to fit ...</p><ul><li>a standard mini-ITX system</li><li>SFX power supply</li><li>full sized GPU</li><li>reasonable CPU cooler</li></ul><p>... though the DA2 offers substantially more room for cooling the CPU and adding fans.</p><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card kg-card-hascaption"><img src="https://blog.codinghorror.com/content/images/2020/04/mini-itx-case-sizes-compared.png" class="kg-image" alt loading="lazy"><figcaption><a href="http://i.imgur.com/odoYjle.jpg">http://i.imgur.com/odoYjle.jpg</a></figcaption></figure><p>I&apos;m not sure you can physically build a smaller standard mini-ITX system than the DAN A4 SFX, at least not without custom parts!</p><blockquote><a href="https://www.dan-cases.com/dana4.php">DAN A4-SFX</a><br>200mm &#xD7; 115mm &#xD7; 317mm = 7.3 liters<br><br><a href="https://www.silverstonetek.com/raven/product-rv.php?pid=606">Silverstone RVZ02</a> / ML08<br>380mm &#xD7; 87mm &#xD7; 370mm = 12.2 liters<br><br><a href="https://ncases.com/products/m1">nCase M1</a><br>240mm &#xD7; 160mm &#xD7; 328 mm = 12.6 liters<br><br>Streacom DA2<br>180mm &#xD7; 286mm &#xD7; 340mm = 17.5 liters</blockquote><p>(For comparison with <a href="https://blog.codinghorror.com/the-golden-age-of-x86-gaming/">The Golden Age of x86 Gaming Consoles</a>, a PS4 Pro occupies 5.3 liters and an Xbox One S 4.3 liters. About 50% more volume for considerably more than 2&#xD7; the power isn&apos;t a bad deal!)</p><p>I chose the Streacom DA2 as my personal build, because after experimenting heavily with the DAN A4 SFX, I realized you need more room to deal with extremely powerful CPUs and GPUs in this form factor, and I wanted a truly powerful system:</p><ul><li>Intel <a href="https://www.intel.com/content/www/us/en/products/processors/core/i9-processors/i9-9900ks.html">i9-9900KS</a> (8 core, 16 thread, 5.0 GHz) CPU </li><li>Samsung 970 PRO 1TB / Samsung 970 EVO 2TB / Samsung 860 QVO 4TB SATA</li><li>64GB DDR4-3000</li><li><a href="http://www.cryorig.com/h7.php">Cryorig H7</a> cooler (exact fit)</li><li>NVIDIA GeForce RTX 2080 Ti GPU</li></ul><p>Compared to my old 2015-2017 system, a slightly overclocked i7-7700k, that at least gives me 2&#xD7; the cores (and faster cores, both in clock rate and IPC), 2&#xD7; the memory, and 2&#xD7; the M.2 slots (two versus one).</p><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"><img src="https://blog.codinghorror.com/content/images/2020/04/streacom-da2-9900ks-stats.png" class="kg-image" alt loading="lazy"></figure><p>The DA2 is a clever case though less perfect than the A4-SFX. What&apos;s neat about it is the hybrid open-air design (on the top and bottom) plus the versatile horizontal and vertical bracket system interior. Per <a href="https://streacom.com/downloads/ug/da2-user-guide-180901.pdf">the manual (pdf)</a>:</p><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"><img src="https://blog.codinghorror.com/content/images/2020/04/streacom-da2-overview.png" class="kg-image" alt loading="lazy"></figure><p>Check out all the bracket mounting options. Incredibly versatile, and easy to manipulate with the captured nut and bolt design:</p><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"><img src="https://blog.codinghorror.com/content/images/2020/04/streacom-da2-bracket-options.png" class="kg-image" alt loading="lazy"></figure><p>Note that you can (and really <em>should</em>) pop out the top and bottom acrylic pieces with the mesh dust net.</p><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"><img src="https://blog.codinghorror.com/content/images/2020/04/streacom-da2-dust-nets.png" class="kg-image" alt loading="lazy"></figure><p>I had <strong>dramatically better temperatures</strong> after I did this, and it also made the build easier since the case can fully &quot;breathe&quot; through the top and bottom. You&apos;ll note that the front of the DA2 is totally solid, no air holes, so you do need that extra airflow.</p><p>I only have a few criticisms of this Streacom DA2 case:</p><ul><li>The side panels are tool free, which is excellent, but the pressure fit makes them fairly difficult to remove. Feels like this could be tweaked?</li><li>(Don&apos;t even think about using a full sized ATX power supply. In theory it is supported, but the build becomes so much more difficult. Use a SFX power supply, which you&apos;d expect to do for a mini-ITX build anyway.)</li><li>My primary complaint is that the <strong>power extension cable gets in the way</strong>. I had to remove it and re-attach it during my build. They should custom route the power cable upwards so it blocks less stuff.</li><li>Less of a criticism and more of an observation: if your build uses a powerful GPU and CPU, you&apos;ll need two case fans. There&apos;s mounting points for a 92mm fan in the rear, and the bracket system makes it easy to mount a 140mm fan blowing inward. You will definitely need both fans!</li></ul><p>Here&apos;s the configuration I recommend, open on both the top and bottom for maximum airflow, with three fans total:</p><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"><img src="https://blog.codinghorror.com/content/images/2020/04/streacom-da2-fan-config.jpg" class="kg-image" alt loading="lazy"></figure><p>If you are a water cooling kind of person &#x2013; I am definitely not, I experienced one too many traumatic cooling fluid leaks in the early 2000s &#x2013; then you will use that 140mm space for the radiator.</p><p>I have definitely <a href="https://blog.codinghorror.com/is-your-computer-stable/">burn-in tested this machine</a>, as I do all systems I build, and it passed with flying colors. But to be honest, if you expect to be under full CPU and GPU loads for extended periods of time you <em>might</em> need to switch to water cooling due to the space constraints. (Or pick slightly less powerful components.)</p><p>If you haven&apos;t built a PC system recently, it&apos;s easier than it has ever been. Heck by the time you install the M.2 drives, memory, CPU, and cooler on the motherboard you&apos;re <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/sffpc/comments/drvb47/your_scientists_were_so_preoccupied_with_whether/">almost done</a>, these days!</p><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"><img src="https://blog.codinghorror.com/content/images/2020/04/open-air-mini-itx-build.jpg" class="kg-image" alt loading="lazy"></figure><p>There are a lot of <a href="https://yuel-beast-designs.myshopify.com/products/motif-monument">interesting compact mini-itx builds</a> out there. Perhaps that&apos;s the primary innovation in PC building for 2020 and beyond &#x2013; <strong>packing all that power into less than 20 liters of space! </strong></p><p>Read a <a href="https://www.ibidemgroup.com/edu/traduccion-como-construir-minipc/">Spanish translation of this article here</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Rise of the Electric Scooter]]></title><description><![CDATA[<!--kg-card-begin: markdown--><p>In an electric car, the (enormous) battery is <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/opinion/articles/2019-04-12/electric-vehicle-battery-shrinks-and-so-does-the-total-cost">a major part of the price</a>.  If electric car prices are decreasing, battery costs <em>must</em> be decreasing, because it&apos;s not like the cost of fabricating rubber, aluminum, glass, and steel into car shapes can decline that much, right?</p>
<p><img src="https://blog.codinghorror.com/content/images/2019/09/ev-battery-costs.png" alt="ev-battery-costs" loading="lazy"></p>
<p>On an</p>]]></description><link>https://blog.codinghorror.com/the-rise-of-the-electric-scooter/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5d5c700979b255003874fb4d</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Jeff Atwood]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 07:24:32 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<!--kg-card-begin: markdown--><p>In an electric car, the (enormous) battery is <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/opinion/articles/2019-04-12/electric-vehicle-battery-shrinks-and-so-does-the-total-cost">a major part of the price</a>.  If electric car prices are decreasing, battery costs <em>must</em> be decreasing, because it&apos;s not like the cost of fabricating rubber, aluminum, glass, and steel into car shapes can decline that much, right?</p>
<p><img src="https://blog.codinghorror.com/content/images/2019/09/ev-battery-costs.png" alt="ev-battery-costs" loading="lazy"></p>
<p>On an <em>electric scooter</em>, though, the effect of battery price has to be even more dramatic because scooters are such <a href="https://blog.codinghorror.com/geek-transportation-systems/">lightweight, compact, and simple machines</a>. They aren&apos;t much more than a battery and an electric motor to begin with. Remember the <a href="https://www.sfgate.com/business/article/Sebastopol-s-Zap-Power-Systems-is-banking-on-3067718.php">the Zappy electric scooter</a> from twenty years ago?</p>
<p><img src="https://blog.codinghorror.com/content/images/2019/09/zappy-electric-scooter-year-2000.jpg" alt="zappy-electric-scooter-year-2000" loading="lazy"></p>
<p>What killed the electric scooter back then is the same thing that <a href="https://blog.codinghorror.com/electric-geek-transportation-systems/">killed the electric car</a> of year 2000: terrible lead-acid battery technology. It&apos;s too heavy, it lacks power, it doesn&apos;t have enough range, it takes too long to charge. These are all different ways of saying the same thing: <em>the battery sucks</em>. It wasn&apos;t until Lithium Ion batteries matured that both the electric car and the electric scooter &#x2014; and pretty much electric <em>everything</em>, if you think about it &#x2014; became viable.</p>
<p>Thus, one way to see if Lithium Ion battery prices are indeed generally dropping independent of all other manufacturing concerns is to examine the cost of electric scooters over the last few years. Let&apos;s consider one of the most popular models, the Xiaomi Mi M365:</p>
<p><a href="https://camelcamelcamel.com/Xiaomi-Electric-Long-range-Fold-n-Carry-Ultra-Lightweight/product/B076KKX4BC"><img src="https://blog.codinghorror.com/content/images/2019/09/xiaomi-mi-m365-price-history-2018-2019.png" alt="xiaomi-mi-m365-price-history-2018-2019" loading="lazy"></a></p>
<p>This graph only shows roughly two years, from January 2018 to now; it looks like the original price for the Xiaomi M365 when it hit the US market in early 2017 was around $800. So <strong>the price of a popular, common electric scooter has <em>halved</em> in three years.</strong> Very good news indeed for electric vehicles of all types!</p>
<p>This dramatic drop in electric scooter price from 2016 to 2019 may not be surprising versus the parallel rise of the quasi-legal electric scooter smartphone app rental industry over roughly the same time period, in the form of Bird, Lime, Skip, Spin, Scoot, etc.</p>
<p><img src="https://blog.codinghorror.com/content/images/2019/09/electric-scooter-rentals-bird-lime.jpg" alt="electric-scooter-rentals-bird-lime" loading="lazy"></p>
<p>Early versions of Bird scooters were <em>actual Xiaomi M365s</em>, slightly modified for rental. Only by late 2018 had they <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bird_(company)#Vehicles">migrated to</a> custom built, ruggedized scooters optimized for the rental market. The rental industries <a href="https://www.latimes.com/business/technology/la-fi-tn-bird-scooters-money-profit-strategy-20190505-story.html">have their own challenges</a>, and ironically have started to pivot to monthly rentals rather than the classic 15 cents per minute.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Bird has experimented with its business model in recent months. In early March, the company altered its repair program in Los Angeles, which had relied on gig workers to fix broken scooters. It moved repairs in-house (though scooters are still charged each night by an army of gig workers). Later that month, the company introduced scooters with locks in some markets, in a bid to prevent theft and vandalism.</p>
<p>In April, it announced the launch of a more traditional rental program in San Francisco and Barcelona, in which users could pay $25 per month to rent a Xiaomi m365 from the company rather than paying per ride.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>But this isn&apos;t meant to be a blog entry about the viability of scooter rental company business models.</p>
<p>I want to tackle a more fundamental question: <strong>are electric scooters the future of transportation?</strong></p>
<p>Even Uber, as screwed up of a company as they still are, knows cars are overkill for a lot of basic transportation needs:</p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Uber believes their current micro fleet of ebikes and scooters can displace trips under 3 miles.<br><br>46% of Uber&apos;s rides are under 3 miles &#x1F440; <a href="https://t.co/OFmb8arZ3j">pic.twitter.com/OFmb8arZ3j</a></p>&#x2014; Micromobility Industries (@MicromobilityCo) <a href="https://twitter.com/MicromobilityCo/status/1116703423108227072?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">April 12, 2019</a></blockquote> <script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>
<p>We have plenty of scooters here at my house, and the family and I enjoy them greatly, but I have never actually ridden or owned an electric scooter. So I bought one. It is of course the popular, inexpensive, and well reviewed <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B076KKX4BC/?tag=codihorr-20">Xiaomi Mi M365</a>.</p>
<p><img src="https://blog.codinghorror.com/content/images/2019/08/m365-scooter.jpg" alt="m365-scooter" loading="lazy"></p>
<p>Here&apos;s a picture of my electric scooter inside <a href="https://blog.codinghorror.com/electric-geek-transportation-systems/">my electric car</a>. (I apologize that I didn&apos;t have an electric bicycle to park next to it for maximum smugness, but you can <em>bet your sweet electrons</em> I&apos;ll work on that next!)</p>
<p><img src="https://blog.codinghorror.com/content/images/2019/09/electric-scooter-in-electric-car.jpg" alt="electric-scooter-in-electric-car" loading="lazy"></p>
<p>The short version of my review is <strong>this electric scooter is incredibly fun, works great, and if you can get it for a price around $300, practically a no-brainer.</strong> I love it, my kids love it, and as long as you&apos;re <a href="https://www.vox.com/technology/2018/11/2/18053650/elon-musk-electric-scooters-dignity-recode-swisher">conceptually OK with the look, unlike Elon Musk</a> &#x1F6F4;&#x1F4A8; then you&apos;ll probably love it too.</p>
<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/0JgCn8-aETA" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe>
<p>I found a neat video covering the &quot;one year later&quot; experience of owning the scooter, and what you might eventually run into or want to tweak.</p>
<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/LyzdSktRfVI" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe>
<p>(The main thing to take away from this video is that flats <em>super suck</em> on tires this small, so be warned. I put Slime in my Mi&apos;s tires out of an abundance of caution, but you could also go with solid tubeless tires &#x2013; at the cost of some ride comfort &#x2013; if you&apos;re really worried.)</p>
<p>That&apos;s not to say that the electric scooter experience is perfect. There are some challenges with electric scooters, starting with the biggest one: <a href="https://www.techradar.com/news/are-electric-scooters-legal-know-the-law-where-you-live">your local government has no idea how to regulate the darn things</a>.</p>
<ul>
<li>Is this regulated like a bicycle? If not, why not?</li>
<li>Are they allowed on the sidewalk?</li>
<li>Do you have to ride them in the road, with cars &#x2026; uh, depending on the speed limit?</li>
<li>Do you need a driver&apos;s license?</li>
<li>Do you need a helmet?</li>
<li>Are you even <em>allowed</em> to legally ride them in public at all outside of private property?</li>
</ul>
<p>The answers also vary wildly depending on where you live, and with no consistency or apparent logic. Here are <a href="https://bayareabicyclelaw.com/new-e-scooter-laws-2019/">the current electric scooter laws in California</a>, for what it&apos;s worth, which <em>require the rider to have a valid driver&apos;s license</em> (unlike electric bicycles) and also disallow them from sidewalks, both of which I feel are onerous and unnecessary restrictions.</p>
<p>One aspect of those laws I <em>definitely</em> agree with, however, is the <strong>15 mile per hour speed restriction</strong>. That&apos;s a plenty brisk top speed for a standing adult with no special safety equipment. Anything faster starts to get decidedly &#x2026; uncomfortable. Consider <a href="https://www.ewheels.com/product/new-turbowheel-lightning-957wh-battery-2x-1000w-3600w-motors/">this monster of a 1165KWh electric scooter</a>, with dual motors and dual suspension that goes up to <em>forty freakin&apos; miles per hour</em>.</p>
<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/z6O7KmJQbJE" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe>
<p>That &#x2026; is &#x2026; terrifying. Even the reviewer, in full motorcycle safety gear, wasn&apos;t willing to push it all the way to 40 MPH. And I don&apos;t blame him! But now that I&apos;ve shown you the undisputed Honda Civic everyman budget model of electric scooter in the M365, hopefully this gives you a taste of the wider emerging diversity in these kinds of minimalistic electric vehicles. If you want a <a href="https://www.unagiscooters.com/products/the-scooter?variant=15012683448435">luxury</a> electric scooter, an <a href="https://fluidfreeride.com/products/mosquito-lightweight-foldable-electric-scooter">ultralight</a> electric scooter, a <a href="https://electrek.co/2019/06/10/widewheel-electric-scooter-off-road-test/">rugged offroad</a> electric scooter &#x2026; all things are possible, for a price.</p>
<p>Another reason the M365 is available for so cheap is that is successor, the <a href="https://www.mi.com/global/mi-electric-scooter-pro/">Xiaomi M365 Pro</a>, was recently released, although it is not quite possible to obtain in the US at the moment.</p>
<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/1i6g-la23HE" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe>
<p>Having ridden my M365 a fair bit, I can confirm all the Pro improvements are welcome, if incremental: bigger battery and disc brake, more power, better display, improved latch mechanism, etc.</p>
<p><img src="https://blog.codinghorror.com/content/images/2019/09/xiaomi-mi-m365-vs-pro.jpg" alt="xiaomi-mi-m365-vs-pro" loading="lazy"></p>
<p>None of those Pro improvements, however, are worth a 2&#xD7; increase in price so I&apos;d recommend sticking with the M365 for now because its value proposition is off the charts. Did I mention there&apos;s a bluetooth connection, and an app, and it is possible to <a href="https://www.gearbest.com/blog/how-to/how-to-install-xiaomi-m365-electric-scooter-firmware-mod-6635">hack the M365 firmware</a>? Pretty cool how electric vehicles are inherently digital, isn&apos;t it?</p>
<p>Here are a few other observations after riding my M365 around a fair bit:</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p><strong>Please be respectful around pedestrians.</strong> Most of the sidewalks around here are not busy at all, but the pedestrians I encountered on the electric scooter were definitely more freaked out than I&#x2019;ve seen before when using regular kick scooters (or skateboards) on the sidewalk, which did surprise me. An electric scooter has more heft to it, both physically at 26 pounds, and in the 15 mile per hour speed it can reach &#x2013; but also mentally in terms of how it looks and how people approach it. I recommend slowing down to just above walking speed when encountering pedestrians, and if there is a bike lane available, I&apos;d definitely recommend using that.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Hills work great.</strong> The kryptonite of traditional kick scooters is hills, and I&apos;m pleased to report that even with a <small>cough</small> sizable adult such as myself riding, I was able to sustain a respectable above-walking speed on most <em>reasonable</em> hills. Where I looked at a hill and thought &quot;this probably should work&quot;, it did. That&apos;s impressive, considering this <em>isn&apos;t</em> the upgraded Pro model with bigger battery and more powerful motor. On flats and downhills the performance is superb, as you&apos;d expect. That said, if you are a really big or tall adult, or live in a particularly hilly area, wait for the Pro model or an equivalent.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Portability is good, but borderline.</strong> At ~26 pounds, the electric scooter is reasonably portable, but it&apos;s not something you a) could really get away with taking inside a restaurant / store with you to prevent theft or b) want to be carrying around on your person for any significant length of time. It&apos;s not nearly as nimble or portable as a kick scooter, but that&apos;s a high bar. You&apos;ll need to carry a bike lock and think about how to lock your scooter on bike racks, which turned out to be &#x2026; more geometrically challenging than I anticipated due to the small tires, disc brakes, and the engine in the front wheel. They need more obvious locking points on the chassis.</p>
</li>
</ul>
<p>To be honest with you I&apos;m still bitter about the whole <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Segway_Inc.">Segway</a> debacle. There was so much hype back in the day. That ridiculous thing was <a href="https://www.wired.com/2009/12/1203segway-unveiled/">supposed to change the world</a>. Instead, we got &#x2026; <em>Paul Blart Mall Cop</em>.</p>
<p><img src="https://blog.codinghorror.com/content/images/2019/09/paul-blart-segway.jpeg" alt="paul-blart-segway" loading="lazy"></p>
<p>A Segway was $5,000 at launch in 2001, which is a whopping $7,248 in inflation adjusted dollars. Here in 2019, cheap $200 to $300 electric scooters are basically the transformational technology the Segway was <em>supposed</em> to be, aren&apos;t they? Are electric scooters the future of (most) transportation? I&apos;m not sure, but I do like where we&apos;re headed, even if it took us twenty years to get there.</p>
<!--kg-card-end: markdown-->]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Electric Geek Transportation Systems]]></title><description><![CDATA[<!--kg-card-begin: markdown--><p>I&apos;ve never thought of myself as a &quot;car person&quot;. The last new car I bought (and in fact, now that I think about it, the <em>first</em> new car I ever bought) was the <a href="https://www.hagerty.com/articles-videos/articles/2018/04/12/cult-of-the-ford-svt-contour">quirky 1998 Ford Contour SVT</a>. Since then we bought a VW station wagon</p>]]></description><link>https://blog.codinghorror.com/electric-geek-transportation-systems/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5d5ba9f979b255003874fb4a</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Jeff Atwood]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2019 11:35:16 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<!--kg-card-begin: markdown--><p>I&apos;ve never thought of myself as a &quot;car person&quot;. The last new car I bought (and in fact, now that I think about it, the <em>first</em> new car I ever bought) was the <a href="https://www.hagerty.com/articles-videos/articles/2018/04/12/cult-of-the-ford-svt-contour">quirky 1998 Ford Contour SVT</a>. Since then we bought a VW station wagon in 2011 and a Honda minivan in 2012 for family transportation duties. That&apos;s it. Not exactly the stuff <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Stig">The Stig&apos;s</a> dreams are made of.</p>
<p>The station wagon made sense for a family of three, but became something of a disappointment because it was purchased before &#x2014; surprise! &#x2014; <a href="https://blog.codinghorror.com/on-parenthood/">we had twins</a>. As <a href="http://www.online-literature.com/twain/3274/">Mark Twain once said</a>:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Sufficient unto the day is one baby. As long as you are in your right mind don&apos;t you ever pray for twins. Twins amount to a permanent riot. And there ain&apos;t any real difference between triplets and an insurrection.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>I&apos;m here to tell you that a station wagon doesn&apos;t <em>quite</em> cut it as a permanent riot abatement tool. For that you need a full sized minivan.</p>
<p>I&apos;m <a href="https://philip.greenspun.com/materialism/cars/sienna">with Philip Greenspun</a>. Like black socks and sandals, minivans are actually &#x2026; <em>kind of awesome?</em> Don&apos;t believe all the SUV propaganda. Minivans are flat out superior vehicle command centers. <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=pUG3Z8Hxa5I">Swagger wagons</a>, really.</p>
<p><img src="https://blog.codinghorror.com/content/images/2019/08/a-team-van.jpg" alt="a-team-van" loading="lazy"></p>
<p>The A-Team <a href="https://starcars.fandom.com/wiki/The_A-Team_Van">drove a <em>van</em></a>, not a freakin&apos; SUV. I rest my case.</p>
<p>After 7 years, the station wagon had to go. We initially looked at hybrids because, well, <a href="https://www.sfgate.com/opinion/article/Oh-so-pious-Prius-drivers-Smugness-drifts-2581016.php">isn&apos;t that required in California at this point?</a> But if you know me at all, you know I&apos;m a boil the sea kinda guy at heart. I figure if you&apos;re going to flirt with partially electric cars, why not put aside these half measures and go all the way?</p>
<p>Do you remember that <a href="https://theoatmeal.com/comics/tesla_model_s">rapturous 2014 Oatmeal comic about the Tesla Model S</a>? Even for a person who has basically zero interest in automobiles, it did sound <em>really cool</em>.</p>
<p><a href="https://theoatmeal.com/comics/tesla_model_s"><img src="https://blog.codinghorror.com/content/images/2019/08/oatmeal-tesla-s-spaceboat.jpg" alt="oatmeal-tesla-s-spaceboat" loading="lazy"></a></p>
<p>It&apos;s been 5 years, but from time to time I&apos;d see some electric vehicle on the road and I&apos;d think about that <strong>Intergalactic SpaceBoat of Light and Wonder</strong>. Maybe it&apos;s time for our family to jump on the electric car trend, too, and just late enough that we can avoid the bleeding edge and end up merely on the &#x2026; <em>leading</em> edge?</p>
<p>That&apos;s why we&apos;re now the proud owners of a <a href="https://www.caranddriver.com/reviews/a26144426/2019-kia-niro-ev-driven/">fully electric 2019 Kia Niro</a>.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.caranddriver.com/reviews/a26144426/2019-kia-niro-ev-driven/"><img src="https://blog.codinghorror.com/content/images/2019/08/kia-niro-2019.jpg" alt="kia-niro-2019" loading="lazy"></a></p>
<p>I&apos;ve somehow gone from being a person who basically doesn&apos;t care about cars at all &#x2026; to being <strong>one of those insufferable electric car people who won&apos;t shut up about them</strong>.  I apologize in advance. If you suddenly feel an overwhelming urge to close this browser tab, I don&apos;t blame you.</p>
<p>I was expecting another car, like the three we bought before. What I got, instead, was a transformation:</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Yes, yes, electric cars are clean, but it&apos;s a revelation how clean <em>everything</em> is in an electric. You take for granted how dirty and noisy gas based cars are in daily operation &#x2013; the engine noise, the exhaust fumes, the brake dust on the rims, the oily residues and thin black film that descends on everything, the way you have to wash your hands every time you use the gas station pumps. You don&apos;t fully appreciate how oppressive those little dirty details were until they&apos;re gone.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Electric cars are (almost) completely silent. I guess technically in 2019 electric cars require artificial soundmakers at low speed for safety, and this car has one. But The Oatmeal was right. Electric cars <em>feel</em> like spacecraft because they move so effortlessly. There&apos;s virtually no delay from action to reaction, near immediate acceleration and deceleration &#x2026; with almost no sound or vibration at all, like you&apos;re in freakin&apos; space! It&apos;s so immensely satisfying!</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Electric cars aren&apos;t just <em>electric</em>, they&apos;re utterly digital to their very core. Gas cars always felt like the classic 1950s Pixar Cars world of grease monkeys and machine shop guys, maybe with a few digital bobbins added here and there as an afterthought. This electric car, on the other hand, is squarely in the post-iPhone world of everyday digital gadgets. It feels more like a giant smartphone than a car. I am a programmer, I&apos;m a digital guy, I love digital stuff. And electric cars are part of <em>my</em> world, rather than the other way around. It feels good.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Electric cars are mechanically much simpler than gasoline cars, which means they are inherently more reliable and cheaper to maintain. An internal combustion engine has hundreds of moving parts, many of which require regular maintenance, fluids, filters, and tune ups. It also has a complex transmission to translate the narrow power band of a gas powered engine. None of this is necessary on an electric vehicle, whose electric motor is basically one moving part with simple 100% direct drive from the motor to the wheels. This newfound simplicity is deeply appealing to a guy who always saw cars as incredibly complicated (but computers, not so much).</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Being able to charge at home overnight is perhaps the most radical transformation of all. Your house is now a &quot;gas station&quot;. Our Kia Niro has a range of about <strong>250 miles</strong> on a full battery. With any modern electric car, provided you drive less than 200 miles a day round trip (who even drives this much?), it&apos;s very unlikely you&apos;ll ever need to &quot;fill the tank&quot; anywhere but at home. Ever. It&apos;s so strange to think that in 50 years, gas stations <a href="https://www.houstonchronicle.com/business/energy/article/As-EVs-threaten-gas-stations-owners-turn-to-14291843.php">may eventually be as odd to see in public as telephone booths now are</a>. Our charger is, conveniently enough, right next to the driveway since that&apos;s where the power breaker box was. With the level 2 charger installed, it literally <em>looks</em> like a gas pump on the side of the house, except this one &quot;pumps&quot; &#x2026; electrons.</p>
</li>
</ul>
<p><img src="https://blog.codinghorror.com/content/images/2019/08/level-2-ev-charger.jpg" alt="level-2-ev-charger" loading="lazy"></p>
<p>This electric car is such a great experience. It&apos;s so much better than our gas powered station wagon that I swear, if there was a fully electric minivan (there isn&apos;t) I would literally sell our Honda minivan <em>tomorrow</em> and switch over. Without question. And believe me, I had no plans to sell that vehicle two months ago. The electric car is <em>that much better</em>.</p>
<p>I was expecting &quot;yet another car&quot;, but what I got instead was a new, radical worldview. Driving a car powered by barely controlled liquid fuel detonations used to be normal. But in an world of more and more viable electric vehicles this status quo increasingly starts to feel &#x2026; deeply unnatural. Electric is so much better of an overall experience that you begin to wonder: why did we <em>ever</em> do it that way?</p>
<p>Gas cars seem, for lack of a better word, <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/features/2016-ev-oil-crisis/"><em>obsolete</em>.</a></p>
<p><a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/features/2016-ev-oil-crisis/"><img src="https://blog.codinghorror.com/content/images/2019/08/ev-sales.jpg" alt="ev-sales" loading="lazy"></a></p>
<p>How did this transformation happen, from my perspective, so suddenly? When exactly did electric cars go from &quot;expensive, experimental thing for crazy people&quot; to &quot;By God, I&apos;ll never buy another old fashioned gasoline based car if I can help it&quot;?</p>
<p>I was vaguely aware of the early electric cars. I even remember one coworker circa 2001 who owned a bright neon green Honda Insight. I ignored it all because, like I said, <em>I&apos;m not a car guy</em>. I needed to do the research to understand the history, and I started with the often recommended documentary <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Who_Killed_the_Electric_Car%3F">Who Killed the Electric Car?</a></p>
<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/-sc-NxP6mmI" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe>
<p>This is mostly about the original highly experimental <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/General_Motors_EV1">General Motors EV1</a> from 1996 to 1999. It&apos;s so early the first models had lead-acid batteries! &#x1F631; There&apos;s a number of conspiracy theories floated in the video, but I think the simple answer to the implied question in the title is straight up <em>price</em>. The battery tech was nowhere near ready, and per the Wikipedia article the estimated actual cost of the car was somewhere between $100,000 and $250,000 though I suspect it was much closer to the latter. It is interesting to note how much the owners (well, leasers) loved their EV1s. Having gone through that same conversion myself, I empathize!</p>
<p>I then watched the sequel, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Revenge_of_the_Electric_Car">Revenge of the Electric Car</a>. This one is essential, because it covers the dawn of the modern electric car we have today.</p>
<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/jkRIu5a6Sb0" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe>
<p>This chronicles the creation of three very influential early electric cars &#x2014; the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nissan_Leaf">Nissan Leaf</a>, the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chevrolet_Volt">Chevy Volt</a>, and of course the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tesla_Roadster_(2008)">Tesla Roadster</a> from 2005 - 2008. The precise moment that Lithium-Ion batteries were in play &#x2013; that&apos;s when electric cars started to become viable. Every one of these three electric cars was well conceived and made it to market in volume, though not without significant challenges, both internal and external. None of them were perfect electric vehicles by any means: the Roadster was $100k, the Leaf had limited range, and the Volt was still technically a hybrid, albeit only using the gasoline engine to charge the battery.</p>
<p>Ten years later, Tesla has the model 3 at $38,000 and we bought our Kia Niro for about the same price. After national and state tax incentives and rebates, that puts the price at around $30,000. It&apos;s not as cheap as it needs to be &#x2026; yet. But it&apos;s getting there. And it&apos;s <a href="https://www.corporateknights.com/channels/clean-technology/faceoff-electric-vs-gas-cars-on-cost-15555966/">already competitive with gasoline vehicles in 2019</a>.</p>
<p><img src="https://blog.codinghorror.com/content/images/2019/08/2019-civic-vs-leaf-1.jpg" alt="2019-civic-vs-leaf-1" loading="lazy"></p>
<p>It&apos;s still early, but the trend lines are clear. And I&apos;m here to tell you that right now, today, I&apos;d buy <em>any</em> modern electric car over a gasoline powered car.</p>
<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/kk7ZTn9g7bY" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe>
<p>If you too are intrigued by the idea of owning an electric car, <em>you should be</em>. It&apos;s freaking awesome! Bring your skepticism, as always; I highly recommend the above Matt Ferrell explainer video on electric vehicle myths.</p>
<p>As for me, I have seen the future, and it is absolutely, inexorably, and unavoidably &#x2026; electric. &#x26A1;</p>
<!--kg-card-end: markdown-->]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[An Exercise Program for the Fat Web]]></title><description><![CDATA[<!--kg-card-begin: markdown--><p>When I wrote about <a href="https://blog.codinghorror.com/app-pocalypse-now/">App-pocalypse Now</a> in 2014, I implied the future still belonged to the web. And it does. But it&apos;s also true that the web has changed a lot in the last 10 years, much less the last 20 or 30.</p>
<p><img src="https://blog.codinghorror.com/content/images/2017/05/fat-city-apple-ii.png" alt="fat city" loading="lazy"></p>
<p>Websites have gotten a lot</p>]]></description><link>https://blog.codinghorror.com/an-exercise-program-for-the-fat-web/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5988f60721f57d0019a2e12a</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Jeff Atwood]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2019 11:04:52 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<!--kg-card-begin: markdown--><p>When I wrote about <a href="https://blog.codinghorror.com/app-pocalypse-now/">App-pocalypse Now</a> in 2014, I implied the future still belonged to the web. And it does. But it&apos;s also true that the web has changed a lot in the last 10 years, much less the last 20 or 30.</p>
<p><img src="https://blog.codinghorror.com/content/images/2017/05/fat-city-apple-ii.png" alt="fat city" loading="lazy"></p>
<p>Websites have gotten a lot &#x2026; <em>fatter</em>.</p>
<p>While I think it&apos;s irrational to pine for the bad old days of <a href="http://info.cern.ch/">HTML 1.0 websites</a>, there are some legitimate concerns here. The best summary is Maciej Ceg&#x142;owski&apos;s <a href="http://idlewords.com/talks/website_obesity.htm">The Website Obesity Crisis</a>.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>To channel a famous motivational speaker, I could go out there tonight, with the materials you&#x2019;ve got, and rewrite the sites I showed you at the start of this talk to make them load in under a second. In two hours.</p>
<p>Can you? Can you?</p>
<p>Of course you can! It&#x2019;s not hard! We knew how to make small websites in 2002. It&#x2019;s not like the secret has been lost to history, like Greek fire or Damascus steel.</p>
<p>But we face pressure to make these sites bloated.</p>
<p>I bet if you went to a client and presented a 200 kilobyte site template, you&#x2019;d be fired. Even if it looked great and somehow included all the tracking and ads and social media crap they insisted on putting in. It&#x2019;s just so far out of the realm of the imaginable at this point.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>The <a href="http://idlewords.com/talks/website_obesity.htm">whole article is essential</a>; you should stop what you&apos;re doing and read it now if you haven&apos;t already. But if you don&apos;t have time, here&apos;s the key point:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>This is a screenshot from an NPR article discussing the rising use of ad blockers. The page is 12 megabytes in size in a stock web browser. <strong>The same article with basic ad blocking turned on is 1 megabyte.</strong></p>
</blockquote>
<p>That&apos;s right, through the simple act of running an ad blocker, you&apos;ve reduced that website&apos;s payload by twelve times. Twelve! That&apos;s like the most effective exercise program <em>ever!</em></p>
<p>Even the traditional advice to <a href="https://hackernoon.com/10-things-i-learned-making-the-fastest-site-in-the-world-18a0e1cdf4a7">keep websites lean and mean for mobile</a> no longer applies because new mobile devices, at least on the Apple side, are <em>faster than most existing desktops and laptops.</em></p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-lang="en"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">The iPhone XS is faster than an iMac Pro on the Speedometer 2.0 JavaScript benchmark. It&apos;s the fastest device I&apos;ve ever tested. Insane 45% jump over the iPhone 8/X chip. How does Apple do it?! &#x2728; <a href="https://t.co/5nCKZUCAYK">pic.twitter.com/5nCKZUCAYK</a></p>&#x2014; DHH (@dhh) <a href="https://twitter.com/dhh/status/1043277162676072449?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 21, 2018</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>
<p>Despite <a href="https://danluu.com/web-bloat/">claims to the contrary</a>, the bad guy isn&apos;t web bloat, per se. <strong>The bad guy is <em>advertising</em></strong>. Unlimited, unfettered ad &quot;tech&quot; has creeped into everything and subsumed the web.</p>
<p>Personally I don&apos;t even want to run ad blockers, and I didn&apos;t for a long time &#x2013; but it&apos;s increasingly difficult to avoid running an ad blocker unless you want a clunky, substandard web experience. There&apos;s a <em>reason</em> the most popular browser plugins are inevitably ad blockers, isn&apos;t there? Just ask Google:</p>
<p><img src="https://blog.codinghorror.com/content/images/2019/05/chrome-best-extensions-google-search.png" alt="chrome-best-extensions-google-search" loading="lazy"></p>
<p>So it&apos;s all the more surprising to learn that Google is <a href="https://9to5google.com/2019/05/29/chrome-ad-blocking-enterprise-manifest-v3/">suddenly clamping down hard on adblockers in Chrome</a>.  Here&apos;s what the author of uBlock Origin, an ad blocking plugin for Chrome, <a href="https://github.com/uBlockOrigin/uBlock-issues/issues/338#issuecomment-496009417">has to say</a> about today&apos;s announcement:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>In order for Google Chrome to reach its current user base, it had to support content blockers &#x2014; these are the top most popular extensions for any browser. Google strategy has been to find the optimal point between the two goals of growing the user base of Google Chrome and preventing content blockers from harming its business.</p>
<p>The blocking ability of the webRequest API caused Google to yield control of content blocking to content blockers. Now that Google Chrome is the dominant browser, it is in a better position to shift the optimal point between the two goals which benefits Google&apos;s primary business.</p>
<p>The deprecation of the blocking ability of the webRequest API is to gain back this control, and to further instrument and report how web pages are filtered, since the exact filters which are applied to web pages are useful information which will be collectable by Google Chrome.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>The ad blockers themselves are arguably just as complicit. Eye/o GmbH owns <a href="https://adblockplus.org/">AdBlock</a> and <a href="https://www.ublock.org/">uBlock</a>, employs 150 people, and in 2016 they had 50 million euros in revenue, of which about 50% was profit. Google&apos;s <a href="https://help.getadblock.com/support/solutions/articles/6000092027-why-does-adblock-allow-non-intrusive-ads-">paid &quot;Acceptable Ads&quot; program</a> is a way to funnel money into adblockers to, uh, <em>encourage</em> them to display certain ads. With money. Lots &#x2026; and lots &#x2026; of money. &#x1F911;</p>
<p>We simultaneously have a very real web obesity crisis, and a looming crackdown on ad blockers, seemingly the only viable weight loss program for websites. What&apos;s a poor web citizen to do? Well, there is one thing you can do to escape the need for browser-based adblockers, at least on your home network. Install and configure <a href="https://pi-hole.net/">Pi-Hole</a>.</p>
<p><img src="https://blog.codinghorror.com/content/images/2019/05/pi-hole-screenshot.png" alt="pi-hole-screenshot" loading="lazy"></p>
<p>I&apos;ve talked about the amazing Raspberry Pi before <a href="https://blog.codinghorror.com/the-raspberry-pi-has-revolutionized-emulation/">in the context of classic game emulation</a>, but this is another brilliant use for a Pi.</p>
<p>Here&apos;s why it&apos;s so cool. If you disable the DHCP server on your router, and let the Pi-Hole become your primary DHCP server, <strong>you get automatic DNS based blocking of ads for every single device on your network</strong>. It&apos;s kind of scary how powerful DNS can be, isn&apos;t it?</p>
<p><img src="https://blog.codinghorror.com/content/images/2019/05/pi-hole-action-shot.jpg" alt="pi-hole-action-shot" loading="lazy"></p>
<p>My Pi-Hole took me about 1 hour to set up, start to finish. All you need is</p>
<ul>
<li>a <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07BC7BMHY/?tag=codihorr-20">Raspberry Pi 3b+ kit</a> $59</li>
<li>a quality <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B00WR4IJBE/?tag=codihorr-20">32GB SD card</a> $9</li>
<li>an ethernet cable</li>
</ul>
<p>I do recommend the 3b+ because it has <a href="https://www.pidramble.com/wiki/benchmarks/networking">native gigabit ethernet</a> and a bit more muscle. But <a href="https://discourse.pi-hole.net/t/what-model-raspberry-pi-should-i-use-for-pi-hole/9635">literally any Raspberry Pi</a> you can find laying around will work, though I&apos;d <em>strongly</em> advise you to pick one with a wired ethernet port since it&apos;ll be your DNS server.</p>
<p>I&apos;m not going to write a whole Pi-Hole installation guide, because there are <a href="https://www.smarthomebeginner.com/pi-hole-tutorial-whole-home-ad-blocking/">lots of great ones</a> out there already. It&apos;s not difficult, and there&apos;s a slick web GUI waiting for you once you complete initial setup. For your initial testing, pick any IP address you like on your network that won&apos;t conflict with anything active. Once you&apos;re happy with the basic setup and web interface:</p>
<ul>
<li>Turn OFF your router&apos;s DHCP server &#x2013; existing leases will continue to work, so nothing will be immediately broken.</li>
<li>Turn ON the pi-hole DHCP server, in the web GUI.</li>
</ul>
<p><img src="https://blog.codinghorror.com/content/images/2019/05/pi-hole-dhcp-server.png" alt="pi-hole-dhcp-server" loading="lazy"></p>
<p>Once you do this, all your network devices will start to grab their DHCP leases from your Pi-Hole, which will <em>also</em> tell them to route all their DNS requests through the Pi-Hole, and that&apos;s when the &#x2728; magic &#x2728; happens!</p>
<p><img src="https://blog.codinghorror.com/content/images/2019/05/pi-hole-blacklists.png" alt="pi-hole-blacklists" loading="lazy"></p>
<p>All those DNS requests from all the devices on your network will be checked against the ad blacklists; anything matching is quickly and silently discarded <strong>before it ever reaches your browser.</strong></p>
<p><img src="https://blog.codinghorror.com/content/images/2019/05/pi-hole-dashboard-stats.png" alt="pi-hole-dashboard-stats" loading="lazy"></p>
<p>(The Pi-Hole also acts as a <a href="https://discourse.pi-hole.net/t/will-pi-hole-slow-down-my-network/2048">caching DNS server</a>, so repeated DNS requests will be serviced rapidly from your local network, too.)</p>
<p>If you&apos;re worried about stability or reliability, you can easily add a cheap battery backed USB plug, or even a second backup Pi-Hole as your secondary DNS provider if you prefer belt and suspenders protection. Switching back to plain boring old vanilla DNS is as easy as unplugging the Pi and flicking the DHCP server setting in your router back on.</p>
<p>At this point if you&apos;re interested (and you should be!), just give it a try. If you&apos;re looking for more information, the project has an <a href="https://discourse.pi-hole.net">excellent forum</a> full of FAQs and roadmaps.</p>
<p><a href="https://discourse.pi-hole.net"><img src="https://blog.codinghorror.com/content/images/2019/05/pi-hole-forums.png" alt="pi-hole-forums" loading="lazy"></a></p>
<p>You can even <a href="https://discourse.pi-hole.net/c/feature-requests?order=votes">vote for your favorite upcoming features!</a></p>
<p>I avoided the Pi-Hole project for a while because I didn&apos;t need it, and I&apos;d honestly rather jump in later when things are more mature.</p>
<p><img src="https://blog.codinghorror.com/content/images/2019/05/pi-hole-pin.jpg" alt="pi-hole-pin" loading="lazy"></p>
<p>With the latest Chrome crackdown on ad blockers, now is the time, and I&apos;m impressed how simple and easy <a href="https://pi-hole.net/">Pi-Hole</a> is to run. Just find a quiet place to plug it in, spend an hour configuring it, and promptly proceed to forget about it forever as you enjoy a lifetime subscription to <em>a glorious web ad instant weight loss program across every single device on your network with (almost) zero effort!</em></p>
<p>Finally, an exercise program I can believe in.</p>
<!--kg-card-end: markdown-->]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Cloud Is Just Someone Else's Computer]]></title><description><![CDATA[<!--kg-card-begin: markdown--><p>When we started <a href="https://discourse.org">Discourse</a> in 2013, our server requirements were high:</p>
<ul>
<li>1GB RAM</li>
<li>modern, fast dual core CPU</li>
<li>speedy solid state drive with 20+ GB</li>
</ul>
<p>I&apos;m not talking about a cheapo shared cpanel server, either, I mean a <em>dedicated</em> virtual private server with those specifications.</p>
<p>We were OK</p>]]></description><link>https://blog.codinghorror.com/the-cloud-is-just-someone-elses-computer/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5c68a26293063200bf4c742b</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Jeff Atwood]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 17 Feb 2019 02:15:26 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<!--kg-card-begin: markdown--><p>When we started <a href="https://discourse.org">Discourse</a> in 2013, our server requirements were high:</p>
<ul>
<li>1GB RAM</li>
<li>modern, fast dual core CPU</li>
<li>speedy solid state drive with 20+ GB</li>
</ul>
<p>I&apos;m not talking about a cheapo shared cpanel server, either, I mean a <em>dedicated</em> virtual private server with those specifications.</p>
<p>We were OK with that, because we were <a href="https://blog.codinghorror.com/why-ruby/">building in Ruby</a> for the next decade of the Internet. I predicted early on that the cost of renting a suitable VPS would drop to $5 per month, and courtesy of Digital Ocean that indeed <a href="https://meta.discourse.org/t/new-digital-ocean-pricing-spoiler-5-for-a-1gb-droplet/78230">happened in January 2018</a>.</p>
<p>The cloud got cheaper, and faster. Not really a surprise, since <a href="https://blog.codinghorror.com/when-hardware-is-free-power-is-expensive/">the price of hardware trends to zero over time</a>. But it&apos;s still the cloud, and that means it isn&apos;t exactly <em>cheap</em>. It is, after all, someone else&apos;s computer that you pay for the privilege of renting.</p>
<p><img src="https://blog.codinghorror.com/content/images/2019/02/there-is-no-cloud.png" alt="there-is-no-cloud" loading="lazy"></p>
<p>But wait &#x2026; <strong>what if you could put your <em>own</em> computer &quot;in the cloud&quot;?</strong></p>
<p>Wouldn&apos;t that be the best of both worlds? Reliable connectivity,  plus a nice low monthly price for extremely fast hardware? If this sounds crazy, it shouldn&apos;t &#x2013; Mac users have been doing this <a href="https://www.macstadium.com/pricing/colo">for years now</a>.</p>
<p><img src="https://blog.codinghorror.com/content/images/2019/02/mac-colocation-2019-1.png" alt="mac-colocation-2019-1" loading="lazy"></p>
<p>I suppose it&apos;s understandable that Mac users would be on the cutting edge here since Apple <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Xserve#Intel_Xserve">barely makes server hardware</a>, whereas the PC world has always been <a href="https://blog.codinghorror.com/building-a-computer-the-google-way/">the literal de-facto standard for server hardware</a>.</p>
<p><img src="https://blog.codinghorror.com/content/images/2019/02/mac-stadium-colocation.jpg" alt="mac-stadium-colocation" loading="lazy"></p>
<p>Given the prevalence and maturity of cloud providers, it&apos;s even a <em>little</em> controversial these days to <a href="https://blog.codinghorror.com/building-servers-for-fun-and-prof-ok-maybe-just-for-fun/">colocate actual servers</a>. We&apos;ve also experimented with <a href="https://blog.codinghorror.com/the-scooter-computer/">colocating mini-pcs</a> in various hosting roles. I&apos;m still curious why there isn&apos;t more of a cottage industry for colocating mini PCs. Because &#x2026; <em>I think there should be</em>.</p>
<p>I originally wrote about <a href="https://blog.codinghorror.com/the-scooter-computer/">the scooter computers</a> we added to our Discourse infrastructure in 2016, plus my own colocation experiment that ran concurrently. <strong>Over the last three years of both experiments, I&apos;ve concluded that these little boxes are plenty reliable</strong>, with one role specific caveat that I&apos;ll explain in the comments. I remain an unabashed fan of mini-PC colocation. I like it so much I put together a new 2019 iteration:</p>
<table style="border-spacing:8px">
    <tr><td><b>2017 &#x2014; $670</b></td><td><b>2019 &#x2014; $820</b></td></tr>
    <tr><td><a href="https://ark.intel.com/products/95451/Intel-Core-i7-7500U-Processor-4M-Cache-up-to-3_50-GHz-">i7-7500u</a><br>2.7-3.5 Ghz, 2c / 4t</td><td><a href="https://ark.intel.com/products/134906/Intel-Core-i7-8750H-Processor-9M-Cache-up-to-4-10-GHz-">i7-8750h</a><br>2.2-4.1 Ghz, 6c / 12t</td></tr>
    <tr><td>16GB DDR3 RAM</td><td>32GB DDR4 RAM</td></tr>
    <tr><td>500GB SATA SSD</td><td>500GB NVMe SSD</td></tr>
</table>
<p>This year&apos;s scooter computer offers <strong>3&#xD7; the cores, 2&#xD7; the memory, and 3&#xD7; faster drive</strong>. It is, as the kids say &#x2026; an <em>absolute unit</em>. &#x1F631;</p>
<p><img src="https://blog.codinghorror.com/content/images/2019/02/2019-scooter-computer-top-interior-1.jpeg" alt="2019-scooter-computer-top-interior-1" loading="lazy"></p>
<p><img src="https://blog.codinghorror.com/content/images/2019/02/2019-scooter-computer-bottom-interior.jpeg" alt="2019-scooter-computer-bottom-interior" loading="lazy"></p>
<p><img src="https://blog.codinghorror.com/content/images/2019/02/2019-scooter-computer-front-and-back.jpg" alt="2019-scooter-computer-front-and-back" loading="lazy"></p>
<p>It also has a rather elegant dual-sided internal layout. There is a slot for an old-school 2.5&quot; drive, plus built in wi-fi, but you won&apos;t see it in my pictures because I physically removed both.</p>
<p>I vetted each box via my <a href="https://blog.codinghorror.com/is-your-computer-stable/">recommended burn in and stability testing</a> and they all passed with flying colors, though I did have to RMA one set of bodgy RAM sticks in the process. The benchmarks tell the story, as compared to the average Digital Ocean droplet:</p>
<p><strong>Per-core performance</strong><br>
<code>sysbench cpu --cpu-max-prime=20000 run</code></p>
<table style="border-spacing:8px">
    <tr><td>DO Droplet</td><td style="text-align:right">2,988</td></tr>
    <tr><td>2017 Mini-PC</td><td style="text-align:right">4,800</td></tr>
    <tr><td>2019 Mini-PC</td><td style="text-align:right">5,671</td></tr>
</table>        
<p><strong>Multi-core performance</strong><br>
<code>sysbench cpu --cpu-max-prime=40000 --num-threads=8 run</code></p>
<table style="border-spacing:8px">
    <tr><td>DO Droplet</td><td style="text-align:right">2,200</td></tr>
    <tr><td>2017 Mini-PC</td><td style="text-align:right">5,588</td></tr>
    <tr><td>2019 Mini-PC</td><td style="text-align:right">14,604</td></tr>
</table>   
<p><strong>Disk performance</strong><br>
<code>dd bs=1M count=512 if=/dev/zero of=test conv=fdatasync</code><br>
<code>hdparm -Tt /dev/sda</code></p>
<table style="border-spacing:8px">
    <tr><td>DO Droplet</td><td style="text-align:right">701 / 8818 / 471 MB/sec</td></tr>
    <tr><td>2017 Mini-PC</td><td style="text-align:right">444 / 12564 / 505 MB/sec</td></tr>
    <tr><td>2019 Mini-PC</td><td style="text-align:right">1200 / 17919 / 3115 MB/sec</td></tr>
</table> 
<p><strong>Discourse rebuild</strong><br>
<code>time ./launcher rebuild app</code></p>
<table style="border-spacing:8px">
    <tr><td>DO Droplet</td><td style="text-align:right">6:59</td></tr>
    <tr><td>2017 Mini-PC</td><td style="text-align:right">3:41</td></tr>
    <tr><td>2019 Mini-PC</td><td style="text-align:right">3:24</td></tr>
</table> 
<p>Power consumption could be a concern, as the 2017 version had a much lower 15 watt TDP, compared to the 45 watts of this version. That 3&#xD7; increase in core count ain&apos;t free! So I tested that, too, with a combination of <code>i7z</code>, <code>stress</code>,  and my handy dandy <a href="https://blog.codinghorror.com/why-estimate-when-you-can-measure/">watt meter</a>.</p>
<p><img src="https://blog.codinghorror.com/content/images/2019/02/2019-mini-pc-i7z-testing.png" alt="2019-mini-pc-i7z-testing" loading="lazy"></p>
<table style="border-spacing:4px">
    <tr><td>(idle login)</td><td>800 Mhz</td><td style="text-align:right">10w</td></tr>
    <tr><td><code>stress --cpu 1</code></td><td>4.1 GHz</td><td style="text-align:right">30w</td></tr>
    <tr><td><code>stress --cpu 2</code></td><td>4.1 GHz</td><td style="text-align:right">42w</td></tr>
    <tr><td><code>stress --cpu 3</code></td><td>4.0 GHz</td><td style="text-align:right">53w</td></tr>
    <tr><td><code>stress --cpu 4</code></td><td>3.9 GHz</td><td style="text-align:right">65w</td></tr>
    <tr><td><code>stress --cpu 5</code></td><td>3.7 GHz</td><td style="text-align:right">65w</td></tr>
    <tr><td><code>stress --cpu 6</code></td><td>3.5 GHz</td><td style="text-align:right">65w</td></tr>
    <tr><td><code>stress --cpu 12</code></td><td>3.3 Ghz</td><td style="text-align:right">65w</td></tr>    
</table>
<p>I&apos;d expect around 10 - 20 watts doing typical low-load stuff that isn&apos;t super CPU intensive. Note that running current-ish versions of <code>mprime</code> jacks power consumption up to 75w &#x1F525; and the overall clock scales down to 3.1 Ghz &#x2026; let me tell you, I&apos;ve learned to be <a href="https://blog.cloudflare.com/on-the-dangers-of-intels-frequency-scaling/">very, <em>very</em> afraid of AVX2 extensions</a>.</p>
<p>(If you&apos;re worried about noise, don&apos;t be. This active cooling solution is clearly overkill for a 65w load, because it barely spun up at all even under full core load. It was <em>extremely</em> quiet.)</p>
<p>So we&apos;re happy that this machine is a slammin&apos; deal for $820, it&apos;s super fast, and plenty reliable. But how about colocation costs? My colocation provider is <a href="https://endoffice.com/">EndOffice</a> out of Boston, and they offer very competitive rates to colocate a Mini-PC: $29/month.</p>
<p><a href="https://endoffice.com/minicolo.html"><img src="https://blog.codinghorror.com/content/images/2019/02/endoffice-mini-pc-colocation.png" alt="endoffice-mini-pc-colocation" loading="lazy"></a></p>
<p>I personally colocate three Mini-PCs for redundancy and just-in-case; there are discounts for colocating more than one. Here they are racked up and in action. Of course I labelled the front and rear before shipping because that&apos;s how I roll.</p>
<p><img src="https://blog.codinghorror.com/content/images/2019/02/endoffice-colocated-2019-mini-pcs.jpg" alt="endoffice-colocated-2019-mini-pcs" loading="lazy"></p>
<p>Let&apos;s break this down and see what the actual costs of colocating a Mini-PC are versus the cloud. Given the plateauing of CPU speeds, I think five years of useful life for these boxes is realistic, but let&apos;s assume a conservative three year lifespan to be safe.</p>
<ul>
<li>$880 mini-pc 32GB RAM, 6 CPUs, 500GB SSD</li>
<li>$120 taxes / shipping / misc</li>
<li>$29 &#xD7; 12 &#xD7; 3 = $1,044</li>
</ul>
<p>That&apos;s <strong>$2,044 for three years of hosting</strong>. How can we do on Digital Ocean? Per <a href="https://www.digitalocean.com/pricing/">their current pricing page</a>:</p>
<ul>
<li>32GB RAM, 8 vCPUs, 640GB SSD</li>
<li>$160/month</li>
<li>$160 &#xD7; 12 &#xD7; 3 = <strong>$5,760</strong></li>
</ul>
<p>This isn&apos;t <em>quite</em> apples to apples, as we are getting an extra 140GB of disk and 2 bonus CPUs, but those CPUs are both slower and partially consumed by multi-tenancy compared to our brand new dedicated, isolated CPUs. (I was curious about this, so I just spun up a new $160/month DO instance for a quick test. The <code>sysbench</code> results are 4086 and 11760 respectively, considerably below the 2019 Mini-PC results, above.) As you can see, <strong>you pay almost three times as much for a cloud server.</strong> &#x1F911;</p>
<p>I&apos;m not saying this is for everyone. If you just need to spin up a quick server or two for testing and experimentation, there&apos;s absolutely no way you need to go to the trouble and up-front cost of building and then racking colocated mini-pcs. There&apos;s no denying that spinning servers up in the cloud offers unparalleled flexibility and redundancy. But if you do have need for <strong>dedicated computing resources over a period of years</strong>, then building your own small personal cloud, with machines <em>you actually own</em>, is not only one third the cost but also &#x2026; kinda cool?</p>
<p><img src="https://blog.codinghorror.com/content/images/2019/02/your-own-personal-cloud.jpg" alt="your-own-personal-cloud" loading="lazy"></p>
<p>If you&apos;d also like to embark upon this project, you can get <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Partaker-Coffee-Graphics-Barebone-System/dp/B07L4KJXWL?tag=codihorr-20">the same Partaker B18 box I did for $490 from Amazon</a>, or <a href="https://www.aliexpress.com/item/Partaker-B18-DDR4-Coffee-Lake-8th-Gen-Mini-PC-Intel-Core-i7-8750H-32GB-RAM-Intel/32948461273.html">$460 direct from China via AliExpress</a>. Add memory and drive to taste, build it up, then check out <a href="https://endoffice.com/">endoffice.com</a> who I can enthusiastically recommend for colocation, or the colocation provider of your choice.</p>
<p>Get something cool hosted out there; let&apos;s do our part to keep the internet <a href="https://jarredsumner.com/codeblog/">fun and weird!</a></p>
<!--kg-card-end: markdown-->]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[What does Stack Overflow want to be when it grows up?]]></title><description><![CDATA[<!--kg-card-begin: markdown--><p>I sometimes get asked by regular people in the actual real world what it is that I do for a living, and here&apos;s my 15 second answer:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>We built a sort of Wikipedia website for computer programmers to post questions and answers. It&apos;s called <a href="https://stackoverflow.com">Stack Overflow</a></p></blockquote>]]></description><link>https://blog.codinghorror.com/what-does-stack-overflow-want-to-be-when-it-grows-up/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5bcd65fc65068a00bfbc3cc1</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Jeff Atwood]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 22 Oct 2018 10:52:32 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<!--kg-card-begin: markdown--><p>I sometimes get asked by regular people in the actual real world what it is that I do for a living, and here&apos;s my 15 second answer:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>We built a sort of Wikipedia website for computer programmers to post questions and answers. It&apos;s called <a href="https://stackoverflow.com">Stack Overflow</a>.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>As of last month, it&apos;s been 10 years since Joel Spolsky and I <a href="https://blog.codinghorror.com/stack-overflow-none-of-us-is-as-dumb-as-all-of-us/">started Stack Overflow</a>. I currently do <a href="https://blog.codinghorror.com/civilized-discourse-construction-kit/">other stuff now</a>, and I have since 2012, but if I will be known for anything when I&apos;m dead, clearly it is going to be good old Stack Overflow.</p>
<p>Here&apos;s where I&apos;d normally segue into a bunch of rah-rah stuff about how great Stack Overflow is, and thus how implicitly great I am by association for being a founder, and all.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.poorlydrawnlines.com/comic/bragging/"><img src="https://blog.codinghorror.com/content/images/2018/10/bragging.png" alt="bragging" loading="lazy"></a></p>
<p>I do not care about any of that.</p>
<p>What I do care about, though, is <em>whether Stack Overflow is useful to working programmers</em>. Let&apos;s check in with <a href="https://blog.codinghorror.com/you-dont-need-millions-of-dollars/">one of my idols</a>, John Carmack. How useful is Stack Overflow, from the perspective of what I consider to be one of the greatest living programmers?</p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-conversation="none" data-lang="en"><p lang="en" dir="ltr"><a href="https://twitter.com/StackExchange?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@StackExchange</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/codinghorror?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@codinghorror</a> SO has probably added billions of dollars of value to the world in increased programmer productivity.</p>&#x2014; John Carmack (@ID_AA_Carmack) <a href="https://twitter.com/ID_AA_Carmack/status/380018564792455168?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 17, 2013</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>
<p>I won&apos;t lie, September 17th, 2013 was a <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=O_05qJTeNNI">pretty good day</a>. I literally got chills when I read that, and not just because I always read the word &quot;billions&quot; in Carl Sagan&apos;s voice. It was also pleasantly the opposite of pretty much every <em>other</em> day I&apos;m on Twitter, scrolling through an oppressive, endless litany of shared human suffering and people screaming at each other. Which reminds me, I should <a href="https://twitter.com/codinghorror">check my Twitter</a> and see who else is wrong on the Internet today.</p>
<p>I am honored and humbled by the public utility that Stack Overflow has unlocked for a whole generation of programmers. But <em>I didn&apos;t do that</em>.</p>
<ul>
<li><em>You</em> did, when you contributed a well researched question to Stack Overflow.</li>
<li><em>You</em> did, when you contributed a succinct and clear answer to Stack Overflow.</li>
<li><em>You</em> did, when you edited a question or answer on Stack Overflow to make it better.</li>
</ul>
<p>All those &quot;fun size&quot; units of Q&amp;A collectively contributed by working programmers from all around the world ended up building a <a href="https://wiki.creativecommons.org/wiki/Case_Studies/StackOverflow.com">Creative Commons resource</a> that truly rivals Wikipedia within our field. That&apos;s ... incredible, actually.</p>
<p><img src="https://blog.codinghorror.com/content/images/2018/10/stack-overflow-homepage-oct-2018.png" alt="stack-overflow-homepage-oct-2018" loading="lazy"></p>
<p>But success stories are boring. The world is filled with people that <a href="https://blogs.scientificamerican.com/beautiful-minds/the-role-of-luck-in-life-success-is-far-greater-than-we-realized/">basically got lucky</a>, and subsequently can&apos;t stop telling people how it was all of their hard work and moxie that made it happen. I find failure much more instructive, and when building a business and planning for the future, I take on the role of Abyss Domain Expert&#x2122; and begin a staring contest. It&apos;s just a little something I like to do, you know ... <em>for me</em>.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/comics/comments/8a4c2h/abyss_oc/"><img src="https://blog.codinghorror.com/content/images/2018/10/abyss-oc.jpg" alt="abyss-oc" loading="lazy"></a></p>
<p>Thus, what I&apos;d like to do right now is peer into that glorious abyss for a bit and introspect about <strong>the challenges I see facing Stack Overflow for the next 10 years.</strong> Before I begin, I do want to be absolutely crystal clear about a few things:</p>
<ol>
<li>
<p>I have not worked at Stack Overflow in any capacity whatsoever <a href="https://blog.codinghorror.com/farewell-stack-exchange/">since February 2012</a> and I&apos;ve had zero day to day operational input since that date, more or less by choice. Do I have opinions about how things should be done? Uh, have you <em>met me?</em> Do I email people every now and then about said opinions? I might, but I honestly do try to keep it to an absolute minimum, and I think my email archive track record here is reasonable.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>The people working at Stack are amazing and most of them (including much of the Stack Overflow community, while I&apos;m at it) could articulate the mission better &#x2014; and perhaps a tad less crankily &#x2014; than I could by the time I left. Would I trust them with my life? No. But I&apos;d trust them with Joel&apos;s life!</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>The whole point of the Stack Overflow exercise is that it&apos;s not beholden to me, or Joel, or <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Great_man_theory">any other Great Person</a>. Stack Overflow works because it empowers regular everyday programmers all over the world, just like you, just like me. I guess in my mind it&apos;s akin to being a parent. The goal is for your children to eventually grow up to be sane, practicing adults who don&apos;t need (or, really, <em>want</em>) you to hang around any more.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Understand that you&apos;re reading <s>the weak opinions strongly held</s> <a href="https://blog.codinghorror.com/strong-opinions-weakly-held/">the strong opinions weakly held</a> of a co-founder who spent prodigious amounts of time working with the community in the first four years of Stack Overflow&apos;s life to shape the rules and norms of the site to fit their needs. These are merely my opinions. I like to think they are <em>informed</em> opinions, but that doesn&apos;t necessarily mean I can predict the future, or that I am even qualified to try. But I&apos;ve never let being &quot;qualified&quot; stop me from doing anything, and I ain&apos;t about to start tonight.</p>
</li>
</ol>
<h3 id="stackoverflowisawikifirst">Stack Overflow is a wiki first</h3>
<p>Stack Overflow ultimately has <em>much</em> more in common with Wikipedia than a discussion forum. By this I mean questions and answers on Stack Overflow are not primarily judged by their usefulness to a specific individual, but by <strong>how many <em>other</em> programmers that question or answer can potentially help over time</strong>. I tried as hard as I could to emphasize this relationship from <a href="https://blog.codinghorror.com/stack-overflow-none-of-us-is-as-dumb-as-all-of-us/">launch day in 2008</a>. Note who has top billing in this venn diagram.</p>
<p><img src="https://blog.codinghorror.com/content/images/2018/10/stack-overflow-venn-diagram.png" alt="stack-overflow-venn-diagram" loading="lazy"></p>
<p>Stack Overflow later added a super neat feature to highlight this core value in user profiles, where it shows how many other people you have potentially helped with your contributed questions and answers so far.</p>
<p><img src="https://blog.codinghorror.com/content/images/2018/10/stackoverflow-people-reached-profile-stat-1.png" alt="stackoverflow-people-reached-profile-stat-1" loading="lazy"></p>
<p>The most common complaints I see about Stack Overflow are usually the result of this fundamental misunderstanding about who the questions and answers on the site are ultimately <em>for</em>, and why there&apos;s so much strictness involved in the whole process.</p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-lang="en"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">I wish more people understood that the goal of Stack Overflow is not &quot;answer my question&quot; but &quot;let&apos;s collaboratively build an artifact that will benefit future coders&quot;. Perhaps SO could be doing more to educate people about this.</p>&#x2014; Jeff Atwood (@codinghorror) <a href="https://twitter.com/codinghorror/status/991082088689381376?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">April 30, 2018</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>
<p>I&apos;m continually amazed at the number of people, even on Hacker News today, who don&apos;t realize that every single question and answer is editable on Stack Overflow, even as a completely anonymous user who isn&apos;t logged in. Which makes sense, right, <em>because Stack Overflow is a wiki</em>, and that&apos;s how wikis work. Anyone can edit them. Go ahead, try it right now if you don&apos;t believe me &#x2014; press the &quot;improve this answer&quot; or &quot;improve this question&quot; button on anything that can be improved, and make it so.</p>
<p><img src="https://blog.codinghorror.com/content/images/2018/10/stack-overflow-edit-question.png" alt="stack-overflow-edit-question" loading="lazy"></p>
<p>The responsibility for this misunderstanding is all on Stack Overflow (and by that I also mean myself, at least up until 2012). I guess the logic is that &quot;every programmer has surely seen, used, and understands Stack Overflow by now, 10 years in&quot; but ... I think that&apos;s a risky assumption. New programmers are minted every second of every day. Complicating matters further, there are three tiers of usage at Stack Overflow, from biggest to smallest, in inverted pyramid style:</p>
<ol>
<li>
<p><strong>I passively search for programming answers.</strong></p>
<p>Passively searching and reading highly ranked Stack Overflow answers as they appear in web search results is arguably the <em>primary goal of Stack Overflow</em>. If Stack Overflow is working like it&apos;s supposed to, 98% of programmers should get all the answers they need from reading search result pages and wouldn&apos;t need to ask or answer a single question in their entire careers. This is a good thing! Great, even!</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>I participate on Stack Overflow when I get stuck on a really hairy problem and searching isn&apos;t helping.</strong></p>
<p>Participating only at those times when you are extra stuck is completely valid. However, I feel this level is where most people tend to run into difficulty on Stack Overflow, because it involves someone who may not be new to Stack Overflow per se, but is new to asking questions, and also at the precise time of stress and tension for them where they <em>must</em> get an answer due to a problem they&apos;re facing &#x2026; and they don&apos;t have the time or inclination to deal with Stack Overflow&apos;s strict wiki type requirements for research effort, formatting, showing previous work, and referencing what they found in prior searches.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>I participate on Stack Overflow for professional development.</strong></p>
<p>At this level you&apos;re talking about experienced Stack Overflow users who have contributed many answers and thus have a pretty good idea of what makes a great question, the kind they&apos;d want to answer themselves. As a result, they don&apos;t tend to ask many questions because they self-medicate through exhaustive searching and research, but when they do ask one, their questions are exemplary.</p>
</li>
</ol>
<p>(There&apos;s technically a fourth tier here, for people who want to selflessly contribute creative commons questions and answers to move the entire field of software development forward for the next generation of software developers. But who has time for saints &#x1F607;, y&apos;all make the rest of us look bad, so knock it off already Skeet.)</p>
<p>It wouldn&apos;t shock me at all if people spent <em>years</em> happily at tier 1 and then got a big unpleasant surprise when reaching tier 2. The primary place to deal with this, in my opinion, is a <strong>massively revamped and improved ask page</strong>. It&apos;s also fair to note that maybe people don&apos;t understand that they&apos;re signing up for a sizable chunk of work by implicitly committing to the wiki standard of &quot;try to make sure it&apos;s useful to more people than just yourself&quot; when asking a question on Stack Overflow, and are then  put off by the negative reaction to what others view as an insufficiently researched question.</p>
<p>Stack Overflow absorbs so much tension from its adoption of wiki standards for content. Even if you know about that requirement up front, it is not always clear what &quot;useful&quot; means, in the same way it&apos;s not always clear what topics, people, and places are deserving of a Wikipedia page. <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Henrietta_Lacks">Henrietta Lacks</a>, absolutely, but what about your cousin Dave in Omaha with his weirdo PHP 5.6 issue?</p>
<h3 id="overtimeduplicatesbecomevastlandminefields">Over time, duplicates become vast landmine fields</h3>
<p>Here&apos;s one thing <a href="https://stackoverflow.blog/2009/04/29/handling-duplicate-questions/">I really, really saw coming</a> and to be honest with you I was kinda glad I left in 2012 before I had to deal with it because of the incredible technical difficulty involved: <strong>duplicates</strong>. Of all the complaints I hear about Stack Overflow, this is the one I am most sympathetic to by far.</p>
<p>If you accept that Stack Overflow is a wiki type system, then for the same reasons that you obviously can&apos;t have five different articles about Italy on Wikipedia, <strong>Stack Overflow can&apos;t allow duplicate questions on the exact same programming problem</strong>. While there is a fair amount of code to do pre-emptive searches as people type in questions, plus <em>many</em> exhortations to search before you ask, with an inviting search field and button right there on the mandatory page you see before asking your first question ...</p>
<p><a href="https://stackoverflow.com/questions/ask/advice"><img src="https://blog.codinghorror.com/content/images/2018/10/stack-overflow-how-to-ask.jpg" alt="stack-overflow-how-to-ask" loading="lazy"></a></p>
<p>... locating and identifying duplicate content is an insanely difficult problem even for a company like Google that&apos;s done nothing but specialize in this exact problem for, what, 20 years now, with a veritable army of the world&apos;s most talented engineers.</p>
<p>When you&apos;re asking a question on a site that doesn&apos;t allow duplicate questions, the problem space of a site with 1 million existing questions is rather different from a site with 10 million existing questions ... or 100 million. Asking a single unique question goes from mildly difficult to mission almost impossible, because your question needs to thread a narrow path through this vast, enormous field of prior art questions without stepping on any of the vaguely similar looking landmines in the process.</p>
<p><img src="https://blog.codinghorror.com/content/images/2018/10/stackoverflow-asking-duplicate-question.png" alt="stackoverflow-asking-duplicate-question" loading="lazy"></p>
<p>But wait! <em>It gets harder!</em></p>
<ul>
<li>
<p><a href="https://stackoverflow.blog/2010/11/16/dr-strangedupe-or-how-i-learned-to-stop-worrying-and-love-duplication/">Some variance in similar-ish questions is OK</a>, because 10 different people will ask a nearly identical question using 10 different sets of completely unrelated words with no overlap. I know, it sounds crazy, but trust me: humans are amazing at this. We want all those duplicates to exist so they can <em>point to</em> the primary question they are a duplicate of, while still being valid search targets for people who ask questions with unusual or rare word choices.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>It can be legitimately difficult to determine if your question is a true duplicate. How much overlap is enough before one programming question is a duplicate of another? And by whose definition? Opinions vary. This is subject to human interpretation, and humans are.. unreliable. Nobody will ever be completely happy with this system, pretty much by design. That tension is baked in permanently and forever.</p>
</li>
</ul>
<p>I don&apos;t have any real answers on the duplicate problem, which only gets worse over time. But I will point out that there is plenty of precedent <a href="https://stackexchange.com/sites#traffic">on the Stack Exchange network</a> for splitting sites into &quot;expert&quot; and &quot;beginner&quot; areas with slightly different rulesets. We&apos;ve seen this for Math vs. MathOverflow, English vs. English Learners, Unix vs. Ubuntu... <strong>perhaps it&apos;s time for a more beginner focused Stack Overflow</strong> where duplicates are less frowned upon, and conversational rules are a bit more lenient?</p>
<h3 id="stackoverflowisacompetitivesystemofpeerreview">Stack Overflow is a competitive system of peer review</h3>
<p>Stack Overflow was indeed built to be a fairly explicitly competitive system, with the caveat that <a href="http://wiki.c2.com/?ThereIsMoreThanOneWayToDoIt">&quot;there&apos;s always more than one way to do it.&quot;</a> This design choice was based on my perennial observation that the best way to motivate any programmer .. is to subtly insinuate that <em>another</em> programmer could have maybe done it better.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.geekherocomic.com/2008/11/14/the-best-way-to-improve-code-performance/"><img src="https://blog.codinghorror.com/content/images/2018/10/geek-hero-motivating-programmers.png" alt="geek-hero-motivating-programmers" loading="lazy"></a></p>
<p>This is manifested in the public reputation system on Stack Overflow, the <a href="https://blog.codinghorror.com/for-a-bit-of-colored-ribbon/">incredible power of a number printed next to someone&apos;s name</a>, writ large. All reputation in Stack Overflow comes from the recognition of your peers, never the &quot;system&quot;.</p>
<p><img src="https://blog.codinghorror.com/content/images/2018/10/stack-overflow-top-rep-by-year.png" alt="stack-overflow-top-rep-by-year" loading="lazy"></p>
<p>Once your question is asked, or your answer is posted, it can then be poked, prodded, edited, flagged, closed, opened, upvoted, downvoted, <a href="http://www.cs.mun.ca/~harold/Courses/Old/CS1400.W15/Diary/Lubar1992.pdf">folded and spindled</a> by your peers. The <em>intent</em> is for Stack Overflow to be a system of peer review and friendly competition, like a code review from a coworker you&apos;ve never met at a different division of the company. It&apos;s also completely fair for a fellow programmer to question the premise of your question, as long as it&apos;s done in a nice way. For example, <a href="https://stackoverflow.com/questions/1732348/regex-match-open-tags-except-xhtml-self-contained-tags">do you <em>really</em> want to use that regular expression to match HTML?</a></p>
<p>I fully acknowledge that <strong>competitive peer review systems aren&apos;t for everyone</strong>, and thus the overall process of having peers review your question may not always feel great, depending on your circumstances and background in the field &#x2014; <em>particularly</em> when combined with the substantial tensions around utility and duplicates Stack Overflow already absorbed from its wiki elements. Kind of a double whammy there.</p>
<p>I&apos;ve heard people describe the process of asking a question on Stack Overflow as anxiety inducing. To me, posting on Stack Overflow is <em>supposed</em> to involve a healthy kind of minor &quot;let me be sure to show off my best work&quot; anxiety:</p>
<ul>
<li>the anxiety of giving a presentation to your fellow peers</li>
<li>the anxiety of doing well on a test</li>
<li>the anxiety of showing up to a new job with talented coworkers you admire</li>
<li>the anxiety of attending your first day at school with other students at your level</li>
</ul>
<p>I imagine systems where there is zero anxiety involved and I can only think of jobs where I had long since stopped caring about the work and thus had no anxiety about whether I even showed for work on any given day. How can that be good? Let&apos;s just say I&apos;m not a fan of zero-anxiety systems.</p>
<p>Maybe competition just isn&apos;t your jam. Could there be a less competitive Q&amp;A system, a system without downvotes, a system without close votes, where there was never any anxiety about posting anything, just a network of super supportive folks who believe in you and want you to succeed no matter what? Absolutely! I think many alternative sites <em>should</em> exist on the internet so people can choose an experience that matches their personal preferences and goals. Should Stack build that alternative? Has it already been built? It&apos;s an open question; feel free to point out examples in the comments.</p>
<h3 id="stackoverflowisdesignedforpracticingprogrammers">Stack Overflow is designed for practicing programmers</h3>
<p>Another point of confusion that comes up a fair bit is who the intended audience for Stack Overflow actually is. That one is straightforward, and it&apos;s  been the same from day one:</p>
<p><img src="https://blog.codinghorror.com/content/images/2018/10/stackoverflow-for-business-description.png" alt="stackoverflow-for-business-description" loading="lazy"></p>
<p>Q&amp;A for <strong>professional and enthusiast programmers</strong>. By that we mean</p>
<blockquote>
<p>People who either already have a job as a programmer, or could potentially be hired as a programmer today if they wanted to be.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Yes, in case you&apos;re wondering, part of this was an overt business decision. To make money you must have an audience of people already on a programmer&apos;s salary, or in the job hunt to be a programmer. The entire Stack Overflow network may be Creative Commons licensed, but it was never a non-profit play. It was planned as a sustainable business from the outset, and that&apos;s why <a href="https://blog.codinghorror.com/stack-overflow-careers-amplifying-your-awesome/">we launched Stack Overflow Careers</a> only one year after Stack Overflow itself ... to be honest far sooner than we should have, in retrospect. Careers has since been smartly subsumed into Stack Overflow proper at <a href="https://stackoverflow.com/jobs">stackoverflow.com/jobs</a> for a more integrated and most assuredly way-better-than-2009 experience.</p>
<p>The choice of audience wasn&apos;t meant to be an exclusionary decision in any way, but Stack Overflow was definitely designed as a fairly strict system of peer review, which is great (IMNSHO, obviously) for already practicing professionals, but <strong>pretty much everything you would <em>not</em> want as a student or beginner</strong>. This is why I cringe so hard I practically turn myself inside out when people on Twitter mention that they have pointed their students at Stack Overflow. What you&apos;d want for a beginner or a student in the field of programming is almost <em>the exact opposite</em> of what Stack Overflow does at every turn:</p>
<ul>
<li>one on one mentoring</li>
<li>real time collaborative screen sharing</li>
<li>live chat</li>
<li>theory and background courses</li>
<li>starter tasks and exercises</li>
<li>playgrounds to experiment in</li>
</ul>
<p>These are all very fine and good things, but Stack Overflow does <em>NONE</em> of them, by design.</p>
<p><em>Can</em> you use Stack Overflow to learn how to program from first principles? Well, technically you can do anything with any software. You could try to have actual conversations on Reddit, if you&apos;re a masochist. But the answer is yes. You could learn how to program on Stack Overflow, in theory, if you are a prodigy who is comfortable with the light competitive aspects (reputation, closing, downvoting) and also perfectly willing to define all your contributions to the site in terms of utility to others, not just yourself as a student attempting to learn things. But I <em>suuuuuuper</em> would not recommend it. There are <a href="https://blog.codinghorror.com/heres-the-programming-game-you-never-asked-for/">far better websites and systems out there for learning to be a programmer</a>. <em>Could</em> Stack Overflow build beginner and student friendly systems like this? I don&apos;t know, and it&apos;s certainly not my call to make. &#x1F914;</p>
<p>And that&apos;s it. We can now resume our normal non-abyss gazing. Or whatever it is that passes for normal in these times.</p>
<p>I hope all of this doesn&apos;t come across as negative. Overall I&apos;d say the state of the Stack is strong. But does it even matter what I think? <a href="https://stackoverflow.blog/2008/11/25/stack-overflow-is-you/">As it was in 2008</a>, so it is in 2018.</p>
<blockquote>
<p><strong>Stack Overflow is <em>you</em>.</strong></p>
<p>This is the scary part, the great leap of faith that Stack Overflow is predicated on: trusting your fellow programmers. The programmers who choose to participate in Stack Overflow are the &#x201C;secret sauce&#x201D; that makes it work. You are the reason I continue to believe in developer community as the greatest source of learning and growth. You are the reason I continue to get so many positive emails and testimonials about Stack Overflow. I can&#x2019;t take credit for that. But you can.</p>
<p>I learned the collective power of my fellow programmers long ago writing on Coding Horror. The community is far, far smarter than I will ever be. All I can ask &#x2014; all any of us can ask &#x2014; is to help each other along the path.</p>
<p>And if your fellow programmers decide to recognize you for that, then I say you&#x2019;ve well and truly earned it.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>The strength of Stack Overflow begins, and ends, with the <a href="https://meta.stackoverflow.com/">community of programmers that power the site</a>. What should Stack Overflow be when it grows up? <strong>Whatever we make it, together.</strong></p>
<p><img src="https://blog.codinghorror.com/content/images/2018/10/stackoverflow-none-of-us-is-as-dumb-as-all-of-us.jpg" alt="stackoverflow-none-of-us-is-as-dumb-as-all-of-us" loading="lazy"></p>
<p>p.s. Happy 10th anniversary Stack Overflow!</p>
<hr>
<p><small>Also see Joel&apos;s take on 10 years of Stack Overflow with <a href="https://www.joelonsoftware.com/2018/04/06/the-stack-overflow-age/">The Stack Overflow Age</a>, <a href="https://www.joelonsoftware.com/2018/04/13/gamification/">A Dusting of Gamification</a>, and <a href="https://www.joelonsoftware.com/2018/04/23/strange-and-maddening-rules/">Strange and Maddening Rules</a>.</small></p>
<!--kg-card-end: markdown-->]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[There is no longer any such thing as Computer Security]]></title><description><![CDATA[<!--kg-card-begin: markdown--><p>Remember &quot;cybersecurity&quot;?</p>
<p><img src="https://blog.codinghorror.com/content/images/2018/09/its-cybersecurity-yay.jpg" alt="its-cybersecurity-yay" loading="lazy"></p>
<p>Mysterious hooded computer guys doing mysterious hooded computer guy .. things! Who knows what kind of naughty digital mischief they might be up to?</p>
<p>Unfortunately, we now live in a world where this kind of digital mischief is literally rewriting the world&apos;s history. For proof</p>]]></description><link>https://blog.codinghorror.com/there-is-no-longer-any-such-thing-as-computer-security/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5ba48d62c848a600beccf034</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Jeff Atwood]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 21 Sep 2018 09:50:53 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<!--kg-card-begin: markdown--><p>Remember &quot;cybersecurity&quot;?</p>
<p><img src="https://blog.codinghorror.com/content/images/2018/09/its-cybersecurity-yay.jpg" alt="its-cybersecurity-yay" loading="lazy"></p>
<p>Mysterious hooded computer guys doing mysterious hooded computer guy .. things! Who knows what kind of naughty digital mischief they might be up to?</p>
<p>Unfortunately, we now live in a world where this kind of digital mischief is literally rewriting the world&apos;s history. For proof of that, you need look no further than this single email that was sent March 19th, 2016.</p>
<p><img src="https://blog.codinghorror.com/content/images/2018/09/podesta-hack-email-text.png" alt="podesta-hack-email-text" loading="lazy"></p>
<p>If you don&apos;t recognize what this is, it is a <a href="https://blog.codinghorror.com/phishing-the-forever-hack/">phishing email</a>.</p>
<p><a href="https://blog.codinghorror.com/phishing-the-forever-hack/"><img src="https://blog.codinghorror.com/content/images/2018/09/phishing-guy.jpg" alt="phishing-guy" loading="lazy"></a></p>
<p>This is by now a very, very famous phishing email, arguably the most famous of all time. But let&apos;s consider <a href="https://www.apnews.com/dea73efc01594839957c3c9a6c962b8a">how this email even got sent to its target in the first place</a>:</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>An attacker slurped up lists of any public emails of 2008 political campaign staffers.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>One 2008 staffer was <em>also</em> hired for the 2016 political campaign</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>That particular staffer had non-public campaign emails in their address book, and one of them was a powerful key campaign member with an extensive email history.</p>
</li>
</ul>
<p>On successful phish leads to an even wider address book attack net down the line. Once they gain access to a person&apos;s inbox, they use it to prepare to their next attack. They&apos;ll harvest existing email addresses, subject lines, content, and attachments to construct plausible looking boobytrapped emails and mail them to all of <em>their</em> contacts. How sophisticated and targeted to a particular person this effort is determines whether it&apos;s so-called &quot;spear&quot; phishing or not.</p>
<p><img src="https://blog.codinghorror.com/content/images/2018/09/phishing-vs-spear-phishing.png" alt="phishing-vs-spear-phishing" loading="lazy"></p>
<p>In this case is it was not at all targeted. This is a remarkably unsophisticated, absolutely generic routine phishing attack. There is zero focused attack effort on display here. But note the target did <em>not</em> immediately click the link in the email!</p>
<p><img src="https://blog.codinghorror.com/content/images/2018/09/podesta-hack-email-link-1.png" alt="podesta-hack-email-link-1" loading="lazy"></p>
<p>Instead, he did exactly what you&apos;d want a person to do in this scenario: <strong>he emailed IT support and asked if this email was valid.</strong> But IT made <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2016/12/13/us/politics/russia-hack-election-dnc.html">a fatal mistake in their response</a>.</p>
<p><img src="https://blog.codinghorror.com/content/images/2018/09/podesta-it-support-response.png" alt="podesta-it-support-response" loading="lazy"></p>
<p>Do you see it? Here&apos;s the kicker:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Mr. Delavan, in an interview, said that his bad advice was a result of a typo: He knew this was a phishing attack, as the campaign was getting dozens of them. He said <strong>he had meant to type that it was an &#x201C;illegitimate&#x201D; email, an error that he said has plagued him ever since.</strong></p>
</blockquote>
<p>One word. He got <em>one</em> word wrong. But what a word to get wrong, and in the first sentence! The email did provide the proper Google address to reset your password. But the lede was already buried since the first sentence said &quot;legitimate&quot;; the phishing link in that email was then clicked. And the rest is literally history.</p>
<p>What&apos;s even funnier (well, in the way of gallows humor, I guess) is that public stats were left enabled for that bit.ly tracking link, so you can see exactly what crazy domain that &quot;Google login page&quot; resolved to, and that it was clicked exactly twice, on the same day it was mailed.</p>
<p><img src="https://blog.codinghorror.com/content/images/2018/09/bitly-podesta-tracking-link.png" alt="bitly-podesta-tracking-link" loading="lazy"></p>
<p>As I said, these were not exactly sophisticated attackers. So yeah, in <em>theory</em> an attentive user could pay attention to the browser&apos;s address bar and notice that after clicking the link, they arrived at</p>
<p><code>http://myaccount.google.com-securitysettingpage.tk/security/signinoptions/password</code></p>
<p>instead of</p>
<p><code>https://myaccount.google.com/security</code></p>
<p>Note that the phishing URL is carefully constructed so the most &quot;correct&quot; part is at the front, and weirdness is sandwiched in the middle. Unless you&apos;re paying very close attention and your address bar is long enough to expose the full URL, it&apos;s &#x2026; tricky. See this 10 second video for a dramatic example.</p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-lang="en"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Quick phishing demo. Would you fall for something like this? <a href="https://t.co/phONMKHBle">pic.twitter.com/phONMKHBle</a></p>&#x2014; Mustafa Al-Bassam (@musalbas) <a href="https://twitter.com/musalbas/status/1038919152826757122?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 9, 2018</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>
<p>(And if you think that one&apos;s good, check out <a href="https://twitter.com/tomscott/status/812265182646927361">this one</a>. Don&apos;t forget all the unicode look-alike trickery you can pull, too.)</p>
<p>I originally wrote this post as a presentation for the Berkeley Computer Science Club back in March, and at that time I gathered a list of public phishing pages I found on the web.</p>
<p><code>nightlifesofl.com</code><br>
<code>ehizaza-limited.com</code><br>
<code>tcgoogle.com</code><br>
<code>appsgoogie.com</code><br>
<code>security-facabook.com</code></p>
<p>Of those five examples from 6 months ago, one is completely gone, one loads just fine, and three present an appropriately scary red interstitial warning page that strongly advises you not to visit the page you&apos;re trying to visit, courtesy of Google&apos;s <a href="https://developers.google.com/safe-browsing/">safe browsing API</a>. But of course this kind of shared blacklist domain name protection will be completely useless on any fresh phishing site. (Don&apos;t even get me started on how <a href="https://blog.codinghorror.com/blacklists-dont-work/">blacklists have never really worked</a> anyway.)</p>
<p><img src="https://blog.codinghorror.com/content/images/2018/09/google-login-phishing-page.png" alt="google-login-phishing-page" loading="lazy"></p>
<p>It doesn&apos;t exactly require a PhD degree in computer science to phish someone:</p>
<ul>
<li>Buy a crazy long, realistic looking domain name.</li>
<li>Point it to a cloud server somewhere.</li>
<li>Get a free HTTPS certificate courtesy of <a href="https://blog.codinghorror.com/lets-encrypt-everything/">our friends at Let&apos;s Encrypt</a>.</li>
<li>Build a realistic copy of a login page that silently transmits everything you type in those login fields to you &#x2013; perhaps even in real time, as the target types.</li>
<li>Harvest email addresses and mass mail a plausible looking phishing email with your URL.</li>
</ul>
<p>I want to emphasize that although clearly mistakes were made in this specific situation, none of the people involved here were amateurs. They had training and experience. They were working with IT and security professionals. Furthermore, they <a href="https://www.apnews.com/dea73efc01594839957c3c9a6c962b8a">knew digital attacks were incoming</a>.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The &#x2026; campaign was no easy target; several former employees said the organization put particular stress on digital safety.</p>
<p>Work emails were protected by two-factor authentication, a technique that uses a second passcode to keep accounts secure. Most messages were deleted after 30 days and staff went through phishing drills. Security awareness even followed the campaigners into the bathroom, where someone put a picture of a toothbrush under the words: &#x201C;You shouldn&#x2019;t share your passwords either.&#x201D;</p>
</blockquote>
<p>The campaign itself used two factor auth extensively, which is why personal gmail accounts were targeted, because they were less protected.</p>
<p>The key takeaway here is that <strong>it&apos;s basically impossible, statistically speaking, to prevent your organization from being phished.</strong></p>
<p>Or is it?</p>
<p><a href="https://techsolidarity.org"><img src="https://blog.codinghorror.com/content/images/2018/09/techsolidarity-logo.png" alt="techsolidarity-logo" loading="lazy"></a></p>
<p>Nobody is doing better work in this space right now than Maciej Ceglowski and Tech Solidarity. Their list of <a href="https://techsolidarity.org/resources/basic_security.htm">basic security precautions for non-profits and journalists</a> is pure gold and has been vetted by many industry professionals with security credentials that are actually impressive, unlike mine. Everyone should read this list very closely, point by point.</p>
<p>Everyone?</p>
<p>Computers, courtesy of smartphones, are <a href="https://blog.codinghorror.com/can-software-make-you-less-racist/">now such a pervasive part of average life for average people</a> that <strong>there is no longer any such thing as &quot;computer security&quot;. There is only <em>security</em>.</strong> In other words, these are normal security practices <em>everyone</em> should be familiar with. Not just computer geeks. Not just political activists and politicians. Not just journalists and nonprofits.</p>
<video poster="/content/images/2018/09/gary-oldman-everyone-poster.jpg" preload="none" controls style="max-width:100%">
<source src="http://discourse-cdn.codinghorror.com/uploads/default/original/3X/2/4/2483fdc1eb5585ebd550bba1614d229da2f2987c.mp4">
</video>
<p><em>Everyone.</em></p>
<p>It is a fair bit of reading, so because I know you are just as lazy as I am, and I am <em>epically</em> lazy, let me summarize what I view as the three important takeaways from the hard work Tech Solidarity put into <a href="https://techsolidarity.org/resources.html">these resources</a>. These three short sentences are the 60 second summary of what you want to do, and what you want to share with others so <em>they</em> do, too.</p>
<p><strong>1) Enable Two Factor authentication through an app, and <em>not SMS</em>, everywhere you can.</strong></p>
<p><img src="https://blog.codinghorror.com/content/images/2018/09/google-2fa-1.png" alt="google-2fa-1" loading="lazy"></p>
<p>Logging in with only a password, now matter how long and unique you attempt to make that password, will never be enough. A password is what you know; you need to add the second factor of something you <em>have</em> (or something you <em>are</em>) to achieve significant additional security. SMS can famously <a href="https://www.wired.com/story/phone-numbers-indentification-authentication/">be intercepted, social engineered, or sim-jacked all too easily</a>. If it&apos;s SMS, it&apos;s not secure, <em>period</em>. So install an authenticator app, and use it, at least for your most important credentials such as your email account and your bank.</p>
<p>Have I mentioned that Discourse <a href="https://blog.discourse.org/2018/05/discourse-2-0-released/">added two factor authentication support in version 2.0</a>, and our just released 2.1 adds printed backup codes, too? There are two paths forward: you can <em>talk</em> about the solution, or you can <em>build</em> the solution. I&apos;m trying to do both to the best of my ability. Look for the 2FA auth option in your user preferences on your favorite Discourse instance. It&apos;s there for you.</p>
<p>(This is also a company policy at Discourse; if you work here, <em>you 2FA everything all the time</em>. No other login option exists.)</p>
<p><strong>2) Make all your passwords 11 characters or more.</strong></p>
<p>It&apos;s a <a href="https://blog.codinghorror.com/hacker-hack-thyself/">long story</a>, but anything under 11 characters <a href="https://blog.codinghorror.com/your-password-is-too-damn-short/">is basically the same as having no password at all</a> these days. I personally recommend at least 14 characters, maybe even 16. But this won&apos;t be a problem for you, because...</p>
<p><strong>3) Use a password manager.</strong></p>
<p>If you use a password manager, you can simultaneously avoid the pernicious danger of password re-use and <a href="https://blog.codinghorror.com/password-rules-are-bullshit/">the difficulty of coming up with unique and random passwords</a> all the time. It is my hope in the long run that cloud based password management gets deeply built into Android, iOS, OSX, and Windows so that people don&apos;t need to run a weird melange of third party apps to achieve this essential task. Password management is foundational and should not be the province of third parties on principle, because you never outsource a core competency.</p>
<p><strong>Bonus rule! For the particularly at-risk, get and use a U2F key.</strong></p>
<p>In the long term, two factor through an app isn&apos;t quite secure enough due to the very real (and growing) specter of real-time phishing. Authentication apps offer timed keys that expire after a minute or two, but if the attacker can get you to type an authentication key and relay it to the target site fast enough, they can still log in as you. If you need ultimate protection, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Universal_2nd_Factor">look into U2F keys</a>.</p>
<p><img src="https://blog.codinghorror.com/content/images/2018/09/u2f-keys.jpg" alt="u2f-keys" loading="lazy"></p>
<p>I believe U2F support is still too immature at the moment, particularly on mobile, for this to be practical for the average person right now. But if you do happen to fall into those groups that will be under attack, you <em>absolutely</em> want to set up U2F keys where you can today. They&apos;re cheap, and the good news is that  they <em>literally make phishing impossible</em> at last. Given that Google had <a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2018/07/google-security-keys-neutralized-employee-phishing/">100% company wide success against phishing with U2F</a>, we know this works.</p>
<p>In today&apos;s world, computers are now so omnipresent that there is no longer any such thing as cybersecurity, online security, or computer security &#x2013; there&apos;s only <em>security</em>. You either have it, or you don&apos;t. If you follow and share these three rules, hopefully you too can have a modicum of security today.</p>
<!--kg-card-end: markdown-->]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[To Serve Man, with Software]]></title><description><![CDATA[<!--kg-card-begin: markdown--><p>I didn&apos;t choose to be a programmer. Somehow, it seemed, <a href="https://blog.codinghorror.com/if-loving-computers-is-wrong-i-dont-want-to-be-right/">the computers chose me</a>. For a long time, that was fine, that was enough; that was all I needed. But along the way I never felt that being a programmer was this <a href="https://blog.codinghorror.com/please-dont-learn-to-code/">unambiguously great-for-everyone</a> career field with zero</p>]]></description><link>https://blog.codinghorror.com/to-serve-man-with-software/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5a481e5fb392750022285b5b</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Jeff Atwood]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2017 02:01:52 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<!--kg-card-begin: markdown--><p>I didn&apos;t choose to be a programmer. Somehow, it seemed, <a href="https://blog.codinghorror.com/if-loving-computers-is-wrong-i-dont-want-to-be-right/">the computers chose me</a>. For a long time, that was fine, that was enough; that was all I needed. But along the way I never felt that being a programmer was this <a href="https://blog.codinghorror.com/please-dont-learn-to-code/">unambiguously great-for-everyone</a> career field with zero downsides. There are absolutely occupational hazards of being a programmer, and <a href="https://blog.codinghorror.com/your-favorite-programming-quote/">one of my favorite programming quotes</a> is an allusion to one of them:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>It should be noted that no ethically-trained software engineer would ever consent to write a <code>DestroyBaghdad</code> procedure. Basic professional ethics would instead require him to write a <code>DestroyCity</code> procedure, to which Baghdad could be given as a parameter.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Which reminds me of <a href="https://waxy.org/2015/12/tracking_the_trump_is_a_comment_section_running_for_president_joke/">another joke that people were telling in 2015</a>:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Donald Trump is basically a comment section running for president</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Which is troubling because technically, <em>technically</em>, I run a company that <a href="https://discourse.org">builds comment sections</a>.</p>
<p>Here at the tail end of 2017, from where I sit neither of these jokes seem particularly funny to me any more. Perhaps I have lost the capacity to feel joy as a human being? <em>Haha just kidding!</em> <em>... kinda.</em></p>
<p>Remember <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/SB10001424053111903480904576512250915629460">in 2011</a> when Marc Andreeseen said that &quot;Software is eating the world?&quot;</p>
<p><img src="https://blog.codinghorror.com/content/images/2017/12/software-is-eating-the-world-marc-andreessen.jpg" alt="software is eating the world, Marc Andreessen" loading="lazy"></p>
<p>That used to sound all hip and cool and inspirational, like &quot;Wow! We software developers really <em>are</em> making a difference in the world!&quot; and now for the life of me I can&apos;t read it as anything other than an ominous warning that we just weren&apos;t smart enough to translate properly at the time. But <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/To_Serve_Man_(The_Twilight_Zone)">maybe now we are</a>.</p>
<p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/To_Serve_Man_(The_Twilight_Zone)"><img src="https://blog.codinghorror.com/content/images/2017/12/to-serve-man.jpg" alt="to-serve-man" loading="lazy"></a></p>
<p>I&apos;ve said many, many times that the key to becoming an experienced software developer is to understand that you are, at all times, <a href="https://blog.codinghorror.com/on-the-meaning-of-coding-horror/">your own worst enemy</a>. I don&apos;t mean this in a negative way &#x2013; you have to constantly plan for and design around your inevitable human mistakes and fallibility. It&apos;s fundamental to good software engineering because, well, we&apos;re all human. The good-slash-bad news is that you&apos;re only <a href="https://blog.codinghorror.com/the-trap-you-set-for-yourself/"><em>accidentally</em> out to get yourself</a>. But what happens when we&apos;re infinitely connected and software is suddenly <em>everywhere</em>, in everyone&apos;s pockets every moment of the day, starting to approximate a natural extension of our bodies? All of a sudden those little collective social software accidents become <a href="https://www.wired.com/story/the-other-tech-bubble/">considerably more dangerous</a>:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The issue is bigger than any single scandal, I told him. As headlines have exposed the troubling inner workings of company after company, startup culture no longer feels like fodder for gentle parodies about ping pong and hoodies. It feels ugly and rotten. Facebook, the greatest startup success story of this era, isn&#x2019;t a merry band of hackers building cutesy tools that allow you to digitally Poke your friends. It&#x2019;s a powerful and potentially sinister collector of personal data, a propaganda partner to government censors, and an enabler of discriminatory advertising.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>I&apos;m reminded of a particular Mitchell and Webb skit: <em>&quot;Are we the baddies?&quot;</em></p>
<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/qv2XGQBcvxQ" frameborder="0" gesture="media" allow="encrypted-media" allowfullscreen></iframe>
<p>On the topic of unanticipated downsides to technology, there is no show more essential than <a href="https://www.netflix.com/title/70264888">Black Mirror</a>. If you haven&apos;t watched Black Mirror yet, do not pass go, do not collect $200, go immediately to Netflix and watch it. Go on! Go ahead!</p>
<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/jDiYGjp5iFg" frameborder="0" gesture="media" allow="encrypted-media" allowfullscreen></iframe>
<blockquote>
<p>&#x26A0; Fair warning: please DO NOT start with season 1 episode 1 of Black Mirror! Start with season 3, and go forward. If you like those, dip into season 2 and the just-released season 4, then the rest. But humor me and please at least watch the first episode of season 3.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>The technology described in Black Mirror can be fanciful at times, but several episodes portray disturbingly plausible scenarios with <em>today&apos;s</em> science and tech, much less what we&apos;ll have 20 to 50 years from now. These are very real cautionary tales, and some of this stuff is well on its way toward being realized.</p>
<p>Programmers don&apos;t think of themselves as people with the power to change the world. Most programmers I know, including myself, grew up as nerds, geeks, social outcasts. Did I ever tell you about the time I wrote a self-destructing Apple // boot disk program to let a girl in middle school know that I liked her? I was (and still am) a terrible programmer, but oh man did I ever test the heck out of <em>that</em> code before copying on to her school floppy disc. But I digress. What do you do when you wake up one day and software <em>has</em> kind of eaten the world, and <strong>it is no longer clear if software is in fact an unambiguously good thing, like we thought, like everyone told us &#x2026; like we <em>wanted it to be?</em></strong></p>
<p>Months ago I submitted a brief interview for a <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/1465462333/?tag=codihorr-20">children&apos;s book about coding</a>.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/1465462333/?tag=codihorr-20"><img src="https://blog.codinghorror.com/content/images/2017/12/9780241285060.jpg" width="400"></a></p>
<p>I recently recieved a complimentary copy of the book in the mail. I paged to <a href="https://blog.codinghorror.com/content/images/2017/12/dk-findout-coding-page-50.jpg">my short interview</a>, alongside the very cool <a href="http://www.prottsman.com/">Kiki Prottsman</a>. I had no real recollection of the interview questions after the months of lead time it takes to print a physical book, but reading the printed page, I suddenly hit myself over the head with the very answer I had been searching my soul for these past 6 months:</p>
<p><a href="https://blog.codinghorror.com/content/images/2017/12/dk-findout-coding-page-50.jpg"><img src="https://blog.codinghorror.com/content/images/2017/12/dk-findout-coding-page-50-quote.jpg" alt="Jeff Atwood quote: what do you love most about coding?" loading="lazy"></a></p>
<p>In attempting to simplify my answers for an audience of kids, I had concisely articulated the one thing that keeps me coming back to software: <strong>to serve man</strong>. Not on a platter, for bullshit monetization &#x2013; but software that <a href="https://blog.codinghorror.com/the-just-in-time-theory/">helps people</a> be the best version of themselves.</p>
<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/cNi_HC839Wo?start=118" frameborder="0" gesture="media" allow="encrypted-media" allowfullscreen></iframe>
<p>And you know why I do it? I need that help, too. I get tired, angry, upset, emotional, cranky, irritable, frustrated and I need to be reminded from time to time to choose to be the better version of myself. I don&apos;t always succeed. But <em>I want to</em>. And I believe everyone else &#x2013; for some reasonable statistical value of everyone else &#x2013; fundamentally does, too.</p>
<p>That was the not-so-secret design philosophy behind Stack Overflow, that <strong>by helping others become better programmers, you too would become a better programmer</strong>. It&apos;s unavoidable. And, even better, if we leave enough helpful breadcrumbs behind for those that follow us, <em>we collectively advance the whole of programming for everyone</em>.</p>
<p>I apologize for not blogging much in 2017.  I&apos;ve certainly been busy with Discourse which is actually going great; we grew to 21 people and <a href="https://blog.discourse.org/2017/12/discourse-gives-back-2017/">gave $55,000 back</a> this year to the open source ecosystem we build on. But that&apos;s no excuse. The truth is that it&apos;s been hard to write because this has been a deeply troubling year in so many dimensions &#x2014; for men, for tech, for American democracy. I&apos;m ashamed of much that happened, and I think one of the first and most important steps we can take is to <a href="https://blog.codinghorror.com/the-hugging-will-continue-until-morale-improves/">embrace explicit codes of conduct</a> throughout our industry. I also continue to believe, if we start to think more holistically about what our software can do to <strong>serve all people</strong>, not just ourselves personally (or, even worse, the company we work for) &#x2014; that software can and should be part of the solution.</p>
<p>I tried to amplify on these thoughts in recent podcasts:</p>
<table>
    <tr>
        <td><img src="https://blog.codinghorror.com/content/images/2017/12/kim-crayton.jpg" width="100" height="100"></td>
        <td>&#xA0;<a href="http://www.kimcrayton.com/commengreport-jeff-atwood/">Community Engineering Report</a> with Kim Crayton</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
        <td><img src="https://blog.codinghorror.com/content/images/2017/12/dave-rael.jpg" width="100" height="100"></td>
        <td>&#xA0;<a href="http://developeronfire.com/podcast/episode-258-jeff-atwood-sharing-the-house">Developer on Fire</a> with Dave Rael</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
        <td><img src="https://blog.codinghorror.com/content/images/2017/12/william-channer.jpg" width="100" height="100"></td>
        <td>&#xA0;<a href="https://drt.fm/jeff-atwood">Dorm Room Tycoon</a> with William Channer</td>
    </tr>
</table>
<p>Software is easy to change, but people ... aren&apos;t. So in the new year, as software developers, let&apos;s make a resolution to focus on the part we <em>can</em> change, and keep asking ourselves one very important question: <strong>how can our software help people become the best version of themselves?</strong></p>
<!--kg-card-end: markdown-->]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Existential Terror of Battle Royale]]></title><description><![CDATA[<!--kg-card-begin: markdown--><p>It&apos;s been a while since I wrote a blog post, I guess in general, but also a blog post about video games. Video games are probably <a href="https://www.google.com/search?q=site%3Ablog.codinghorror.com+%22video+games%22">the single thing most attributable to my career as a programmer</a>, and everything else I&apos;ve done professionally after that. I</p>]]></description><link>https://blog.codinghorror.com/the-existential-terror-of-battle-royale/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">59fc20474dd8920022728f05</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Jeff Atwood]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2017 10:02:53 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<!--kg-card-begin: markdown--><p>It&apos;s been a while since I wrote a blog post, I guess in general, but also a blog post about video games. Video games are probably <a href="https://www.google.com/search?q=site%3Ablog.codinghorror.com+%22video+games%22">the single thing most attributable to my career as a programmer</a>, and everything else I&apos;ve done professionally after that. I still feel video games are one of the best ways to learn and teach programming, <a href="https://blog.codinghorror.com/heres-the-programming-game-you-never-asked-for/">if properly scoped</a>, and furthermore I take <a href="https://blog.codinghorror.com/level-one-the-intro-stage/">many cues from video games in building software</a>.</p>
<p>I would characterize my state of mind for the last six to eight months as &#x2026; <em>poor</em>. Not only because of <a href="https://blog.codinghorror.com/im-loyal-to-nothing-except-the-dream/">current events in the United States</a>, though the neverending barrage of bad news weighs heavily on me, and I continue to be profoundly disturbed by the erosion of core values that I thought most of us stood for as Americans. Didn&apos;t we used to look out for each other, care about each other, and fight to protect those that can&apos;t protect themselves?</p>
<p>In times like these, I sometimes turn to video games for escapist entertainment. One game in particular caught my attention because of its meteoric rise in player count over the last year.</p>
<p><a href="http://steamcharts.com/app/578080"><img src="https://blog.codinghorror.com/content/images/2017/11/pubg-steam-stats-nov-2017.png" alt="pubg-steam-stats-nov-2017" loading="lazy"></a></p>
<p>That game is <a href="http://store.steampowered.com/app/578080/PLAYERUNKNOWNS_BATTLEGROUNDS/">Player Unknown&apos;s Battlegrounds</a>. I was increasingly curious why it was so popular, and kept getting more popular every month. Calling it a mere phenomenon seems like underselling it; something truly unprecedented is happening here. I finally broke down and bought a copy for $30 in September.</p>
<p><img src="https://blog.codinghorror.com/content/images/2017/11/player-unknown-battleground.jpg" alt="player-unknown-battleground" loading="lazy"></p>
<p>After a few hours in, I had major flashbacks to <a href="https://blog.codinghorror.com/the-gamification/">the first time I played Counter-Strike in 1998</a>. I realized that <strong>we are witnessing the birth of an entirely new genre of game: the Battle Royale</strong>. I absolutely believe that huge numbers of people will still be playing some form of this game 20 years from now, too.</p>
<p><a href="http://store.steampowered.com/stats/"><img src="https://blog.codinghorror.com/content/images/2017/11/steam-top-games-by-player-count-nov-2017.png" alt="steam-top-games-by-player-count-nov-2017" loading="lazy"></a></p>
<p>I&apos;ve seen <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Battle_Royale_(film)">the Japanese movie</a>, and it&apos;s true that there were <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Battle_royale_game">a few Battle Royale games</a> before PUBG, but this is clearly the defining moment and game for the genre, the one that sets a precedent for everyone else to follow.</p>
<p>It&apos;s hard to explain why Battlegrounds is so compelling, but let&apos;s start with the loneliness.</p>
<p>Although you can play in squads (and I recommend it), the purest original form of the game is 100 players, last man standing. You begin with nothing but the clothes on your back, in a cargo aircraft, flying over an unknown island in a random trajectory.</p>
<p><img src="https://blog.codinghorror.com/content/images/2017/11/battlegrounds-cargo-plane.jpg" alt="battlegrounds-cargo-plane" loading="lazy"></p>
<p>It&apos;s up to you to decide when to drop, and where to land on this huge island, full of incredibly detailed cities, buildings and houses &#x2013; but strangely devoid of all life.</p>
<p><img src="https://blog.codinghorror.com/content/images/2017/11/playerunknown-battleground-drop.jpg" alt="playerunknown-battleground-drop" loading="lazy"></p>
<p>What happened to everyone? Where did they go? The sense of apocalypse is overwhelming. It&apos;s you versus the world, but where did the rest of the world go? You&apos;ll wander this vast deserted island, scavenging for weapons and armor in near complete silence. You&apos;ll hear nothing but the wind blowing and the occasional buzzing of flies. But then, suddenly the jarring pak-pak-pak of gunfire off in the distance, reminding you that other people are here. And they aren&apos;t your friends.</p>
<p><img src="https://blog.codinghorror.com/content/images/2017/11/battle-royale-vista.jpg" alt="battle-royale-vista" loading="lazy"></p>
<p>the dread of never knowing when another of the 100 players on this enormous island is going to suddenly appear around a corner or over a hill is <em>intense</em>. You&apos;ll find yourself wearing headphones, cranking the volume, constantly on edge listening for the implied threat of footfalls. Wait, did I hear someone just now, or was that me? You clench, and wait. I&apos;ve had so many visceral panic moments playing this game, to the point that I had to stop playing just to calm down.</p>
<p><img src="https://blog.codinghorror.com/content/images/2017/11/pubg-combat.jpg" alt="pubg-combat" loading="lazy"></p>
<p>PUBG is, in its way, the scariest zombie movie I&apos;ve ever seen, though it lacks a single zombie. It dispenses with the pretense of a story, so you can realize much sooner that the zombies, as terrible as they may be, are nowhere as dangerous to you as your fellow man.</p>
<p>Meanwile, that huge cargo airplane still roars overhead every so often, impassive, indifferent, occasionally dropping supply crates with high powered items to fight over. Airstrikes randomly target areas circled in red on the map, masking footfalls, and forcing movement while raining arbitrary death and terror.</p>
<p><img src="https://blog.codinghorror.com/content/images/2017/11/pubg-map.jpg" alt="pubg-map" loading="lazy"></p>
<p>Although the island is huge and you can land anywhere, after a few minutes a random circle is overlaid on the map, and a slowly moving wall of deadly energy starts closing in on that circle. Stay outside that circle at your peril; if you find yourself far on the opposite side of the map from a circle, you better start hunting for a vehicle or boat (they&apos;re present, but rare) quickly. These terrordome areas are always shrinking, always impending, in an ever narrowing cone, forcing the remaining survivors closer and closer together. The circles get tighter and deadlier and quicker as the game progresses, ratcheting up the tension and conflict.</p>
<p>Eventually the circle becomes so small that it&apos;s impossible for the handful of remaining survivors to avoid contact, and one person, <em>one</em> out of the hundred that originally dropped out of the cargo plane, emerges as the winner. I&apos;ve never won solo, but I have won squad, and even finishing first out of 25 squads is an unreal, euphoric experience. The odds are so incredibly against you from the outset, plus you quickly discover that 85% of the game is straight up chance: someone happens to roll up behind you, a sniper gets the drop on you, or you get caught in the open with few options. Wrong place, wrong time, game over. Sucks to be you.</p>
<p><img src="https://blog.codinghorror.com/content/images/2017/11/pubg-vehicle-shooting.jpg" alt="pubg-vehicle-shooting" loading="lazy"></p>
<p>You definitely learn to be careful, but there&apos;s only so careful you can be. Death comes quickly, without warning, and often at random. What else can you expect from a game mode where there are 100 players but only 1 eventual winner?</p>
<p>There haven&apos;t been many Battle Royale games, so this game mode is a relatively new phenomenon. If you&apos;d like to give it a try for free, <strong>I highly recommend <a href="https://www.epicgames.com/fortnite/">Fortnite&apos;s Battle Royale mode</a> which is 100% free, a near-clone of PUBG, and quite good in its own right.</strong> They added their Battle Royale mode well after the fact; the core single player &quot;save the world&quot; gameplay of building stuff and fighting zombie hordes is quite fun too, though a bit shallow. It also has what is, in my opinion, some of the most outstanding visual style I&apos;ve ever seen in a game &#x2013; a cool, hyperbolic cartoon mix of Chuck Jones, Sam &amp; Max, and Cloudy with a Chance of Meatballs. It&apos;s also delightfully diverse in its character models.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.epicgames.com/fortnite/"><img src="https://blog.codinghorror.com/content/images/2017/11/fortnite-battle-royale.jpg" alt="fortnite-battle-royale" loading="lazy"></a></p>
<p>(The only things you&apos;ll give up over PUBG are the realistic art style, vehicles, and going prone. But the superb structure building system in Fortnite <em>almost</em> makes up for that. If nothing else it is a demonstration of how incredibly compelling the Battle Royale game mode is, because that part of the game is <a href="https://www.pcgamesn.com/fortnite/fortnite-battle-royale-player-numbers">wildly successful</a> in a a way that the core game, uh, wasn&apos;t. Also it&apos;s free!)</p>
<p>I didn&apos;t intend for this to happen, but to me, <strong>the Battle Royale game mode perfectly captures the zeitgeist of the current moment</strong>, and matches my current state of mind to a disturbing degree. It&apos;s an absolutely terrifying experience of every human for themselves, winner takes all, with impossible odds. There are moments it can be thrilling, even inspiring, but mostly it&apos;s brutal and unforgiving. To succeed you need to be exceedingly cautious, highly skilled, and just plain <em>lucky</em>. Roll the dice again, but know that everyone will run towards the sound of gunfire in hopes of picking off survivors and looting their corpses. Including you.</p>
<p>Battle Royale is not the game mode we wanted, it&apos;s not the game mode we needed, it&apos;s the game mode we all <em>deserve</em>. And the best part is, when we&apos;re done playing, we can turn it off.</p>
<!--kg-card-end: markdown-->]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Hacker, Hack Thyself]]></title><description><![CDATA[<!--kg-card-begin: markdown--><p>We&apos;ve read so many sad stories about communities that were fatally compromised or destroyed due to security exploits. We took that lesson to heart when we founded the <a href="https://discourse.org">Discourse</a> project; we endeavor to build open source software that is secure and safe for communities by default, even if</p>]]></description><link>https://blog.codinghorror.com/hacker-hack-thyself/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5988f60721f57d0019a2e12b</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Jeff Atwood]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jun 2017 08:11:16 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<!--kg-card-begin: markdown--><p>We&apos;ve read so many sad stories about communities that were fatally compromised or destroyed due to security exploits. We took that lesson to heart when we founded the <a href="https://discourse.org">Discourse</a> project; we endeavor to build open source software that is secure and safe for communities by default, even if there are thousands, or millions, of them out there.</p>
<p>However, we also value <em>portability</em>, the ability to get your data into and out of Discourse at will. This is why Discourse, unlike other forum software, defaults to a Creative Commons license. As a basic user on any Discourse you can easily export and download all your posts right from your user page.</p>
<p><img src="https://blog.codinghorror.com/content/images/2017/06/discourse-download-all.png" alt="Discourse Download All Posts" loading="lazy"></p>
<p>As a site owner, you can easily back up and restore your entire site database from the admin panel, right in your web browser. Automated weekly backups are set up for you out of the box, too. I&apos;m not <a href="https://blog.codinghorror.com/international-backup-awareness-day/">the world&apos;s foremost expert on backups</a> for nothing, man!</p>
<p><img src="https://blog.codinghorror.com/content/images/2017/06/discourse-backups.png" alt="Discourse database backup download" loading="lazy"></p>
<p>Over the years, we&apos;ve learned that balancing security and data portability can be tricky.  You bet your sweet ASCII a <strong>full database download</strong> is what hackers start working toward the minute they gain any kind of foothold in your system. It&apos;s the ultimate prize.</p>
<p>To mitigate this threat, we&apos;ve slowly tightened restrictions around Discourse backups in various ways:</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Administrators have a minimum password length of 15 characters.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Both backup creation and backup download administrator actions are formally logged.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Backup download tokens are single use and emailed to the address of the administrator, to confirm that user has full control over the email address.</p>
</li>
</ul>
<p>The name of the security game is defense in depth, so all these hardening steps help &#x2026; but we still need to <strong>assume that Internet Bad Guys will somehow get a copy of your database</strong>. And then what? Well, what&apos;s in the database?</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Identity cookies</p>
<p>Cookies are, of course, how the browser can tell who you are. Cookies are usually stored as hashes, rather than the actual cookie value, so having the hash doesn&apos;t let you impersonate the target user. Furthermore, most modern web frameworks rapidly cycle cookies, so they are only valid for a brief 10 to 15 minute window anyway.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Email addresses</p>
<p>Although users have reason to be concerned about their emails being exposed, very few people treat their email address as anything particularly precious these days.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>All posts and topic content</p>
<p>Let&apos;s assume for the sake of argument that this is a fully public site and nobody was posting anything particularly sensitive there. So we&apos;re not worried, at least for now, about trade secrets or other privileged information being revealed, since they were all public posts anyway. If we were, that&apos;s a whole other blog post I can write at a later date.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Password hashes</p>
<p>What&apos;s left is <strong>the password hashes</strong>. And that&apos;s &#x2026; <a href="https://blog.codinghorror.com/speed-hashing/">a serious problem indeed</a>.</p>
</li>
</ul>
<p>Now that the attacker has your database, they can crack your password hashes with <a href="https://blog.codinghorror.com/your-password-is-too-damn-short/">large scale offline attacks</a>, using the full resources of any cloud they can afford. And once they&apos;ve cracked a particular password hash, <strong>they can log in as that user &#x2026; forever</strong>. Or at least until that user changes their password.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&#x26A0;&#xFE0F; That&apos;s why, if you know (or even suspect!) your database was exposed, the very first thing you should do is reset everyone&apos;s password.</p>
</blockquote>
<p><img src="https://blog.codinghorror.com/content/images/2017/06/discourse-db-password-hashes.png" alt="Discourse database password hashes" loading="lazy"></p>
<p>But what if you <em>don&apos;t</em> know? Should you preemptively reset everyone&apos;s password every 30 days, like the world&apos;s worst bigco IT departments? That&apos;s downright user hostile, and leads to serious pathologies of its own. The reality is that you probably <em>won&apos;t</em> know when your database has been exposed, at least not until it&apos;s too late to do anything about it. So it&apos;s crucial to slow the attackers down, to give yourself time to deal with it and respond.</p>
<p>Thus, the only real protection you can offer your users is just how resistant to attack your stored password hashes are. There are two factors that go into password hash strength:</p>
<ol>
<li>
<p><strong>The hashing algorithm</strong>. As slow as possible, and ideally designed to be <em>especially</em> slow on GPUs for reasons that will become painfully obvious about 5 paragraphs from now.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>The work factor</strong> or <strong>number of iterations</strong>. Set this as high as possible, without opening yourself up to a possible denial of service attack.</p>
</li>
</ol>
<p>I&apos;ve seen guidance that said you should set the overall work factor high enough that hashing a password takes at least 8ms on the target platform. It turns out <a href="https://samsaffron.com/">Sam Saffron</a>, one of my Discourse co-founders, made a good call back in 2013 when he selected the NIST recommendation of <strong>PBKDF2-HMAC-SHA256</strong> and <strong>64k iterations</strong>. We measured, and that indeed takes roughly 8ms using our existing Ruby login code on our current (fairly high end, Skylake 4.0 Ghz) servers.</p>
<p>But that was 4 years ago. Exactly how secure are our password hashes in the database today? Or 4 years from now, or 10 years from now? We&apos;re building open source software for the long haul, and we need to be sure we are making reasonable decisions that protect everyone. So in the spirit of <a href="https://blog.codinghorror.com/designing-for-evil/">designing for evil</a>, it&apos;s time to put on our Darth Helmet and play the bad guy &#x2013; <strong>let&apos;s crack our own hashes!</strong></p>
<p><img src="https://blog.codinghorror.com/content/images/2017/06/dark-helmet.jpg" alt loading="lazy"></p>
<p>We&apos;re gonna use the biggest, baddest single GPU out there at the moment, <a href="https://gist.github.com/epixoip/a83d38f412b4737e99bbef804a270c40#gistcomment-2060753">the GTX 1080 Ti</a>. As a point of reference, for PBKDF2-HMAC-SHA256 the 1080 achieves 1180 kH/s, whereas the 1080 Ti achieves 1640 kH/s. In a <em>single</em> video card generation the attack hash rate has increased nearly 40 percent. Ponder that.</p>
<p>First, a tiny hello world test to see if things are working. I downloaded <a href="https://hashcat.net/hashcat/">hashcat</a>. I logged into our demo at try.discourse.org and created a new account with the password <code>0234567890</code>; I checked the database, and this generated the following values in the hash and salt database columns for that new user:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>hash<br>
<code>93LlpbKZKficWfV9jjQNOSp39MT0pDPtYx7/gBLl5jw=</code><br>
salt<br>
<code>ZWVhZWQ4YjZmODU4Mzc0M2E2ZDRlNjBkNjY3YzE2ODA=</code></p>
</blockquote>
<p>Hashcat requires the following input file format: one line per hash, with the hash type, number of iterations, salt and hash (base64 encoded) separated by colons:</p>
<pre><code>type   iter  salt                                         hash
sha256:64000:ZWVhZWQ4YjZmODU4Mzc0M2E2ZDRlNjBkNjY3YzE2ODA=:93LlpbKZKficWfV9jjQNOSp39MT0pDPtYx7/gBLl5jw=
</code></pre>
<p>Let&apos;s hashcat it up and see if it works:</p>
<p><code>./h64 -a 3 -m 10900 .\one-hash.txt 0234567?d?d?d</code></p>
<p>Note that this is an intentionally tiny amount of work, it&apos;s only guessing three digits. And sure enough, we cracked it fast! See the password there on the end? We got it.</p>
<p><code>sha256:64000:ZWVhZWQ4YjZmODU4Mzc0M2E2ZDRlNjBkNjY3YzE2ODA=:93LlpbKZKficWfV9jjQNOSp39MT0pDPtYx7/gBLl5jw=:0234567890</code></p>
<p>Now that we know it works, let&apos;s get down to business. But we&apos;ll start easy. How long does it take to brute force attack <strong>the easiest possible Discourse password, 8 numbers</strong> &#x2013; that&apos;s &quot;only&quot; 10<sup>8</sup> combinations, a little over one hundred million.</p>
<pre><code>Hash.Type........: PBKDF2-HMAC-SHA256
Time.Estimated...: Fri Jun 02 00:15:37 2017 (1 hour, 0 mins)
Guess.Mask.......: ?d?d?d?d?d?d?d?d [8]
</code></pre>
<p>Even with a top of the line GPU that&apos;s &#x2026; OK, I guess. Remember this is just one hash we&apos;re testing against, so you&apos;d need one hour per row (user) in the table. And I have more bad news for you: Discourse hasn&apos;t allowed 8 character passwords for <a href="https://blog.codinghorror.com/your-password-is-too-damn-short/">quite some time now</a>. How long does it take if we try longer numeric passwords?</p>
<pre><code>?d?d?d?d?d?d?d?d?d [9]
Fri Jun 02 10:34:42 2017 (11 hours, 18 mins)

?d?d?d?d?d?d?d?d?d?d [10]
Tue Jun 06 17:25:19 2017 (4 days, 18 hours)

?d?d?d?d?d?d?d?d?d?d?d [11]
Mon Jul 17 23:26:06 2017 (46 days, 0 hours)

?d?d?d?d?d?d?d?d?d?d?d?d [12]
Tue Jul 31 23:58:30 2018 (1 year, 60 days)
</code></pre>
<p>But all digit passwords are easy mode, for babies! How about some <em>real</em> passwords that use at least lowercase letters, or lowercase + uppercase + digits?</p>
<pre><code>Guess.Mask.......: ?l?l?l?l?l?l?l?l [8]
Time.Estimated...: Mon Sep 04 10:06:00 2017 (94 days, 10 hours)

Guess.Mask.......: ?1?1?1?1?1?1?1?1 [8] (-1 = ?l?u?d)
Time.Estimated...: Sun Aug 02 09:29:48 2020 (3 years, 61 days)
</code></pre>
<p>A brute force try-every-single-letter-and-number attack is not looking so hot for us at this point, even with a high end GPU. But what if we divided the number by <strong>eight</strong> &#x2026; <a href="https://gist.github.com/epixoip/a83d38f412b4737e99bbef804a270c40">by putting eight video cards in a single machine?</a> That&apos;s well within the reach of a small business budget or a wealthy individual. Unfortunately, dividing 38 months by 8 isn&apos;t such a dramatic reduction in the time to attack. Instead, let&apos;s talk about nation state attacks where they have the budget to throw <em>thousands</em> of these GPUs at the problem (1.1 days), maybe even <em>tens of thousands</em> (2.7 hours), then &#x2026; yes. Even allowing for 10 character password minimums, you are in serious trouble at that point.</p>
<p><img src="https://blog.codinghorror.com/content/images/2017/06/8-gpu-cracking-rig.jpg" alt loading="lazy"></p>
<p>If we want Discourse to be nation state attack resistant, clearly we&apos;ll need to do better. Hashcat has a handy benchmark mode, and <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1iwoMR5TBYAZ5eiSphkIQfIEfbrVvWW_tKwS4L1cYlaI/pubhtml?gid=0&amp;single=true">here&apos;s a sorted list of the strongest (slowest) hashes that Hashcat knows about</a> benchmarked on a rig with 8 Nvidia GTX 1080 GPUs. Of the things I recognize on that list, <strong>bcrypt</strong>, <strong>scrypt</strong> and <strong>PBKDF2-HMAC-SHA512</strong> stand out.</p>
<p>My quick hashcat results gave me some confidence that we weren&apos;t doing anything terribly wrong with the Discourse password hashes stored in the database. But I wanted to be <em>completely sure</em>, so I hired someone with a background in security and penetration testing to, under a signed NDA, try cracking the password hashes of two live and very popular Discourse sites <a href="https://discourse.org/customers">we currently host</a>.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>I was provided two sets of password hashes from two different Discourse communities, containing 5,909 and 6,088 hashes respectively. Both used the PBKDF2-HMAC-SHA256 algorithm with a work factor of 64k. Using hashcat, my Nvidia GTX 1080 Ti GPU generated these hashes at a rate of ~27,000/sec.</p>
<p>Common to all discourse communities are various password requirements:</p>
<ul>
<li>All users must have a minimum password length of 10 characters.</li>
<li>All administrators must have a minimum password length of 15 characters.</li>
<li>Users cannot use any password matching a blacklist of the 10,000 most commonly used passwords.</li>
<li>Users can choose to create a username and password or use various third party authentication mechanisms (Google, Facebook, Twitter, etc). If this option is selected, a secure random 32 character password is autogenerated. It is not possible to know whether any given password is human entered, or autogenerated.</li>
</ul>
<p>Using common password lists and masks, I cracked 39 of the 11,997 hashes in about three weeks, 25 from the &#x2588;&#x2588;&#x2588;&#x2588;&#x2588;&#x2588;&#x2588;&#x2588; community and 14 from the &#x2588;&#x2588;&#x2588;&#x2588;&#x2588;&#x2588;&#x2588;&#x2588; community.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This is a security researcher who commonly runs these kinds of audits, so all of the attacks used <strong>wordlists</strong>, along with known effective patterns and <a href="https://hashcat.net/wiki/doku.php?id=mask_attack">masks</a> derived from the researcher&apos;s previous password cracking experience, instead of raw brute force. That recovered the following passwords (and one duplicate):</p>
<table>
<tr>
<td>
<code>007007bond</code><br>
<code>123password</code><br>
<code>1qaz2wsx3e</code><br>
<code>A3eilm2s2y</code><br>
<code>Alexander12</code><br>
<code>alexander18</code><br>
<code>belladonna2</code><br>
<code>Charlie123</code><br>
<code>Chocolate1</code><br>
<code>christopher8</code><br>
<code>Elizabeth1</code><br>
<code>Enterprise01</code><br>
<code>Freedom123</code><br>
<code>greengrass123</code><br>
<code>hellothere01</code><br>
<code>I123456789</code><br>
<code>Iamawesome</code><br>
<code>khristopher</code><br>
<code>l1ghthouse</code><br>
</td>
<td>
<code>l3tm3innow</code><br>
<code>Neversaynever</code><br>
<code>password1235</code><br>
<code>pittsburgh1</code><br>
<code>Playstation2</code><br>
<code>Playstation3</code><br>
<code>Qwerty1234</code><br>
<code>Qwertyuiop1</code><br>
<code>qwertyuiop1234567890</code><br>
<code>Spartan117</code><br>
<code>springfield0</code><br>
<code>Starcraft2</code><br>
<code>strawberry1</code><br>
<code>Summertime</code><br>
<code>Testing123</code><br>
<code>testing1234</code><br>
<code>thecakeisalie02</code><br>
<code>Thirteen13</code><br>
<code>Welcome123</code><br>
</td>
</tr>
</table>
<p>If we multiply this effort by 8, and double the amount of time allowed, it&apos;s conceivable that a <em>very</em> motivated attacker, or <a href="https://arstechnica.com/security/2013/10/how-the-bible-and-youtube-are-fueling-the-next-frontier-of-password-cracking/">one with a sophisticated set of wordlists and masks</a>, could eventually recover 39 &#xD7; 16 = 624 passwords, or about <strong>five percent</strong> of the total users. That&apos;s reasonable, but higher than I would like. We absolutely plan to add a hash type table in future versions of Discourse, so we can switch to an even more secure (read: <a href="http://www.pxdojo.net/2015/08/what-i-learned-from-cracking-4000.html">much slower</a>) password hashing scheme in the next year or two.</p>
<pre><code>bcrypt $2*$, Blowfish (Unix)
  20273 H/s

scrypt
  886.5 kH/s

PBKDF2-HMAC-SHA512
  542.6 kH/s 

PBKDF2-HMAC-SHA256
 1646.7 kH/s 
</code></pre>
<p>After this exercise, I now have a much deeper understanding of our worst case security scenario, a database compromise combined with a professional offline password hashing attack. I can also more confidently recommend and stand behind our engineering work in making Discourse secure for everyone. So if, like me, you&apos;re not entirely sure you are doing things securely, it&apos;s time to put those assumptions to the test. Don&apos;t wait around for hackers to attack you &#x2014; <strong>hacker, hack thyself!</strong></p>
<table>  
<tr><td class="welovecodinghorror">[advertisement] At Stack Overflow, we put developers first. We already help you find answers to your tough coding questions; now let us help you <a href="http://careers.stackoverflow.com" rel="nofollow">find your next job</a>.</td></tr>  
</table>  <!--kg-card-end: markdown-->]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Thunderbolting Your Video Card]]></title><description><![CDATA[<!--kg-card-begin: markdown--><p>When I wrote about <a href="https://blog.codinghorror.com/the-golden-age-of-x86-gaming/">The Golden Age of x86 Gaming</a>, I <em>implied</em> that, in the future, it might be an interesting, albeit expensive, idea to upgrade your video card via an external Thunderbolt 3 enclosure.</p>
<p><img src="https://blog.codinghorror.com/content/images/2017/03/skull-canyon-nuc-with-razer-core.jpg" alt loading="lazy"></p>
<p>I&apos;m here to report that <strong>the future is now</strong>.</p>
<p>Yes, that&apos;s</p>]]></description><link>https://blog.codinghorror.com/thunderbolting-your-video-card/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5988f60721f57d0019a2e129</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Jeff Atwood]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 24 Mar 2017 09:08:37 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<!--kg-card-begin: markdown--><p>When I wrote about <a href="https://blog.codinghorror.com/the-golden-age-of-x86-gaming/">The Golden Age of x86 Gaming</a>, I <em>implied</em> that, in the future, it might be an interesting, albeit expensive, idea to upgrade your video card via an external Thunderbolt 3 enclosure.</p>
<p><img src="https://blog.codinghorror.com/content/images/2017/03/skull-canyon-nuc-with-razer-core.jpg" alt loading="lazy"></p>
<p>I&apos;m here to report that <strong>the future is now</strong>.</p>
<p>Yes, that&apos;s right, I paid $500 for <a href="https://www.razerzone.com/store/razer-core">an external Thunderbolt 3 enclosure</a> to fit a $600 video card, all to enable a plug-in upgrade of a GPU on a <a href="https://blog.codinghorror.com/the-golden-age-of-x86-gaming/">Skull Canyon NUC</a> that itself cost around $1000 fully built. I know, it sounds crazy, and &#x2026; OK fine, I won&apos;t argue with you. It&apos;s crazy.</p>
<p>This matters mostly because of 4k, aka 2160p, aka 3840 &#xD7; 2160, aka <strong>Ultra HD</strong>.</p>
<p><img src="https://blog.codinghorror.com/content/images/2015/08/common-hd-resolutions-compared.png" alt="4k compared to 1080p" loading="lazy"></p>
<p>Plain old regular HD, aka 1080p, aka 1920 &#xD7; 1080, is one quarter the size of 4k, and &#xBC; the work. By today&apos;s GPU standards HD is pretty much <em>easy mode</em> these days. It&apos;s not even interesting. No offense to console fans, or anything.</p>
<p>Late in 2016, I got a <a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B01CDD4J58/?tag=codihorr-20">4k OLED display</a> and it &#x2026; kind of blew my mind. I have never seen blacks so black, colors so vivid, on a display so thin. It made my previous 2008 era Panasonic plasma set look lame. It&apos;s so good that I&apos;m now a little angry that every display that my eyes touch isn&apos;t OLED already. I even got into nerd fights over it, and to be honest, I&apos;d still throw down for OLED. It is legitimately <em>that good</em>. Come at me, bro.</p>
<p>Don&apos;t believe me? Well, guess which display in the below picture is OLED? Go on, guess:</p>
<p><a href="http://www.consumerreports.org/lcd-led-oled-tvs/2016-LG-4K-oled-tvs/"><img src="https://blog.codinghorror.com/content/images/2017/03/CptX7RCVYAAKNOP.jpg" alt="Guess which screen is OLED?" loading="lazy"></a></p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-lang="en"><p lang="en" dir="ltr"><a href="https://twitter.com/andrewbstiles">@andrewbstiles</a> if it was physically possible to have sex with this TV I.. uh.. I&apos;d take it on long, romantic walks</p>&#x2014; Jeff Atwood (@codinghorror) <a href="https://twitter.com/codinghorror/status/764304493483663361">August 13, 2016</a></blockquote>
<script async src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>
<p>There&apos;s a reason every site that reviews TVs had to recalibrate their results when <a href="http://thewirecutter.com/reviews/best-tv/">they reviewed the 2016 OLED sets</a>.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>In my extended review at Reference Home Theater, I call it &#x201C;the best looking TV I&#x2019;ve ever reviewed.&#x201D; But we aren&#x2019;t alone in loving the E6. Vincent Teoh at HDTVtest writes, &#x201C;We&#x2019;re not even going to qualify the following endorsement: if you can afford it, this is the TV to buy.&#x201D; Rtings.com gave <a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B01CDD4J58/?tag=codihorr-20">the E6 OLED</a> the highest score of any TV the site has ever tested. Reviewed.com awarded it a 9.9 out of 10, with only the LG G6 OLED (which offers the same image but better styling and sound for $2,000 more) coming out ahead.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>But I digress.</p>
<p>Playing games at 1080p in my living room was already possible. But now that I have an incredible 4k display in the living room, it&apos;s a whole other level of difficulty. Not just twice as hard &#x2013; and remember current consoles <em>barely</em> manage to eke out 1080p at 30fps in most games &#x2013; but <strong>four times as hard</strong>. That&apos;s where external GPU power comes in.</p>
<p><img src="https://blog.codinghorror.com/content/images/2017/03/razer-core-with-gpu.jpg" alt loading="lazy"></p>
<p>The cool technology underpinning all of this is <strong>Thunderbolt 3</strong>. The thunderbolt cable bundled with the Razer Core is rather &#x2026; diminutive. There&apos;s <a href="https://blog.startech.com/post/thunderbolt-3-the-basics/">a reason for this</a>.</p>
<blockquote>
<p><strong>Is there a maximum cable length for Thunderbolt 3 technology?</strong></p>
<p>Thunderbolt 3 passive cables have maximum lengths.</p>
<ul>
<li>0.5m TB 3 (40Gbps)</li>
<li>1.0m TB 3 (20Gbps)</li>
<li>2.0m TB 3 (20Gbps)</li>
</ul>
<p>In the future we will offer active cables which will provide 40Gbps of bandwidth at longer lengths.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>40Gbps is, for the record, an <em>insane</em> amount of bandwidth. Let&apos;s use our rule of thumb based on ultra common gigabit ethernet, that 1 gigabit = 120 megabytes/second, and we arrive at <strong>4.8 gigabytes/second</strong>. Zow.</p>
<p>That&apos;s more than enough bandwidth to run even the highest of high end video cards, but it is not without overhead. There&apos;s <a href="http://www.ultrabookreview.com/10761-razer-core-review/">a mild performance hit</a> for running the card externally, on the order of <strong>15%</strong>. There&apos;s also a further performance hit of 10% if you are in &quot;loopback&quot; mode on a laptop where you don&apos;t <em>have</em> an external display, so the video frames have to be shuttled back from the GPU to the internal laptop display.</p>
<p>This may look like a gamer-only thing, but surprisingly, it isn&apos;t. What you get is the general purpose ability to attach <strong>any PCI express card</strong> to any computer with a <strong>Thunderbolt 3</strong> port and, for the most part, it just works!</p>
<p>Linus breaks it down and answers all your most difficult questions:</p>
<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/2D79GsrEqe4" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>
<p>Please watch the above video closely if you&apos;re actually interested in this stuff; it is essential. I&apos;ll add some caveats of my own after working with the Razer Core for a while:</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Make sure the video card you plan to put into the Razer Core is not too tall, or too wide. You can tell if a card is going to be too tall by looking at pictures of the mounting rear bracket. If the card extends significantly above the standard rear mounting bracket, it won&apos;t fit. If the card takes more than 2 slots in width, it also won&apos;t fit, but this is more rare. Depth (length) is rarely an issue.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>There are four fans in the Razer Core and although it is <em>reasonably</em> quiet, it&apos;s not super silent or anything. You may want to <a href="http://forum.notebookreview.com/threads/razer-core-disassembly-fan-location-guide.802000/">mod the fans</a>. The Razer Core is a remarkably simple device, internally, it&apos;s really just a power supply, some Thunderbolt 3 bridge logic, and a PCI express slot. I agree with Linus that the #1 area Razer could improve in the future, beyond generally getting the price down, is to use fewer and larger fans that run quieter.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>If you&apos;re putting a heavy hitter GPU in the Razer Core, I&apos;d try to avoid blower style cards (the ones that exhaust heat from the rear) in favor of those that cool with large fans blowing down and around the card. Dissipating 150w+ is no mean feat and you&apos;ll definitely need to keep the enclosure in open air &#x2026; and of course within 0.5 meters of the computer it&apos;s connected to.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>There is no visible external power switch on the Razer Core. It doesn&apos;t power on until you connect a TB3 cable to it. I was totally not expecting that. But once connected, it powers up and the Windows 10 Thunderbolt 3 drivers kick in and ask you to authorize the device, which I did (always authorize). Then it spun a bit, detected the new GPU, and suddenly I had multiple graphics card active on the same computer. I also installed the latest Nvidia drivers just to make sure everything was ship shape.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>It&apos;s kinda ... <em>weird</em> having multiple GPUs simultaneously active. I wanted to make the Razer Core display the only display, but you can&apos;t really turn off the built in GPU &#x2013; you can select &quot;only use display 2&quot;, that&apos;s all. I got into several weird states where windows were opening on the other display and I had to mess around a fair bit to get things locked down to just one display. You may want to consider whether you have both &quot;displays&quot; connected for troubleshooting, or not.</p>
</li>
</ul>
<p>And then, there I am, playing Lego Marvel in splitscreen co-op at glorious 3840 &#xD7; 2160 UltraHD resolution on an amazing OLED display with my son. It is <em>incredible</em>.</p>
<p><img src="https://blog.codinghorror.com/content/images/2017/03/lego-marvel-4k.jpg" alt loading="lazy"></p>
<p>Beyond the technical &quot;because I could&quot;, I am <strong>wildly optimistic about the future of external Thunderbolt 3 expansion boxes</strong>, and here&apos;s why:</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>The main expense and bottleneck in any stonking gaming rig is, by <em>far</em>, the GPU. It&apos;s also the item you are most likely to need to replace a year or two from now.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>The CPU and memory speeds available today are so comically fast that any device with a low-end i3-7100 for $120 will make zero difference in real world gaming at 1080p or higher &#x2026; if you&apos;re OK with 30fps minimum. If you bump up to $200, you can get a quad-core i5-7500 that guarantees you 60fps minimum everywhere.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>If you prefer a small system or a laptop, an external GPU makes it so much more flexible. Because CPU and memory speeds are already so fast, 99.9% of the time your bottleneck is the GPU, and almost <strong>any small device you can buy with a Thunderbolt 3 port can now magically transform into a potent gaming rig with a single plug</strong>. Thunderbolt 3 may be a bit cutting edge today, but more and more devices are shipping with Thunderbolt 3. Within a few years, I predict TB3 ports will be as common as USB3 ports.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>A general purpose external PCI express enclosure will be usable for a very long time. My last <em>seven</em> video card upgrades were plug and play PCI Express cards that would have worked fine in any computer I&apos;ve built in the last ten years.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>External GPUs are not meaningfully bottlenecked by Thunderbolt 3 bandwidth; the impact is 15%  to 25%, and perhaps even less over time as drivers and implementations mature. While Thunderbolt 3 has &quot;only&quot; PCI Express x4 bandwidth, many benchmarkers have noted that GPUs moving from PCI Express x16 to x8 has <a href="https://www.pugetsystems.com/labs/articles/Impact-of-PCI-E-Speed-on-Gaming-Performance-518/">almost no effect on performance</a>. And there&apos;s always Thunderbolt 4 on the horizon.</p>
</li>
</ul>
<p>The future, as they say, is already here &#x2013; it&apos;s just not evenly distributed.</p>
<p>I am painfully aware that <strong>costs need to come down</strong>. Way, <em>way</em> down. The <a href="https://www.razerzone.com/store/razer-core">$499 Razer Core</a> is well made, on the vanguard of what&apos;s possible, a harbinger of the future, and fantastically enough, it does <em>even more</em> than what it says on the tin. But it&apos;s not exactly <em>affordable</em>.</p>
<p>I would absolutely love to see a modest, dedicated $200 external Thunderbolt 3 box that included an inexpensive current-gen GPU. This would <em>clobber</em> any onboard GPU on the planet. Let&apos;s compare my Skull Canyon NUC, which has Intel&apos;s <a href="http://www.notebookcheck.net/Intel-Iris-Pro-Graphics-580.160664.0.html">fastest ever, PS4 class embedded GPU</a>, with the modest $150 <a href="http://www.notebookcheck.com/NVIDIA-GeForce-GTX-1050-Ti-Desktop.181030.0.html">GeForce GTX 1050 Ti</a>:</p>
<table width="300px">
<tr>
<td colspan="2"><b>1920 &#xD7; 1080 high detail</b></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Bioshock Infinite</td><td>15 &#x2192; 79 fps</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Rise of the Tomb Raider</td><td>12 &#x2192; 49 fps</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Overwatch</td><td>43 &#x2192; 114 fps</td>
</tr>
</table>
<p>As predicted, that&apos;s a 3x-5x stompdown. Mac users lamenting their general lack of upgradeability, hear me: <em>this sort of box is exactly what you want and need</em>. Imagine if Apple was to embrace upgrading their laptops and all-in-one systems via Thunderbolt 3.</p>
<p><img src="https://blog.codinghorror.com/content/images/2017/03/razer-core-and-razer-laptop.jpg" alt loading="lazy"></p>
<p>I know, I know. It&apos;s a stretch. But a man can dream &#x2026; of externally upgradeable GPUs. That are too expensive, sure, but they are here, right now, today. They&apos;ll only get cheaper over time.</p>
<table>  
<tr><td class="welovecodinghorror">  
[advertisement] <a href="http://careers.stackoverflow.com" rel="nofollow">Find a better job the Stack Overflow way</a> - what you need when you need it, no spam, and no scams.
</td></tr>  
</table>  <!--kg-card-end: markdown-->]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Password Rules Are Bullshit]]></title><description><![CDATA[<!--kg-card-begin: markdown--><p>Of the many, many, <em>many</em> <a href="https://blog.codinghorror.com/the-dirty-truth-about-web-passwords/">bad things about passwords</a>, you know what the worst is? Password rules.</p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-lang="en"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">If we don&apos;t solve the password problem for users in my lifetime I am gonna haunt you from beyond the grave as a ghost <a href="http://t.co/Tf9EnwgoZv">pic.twitter.com/Tf9EnwgoZv</a></p>&#x2014; Jeff Atwood</blockquote>]]></description><link>https://blog.codinghorror.com/password-rules-are-bullshit/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5988f60721f57d0019a2e128</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Jeff Atwood]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2017 11:16:26 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<!--kg-card-begin: markdown--><p>Of the many, many, <em>many</em> <a href="https://blog.codinghorror.com/the-dirty-truth-about-web-passwords/">bad things about passwords</a>, you know what the worst is? Password rules.</p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-lang="en"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">If we don&apos;t solve the password problem for users in my lifetime I am gonna haunt you from beyond the grave as a ghost <a href="http://t.co/Tf9EnwgoZv">pic.twitter.com/Tf9EnwgoZv</a></p>&#x2014; Jeff Atwood (@codinghorror) <a href="https://twitter.com/codinghorror/status/631238409269309440">August 11, 2015</a></blockquote>
<script async src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>
<p>Let this pledge be duly noted on the permanent record of the Internet. I don&apos;t know if there&apos;s an afterlife, but I&apos;ll be finding out soon enough, and I plan to go out <em>mad as hell</em>.</p>
<p>The world is absolutely awash in terrible password rules:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/duffn/dumb-password-rules">Dumb Password Rules</a></li>
<li><a href="http://badpasswordpolicies.tumblr.com/">Bad Password Policies</a></li>
<li><a href="http://password-shaming.tumblr.com/">Password Requirements Shaming</a></li>
</ul>
<p>But I don&apos;t need to tell you this. The more likely you are to use a truly random password generation tool, like us &#xFC;ber-geeks are supposed to, the more likely you have suffered mightily &#x2013; and daily &#x2013; under this regime.</p>
<p>Have you seen the classic XKCD <a href="https://xkcd.com/936/">about passwords</a>?</p>
<p><img src="https://blog.codinghorror.com/content/images/2017/03/password_strength.png" alt="To anyone who understands information theory and security and is in an infuriating argument with someone who does not (possibly involving mixed case), I sincerely apologize." loading="lazy"></p>
<p>We <a href="https://security.stackexchange.com/questions/6095/xkcd-936-short-complex-password-or-long-dictionary-passphrase">can certainly debate</a> whether &quot;correct horse battery staple&quot; is a viable password strategy or not, but the argument here is mostly that <em>length matters</em>.</p>
<p><img src="https://blog.codinghorror.com/content/images/2017/03/twss.jpg" alt="That&apos;s What She Said" loading="lazy"></p>
<p>No, seriously, it does. I&apos;ll go so far as to say <a href="https://blog.codinghorror.com/your-password-is-too-damn-short/">your password is too damn short</a>. These days, given the state of cloud computing and GPU password hash cracking, any password of 8 characters or less is perilously close to <em>no password at all</em>.</p>
<p>So then perhaps we have one rule, that <strong>passwords must not be short</strong>. A long password is much more likely to be secure than a short one &#x2026; right?</p>
<p>What about this four character password?</p>
<h1 id>&#x2705;&#x1F40E;&#x1F50B;&#x1F587;&#xFE0F;</h1>
<p>What about this eight character password?</p>
<h1 id>&#x6B63;&#x786E;&#x9A6C;&#x7535;&#x6C60;&#x8BA2;&#x4E66;&#x9489;</h1>
<p>Or this (hypothetical, but all too real) seven character password?</p>
<h1>&#x634;&#x5BFC;&#xE1E;&#xE34;&#xD55C;<img src="https://blog.codinghorror.com/content/images/2017/06/klingon-char.png" width="35" height="42" alt style="display:inline; vertical-align:middle">&#x270C;&#xFE0E;&#x1F696;</h1>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-conversation="none" data-lang="en"><p lang="en" dir="ltr"><a href="https://twitter.com/codinghorror">@codinghorror</a> I&apos;m sorry but your password must contain 1 char each from: Arabic, Chinese, Thai, Korean, Klingon, Wingdings and an emoji</p>&#x2014; Finley Creative (@FinleyCreative) <a href="https://twitter.com/FinleyCreative/status/705349059217784833">March 3, 2016</a></blockquote>
<script async src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>
<p>You may also be surprised, if you paste the above four Unicode emojis into your favorite login dialog (go ahead &#x2013; try it), to discover that it &#x2026; <em>isn&apos;t</em> in fact four characters.</p>
<p><img src="https://blog.codinghorror.com/content/images/2017/03/discourse-login-emoji-password.png" alt loading="lazy"></p>
<p>Oh dear.</p>
<pre><code>&quot;&#x1F4A9;&quot;.length === 2
</code></pre>
<p>Our old pal Unicode <a href="http://blog.jonnew.com/posts/poo-dot-length-equals-two">strikes again</a>.</p>
<p>As it turns out, even the simple rule that &quot;your password must be of reasonable length&quot; &#x2026; ain&apos;t necessarily so. Particularly if we stop thinking like <a href="https://blog.codinghorror.com/the-ugly-american-programmer/">Ugly ASCII Americans</a>.</p>
<p>And what of those nice, long passwords? Are they <em>always</em> secure?</p>
<pre><code>aaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaa
0123456789012345689
passwordpassword
usernamepassword
</code></pre>
<p>Of course not, because <em>have you met any users lately?</em></p>
<p><img src="https://blog.codinghorror.com/content/images/2017/03/incorrect-password.jpg" alt="I changed all my passwords to &quot;incorrect&quot;" loading="lazy"></p>
<p>They consistently ruin every piece of software I&apos;ve ever written. Yes, yes, I know you, Mr. or Ms. &#xFC;ber-geek, know <em>all</em> about the concept of entropy. But expressing your love of entropy as terrible, idiosyncratic password rules &#x2026;</p>
<ul>
<li>must contain uppercase</li>
<li>must contain lowercase</li>
<li>must contain a number</li>
<li>must contain a special character</li>
</ul>
<p>&#x2026; is a spectacular failure of imagination in a world of Unicode and Emoji.</p>
<p>As we built <a href="https://discourse.org">Discourse</a>, I discovered that <a href="https://blog.codinghorror.com/the-god-login/">the login dialog was a remarkably complex piece of software</a>, despite its surface simplicity. The primary password rule we used was also the simplest one: <strong>length</strong>. Since I wrote that, we&apos;ve already increased our minimum password default length from 8 to 10 characters. And if you happen to be an admin or moderator, we decided the minimum has to be even more, <strong>15</strong> characters.</p>
<p>I also advocated <strong>checking passwords against the 100,000 most common passwords</strong>. If you look at <a href="https://blog.keepersecurity.com/2017/01/13/most-common-passwords-of-2016-research-study/">10 million passwords from data breaches in 2016</a>, you&apos;ll find the top 25 most used passwords are:</p>
<table width="320px">
<tr>
<td style="vertical-align:top">
<code>123456</code><br>
<code>123456789</code><br>
<code>qwerty</code><br>
<code>12345678</code><br>
<code>111111</code><br>
<code>1234567890</code><br>
<code>1234567</code><br>
<code>password</code><br>
<code>123123</code><br>
<code>987654321</code><br>
<code>qwertyuiop</code><br>
<code>mynoob</code><br>
</td>
<td style="vertical-align:top">
<code>123321</code><br>
<code>666666</code><br>
<code>18atcskd2w</code><br>
<code>7777777</code><br>
<code>1q2w3e4r</code><br>
<code>654321</code><br>
<code>555555</code><br>
<code>3rjs1la7qe</code><br>
<code>google</code><br>
<code>1q2w3e4r5t</code><br>
<code>123qwe</code><br>
<code>zxcvbnm</code><br>
<code>1q2w3e</code><br>
</td>
</tr>
</table>
<p>Even this data betrays some ASCII-centrism. The numbers are the same in any culture I suppose, but I find it hard to believe the average Chinese person will ever choose the passwords &quot;password&quot;, &quot;quertyuiop&quot;, or &quot;mynoob&quot;. So this list <em>has</em> to be customizable, localizable.</p>
<p>(One interesting idea is to search for common shorter password matches inside longer passwords, but I think this would cause too many false positives.)</p>
<p>If you examine the data, this also turns into an argument in favor of password length. Note that only 5 of the top 25 passwords are 10 characters, so if we require 10 character passwords, we&apos;ve already reduced our exposure to the most common passwords by 80%. I saw this originally when I <a href="https://github.com/danielmiessler/SecLists/tree/master/Passwords">gathered millions and millions of leaked passwords for Discourse research</a>, then filtered the list down to just those passwords reflecting our new minimum requirement of 10 characters or more.</p>
<p><img src="https://blog.codinghorror.com/content/images/2017/03/top-million-common-passwords-by-length.png" alt loading="lazy"></p>
<p>It suddenly became a <em>tiny</em> list. (If you&apos;ve done similar common password research, please do share your results in the comments.)</p>
<p>I&apos;d like to offer the following common sense advice to my fellow developers:</p>
<h4 id="1passwordrulesarebullshit">1. Password rules are bullshit</h4>
<ul>
<li>They don&apos;t work.</li>
<li>They heavily penalize your ideal audience, people that use real random password generators. Hey guess what, that password randomly <em>didn&apos;t</em> have a number or symbol in it. I just double checked my math textbook, and yep, it&apos;s possible. I&apos;m pretty sure.</li>
<li>They frustrate average users, who then become uncooperative and use &quot;creative&quot; workarounds that make their passwords <em>less</em> secure.</li>
<li>They are often wrong, in the sense that the rules chosen are grossly incomplete and/or insane, per the many shaming links I&apos;ve shared above.</li>
<li>Seriously, for the <em>love of God</em>, stop with this arbitrary password rule nonsense already. If you won&apos;t take my word for it, read <a href="https://nakedsecurity.sophos.com/2016/08/18/nists-new-password-rules-what-you-need-to-know/">this 2016 NIST password rules recommendation</a>. It&apos;s right there, &quot;no composition rules&quot;. However, I do see one error, it should have said &quot;no <em>bullshit</em> composition rules&quot;.</li>
</ul>
<h4 id="2enforceaminimumunicodepasswordlength">2. Enforce a minimum <em>Unicode</em> password length</h4>
<p>One rule is at least easy to remember, understand, and enforce. This is the proverbial one rule to bring them all, and in the darkness bind them.</p>
<p><img src="https://blog.codinghorror.com/content/images/2017/03/one-donut-to-bind-them-all.jpg" alt loading="lazy"></p>
<ul>
<li>It&apos;s simple. Users can count. Most of them, anyway.</li>
<li>It works. The data <em>shows us</em> it works; just download any common password list of your choice and group by password length.</li>
<li>The math doesn&apos;t lie. All other things being equal, a longer password <em>will</em> be more random &#x2013; and thus more secure &#x2013; than a short password.</li>
<li>Accept that even this one rule isn&apos;t inviolate. A minimum password length of 6 on a Chinese site <em>might</em> be perfectly reasonable. A 20 character password <em>can</em> be ridiculously insecure.</li>
<li>If you don&apos;t allow (almost) every single unicode character in the password input field, you are probably doing it wrong.</li>
<li>It&apos;s a bit of an implementation detail, but make sure <em>maximum</em> password length is reasonable as well.</li>
</ul>
<h4 id="3checkforcommonpasswords">3. Check for common passwords</h4>
<p>As I&apos;ve already noted, the definition of &quot;common&quot; depends on your audience, and language, but it is a terrible disservice to users when you let them choose passwords that exist in the list of 10k, 100k, or million most common known passwords from data breaches. There&apos;s <em>no question</em> that a hacker will submit these common passwords in a hack attempt &#x2013; and it&apos;s shocking how far you can get, even with aggressive password attempt rate limiting, using <a href="https://xato.net/10-000-top-passwords-6d6380716fe0">just the 1,000 most common passwords</a>.</p>
<ul>
<li>1.6% have a password from the top 10 passwords</li>
<li>4.4% have a password from the top 100 passwords</li>
<li>9.7% have a password from the top 500 passwords</li>
<li>13.2% have a password from the top 1,000 passwords</li>
<li>30% have a password from the top 10,000 passwords</li>
</ul>
<p>Lucky you, there are millions and millions of real breached password lists out there to sift through. It is sort of fun to do data forensics, because these aren&apos;t hypothetical synthetic Jack the Ripper password rules some bored programmer dreamed up, these are <em>real</em> passwords used by <em>real</em> users.</p>
<p>Do the research. Collect the data. Protect your users from themselves.</p>
<h4 id="4checkforbasicentropy">4. Check for basic entropy</h4>
<p>No need to get fancy here; pick the measure of entropy that satisfies you deep in the truthiness of your gut. But remember you have to be able to <em>explain</em> it to users when they fail the check, too.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.digifail.com/software/spectra.shtml"><img src="https://blog.codinghorror.com/content/images/2017/03/entropy2.png" alt="entropy visualized" loading="lazy"></a></p>
<p>I had a bit of a sad when I realized that we  were perfectly fine with users selecting a 10 character password that was literally &quot;aaaaaaaaaa&quot;. In my opinion, the simplest way to do this is to ensure that there are at least (x) unique characters out of (y) total characters. And that&apos;s what we do as of the current beta version of Discourse. But I&apos;d love your ideas in the comments, too. The simpler and clearer the better!</p>
<h4 id="5checkforspecialcasepasswords">5. Check for special case passwords</h4>
<p>I&apos;m embarrassed to admit that when building the Discourse login, <a href="https://blog.codinghorror.com/the-god-login/">as I discussed in The God Login</a>, we missed two common cases that you really <em>have</em> to block:</p>
<ul>
<li>password equal to username</li>
<li>password equal to email address</li>
</ul>
<p>&#x1F926; If you are using Discourse versions earlier than 1.4, I&apos;m so sorry and <em>please upgrade immediately</em>.</p>
<p>Similarly, you might also want to block other special cases like</p>
<ul>
<li>password equal to URL or domain of website</li>
<li>password equal to app name</li>
</ul>
<p>In short, try to think outside the password input box, like a user would.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&#x1F514; <strong>Clarification</strong></p>
<p>A few people have interpreted this post as &quot;all the <em>other</em> password rules are bullshit, except these four I will now list.&quot; That&apos;s not what I&apos;m trying to say here.</p>
<p>The idea is to focus on the one understandable, simple, practical, works-in-real-life-in-every-situation rule: <strong>length</strong>. Users can enter (almost) anything, in proper Unicode, <em>provided it&apos;s long enough</em>. That&apos;s the <strong>one rule to bind them all</strong> that we need to teach users: length!</p>
<p>Items #3 through #5 are more like genie-special-exception checks, a <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Bwic3hJ4q1A">you can&apos;t wish for infinite wishes</a> kind of thing. It doesn&apos;t need to be discussed up front because it <em>should</em> be really rare. Yes, you must stop users from having comically bad passwords that equal their username, or <code>aaaaaaaaaaa</code> or <code>0123456789</code>, but only as post-entry checks, not as rules that need to be explained in advance.</p>
<p>So TL;DR: one rule. Length. Enter whatever you want, just make sure it&apos;s long enough to be a reasonable password.</p>
</blockquote>
<table>
<tr><td class="welovecodinghorror">
[advertisement] Building out your tech team? <a href="http://careers.stackoverflow.com/products" rel="nofollow">Stack Overflow Careers</a> helps you hire from the largest community for programmers on the planet. We built our site with developers like you in mind.
</td></tr>
</table>
<!--kg-card-end: markdown-->]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[I'm Loyal to Nothing Except the Dream]]></title><description><![CDATA[<!--kg-card-begin: markdown--><p>There is much I take for granted in my life, and the normal functioning of American government is one of those things. In my 46 years, I&apos;ve lived under nine different presidents. The first I remember is Carter. I&apos;ve voted in every presidential election since 1992,</p>]]></description><link>https://blog.codinghorror.com/im-loyal-to-nothing-except-the-dream/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5988f60721f57d0019a2e127</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Jeff Atwood]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2017 09:19:56 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<!--kg-card-begin: markdown--><p>There is much I take for granted in my life, and the normal functioning of American government is one of those things. In my 46 years, I&apos;ve lived under nine different presidents. The first I remember is Carter. I&apos;ve voted in every presidential election since 1992, but I do not consider myself a Democrat, or a Republican. I vote based on leadership &#x2013; above all, leadership &#x2013; and issues.</p>
<p>In my 14 years of blogging, I&apos;ve never written a political blog post. I haven&apos;t needed to.</p>
<p>Until now.</p>
<p>It is quite clear <strong>something has become deeply unglued in the state of American politics.</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>The nuclear doomsday clock was <a href="http://www.reuters.com/article/us-science-doomsdayclock-idUSKBN15A2JJ">just moved as close to midnight</a> as it has been in 64 years.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>America was downgraded from a <a href="http://www.cnbc.com/2017/01/25/us-is-no-longer-a-full-democracy-eiu-warns.html">Democracy to a Flawed Democracy</a>.</p>
</li>
</ul>
<p>As of 2017, the United States, through a sequence of highly improbable events, managed to elect an extremely controversial president.</p>
<p><img src="https://blog.codinghorror.com/content/images/2017/01/voting-in-2016-presidential-election.png" alt loading="lazy"></p>
<p>A president with <a href="http://fortune.com/2017/01/29/donald-trump-approval-rating-gallup/">historically low approval ratings</a>, elected on a platform many considered <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2016/oct/31/peter-thiel-defends-donald-trump-muslim-ban-mexico-wall">too extreme to even be taken literally</a>:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Asked about Trump&#x2019;s statements proposing the construction of a wall on the US-Mexico border and a ban on all Muslims entering the country, Thiel suggested that Trump supporters do not actually endorse those policies.</p>
<p>&#x201C;I don&#x2019;t support a religious test. I certainly don&#x2019;t support the specific language that Trump has used in every instance,&#x201D; he said. &#x201C;But I think one thing that should be distinguished here is that the media is always taking Trump literally. It never takes him seriously, but it always takes him literally.&#x201D;</p>
<p>The billionaire went on to define how he believes the average Trump supporter interprets the candidate&#x2019;s statements. &#x201C;I think a lot of voters who vote for Trump take Trump seriously but not literally, so when they hear things like the Muslim comment or the wall comment their question is not, &#x2018;Are you going to build a wall like the Great Wall of China?&#x2019; or, you know, &#x2018;How exactly are you going to enforce these tests?&#x2019; What they hear is we&#x2019;re going to have a saner, more sensible immigration policy.&#x201D;</p>
</blockquote>
<p>A little over a week into the new presidency, it is obvious that <strong>Trump meant every word of what he said.</strong> He will <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2017/01/26/world/mexicos-president-cancels-meeting-with-trump-over-wall.html">build a US-Mexico wall</a>. And he signed an executive order that <em>literally</em>, not figuratively, <a href="http://www.cnn.com/2017/01/28/politics/donald-trump-executive-order-immigration-reaction/">banned Muslims from entering the US</a> &#x2014; even if they held valid green cards.</p>
<p>As I said, I vote on policies, and <strong>as an American, I reject these two policies.</strong> Our Mexican neighbors are not an evil to be kept out with a wall, but an ally to be cherished. One of my <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Miguel_de_Icaza">favorite people</a> is a Mexican immigrant. Mexican culture is ingrained deeply into America and we are all better for it. The history of America is the history of immigrants seeking religious freedom from persecution, finding a new life in the land of opportunity. Imagine the bravery it takes to leave everything behind, your relatives, your home, your <em>whole life as you know it</em>, to take your entire family on a five thousand mile journey to another country on nothing more than the promise of a dream. I&apos;ve never done that, though my great-great grandparents did. Muslim immigrants are <a href="https://www.buzzfeed.com/sarahmathews/how-to-get-your-green-card-in-america?utm_term=.lsbOAjkpl#.vjXYP1qbQ">more American than I will ever be</a>, and I am incredibly proud to have them here, as fellow Americans.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.snopes.com/superman-1950-poster-diversity/"><img src="https://blog.codinghorror.com/content/images/2017/01/help-keep-your-school-all-american.jpg" alt="Help Keep Your School All American!"></a></p>
<p>Trump is the first president in 40 years to <a href="http://money.cnn.com/2017/01/23/news/economy/donald-trump-tax-returns/">refuse to release</a> his tax returns in office. He has also refused to <a href="http://www.npr.org/sections/thetwo-way/2017/01/12/509421108/u-s-ethics-official-trumps-divestiture-is-hard-pricy-and-essential">divest himself</a> from his dizzying array of businesses across the globe, which present financial conflicts of interest. All of this, plus the hasty way he is ramrodding his campaign plans through on executive orders, with little or no forethought to how it would work &#x2013; or if it would work at all &#x2013; speaks to <strong>how negligent and dangerous Trump is as the leader of the free world.</strong> I want to reiterate that I don&apos;t care about party; I&apos;d be absolutely over the moon with President Romney or President McCain, or any other rational form of leadership at this point.</p>
<p>It is unclear to me how we got where we are today. But echoes of this appeal to nationalism <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/europe/in-poland-a-window-on-what-happens-when-populists-come-to-power/2016/12/18/083577e8-c203-11e6-92e8-c07f4f671da4_story.html?utm_term=.31b3ca7bd3e6">in Poland</a>, and <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/posteverything/wp/2017/01/27/in-venezuela-we-couldnt-stop-chavez-dont-make-the-same-mistakes-we-did/?utm_term=.b8a94d3760b2">in Venezula</a>, offer clues. We brought <a href="https://bbs.boingboing.net/t/when-youre-accustomed-to-privilege-equality-feels-like-oppression/81995">fact checkers to a culture war</a> &#x2026; and we lost. During the election campaign, I was strongly reminded of Frank Miller&apos;s 1986 Nuke story arc, which I read in Daredevil as a teenager &#x2014; the seductive appeal of unbridled nationalism bleeding across the page in stark primary colors.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/0785134816/?tag=codihorr-20"><img src="https://blog.codinghorror.com/content/images/2017/01/daredevil-233-page.png" alt="Daredevil issue 233, page excerpt" loading="lazy"></a></p>
<p>Nuke is a self-destructive form of <a href="https://library.ucsd.edu/dc/search?f%5Bcollection_sim%5D%5B%5D=Dr.+Seuss+Political+Cartoons&amp;f%5Bobject_type_sim%5D%5B%5D=image&amp;f%5Bsubject_topic_sim%5D%5B%5D=War+and+domestic+issues--America+first">America First nationalism</a> that, for whatever reasons, won the presidency through dark subvocalized whispers, and is now playing out in horrifying policy form. But we are not now a different country; we remain <em>the very same country that elected Reagan and Obama.</em> We lead the free world. And we do it by taking the higher moral ground, choosing to do what is <em>right</em> before doing what is expedient.</p>
<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/mUkv_jPgTeg" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>
<p>I exercised my rights as a American citizen and I voted, yes. But <strong>I mostly ignored government beyond voting</strong>. I assumed that the wheels of American government would turn, and reasonable decisions would be made by reasonable people. Some I would agree with, others I would not agree with, but I could generally trust that the arc of American history inexorably bends toward justice, towards freedom, toward equality. Towards the things that make up the underlying American dream that this country is based on.</p>
<p>This is no longer the case.</p>
<p>I truly believe we are at an unprecedented time in American history, in uncharted territory. I have benefited from democracy passively, without trying at all, for 46 years. I now understand that the next four years is perhaps <a href="http://fusion.net/story/379938/comic-trump-election-protest-civil-rights-movement-memphis/">the most important time to be an activist in the United States since the civil rights movement</a>. <strong>I am ready to do the work.</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>I have never once in my life called my representatives in congress. That will change. I will be calling and writing my representatives regularly, using <a href="https://5calls.org/"><strong>tools like 5 Calls</strong></a> to do so.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>I will strongly support, advocate for, and advertise any technical tools on web or smartphone that help Americans have their voices heard by their representatives, even if it takes faxing to do so. Build these tools. <em>Make them amazing</em>.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>I am subscribing to support essential investigative journalism such as the <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/subscriptions/Multiproduct/lp8HYKU.html">New York Times</a>, <a href="https://myaccount2.latimes.com/dsssubscribe.aspx">Los Angeles Times</a>, and <a href="https://subscribe.washingtonpost.com/">Washington Post</a>.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>I have set up large monthly donations to the <a href="https://www.aclu.org/">ACLU</a> which is doing critical work in fighting governmental abuse under the current regime.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>I have set up monthly donations to independent journalism such as <a href="https://www.propublica.org/donate/">ProPublica</a> and <a href="http://www.npr.org/stations/">NPR</a>.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>I have set up monthly donations to agencies that fight for vulnerable groups, such as <a href="https://www.plannedparenthood.org/">Planned Parenthood</a>, <a href="https://www.reproductiverights.org/">Center for Reproductive Rights</a>, <a href="https://refugeerights.org/">Refugee Rights</a>, <a href="http://www.naacp.org/">NAACP</a>, <a href="http://www.maldef.org/">MALDEF</a>, <a href="http://www.thetrevorproject.org/">the Trevor Project</a>, and so on.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>I wish to see the formation of a third political party in the United States, led by those who are willing to speak truth to power like <a href="https://www.evanmcmullin.com/">Evan McMullin</a>. It is shameful how many elected representatives will not speak out. Those who do: trust me, we&apos;re watching and taking notes. And we will be bringing all our friends and audiences to bear to help you win.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>I will be watching closely to see which representatives rubber-stamp harmful policies and appointees, and I will vote against them across the ticket, on every single ticket I can vote on.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>I will actively support all efforts to make the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/National_Popular_Vote_Interstate_Compact">National Popular Vote Interstate Compact</a> happen, to reform the electoral college.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>To the extent that my schedule allows, I will participate in protests to combat policies that I believe are harmful to Americans.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>I am not quite at a place in my life where I&apos;d consider running for office, but I will be, eventually. To the extent that <a href="https://stackoverflow.blog/2010/12/stack-exchange-moderator-elections-begin/">any Stack Overflow user can be elected a moderator</a>, I could be elected into office, locally, in the house, even the senate. Has anyone asked Joel Spolsky if he&apos;d be willing to run for office? Because I&apos;d be hard pressed to come up with someone I trust more than my old business partner Joel to do the right thing. I would vote for him so hard I&apos;d break the damn voting machine.</p>
</li>
</ul>
<p>I want to pay back this great country for everything it has done for me in my life, and carry the dream forward, not just selfishly for myself and my children, but for everyone&apos;s children, and our children&apos;s children. I do not mean <a href="http://progressive.org/dispatches/howard-zinn-s-july-4-wisdom-stands-test-time/">the hollow promises of American nationalism</a> &#x2026;</p>
<blockquote>
<p>We would do well to renounce nationalism and all its symbols: its flags, its pledges of allegiance, its anthems, its insistence in song that God must single out America to be blessed.</p>
<p>Is not nationalism&#x2014;that devotion to a flag, an anthem, a boundary so fierce it engenders mass murder&#x2014;one of the great evils of our time, along with racism, along with religious hatred?</p>
<p>These ways of thinking&#x2014;cultivated, nurtured, indoctrinated from childhood on&#x2014; have been useful to those in power, and deadly for those out of power.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>&#x2026; but the enduring values of freedom, justice, and equality that this nation was founded on. <strong>I pledge my allegiance to the American dream, and the American people</strong> &#x2013; not to the nation, <em>never</em> to the nation.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/0785134816/?tag=codihorr-20"><img src="https://blog.codinghorror.com/content/images/2017/01/daredevil-233-page-loyal-to-nothing-except-the-dream.png" alt="Daredevil issue 233, page excerpt" loading="lazy"></a></p>
<p>I apologize that it&apos;s taken me 46 years to wake up and realize that some things, like the American dream, aren&apos;t guaranteed. There will come a time where you <em>have</em> to stand up and fight for them, for democracy to work. I will.</p>
<p>Will you?</p>
<table>
<tr><td class="welovecodinghorror">
[advertisement] At Stack Overflow, we help developers learn, share, and grow. Whether you&#x2019;re looking for your next dream job or looking to build out your team, <a href="http://careers.stackoverflow.com" rel="nofollow">we&apos;ve got your back</a>.
</td></tr>
</table><!--kg-card-end: markdown-->]]></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>