<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<rdf:RDF
 xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
 xmlns="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/"
 xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
 xmlns:taxo="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/taxonomy/"
 xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
 xmlns:syn="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
 xmlns:admin="http://webns.net/mvcb/"
>

<channel rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/">
<title>cs.FL updates on arXiv.org</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">Computer Science -- Formal Languages and Automata Theory (cs.FL) updates on the arXiv.org e-print archive</description>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:date>2022-11-03T20:30:00-05:00</dc:date>
<dc:publisher>help@arxiv.org</dc:publisher>
<dc:subject>Computer Science -- Formal Languages and Automata Theory</dc:subject>
<syn:updateBase>1901-01-01T00:00+00:00</syn:updateBase>
<syn:updateFrequency>1</syn:updateFrequency>
<syn:updatePeriod>daily</syn:updatePeriod>
<items>
 <rdf:Seq>
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01508" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2101.09100" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2204.11235" />
 </rdf:Seq>
</items>
<image rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif" />
</channel>
<image rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif">
<title>arXiv.org</title>
<url>http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif</url>
<link>http://arxiv.org/</link>
</image>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01508">
<title>Partially-Observable Security Games for Automating Attack-Defense Analysis. (arXiv:2211.01508v1 [cs.CR])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01508</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Network systems often contain vulnerabilities that remain unfixed in a
network for various reasons, such as the lack of a patch or knowledge to fix
them. With the presence of such residual vulnerabilities, the network
administrator should properly react to the malicious activities or proactively
prevent them, by applying suitable countermeasures that minimize the likelihood
of an attack by the attacker. In this paper, we propose a stochastic
game-theoretic approach for analyzing network security and synthesizing defense
strategies to protect a network. To support analysis under partial observation,
where some of the attacker&apos;s activities are unobservable or undetectable by the
defender, we construct a one-sided partially observable security game and
transform it into a perfect game for further analysis. We prove that this
transformation is sound for a sub-class of security games and a subset of
properties specified in the logic rPATL. We implement a prototype that fully
automates our approach, and evaluate it by conducting experiments on a
real-life network.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Khakpour_N/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Narges Khakpour&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Parker_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;David Parker&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2101.09100">
<title>A Categorical Semantics for Bounded Petri Nets. (arXiv:2101.09100v3 [math.CT] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2101.09100</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We provide a categorical semantics for bounded Petri nets, both in the
collective- and individual-token philosophy. In both cases, we describe the
process of bounding a net internally, by just constructing new categories of
executions of a net using comonads, and externally, using lax-monoidal-lax
functors. Our external semantics is non-local, meaning that tokens are endowed
with properties that say something about the global state of the net. We then
prove, in both cases, that the internal and external constructions are
equivalent, by using machinery built on top of the Grothendieck construction.
The individual-token case is harder, as it requires a more explicit reliance on
abstract methods.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Genovese_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Fabrizio Romano Genovese&lt;/a&gt; (University of Pisa, Statebox), &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Loregian_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Fosco Loregian&lt;/a&gt; (Tallinn University of Technology), &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Palombi_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Daniele Palombi&lt;/a&gt; (Sapienza University of Rome)</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2204.11235">
<title>Continuous rational functions are deterministic regular. (arXiv:2204.11235v2 [cs.FL] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2204.11235</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;A word-to-word function is rational if it can be realized by a
non-deterministic one-way transducer. Over finite words, it is a classical
result that any rational function is regular, i.e. it can be computed by a
deterministic two-way transducer, or equivalently, by a deterministic streaming
string transducer (a one-way automaton which manipulates string registers).
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This result no longer holds for infinite words, since a non-deterministic
one-way transducer can guess, and check along its run, properties such as
infinitely many occurrences of some pattern, which is impossible for a
deterministic machine. In this paper, we identify the class of rational
functions over infinite words which are also computable by a deterministic
two-way transducer. It coincides with the class of rational functions which are
continuous, and this property can thus be decided. This solves an open question
raised in a previous paper of Dave et al.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Carton_O/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Olivier Carton&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Doueneau_Tabot_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ga&amp;#xeb;tan Dou&amp;#xe9;neau-Tabot&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
</rdf:RDF>