<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<rdf:RDF
 xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
 xmlns="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/"
 xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
 xmlns:taxo="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/taxonomy/"
 xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
 xmlns:syn="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
 xmlns:admin="http://webns.net/mvcb/"
>

<channel rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/">
<title>gr-qc updates on arXiv.org</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">General Relativity and Quantum Cosmology (gr-qc) updates on the arXiv.org e-print archive</description>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:date>2022-11-03T20:30:00-05:00</dc:date>
<dc:publisher>www-admin@arxiv.org</dc:publisher>
<dc:subject>General Relativity and Quantum Cosmology</dc:subject>
<syn:updateBase>1901-01-01T00:00+00:00</syn:updateBase>
<syn:updateFrequency>1</syn:updateFrequency>
<syn:updatePeriod>daily</syn:updatePeriod>
<items>
 <rdf:Seq>
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01369" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01385" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01394" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01396" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01399" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01401" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01405" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01520" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01525" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01546" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01582" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01652" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01657" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01674" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01691" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01702" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01728" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01739" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01766" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01769" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01807" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01810" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01854" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01880" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01888" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01949" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.02008" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/1811.04975" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2109.06342" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2110.01837" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2111.13380" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2201.00809" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2201.09016" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2203.05461" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2203.07690" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2203.16704" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2206.12597" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2206.14755" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2207.03183" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2207.10658" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2208.06564" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2208.11982" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.00492" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.02431" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01130" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.00940" />
 </rdf:Seq>
</items>
<image rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif" />
</channel>
<image rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif">
<title>arXiv.org</title>
<url>http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif</url>
<link>http://arxiv.org/</link>
</image>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01369">
<title>Gravitational Dimensionality Reduction Using Newtonian Gravity and Einstein&apos;s General Relativity. (arXiv:2211.01369v1 [cs.LG])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01369</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Due to the effectiveness of using machine learning in physics, it has been
widely received increased attention in the literature. However, the notion of
applying physics in machine learning has not been given much awareness to. This
work is a hybrid of physics and machine learning where concepts of physics are
used in machine learning. We propose the supervised Gravitational
Dimensionality Reduction (GDR) algorithm where the data points of every class
are moved to each other for reduction of intra-class variances and better
separation of classes. For every data point, the other points are considered to
be gravitational particles, such as stars, where the point is attracted to the
points of its class by gravity. The data points are first projected onto a
spacetime manifold using principal component analysis. We propose two variants
of GDR -- one with the Newtonian gravity and one with the Einstein&apos;s general
relativity. The former uses Newtonian gravity in a straight line between points
but the latter moves data points along the geodesics of spacetime manifold. For
GDR with relativity gravitation, we use both Schwarzschild and Minkowski metric
tensors to cover both general relativity and special relativity. Our
simulations show the effectiveness of GDR in discrimination of classes.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Ghojogh_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Benyamin Ghojogh&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Sharma_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Smriti Sharma&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01385">
<title>A deformed IR: a new IR fixed point for four-dimensional holographic theories. (arXiv:2211.01385v1 [hep-th])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01385</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;In holography, the IR behavior of a quantum system at nonzero density is
described by the near horizon geometry of an extremal charged black hole. It is
commonly believed that for systems on $S^3$, this near horizon geometry is
$AdS_2\times S^3 $. We show that this is not the case: generic static,
nonspherical perturbations of $AdS_2\times S^3 $ blow up at the horizon,
showing that it is not a stable IR fixed point. We then construct a new near
horizon geometry which is invariant under only $SO(3)$ (and not $SO(4)$)
symmetry and show that it is stable to $SO(3)$-preserving perturbations (but
not in general). We also show that an open set of nonextremal,
$SO(3)$-invariant charged black holes develop this new near horizon geometry in
the limit $T \to 0$. Our new IR geometry still has $AdS_2$ symmetry, but it is
warped over a deformed sphere. We also construct many other near horizon
geometries, including some with no rotational symmetries, but expect them all
to be unstable IR fixed points.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Horowitz_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Gary T. Horowitz&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Kolanowski_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Maciej Kolanowski&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Santos_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jorge E. Santos&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01394">
<title>Self-Similar Gravitational Dynamics, Singularities and Criticality in 2D. (arXiv:2211.01394v1 [hep-th])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01394</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We initiate a systematic study of continuously self-similar (CSS)
gravitational dynamics in two dimensions, motivated by critical phenomena
observed in higher dimensional gravitational theories. We consider CSS
spacetimes admitting a homothetic Killing vector (HKV) field. For a general
two-dimensional gravitational theory coupled to a dilaton field and Maxwell
field, we find that the assumption of continuous self-similarity determines the
form of the dilaton coupling to the curvature. Certain limits produce two
important classes of models, one of which is closely related to two-dimensional
target space string theory and the other being Liouville gravity. The gauge
field is shown to produce a shift in the dilaton potential strength. We
consider static black hole solutions and find spacetimes with uncommon
asymptotic behaviour. We show the vacuum self-similar spacetimes to be special
limits of the static solutions. We add matter fields consistent with
self-similarity (including a certain model of semi-classical gravity) and write
down the autonomous ordinary differential equations governing the gravitational
dynamics. Based on the phenomenon of finite-time blow-up in ODEs, we argue that
spacetime singularities are generic in our models. We present qualitatively
diverse results from analytical and numerical investigations regarding matter
field collapse and singularities. We find interesting hints of a Choptuik-like
scaling law.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Moitra_U/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Upamanyu Moitra&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01396">
<title>Prospects for a precise equation of state measurement from Advanced LIGO and Cosmic Explorer. (arXiv:2211.01396v1 [astro-ph.HE])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01396</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Gravitational-wave observations of neutron star mergers can probe the nuclear
equation of state by measuring the imprint of the neutron star&apos;s tidal
deformability on the signal. We investigate the ability of future
gravitational-wave observations to produce a precise measurement of the
equation of state from binary neutron star inspirals. Since measurability of
the tidal effect depends on the equation of state, we explore several equations
of state that span current observational constraints. We generate a population
of binary neutron stars as seen by a simulated Advanced LIGO-Virgo network, as
well as by a planned Cosmic Explorer observatory. We perform Bayesian inference
to measure the parameters of each signal, and we combine measurements across
each population to determine $R_{1.4}$, the radius of a $1.4M_{\odot}$ neutron
star. We find that with 321 signals the LIGO-Virgo network is able to measure
$R_{1.4}$ to better than 2% precision for all equations of state we consider,
however we find that achieving this precision could take decades of
observation, depending on the equation of state and the merger rate. On the
other hand we find that with one year of observation, Cosmic Explorer will
measure $R_{1.4}$ to better than 0.6% precision. In both cases we find that
systematic biases, such as from an incorrect mass prior, can significantly
impact measurement accuracy and efforts will be required to mitigate these
effects.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Finstad_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Daniel Finstad&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+White_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Laurel V. White&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Brown_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Duncan A. Brown&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01399">
<title>Strong-field scattering of two black holes: Numerical Relativity meets Post-Minkowskian gravity. (arXiv:2211.01399v1 [gr-qc])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01399</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We compare numerical relativity (NR) data on the scattering of equal-mass,
non-spinning binary black holes to various analytical predictions, based on
post-Minkowskian (PM) results. While the usual sequence of PM-expanded
scattering angles shows a rather poor convergence towards NR data, we find that
a reformulation of PM information in terms of Effective-One-Body radial
potentials leads to remarkable agreement with NR data, especially when using
the radiation-reacted 4PM information. Using Firsov&apos;s inversion formula we
directly extract, for the first time, from NR simulations a (radiation-reacted)
gravitational potential describing the scattering of equal-mass, non-spinning
binary black holes. We urge the NR community to compute more sequences of
scattering simulations, so as to extend this knowledge to a wider region of
parameter space.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Damour_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Thibault Damour&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Rettegno_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Piero Rettegno&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01401">
<title>Efficient Gravitational Wave Searches with Pulsar Timing Arrays using Hamiltonian Monte Carlo. (arXiv:2211.01401v1 [astro-ph.IM])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01401</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Pulsar timing arrays (PTAs) detect low-frequency gravitational waves (GWs) by
looking for correlated deviations in pulse arrival times. Current Bayesian
searches use Markov Chain Monte Carlo (MCMC) methods, which struggle to sample
the large number of parameters needed to model the PTA and GW signals. As the
data span and number of pulsars increase, this problem will only worsen. An
alternative Monte Carlo sampling method, Hamiltonian Monte Carlo (HMC),
utilizes Hamiltonian dynamics to produce sample proposals informed by
first-order gradients of the model likelihood. This in turn allows it to
converge faster to high dimensional distributions. We implement HMC as an
alternative sampling method in our search for an isotropic stochastic GW
background, and show that this method produces equivalent statistical results
to similar analyses run with standard MCMC techniques, while requiring 100-200
times fewer samples. We show that the speed of HMC sample generation scales as
$\mathcal{O}(N_\mathrm{psr}^{5/4})$ where $N_\mathrm{psr}$ is the number of
pulsars, compared to $\mathcal{O}(N_\mathrm{psr}^2)$ for MCMC methods. These
factors offset the increased time required to generate a sample using HMC,
demonstrating the value of adopting HMC techniques for PTAs.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Freedman_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Gabriel E. Freedman&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Johnson_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Aaron D. Johnson&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Haasteren_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Rutger van Haasteren&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Vigeland_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Sarah J. Vigeland&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01405">
<title>Gravitational wave stochastic background in reduced Horndeski theories. (arXiv:2211.01405v1 [gr-qc])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01405</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We generalize to reduced Horndeski theories of gravity, where gravitational
waves (GWs) travel at the speed of light, the expression of a statistically
homogeneous and unpolarized stochastic gravitational wave background (SGWB)
signal measured as the correlation between the individual signals detected by
two interferometers in arbitrary configurations. We also discuss some results
found in the literature regarding cosmological distances in modified theories,
namely, the simultaneous validity of a duality distance relation for GW signals
and of the coincidence between the gravitational wave luminosity distance,
based on the energy flux, and the distance inferred from the wave amplitude.
This discussion allows us to conclude that the spectral energy density per unit
solid angle of an astrophysical SGWB signal has the same functional dependency
with the luminosity of each emitting source as in General Relativity (GR).
Using the generalized expression of the GW energy-momentum tensor and the
modified propagation law for the tensor modes, we conclude that the energy
density of a SGWB maintains the same functional relation with the scale factor
as in GR, provided that the modified theory coincides with GR in a given
hypersurface of constant time. However, the relation between the detected
signal and the spectral energy density is changed by the global factor
$G_4(\varphi(t_0))$, thus potentially serving as a probe for modified gravity
theories.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Lobato_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jo&amp;#xe3;o C. Lobato&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Matos_I/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Isabela S. Matos&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Calvao_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Maur&amp;#xed;cio O. Calv&amp;#xe3;o&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Waga_I/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ioav Waga&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01520">
<title>Deep Residual Networks for Gravitational Wave Detection. (arXiv:2211.01520v1 [gr-qc])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01520</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Traditionally, gravitational waves are detected with techniques such as
matched filtering or unmodeled searches based on wavelets. However, in the case
of generic black hole binaries with non-aligned spins, if one wants to explore
the whole parameter space, matched filtering can become impractical, which sets
severe restrictions on the sensitivity and computational efficiency of
gravitational-wave searches. Here, we use a novel combination of
machine-learning algorithms and arrive at sensitive distances that surpass
traditional techniques in a specific setting. Moreover, the computational cost
is only a small fraction of the computational cost of matched filtering. The
main ingredients are a 54-layer deep residual network (ResNet), a Deep Adaptive
Input Normalization (DAIN), a dynamic dataset augmentation, and curriculum
learning, based on an empirical relation for the signal-to-noise ratio. We
compare the algorithm&apos;s sensitivity with two traditional algorithms on a
dataset consisting of a large number of injected waveforms of non-aligned
binary black hole mergers in real LIGO O3a noise samples. Our machine-learning
algorithm can be used in upcoming rapid online searches of gravitational-wave
events in a sizeable portion of the astrophysically interesting parameter
space. We make our code, AResGW, and detailed results publicly available at
https://github.com/vivinousi/gw-detection-deep-learning.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Nousi_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Paraskevi Nousi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Koloniari_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Alexandra E. Koloniari&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Passalis_N/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Nikolaos Passalis&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Iosif_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Panagiotis Iosif&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Stergioulas_N/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Nikolaos Stergioulas&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Tefas_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Anastasios Tefas&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01525">
<title>Exploring quantum geometry created by quantum matter. (arXiv:2211.01525v1 [gr-qc])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01525</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Exactly soluble models can serve as excellent tools to explore conceptual
issues in non-perturbative quantum gravity. In perturbative approaches, it is
only the two radiative modes of the linearized gravitational field that are
quantized. The goal of this investigation is to probe the `Coulombic&apos; aspects
of quantum geometry that are governed entirely by matter sources. Since there
are no gravitational waves in 3 dimensions, 3-d gravity coupled to matter
provides an ideal arena for this task. Our analysis will reveal novel aspects
of quantum gravity that bring out limitations of classical and semi-classical
theories in unforeseen regimes: non-linearities of general relativity can
magnify small quantum fluctuations in the matter sector to large effects in the
gravitational sector. Finally, this analysis leads to thought experiments that
bring out rather starkly why understanding of the nature of physical reality
depends sensitively on the theoretical lens with which it is probed. As
theories becomes richer, new scales emerge, triggering novel effects that could
not be imagined before. The model provides a concise realization of this
well-known chain.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Ashtekar_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Abhay Ashtekar&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01546">
<title>On the superstring-inspired quantum correction to the Starobinsky model of inflation. (arXiv:2211.01546v1 [gr-qc])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01546</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Superstring/M-theory is the theory of quantum gravity that can provide the
UV-completion to viable inflation models. We modify the Starobinsky inflation
model by adding the Bel-Robinson tensor $T^{\mu\nu\lambda\rho}$ squared term
proposed as the leading quantum correction inspired by superstring theory. The
$(R+\frac{1}{6m^2}R^2 -\frac{\beta}{8m^6}T^2)$ model under consideration has
two parameters: the inflaton mass $m$ and the string-inspired positive
parameter $\beta$. We derive the equations of motion in the
Friedmann-Lemaitre-Robertson-Walker universe and investigate its solutions. We
find the physical bounds on the value of the parameter $\beta$ by demanding the
absence of ghosts and consistency of the derived inflationary observables with
the measurements of the cosmic microwave background radiation.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Ketov_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Sergei V. Ketov&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Pozdeeva_E/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ekaterina O. Pozdeeva&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Vernov_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Sergey Yu. Vernov&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01582">
<title>Spacetime continuity and quantum information loss. (arXiv:2211.01582v1 [gr-qc])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01582</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Continuity across the shock wave of two regions in the metric during the
formation of a black hole can be relaxed in order to achieve information
preservation. A Planck scale sized spacetime discontinuity leads to unitarity
(a constant asymptotic entanglement entropy) by restricting the origin of
coordinates (moving mirror) to be timelike. Moreover, thermal equilibration
occurs and total evaporation energy emitted is finite.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Good_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Michael R.R. Good&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01652">
<title>Viscous attenuation of gravitational waves propagating through an inhomogeneous background. (arXiv:2211.01652v1 [gr-qc])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01652</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We consider the propagation of gravitational waves in the late-time Universe,
in the presence of structure, and we also consider the cosmic fluid to be
viscous. In this work, we investigate the cumulative effect of inhomogeneities
and viscosity of the cosmic-fluid, on the observables associated with the
sources of the gravitational waves. Employing Buchert&apos;s averaging procedure in
the backreaction framework, we consider a model of inhomogeneous spacetime.
Using the modified redshift versus distance relation, through the averaging
process in the context of the model, we study the variation of the
redshift-dependent part of the observed gravitational wave amplitude for
different combinations of our model parameters, while simultaneously
considering damping of the gravitational wave amplitude due to viscosity of the
cosmic-fluid. Then, we investigate the differences occurring in the variation
of the redshift-dependent part of the observed gravitational wave amplitude,
due to consideration of viscous attenuation. We show that there are significant
deviations after the inclusion of viscous attenuation in our analysis,
depending on the chosen value of the coefficient of viscosity. Our result
signifies the importance of the effect of viscosity, within the model of an
inhomogeneous Universe, on precision measurements of parameters of
compact-binary sources of gravitational waves.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Pandey_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Shashank Shekhar Pandey&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Sarkar_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Arnab Sarkar&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Ali_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Amna Ali&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Majumdar_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;A. S. Majumdar&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01657">
<title>Semiclassical spacetimes at super-Planckian scales from delocalized sources. (arXiv:2211.01657v1 [gr-qc])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01657</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We derive the gravitational field and the spacetime metric generated by
sources in quantum superposition of different locations. We start by working in
a Newtonian approximation, in which the effective gravitational potential is
computed as the expectation value of the gravitational potential operator in a
Gaussian distribution of width $R$ for the position of the source. The
effective gravitational potential is then covariantly uplifted to a fully
relativistic metric in general relativity, describing the spacetime generated
by averaging over the state of such sources. These results are then rederived
and extended by adopting an independent construction in terms of quantum
reference frames. We find three classes of quantum effective metrics which are
all asymptotically flat and reproduce the Schwarzschild metric at great
distances. The solutions differ, however, in the inner core. The quantum
uncertainty $\Delta r\sim R$ in the position of the source prevents the radius
of the transverse two-sphere to shrink to zero. Depending on the strength of
the quantum superposition effects, we have either a nonsingular black hole with
a ``quantum hair&apos;&apos; and an event horizon, a one-way wormhole with a critical
null throat or a traversable wormhole. We also provide a detailed study of the
geometric and thermodynamic properties of the spacetime structure for each of
these three families of models, as well as their phenomenology.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Akil_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ali Akil&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Cadoni_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Mariano Cadoni&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Modesto_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Leonardo Modesto&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Oi_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Mauro Oi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Sanna_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Andrea Pierfrancesco Sanna&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01674">
<title>Photon Rings Around Warped Black Holes. (arXiv:2211.01674v1 [gr-qc])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01674</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The black hole photon ring is a prime target for upcoming space-based VLBI
missions seeking to image the fine structure of astrophysical black holes. The
classical Lyapunov exponents of the corresponding nearly bound null geodesics
control the quasinormal ringing of a perturbed black hole as it settles back
down to equilibrium, and they admit a holographic interpretation in terms of
quantum Ruelle resonances of the microstate dual to the Kerr black hole. Recent
work has identified a number of emergent symmetries related to the intricate
self-similar structure of the photon ring. Here, we explore this web of
interrelated phenomena in an exactly soluble example that arises as an
approximation to the near-extremal Kerr black hole. The self-dual warped
AdS$_3$ geometry has a photon ring as well as $\mathsf{SL}(2,\mathbb{R})$
isometries and an exactly calculable quasinormal mode (QNM) spectrum. We show
explicitly that the geometric optics approximation reproduces the eikonal limit
of the exact QNM spectrum, as well as the approximate &quot;near-ring&quot;
wavefunctions. The $\mathsf{SL}(2,\mathbb{R})$ isometries are directly related
to the emergent conformal symmetry of the photon ring in black hole images but
are distinct from a recently discussed conformal symmetry of the eikonal QNM
spectrum. The equivalence of the classical QNM spectrum -- and thus the photon
ring -- to the quantum Ruelle resonances in the context of a spacetime with a
putative holographic dual suggests that the photon ring of a warped black hole
is indeed part of the black hole hologram.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Kapec_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Daniel Kapec&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Lupsasca_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Alexandru Lupsasca&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Strominger_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Andrew Strominger&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01691">
<title>Properties and Patterns of Polarized Gravitational Waves. (arXiv:2211.01691v1 [gr-qc])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01691</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We discuss polarization of gravitational radiation within the standard
framework of linearized general relativity. The recent experimental discovery
of gravitational waves provides the impetus to revisit the implications of the
spin-rotation-gravity coupling for polarized gravitational radiation;
therefore, we consider the coupling of helicity of gravitational waves to the
rotation of an observer or the gravitomagnetic field of a rotating astronomical
source. Observational possibilities regarding polarization-dependent effects in
connection with future gravitational wave detectors are briefly explored.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Mashhoon_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Bahram Mashhoon&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Rahvar_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Sohrab Rahvar&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01702">
<title>On diagonal canonical solutions to the Einstein field equations and their meromorphic deformations. (arXiv:2211.01702v1 [math-ph])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01702</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Explicit solutions to the non-linear field equations of gravitational
theories can be obtained, using a Riemann-Hilbert approach, from an appropriate
factorization of certain matrix functions. Here we study a class of solutions,
which we call diagonal canonical solutions, obtained via Wiener-Hopf
factorization of diagonal matrices. This class comprises, among others, the
Schwarzschild, Kasner, Einstein-Rosen and gravitational pulse wave solutions.
We show that new solutions can be obtained by a method of meromorphic
deformation of the diagonal canonical solutions and that we can define Abelian
groups of such solutions indexed by a curve in the complex plane.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math-ph/1/au:+Camara_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;M. Cristina C&amp;#xe2;mara&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math-ph/1/au:+Cardoso_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Gabriel Lopes Cardoso&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01728">
<title>Primordial non-gaussianity up to all orders: theoretical aspects and implications for primordial black hole models. (arXiv:2211.01728v1 [astro-ph.CO])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01728</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We develop an exact formalism for the computation of the abundance of
primordial black holes (PBHs) in the presence of local non-gaussianity (NG) in
the curvature perturbation field. For the first time, we include NG going
beyond the widely used quadratic and cubic approximations, and consider a
completely generic functional form. Adopting threshold statistics of the
compaction function, we address the computation of the abundance both for
narrow and broad power spectra. While our formulas are generic, we discuss
explicit examples of phenomenological relevance considering the physics case of
the curvaton field. We carefully assess under which conditions the conventional
perturbative approach can be trusted. In the case of a narrow power spectrum,
this happens only if the perturbative expansion is pushed beyond the quadratic
order (with the optimal order of truncation that depends on the width of the
spectrum). Most importantly, we demonstrate that the perturbative approach is
intrinsically flawed when considering broad spectra, in which case only the
non-perturbative computation captures the correct result. Finally, we describe
the phenomenological relevance of our results for the connection between the
abundance of PBHs and the stochastic gravitational wave (GW) background related
to their formation. As NGs modify the amplitude of perturbations necessary to
produce a given PBHs abundance and boost PBHs production at large scales for
broad spectra, modelling these effects is crucial to connect the PBH scenario
to its signatures at current and future GWs experiments.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Ferrante_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Giacomo Ferrante&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Franciolini_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Gabriele Franciolini&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Iovino_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Antonio Junior Iovino&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Urbano_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Alfredo Urbano&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01739">
<title>Modified expansion law with Kodama-Hayward temperature for the horizon. (arXiv:2211.01739v1 [gr-qc])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01739</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The expansion law proposed by Padmanabhan suggests that the evolution of the
volume of the horizon is due to the difference between the degrees of freedom
on the horizon and the degrees of freedom in the bulk enclosed by the horizon.
In formulating this law, Padmanabhan used the temperature, $T=H/2\pi$, for a
dynamical expansion. In this work, we modified the expansion law using
Kodama-Hayward temperature, the dynamical temperature, for the horizon, first
in (3+1) Einstein&apos;s gravity and extended it to higher order gravity theories
such as (n+1) Einstein gravity, Gauss-Bonnet gravity, and more general Lovelock
gravity. Contrary to the conventional approach, we expressed degrees of freedom
of the horizon in terms of the surface energy of the horizon. Also, we have
expressed modified expansion law in terms of cosmic components. It then turns
out that it is possible to express the modified expansion law in a form as if
$T=H/2\pi$ is the temperature of the dynamical horizon.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+M_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Muhsinath. M&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+T%2E_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Hassan Basari V. T.&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Mathew_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Titus K. Mathew&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01766">
<title>Scalarization. (arXiv:2211.01766v1 [gr-qc])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01766</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Scalarization is a mechanism that endows strongly self-gravitating bodies,
such as neutron stars and black holes, with a scalar field configuration. It
resembles a phase transition in that the scalar configuration only appears when
a certain quantity that characterizes the compact object, e.g., its compactness
or spin, is beyond a threshold. We provide a critical and comprehensive review
of scalarization, including the mechanism itself, theories that exhibit it, its
manifestation in neutron stars, black holes, and their binaries, potential
extension to other fields, and a thorough discussion of future perspectives.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Doneva_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Daniela D. Doneva&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Ramazanoglu_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Fethi M. Ramazano&amp;#x11f;lu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Silva_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Hector O. Silva&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Sotiriou_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Thomas P. Sotiriou&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Yazadjiev_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Stoytcho S. Yazadjiev&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01769">
<title>Beyond Schwarzschild-de Sitter spacetimes: I. A new exhaustive class of metrics inspired by Buchdahl for pure $R^2$ gravity in a compact form. (arXiv:2211.01769v1 [gr-qc])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01769</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Some sixty years ago Buchdahl pioneered a program in search of static
spherically symmetric vacua for pure $R^{2}$ gravity (Nuovo Cimento, Vol 23, No
1, pp 141-157 (1962); [https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/BF02733549]).
Surpassing several obstacles, his work culminated in a non-linear second-order
ordinary differential equation (ODE) which required being solved. However
Buchdahl deemed the ODE intractable and prematurely abandoned his pursuit for
an analytical solution. We have finally managed to break this six-decades-old
impasse and accomplish his goal. Reformulating the Buchdahl ODE, we obtain a
novel exhaustive class of metrics (which we shall call the Buchdahl-inspired
metrics hereafter) in a compact form. We are able to verify ex post, via direct
inspection, that the metric obtained herein satisfies the $R^{2}$ vacuo field
equation, hence establishing its validity. We show why the Buchdahl-inspired
metrics, which exhibit non-constant scalar curvature, defeat a
Lichnerowicz-type no-go theorem, previously proved for quadratic gravity, by
evading the overly strong restriction on the asymptotic falloff of the metric
at spatial infinity. Our novel solution thereby completes Buchdahl&apos;s
six-decades-old program. We also explore the mathematical properties of the
Buchdahl-inspired metrics in the limit of small k and in the region around the
coordinate origin.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Nguyen_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Hoang Ky Nguyen&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01807">
<title>Influence of Charge on Decoupled Anisotropic Spheres in $f(G,T)$ Gravity. (arXiv:2211.01807v1 [gr-qc])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01807</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;In this paper, we develop two anisotropic solutions for static
self-gravitating spherical structure in the presence of electromagnetic field
through gravitational decoupling approach in $f(G,T)$ theory, where $G$ and $T$
denote the Gauss-Bonnet term and trace of the energy-momentum tensor,
respectively. The extra source with isotropic seed sector is responsible for
generating anisotropy in the spacetime. The system of field equations is
decoupled into two arrays by using minimal geometric deformation in the radial
component. The first set portrays the isotropic regime whereas the second set
represents the anisotropic system. The metric coefficients of the Krori-Barua
spacetime are employed to extract solution of the first set while two
constraints on the radial and temporal components of the extra source yield the
corresponding two solutions. Finally, we investigate the influence of charge
and decoupling parameter on the physical viability and stability of the
obtained solutions. We conclude that the resulting solutions in this modified
theory indicate more feasible and stable structures.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Sharif_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;M. Sharif&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Hassan_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Komal Hassan&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01810">
<title>Observational Signatures of Frame Dragging in Strong Gravity. (arXiv:2211.01810v1 [gr-qc])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01810</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Objects orbiting in the presence of a rotating massive body experience a
gravitomagnetic frame-dragging effect, known as the Lense-Thirring effect, that
has been experimentally confirmed in the weak-field limit. In the strong-field
limit, near the horizon of a rotating black hole, frame dragging becomes so
extreme that all objects must co-rotate with the black hole&apos;s angular momentum.
In this work, we perform general relativistic numerical simulations to identify
observable signatures of frame dragging in the strong-field limit that appear
when infalling gas is forced to flip its direction of rotation as it is being
accreted. In total intensity images, infalling streams exhibit &quot;S&quot;-shaped
features due to the switch in the tangential velocity. In linear polarization,
a flip in the handedness of spatially resolved polarization ticks as a function
of radius encodes a transition in the magnetic field geometry that occurs due
to magnetic flux freezing in the dragged plasma. Using a network of telescopes
around the world, the Event Horizon Telescope collaboration has demonstrated
that it is now possible to directly image black holes on event horizon scales.
We show that the phenomena described in this work would be accessible to the
next-generation Event Horizon Telescope (ngEHT) and extensions of the array
into space, which would produce spatially resolved images on event horizon
scales with higher spatial resolution and dynamic range.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Ricarte_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Angelo Ricarte&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Palumbo_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Daniel C. M. Palumbo&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Narayan_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ramesh Narayan&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Roelofs_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Freek Roelofs&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Emami_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Razieh Emami&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01854">
<title>Ultralight dark matter searches at the sub-Hz frontier with atom multi-gradiometry. (arXiv:2211.01854v1 [hep-ph])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01854</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Single-photon atom gradiometry is a powerful experimental technique that can
be employed to search for the oscillation of atomic transition energies induced
by ultralight scalar dark matter (ULDM). In the sub-Hz regime the background is
expected to be dominated by gravity gradient noise (GGN), which arises as a
result of mass fluctuations around the experiment. In this work we model the
GGN as surface Rayleigh waves and construct a likelihood-based analysis that
consistently folds GGN into the sensitivity estimates of vertical atom
gradiometers in the frequency window between 1 mHz and 1 Hz. We show that in
certain geological settings GGN can be significantly mitigated when operating a
multi-gradiometer configuration, which consists of three or more atom
interferometers in the same baseline. Multi-gradiometer experiments, such as
future versions of AION and MAGIS-100, have the potential to probe regions of
scalar ULDM parameter space in the sub-Hz regime that have not been excluded by
existing experiments.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Badurina_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Leonardo Badurina&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Gibson_V/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Valerie Gibson&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+McCabe_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Christopher McCabe&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Mitchell_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jeremiah Mitchell&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01880">
<title>Performance of different correction maps in the extended phase-space method for spinning compact binaries. (arXiv:2211.01880v1 [gr-qc])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01880</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Since the first detection of gravitational waves by the LIGO/VIRGO team, the
related research field has attracted more attention. The spinning compact
binaries system, as one of the gravitational-wave sources for broadband laser
interferometers, has been widely studied by related researchers. In order to
analyze the gravitational wave signals using matched filtering techniques,
reliable numerical algorithms are needed. Spinning compact binaries systems in
Post-Newtonian (PN) celestial mechanics have an inseparable Hamiltonian. The
extended phase-space algorithm is an effective solution for the problem of this
system. We have developed correction maps for the extended phase-space method
in our previous work, which significantly improves the accuracy and stability
of the method with only a momentum scale factor. In this paper, we will add
more scale factors to modify the numerical solution in order to minimize the
errors in the constants of motion. However, we find that these correction maps
will result in a large energy bias in the subterms of the Hamiltonian in
chaotic orbits, whose potential and kinetic energy, etc. are calculated
inaccurately. We develop new correction maps to reduce the energy bias of the
subterms of the Hamiltonian, which can instead improve the accuracy of the
numerical solution and also provides a new idea for the application of the
manifold correction in other algorithms.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Luo_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Junjie Luo&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Feng_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jie Feng&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Zhang_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Hong-Hao Zhang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Lin_W/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Weipeng Lin&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01888">
<title>Accurate waveform models for gravitational-wave astrophysics: synergetic approaches from analytical relativity. (arXiv:2211.01888v1 [gr-qc])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01888</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Gravitational-wave (GW) astrophysics is a field in full blossom. Since the
landmark detection of GWs from a binary black hole on September 14th 2015,
several compact-object binaries have been reported by the LIGO-Virgo
collaboration. Such events carry astrophysical and cosmological information
ranging from an understanding of how black holes and neutron stars are formed,
what neutron stars are composed of, how the Universe expands, and allow testing
general relativity in the highly-dynamical strong-field regime. It is the goal
of GW astrophysics to extract such information as accurately as possible. Yet,
this is only possible if the tools and technology used to detect and analyze
GWs are advanced enough. A key aspect of GW searches are waveform models, which
encapsulate our best predictions for the gravitational radiation under a
certain set of parameters, and that need to be cross-correlated with data to
extract GW signals. Waveforms must be very accurate to avoid missing important
physics in the data, which might be the key to answer the fundamental questions
of GW astrophysics. The continuous improvements of the current LIGO-Virgo
detectors, the development of next-generation ground-based detectors such as
the Einstein Telescope or the Cosmic Explorer, as well as the development of
the Laser Interferometer Space Antenna (LISA), demand accurate waveform models.
[Abridged.]
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Antonelli_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Andrea Antonelli&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01949">
<title>Impact of multiple modes on the evolution of self-interacting axion condensate around rotating black holes. (arXiv:2211.01949v1 [gr-qc])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01949</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Ultra-light particles, such as axions, form a macroscopic condensate around a
highly spinning black hole by the superradiant instability. Due to its
macroscopic nature, the condensate opens the possibility of detecting the axion
through gravitational wave observations. However, the precise evolution of the
condensate must be known for the actual detection. For future observation, we
numerically study the influence of the self-interaction, especially interaction
between different modes, on the evolution of the condensate in detail. First,
we focus on the case when condensate starts with the smallest possible angular
quantum number. For this case, we perform the non-linear calculation and show
that the dissipation induced by the mode interaction is strong enough to
saturate the superradiant instability, even if the secondary cloud starts with
quantum fluctuations. Our result indicates that explosive phenomena such as
bosenova do not occur in this case. We also show that the condensate settles to
a quasi-stationary state mainly composed of two modes, one with the smallest
angular quantum number for which the superradiant instability occurs and the
other with the adjacent higher angular quantum number. We also study the case
when the condensate starts with the dominance of the higher angular quantum
number. We show that the dissipation process induced by the mode coupling does
not occur for small gravitational coupling. Therefore, bosenova might occur in
this case.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Omiya_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Hidetoshi Omiya&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Takahashi_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Takuya Takahashi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Tanaka_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Takahiro Tanaka&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Yoshino_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Hirotaka Yoshino&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.02008">
<title>Orbital Motion of a test particle around a Schwarzschild&apos;s Black Hole in STVG gravity. (arXiv:2211.02008v1 [gr-qc])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.02008</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;In this article, we have examined the existence of a static spherically
symmetric solution in the Scalar Tensor Vector Gravity (STVG) and investigated
its horizon distances to develop boundary limitations for our test particle. We
have computed the Kretschmann invariant of the metric to study the
singularities and verify that it reduces to general relativity&apos;s Kretschmann
invariant as $\alpha\rightarrow0$. Further, we investigated the orbital motion
of a time-like and light-like test particle around the static solution by
developing an effective potential and the radius of the innermost stable
circular orbit (ISCO).
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Shukla_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Devansh Shukla&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+A_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Abhay Menon A&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Pathak_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Kamlesh Pathak&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/1811.04975">
<title>Effective sound speed in relativistic accretion discs around rotating black holes. (arXiv:1811.04975v3 [astro-ph.HE] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/1811.04975</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;For axially symmetric accretion maintained in the hydrostatic equilibrium
along the vertical direction in the Kerr metric, the radial Mach number does
not become unity at the critical point. The sonic points are, thus, formed at a
radial distance different from that where the critical points are formed. We
propose that a modified dynamical sound speed can be defined through the linear
perturbation of the full space-time dependent equations describing the
aforementioned accretion flow structure. The linear stability analysis of such
fluid equations leads to the formation of an wave equation which describes the
propagation of linear acoustic perturbation. The speed of propagation of such
perturbation can be used as the effective sound speed which makes the value of
the Mach number to be unity when evaluated at the critical points. This allows
the critical points to coalesce with the sonic points. We study how the spin
angular momentum of the black hole (the Kerr parameter) influences the value of
the effective sound speed.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Maity_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Susovan Maity&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Shaikh_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Md Arif Shaikh&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Das_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Tapas Kumar Das&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2109.06342">
<title>Gravity from symmetry: Duality and impulsive waves. (arXiv:2109.06342v4 [hep-th] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2109.06342</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We show that we can derive the asymptotic Einstein&apos;s equations that arises at
order $1/r$ in asymptotically flat gravity purely from symmetry considerations.
This is achieved by studying the transformation properties of functionals of
the metric and the stress-energy tensor under the action of the Weyl BMS group,
a recently introduced asymptotic symmetry group that includes arbitrary
diffeomorphisms and local conformal transformations of the metric on the
2-sphere. Our derivation, which encompasses the inclusion of matter sources,
leads to the identification of covariant observables that provide a definition
of conserved charges parametrizing the non-radiative corner phase space. These
observables, related to the Weyl scalars, reveal a duality symmetry and a
spin-2 generator which allow us to recast the asymptotic evolution equations in
a simple and elegant form as conservation equations for a null fluid living at
null infinity. Finally we identify non-linear gravitational impulse waves that
describe transitions among gravitational vacua and are non-perturbative
solutions of the asymptotic Einstein&apos;s equations. This provides a new picture
of quantization of the asymptotic phase space, where gravitational vacua are
representations of the asymptotic symmetry group and impulsive waves are
encoded in their couplings.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Freidel_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Laurent Freidel&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Pranzetti_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Daniele Pranzetti&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2110.01837">
<title>A Linear Response relation for perturbations in compact stars and the classical Einstein-Langevin formalism. (arXiv:2110.01837v2 [gr-qc] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2110.01837</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We give a linear response relation for perturbations in relativistic stars
and classify them in terms of implicit and induced perturbations. The focus in
this article is on the induced perturbations which may arise due to internal
sources in dense matter compact objects. Based on the linear response relation,
an Einstein Langevin equation is given and its solutions for a simple case are
obtained in closed analytical form as a first exercise. Our results show how
perturbations in relativistic stars can arise due to a cumulative effect of
mesoscopic scale fluctuations in the dense matter fluids, which otherwise seem
to be screened off at hydrodynamic scales due to averaging. We discuss the
relevance of such a framework and its potential towards building up a theme of
research in asteroseismology using a first principles approach.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Satin_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Seema Satin&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2111.13380">
<title>Hairy black holes in dilatonic Einstein-Gauss-Bonnet theory. (arXiv:2111.13380v2 [gr-qc] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2111.13380</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We study black hole solutions in dilatonic Einstein-Gauss-Bonnet theory with
a coupling constant $\alpha$ between the dilaton field and the Gauss-Bonnet
term. In a previous study, we considered the black hole with the vanishing
cosmological constant in this theory and constructed the hairy black hole
solution with the negative $\alpha$. In this study, we present black hole
solutions numerically with various physical properties in anti-de Sitter
spacetime. We describe the procedure for constructing the black hole solutions
in detail.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Lee_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Bum-Hoon Lee&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Lee_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Hocheol Lee&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Lee_W/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Wonwoo Lee&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2201.00809">
<title>A Wheeler-DeWitt Equation with Time. (arXiv:2201.00809v4 [gr-qc] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2201.00809</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The equation for canonical gravity produced by Wheeler and DeWitt in the late
1960s still presents difficulties both in terms of its mathematical solution
and its physical interpretation. One of these issues is, notoriously, the
absence of an explicit time. In this short note, we suggest one simple and
straightforward way to avoid this occurrence. We go back to the classical
equation that inspired Wheeler and DeWitt (namely, the
Hamilton--Jacobi--Einstein equation) and make explicit, before quantization,
the presence of a known, classically meaningful notion of time. We do this by
allowing Hamilton&apos;s principal function to be explicitly dependent on this time
locally. This choice results in a Wheeler--DeWitt equation with time. A working
solution for the de Sitter minisuperspace is shown.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Rotondo_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Marcello Rotondo&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2201.09016">
<title>A minimal self tuning model to solve the cosmological constant problem. (arXiv:2201.09016v2 [astro-ph.CO] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2201.09016</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The expansion of the Universe is observed to be accelerating, with the
simplest solution being a classical cosmological constant. However, this
receives contributions from the quantum vacuum, which are predicted to be many
orders of magnitude larger than observations, and suffers from radiative
instabilities requiring repeated fine tuning. In this paper we present a
minimal, self tuning scalar field model that can dynamically cancel a large
quantum vacuum energy, avoiding Weinberg&apos;s No Go Theorem, and produce
accelerated de Sitter expansion at a lower energy scale as a solution to the
problem. Our minimal model, which contains a non canonical kinetic energy and a
linear potential, belongs to the Kinetic Gravity Braiding subclass of Horndeski
theory which is not observationally excluded, and lies outside of the known Fab
Four or Well Tempered models. We find analytic solutions in the limits of slow
roll and fast roll, and numerically solve the equations of motion to illustrate
our model. We show that the model allows for a matter dominated era, and that
the attractor solution is stable under a phase transition in the vacuum energy
density. We also consider the energy scales required to match observations. Our
model shows the existence of a wider class of successful self tuning models
than previously assumed.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Khan_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Arnaz Khan&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Taylor_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Andy Taylor&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2203.05461">
<title>Binary neutron star mergers as a probe of quark-hadron crossover equations of state. (arXiv:2203.05461v2 [gr-qc] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2203.05461</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;It is anticipated that the gravitational radiation detected in future
gravitational wave (GW) detectors from binary neutron star (NS) mergers can
probe the high-density equation of state (EOS). We perform the first
simulations of binary NS mergers which adopt various parametrizations of the
quark-hadron crossover (QHC) EOS. These are constructed from combinations of a
hadronic EOS ($n_{b} &amp;lt; 2~n_0$) and a quark-matter EOS ($n_{b} &amp;gt; 5~n_0$), where
$n_{b}$ and $n_0$ are the baryon number density and the nuclear saturation
density, respectively. At the crossover densities ($2~ n_0 &amp;lt; n_{b} &amp;lt; 5~ n_0$)
the QHC EOSs continuously soften, while remaining stiffer than hadronic and
first-order phase transition EOSs, achieving the stiffness of strongly
correlated quark matter. This enhanced stiffness leads to significantly longer
lifetimes of the postmerger NS than that for a pure hadronic EOS. We find a
dual nature of these EOSs such that their maximum chirp GW frequencies
$f_{max}$ fall into the category of a soft EOS while the dominant peak
frequencies ($f_{peak}$) of the postmerger stage fall in between that of a soft
and stiff hadronic EOS. An observation of this kind of dual nature in the
characteristic GW frequencies will provide crucial evidence for the existence
of strongly interacting quark matter at the crossover densities for QCD.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Kedia_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Atul Kedia&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Kim_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Hee Il Kim&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Suh_I/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;In-Saeng Suh&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Mathews_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Grant J. Mathews&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2203.07690">
<title>Asymptotically flat vacuum solution for a rotating black hole in a modified gravity theory. (arXiv:2203.07690v2 [gr-qc] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2203.07690</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The theory of f(R)-gravity is one of the theories of modified Einstein
gravity. The vacuum solution, on the other hand, of the field equation is the
solution for black hole geometry. We establish here an asymptotically flat
rotating black hole solution in an f(R)-gravity. This essentially leads to the
modified solution to the Kerr black hole. This solution exhibits the change in
fundamental properties of the black hole and its geometry. It particularly
shows that radii of marginally stable and bound orbits and black hole event
horizon increase compared to those in Einstein gravity, depending on the
modified gravity parameter. It further argues for faster spinning black holes
with spin (Kerr) parameter greater than unity, without any naked singularity.
This supports the weak cosmic censorship hypothesis.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Das_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Arghya Ranjan Das&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Mukhopadhyay_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Banibrata Mukhopadhyay&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2203.16704">
<title>Complexity factor of spherically anisotropic polytropes from gravitational decoupling. (arXiv:2203.16704v2 [gr-qc] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2203.16704</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;In this work we will analyse the complexity factor, proposed by L. Herrera,
for spherically symmetric static matter distributions satisfying a polytropic
equation through the gravitational decoupling method. Specifically, we will use
the 2-step GD, which is a particular case of the extended geometric deformation
(EGD), to obtain analytic polytropic solutions of Einstein&apos;s equations. In
order to give an example, we construct a model satisfying a polytropic equation
of state using Tolman IV as a seed solution.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Heras_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;C. Las Heras&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Leon_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;P. Leon&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2206.12597">
<title>Metric reconstruction from celestial multipoles. (arXiv:2206.12597v2 [hep-th] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2206.12597</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The most general vacuum solution to Einstein&apos;s field equations with no
incoming radiation can be constructed perturbatively from two infinite sets of
canonical multipole moments, which are found to be mapped into each other under
gravitational electric-magnetic duality at the non-linear level. We demonstrate
that in non-radiative regions such spacetimes are completely characterized by a
set of conserved celestial charges that consist of the Geroch-Hansen multipole
moments, the generalized BMS charges and additional celestial multipoles
accounting for subleading memory effects. Transitions among non-radiative
regions, induced by radiative processes, are therefore labelled by celestial
charges, which are identified in terms of canonical multipole moments of the
linearized gravitational field. The dictionary between celestial charges and
canonical multipole moments allows to holographically reconstruct the metric in
de Donder, Newman-Unti or Bondi gauge outside of sources.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Compere_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Geoffrey Comp&amp;#xe8;re&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Oliveri_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Roberto Oliveri&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Seraj_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ali Seraj&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2206.14755">
<title>Radiative corrections to the Lorentzian EPRL spin foam propagator. (arXiv:2206.14755v3 [gr-qc] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2206.14755</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We numerically estimate the divergence of several two-vertex diagrams that
contribute to the radiative corrections for the Lorentzian EPRL spin foam
propagator. We compute the amplitudes as functions of a homogeneous cutoff over
the bulk quantum numbers, fixed boundary data, and different Immirzi
parameters, and find that for a class of two-vertex diagrams, those with fewer
than six internal faces are convergent. The calculations are done with the
numerical framework sl2cfoam-next.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Dona_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Pietro Don&amp;#xe0;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Frisoni_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Pietropaolo Frisoni&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Wilson_Ewing_E/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Edward Wilson-Ewing&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2207.03183">
<title>Trouble with geodesics in black-to-white hole bouncing scenarios. (arXiv:2207.03183v2 [gr-qc] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2207.03183</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;By utilizing the thin shell approximation, we investigate the behavior of
radial timelike geodesics in a black hole to white hole bouncing scenario with
a mass (de-)amplification relation. We show that those geodesics lose energy
after crossing the transition surface if the white hole mass is less than the
black hole mass and vice versa. That is, the bounded timelike radial geodesics
become closer to the event horizon in the mass decreasing direction. We then
show that by tracing a finite amount of bouncing cycles along the mass
decreasing direction, all bounded radial geodesics can be squeezed into the
range of the stretched horizon while the black hole and white hole are still
massive. Those highly squeezed geodesics are problematic since there exists a
Planck-scale blueshift between them and the regular infalling trajectories. We
also discuss the possible implication and rescues.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Hong_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Deog Ki Hong&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Lin_W/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Wei-Chen Lin&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Yeom_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Dong-han Yeom&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2207.10658">
<title>Local Dirac energy decay in the 5D Myers-Perry geometry using an integral spectral representation for the Dirac propagator. (arXiv:2207.10658v3 [gr-qc] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2207.10658</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We consider the massive Dirac equation in the exterior region of the
5-dimensional Myers-Perry black hole. Using the resulting ODEs obtained from
the separation of variables of the Dirac equation, we construct an integral
spectral representation for the solution of the Cauchy problem with compactly
supported smooth initial data. We then prove that the probability of presence
of a Dirac particle to be in any compact region of space decays to zero as
$t\to\infty$, in analogy with the case of the Dirac operator in the Kerr-Newman
geometry.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Wang_Q/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Qiu Shi Wang&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2208.06564">
<title>Galactic rotation dynamics in a new $f(\mathcal{R})$ gravity model. (arXiv:2208.06564v2 [gr-qc] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2208.06564</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We propose to test the viability of the recently introduced $f(\mathcal{R})$
gravity model in the galactic scales. For this purpose we consider test
particles moving in stable circular orbits around the galactic center. We study
the Palatini approach of $f(\mathcal{R})$ gravity via Weyl transformation,
which is the frame transformation from the Jordan frame to the Einstein frame.
We derive the expression of rotational velocities of test particles in the new
$f(\mathcal{R})$ gravity model. For the observational data of samples of high
surface brightness and low surface brightness galaxies, we show that the
predicted rotation curves are well fitted with observations, thus implying that
this model can explain flat rotation curves of galaxies. We also study an ultra
diffuse galaxy, AGC $242019$ which has been claimed in literature to be a dark
matter dominated galaxy similar to low surface brightness galaxies with a
slowly rising rotation curve. The rotation curve of this galaxy also fits well
with the model prediction in our study. Furthermore, we studied the
Tully-Fisher relation for the entire sample of galaxies and found that the
model prediction shows the consistency with the data.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Parbin_N/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Nashiba Parbin&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Goswami_U/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Umananda Dev Goswami&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2208.11982">
<title>Island on codimension-two branes in AdS/dCFT. (arXiv:2208.11982v2 [hep-th] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2208.11982</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The previous studies of the island and double holography mainly focus on
codimension-one branes. This paper explores the island on the codimension-two
brane in AdS/dCFT. The codimension-two brane is closely related to conical
singularity, which is very different from the codimension-one brane. We analyze
the mass spectrum of gravitons on the codimension-two brane and find that the
larger the brane tension is, the smaller the gravitational mass is. The
massless mode is forbidden by either the boundary or normalization conditions.
We prove that the first massive gravitational mode is located on the
codimension-two brane; the larger the tension, the better the localization. It
is similar to the case of codimension-one brane and builds an excellent
physical foundation for the study of black hole evolution on codimension-two
branes. We find that the Page curve of eternal black holes can be recovered due
to the island ending on the codimension-two brane. The new feature is that the
extremal surface passing the horizon cannot be defined after some finite time
in the no-island phase. Fortunately, this unusual situation does not affect the
Page curve since it happens after Page time.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Hu_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Peng-Ju Hu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Li_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Dongqi Li&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Miao_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Rong-Xin Miao&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.00492">
<title>Properties of a proposed background independent exact renormalization group. (arXiv:2210.00492v2 [hep-th] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.00492</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We explore the properties of a recently proposed background independent exact
renormalization group approach to gauge theories and gravity. In the process we
also develop the machinery needed to study it rigorously. The proposal comes
with some advantages. It preserves gauge invariance manifestly, avoids
introducing unphysical fields, such as ghosts and Pauli-Villars fields, and
does not require gauge-fixing. However, we show that in the simple case of
SU(N) Yang-Mills it does not completely regularise the longitudinal part of
vertex functions already at one loop, invalidating certain methods for
extracting universal components. Moreover we demonstrate a kind of no-go
theorem: within the proposed structure, whatever choice is made for
covariantisation and cutoff profiles, the two-point vertex flow equation at one
loop cannot be both transverse, as required by gauge invariance, and fully
regularised.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Mandric_V/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Vlad-Mihai Mandric&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Morris_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Tim R. Morris&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.02431">
<title>Black hole thermodynamics from logotropic fluids. (arXiv:2210.02431v2 [gr-qc] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.02431</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We show that Einstein&apos;s field equations with a negative cosmological constant
can admit black hole solutions whose thermodynamics coincides with that of
logotropic fluids, recently investigated to heal some cosmological and
astrophysical issues. For this purpose, we adopt the Anton-Schmidt equation of
state, which represents a generalized version of logotropic fluids. We thus
propose a general treatment to obtain an asymptotic anti-de Sitter metric,
reproducing the thermodynamic properties of both Anton-Schmidt and logotropic
fluids. Hence, we explore how to construct suitable spacetime functions,
invoking an event horizon and fulfilling the null, weak, strong and dominant
energy conditions. We further relax the strong energy condition to search for
possible additional solutions. Finally, we discuss the optical properties
related to a specific class of metrics and show how to construct an effective
refractive index depending on the spacetime functions and the thermodynamic
quantities of the fluid under study. We also explore possible departures with
respect to the case without the fluid.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Capozziello_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Salvatore Capozziello&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+DAgostino_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Rocco D&amp;#x27;Agostino&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Lapponi_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Alessio Lapponi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Luongo_O/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Orlando Luongo&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01130">
<title>Unimodular gravity and the gauge/gravity duality. (arXiv:2211.01130v2 [hep-th] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01130</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Unimodular gravity can be formulated so that transverse diffeomorphisms and
Weyl transformations are symmetries of the theory. For this formulation of
unimodular gravity, we work out the two-point and three-point $h_{\mu\nu}$
contributions to the on-shell classical gravity action in the leading
approximation and for an Euclidean AdS background. We conclude that these
contributions do not agree with those obtained by using General Relativity due
to IR divergent contact terms. The subtraction of these IR divergent terms
yields the same IR finite result for both unimodular gravity and General
Relativity. Equivalence between unimodular gravity and General Relativity with
regard to the gauge/gravity duality thus emerges in a non trivial way.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Anero_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jesus Anero&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Martin_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Carmelo P. Martin&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.00940">
<title>Continuous gravitational wave detection to understand the generation mechanism of fast radio bursts. (arXiv:2211.00940v1 [astro-ph.HE] CROSS LISTED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.00940</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Since the unexpected discovery of fast radio bursts (FRBs), researchers have
proposed varied theories and models to explain their phenomena. One such model
that has recently been developed incorporates the so-called
Gertsenshtein-Zel&apos;dovich (GZ) effect, which states that when gravitational
waves traverse the pulsar magnetosphere, a portion of their gravitational
radiation is transformed into electromagnetic (EM) radiation. The observed
properties of FRBs are consistent with the properties of this EM radiation,
implying, remarkably, that the GZ effect can account for both repeating and
non-repeating FRBs. If this model is correct, the pulsar&apos;s properties should
not change over time, and it would continue to emit both EM dipole and
gravitational quadrupole radiation for a long period of time. This article
targets the gravitational radiation produced by the pulsar mechanism and shows
that several proposed gravitational wave detectors can detect these
gravitational waves. If such detections are performed in the future from the
positions of FRBs, it will validate the GZ process for FRB production and can
rule out several other FRB theories.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Kalita_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Surajit Kalita&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Weltman_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Amanda Weltman&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
</rdf:RDF>