<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<rdf:RDF
 xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
 xmlns="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/"
 xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
 xmlns:taxo="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/taxonomy/"
 xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
 xmlns:syn="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
 xmlns:admin="http://webns.net/mvcb/"
>

<channel rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/">
<title>astro-ph.GA updates on arXiv.org</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">Astrophysics -- Astrophysics of Galaxies (astro-ph.GA) updates on the arXiv.org e-print archive</description>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:date>2022-11-03T20:30:00-05:00</dc:date>
<dc:publisher>help@arxiv.org</dc:publisher>
<dc:subject>Astrophysics -- Astrophysics of Galaxies</dc:subject>
<syn:updateBase>1901-01-01T00:00+00:00</syn:updateBase>
<syn:updateFrequency>1</syn:updateFrequency>
<syn:updatePeriod>daily</syn:updatePeriod>
<items>
 <rdf:Seq>
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01377" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01378" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01382" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01384" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01389" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01391" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01395" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01424" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01445" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01449" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01460" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01526" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01534" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01608" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01619" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01636" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01641" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01694" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01708" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01718" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01744" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01821" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01891" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01897" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01922" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01931" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.02038" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2201.10480" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2205.08174" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2208.07376" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2209.04344" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.10038" />
 </rdf:Seq>
</items>
<image rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif" />
</channel>
<image rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif">
<title>arXiv.org</title>
<url>http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif</url>
<link>http://arxiv.org/</link>
</image>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01377">
<title>A 4 Gyr M-dwarf Gyrochrone from CFHT/MegaPrime Monitoring of the Open Cluster M67. (arXiv:2211.01377v1 [astro-ph.SR])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01377</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We present stellar rotation periods for late K- and early M-dwarf members of
the 4 Gyr old open cluster M67 as calibrators for gyrochronology and tests of
stellar spin-down models. Using Gaia EDR3 astrometry for cluster membership and
Pan-STARRS (PS1) photometry for binary identification, we build this set of
rotation periods from a campaign of monitoring M67 with the
Canada-France-Hawaii Telescope&apos;s MegaPrime wide field imager. We identify 1807
members of M67, of which 294 are candidate single members with significant
rotation period detections. Moreover, we fit a polynomial to the period versus
color-derived effective temperature sequence observed in our data. We find that
the rotation of very cool dwarfs can be explained by a simple solid-body
spin-down between 2.7 and 4 Gyr. We compare this rotational sequence to the
predictions of gyrochronological models and find that the best match is
Skumanich-like spin-down, P_rot \propto t^0.62, applied to the sequence of
Ruprecht 147. This suggests that, for spectral types K7-M0 with near-solar
metallicity, once a star resumes spinning down, a simple Skumanich-like is
sufficient to describe their rotation evolution, at least through the age of
M67. Additionally, for stars in the range M1-M3, our data show that spin-down
must have resumed prior to the age of M67, in conflict with predictions of the
latest spin-down models.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Dungee_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ryan Dungee&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Saders_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jennifer van Saders&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Gaidos_E/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Eric Gaidos&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Chun_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Mark Chun&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Garcia_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Rafael A. Garcia&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Magnier_E/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Eugene A. Magnier&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Mathur_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Savita Mathur&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Santos_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Angela R. G. Santos&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01378">
<title>A correlation between accreted stellar kinematics and dark matter halo spin in the ARTEMIS simulations. (arXiv:2211.01378v1 [astro-ph.GA])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01378</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We report a correlation between the presence of a Gaia-Sausage-Enceladus
(GSE) analogue and dark matter halo spin in the ARTEMIS simulations of Milky
Way-like galaxies. The haloes which contain a large population of accreted
stars on highly radial orbits (like the GSE) have lower spin on average than
their counterparts with more isotropic stellar velocity distributions. The
median modified spin parameters $\lambda^\prime$ differ by a factor of
$\sim1.7$ at the present-day, with a similar value when the haloes far from
virial equilibrium are removed. We also show that accreted stars make up a
smaller proportion of the stellar populations in haloes containing a GSE
analogue, and are stripped from satellites with stellar masses typically
$\sim4$ times smaller. Our findings suggest that the higher spin of DM haloes
without a GSE-like feature is due to mergers with large satellites of stellar
mass $\sim10^{10}M_\odot$, which do not result in prominent radially
anisotropic features like the GSE.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Dillamore_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Adam M. Dillamore&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Belokurov_V/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Vasily Belokurov&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Evans_N/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;N. Wyn Evans&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Font_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Andreea S. Font&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01382">
<title>The Mass-Metallicity Relation of Dwarf Galaxies at the Cosmic Noon in the JWST Era. (arXiv:2211.01382v1 [astro-ph.GA])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01382</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We present the mass-metallicity relation (MZR) at $z=2-3$ in the stellar mass
range of $M_\star\approx 10^{6.5}-10^{9.5}M_\odot$ using 55 dwarf galaxies in
the Abell 2744 and SMACS J0723-3732 galaxy cluster fields. These dwarf galaxies
are identified and confirmed by deep JWST/NIRISS imaging and slitless grism
spectroscopic observations. Taking advantage of the gravitational lensing
effect, we extend the previous MZR relation at $z=2-3$ to a much lower mass
regime by more than 2.5 orders of magnitude compared with previous studies. We
find that the MZR has a shallower slope at the low-mass end
($M_\star&amp;lt;10^{9}M_\odot$) compared to that at the high-mass end
($M_\star&amp;gt;10^{9}M_\odot$), with a slope turnover point at around the stellar
mass of $10^9 M_\odot$. This implies that dominating feedback processes in
dwarf galaxies may be different from that in galaxies with higher mass. From
$z=3$ to $z=2$, the metallicity of the dwarf galaxies is enhanced by
$\approx0.1$ dex for a given stellar mass, consistent with the mild evolution
found in galaxies with higher mass. Further, we confirm the existence of a 3D
relation between the gas-phase metallicity, stellar mass, and star formation
rate, i.e., fundamental metallicity relation (FMR), in dwarf galaxies at
$z=2-3$. Our derived FMR, which has no significant redshift evolution, can be
used as a benchmark to understand the origin of the anti-correlation between
SFR and metallicity of dwarf galaxies in the high-redshift Universe.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Li_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Mingyu Li&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Cai_Z/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Zheng Cai&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Bian_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Fuyan Bian&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Lin_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xiaojing Lin&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Li_Z/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Zihao Li&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Wu_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yunjing Wu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Sun_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Fengwu Sun&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Zhang_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Shiwu Zhang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Zou_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Siwei Zou&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Fan_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xiaohui Fan&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Egami_E/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Eiichi Egami&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Charlot_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Stephane Charlot&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Bruzual_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Gustavo Bruzual&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Chevallard_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jacopo Chevallard&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01384">
<title>Distinguishing Dark Matter Cusps from Cores using Globular Clusters. (arXiv:2211.01384v1 [astro-ph.GA])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01384</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Globular Clusters (GCs) provide valuable insight into the properties of their
host galaxies&apos; dark matter halos. Using N-body simulations incorporating
semianalytic dynamical friction and GC-GC merger prescriptions, we study the
evolution of GC radial distributions and mass functions in cuspy and cored dark
matter halos. Modeling the dynamics of the GC-rich system in the dwarf galaxy
UGC7369, we find that friction-induced inspiral and subsequent mergers of
massive GCs can naturally and robustly explain the mass segregation of the GCs
and the existence of a nuclear star cluster (NSC). However, the multiple
mergers required to form the NSC only take place when the dark matter halo is
cuspy. In a cored halo, stalling of the dynamical friction within the core
halts the inspiral of the GCs, and so the GC merger rate falls significantly,
precluding the formation of an NSC. We therefore argue that the presence of an
NSC requires a cusp in UGC7369. More generally, we propose that the presence of
an NSC and the corresponding alteration of the GC mass function due to mergers
may be used as an indicator of a cuspy halo for galaxies in which we expect NSC
formation to be merger-dominated. These observables represent a simple,
powerful complement to other inner halo density profile constraint techniques,
and should allow for straightforward extension to larger samples.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Modak_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Shaunak Modak&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Danieli_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Shany Danieli&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Greene_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jenny E. Greene&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01389">
<title>Seeking the growth of the first black hole seeds with JWST. (arXiv:2211.01389v1 [astro-ph.GA])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01389</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Surveys with the James Webb Space Telescope (JWST) will have the sensitivity
to explore the assembly history of the first nuclear black holes (BHs), as they
grow in mass from the scale of the first heavy BH seeds ($\rm M_{BH}\sim 10^4 -
10^6 M_\odot$), to the supermassive black holes (SMBHs, $\rm M_{BH} &amp;gt; 10^8
M_\odot$) powering luminous quasars out to $z \sim 7.5$. In this paper we
provide predictions for the number of accreting BHs that would be observable
with planned JWST surveys at $5 \le z &amp;lt; 15$. We base our study on the recently
developed Cosmic Archaeology Tool (CAT), which allows us to model BH seeds
formation and growth, while being consistent with the general population of
AGNs and galaxies observed at $4 \le z \le 7$. We find that JWST planned
surveys will provide a complementary view on the active BH population at $z &amp;gt;
5$, with JADES-Medium/-Deep being capable of detecting the numerous BHs that
populate the faint-end of the distribution, COSMOS-Web sampling a large enough
area to detect the rarest brightest systems, and CEERS/PRIMER bridging the gap
between these two regimes. The relatively small field of view of the above
surveys preferentially selects BHs with masses $\rm 6 \leq Log(M_{BH}/M_\odot)
&amp;lt; 8$ at $7 \le z &amp;lt; 10$, residing in relatively metal poor galaxies ($\rm
Log(Z/Z_\odot) \ge -2$). At $z \ge 10$, only JADES-Deep will have the
sensitivity to detect growing BHs with masses $\rm 4 \leq Log(M_{BH}/M_\odot) &amp;lt;
6$, hosted in even more metal poor environments ($\rm -3 \leq Log(Z/Z_\odot) &amp;lt;
-2$). In our model, the latter population corresponds to heavy BH seeds formed
by the direct collapse of super-massive stars in their earliest phases of mass
growth. Detecting these systems would provide unvaluable insights on the nature
and early growth of the first BH seeds.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Trinca_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Alessandro Trinca&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Schneider_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Raffaella Schneider&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Maiolino_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Roberto Maiolino&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Valiante_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Rosa Valiante&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Graziani_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Luca Graziani&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Volonteri_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Marta Volonteri&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01391">
<title>The Origin of Buckling Instability in Galactic Bars: Searching for the Scapegoat. (arXiv:2211.01391v1 [astro-ph.GA])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01391</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The buckling process in stellar bars is full of unsolved issues. We analyze
the origin of the buckling instability in stellar bars using high-resolution
N-body simulations. Previous studies have promoted the nonresonant firehose
instability to be responsible for the vertical buckling. We have analyzed the
buckling process in terms of the resonant excitation of stellar orbits in the
bar, which pumps energy into vertical oscillations. We find that (1) the
buckling is associated with an abrupt increase in the central mass
concentration and triggers velocities along the bar and along its rotation
axis. The velocity field projected on one of the main axes forms circulation
cells and increases vorticity, which are absent in firehose instability; (2)
The bending amplitude is nonlinear when measured by isodensity contours or
curvature of the Laplace plane, which has a substantial effect on the stellar
motions; (3) In the linear description, the planar and vertical 2:1 resonances
appear only with the buckling and quickly reach the overlapping phase, thus
supporting the energy transfer; (4) Using nonlinear orbit analysis, we analyze
the stellar oscillations along the bar and along the rotation axis and find
that stars cross the vertical 2:1 resonance simultaneously with the buckling.
The overlapping planar and vertical 2:1 resonances trapping more than 25% of
the bar particles provide the &apos;smoking gun&apos; pointing to a close relationship
between the bending of stellar orbits and the resonant action -- these
particles provide the necessary ingredient assuring the cohesive response in
the growing vertical asymmetry. We conclude that resonant excitation is
important in triggering the buckling instability, and the contribution from the
firehose instability should be reevaluated. Finally, we discuss some
observational implications of buckling.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Li_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xingchen Li&lt;/a&gt; (University of Kentucky), &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Shlosman_I/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Isaac Shlosman&lt;/a&gt; (University of Kentucky and Theoretical Astrophysics, Osaka University), &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Pfenniger_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Daniel Pfenniger&lt;/a&gt; (University of Geneva), &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Heller_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Clayton Heller&lt;/a&gt; (Georgia Southern University)</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01395">
<title>The Anatomy of a Turbulent Radiative Mixing Layer: Insights from an Analytic Model with Turbulent Conduction and Viscosity. (arXiv:2211.01395v1 [astro-ph.GA])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01395</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Turbulent Radiative Mixing Layers (TRMLs) form at the interface of cold,
dense gas and hot, diffuse gas in motion with each other. TRMLs are ubiquitous
in and around galaxies on a variety of scales, including galactic winds and the
circumgalactic medium. They host the intermediate temperature gases that are
efficient in radiative cooling, thus play a crucial role in controlling the
cold gas supply, phase structure, and spectral features of galaxies. In this
work, we introduce a simple parameterization of the effective turbulent
conductivity and viscosity that enables us to develop a simple and intuitive
analytic 1.5 dimensional model for TRMLs. Our analytic model reproduces the
mass flux, total cooling, and phase structure of 3D simulations of TRMLs at a
fraction of the computational cost. It also reveals essential insights into the
physics of TRMLs, particularly the importance of the viscous dissipation of
relative kinetic energy in balancing radiative cooling. This dissipation takes
place both in the intermediate temperature phase, which offsets the enthalpy
flux from the hot phase, and in the cold phase, which enhances radiative
cooling. Additionally, our model provides a fast and easy way of computing the
column density and surface brightness of TRMLs, which can be directly linked to
observations.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Chen_Z/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Zirui Chen&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Fielding_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Drummond B. Fielding&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Bryan_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Greg L. Bryan&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01424">
<title>A solar metallicity galaxy at $z &gt;$ 7? Detection of the [N II] 122 $\mu$m and [O III] 52 $\mu$m lines. (arXiv:2211.01424v1 [astro-ph.GA])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01424</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We present the first detection of the [N II] 122 $\mu$m and [O III] 52 $\mu$m
lines for a reionisation-epoch galaxy. Based on these lines and previous [C II]
158 $\mu$m and [O III] 88 $\mu$m measurements, we estimate an electron density
of $\lesssim$ 500 cm$^{-3}$ and a gas-phase metallicity $Z/Z_\odot \sim 1.1 \pm
0.2$ for A1689-zD1, a gravitationally-lensed, dusty galaxy at $z$ = 7.133.
Other measurements or indicators of metallicity so far in galaxy ISMs at $z
\gtrsim$ 6 are typically an order of magnitude lower than this. The unusually
high metallicity makes A1689-zD1 inconsistent with the fundamental metallicity
relation, although there is likely significant dust obscuration of the stellar
mass, which may partly resolve the inconsistency. Given a solar metallicity,
the dust-to-metals ratio is a factor of several lower than expected, hinting
that galaxies beyond $z \sim$ 7 may have lower dust formation efficiency.
Finally, the inferred nitrogen enrichment compared to oxygen, on which the
metallicity measurement depends, indicates that star-formation in the system is
older than about 250 Myr, pushing the beginnings of this galaxy to $z &amp;gt;$ 10.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Killi_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Meghana Killi&lt;/a&gt; (1 and 2), &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Watson_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Darach Watson&lt;/a&gt; (1 and 2), &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Fujimoto_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Seiji Fujimoto&lt;/a&gt; (1 and 2), &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Akins_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Hollis Akins&lt;/a&gt; (3), &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Knudsen_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Kirsten Knudsen&lt;/a&gt; (4), &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Richard_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Johan Richard&lt;/a&gt; (5), &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Harikane_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yuichi Harikane&lt;/a&gt; (6 and 7), &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Rigopoulou_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Dmitra Rigopoulou&lt;/a&gt; (8), &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Rizzo_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Francesca Rizzo&lt;/a&gt; (1 and 2), &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Ginolfi_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Michele Ginolfi&lt;/a&gt; (9), &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Popping_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Gerg&amp;#xf6; Popping&lt;/a&gt; (9), &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Kokorev_V/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Vasily Kokorev&lt;/a&gt; (1 and 2) ((1) Cosmic Dawn Center (DAWN), (2) Niels Bohr Institute, University of Copenhagen, (3) Department of Astronomy, The University of Texas at Austin, (4) Department of Space, Earth and Environment, Chalmers University of Technology, Onsala Space Observatory, (5) Univ Lyon, Centre de Recherche Astrophysique de Lyon, (6) Institute for Cosmic Ray Research, The University of Tokyo, (7) Department of Physics and Astronomy, University College London, (8) Astrophysics, Department of Physics, University of Oxford, (9) European Southern Observatory, Garching, Germany)</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01445">
<title>The apparent eta Carinae&apos;s long-term evolution and the critical role played by the strengthening of P Cygni absorption lines. (arXiv:2211.01445v1 [astro-ph.SR])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01445</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Over the entire 20th century, Eta Carinae (\ec) has displayed a unique
spectrum, which recently has been evolving towards that of a typical LBV. The
two competing scenarios to explain such evolution are: (1) a dissipating
occulter in front of a stable star or (2) a decreasing mass loss rate of the
star. The first mechanism simultaneously explains why the central star appears
to be secularly increasing its apparent brightness while its luminosity does
not change; why the Homunculus&apos; apparent brightness remains almost constant;
and why the spectrum seen in direct light is becoming more similar to that
reflected from the Homunculus (and which resembles a typical LBV). The second
scenario does not account for these facts and predicts an increase in the
terminal speed of the wind, contrary to observations. In this work, we present
new data showing that the P Cygni absorption lines are secularly strengthening,
which is not the expected behaviour for a decreasing wind-density scenario.
CMFGEN modelling of the primary&apos;s wind with a small occulter in front agrees
with observations. One could argue that invoking a dissipating coronagraphic
occulter makes this object even more peculiar than it already appears to be.
However, on the contrary, it solves the apparent contradictions between many
observations. Moreover, by assigning the long-term behaviour to circumstellar
causes and the periodic variations due to binarity, a star more stable after
the 1900s than previously thought is revealed, contrary to the earlier paradigm
of an unpredictable object.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Damineli_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;A. Damineli&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Hillier_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;D. J. Hillier&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Navarete_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;F. Navarete&lt;/a&gt; (3), &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Moffat_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;A. F. J. Moffat&lt;/a&gt; (4), &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Weigelt_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;G. Weigelt&lt;/a&gt; (7), &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Gull_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;T. R. Gull&lt;/a&gt; (5), &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Corcoran_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;M.F. Corcoran&lt;/a&gt; (10, 11), &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Richardson_N/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;N. D. Richardson&lt;/a&gt; (6), &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Ho_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;T. P. Ho&lt;/a&gt; (8), &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Madura_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;T.I. Madura&lt;/a&gt; (9), &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Espinoza_Galeas_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;D. Espinoza-Galeas&lt;/a&gt; (12), &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Hartman_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;H. Hartman&lt;/a&gt; (13), &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Morris_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;P. Morris&lt;/a&gt; (14), &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Pickett_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;C. S. Pickett&lt;/a&gt; (15), &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Stevens_I/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;I. R. Stevens&lt;/a&gt; (16), &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Russell_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;C. M. P. Russell&lt;/a&gt; (10, 11), &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Hamaguchi_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;K. Hamaguchi&lt;/a&gt; (10, 17), &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Jablonski_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;F. J. Jablonski&lt;/a&gt; (18), &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Teodoro_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;M. Teodoro&lt;/a&gt; (19), &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+McGee_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;P. McGee&lt;/a&gt; (20, 21), &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Cacella_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;P. Cacella&lt;/a&gt; (21), &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Heathcote_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;B. Heathcote&lt;/a&gt; (21), &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Harrison_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;K. Harrison&lt;/a&gt; (21), &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Johnston_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;M. Johnston&lt;/a&gt; (21), &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Bohlsen_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;T. Bohlsen&lt;/a&gt; (21), &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Scala_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;G. Di Scala&lt;/a&gt; (21) ((1) Universidade de S&amp;#xe3;o Paulo, Instituto de Astronomia, Geof&amp;#xed;sica e Ci&amp;#xea;ncias Atmosf&amp;#xe9;ricas, S&amp;#xe3;o Paulo, Brazil, (2) Department of Physics and Astronomy &amp;amp; Pittsburgh Particle Physics, Astrophysics, and Cosmology Center (PITT PACC), University of Pittsburgh, Pittsburgh, PA, USA, (3) SOAR Telescope/NSF&amp;#x27;s NOIRLab, La Serena, Chile, (4) D&amp;#xe9;partement de Physique and Centre de Recherche en Astrophysique du Qu&amp;#xe9;bec (CRAQ), Universit&amp;#xe9; de Montr&amp;#xe9;al, Montr&amp;#xe9;al, Qu&amp;#xe9;bec, Canada, (5) Exoplanets &amp;amp; Stellar Astrophysics Laboratory, NASA/Goddard Space Flight Center, Greenbelt, MD, USA, (6) Department of Physics and Astronomy, Embry-Riddle Aeronautical University, Prescott, AZ, USA, (7) Max Planck Institute for Radio Astronomy, Bonn, Germany, (8) Department of Applied Mathematics, University of California, Santa Cruz, Santa Cruz, CA, USA, (9) Department of Physics and Astronomy, San Jos&amp;#xe9; State University, San Jos&amp;#xe9;, CA, USA, (10) CRESST II and X-ray Astrophysics Laboratory, NASA/Goddard Space Flight Center, Greenbelt, MD, USA, (11) The Catholic University of America, Washington, DC, USA, (12) Departamento de Astronomia y Astrofisica, Facultad de Ciencias Espaciales, Universidad Nacional Autonoma de Honduras, Bulevar Suyapa, Tegucigalpa, M.D.C, Honduras, Centroamerica, (13) Materials Science and Applied Mathematics, Malm&amp;#xf6; University, Malm&amp;#xf6;, Sweden, (14) California Institute of Technology, IPAC, Pasadena, CA, USA, (15) Department of Physics and Astronomy, Embry-Riddle Aeronautical University, Prescott, AZ, USA, (16) School of Physics &amp;amp; Astronomy, University of Birmingham, Birmingham, UK, (17) Department of Physics, University of Maryland Baltimore County, Baltimore, MD, USA, (18) Instituto Nacional de Pesquisas Espaciais/MCTIC, S&amp;#xe3;o Jos&amp;#xe9; dos Campos, SP, Brazil, (19) Space Telescope Science Institute, Baltimore, MD, USA, (20) Department of Physics, School of Physical Sciences, University of Adelaide, South Australia, (21) SASER Team, South Yarra, Vic, Australia)</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01449">
<title>The Fifth Catalogue of Nearby Stars (CNS5). (arXiv:2211.01449v1 [astro-ph.SR])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01449</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We present the compilation of the Fifth Catalogue of Nearby Stars (CNS5),
based on astrometric and photometric data from Gaia EDR3 and Hipparcos, and
supplemented with parallaxes from ground-based astrometric surveys carried out
in the infrared.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The aim of the CNS5 is to provide the most complete sample of objects in the
solar neighbourhood. For all known stars and brown dwarfs in the 25 pc sphere
around the Sun, basic astrometric and photometric parameters are given.
Furthermore, we provide the colour-magnitude diagram and various luminosity
functions of the stellar content in the solar neighbourhood, and characterise
the completeness of the CNS5 catalogue.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We compile a sample of stars and brown dwarfs which most likely are located
within 25 pc of the Sun, taking space-based parallaxes from Gaia EDR3 and
Hipparcos as well as ground-based parallaxes from Best et al. (2021),
Kirkpatrick et al. (2021), and from the CNS4 into account. We develop a set of
selection criteria to clean the sample from spurious sources. Furthermore, we
show that effects of blending in the Gaia photometry, which affect mainly the
faint and red sources in Gaia, can be mitigated, to reliably place those
objects in a colour-magnitude diagram. We also assess the completeness of the
CNS5 using a Kolmogorov-Smirnov test and derive observational optical and
mid-infrared luminosity functions for the main-sequence stars and white dwarfs
in the solar neighbourhood. The CNS5 contains 5931 objects, including 5230
stars (4946 main-sequence stars, 20 red giants and 264 white dwarfs) and 701
brown dwarfs.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We find that the CNS5 catalogue is statistically complete down to 19.7 mag in
G-band and 11.8 mag in W1-band absolute magnitudes, corresponding to a spectral
type of L8.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Golovin_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Alex Golovin&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Reffert_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Sabine Reffert&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Just_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Andreas Just&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Jordan_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Stefan Jordan&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Vani_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Akash Vani&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Jahreiss_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Hartmut Jahrei&amp;#xdf;&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01460">
<title>Possible optical counterparts of ULXs in NGC 1672. (arXiv:2211.01460v1 [astro-ph.SR])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01460</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;In this study, we use archival data from HST, Chandra, XMM-Newton, and
Swift-XRT, to probe the nature of 9 (X1-X9) candidate ULXs in NGC 1672. Our
study focuses on using the precise source positions obtained via improved
astrometry based on {\it Chandra} and HST observations to search for and
identify optical counterparts for these ULXs.Unique optical counterparts are
identified for X2 an{d X6; two potential counterparts were determined for X1,
X5 and X7 within the respective error radii while no optical counterparts were
found for the remaining four sources. Based on spectral energy distributions
(SEDs), X-ray and optical temporal analyses, some evidences about the nature of
X1 and X2 were obtained.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Allak_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;S. Allak&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Akyuz_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;A. Akyuz&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Sonbas_E/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;E. Sonbas&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Dhuga_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;K. S. Dhuga&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01526">
<title>Dust temperature uncertainties hamper the inference of dust and molecular gas masses from the dust continuum emission of quiescent high-redshift galaxies. (arXiv:2211.01526v1 [astro-ph.GA])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01526</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Single flux density measurements at observed-frame sub-millimeter and
millimeter wavelengths are commonly used to probe dust and gas masses in
galaxies. In this Letter, we explore the robustness of this method to infer
dust mass, focusing on quiescent galaxies, using a series of controlled
experiments on four massive haloes from the Feedback in Realistic Environments
(FIRE) project. Our starting point is four star-forming, central galaxies at
seven redshifts between z=1.5 and z=4.5. We generate modified quiescent
galaxies that have been quenched for 100Myr, 500Myr, or 1Gyr prior to each of
the studied redshifts by re-assigning stellar ages. We derive spectral energy
distributions for each fiducial and modified galaxy using radiative transfer.
We demonstrate that the dust mass inferred is highly dependent on the assumed
dust temperature, T_dust, which is often unconstrained observationally.
Motivated by recent work on quiescent galaxies that assumed T_dust~25K, we show
that the ratio between dust mass and 1.3mm flux density can be higher than
inferred by up to an order of magnitude, due to the considerably lower dust
temperatures seen in non star-forming galaxies. This can lead to an
underestimation of dust mass (and, when sub-mm flux density is used as a proxy
for molecular gas content, gas mass). This underestimation is most severe at
higher redshifts, where the observed-frame 1.3mm flux density probes rest-frame
wavelengths far from the Rayleigh-Jeans regime, and hence depends
super-linearly on dust temperature. We fit relations between ratios of
rest-frame far-infrared flux densities and mass-weighted dust temperature that
can be used to constrain dust temperatures from observations and hence derive
more reliable dust and molecular gas masses.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Cochrane_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;R. K. Cochrane&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Hayward_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;C. C. Hayward&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Angles_Alcazar_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;D. Angl&amp;#xe9;s-Alc&amp;#xe1;zar&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01534">
<title>Constructing the Milky Way Stellar Halo in the Galactic Center by Direct Orbit Integration. (arXiv:2211.01534v1 [astro-ph.GA])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01534</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The halo stars on highly radial orbits should inevitably pass the center
regions of the Milky Way. Under the assumption that the stellar halo is in
dynamical equilibrium and axisymmetric, we integrate the orbits of $\sim
10,000$ halo K-giants at $5\leq r \leq 50$ kpc cross-matched from LAMOST DR5
and $Gaia$ DR3. By carefully considering the selection function, we construct
the stellar halo distribution at the entire regions of $r \leq 50$ kpc. We find
that a double-broken power-law function well describes the stellar halo density
distribution with shallower slopes in the inner regions and the two breaks at
$r=10$ kpc and $r=25$ kpc, respectively. The stellar halo becomes flatter from
outer to inner regions but has $q\sim 0.5$ at $r \lesssim 5$ kpc. The stellar
halo becomes isotropic with a slight prograde rotation in the inner 5 kpc, and
reaches velocity dispersions of $\sim 250\rm \ km\ s^{-1}$. We get a weak
negative metallicity gradient of $-0.005$ dex kpc$^{-1}$ at $5\leq r \leq 50$
kpc, while there is an excess of relative metal-rich stars with [Fe/H]$&amp;gt;-1$ in
the inner 10 kpc. The halo interlopers at $r \leq 5$ kpc from integration of
our sample has a mass of $\sim1.2 \times 10^8\ M_{\odot}$ ($\sim 4.7 \times
10^7\ M_{\odot}$ at [Fe/H]$&amp;lt;-1.5$), which can explain 50-100% of the metal-poor
stars with [Fe/H]$&amp;lt;-1.5$ directly observed in the Galactic central regions.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Yang_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Chengqun Yang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Zhu_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ling Zhu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Tahmasebzadeh_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Behzad Tahmasebzadeh&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Xue_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xiang-Xiang Xue&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Liu_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Chao Liu&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01608">
<title>Detection of complex nitrogen-bearing molecule ethyl cyanide towards the hot molecular core G10.47+0.03. (arXiv:2211.01608v1 [astro-ph.GA])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01608</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The studies of the complex molecular lines towards the hot molecular cores at
millimeter and submillimeter wavelengths provide instructive knowledge about
the chemical complexity in the interstellar medium (ISM). We presented the
detection of the rotational emission lines of the complex nitrogen-bearing
molecule ethyl cyanide (C$_{2}$H$_{5}$CN) towards the hot molecular core
G10.47+0.03 using the Atacama Large Millimeter/Submillimeter Array (ALMA) band
4 observations. The estimated column density of C$_{2}$H$_{5}$CN towards
G10.47+0.03 was (9.5$\pm$0.1)$\times$10$^{16}$ cm$^{-2}$ with the rotational
temperature of 223.8$\pm$4.3 K. The estimated fractional abundance of
C$_{2}$H$_{5}$CN with respect to H$_{2}$ towards G10.47+0.03 was
1.90$\times$10$^{-8}$. We observed that the estimated fractional abundance of
C$_{2}$H$_{5}$CN is nearly similar to the simulated abundance of
C$_{2}$H$_{5}$CN which was predicted by the three-phase warm-up model from
Garrod (2013). We also discuss the possible formation mechanism of
C$_{2}$H$_{5}$CN towards the hot molecular cores and we claimed the barrierless
and exothermic radical-radical reaction between CH$_{2}$ and CH$_{2}$CN is
responsible for the production of high abundant C$_{2}$H$_{5}$CN
($\sim$10$^{-8}$) towards G10.47+0.03 during the warm-up phases.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Manna_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Arijit Manna&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Pal_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Sabyasachi Pal&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01619">
<title>The Steady-State Multi-TeV Diffuse Gamma-Ray Emission Predicted with GALPROP and Prospects for the Cherenkov Telescope Array. (arXiv:2211.01619v1 [astro-ph.HE])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01619</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Cosmic Rays (CRs) interact with the diffuse gas, radiation, and magnetic
fields in the interstellar medium (ISM) to produce electromagnetic emissions
that are a significant component of the all-sky flux across a broad wavelength
range. The Fermi Large Area Telescope (LAT) has measured these emissions at GeV
$\gamma$-ray energies with high statistics. Meanwhile, the High-Energy
Stereoscopic System (H.E.S.S.) telescope array has observed large-scale
Galactic diffuse emission in the TeV $\gamma$-ray energy range. The emissions
observed at GeV and TeV energies are connected by the common origin of the CR
particles injected by the sources, but the energy dependence of the mixture
from the general ISM (true `diffuse&apos;), those emanating from the relatively
nearby interstellar space about the sources, and the sources themselves, is not
well understood. In this paper, we investigate predictions of the broadband
emissions using the GALPROP code over a grid of steady-state 3D models that
include variations over CR sources, and other ISM target distributions. We
compare, in particular, the model predictions in the VHE ($\geq$100 GeV)
$\gamma$-ray range with the H.E.S.S. Galactic plane survey (HGPS) after
carefully subtracting emission from catalogued $\gamma$-ray sources. Accounting
for the unresolved source contribution, and the systematic uncertainty of the
HGPS, we find that the GALPROP model predictions agree with lower estimates for
the HGPS source-subtracted diffuse flux. We discuss the implications of the
modelling results for interpretation of data from the next generation Cherenkov
Telescope Array (CTA).
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Marinos_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;P. D. Marinos&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Rowell_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;G. P. Rowell&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Porter_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;T. A. Porter&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Johannesson_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;G. J&amp;#xf3;hannesson&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01636">
<title>Rotational spectra of interstellar N- and CN-PAHs: pyrene and coronene. (arXiv:2211.01636v1 [astro-ph.GA])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01636</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The detection of benzonitrile (C6H5CN), 1- and 2-cyano-naphthalene (C10H7CN)
in the cold, dark molecular cloud TMC-1 at centimetre (cm) wavelengths has
opened up prospects for the detection of other N- and CN-containing polycyclic
aromatic hydrocarbons (PAHs). In this light, the pure rotational spectra of
N-pyrene (C15H9N), CN-pyrene (C15H9CN), N-coronene (C23H11N) and CN-coronene
(C23H11CN) are reported here for the first time. The B3LYP/6-311+G(d,p) level
of theory, in the Density Functional Theory (DFT) calculations, achieves the
best performance for calculating the spectroscopic parameters and simulating
the rotational spectra. The large permanent dipole moment of CN-PAHs makes them
the most suitable PAH species for detection in the interstellar medium.
Additionally, pyrene&apos;s smaller partition function makes CN-pyrene a prime
candidate to be discovered in cold, dark molecular clouds such as the TMC-1.
The present work sets a benchmark for theoretical rotational spectra of N- and
CN-containing PAHs and may act as a guide for laboratory experiments and
observational searches.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Vats_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Akant Vats&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Pathak_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Amit Pathak&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01641">
<title>The Unusual AGN Host NGC 1266: Evidence for Shocks in a Molecular Gas Rich S0 Galaxy with a Low Luminosity Nucleus. (arXiv:2211.01641v1 [astro-ph.GA])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01641</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;NGC 1266 is a lenticular galaxy (S0) hosting an active galactic nucleus
(AGN), and known to contain a large amount of shocked gas. We compare the
luminosity ratio of mid-\emph{J} CO lines to IR continuum with star-forming
galaxies (SFGs), and then model the CO spectral line energy distribution
(SLED). We confirm that in the mid- and high-\emph{J} regions ($J_{\rm up}$ =
4--13), the C-type shock ($v_{\rm s}$ = 25 km s$^{-1}$, $n_{\rm H}$ =
$5\times10^{4}$ cm$^{-3}$) can reproduce the CO observations well. The galaxy
spectral energy distribution (SED) is constructed and modeled by the code {\tt
X-CIGALE} and obtains a set of physical parameters including the star formation
rate (SFR, 1.17 $\pm$ 0.47 \emph{M$_{\odot}$}yr$^{-1}$). Also, our work
provides SFR derivation of [C\,{\sc ii}] from the neutral hydrogen regions only
(1.38 $\pm$ 0.14 $M_{\odot}$yr$^{-1}$). Previous studies have illusive
conclusions on the AGN or starburst nature of the NGC 1266 nucleus. Our SED
model shows that the hidden AGN in the system is intrinsically low-luminosity,
consequently the infrared luminosity of the AGN does not reach the expected
level. Archival data from \emph{NuSTAR} hard X-ray observations in the 3--79
keV band shows a marginal detection, disfavoring presence of an obscured
luminous AGN and implying that a compact starburst is more likely dominant for
the NGC 1266 nucleus.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Chen_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Peibin Chen&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Zhao_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yinghe Zhao&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Wang_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Junfeng Wang&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01694">
<title>Spectroscopic follow-up of a sub-set of the Gaia/IPHAS catalogue of H\alpha-excess sources. (arXiv:2211.01694v1 [astro-ph.GA])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01694</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;State-of-the-art techniques to identify H\alpha emission line sources in
narrow-band photometric surveys consist of searching for H\alpha excess with
reference to nearby objects in the sky (position-based selection). However,
while this approach usually yields very few spurious detections, it may fail to
select intrinsically faint and/or rare H\alpha-excess sources. In order to
obtain a more complete representation of the heterogeneous emission line
populations, we recently developed a technique to find outliers relative to
nearby objects in the colour-magnitude diagram (CMD-based selection). By
combining position-based and CMD-based selections, we built an updated
catalogue of H\alpha-excess candidates in the northern Galactic Plane. Here we
present spectroscopic follow-up observations and classification of 114 objects
from this catalogue, that enable us to test our novel selection method. Out of
the 70 spectroscopically confirmed H\alpha emitters in our sample, 15 were
identified only by the CMD-based selection, and would have been thus missed by
the classic position-based technique. In addition, we explore the distribution
of our spectroscopically confirmed emitters in the Gaia CMD. This information
can support the classification of emission line sources in large surveys, such
as the upcoming WEAVE and 4MOST, especially if augmented with the introduction
of other colours.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Fratta_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;M. Fratta&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Scaringi_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;S. Scaringi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Monguio_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;M. Mongui&amp;#xf3;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Pala_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;A. F. Pala&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Drew_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;J. E. Drew&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Knigge_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;C. Knigge&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Ilkiewicz_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;K. A. I&amp;#x142;kiewicz&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Gandhi_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;P. Gandhi&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01708">
<title>Ionising feedback from an O star formed in a shock-compressed layer. (arXiv:2211.01708v1 [astro-ph.GA])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01708</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We develop a simple analytic model for what happens when an O star (or
compact cluster of OB stars) forms in a shock compressed layer and carves out
an approximately circular hole in the layer, at the waist of a bipolar HII
Region (HIIR). The model is characterised by three parameters: the
half-thickness of the undisturbed layer, Zlay, the mean number-density of
hydrogen molecules in the undisturbed layer, nlay, and the (collective)
ionising output of the star(s), NdotLyC. The radius of the circular hole is
given by WIF ~ 3.8 pc [Zlay/0.1pc]^{-1/6} [nlay/10^4cm^{-3}]^{-1/3}
[NdotLyC/10^{49} s^{-1}]^{1/6} [t/Myr]^{2/3}. Similar power-law expressions are
obtained for the rate at which ionised gas is fed into the bipolar lobes; the
rate at which molecular gas is swept up into a dense ring by the shock front
(SF) that precedes the ionisation front (IF); and the density in this dense
ring. We suggest that our model might be a useful zeroth-order representation
of many observed HIIRs. From viewing directions close to the midplane of the
layer, the HIIR will appear bipolar. From viewing directions approximately
normal to the layer it will appear to be a limb-brightened shell but too faint
through the centre to be a spherically symmetric bubble. From intermediate
viewing angles more complicated morphologies can be expected.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Whitworth_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Anthony Whitworth&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Priestley_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Felix Priestley&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Geen_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Samuel Geen&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01718">
<title>The SPHERE view of multiple star formation. (arXiv:2211.01718v1 [astro-ph.SR])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01718</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;While a large fraction of the stars are in multiple systems, our
understanding of the processes leading to the formation of these systems is
still inadequate. Given the large theoretical uncertainties, observation plays
a basic role. Here we discuss the contribution of high contrast imaging, and
more specifically of the SPHERE instrument at the ESO Very Large Telescope, in
this area. SPHERE nicely complements other techniques - in particular those
exploiting Gaia and ALMA - in detecting and characterising systems near the
peak of the distribution with separation and allows to capture snapshots of
binary formation within disks that are invaluable for the understanding of disk
fragmentation.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Gratton_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;R.Gratton&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Desidera_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;S. Desidera&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Marzari_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;F. Marzari&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Bonavita_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;M. Bonavita&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01744">
<title>The galaxy formation origin of the lensing is low problem. (arXiv:2211.01744v1 [astro-ph.CO])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01744</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;It is now well-established that $\Lambda$CDM predictions overestimate
gravitational lensing measurements around massive galaxies by about 30%, the
so-called lensing is low problem. Using a state-of-the-art hydrodynamical
simulation, we show that this discrepancy reflects shortcomings in standard
structure formation models rather than tensions within the $\Lambda$CDM
paradigm itself. Specifically, this problem results from ignoring a variety of
galaxy formation effects in simple models, including assembly bias, segregation
of satellite galaxies relative to dark matter, and baryonic effects on the
matter distribution. Each of these contributes towards overestimating
gravitational lensing and, when combined, these explain the amplitude and scale
dependence of the lensing is low problem. We conclude that simplistic structure
formation models are inadequate to interpret lensing and clustering together,
and that it is crucial to employ more sophisticated models for the upcoming
generation of large-scale surveys.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Chaves_Montero_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jonas Chaves-Montero&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Angulo_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Raul E. Angulo&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Contreras_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Sergio Contreras&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01821">
<title>A Virgo Environmental Survey Tracing Ionised Gas Emission (VESTIGE).XIV. The main sequence relation in a rich environment down to M_star ~ 10^6 Mo. (arXiv:2211.01821v1 [astro-ph.GA])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01821</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Using a compilation of Halpha fluxes for 384 star forming galaxies detected
during the VESTIGE survey, we study several important scaling relations for a
complete sample of galaxies in a rich environment. The extraordinary
sensitivity of the data allows us to sample the whole dynamic range of the
Halpha luminosity function, from massive (M*~10^11 Mo) to dwarf systems
(M*~10^6 Mo). This extends previous works to a dynamic range in stellar mass
and star formation rate (10^-4&amp;lt;SFR&amp;lt;10 Mo yr^-1) never explored so far. The main
sequence (MS) relation derived for all star forming galaxies within one virial
radius of the Virgo cluster has a slope comparable to that observed in other
nearby samples of isolated objects, but has a dispersion ~3 times larger. The
dispersion is tightly connected to the available amount of HI gas, with
gas-poor systems located far below objects of similar stellar mass but with a
normal HI content. When measured on unperturbed galaxies with a normal HI gas
content, the relation has a slope a=0.92, an intercept b=-1.57, and a scatter
~0.40. We compare these observational results to the prediction of models. The
observed scatter in the MS relation can be reproduced only after a violent and
active stripping process such as ram-pressure that removes gas from the disc
and quenches star formation on short (&amp;lt;1 Gyr) timescales. This rules out milder
processes such as starvation. This interpretation is also consistent with the
position of galaxies of different star formation activity and gas content
within the phase-space diagram. We also show that the star forming regions
formed in the stripped material outside perturbed galaxies are located well
above the MS relation drawn by unperturbed systems. These HII regions, which
might be at the origin of compact sources typical in rich environments, are
living a starburst phase lasting only &amp;lt;50 Myr, later becoming quiescent
systems.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Boselli_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;A. Boselli&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Fossati_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;M. Fossati&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Roediger_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;J. Roediger&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Boquien_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;M. Boquien&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Fumagalli_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;M. Fumagalli&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Balogh_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;M. Balogh&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Boissier_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;S. Boissier&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Braine_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;J. Braine&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Ciesla_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;L. Ciesla&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Cote_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;P. C&amp;#xf4;t&amp;#xe9;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Cuillandre_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;J.C. Cuillandre&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Ferrarese_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;L. Ferrarese&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Gavazzi_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;G. Gavazzi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Gwyn_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;S. Gwyn&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Junais/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Junais&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Hensler_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;G. Hensler&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Longobardi_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;A. Longobardi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Sun_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;M. Sun&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01891">
<title>Protostellar collapse simulations in spherical geometry with dust coagulation and fragmentation. (arXiv:2211.01891v1 [astro-ph.GA])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01891</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We model the coagulation and fragmentation of dust grains during the
protostellar collapse with our newly developed shark code. It solves the
gas-dust hydrodynamics in a spherical geometry and the
coagulation/fragmentation equation. It also computes the ionization state of
the cloud and the Ohmic, ambipolar and Hall resistivities. We find that the
dust size distribution evolves significantly during the collapse, large grain
formation being controlled by the turbulent differential velocity. When
turbulence is included, only ambipolar diffusion remains efficient at removing
the small grains from the distribution, brownian motion is only efficient as a
standalone process. The macroscopic gas-dust drift is negligible for grain
growth and only dynamically significant near the first Larson core. At high
density, we find that the coagulated distribution is unaffected by the initial
choice of dust distribution. Strong magnetic fields are found to enhance the
small grains depletion, causing an important increase of the ambipolar
diffusion. This hints that the magnetic field strength could be regulated by
the small grain population during the protostellar collapse. Fragmentation
could be effective for bare silicates, but its modeling relies on the choice of
ill-constrained parameters. It is also found to be negligible for icy grains.
When fragmentation occurs, it strongly affects the magnetic resistivities
profiles. Dust coagulation is a critical process that needs to be fully taken
into account during the protostellar collapse. The onset and feedback of
fragmentation remains uncertain and its modeling should be further
investigated.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Lebreuilly_U/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ugo Lebreuilly&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Vallucci_Goy_V/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Valentin Vallucci-Goy&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Guillet_V/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Vincent Guillet&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Lombart_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Maxime Lombart&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Marchand_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Pierre Marchand&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01897">
<title>Demographics of the M-star Multiple Population in the Orion Nebula Cluster. (arXiv:2211.01897v1 [astro-ph.GA])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01897</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We present updated results constraining multiplicity demographics for the
stellar population of the Orion Nebula Cluster (ONC, a high-mass, high-density
star-forming region), across primary masses 0.08-0.7M$_{\odot}$. Our study
utilizes archival Hubble Space Telescope data obtained with the Advanced Camera
for Surveys using multiple filters (GO-10246). Previous multiplicity surveys in
low-mass, low-density associations like Taurus identify an excess of companions
to low-mass stars roughly twice that of the Galactic field and find the mass
ratio distribution consistent with the field. Previously, we found the
companion frequency to low-mass stars in the ONC is consistent with the
Galactic field over mass ratios=0.6-1.0 and projected separations=30-160au,
without placing constraints on the mass ratio distribution. In this study, we
investigate the companion population of the ONC with a double point-spread
function (PSF) fitting algorithm sensitive to separations larger than 10au
(0.025&quot;) using empirical PSF models. We identified 44 companions (14 new), and
with a Bayesian analysis, estimate the companion frequency to low-mass stars in
the ONC =0.13$^{+0.05}_{-0.03}$ and the power law fit index to the mass ratio
distribution =2.08$^{+1.03}_{-0.85}$ over all mass ratios and projected
separations of 10-200au. We find the companion frequency in the ONC is
consistent with the Galactic field population, likely from high transient
stellar density states, and a probability of 0.002 that it is consistent with
that of Taurus. We also find the ONC mass ratio distribution is consistent with
the field and Taurus, potentially indicative of its primordial nature, a direct
outcome of the star formation process.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Furio_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Matthew De Furio&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Liu_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Christopher Liu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Meyer_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Michael R. Meyer&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Reiter_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Megan Reiter&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Kraus_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Adam Kraus&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Dupuy_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Trent Dupuy&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Monnier_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;John Monnier&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01922">
<title>Star Formation Variability as a Probe for the Baryon Cycle within Galaxies. (arXiv:2211.01922v1 [astro-ph.GA])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01922</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We investigate the connection of the regulation of star formation and the
cycling of baryons within and in and out of galaxies. We use idealized
numerical simulations of Milky Way-mass galaxies, in which we systemically vary
the galaxy morphology (bulge-to-total mass ratio) and stellar feedback strength
(total eight setups with 80 simulations). By following individual gas parcels
through the disk, spiral arms, and massive star-forming clumps, we quantify how
gas moves and oscillates through the different phases of the interstellar
medium (ISM) and forms stars. We show that the residence time of gas in the
dense ISM phase ($\tau_{\rm SF}$), the nature of spiral arms (strength,
number), and the clump properties (number, mass function, and young star
fraction) depend on both the galaxy morphology and stellar feedback. Based on
these results, we quantify signatures of the baryon cycle within galaxies using
the temporal and spatial power spectrum density (PSD) of the star formation
history (SFH). Stronger stellar feedback leads to more bursty star formation
while the correlation timescale of the SFH is longer, because stronger feedback
dissolves the dense, star-forming ISM phase, leading to a more homogeneous ISM
and a decrease in $\tau_{\rm SF}$. The bulge strength has a similar effect: the
deep gravitational potential in a bulge-dominant galaxy imposes a strong shear
force that effectively breaks apart gas clumps in the ISM; this subsequently
inhibits the fragmentation of cool gas and therefore the star formation in the
disk, leading to a decrease in the spatial power on scales of $\sim$ 1 kpc. We
conclude that measurements of the temporal and spatial PSD of the SFH can
provide constraints on the baryon cycle and the star formation process.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Shin_E/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Eun-jin Shin&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Tacchella_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Sandro Tacchella&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Kim_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ji-hoon Kim&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Iyer_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Kartheik G. Iyer&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Semenov_V/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Vadim A. Semenov&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01931">
<title>The Effect of Shock Wave Duration on Star Formation and the Initial Condition of Massive Cluster Formation. (arXiv:2211.01931v1 [astro-ph.GA])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01931</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Stars are born in dense molecular filaments irrespective of their mass.
Compression of the ISM by shocks cause filament formation in molecular clouds.
Observations show that a massive star cluster formation occurs where the peak
of gas column density in a cloud exceeds 10^23 cm^-2. In this study, we
investigate the effect of the shock-compressed layer duration on filament/star
formation and how the initial conditions of massive star formation are realized
by performing three-dimensional (3D) isothermal magnetohydrodynamics (MHD)
simulations with {gas inflow duration from the boundaries (i.e., shock wave
duration)} as a controlling parameter. Filaments formed behind the shock expand
after the duration time for short shock duration models, whereas long duration
models lead to star formation by forming massive supercritical filaments.
Moreover, when the shock duration is longer than two postshock free-fall times,
the peak column density of the compressed layer exceeds 10^23 cm^-2, and {the
gravitational collapse of the layer causes that} the number of OB stars
expected to be formed in the shock-compressed layer reaches the order of ten
(i.e., massive cluster formation).
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Abe_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Daisei Abe&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Inoue_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Tsuyoshi Inoue&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Enokiya_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Rei Enokiya&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Fukui_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yasuo Fukui&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.02038">
<title>On the observability and identification of Population III galaxies with JWST. (arXiv:2211.02038v1 [astro-ph.GA])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.02038</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We utilise theoretical models of Population III stellar+nebular spectra to
investigate the prospects of observing and accurately identifying Population
III galaxies with JWST using both deep imaging and spectroscopy. We investigate
a series of different colour cuts, finding that a combination of NIRCam and
MIRI photometry through the F444W-F560W, F560W-F770W colours offers the most
robust identifier of potential $z=8$ Pop III candidates. We calculate that
NIRCam will have to reach $\sim$28.5-30.0 AB mag depths (1-20 h), and MIRI
F560W must reach $\sim$27.5-29.0 AB mag depths (10-100 h) to achieve $5\sigma$
continuum detections of $M_* = 10^6~\mathrm{M}_\odot$ Pop III galaxies at
$z=8$. We also discuss the prospects of identifying Pop III candidates through
slitless and NIRSpec spectroscopic surveys that target Ly$\alpha$, H$\beta$
and/or He II $\lambda 1640$. We find small differences in the H$\beta$
rest-frame equivalent width (EW) between Pop III and non-Pop III galaxies,
rendering this diagnostic likely impractical. We find that the detection of
high EW He II $\lambda 1640$ emission will serve as the definitive Pop III
identifier, requiring (ultra-)deep integrations (10-250 h) with NIRSpec/G140M
for $M_*=10^6~\mathrm{M}_\odot$ Pop III galaxies at $z=8$. With moderate
($\mu=$2-3) lensing and/or moderately massive ($M_*=
2$-$3\times10^6~\mathrm{M}_\odot$) Pop III galaxies, such line detections can
be achieved in medium-sized JWST GO programs. However, MIRI F770W detections of
Pop III galaxies will require substantial gravitational lensing ($\mu=10$)
and/or fortuitous imaging of exceptionally massive ($M_* =
10^7~\mathrm{M}_\odot$) Pop III galaxies. Thus, NIRCam medium-band imaging
surveys that can search for high EW He II $\lambda 1640$ emitters in photometry
may perhaps be a viable alternative for finding Pop III candidates.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Trussler_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;James A. A. Trussler&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Conselice_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Christopher J. Conselice&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Adams_N/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Nathan J. Adams&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Maiolino_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Roberto Maiolino&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Nakajima_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Kimihiko Nakajima&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Zackrisson_E/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Erik Zackrisson&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Ferreira_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Leonardo Ferreira&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2201.10480">
<title>Galaxy and Mass Assembly (GAMA): Mid-infrared properties as tracers of galaxy environment. (arXiv:2201.10480v2 [astro-ph.GA] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2201.10480</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We investigate how different mid-infrared (mid-IR) properties of galaxies
trace the environment in which the galaxies are located. For this purpose, we
first study the dependence of galaxy clustering on the absolute magnitude at
3.4 $\mu$m and redshift. Then, we look into the environmental dependence of
mid-IR luminosities and the galaxy properties derived from these luminosities.
We also explore how various infrared galaxy luminosity selections influence the
galaxy clustering measurements. We use a set of W1 (3.4 $\mu$m) absolute
magnitude ($M_\text{W1}$) selected samples from the Galaxy and Mass Assembly
(GAMA) survey matched with mid-IR properties from the Wide-field Infrared
Survey Explorer (WISE) in the redshift range $0.07 \leq z &amp;lt; 0.43$. We compute
the galaxy two-point correlation function (2pCF) and compare the clustering
lengths between subsamples binned in $M_\text{W1}$ and in redshift. We also
measure the marked correlation functions (MCFs) using the luminosities in the
WISE W1 to W4 (3.4 to 22 $\mu$m) bands as marks. Additionally, we compare the
measurements of MCFs with different estimates of stellar mass and star
formation rate used as marks. Finally, we check how different selections
applied to the sample affect the clustering measurements. We show strong
clustering dependence on the W1 absolute magnitude: galaxies brighter in the W1
band are more strongly clustered than their fainter counterparts. We also
observe a lack of significant redshift dependence of clustering in the redshift
range $0.07 \leq z &amp;lt; 0.43$. We show that although W1 and W2 bands are direct
indicators of stellar mass, a galaxy sample selected based on W1 or W2 bands
does not perfectly show the clustering behaviour of a stellar mass selected
sample. Similar is the case with the proxy relation between W3 and W4 bands and
star formation rate.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Sureshkumar_U/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;U. Sureshkumar&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Durkalec_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;A. Durkalec&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Pollo_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;A. Pollo&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Bilicki_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;M. Bilicki&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Cluver_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;M. E. Cluver&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Bellstedt_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;S. Bellstedt&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Farrow_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;D. J. Farrow&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Loveday_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;J. Loveday&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Taylor_E/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;E. N. Taylor&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Bland_Hawthorn_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;J. Bland-Hawthorn&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2205.08174">
<title>Turbulent diffusion of streaming cosmic rays in compressible, partially ionised plasma. (arXiv:2205.08174v2 [astro-ph.GA] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2205.08174</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Cosmic rays (CRs) are a dynamically important component of the interstellar
medium (ISM) of galaxies. The $\sim$GeV CRs that carry most CR energy and
pressure are likely confined by self-generated turbulence, leading them to
stream along magnetic field lines at the ion Alfv\&apos;en speed. However, the
consequences of self-confinement for CR propagation on galaxy scales remain
highly uncertain. In this paper, we use a large ensemble of
magnetohydrodynamical turbulence simulations to quantify how the basic
parameters describing ISM turbulence -- the sonic Mach number, $\mathcal{M}$
(plasma compressibility), Alfv\&apos;en Mach number, $\mathcal{M}_{A0}$ (strength of
the large-scale field with respect to the turbulence), and ionisation fraction
by mass, $\chi$ -- affect the transport of streaming CRs. We show that the
large-scale transport of CRs whose small-scale motion consists of streaming
along field lines is well described as a combination of streaming along the
mean field and superdiffusion both along (parallel to) and across
(perpendicular to) it; $\mathcal{M}_{A0}$ drives the level of anisotropy
between parallel and perpendicular diffusion and $\chi$ modulates the magnitude
of the diffusion coefficients, while in our choice of units, $\mathcal{M}$ is
unimportant except in the sub-Alfv\&apos;enic ($\mathcal{M}_{A0} \lesssim 0.5$)
regime. Our finding that superdiffusion is ubiquitous potentially explains the
apparent discrepancy between CR diffusion coefficients inferred from
measurements close to individual sources compared to those measured on larger,
Galactic scales. Finally, we present empirical fits for the diffusion
coefficients as a function of plasma parameters that may be used as sub-grid
recipes for global interstellar medium, galaxy or cosmological simulations.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Sampson_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Matt L. Sampson&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Beattie_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;James R. Beattie&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Krumholz_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Mark R. Krumholz&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Crocker_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Roland M. Crocker&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Federrath_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Christoph Federrath&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Seta_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Amit Seta&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2208.07376">
<title>Galactic satellite systems in CDM, WDM and SIDM. (arXiv:2208.07376v3 [astro-ph.GA] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2208.07376</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We investigate the population of bright satellites ($M_{*} \geq 10^{5}
\mathrm{M}_{\odot}$) of haloes of mass comparable to that of the Milky Way in
cosmological simulations in which the dark matter (DM) is either cold, warm or
self-interacting (CDM, WDM and SIDM respectively). The nature of the DM gives
rise to differences in the abundance and structural properties of field halos.
In WDM, the main feature is a reduction in the total number of galaxies that
form, reflecting a suppression of low-mass DM haloes and lower galaxy formation
efficiency compared to CDM. For SIDM, the changes are structural, restricted to
the central regions of haloes and dependent on the assumed self-interaction
cross-section. We also consider different baryonic subgrid physics models for
galaxy formation, in which supernova gas blowouts can or cannot induce the
formation of a core in dwarf galaxies. Overall, the inclusion of baryons lessen
the differences in the halo properties in the different DM models compared to
DM-only simulations. This affects the satellite properties at infall and
therefore their subsequent tidal stripping and survival rates. Nonetheless, we
find slightly less concentrated satellite radial distributions as the SIDM
cross-section increases. Unfortunately, we also find that the satellite
populations in simulations with baryon-induced cores in CDM and WDM can mimic
the results found in SIDM, making the satellite stellar mass and maximum
circular velocity functions heavily degenerate on the assumed nature of the DM
and the adopted subgrid modelling. These degeneracies preclude using the
brightest satellites of the Milky Way to constrain the nature of DM.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Moreno_V/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Victor J. Forouhar Moreno&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Benitez_Llambay_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Alejandro Benitez-Llambay&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Cole_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Shaun Cole&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Frenk_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Carlos Frenk&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2209.04344">
<title>Empirical constraints on the turbulence in QSO host nebulae from velocity structure function measurements. (arXiv:2209.04344v2 [astro-ph.GA] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2209.04344</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We present the first empirical constraints on the turbulent velocity field of
the diffuse circumgalactic medium around four luminous QSOs at
$z\!\approx\!0.5$--1.1. Spatially extended nebulae of $\approx\!50$--100
physical kpc in diameter centered on the QSOs are revealed in
[OII]$\lambda\lambda\,3727,3729$ and/or [OIII]$\lambda\,5008$ emission lines in
integral field spectroscopic observations obtained using MUSE on the VLT. We
measure the second- and third-order velocity structure functions (VSFs) over a
range of scales, from $\lesssim\!5$ kpc to $\approx\!20$--50 kpc, to quantify
the turbulent energy transfer between different scales in these nebulae. While
no constraints on the energy injection and dissipation scales can be obtained
from the current data, we show that robust constraints on the power-law slope
of the VSFs can be determined after accounting for the effects of atmospheric
seeing, spatial smoothing, and large-scale bulk flows. Out of the four QSO
nebulae studied, one exhibits VSFs in spectacular agreement with the Kolmogorov
law, expected for isotropic, homogeneous, and incompressible turbulent flows.
The other three fields exhibit a shallower decline in the VSFs from large to
small scales. However, with a limited dynamic range in the spatial scales in
seeing-limited data, no constraints can be obtained for the VSF slopes of these
three nebulae. For the QSO nebula consistent with the Kolmogorov law, we
determine a turbulence energy cascade rate of $\approx\!0.2$ cm$^{2}$ s$^{-3}$.
We discuss the implication of the observed VSFs in the context of QSO feeding
and feedback in the circumgalactic medium.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Chen_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Mandy C. Chen&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Chen_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Hsiao-Wen Chen&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Rauch_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Michael Rauch&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Qu_Z/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Zhijie Qu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Johnson_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Sean D. Johnson&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Li_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jennifer I-Hsiu Li&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Schaye_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Joop Schaye&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Rudie_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Gwen C. Rudie&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Zahedy_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Fakhri S. Zahedy&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Boettcher_E/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Erin Boettcher&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Cooksey_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Kathy L. Cooksey&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Cantalupo_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Sebastiano Cantalupo&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.10038">
<title>On the genesis of spiral galaxies -- Classical and pseudo bulges as extremities of a continuous sequence. (arXiv:2210.10038v2 [astro-ph.GA] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.10038</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;A tantalizing enigma in extragalactic astronomy concerns the chronology and
driving mechanisms of the build-up of late-type galaxies (LTGs). The standard
scenario envisages two formation routes, with classical bulges (CBs) assembling
first in a quick quasi-monolithic episode followed by gradual disk assembly,
and pseudo-bulges (PBs) forming over the Gyr-long secular evolution of LTGs.
The expectation is, therefore, the segregation of present-day LTG bulges into
two distinct groups. Here we analyse the star formation histories (SFHs) of
bulges and disks for 135 LTGs from the CALIFA survey covering the relevant
range in LTG mass. In addition, their physical properties were contrasted with
predictions from evolutionary synthesis models, adopting exponentially
declining SFHs, with an e-folding time 0.1 &amp;lt; $\tau$ &amp;lt; 20 Gyr. Analysis of the
SFHs of ~ half-million spaxels consistently reveals that the main properties of
bulges and disks show a continuous distribution across total stellar mass.
Moreover, the $\tau$ in high-mass LTGs radially increases, suggesting that
these grow in an inside-out fashion, while lower-mass LTGs display roughly the
same $\tau$ throughout their entire radial extent. Evolutionary synthesis
predictions are consistent with observations. Finally, bulges and disks of
higher mass LTGs exhibit shorter formation timescales as compared to their
lower mass counterparts. Collectively, the obtained results evince a coherent
and unified picture for the formation and evolution of LTGs, in which PBs and
CBs denote extremities of a continuous sequence. This analysis is consistent
with the framework where bulges are assembled with their parent disks by
gradual inside-out growth, at a pace that is regulated by the depth of the
galactic potential. In accordance is the utter absence of bimodal correlations,
as expected if CBs and PBs were to emerge from two distinct formation routes.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Breda_I/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Iris Breda&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Papaderos_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Polychronis Papaderos&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
</rdf:RDF>