<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>American Enterprise Institute &#8211; AEI</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.aei.org/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.aei.org/</link>
	<description>The American Enterprise Institute, AEI, is a nonpartisan public policy research institute with a community of scholars and supporters committed to expanding liberty, increasing individual opportunity and strengthening free enterprise.</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2022 14:57:14 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.0.3</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Most College Students Do See a Value in Voting</title>
		<link>https://www.aei.org/politics-and-public-opinion/most-college-students-do-see-a-value-in-voting/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[George Pierson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2022 14:23:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Elections]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Politics and Public Opinion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Polls]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[college]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Generation Z]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Midterm elections]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[voting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Young voters]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.aei.org/?p=1008664774</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Gen Z Americans believe voting can make a difference, but a strong turnout is not assured. Nor should a strong showing by Gen Z students be assumed to be a win for the Democrats.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.aei.org/politics-and-public-opinion/most-college-students-do-see-a-value-in-voting/">Most College Students Do See a Value in Voting</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.aei.org">American Enterprise Institute - AEI</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Despite widespread politicization of life on collegiate campuses today, along with <a href="https://www.acenet.edu/News-Room/Pages/2022-Political-Campaigns-Issue-Brief.aspx" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">increased voter turnout</a> and <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/women-college-are-moving-left-men-are-migrating-right-opinion-1742192" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">political activity</a> among college students in recent years, questions about their turnout next week remain. New survey data reveal that for all the difficulties faced by students to vote, from registering away from home to traveling to the polls on Election Day, the majority of college and university students do see the value of voting today even though <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2020/10/08/upshot/youth-voting-2020-election.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">most young people in the United States do not vote</a>. So, what might this mean for the upcoming elections?</p>



<p><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2022/10/31/us/politics/democrats-republicans-senate-election-polls.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Recent polling shows</a> that there is a strong possibility of a national rejection of the Democratic Party. But will Gen Z be part of the narrative, finally be regarded as a real electoral cohort, and play a pivotal role in a host of tight races that will shape the direction of Congress?</p>



<p>We will only know the answers on Election Day itself. However, we do have strong indicators that Gen Z college and university students have not become apathetic or turned off from politics. College Pulse&#8217;s Future of Politics survey held interviews with over 1,500 undergraduate students at 91 different colleges and universities at the end of summer break. <a href="https://www.usnews.com/news/elections/articles/2022-10-27/motivated-youth-in-play-at-the-polls" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Vote intention questions</a> are very dubious and unreliable, but the survey does shed some light on the question of turnout. The survey asks if respondents “think that voting lets people like you make a difference in how government works, or do you think that voting doesn&#8217;t really make a difference?” The data leans to the positive side: Almost six in 10 (59 percent) college and university students today do believe that voting does indeed make a difference, while just over a quarter (29 percent) feel that voting has no real impact.</p>



<p>In addition, partisan students are more likely to think that voting matters compared to Independents. Almost three-quarters of Democratic students (73 percent) and two-thirds of Republican students (67 percent) currently believe that voting can have an impact. Eight in 10 strong Democrats currently think that voting matters, and this is only 8 points higher than their strong Republican counterparts.</p>



<p>There is no elite effect here either. While elite colleges and universities tend to fare worse on issues like viewpoint diversity and free speech, the data show that students at higher-ranked schools do not have higher levels of electoral efficacy compared to lower-ranked schools. Sixty-two percent of students in the top 25 colleges and universities, and 61 percent of students in schools ranked over 101, believe that voting makes a difference in shaping policy. Sixty-four percent of students in regional schools feel the same way. This suggests that those who engage in higher education recognize the power and value of casting a ballot.</p>



<p>There are some demographic cleavages worth noting. Students of working-class backgrounds have lower efficacy rates, with 55 percent of students here believing that their vote has power compared to 63 percent of those from upper-middle-class backgrounds. Although not a huge difference, clearly historical legacy issues persist with respect to ideas about the power of voting and whose voice matters; higher education may help correct these misconceptions.</p>



<p>As for race and gender, there have long been questions about the value of voting among minority communities, and differences in terms of gender are practically non-existent as we head into next week. Fifty-nine percent of both men and women believe that voting does make a difference. With respect to race, 61 percent of White students, 62 percent of Hispanic, and 60 percent of Asian students all state that voting makes a difference. Yet, just 49 percent of Black students in our nation’s colleges and universities believe that this is true, and this could be partly a result of historical cases of voter intimidation and suppression and lack of trust and skepticism in the government.</p>



<p>In short, there is strong support for the value of voting in 2022, but a strong turnout is not assured. Nor should a strong showing by Gen Z students be assumed to be a win for the Democrats. <a href="https://5666503.fs1.hubspotusercontent-na1.net/hubfs/5666503/CFSR_2022_Report.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">FIRE’s 2022 survey</a> of almost 45,000 currently enrolled students at over 200 schools reveals students are not monolithically Democratic whatsoever. About a third of students (34 percent) are Democrats and 12 percent are Republicans. Most students happen to be Independents or leaners (54 percent). This large middle is unanchored, leaning to the right for many candidates and races. College students could make a difference and we know they are not turned off. Keep an eye on this group next week.</p>



<p><em>Samuel J. Abrams is a professor of politics at Sarah Lawrence College and a senior fellow at the American Enterprise Institute.</em></p>



<div class="related-items shortcode "><p><strong>Learn more: </strong><a href="https://www.aei.org/politics-and-public-opinion/why-are-liberal-arts-college-faculty-building-better-relationships-with-their-students/">Why Are Liberal Arts College Faculty Building Better Relationships with Their Students?</a> | <a href="https://www.aei.org/society-and-culture/the-positive-side-of-social-media/">The Positive Side of Social Media</a> | <a href="https://www.aei.org/op-eds/finding-third-places-across-america/">Finding third places across America</a> | <a href="https://www.aei.org/articles/cancel-culture-is-not-just-in-colleges-and-universities/">Cancel Culture Is Not Just in Colleges and Universities</a></p></div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.aei.org/politics-and-public-opinion/most-college-students-do-see-a-value-in-voting/">Most College Students Do See a Value in Voting</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.aei.org">American Enterprise Institute - AEI</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bibi Netanyahu Hinted He Might Arm Ukraine. Probably Not.</title>
		<link>https://www.aei.org/foreign-and-defense-policy/bibi-netanyahu-hinted-he-might-arm-ukraine-probably-not/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[George Pierson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2022 14:16:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Foreign and Defense Policy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Benjamin Netanyahu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[israel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Russia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Russia-Ukraine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ukraine]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.aei.org/?p=1008664764</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Israel’s failure to stand with another democracy under attack—a problem with which Jerusalem should empathize—casts an unpleasant light on its government.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.aei.org/foreign-and-defense-policy/bibi-netanyahu-hinted-he-might-arm-ukraine-probably-not/">Bibi Netanyahu Hinted He Might Arm Ukraine. Probably Not.</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.aei.org">American Enterprise Institute - AEI</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>“I remind you that in the election campaign Netanyahu said that he would consider revising Israel’s policy on the supply of weapons to Ukraine . . . how actively this will continue with the Netanyahu government, if he manages to form it, we will see.” Thus <a href="https://en.interfax.com.ua/news/general/869843.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">spoke</a> Ukrainian Ambassador to Israel Yevhen Korniychuk on Thursday following Benjamin Netanyahu’s <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2022/11/03/world/middleeast/israel-netanyahu-election.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">victory</a> in the Israeli elections.</p>



<p>Korniychuk is right—Netanyahu, just before capturing office, had <a href="https://www.usatoday.com/story/news/politics/2022/10/21/netanyahu-would-evaluate-helping-ukraine-if-elected-prime-minister/10560607002/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">hinted</a> that Israel may provide increased support to Ukraine should he be elected, saying that he would “look into” supplying military support if he regained office. With his premiership now secured, however, Korniychuk’s doubts seem well placed. In his previous incarnations as prime minister, Netanyahu prided himself on a congenial working relationship with Russia, <a href="https://www.google.com/url?sa=t&amp;rct=j&amp;q=&amp;esrc=s&amp;source=web&amp;cd=&amp;cad=rja&amp;uact=8&amp;ved=2ahUKEwjlzP63zJL7AhVnFlkFHWJ2B-gQFnoECBkQAQ&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.axios.com%2F2022%2F10%2F25%2Fukraine-russia-israel-netanyahu-putin-lapid-kuleba&amp;usg=AOvVaw0AXDa02Id_ui4jhXW5WIar" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">labeling</a> the Russian dictator “smart, sophisticated and focused on one goal—returning Russia to its historical greatness” in his recent book.</p>



<p>In June, Netanyahu <a href="https://www.timesofisrael.com/netanyahu-blames-pm-for-russia-crisis-lapid-you-havent-bothered-to-get-updates/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">criticized</a> then Prime Minister Yair Lapid and Defense Minister Benny Gantz for departing from the “measured, balanced and responsible relationship” Israel enjoyed with Russia before the war, and cautioned, “We can and need to get out of this crisis. I’m worried that what we built over years is being undermined before our eyes in recent weeks.”</p>



<p>Bibi’s cautions are not entirely political. Neither the previous government nor the new one can afford to write off Vladimir Putin. One the one hand, Israeli officials have clearly <a href="https://twitter.com/IsraeliPM/status/1583160629531414528" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">stated</a> that they stand with Ukraine. But, but, but. Their concern is two-fold: First, Russia controls Syrian air space, where Israel has <a href="https://www.haaretz.com/israel-news/2022-09-02/ty-article/.premium/as-israeli-attributed-strikes-rattle-syria-russia-and-the-u-s-are-losing-interest/00000182-fa70-d94b-afbf-fa77b35d0000" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">ongoing operations</a> against Iranian targets helping arm Hezbollah. Second, and perhaps less credible, Tehran’s recent support for Moscow has raised <a href="https://www.barrons.com/news/israel-pm-deeply-concerned-over-russia-iran-military-ties-01666293907" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">concerns</a> that eventually Israeli-supplied weapons could end up in Iran. &nbsp;</p>



<p>But Israel is failing to account for the costs of ignoring Ukraine’s pleas for support. Ever conscious of the risk of antagonizing Putin, Jerusalem has ignored the costs of shunning Ukraine. Indeed, Ukrainian President Voldomyr Zelensky recently <a href="https://www.axios.com/2022/10/24/zelensky-israel-iran-russia-nuclear-program-drones" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">laid into</a> the Jewish state—Zelensky himself is Jewish—asking what Israeli leaders thought Iran would get from Russia in exchange for sharing weapons with Moscow. “How does Russia pay Iran for this, in your opinion?” he asked. “Is Iran just interested in money? Probably not money at all, but Russian assistance to the Iranian nuclear program. Probably, this is exactly the meaning of their alliance.&#8221;</p>



<p>Israel’s failure to stand with another democracy under attack—a problem with which Jerusalem should empathize—casts an unpleasant light on its government. And as Russia <a href="https://www.google.com/url?sa=t&amp;rct=j&amp;q=&amp;esrc=s&amp;source=web&amp;cd=&amp;cad=rja&amp;uact=8&amp;ved=2ahUKEwjwybP_y5L7AhUFF1kFHQkbBkoQFnoECA8QAw&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.i24news.tv%2Fen%2Fnews%2Finternational%2F1666248144-report-russia-shrinks-forces-in-syria-to-bolster-ukraine-war&amp;usg=AOvVaw1HB_J8CIJC5BmuR4bcf6Y0" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">shifts</a> troops out of Syria to help fight its losing war in Ukraine, Israeli excuses for rejecting Kyiv’s pleas seem increasingly hollow.</p>



<div class="related-items shortcode "><p><strong>Learn more: </strong><a href="https://www.aei.org/foreign-and-defense-policy/the-abraham-accords-arent-perfect-but-abbas-cant-afford-to-pass-them-up/">Abbas Can’t Afford to Ignore the Abraham Accords</a> | <a href="https://www.aei.org/op-eds/middle-east-defense-agreements-need-clear-objectives/">Middle East Defense Agreements Need Clear Objectives</a></p></div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.aei.org/foreign-and-defense-policy/bibi-netanyahu-hinted-he-might-arm-ukraine-probably-not/">Bibi Netanyahu Hinted He Might Arm Ukraine. Probably Not.</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.aei.org">American Enterprise Institute - AEI</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Night of the Living Pandemic Tech Patent Waiver</title>
		<link>https://www.aei.org/technology-and-innovation/night-of-the-living-pandemic-tech-patent-waiver/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Matthew Glavish]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2022 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Intellectual Property]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology and Innovation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Biden administration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Coronavirus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[developing countries]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Innovation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Intellectual property]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[patents]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[White House]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[World Trade Organization]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.aei.org/?p=1008664698</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Despite reaching a consensus on intellectual property rights for COVID-19 vaccines in June 2022, the debate at the World Trade Organization regarding IP rights for COVID-19 diagnostics and treatments won’t be so easily put to rest.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.aei.org/technology-and-innovation/night-of-the-living-pandemic-tech-patent-waiver/">Night of the Living Pandemic Tech Patent Waiver</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.aei.org">American Enterprise Institute - AEI</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Like a classic Halloween horror movie villain, the debate over intellectual property (IP) protections related to COVID-19 simply refuses to die.</p>



<p>Just when we thought we’d seen the last of this issue over the summer, the dispute roared back to life last month at another World Trade Organization (WTO) meeting. In June 2022, the WTO at long last reached an agreement on waiving trade-related aspects of intellectual property rights (TRIPS) for COVID-19 vaccines—but not for all COVID-19-related technology.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img width="5076" height="3396" src="https://www.aei.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/World-Trade-Organization-Generic-Photo.jpg?x91208" alt="" class="wp-image-1008664699"/><figcaption>via Reuters</figcaption></figure>



<p>Recall that India and South Africa <a href="https://www.aei.org/technology-and-innovation/covid-19-vaccine-patent-waiver-debate-intensifies-ahead-of-key-wto-meeting/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">petitioned</a> the organization in late 2020 to override patent rights associated with COVID-19 diagnostics, treatments, and vaccines, which at the time had not yet even been administered. While the Trump administration and its European allies initially opposed the request, President Joe Biden’s trade representative <a href="https://ustr.gov/about-us/policy-offices/press-office/press-releases/2021/may/statement-ambassador-katherine-tai-covid-19-trips-waiver" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">reversed course</a> in May 2021 to great fanfare.</p>



<p>However, as predicted, by the time the WTO <a href="https://www.aei.org/technology-and-innovation/the-covid-19-patent-waiver-compromise-finally-breaks-through-and-nobodys-happy/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">finally acted</a> on the petition in June 2022, the pandemic had ebbed, and billions of vaccine doses had been administered around the world—at extremely low cost to the developing world. According to the <a href="https://docs.wto.org/dol2fe/Pages/SS/directdoc.aspx?filename=q:/WT/MIN22/30.pdf&amp;Open=True" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">agreement</a>, painstakingly negotiated to achieve consensus among WTO member states:</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>Notwithstanding the provision of patent rights under its domestic legislation, an eligible Member may limit the rights provided for under Article 28.1 of the TRIPS Agreement . . . by authorizing the use of the subject matter of a patent required for the production and supply of COVID-19 vaccines without the consent of the right holder to the extent necessary to address the COVID-19 pandemic.</p></blockquote>



<p>The WTO decision, <a href="https://www.aei.org/events/where-does-the-debate-over-intellectual-property-protections-for-covid-19-vaccines-stand-one-year-later/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">which</a> <a href="https://www.aei.org/technology-and-innovation/the-covid-19-patent-waiver-compromise-finally-breaks-through-and-nobodys-happy/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">displeased</a> waiver advocates and opponents alike, covered only vaccines, not treatments or diagnostics, but vowed to consider the latter issue within six months.</p>



<p>And sure enough, last month, the WTO revived the discussions, where, according to the <a href="https://www.wto.org/english/news_e/news22_e/trip_13oct22_e.htm" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">official readout</a>, “members who support an extension of the Decision to cover COVID-19 diagnostics and therapeutics favoured a blanket approach of the extension to therapeutics and diagnostics and stressed that the current COVID-19 IP waiver decision should be adopted ‘as is.’” Those countries “emphasized that the pandemic is far from over and noted that equitable access to therapeutics and diagnostics is critical in helping detect new COVID-19 cases and variants,” noting that “this extension is more urgent than ever, as many least developed countries (LDCs) lack access to life-saving drugs and testing therapeutics.”</p>



<p>For their part, “a group of developing and developed members expressed their readiness to advance the discussions but insisted on seeing evidence of where and how intellectual property (IP) constitutes a barrier to access to therapeutics and diagnostics before considering an extension,” along the way “reiterat[ing] the need for members to fully make use of all the flexibilities that already exist in the TRIPS Agreement (including compulsory licensing) before requesting new flexibilities.”</p>



<p>Indeed, the latest request by India, South Africa, and its allies in the WTO caucus realizes a key concern expressed during the original debate—that the initial TRIPS waiver would trigger a further deterioration of IP rights. Once the door was cracked ajar, various public health advocates would ram it open fully. To change metaphors, by acceding to the petition in June 2022, the WTO fanned the flames of anti-IP sentiment, flames that may soon threaten to consume the entire structure of international patent rights.</p>



<p>“IP has never been a barrier,” says Komal Kalha, the associate director of IP and trade policy at the Geneva-based International Federation of Pharmaceutical Manufacturers &amp; Associations and a <a href="https://www.aei.org/events/where-does-the-debate-over-intellectual-property-protections-for-covid-19-vaccines-stand-one-year-later/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">panelist</a> at the AEI forum on this issue in June, <a href="https://cen.acs.org/policy/intellectual-property/Debate-over-COVID-19-product/100/i37" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">telling</a> <em>Chemical &amp; Engineering News</em>, “You take that away, what you’re doing is you are fracturing a system that delivers in real time but also for the future.”</p>



<p>This concern seems especially salient in the area of COVID-19 diagnostics and treatments, which can be used in a variety of non-COVID-19 situations. In other words, the patents underlying COVID-19 treatments and diagnostics are the result of substantial research and development investment and underpin commercially valuable products whose use cases include illnesses entirely unrelated to COVID-19. Unlocking IP protection for these innovations would severely dampen incentives for the development of future such breakthroughs.</p>



<p>In the meantime, the WTO debate will continue, and if the difficulty in reaching a consensus on the original petition is any indication, the diagnostics and treatments issue will take months to resolve. Here’s hoping that this time, it’s put to rest.</p>


<div class="related-items shortcode "><p><strong>See also:  </strong><a href="https://www.aei.org/technology-and-innovation/where-the-debate-over-intellectual-property-protections-for-covid-19-vaccines-stands-one-year-later-highlights-from-an-expert-panel-discussion/">Where the Debate over Intellectual Property Protections for COVID-19 Vaccines Stands One Year Later: Highlights from an Expert Panel Discussion</a> | <a href="https://www.aei.org/technology-and-innovation/the-covid-19-patent-waiver-compromise-finally-breaks-through-and-nobodys-happy/">The COVID-19 Patent Waiver Compromise Finally Breaks Through (And Nobody’s Happy)</a> | <a href="https://www.aei.org/technology-and-innovation/covid-19-vaccine-patent-waiver-debate-intensifies-ahead-of-key-wto-meeting/">COVID-19 Vaccine Patent Waiver Debate Intensifies Ahead of Key WTO Meeting</a> | <a href="https://www.aei.org/events/where-does-the-debate-over-intellectual-property-protections-for-covid-19-vaccines-stand-one-year-later/">Where Does the Debate over Intellectual Property Protections for COVID-19 Vaccines Stand One Year Later?</a></p></div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.aei.org/technology-and-innovation/night-of-the-living-pandemic-tech-patent-waiver/">Night of the Living Pandemic Tech Patent Waiver</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.aei.org">American Enterprise Institute - AEI</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Do the FBI’s Crime Statistics Add Up?</title>
		<link>https://www.aei.org/society-and-culture/do-the-fbis-crime-statistics-add-up/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[George Pierson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 20:10:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Society and Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Crime]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Department of Justice (DOJ)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[FBI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Midterm elections]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.aei.org/?p=1008664739</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Not-ready-for-prime-time national crime stats, of obviously dubious quality, released a month before a national election, will do little to enhance policing in our country.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.aei.org/society-and-culture/do-the-fbis-crime-statistics-add-up/">Do the FBI’s Crime Statistics Add Up?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.aei.org">American Enterprise Institute - AEI</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Believe it or not, someone on the internet is now claiming that violent crime in America <em>fell</em> last year. Unfortunately, that “someone” happens to be the FBI—brandishing a new crime-count methodology, and telling the public, in effect, to ignore the evidence of its own senses.</p>



<p>As more or less everyone in the United States today knows, crime is a hot button issue this election cycle—and for a reason. Next week a “red wave” stands to punish Democratic candidates across the country, not least because so many voters blame the Democrats for a nationwide decline in public safety since Team Blue took the White House and the Congress in 2020.</p>



<p>Yet you would have no inkling of this—neither the problem itself, nor the public’s anxiety, much less the coming electoral backlash—from perusing Washington’s new official numbers on national crime trends. These data were released last month by the FBI and the Bureau of Justice Statistics (BJS) under their new “<a href="https://www.justice.gov/opa/blog/new-and-better-crime-data-nation" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">National Incident Based Reporting System</a>” (NIBRS), which formally displaced their previous “Summary Reporting System” (SRS) at the beginning of 2021. According to these numbers, America did not suffer a crime wave in 2021. Quite the contrary: the FBI maintains that violent crime actually <em>fell</em> last year.</p>



<p>True: the FBI’s NIBRS does acknowledge that murders rose in 2021—some 4 percent above 2020 levels, it says. Nevertheless, according to the purportedly improved methodology about which Justice Department officials boast, the US enjoyed a 1 percent overall decline in violent crime between 2020 and 2021.</p>



<p>How did the Feds manage to get their crime assessment for America—even the direction of the arrow—so laugh-out-loud wrong? A closer look reveals some of the awkward details.</p>



<p>Transition to exclusive NIBRS collection as of January 1, 2021 was <a href="https://ucr.fbi.gov/nibrs/2015" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">announced</a> in 2015. But unsurprisingly, more detailed data collection is time consuming and expensive. Many jurisdictions have thus far declined to join in the NIBRS. Consequently, despite <a href="https://www.axios.com/2022/06/14/fbi-crime-data-2021-police-reporting-failures#:~:text=Worth%20noting%3A%20Law%20enforcement%20agencies%20nationwide%20have%20received%20over%20%24160%20million%20in%20federal%20funding%20to%20help%20with%20the%20transition%20since%20the%20switch%20to%20NIBRS%20was%20announced%20in%202015." target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">significant funding</a> of transition efforts and FBI <a href="https://www.fbi.gov/news/stories/five-things-to-know-about-nibrs-112520#:~:text=In%202021%2C%20the%20FBI%20expects%2075%25%20of%20law%20enforcement%20agencies%20to%20have%20moved%20to%20NIBRS.%20Those%20departments%20serve%20more%20than%2080%25%20of%20the%20U.S.%20population." target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">expectations</a> of 80+ percent population coverage for the 2021 NIBRS data, as late as June 2022, <a href="https://bjs.ojp.gov/national-incident-based-reporting-system-nibrs#:~:text=66%25%20of%20the%20U.S.%20population%20is%20covered%20by%20NIBRS%2Dreporting%20law%20enforcement%20agencies" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">only 66 percent</a> of the population was covered.</p>



<p>For 2021, almost half of the country’s 18,000 law enforcement agencies <a href="https://edition.cnn.com/2022/10/05/us/fbi-national-crime-report-2021-data" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">reportedly failed</a> to provide data for the entire calendar year. But the Feds, who seemed to feel duty bound to use an instrument that was clearly incapable of offering a comprehensive picture of national crime for that year, stubbornly went ahead and used it anyway.</p>



<p>To do so they had to fill in big gaps: including almost all of California and New York State. They had to “approximate” missing data with so-called “<a href="https://www.fbi.gov/news/stories/five-things-to-know-about-nibrs-112520#:~:text=advanced%20methodologies%20to%20estimate%20national%20crime%20statistics%20when%20a%20particular%20state%20or%20locality%20doesn%E2%80%99t%20provide%20data" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">advanced methodologies</a>”: in a manner that was not only opaque, but at times bizarre.</p>



<p>Somehow, for example, NIBRS came up with <a href="https://crime-data-explorer.app.cloud.gov/pages/explorer/crime/nibrs-estimation" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">violent crime estimates</a> for New York State that implied 2021 levels were less than a third of what the SRS <a href="https://crime-data-explorer.app.cloud.gov/pages/downloads#additionalDownloads" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">reported for 2020</a> (and barely a quarter of <a href="https://www.criminaljustice.ny.gov/crimnet/ojsa/stats.htm" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">NY State’s own numbers</a> for 2021).</p>



<p>Really? If the NIBRS’ New York 2021 “advanced methodology” crime numbers were correct, Governor Kathy Hochul would not be fighting for her political life at this writing.</p>



<p>We cannot tell from NIBRS what the true crime trend has been in America since the Biden administration came to office. But we can get some sense of how far off their numbers may be by comparing state-level figures for the old SRS in 2020 and the new NIBRS in 2021. [SEE FIGURE 1]</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img loading="lazy" width="1191" height="746" src="https://www.aei.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Eberstadt-11-3-chart.jpg?x91208" alt="" class="wp-image-1008664783"/></figure>



<p>Holding other states’ NIBRS levels constant, if New York’s violent crime were at the level estimated by the state, that alone would indicate a national <strong><u>3 percent increase</u></strong> over the FBI’s NIBRS 2020 estimates of violent crime and a <strong><u>4 percent increase</u></strong> over the 2020 SRS estimates. If Illinois numbers (derived from the NIBRS estimates for the Midwest and its component states) were in line with the past five years of SRS data, that would add another percentage point to the 2021 violent crime growth rate versus the national SRS 2020 numbers.</p>



<p>Other soundings likewise point to a 2021 NIBRS underestimate of violent crime in America.</p>



<p>A few weeks ago, a CDC team, relying upon National Vital Statistics System mortality data, <a href="https://www.cdc.gov/mmwr/volumes/71/wr/mm7140a4.htm" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">estimated</a> that US 2021 firearm homicides were over 8 percent higher in 2021 than in 2020—a magnitude that cannot be reconciled with NIBRS’ estimate of a 4 percent increase in murders by all weapons. And an inconvenient <a href="https://bjs.ojp.gov/sites/g/files/xyckuh236/files/media/document/ncvsnibrscpc21.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">BJS study</a>, also released last month, shows that the National Crime Victimization Survey registered an <em>increase</em> in the rate of violent crime of almost 5 percent in 2021.</p>



<p>National crime stats of obviously dubious quality, released a month before a national election, will do little to enhance policing in our country. Nor are they likely to raise public confidence in an FBI whose reputation for political impartiality has come increasingly into question recently.</p>



<div class="related-items shortcode "><p><strong>Learn more: </strong><a href="https://www.aei.org/articles/a-nation-of-quitters/">A Nation of Quitters</a> | <a href="https://www.aei.org/articles/americas-education-crisis-as-a-national-security-threat/">America’s Education Crisis as a National Security Threat</a> | <a href="https://www.aei.org/articles/americas-education-crisis-is-a-national-security-threat/">America’s Education Crisis Is a National Security Threat</a> | <a href="https://www.aei.org/op-eds/whats-behind-the-flight-from-work-in-post-pandemic-america/">What’s Behind the Flight from Work in Post-Pandemic America</a></p></div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.aei.org/society-and-culture/do-the-fbis-crime-statistics-add-up/">Do the FBI’s Crime Statistics Add Up?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.aei.org">American Enterprise Institute - AEI</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>New Research Shows the Importance of Family Environment on Upward Mobility</title>
		<link>https://www.aei.org/poverty-studies/new-research-shows-the-importance-of-family-environment-on-upward-mobility/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[George Pierson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 19:47:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Poverty Studies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[child poverty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[low-income]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Poverty]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.aei.org/?p=1008664708</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>In the midst of a robust debate on child poverty, policymakers should focus on improving the family environment instead of expensive income transfer programs that likely have limited effects on long-term upward mobility.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.aei.org/poverty-studies/new-research-shows-the-importance-of-family-environment-on-upward-mobility/">New Research Shows the Importance of Family Environment on Upward Mobility</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.aei.org">American Enterprise Institute - AEI</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Over the past several years, there has been a robust debate over the best way to reduce child poverty in the US. One <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/opinions/2022/01/29/giving-up-expanding-child-tax-credit-would-be-disaster-poor-people/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">point of view</a> believes that poverty is fundamentally a problem of limited income; therefore, the <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/us-policy/2022/02/17/child-tax-credit-poverty/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">best way</a> to reduce poverty is to redistribute income through government programs. The other point of view suggests that, while limited income is certainly a defining feature, poverty is the product of other problems, such as inadequate education, family structure, and detachment from the labor force.</p>



<p>The first view—that poverty merely reflects limited income—was the argument behind the <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/build-back-better/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">plan</a> from President Joe Biden and congressional Democrats to expand the child tax credit, first as temporary pandemic relief in 2021 (which they successfully passed) and then permanently (which they did not pass). Under the Democrats’ plan, most families no matter their income tax liability would have received up to $300 per month for each child in the household under 18—meaning that a nonworking family with two young children would have received $7,200 from the federal government each year.</p>



<p>As policies go, the idea of sending poor families money from the federal government is relatively simple. And at least on paper, it would reduce poverty rates in the short term. But because this approach assumes poverty is solely a shortage of income, it also absolves policymakers of the responsibility to create policies that allow American households to thrive. If they can “solve” poverty by redistributing just enough money to push those at the bottom above the poverty line, then policymakers can focus less on the problems that cause poverty in the first place.</p>



<p>An alternative view believes that families have a better chance to escape poverty over the long term when government policies address the underlying factors linked to poverty. In this view, the focus is not only on the short term—fewer people below the poverty line today—but also on the long term—more families and children equipped with the skills and resources necessary to flourish.</p>



<p>A new NBER <a href="https://www.nber.org/papers/w30610" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">working paper</a> by Jorge Luis García and James Heckman expands on this point of view and offers policymakers who are interested in supporting upward mobility a useful framework. Relying on their research of the Perry Preschool and <a href="https://abc.fpg.unc.edu/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">The Carolina Abecedarian Project</a>, they showed that the quality of the family environment (specifically, parent-child interactions) during childhood was among the most important drivers of long-term positive outcomes for children, including higher incomes, more marriage, and increased stability over the life cycle.</p>



<p>While this contribution is important on its own, they also offered skepticism of policies that focus on income alone. They wrote:</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>Income has many competing uses. Enhancing it likely has smaller impacts on child development than equally expensive interventions that target specific aspects of child development (Del Boca et al., 2014).</p></blockquote>



<p>Moreover, they criticized the current policymaking approach, which they described as promoting “off the shelf” programs at the expense of understanding the precise mechanisms that lead to success.</p>



<p>Because their research found that improved family environment was crucial to explaining the long-term success of the Perry Preschool and Abecedarian Project, they appeared unconvinced that preschool programs (without a focus on parent-child interactions) would achieve desired results. Instead, they argued that policies should help to create enriching home environments for disadvantaged children:</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>The traditional literature focuses on credentials of program staff and curricula and overlooks the role of the family in bolstering child development. Previous research links the impacts of Perry and ABC on skills to its impacts on long-term outcomes (e.g., education, labor income, and crime; Heckman et al., 2013). Our evidence on the impact of these programs on parenting and parental investment gives a better understanding of the mechanisms underlying program success. It provides evidence of the connection between home environments and skill formation.</p></blockquote>



<p>García and Heckman further showed that programs that similarly enhanced the parent-child relationship had equally impressive outcomes at much less cost. Aspects of these programs involved trained professionals teaching parents about child development and showing them positive ways to interact with their child. García and Heckman argued that focusing on the home environment could substantially improve upward mobility for low-income children—something that few <a href="https://www.nber.org/system/files/working_papers/w30373/w30373.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">government programs</a> and policies have been able to show. For example, García, Heckman, and Ronda (2021) <a href="https://www.nber.org/system/files/working_papers/w29057/w29057.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">found</a> that Perry Preschool participants earned almost $10,000 more <em>per year</em> as adults than control group members, substantially more than the long-term gains from <a href="https://www.nber.org/system/files/working_papers/w30373/w30373.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">receiving the EITC</a> as a child.</p>



<p>The insights from García and Heckman offer a framework that should be useful to policymakers. Instead of expensive income transfer programs that likely have limited effects on long-term upward mobility, policymakers should focus on improving the family environment.</p>



<div class="related-items shortcode "><p><strong>Learn more: </strong><a href="https://www.aei.org/poverty-studies/brett-favre-welfare-fraud-and-the-tanf-block-grant/">Brett Favre, Welfare Fraud, and the TANF Block Grant</a> | <a href="https://www.aei.org/poverty-studies/conservative-policies-have-driven-child-poverty-declines/">Conservative Policies Have Driven Child Poverty Declines</a> | <a href="https://www.aei.org/op-eds/will-the-white-house-take-the-diet-crisis-seriously/">Will the White House Take the Diet Crisis Seriously?</a> | <a href="https://www.aei.org/poverty-studies/does-more-federal-assistance-lead-to-less-food-insecurity/">Does More Federal Assistance Lead to Less Food Insecurity?</a></p></div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.aei.org/poverty-studies/new-research-shows-the-importance-of-family-environment-on-upward-mobility/">New Research Shows the Importance of Family Environment on Upward Mobility</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.aei.org">American Enterprise Institute - AEI</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Lead Like Mitch: Lessons on Leadership in Higher Education from Mitch Daniels</title>
		<link>https://www.aei.org/education/lead-like-mitch-lessons-on-leadership-in-higher-education-from-mitch-daniels/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[George Pierson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 18:07:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Higher Education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[college]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Higher education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Higher Education Reform]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.aei.org/?p=1008664731</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>We should aim to honor Mitch Daniels' contributions to higher education by employing the leadership practices he exemplified to help our broader system of higher education work to better serve students of this nation.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.aei.org/education/lead-like-mitch-lessons-on-leadership-in-higher-education-from-mitch-daniels/">Lead Like Mitch: Lessons on Leadership in Higher Education from Mitch Daniels</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.aei.org">American Enterprise Institute - AEI</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Last week I had the honor and pleasure of speaking with Mitch Daniels, former governor of Indiana and outgoing president of Purdue University. We <a href="https://www.c-span.org/video/?523833-1/purdue-university-president-mitch-daniels-higher-education" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">invited President Daniels to AEI</a> to celebrate his <a href="https://www.aei.org/education/the-end-of-an-era-mitch-daniels-to-step-down-from-purdue-presidency/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">impressive tenure</a> at the helm of Purdue, but also to learn from his successes—ranging from the 10-year freeze on tuition to becoming a leading institution in the movement to protect free speech on college campuses. In speaking with President Daniels, I observed three characteristics of his leadership that I believe contributed to his success and could serve other leaders well in efforts to better higher education across the United States.</p>



<p><strong>Measure outcomes and hold your institution accountable</strong>. Accountability is central to Daniels’ leadership style. When first Governor of Indiana, one of his top priorities was fixing the Department of Motor Vehicles—a piece of state government that touched almost every citizen.</p>



<p>In doing so, he timed the duration of every transaction and printed it on the customer’s receipt. The point was to make it impossible for employees and managers to hide from the truth, good or bad, about the quality of the service they were providing. He applied the same principles in his leadership at Purdue, demanding maintenance of quality while he simultaneously grew Purdue’s student body, faculty, and presence in the community. In one of the initiatives he led, the <a href="https://www.purdue.edu/backaboiler/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Back-a-Boiler</a> program, Daniels created a similar or even harsher mechanism of accountability for the institution. The program was complex, but in essence its creation meant that Purdue only got paid when the students succeeded.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Embrace innovation and change</strong>. Throughout his political career, Daniels embraced the role of change maker and he brought that mindset with him to Purdue. In a sector often characterized by stagnation, he brought innovation to campus and challenged well-worn beliefs about how the institution should operate.</p>



<p>The changes he brought to campus weren’t changes for the sake of change. They were often simple ideas that made a profound difference in the lives of students they touched. For example, President Daniels managed to keep Purdue’s tuition flat for a full 10 years, when prior price hikes had been levied every academic year for over three decades before his arrival on campus. Challenging the status quo and embracing necessary change made Daniels’ tenure at Purdue exceptional and would likely go a long way in improving outcomes at institutions across the nation.</p>



<p><strong>“Boots on the ground” leadership</strong>. Throughout his career, Daniels connected with the “product”: He has never been the type of leader who hides in his office or behind staff. And in the case of higher education, that meant getting to know and understand students. Daniels met and interacted with thousands of students during his time at Purdue and many of the initiatives he implemented during his presidency were inspired by what he learned in doing so.</p>



<p>Daniels made a mark on Purdue, but also on the broader realm of higher education. When he leaves office at the end of this year, the industry will lose an incredible leader. We should aim to honor his contributions to higher education by employing the leadership practices he exemplified to help our broader system of higher education work to better serve students of this nation.</p>



<div class="related-items shortcode "><p><strong>Learn more: </strong><a href="https://www.aei.org/education/student-loan-cancellation-update/">Student Loan Cancellation Update</a> | <a href="https://www.aei.org/education/the-hidden-landmine-in-bidens-student-loan-announcement/">The Hidden Landmine in Biden’s Student Loan Announcement</a> | <a href="https://www.aei.org/education/3-things-to-know-about-the-september-jobs-report/">3 Things to Know About the September Jobs Report</a> | <a href="https://www.aei.org/education/white-house-rescinds-student-loan-forgiveness-for-as-many-as-four-million-borrowers/">White House Rescinds Student Loan Forgiveness for as Many as Four Million Borrowers</a></p></div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.aei.org/education/lead-like-mitch-lessons-on-leadership-in-higher-education-from-mitch-daniels/">Lead Like Mitch: Lessons on Leadership in Higher Education from Mitch Daniels</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.aei.org">American Enterprise Institute - AEI</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Federal Government Can Do More to Fight Credential Inflation</title>
		<link>https://www.aei.org/education/the-federal-government-can-do-more-to-fight-credential-inflation/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[George Pierson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 17:49:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Higher Education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Biden administration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Higher education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Student loans]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.aei.org/?p=1008664691</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Removing some degree requirements, in the long run, may do more to promote opportunity and limit student debt than any debt forgiveness program ever could.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.aei.org/education/the-federal-government-can-do-more-to-fight-credential-inflation/">The Federal Government Can Do More to Fight Credential Inflation</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.aei.org">American Enterprise Institute - AEI</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>In a recent piece, Rick Hess <a href="https://www.aei.org/op-eds/student-borrowing-is-the-symptom-legally-suspect-degree-requirements-are-the-problem/?mkt_tok=NDc1LVBCUS05NzEAAAGH0bJKagorDJIE7YzpYRJ7mXnmGOdd4fy8ZsPhiaYUq8E-5sNAN5O_JlY4bsVBp5HYdvL_Gd1-FQm8dOl63w_4VfDJXkN05NwxcFT3CE-jrxdJGV8" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">argues</a> that there is a strong link between the growing student debt burden (which has led to President Joe Biden’s recent loan forgiveness) and “credential inflation,” whereby employers require higher levels of education for jobs that have not changed much over the years in terms of responsibilities or compensation. He’s exactly right. </p>



<p>Research has <a href="https://www.hbs.edu/managing-the-future-of-work/Documents/dismissed-by-degrees.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">shown</a> massive increases in the proportion of job postings that require a degree for positions such as office administrators and supervisory roles in retail, sales, and the trades. Once these were viable rungs on the ladder to the middle class for those without college degrees, but today that is less frequently the case.</p>



<p>Drivers of these inflated requirements include employer hiring practices, actions by state licensing bodies, and even college accreditors. Motivations for filtering out anyone lacking a college degree vary too. It may simply be easier to sort through fewer applications and degree requirements. It also may be one of the few easy and (for now) legally permissible filters employers can use. Or it may have to do with elitism or protectionism: the desire to build walls to keep those with less prestigious credentials, or simply more competition, out of a given profession.</p>



<p>Regardless of the cause, however, the result is the same: It costs more to get the credentials necessary to do the same job at the same pay than in the past. The connection between these requirements and the necessary cost (both to students and taxpayers) to obtain the required credentials should be obvious but is too-seldom discussed. As Rick points out:</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>Washington has distorted the labor market by encouraging employers to turn college degrees into an all-purpose proxy for employability. This has fueled degree inflation, exaggerated the importance of a college degree, and inflated costs.</p></blockquote>



<p>Rick also rightly notes that the federal government could do more to “ensure that legally suspect degree requirements are subjected to the same scrutiny as any other potentially suspect hiring test.”</p>



<p>But the federal government also has a role to play as an employer; in fact, it is the nation’s largest.  During the previous administration, <a href="https://www.federalregister.gov/documents/2020/07/01/2020-14337/modernizing-and-reforming-the-assessment-and-hiring-of-federal-job-candidates" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Executive Order 13932</a> removed degree requirements and preferences for federal civilian jobs and created broad space for what federal jobs could require instead.</p>



<p>Fortunately, this might be the only executive order from his predecessor dealing with the civil service that President Biden left in place. His Office of Personnel Management has its work cut out for it to ensure that, not only will federal agencies implement the order with fidelity, but also that they have the tools necessary to cast a wider net and find talent in better ways.</p>



<p>As is the case in the private sector—where some major companies have also pledged to do away with degree requirements—implementation is what will matter most. Hiring based on what people know and can do, rather than simply how many years they spent in school, is a smarter strategy that can help companies limit turnover, improve diversity, and reduce time-to-hire.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The federal government could help both itself and the private sector by aggressively implementing this order and developing concrete strategies the private sector might then feel comfortable enough to adopt. In the long run, this may do more to promote opportunity and limit student debt than any debt forgiveness program ever could.</p>



<div class="related-items shortcode "><p><strong>Learn more: </strong><a href="https://www.aei.org/education/are-congressional-staff-now-the-biggest-student-loan-forgiveness-winners/">Are Congressional Staff Now the Biggest Student Loan Forgiveness Winners?</a> | <a href="https://www.aei.org/op-eds/bidens-future-plans-for-higher-education-will-be-even-more-radical/">Biden’s Future Plans for Higher Education Will Be Even More Radical</a> | <a href="https://www.aei.org/op-eds/school-choice-must-not-be-absorbed-by-the-blob/">School Choice Must Not Be Absorbed by the Blob</a> | <a href="https://www.aei.org/education/in-higher-education-focus-on-the-program-not-just-the-college/">In Higher Education, Focus on the Program—Not Just the College</a></p></div>



<p></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.aei.org/education/the-federal-government-can-do-more-to-fight-credential-inflation/">The Federal Government Can Do More to Fight Credential Inflation</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.aei.org">American Enterprise Institute - AEI</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Elections and Demography: A Final Look at the Polls</title>
		<link>https://www.aei.org/politics-and-public-opinion/elections-and-demography-a-final-look-at-the-polls/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[George Pierson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 16:04:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Politics and Public Opinion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Demographics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Elections]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Midterm elections]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Politics and Public Opinion Responses on Polling]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Polls]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.aei.org/?p=1008664679</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>In this final edition of an AEIdeas series on elections and demography, Republicans are increasing their lead in the generic ballot just before the elections on November 8.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.aei.org/politics-and-public-opinion/elections-and-demography-a-final-look-at-the-polls/">Elections and Demography: A Final Look at the Polls</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.aei.org">American Enterprise Institute - AEI</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img loading="lazy" width="2554" height="546" src="https://www.aei.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/AEI-Elections-Demography-banner.jpg?x91208" alt="" class="wp-image-1008662428"/></figure>



<p>This is the final pre-election issue of an AEIdeas series that focuses on elections and demographic voting patterns. After the election, we will look at what we learned from the 2022 results and move forward to future elections in 2023 and 2024. During the 2022 campaign, we have looked weekly at demographic subgroup averages from a month of polls.</p>



<p>Since this project began in July, midterm momentum has swung back and forth several times. Republicans entered the summer in an incredibly strong position, before Democrats came roaring back in late July and August. Surprising special election results offered even more summer optimism for congressional Democrats. Just as pundits were ready to declare 2022 a midterm akin to 1998 and 2002, Republicans picked up the momentum again. With millions of votes already cast, our final averages offer a snapshot of polling demographics before Election Day. Republicans appear poised to win the generic ballot: The most recent high-quality polls suggest somewhere in the range of 2–4 points. The swings we have seen over the summer and fall may seem small, but they could make a difference of 10 or 20 seats in the House—and several Senate seats.</p>



<p>Any polling discussion is incomplete without recognizing the intense difficulties facing even the most reputable pollsters. After a couple cycles with significant polling errors, the total number of surveys fell dramatically this year. District-level polls were nearly non-existent. Nate Cohn of the <em>New York Times</em> has noted that response rates have cratered, particularly among Republican-leaning voters. This has made polling even more time consuming and expensive.</p>



<p>Between opaque methodologies and differential response rates, neutral aggregators like our own are all the more essential.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full"><img loading="lazy" width="565" height="630" src="https://www.aei.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/image-1.png?x91208" alt="" class="wp-image-1008664715"/></figure></div>


<p><strong>Key Findings</strong></p>



<ul><li>After retaking the generic ballot lead last week, Republicans increased their edge by a half-point this week. Compared to our late September average, Republicans have picked up 3.6 points—a profound swing for just a month-long difference.</li><li>Since the Democratic peak in September, women have moved sharply towards Republicans. While President Biden carried women by 13 points in 2020, the Democratic advantage today is down to just 6.4 points. This week’s <a href="https://s3.documentcloud.org/documents/23257500/cnn-poll.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">CNN/SSRS poll</a> has Democrats up just 6 points among women and <a href="https://maristpoll.marist.edu/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/NPR_PBS-NewsHour_Marist-Poll_USA-NOS-and-Tables_202210281214.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">NPR/PBS/Marist</a> shows just a 4-point Democratic lead with them. Prospects for a <em>Dobbs</em>-generated gender shift towards Democrats have evaporated in recent weeks. It now appears incredibly unlikely that congressional Democrats will match Biden’s margin with women on Tuesday.</li><li>White college voters also standout in the recent rightward shift. Once a double-digit lead, the Democratic advantage has shrunk over the past few weeks. <a href="https://www.monmouth.edu/polling-institute/region/national/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Monmouth</a> and CNN/SSRS actually have Democrats <em>losing </em>white college voters in their most recent polls. As inflation and the economy have moved front of mind, some white college voters—perhaps once motivated by abortion—now plan to vote for Republicans.</li><li>Generally, our data indicate that educational polarization will be a huge factor in this election, just as it was in 2020. Our average shows, as have many individual polls, support among college-educated and non-college voters being almost mirror images of each other—an advantage for Democrats among the college-educated being matched by an almost equal deficit among non-college voters.</li><li>Even as most pollsters have shifted to likely voter screens, almost 14 percent of Hispanic voters remain undecided. With Democrats stuck at just a 19-point margin among them, these late-deciding voters could make or break Democratic chances in several essential contests—particularly Senate races in Arizona and Nevada. As we noted last week, however, undecideds appear to be moving towards Republicans.</li><li>The Democrats’ margin among black voters also is running far under the advantage Democrats have enjoyed in previous elections.</li></ul>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full"><img loading="lazy" width="700" height="738" src="https://www.aei.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/image.png?x91208" alt="" class="wp-image-1008664682"/></figure></div>


<p><em>Previous election data is drawn from Catalist crosstab estimates. Catalist is a Democratic data analytics organization.</em></p>



<p><em>*How we did this: This month-long average is a compilation of online and live-caller polls that release crosstabs. Internal and explicitly partisan polls are excluded. This edition averages polls from Monmouth University, Grinnell College/Selzer &amp; Company, Economist/YouGov, Morning Consult/Politico, Harvard/Harris, CBS News, Emerson, Marist, Yahoo News, Rasmussen, Echelon Insights, Marist College/NPR/PBS NewsHour, New York Times/Siena College, and Fox News.</em></p>



<div class="related-items shortcode "><p><strong>Learn more: </strong><a href="https://www.aei.org/politics-and-public-opinion/elections-and-demography-undecideds-break-for-republicans/">Elections and Demography: Undecideds Break for Republicans</a> | <a href="https://www.aei.org/politics-and-public-opinion/elections-and-demography-democrats-lose-ground-need-strong-turnout/">Elections and Demography: Democrats Lose Ground, Need Strong Turnout</a> | <a href="https://www.aei.org/politics-and-public-opinion/elections/elections-and-demography-one-month-to-go/">Elections and Demography: One Month to Go</a> | <a href="https://www.aei.org/politics-and-public-opinion/elections-and-demography-signs-of-a-tightening-race/">Elections and Demography: Signs of a Tightening Race</a></p></div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.aei.org/politics-and-public-opinion/elections-and-demography-a-final-look-at-the-polls/">Elections and Demography: A Final Look at the Polls</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.aei.org">American Enterprise Institute - AEI</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The New Social Media Playbook</title>
		<link>https://www.aei.org/technology-and-innovation/the-new-social-media-playbook/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Matthew Glavish]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Technology and Innovation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Censorship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Elon Musk]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[European Union (EU)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Free speech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Innovation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[internet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Online Speech Project]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social media]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.aei.org/?p=1008664585</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>With Elon Musk at the helm of Twitter, he has the opportunity to both revolutionize social media generally and find unique applications for Twitter’s capabilities in the real world.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.aei.org/technology-and-innovation/the-new-social-media-playbook/">The New Social Media Playbook</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.aei.org">American Enterprise Institute - AEI</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img loading="lazy" width="1800" height="250" src="https://www.aei.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/AEIsection230banner.png?x91208" alt="" class="wp-image-1008627382"/><figcaption>Note: This post and all affiliated content are part of AEI’s Online Speech Project. To learn more about the project, click <a href="https://www.aei.org/online-speech-project/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">here</a>.</figcaption></figure>



<p>Donald Trump and Elon Musk have three things in common: Each is so compelling that friends and foes alike cannot look away; some foes cannot contain their strong visceral reactions; and each man uses the first two effects to his advantage. Watch these show up in Musk’s Twitter playbook.</p>



<p>Musk’s celebrity status is well known. He <a href="https://twitter.com/elonmusk" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">has</a> 113.6 million Twitter followers at the time of publication. The Teal Mango <a href="https://www.thetealmango.com/featured/most-famous-persons-in-the-world/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">ranks</a> him as the third best-known person in the world. <em>Forbes </em><a href="https://www.forbes.com/billionaires/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">lists</a> him as the richest person in the world.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img loading="lazy" width="4181" height="2787" src="https://www.aei.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Another-Elon-Musk-Photo.jpg?x91208" alt="" class="wp-image-1008664586"/><figcaption>via Reuters</figcaption></figure>



<p>Critics reacted swiftly and aggressively to his purchase of Twitter. One anti-Musker <a href="https://twitter.com/Otto_English/status/1585892142660083713" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">predicted</a> that there will be “a rush of left leaning people to other platforms,” once the right come “crawling back.” <em>New York Times</em> editorial board member Greg Bensinger <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2022/04/25/opinion/editorials/twitter-elon-musk.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">wrote</a> that “Twitter under Elon Musk will be a scary place.” CBS’s Norah O’Donnell <a href="https://www.nationalreview.com/corner/the-bad-ugly-and-ignorant-reactions-to-elon-musks-purchase-of-twitter/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">said</a> Musk might “make Twitter a haven for disinformation and hate speech” and claimed that Musk has used Twitter to bully critics and reporters. Some tweeters <a href="https://twitter.com/HSouthwellFE/status/1585880826725556225" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">encouraged</a> people to <a href="https://mashable.com/article/elon-musk-twitter-reactions-takeover" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sabotage</a> Twitter. Perhaps these Musk critics are following through, as Twitter users are <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/twitter-is-drafting-broad-job-cuts-days-after-elon-musks-takeover-11667143301?mod=trending_now_news_3" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">reporting</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/TaylorLorenz/status/1585838262173675520" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">significant</a> increases in hateful and racist comments despite there being <a href="https://twitter.com/elonmusk/status/1586149451348910081" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">no changes</a> in Twitter’s content moderation policies.</p>



<p>The European Union also reacted. When Musk <a href="https://twitter.com/elonmusk/status/1585841080431321088" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">tweeted</a> on October 27th that “the bird is freed,” EU Commissioner Thierry Breton <a href="https://twitter.com/ThierryBreton/status/1585902196864045056" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">responded</a> the next day, “In Europe, the bird will fly by our rules.” Perhaps the commissioner wasn’t serious, as his tweet is a non sequitur: Musk’s freed-bird tweet coincided with his <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2022/10/27/tech/elon-musk-twitter" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">clearing</a> of Twitter’s executive suites. He didn’t assert that government rules will be broken.</p>



<p>Musk’s critics appear to be afraid that his Twitter will allow others to have freedom of speech. Actually, the critics should embrace such freedom, as it is <a href="https://www.aei.org/technology-and-innovation/free-expression-in-the-digital-age-highlights-from-an-expert-discussion/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">necessary</a> for <a href="https://www.aei.org/events/free-speech-in-the-digital-age-assessing-the-values-and-consequences-of-free-expression/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">fighting</a> the very abuses the critics claim to abhor, identifying truth, and developing strong minds and a robust society. A recent <a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S073658532200123X?dgcid=raven_sd_via_email#b0290" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">study</a> adds to the reasons for freeing speech. It found that exposure to misinformation prompts internet users to conduct their own investigations, which, if true, should make them less vulnerable to fallacies. And at least one of the study’s examples of misinformation highlighted just how hard actual misinformation is to identify. One claimed piece of misinformation—“COVID-19 death rates are inflated”—is not only open to multiple interpretations but is also a topic on which <a href="https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s10654-021-00787-9" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">researchers</a> <a href="https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s11845-020-02370-9" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">have</a> found wide disparities across countries and over time.</p>



<p>How might Musk use such attention and controversies in his Twitter playbook? One use will be for marketing. Musk famously <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Power-Play-Tesla-Elon-Century/dp/0385545452/ref=tmm_hrd_swatch_0?_encoding=UTF8&amp;qid=&amp;sr=" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">spent little</a> on marketing when launching Tesla’s cars because word of mouth and media attention did the work for him. Trump’s campaign <a href="https://www.politico.com/story/2016/12/trump-clinton-campaign-fundraising-totals-232400" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">leveraging</a> media attention in 2016 to beat Hillary Clinton while spending far fewer campaign dollars than she did echoes this strategy.</p>



<p>Musk will also create multiple <a href="https://thehill.com/opinion/technology/3476968-a-new-twitter-is-a-threat-to-meta-not-to-democracy/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">channels</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/elonmusk/status/1587498907336118274" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">financial</a> arrangements. This internal platform diversity will have several consequences, including generating new <a href="https://www.aei.org/technology-and-innovation/market-solutions-for-social-media-content-moderation/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">opportunities</a> for content creators and diverse communities, both for people with common interests and those who can tolerate an exploration of conflicting views.</p>



<p>Also, watch out for black swan <a href="https://www.politico.com/newsletters/digital-future-daily/2022/11/01/elon-drags-twitter-screaming-somewhere-00064480?tab=most-read" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">events</a>. Musk ties his business interests to his beliefs in the importance of the internet, sustainable energy, space exploration, artificial intelligence, and human genetics. Look for Twitter capabilities to show up in his broadband, automotive, and energy businesses—not as social media, but as a machine-to-machine and machine-to-person communications platform that creates and uses data for improved efficiencies and user experiences.</p>



<p>Look for him to transform some elements of the power sector. Tesla is already <a href="https://quickelectricity.com/tesla-energy-texas/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">approved</a> to be a retail electricity provider in Texas. A Twitter channel dedicated to drawing data from SpaceX satellites, Twitter users, and Teslas could use artificial intelligence to improve energy use across homes, automobiles, and more.</p>



<p>If even only a few of my predictions are right, Musk’s Twitter will change social media forever. Books analyzing the development of <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Power-Play-Tesla-Elon-Century/dp/0385545452/ref=tmm_hrd_swatch_0?_encoding=UTF8&amp;qid=&amp;sr=" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Tesla</a>, <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Liftoff-Desperate-Early-Launched-SpaceX/dp/0062979973/ref=tmm_hrd_swatch_0?_encoding=UTF8&amp;qid=&amp;sr=" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">SpaceX</a>, and <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Founders-Paypal-Entrepreneurs-Shaped-Silicon/dp/1501197266/ref=tmm_hrd_swatch_0?_encoding=UTF8&amp;qid=1667389771&amp;sr=1-1" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">PayPal</a> reveal a person that makes big bets, uses his many mistakes to find the right answers, admires innovation, seeks to dominate industries, and doesn&#8217;t like being told &#8220;no.&#8221; These strategies applied to re-creating Twitter will take the “social” out of social media to create spaces for innovation, shared work, and machine work.</p>



<p>What could go wrong? Politicians are keenly aware of the <a href="https://www.aei.org/technology-and-innovation/big-tech-will-never-be-the-same/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">power</a> of the legacy platforms and might act to protect them.</p>


<div class="related-items shortcode "><p><strong>See also:  </strong><a href="https://www.aei.org/technology-and-innovation/twitter-should-moderate-communities-not-content/">Twitter Should Moderate Communities, Not Content</a> | <a href="https://www.aei.org/technology-and-innovation/elon-musk-confronts-the-moderators-dilemma-holds-mirror-to-users/">Elon Musk Confronts the Moderator’s Dilemma and Holds a Mirror to Users</a> | <a href="https://www.aei.org/technology-and-innovation/market-solutions-for-social-media-content-moderation/">Market Solutions for Social Media Content Moderation</a> | <a href="https://www.aei.org/technology-and-innovation/big-tech-will-never-be-the-same/">Big Tech Will Never Be the Same</a></p></div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.aei.org/technology-and-innovation/the-new-social-media-playbook/">The New Social Media Playbook</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.aei.org">American Enterprise Institute - AEI</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Many More Student Loan Borrowers to Get Discharges Through a Determination of Disability</title>
		<link>https://www.aei.org/health-care/many-more-student-loan-borrowers-to-get-discharges-through-a-determination-of-disability/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Josiah Johnson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2022 18:49:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Health Care]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Health Economics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Department of Education (ED)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Office of Management and Budget (OMB)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social Security Disability Insurance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Student debt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Student loans]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.aei.org/?p=1008664629</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The Department of Education has issued a final regulation that significantly expands various classes of individuals eligible to get their federal student loans forgiven. Among the classes affected are individuals with disabilities.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.aei.org/health-care/many-more-student-loan-borrowers-to-get-discharges-through-a-determination-of-disability/">Many More Student Loan Borrowers to Get Discharges Through a Determination of Disability</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.aei.org">American Enterprise Institute - AEI</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>On October 31, the Department of Education (DoED) issued a <a href="https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/FR-2022-11-01/pdf/2022-23447.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">final regulation</a> that significantly expands various classes of individuals eligible to get their federal student loans forgiven. Among the classes affected are individuals with disabilities.</p>



<p>First, the regulation increases substantially the group of student loan borrowers, including parents, who can get a loan discharge based on disability as determined by the Social Security Administration (SSA) for Disability Insurance (DI) or Supplemental Security Income (SSI). Specifically, it expands from those designated by SSA as Medical Improvement Not Expected (a minority of disability beneficiaries) to those designated as Medical Improvement Possible (a larger group), those who transitioned from DI to retirement benefits (another large group), those with a severe medical impairment, and those whose disability onset date was five years before or whose receipt of disability benefits has lasted five years before the loan discharge application (again, a large group). That is, in total, a substantial majority of DI and SSI disability and some retirement beneficiaries are now eligible for student loan discharges.</p>



<p>Second, the regulations eliminate the current requirement that borrowers must supply to the DoED their income information annually through a three-year post-discharge monitoring period to ensure that they continue to meet the earnings criteria for the program. Finally, the regulation expands the list of eligible health care professionals able to certify an individual’s total and permanent disability (in addition to physicians and outside of the SSA and Veterans Affairs’ official determinations) to include nurse practitioners, physicians assistants, and psychologists.</p>



<p>DoED estimates that these changes will cost taxpayers $1.5 billion on an annualized basis. Although the final regulation gives some data to support this estimate, in particular that the number eligible for loan discharge on the basis of SSA-determined disability will double, my hunch is that this is an underestimate, given the substantial expansion of the groups. (The DoED has a <a href="https://www.gao.gov/products/gao-22-105365" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">poor track record</a> at scoring the cost of student loans, resulting in severe underestimates.) The regulation also considerably downplays a potential explosion of discharges from the separate and combined effects of greatly expanding the list of eligible health care professionals certifying disability, and the elimination of the earnings monitoring period. It is certainly possible, even probable given DoED is unlikely to closely supervise the process, that the new inclusion of hundreds of thousands of relatively lower-paid health care professionals who are not experts in disability determination will lead to many student loan borrowers asking for and getting from their health providers a declaration of disability, outside of the fairly rigorous process now in place at SSA for disability determination and earnings follow-up. This is so particularly given the current known and reasonable reluctance of physicians to participate in this process.</p>



<p>The lack of a follow-up on earnings by DoED, which might have caught the mistakes (and fraud) of this new group of health providers, will expand the loss to taxpayers. The regulation’s score estimators—and their Office of Management and Budget (OMB) overseers—also seem to be unaware of an important trend in DI beneficiaries: Whereas in the past most did not have college educations, now the majority of new beneficiaries do and many of them will have student loans.</p>



<p>Extending the review of this rule change further, the disability class expansion is not well targeted as required by the Higher Education Act and good policy. It includes those whose disabilities will improve and can return to work, those who have considerable individual and household incomes and assets, and those whose disabilities will be determined by non-experts and are therefore doubtful or minimal. DoED is not being creative in the use of data exchanges on income and earnings with other government agencies. The entire final regulation containing numerous major changes was pushed through in an extremely rushed fashion (three months!) and through a DoED-selected commission of interested and conflicted parties with no representation from researchers on higher education finance or the general public, i.e. taxpayers. Although I am unable to be specific in this quick review, I am suspicious that not all of the extensive and several OMB data, research, legal and other requirements and layers of review on the regulatory process were satisfied, given the rush and <a href="https://www.regulations.gov/docket/ED-2021-OPE-0077/comments">more than 5,000 comments</a>, certainly compared to my own experience of several arduous years spent at SSA working on disability regulations with OMB civil servants.</p>



<div class="related-items shortcode "><p><strong>Learn more: </strong><a href="https://www.aei.org/op-eds/if-you-think-the-deficit-is-bad-now-it-will-soon-get-worse/">If You Think the Deficit Is Bad Now, It Will Soon Get Worse</a> | <a href="https://www.aei.org/op-eds/reforming-supplemental-security-income-the-sensible-way/">Reforming Supplemental Security Income the Sensible Way</a> | <a href="https://www.aei.org/op-eds/the-rich-are-using-long-term-care-funds-meant-for-the-poor/">The Rich Are Using Long-Term Care Funds Meant for the Poor</a> | <a href="https://www.aei.org/op-eds/the-social-security-fairness-act-is-unfair/">The “Social Security Fairness Act” Is Unfair</a></p></div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.aei.org/health-care/many-more-student-loan-borrowers-to-get-discharges-through-a-determination-of-disability/">Many More Student Loan Borrowers to Get Discharges Through a Determination of Disability</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.aei.org">American Enterprise Institute - AEI</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Reality Check on the Importance of Teacher Expectations</title>
		<link>https://www.aei.org/education/a-reality-check-on-the-importance-of-teacher-expectations/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[George Pierson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2022 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Education reform]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[High Schools]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[public schools]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[teachers]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.aei.org/?p=1008664478</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>At a time when data-free ideologues are hailing the merits of low expectations in the name of equity and kind-heartedness, Fordham University Professor Seth Gershenson provides a timely reality check.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.aei.org/education/a-reality-check-on-the-importance-of-teacher-expectations/">A Reality Check on the Importance of Teacher Expectations</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.aei.org">American Enterprise Institute - AEI</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>As I’ve noted many times (see, for instance, <a href="https://www.aei.org/op-eds/oregon-democrats-resurrect-the-soft-bigotry-of-low-expectations/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">here</a>, <a href="https://www.aei.org/op-eds/california-wants-teachers-to-violate-educations-hippocratic-oath/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">here</a>, and <a href="https://thedispatch.com/article/defend-gifted-education-and-then/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">here</a>), some corners in schooling today are marked by a bizarre enthusiasm for low expectations. This has fueled a push to eliminate graduation requirements, do away with advanced classes, eliminate gifted programs, and stop asking students to show their work. All of this was promoted by self-proclaimed agents of “equity” before the pandemic and has only gained momentum as school leaders “temper” their expectations in light of pandemic-fueled learning loss.</p>



<p>While going easy may seem like a genial accommodation after the disruptions of the past few years, it does students no favors—with the worst impacts on the most vulnerable kids.</p>



<p>Now, when the air is thick with suggestions that grading is hopelessly biased and even that hard work is a product of “white supremacy culture,” it takes backbone for teachers to hold fast to high expectations. That’s doubly true when low expectations are easier, making for less work, happier students, and fewer parental gripes about low grades or classroom discipline.</p>



<p>Despite all of this, some teachers are still willing to hold fast to high expectations. On that score, a provocative new Fordham Institute <a href="https://fordhaminstitute.org/national/research/the-power-of-expectations-district-charter" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">study</a> by American University professor Seth Gershenson uses federal data from two nationally representative surveys to get a sense of high school teachers’ expectations and how those expectations vary across different kinds of schools.</p>



<p>Unfortunately, Gershenson struggles with a variety of limitations, since the data sets he uses weren’t necessarily intended for this purpose. For starters, he leans heavily on a question which asks whether teachers think their students will go on to complete a four-year college. This has serious limitations: This metric clearly favors schools focused on preparing students for college. And it’s not a great way to gauge whether teachers have rigorous expectations in the classroom for conduct, effort, or mastery. Of course, Gershenson can only make do with the questions that were asked.</p>



<p>Another issue is simply the age of the data, as the two data sets Gershenson uses are comprised of students who were in tenth grade in 2002 or 2009. While the analysis is informative, it can’t tell us anything about what expectations look like in 2022—whether they’ve been affected by the pandemic, lowered by a misguided understanding of “equity,” or even if the same patterns are still evident across kinds of schools.</p>



<p>For all the limitations, though, the results are worth mulling over. Across the data, Gershenson finds that 48 percent of traditional public high school math teachers and 49 percent of their English-teaching peers expected students to complete a four-year college education. At charter high schools, the figures were 63 and 53 percent; at private schools, 79 and 80 percent.</p>



<p>Since the high expectations in charter and private schools could have been a function of student or school characteristics (rather than teacher mindset), Gershenson used multivariate analysis to try and control for those factors. He found that, other things equal, private high school English and math teachers were about 20 percentage points more likely than their district peers to expect students to complete college. Charter school teachers’ expectations weren’t quite as high as those in private schools, but were noticeably higher than those in district schools.</p>



<p>Gershenson also finds that when high school teachers have high expectations, it appear to have an impact on things like high school graduation and college completion. This shouldn’t be all that surprising and is consistent with a pretty substantial body of research. But it’s a reminder that seems necessary right about now.</p>



<p>With its older data, imperfect measures, and statistical gymnastics, this kind of analysis always merits careful handling. But at a time when data-free ideologues are hailing the merits of low expectations in the name of equity and kind-heartedness, Gershenson has provided a timely reality check.</p>



<div class="related-items shortcode "><p><strong>Learn more: </strong><a href="https://www.aei.org/op-eds/searching-for-common-ground-student-loan-forgiveness-and-the-cost-of-higher-ed/">Searching for Common Ground: Student-Loan Forgiveness and the Cost of Higher Ed.</a> | <a href="https://www.aei.org/op-eds/choice-of-ben-sasse-for-univ-of-florida-causes-a-ruckus-what-do-college-presidents-even-do/">Choice of Ben Sasse for University of Florida Causes a Ruckus. What Do College Presidents Even Do?</a> | <a href="https://www.aei.org/op-eds/scotus-may-end-race-based-admissions-preferences-congress-should-do-same-for-wealth-based-preferences/">As Supreme Court Considers Affirmative Action's Future, Legacy Admissions Also Need to End</a> | <a href="https://www.aei.org/op-eds/whats-the-point-of-civics-education/">What’s the Point of Civics Education?</a></p></div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.aei.org/education/a-reality-check-on-the-importance-of-teacher-expectations/">A Reality Check on the Importance of Teacher Expectations</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.aei.org">American Enterprise Institute - AEI</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Twitter Should Moderate Communities, Not Content</title>
		<link>https://www.aei.org/technology-and-innovation/twitter-should-moderate-communities-not-content/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Matthew Glavish]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2022 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Technology and Innovation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Censorship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Elon Musk]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[internet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Online Speech Project]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[twitter]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.aei.org/?p=1008664512</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Rather than playing Sisyphus in the content moderation theatrics, Twitter should instead borrow from reputation systems to incentivize community moderation to reward people for platform credibility and moderate behavior.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.aei.org/technology-and-innovation/twitter-should-moderate-communities-not-content/">Twitter Should Moderate Communities, Not Content</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.aei.org">American Enterprise Institute - AEI</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img loading="lazy" width="1800" height="250" src="https://www.aei.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/AEIsection230banner.png?x91208" alt="" class="wp-image-1008627382"/><figcaption>Note: This post and all affiliated content are part of AEI’s Online Speech Project. To learn more about the project, click <a href="https://www.aei.org/online-speech-project/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">here</a>.</figcaption></figure>



<p>With Elon Musk’s acquisition of Twitter now finalized, the issue of how he is going to run the company is fully joined. Musk <a href="https://twitter.com/elonmusk/status/1586149451348910081" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">announced</a> that there would be no change to Twitter’s content policies until a “content moderation council” is convened. It’s a good time to consider the truly vast range of options available to Musk and Twitter. In my opinion, Twitter should de-emphasize content moderation in favor of <em>community</em> moderation.</p>



<p>In <a href="https://www.aei.org/research-products/testimony/testimony-privacy-and-other-challenges-for-mandated-internet-platform-disclosure/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">testimony</a> to the Senate Judiciary Committee earlier this year, I discussed content moderation in the context of a proposal to <a href="https://www.aei.org/technology-and-innovation/mandated-platform-transparency-speech-regulation-is-in-the-air-everywhere/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">force transparency</a> on internet platforms. I noted how some users are relentless in their efforts to reverse engineer and then evade every content moderation policy and practice. Content moderation is similar to platform security; attackers are motivated, adaptive, and wily.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img loading="lazy" width="2610" height="1740" src="https://www.aei.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Musk-Twitter-Complaint-Hotline-Operator.jpg?x91208" alt="" class="wp-image-1008664515"/><figcaption>via Reuters</figcaption></figure>



<p>As I did in my testimony, my colleague Daniel Lyons recently <a href="https://www.aei.org/technology-and-innovation/elon-musk-confronts-the-moderators-dilemma-holds-mirror-to-users/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">discussed</a> giving content moderation tools to users. That would be consistent with what makes the internet great: This “dumb” network pushes innovation and responsibility to the edges, <a href="https://fee.org/articles/decentralization-why-dumb-networks-are-better/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">which is smart</a>. With tools in hand, users can array their motivations, adaptability, and wiles against social attackers. Importantly, this can weaken the bipartisan political demand for companies to “fix” content.</p>



<p>But users may not be able to overcome their fascination with conflict.</p>



<p>Twitter need not wait for users to mature on their own. Information that can tune the community’s zeitgeist are there to be harvested. Think in terms of reputation systems.</p>



<p>Credit reporting and Google’s <a href="https://www.google.com/search/howsearchworks/how-search-works/ranking-results/#quality" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">PageRank algorithm</a> are both reputation systems. They use information gathered from third parties to gauge a given resource’s reliability. In the case of credit reporting, records of reliable bill payments tell you how likely a person is to pay bills in the future.</p>



<p>In PageRank, the focus is on links. A hyperlink from one web page to another is a vote saying, “This resource is good.” Pages with more links pointing their way are probably better resources than pages with fewer. The process is recursive: If a web page that others recognize as a good resource points to another web page, that can be treated as a stronger up vote than the vote of a lower-ranked page.</p>



<p>The same type of process can animate Twitter’s curation of community. <em>In general</em>: Follows are votes. Retweets are votes. Replies are votes. And so on.</p>



<p>Those indicia are subject to gaming. But many others are harder to game, or they can’t be gamed at all. All of them can be fed into a reputation algorithm that rewards productive contribution and disincentivizes antisocial behavior.</p>



<p>How long has an account existed? How much does an account parrot others or itself? Does the account have the daily, weekly, and monthly participation cadence of a well-adjusted human? Has the account holder submitted (optional) proof of identity? <a href="https://twitter.com/elonmusk/status/1587498907336118274" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Paid a fee</a>? Does the account connect from a normal distribution of IP addresses? Does the account have a variegated (non-bubble) network of followers and followees? Does the account follow links? How long does the account take to write tweets or replies? Does the account abandon and delete tweets? Does the tenor or language of an account’s interactions follow healthy patterns? Does the account respond to randomized <a href="http://www.captcha.net/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">CAPTCHAs</a>?</p>



<p>Some of these data are probably used now to help root out “fake” accounts. All these things and many more could be tested as dials that tune the community toward normalcy by increasing the public availability of “healthy” accounts.</p>



<p>There is no need for this approach to be a <a href="https://www.arimetrics.com/en/digital-glossary/black-box-algorithm" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">black box</a> eliciting paranoid claims of <a href="https://www.theatlantic.com/technology/archive/2022/04/social-media-shadowbans-tiktok-twitter/629702/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">shadow banning</a>. Publish at least summary guidelines of what the algorithm prefers so that people can adjust their behavior accordingly. If an obsessive person must post judiciously to be heard, so be it. If a “fake” account must act like a healthy human to survive, what’s the difference?</p>



<p>If you think this style of moderation is impossible, consider an arena in which people actually earn money by defeating a reputation system. That’s Google. And Google has done this kind of moderation at scale. Ask <a href="https://searchengineland.com/google-head-web-spam-221482" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Matt Cutts</a>. Google keeps “search engine optimization” in check well enough to continue thriving as a business.</p>



<p>In opining here, I’ve said nothing about the substantive content of tweets. Other than universally disapproved gore, scatology, and so on, it’s a fool’s errand to try to moderate content based on content. The alternative is moderating communities—not in the censorious mode that addresses what people can say, but in a civilizing mode that addresses how people can act. Regardless of content, Twitter can give more voice to people whose behavior is moderate.</p>


<div class="related-items shortcode "><p><strong>See also:  </strong><a href="https://www.aei.org/technology-and-innovation/elon-musk-confronts-the-moderators-dilemma-holds-mirror-to-users/">Elon Musk Confronts the Moderator’s Dilemma and Holds a Mirror to Users</a> | <a href="https://www.aei.org/technology-and-innovation/mandated-platform-transparency-speech-regulation-is-in-the-air-everywhere/">Mandated Platform Transparency: Speech Regulation Is in the Air Everywhere</a> | <a href="https://www.aei.org/technology-and-innovation/market-solutions-for-social-media-content-moderation/">Market Solutions for Social Media Content Moderation</a> | <a href="https://www.aei.org/events/separating-fact-from-fiction-election-disinformation-on-online-platforms/">Separating Fact from Fiction: Election Disinformation on Online Platforms</a></p></div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.aei.org/technology-and-innovation/twitter-should-moderate-communities-not-content/">Twitter Should Moderate Communities, Not Content</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.aei.org">American Enterprise Institute - AEI</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Why Are Liberal Arts College Faculty Building Better Relationships with Their Students?</title>
		<link>https://www.aei.org/politics-and-public-opinion/why-are-liberal-arts-college-faculty-building-better-relationships-with-their-students/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[George Pierson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2022 17:56:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Politics and Public Opinion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[college]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[college admissions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Education]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.aei.org/?p=1008664471</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Prospective students who want stronger connections with professors should look toward liberal arts colleges to gain the real value of truly knowing and working with your college professors.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.aei.org/politics-and-public-opinion/why-are-liberal-arts-college-faculty-building-better-relationships-with-their-students/">Why Are Liberal Arts College Faculty Building Better Relationships with Their Students?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.aei.org">American Enterprise Institute - AEI</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Over a decade ago, after finishing teaching Robert Putnam’s classic <em><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Bowling-Alone-Collapse-American-Community/dp/0743203046" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Bowling Alone</a> </em>at NYU, I took my students bowling to unwind one evening and this was met with surprise and shock by a handful of department faculty members. I was told that it was a mistake to have spent time with students, for such engagement with undergraduates signaled that I was not a serious scholar. I was taken aback. I enjoyed being more than a fairly removed, anonymous, twice-a-week lecturer helping guide these students along their academic and post-collegiate professional journeys. Yet, it was clear that connecting with undergraduate students was not a real priority at NYU, at least within the politics department.</p>



<p>Now, I teach as a professor at Sarah Lawrence College, a small liberal arts college in New York. A significant part of the undergraduate experience at Sarah Lawrence involves close faculty work with students and helping supervise research regularly. Many liberal arts colleges promote themselves <a href="https://www.amherst.edu/academiclife" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">as teaching-centered</a>, personal, and dynamic compared to a typical university experience that tends to focus more on faculty research than teaching. These significant institutional details have certainly been my experience over the years, and I have long wondered if this perception is generally correct.</p>



<p>New data from College Pulses’ <a href="https://www.insidehighered.com/news/2022/05/20/survey-students-want-connections-professors-may-not-initiate-them" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Students Views on Faculty survey</a> provides some insight here as the survey captured the voices of 2000 students at 120 schools ranging from liberal arts colleges to community colleges and universities. The survey explicitly asks students how well they believe their professors and instructors build relationships with students, and the results from the data are encouraging: six in 10 (60 percent) of current students in higher education institutions think that professors are excellent or good, while just 13 percent think that faculty do a poor job interfacing with their students. Unlike many caricatures, professors are not aloof and the majority do connect with their students.</p>



<p>Such positive sentiments toward faculty, however, are not uniform across higher education institutions. Liberal arts schools that, like my own, take great pride in intimate teaching do truly stand apart. Seventy-two percent of enrolled students in these small collegiate settings report that their professors are good or excellent in terms of building relationships with their students. In contrast, the figure is appreciably lower at 57 percent for universities. Sixty-four percent of students at both community colleges and at regional schools—institutions with huge enrollments that often transform the lives of their students—think that their faculty members are good or excellent at connecting with them, suggesting that big research universities leave something to be desired on the teaching front.</p>



<p>Breaking this down a bit further, among the top 25 universities per <a href="https://www.usnews.com/best-colleges/rankings/national-universities" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">the US News rankings</a>, 55 percent of their students rank their faculty as good or excellent in connecting with students. That figure climbs to 63 percent from 26 through 100 ranked universities; for schools ranked above 100, the figure is back down a bit to 55 percent, suggesting that even in schools which have lower reputational status, connecting with students is still a lower priority compared to liberal arts colleges. Turning to liberal arts schools, 68 percent of students at a top-25 school have a good or excellent connection with their professor. Liberal arts students at schools from 25 to 100 are more positive at 93 percent. While scholarship remains a priority among the liberal arts, these lower-ranked liberal arts schools focus on teaching, while research is not as much of a priority. This creates a culture of teaching and intimacy.</p>



<p>It is unambiguously clear that faculty in liberal arts colleges are far more likely to be connected with their students compared to those in universities. There are <a href="https://www.apu.edu/articles/the-importance-of-the-professor-and-student-connection/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">so many benefits</a> that flow from these relationships, from promoting better in-class performance to faculty members serving as mentors and advocates.&nbsp;I have loved working with so many students so closely over the years; it has helped me better understand political and generational change and has provided endless insights into my own research. And now, new data backs up my own experiences. While it is true that university professors can and do form real relationships and connect with their students, connectivity at liberal arts colleges is far deeper. Thus, prospective students who <a href="https://www.insidehighered.com/news/2022/05/20/survey-students-want-connections-professors-may-not-initiate-them" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">want stronger connections with professors</a> should look toward liberal arts colleges and accept that there are some tradeoffs because of scale and scope, but what is gained is the real value in truly knowing and working with your college professors.</p>



<p><em>Samuel J. Abrams is a professor of politics at Sarah Lawrence College and a senior fellow at the American Enterprise Institute.</em></p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"/>



<div class="related-items shortcode "><p><strong>Learn more: </strong><a href="https://www.aei.org/society-and-culture/the-positive-side-of-social-media/">The Positive Side of Social Media</a> | <a href="https://www.aei.org/politics-and-public-opinion/finding-third-places-across-america/">Finding Third Places Across America</a> | <a href="https://www.aei.org/op-eds/finding-third-places-across-america/">Finding third places across America</a> | <a href="https://www.aei.org/articles/a-collegiate-reality-check%ef%bf%bc/">A Collegiate Reality Check</a></p></div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.aei.org/politics-and-public-opinion/why-are-liberal-arts-college-faculty-building-better-relationships-with-their-students/">Why Are Liberal Arts College Faculty Building Better Relationships with Their Students?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.aei.org">American Enterprise Institute - AEI</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Elon Musk Confronts the Moderator’s Dilemma and Holds a Mirror to Users</title>
		<link>https://www.aei.org/technology-and-innovation/elon-musk-confronts-the-moderators-dilemma-holds-mirror-to-users/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Matthew Glavish]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2022 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Technology and Innovation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[big tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Censorship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Elon Musk]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[First Amendment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Free speech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Innovation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[internet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Online Speech Project]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[twitter]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.aei.org/?p=1008664191</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>With Elon Musk’s Twitter acquisition finalized, what needs to happen next for the social media platform to become the digital town square that Musk envisions?</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.aei.org/technology-and-innovation/elon-musk-confronts-the-moderators-dilemma-holds-mirror-to-users/">Elon Musk Confronts the Moderator’s Dilemma and Holds a Mirror to Users</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.aei.org">American Enterprise Institute - AEI</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img loading="lazy" width="1800" height="250" src="https://www.aei.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/AEIsection230banner.png?x91208" alt="" class="wp-image-1008627382"/><figcaption>Note: This post and all affiliated content are part of AEI’s Online Speech Project. To learn more about the project, click <a href="https://www.aei.org/online-speech-project/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">here</a>.</figcaption></figure>



<p>Last week, Elon Musk announced his acquisition of Twitter as only he could: with a triumphant entry into the company’s headquarters, beaming with the self-amusement of a man who knows he’s about to land the perfect dad joke. (Let that <a href="https://twitter.com/elonmusk/status/1585341984679469056" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sink</a> in.) Shortly thereafter, he adopted the moniker of Chief Twit and told the world “<a href="https://twitter.com/elonmusk/status/1585841080431321088" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">the bird is freed</a>.”</p>



<p>In an <a href="https://twitter.com/elonmusk/status/1585619322239561728" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">open letter</a>, Musk reiterated the commitment to free speech that prompted his initial bid several months ago. “The reason I acquired Twitter,” he explained, “is because it is important to the future of civilization to have a common digital town square, where a range of beliefs can be debated in a healthy manner, without resorting to violence.” He hopes this new Twitter will break the cycle of promoting ever-more extreme content in the relentless pursuit of clicks—and the subsequent fracturing of society into political silos.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img loading="lazy" width="3691" height="2240" src="https://www.aei.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Elon-Musk-Chief-Twit.jpg?x91208" alt="" class="wp-image-1008664192"/><figcaption>via Reuters</figcaption></figure>



<p>Since then, the digital birdhouse has been atwitter about the ramifications of this vision. The fringe right <a href="https://twitter.com/ncri_io/status/1586007698910646272" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">met Musk’s takeover</a> with the maturity of Bart Simpson, suddenly realizing the parents are gone and promptly shedding any remaining shred of decorum on the platform. (Twitter has <a href="https://twitter.com/yoyoel/status/1586542286342475776" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">questioned the authenticity</a> of these accounts.) Meanwhile on the left, users posted screenshots of these offensive comments, thus spotlighting the very content they feared would spread. Later that weekend, Musk himself posted a since-deleted tweet linking to a conspiracy theory about the Paul Pelosi attack—a tweet immediately covered by none other than the <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2022/10/30/business/musk-tweets-hillary-clinton-pelosi-husband.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><em>New York Times</em></a>, which dutifully explained the conspiracy to readers.</p>



<p>Both vignettes display a bizarre permutation of the <a href="https://www.economist.com/the-economist-explains/2013/04/15/what-is-the-streisand-effect" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Streisand Effect</a>. But instead of an actor trying to hide information and unintentionally drawing attention to it, we see actors wanting to go viral and succeeding because of the efforts of those who want the message suppressed. One might call it the “outrage dilemma.”</p>



<p>Accomplishing Musk’s vision of a shared digital space will involve developing more productive ways of navigating that shared space together. To do so, we might heed the advice of the late Supreme Court Justice Ruth Bader Ginsburg. When asked about traversing difficult relationships, including on the Court, <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2016/10/02/opinion/sunday/ruth-bader-ginsburgs-advice-for-living.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">she quoted her mother-in-law’s advice</a> on her wedding day: “In every good marriage . . . it helps sometimes to be a little deaf.” Twitter gives its users ample tools to do so, including options to block or mute users and words. In a sense, this is a conception of free speech that the left often touted in the net neutrality debates: Rather than relying on companies to regulate the flow of information to consumers, give users tools to customize and filter their internet experiences. Alternatively, users may simply choose not to engage with offensive content. Ginsburg continued, “When a thoughtless or unkind word is spoken, best tune out. Reacting in anger or annoyance will not advance one’s ability to persuade.”</p>



<p>Musk is likely to find that some company-side content moderation is also necessary to achieve his vision of the digital public square. The right to speak freely means little if there’s no audience to listen. Even with robust user-side filtering tools in place, Twitter probably must continue policing the edges of the square to make sure it remains a space where users—and advertisers—want to be. Musk’s open letter acknowledges this, noting that “Twitter cannot become a free-for-all hellscape.” He has also <a href="https://twitter.com/elonmusk/status/1586149451348910081" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">frozen</a> the company’s pre-acquisition moderation practices for the moment and hinted at forming a <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2022/10/28/technology/twitter-elon-musk-content-moderation.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">content moderation council</a> similar to Facebook’s <a href="https://oversightboard.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Oversight Board</a>.</p>



<p>As I’ve <a href="https://www.aei.org/technology-and-innovation/on-texas-social-media-law-its-the-fifth-circuit-versus-the-first-amendment/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">discussed</a> <a href="https://www.aei.org/technology-and-innovation/social-media-common-carriage-and-the-first-amendment/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">before</a>, the First Amendment protects Twitter’s right to moderate site content. But Musk will find it difficult to do so, as any moderation opens him to the charge of becoming the very thing he sought to avoid. As the Chief Twit, he must be willing to take criticism from those who feel silenced by moderation policies. He may take comfort from studies showing that most users <a href="https://www.pewresearch.org/fact-tank/2020/08/19/55-of-u-s-social-media-users-say-they-are-worn-out-by-political-posts-and-discussions/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">dislike</a> polarizing discussions online. Transparency can mitigate such conflicts; clear and consistent rules can reduce claims of pretextual takedowns and shadow bans that drive the right’s criticism of Big Tech.</p>



<p>At the end of the day, moderation is how social media platforms compete for user attention. Each company develops complex algorithms designed to give users personalized content feeds that promote retention and interaction with others. Musk has shown a tendency to disrupt traditional industries by experimenting with new business models. Hopefully, he will innovate in this space, testing to find the right combination of moderation rules and user tools to attract and promote constructive dialogue on important issues. This innovation will be crucial to help Twitter achieve Musk’s dream of a digital salon and avoid critics’ fears that it will instead devolve into an online cesspool.</p>


<div class="related-items shortcode "><p><strong>See also:  </strong><a href="https://www.aei.org/technology-and-innovation/on-texas-social-media-law-its-the-fifth-circuit-versus-the-first-amendment/">On Texas Social Media Law, It’s the Fifth Circuit Versus the First Amendment</a> | <a href="https://www.aei.org/technology-and-innovation/social-media-common-carriage-and-the-first-amendment/">Social Media, Common Carriage, and the First Amendment</a> | <a href="https://www.aei.org/events/separating-fact-from-fiction-election-disinformation-on-online-platforms/">Separating Fact from Fiction: Election Disinformation on Online Platforms</a> | <a href="https://www.aei.org/technology-and-innovation/market-solutions-for-social-media-content-moderation/">Market Solutions for Social Media Content Moderation</a></p></div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.aei.org/technology-and-innovation/elon-musk-confronts-the-moderators-dilemma-holds-mirror-to-users/">Elon Musk Confronts the Moderator’s Dilemma and Holds a Mirror to Users</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.aei.org">American Enterprise Institute - AEI</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Positive Side of Social Media</title>
		<link>https://www.aei.org/society-and-culture/the-positive-side-of-social-media/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Josiah Johnson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2022 16:37:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Society and Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[college]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Generation Z]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[students]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[technology]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.aei.org/?p=1008664075</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Global social media platforms like TikTok and Instagram have been blamed for creating a plethora of problems. But there's a silver lining: Social media can improve the ability of students to process and integrate huge amounts of information and then communicate their ideas clearly and succinctly to others.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.aei.org/society-and-culture/the-positive-side-of-social-media/">The Positive Side of Social Media</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.aei.org">American Enterprise Institute - AEI</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Global social media platforms like TikTok and Instagram have been blamed for creating a plethora of problems in young people’s lives. From helping foster insular and narrow socio-political outlooks to a fixation on <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2018/jul/23/social-media-and-celebrity-culture-harming-young-people" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">celebrity culture, materialism, and consumption</a> to increasing concerns about <a href="https://www.bostonglobe.com/2022/09/26/opinion/an-us-vs-them-mentality-campuses-turns-potential-friends-into-allies-or-enemies/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">self-harm, mental health, and inclusion</a>, social media has altered the way students engage with the world as well as themselves <a href="https://www.hsph.harvard.edu/news/features/how-social-medias-toxic-content-sends-teens-into-a-dangerous-spiral/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">in significant and harmful ways</a>.</p>



<p>As a college professor, I have sadly seen these effects play out in front of me to the detriment of open inquiry and student sanity. But I want to share that there has been one appreciable effect of social media that has been quite positive: the improved ability of students to process and integrate huge amounts of information and then communicate their ideas clearly and succinctly to others.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full"><img loading="lazy" width="700" height="700" src="https://www.aei.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Abrams-10-31-featured-1.png?x91208" alt="" class="wp-image-1008664080"/><figcaption>Via AdobeStock</figcaption></figure></div>


<p>This change in how students share and debate ideas has clearly emerged in my seminars. My students are tasked to summarize the week’s readings and then present critical questions to the group beyond the central research questions or problems raised by the author. Students must lay out core concepts, evidence, and research methods and then explain the various up- and downsides of the author’s choices. They are asked to talk about any sources of bias in the work, and I often push the students to share what they believe it would require to persuade them to think differently about the work. I also want my students to identify the key norms, agents, and institutions in the various works, and I regularly ask them to suggest if it is possible to improve an argument with further empirical evidence or historical study.</p>



<p>These tasks are not easy. But I have been doing this for almost 15 years with very powerful results. There are two particular reasons behind making this pedagogical decision. First, I am pushing the students to directly and actively engage with ideas and arguments in various works. This allows each student to come away with a nuanced understanding of the key questions posed by the author(s) and how they answered those questions. This exercise highlights what has been learned from the work and what still needs to be explored. Doing so requires pulling together competing ideas and separating key signals from quite a bit of noise.</p>



<p>The second impetus behind these presentations is that I want students to actively listen, question, and wrestle with their ideas and the thoughts of others; it means that students must take the lead themselves and cannot passively record and regurgitate my ideas and thoughts. Presenting in class helps improve intimacy as a group and often compels students to share their views and logic and defend their ideas in front of others. It pushes students to refine their thinking, deeply criticize and evaluate work, and develop into effective public presenters outside of their bubbles. While often jarring and initially uncomfortable, many students have come to thank me, saying it helped them become active learners and comfortable in more open and public settings.</p>



<p>When I first started with this approach, as a general phenomenon, students were uncomfortable speaking and making eye contact with their peers and had difficulty pulling their ideas together and then critically evaluating evidence to reach a conclusion. I worked with many students for countless hours over the years, trying to help them become comfortable public speakers and help them to cultivate the skill set of evaluating evidence and competing ideas. This was a huge but rewarding challenge. Today, in contrast, students come to my seminars prepared with quasi-professional presentations, have little trouble or fear of speaking in front of others, and happily criticize ideas while trying to make sense of arguments without as much involvement from me.</p>



<p>Social media and its video-based format has clearly played a potent role in this momentous change. Our Gen Z students have grown up and are maturing in a world of social media ubiquity. With so many apps and platforms that promote video and sharing, students have become far more comfortable publicly expressing their ideas and presenting themselves to others. Students have also become proficient in sorting and managing countless sources of information and are seemingly untroubled by a world filled with disagreement and viewpoint diversity. There are so many threads and sources online and managing information and searching for narratives and truths has almost become second nature.</p>



<p>Students now come to class with a desire to make sense of the noise and with a genuine excitement to search for the truth. Thus, while social media is causing countless social problems, this represents quite a positive change for not only teaching but also for politics and the chances of Gen Zers finding solutions and common ground on public policy questions today.</p>



<p><em>Samuel J. Abrams is a professor of politics at Sarah Lawrence College and a senior fellow at the American Enterprise Institute.</em></p>



<div class="related-items shortcode "><p><strong>Learn more: </strong><a href="https://www.aei.org/politics-and-public-opinion/finding-third-places-across-america/">Finding Third Places Across America</a> | <a href="https://www.aei.org/politics-and-public-opinion/southern-schools-are-more-ideologically-diverse/">Southern Schools Are More Ideologically Diverse</a> | <a href="https://www.aei.org/politics-and-public-opinion/more-liberal-hypocrisy-on-college-campuses/">More Liberal Hypocrisy on College Campuses</a> | <a href="https://www.aei.org/education/college-students-with-no-faith-are-more-likely-to-want-to-shut-down-speech/">College Students with No Faith Are More Likely to Want to Shut Down Speech</a></p></div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.aei.org/society-and-culture/the-positive-side-of-social-media/">The Positive Side of Social Media</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.aei.org">American Enterprise Institute - AEI</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Election Reform: Is History Repeating? A Q&#038;A with Jack Santucci</title>
		<link>https://www.aei.org/politics-and-public-opinion/election-reform-is-history-repeating-a-qa-with-jack-santucci/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[George Pierson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2022 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Elections]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Politics and Public Opinion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Election reform]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Election reform Q&A]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.aei.org/?p=1008663815</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>With the rise of Americans who are unhappy with the quality of government, calls for election reform have increased. Dr. Jack Santucci answers questions about some commonly proposed reforms and election concerns.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.aei.org/politics-and-public-opinion/election-reform-is-history-repeating-a-qa-with-jack-santucci/">Election Reform: Is History Repeating? A Q&#038;A with Jack Santucci</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.aei.org">American Enterprise Institute - AEI</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" width="1024" height="284" src="https://www.aei.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Kosar-Series-Banner_1-1024x284.jpg?x91208" alt="" class="wp-image-1008601867"/></figure>



<p>Many Americans are unhappy with the quality of governance and the two major parties. Last month, <a href="https://news.gallup.com/poll/15370/party-affiliation.aspx" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">43 percent of Americans</a> surveyed by Gallup declared themselves independents. Unsurprisingly, public dissatisfaction has coincided with calls to reform elections, including nonpartisan primaries, ranked-choice voting, and other systems.</p>



<p>We have been here before. Dr. Jack Santucci’s new book, <a href="https://amzn.to/3swdSWF" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">More Parties or No Parties: The Politics of Electoral Reform in America</a> (Oxford University Press), tells the story of the election reform movement of a century ago. While history is not quite repeating, it may be rhyming. I recently caught up with Jack, an assistant teaching professor of politics at Drexel University, to get his take on the state of play.</p>



<p><strong>Your book begins with a tweet by Mark Cuban: “</strong><a href="https://twitter.com/mcuban/status/1319287043311063041" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">The solution is walking away from parties</a><strong>, expanding ranked-choice voting, hopefully leading to more independent legislators.” This sentiment was in the air a century ago, wasn’t it?</strong></p>



<p>Yes, in the mid-1890s, the Gilded Age party system started falling apart. Some of this turns up as third-party activity, mainly on the left (e.g., People’s Party, flavors of Socialism). Another group of Americans targeted parties <em>in general</em>. These mugwumps tended to speak in terms of anti-corruption and <a href="https://catalog.hathitrust.org/Record/001140455" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">disliked</a> party discipline at all levels of government.</p>



<p><strong>One major reform movement, which your book details, pushed to enact reforms that sound a lot like what gets called “ranked-choice voting” today.</strong></p>



<p>The <a href="https://doi.org/10.17645/pag.v9i2.3955" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">set of reforms</a> we call “ranked-choice voting” (RCV) was known as “preferential voting” or “the preferential ballot.” Preferential voting came in three basic flavors, two of which are still around. One was an attempt to <a href="https://books.google.com/books?id=hftm7pqI9a0C&amp;newbks=1&amp;newbks_redir=0&amp;lpg=PA231&amp;dq=american%2520direct%2520primary%2520alternative%2520vote&amp;pg=PA231#v=onepage&amp;q=american%2520direct%2520primary%2520alternative%2520vote&amp;f=false" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">manage factionalism</a> in party primaries, which also were new at the time. Another was part of a larger effort to restructure city governments, mainly by adopting at-large elections, and allowed the majority faction to win every seat in council. The third attempted to improve on the second by giving seats to one or more numerical minorities. Political scientists call the third version single transferable vote (STV). Reformers now call it proportional RCV.</p>



<p>Overall, RCV was part of the movement for nonpartisan elections. Supporters <a href="https://doi.org/10.1002/ncr.4110030316" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">made</a> <a href="https://doi.org/10.1002/ncr.4110010306" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">arguments</a> we again hear today: more choice for voters, lower barriers to candidates, no gatekeeping by “bosses,” more positive campaigns, cost savings from getting rid of primaries, etc. One advocate even <a href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/1011423" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">wrote</a> that the nonpartisan, ranked-choice ballot “results practically in an educational qualification for voters, and greatly reduces the number of ignorant and corrupt votes.” They felt parties were in the way of “good government,” and the solution was a better algorithm.</p>



<p><strong>Many cities and some states made these changes—61 or more, according to your book. But these reforms got rolled back by politics. What happened?</strong></p>



<p>One way to understand the reform trajectory is in terms of ‘shifting coalitions.’ Party systems are changing all the time, but sometimes the change accelerates. Modern examples might be ‘education polarization’ or recent rates of vote switching.</p>



<p>If reform is about getting (or keeping) control of government, <a href="https://doi.org/10.1007/s10602-021-09326-w" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">a</a> <a href="https://press.uchicago.edu/ucp/books/book/chicago/W/bo11315021.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">simple</a> <a href="https://doi.org/10.1017/CBO9781139814775" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">model</a> implies three reform types: an existing coalition seeks to <em>insulate</em> itself, some coalition-in-waiting seeks to <em>realign</em> the party system, and opposing sides of the aisle seek to <em>polarize</em> politics because some middle is (or has become) unpredictable.</p>



<p>My book focused on the STV cases. Broadly, STV came from a party alignment in which activists disliked parties. Not all reformers felt that way, but in 1913, the mugwumps blocked <a href="https://www.aei.org/politics-and-public-opinion/what-is-the-one-vote-system-a-qa-with-jack-santucci/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">proportional representation based on party lists</a>. Two-dozen cities went on to adopt STV. It did not produce a multiparty system. STV held firm as long as reformers could reinvent the corruption issue and keep it salient. They even formed good government parties to do so, but new issues pulled them apart. Case specifics vary, but one frequent factor was major-party leadership quitting the good-government alliance. STV then got repealed in <em>polarizing</em> fashion.</p>



<p>What about the other types of RCV? In <a href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/42879396" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">party primaries</a>, it went away quietly or got replaced by runoffs. In local government, however, the non-RCV reforms persisted: nonpartisan, at-large elections to small city councils.</p>



<p><strong>Fast-forward to today. Democracies don’t work without parties, right? So, in thinking about election reform should we aim to improve the two party system or go for more parties?</strong></p>



<p>I don’t think we can pull multiparty politics out of a hat—especially the <a href="https://www.newamerica.org/political-reform/reports/political-parties-good-for/the-development-and-decay-of-democracy" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">left-wing sort</a> that <a href="https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/full/10.1177/0010414018762369" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">catalyzed</a> <a href="https://doi.org/10.1017/S1755773919000225" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">reform</a> in other countries. That leaves us with no reform at all, or with the independent-politics reforms we’re again seeing. We should be prepared for those reforms to get repealed and take care to not combine them with features we might regret.</p>



<p>More broadly, there should be less fear of multiparty politics. The old instability arguments <a href="https://www.journals.uchicago.edu/doi/abs/10.1086/708937" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">don’t hold up</a> <a href="https://doi.org/10.12987/9780300210705" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">in most cases</a>, and the factional politics described in my book were anything but stable.</p>



<p><strong>Thank you, Jack.</strong></p>



<div class="related-items shortcode "><p><strong>Learn more: </strong><a href="https://www.aei.org/op-eds/americas-fiscal-stewards-have-left-their-stations/">America’s Fiscal Stewards Have Left Their Stations</a> | <a href="https://www.aei.org/op-eds/to-win-more-seats-in-congress-the-gop-must-rethink-primaries/">To Win More Seats in Congress, the GOP Must Rethink Primaries</a> | <a href="https://www.aei.org/op-eds/alaskas-election-results-do-not-discredit-final-four-voting%ef%bf%bc/">Alaska’s Election Results Do Not Discredit ‘Final Four’ Voting</a> | <a href="https://www.aei.org/uncategorized/whats-going-on-with-ranked-choice-voting-in-utah-a-qa-with-derek-monson/">What’s Going On with Ranked Choice Voting in Utah? A Q&A with Derek Monson</a></p></div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.aei.org/politics-and-public-opinion/election-reform-is-history-repeating-a-qa-with-jack-santucci/">Election Reform: Is History Repeating? A Q&#038;A with Jack Santucci</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.aei.org">American Enterprise Institute - AEI</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>AI Algorithm Bias: What Can Be Done About It?</title>
		<link>https://www.aei.org/technology-and-innovation/ai-algorithms-bias-what-can-be-done-about-it/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Matthew Glavish]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2022 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Technology and Innovation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Automation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bias]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Innovation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[technology]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.aei.org/?p=1008664023</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>As AI algorithms will reflect the biases of the data used to train them, thoughtful modeling practices can help minimize the negative effects of these inherent errors.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.aei.org/technology-and-innovation/ai-algorithms-bias-what-can-be-done-about-it/">AI Algorithm Bias: What Can Be Done About It?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.aei.org">American Enterprise Institute - AEI</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Artificial intelligence (AI) algorithms are a fact of modern digital life. They inhabit the “<a href="https://www.arimetrics.com/en/digital-glossary/black-box-algorithm" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">black boxes</a>” by which <a href="https://www.simplilearn.com/how-netflix-uses-ai-data-science-and-ml-article" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Netflix determines which programs</a> to recommend or—infamously—<a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/kashmirhill/2012/02/16/how-target-figured-out-a-teen-girl-was-pregnant-before-her-father-did/?sh=121d7b066668" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">who</a> should be targeted for baby product advertising. They are also increasingly used to <a href="https://blog.mcquaig.com/ai-recruiting/?creative=630514210501&amp;campaign=%7bcampaign%7d&amp;keyword=&amp;matchtype=&amp;network=g&amp;device=c&amp;gclid=CjwKCAjw2OiaBhBSEiwAh2ZSP2xw8OpAilm-Xfj-zADe4SW9_f-Y5QWcLiBeOYguKzx7VNFCa2wkNBoCiioQAvD_BwE" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">short-list applicants</a> for recruitment decisions, <a href="https://aws.amazon.com/health/machine-learning/?trk=4fc067d2-884f-4438-885e-f8fab01b4adc&amp;sc_channel=ps&amp;s_kwcid=AL!4422!3!608594786365!p!!g!!ai%20and%20medicine&amp;ef_id=CjwKCAjw2OiaBhBSEiwAh2ZSPxn_TIpvsfMVO1vp5_lKsFLSxqCRX6COPXnW9pNvZ8DoP_769mVvpRoCsTEQAvD_BwE:G:s&amp;s_kwcid=AL!4422!3!608594786365!p!!g!!ai%20and%20medicine" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">read medical images</a> and make diagnoses, <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/pulse/prediction-loan-eligibility-using-machine-learning-models-raja-basu/?trk=articles_directory" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">determine applicant eligibility</a> for loans, and <a href="https://www.nzherald.co.nz/nz/nz-developed-ai-can-predict-kids-hospital-risk/UNNQNQJNBTGRN3SBUYGCJS6ZB4/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">identify children “at risk”</a> of hospital admission, thereby facilitating preemptive allocation of social support to prevent future harm and reduce hospitalization costs.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img loading="lazy" width="4743" height="3162" src="https://www.aei.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Artificial-intelligence-generic-stock-photo.jpeg?x91208" alt="" class="wp-image-1008664024"/><figcaption>via Adobe open commons</figcaption></figure>



<p>While the workings within the black box may appear mysterious, it must be remembered that algorithms are just specified processes or designated sets of rules for using inputs to get a defined output. There is nothing particularly special about computers and algorithms. A knitting pattern is an algorithm, just like the checklist that pilots go through before the plane takes off. Algorithms serve to reduce variability in the interpretation and use of inputs when seeking outputs. When precisely followed (i.e., with none of the variation that might occur when humans interpret inputs differently), the outputs will be predictable.</p>



<p>On one hand, algorithms are simply models built using observed data. AI algorithms are an advancement on standard algorithms because specified processes can be used in building and refining the algorithm itself. Input data can be used to “train” the model without human involvement. Hence, models tend to <a href="https://www.15minutebusinessbooks.com/blog/2021/07/19/noise-a-flaw-in-human-judgement-by-daniel-kahneman-olivier-sibony-and-cass-r-sunstein-here-are-my-five-lessons-and-takeaways/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">outperform human decision makers</a> for consistency when it comes to decisions such as the sentences judges impose for crimes (in which it has been shown that the judge’s biases, disposition, or even whether or not they had lunch can lead to inconsistencies between sentences for otherwise identical crimes).</p>



<p>On the other hand, AI algorithms, as deterministic programs, will reflect any errors or inconsistencies inherent in the data or human processes used to specify and train them in the first place. Just as with any other computer program, “garbage in” leads to “garbage out.” The model will be only as good as the data training it. Hence, algorithms trained to <a href="https://singularityhub.com/2019/01/28/can-ai-tell-the-difference-between-a-polar-bear-and-a-can-opener/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">identify polar bears</a> may fail to identify a polar bear in a zoo if all the training examples show polar bears in their natural, snowy, environment. The algorithm doesn’t recognize a polar bear the same way a human would, and the common repeated characteristics in the input data—in this case snow—could cause the algorithm to fail at identifying the polar bear in a snowless zoo.</p>



<p>Similarly, biases, unintended or otherwise, captured in the training data will be <a href="https://www.productivity.govt.nz/futureworknzblog/biased-algorithms-a-good-or-bad-thing/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">reliably replicated</a> in the algorithm-determined models. If, for example, the data for deciding who is eligible for a loan includes biases against, say, women (even if gender isn’t specifically included as a variable in the training data), then the ensuing model will deliver decisions biased against women. But if the decision maker explicitly wants to bias decisions in favor of a specific group, then a model derived from unbiased data will not serve the purpose. As AI algorithms extend the art of decision-making modeling, it thus makes sense to subject their uses to a set of well-tested principles governing the design and use of models.</p>



<p>First, the modeler must understand the context in which the algorithm will be used—that is, have a clear understanding of the problem to which an answer is sought. Models should assist in making decisions, not become rule makers that then indiscriminately determine the future outcome. Though, in some cases, this may be the decision maker’s objective—for example, social media algorithms created for removing terrorist material. </p>



<p>Second, the modeler needs to know the data used to train the algorithm. They should know where and how was the data was collected, what biases may have been present in its collection, and what data is actually being included in the algorithm and what isn’t. This will assist in identifying the model’s limits—what it will be good at doing and where it may fall short. This will then help answer future questions when the algorithm appears to provide anomalous outputs. Understanding the data also minimizes the risk of algorithms and data being used in situations where they are more likely to lead to errors or anomalies.</p>



<p>These precautions help resist the “rush to computerize” urge. Just because the data exists and computer algorithms enable it does not always mean that any one AI model will be good or fit for the purpose to which it is applied. Thoughtful modeling practice will necessarily lead to better AI modeling.</p>


<div class="related-items shortcode "><p><strong>See also:  </strong><a href="https://www.aei.org/technology-and-innovation/scaling-in-ai-and-automation-a-roadmap-for-policymakers/">Harnessing the Best of Automation While Minimizing the Downside Risks</a> | <a href="https://www.aei.org/technology-and-innovation/whats-holding-up-the-autonomous-vehicle-takeover/">What’s Holding Up the Autonomous Vehicle Takeover?</a> | <a href="https://www.aei.org/op-eds/does-artificial-intelligence-really-reduce-jobs-a-historic-perspective/">Does Artificial Intelligence Really Reduce Jobs? A Historic Perspective</a> | <a href="https://www.aei.org/technology-and-innovation/the-challenge-of-encoding-values-in-ai/">The Challenge of Encoding Values in AI</a></p></div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.aei.org/technology-and-innovation/ai-algorithms-bias-what-can-be-done-about-it/">AI Algorithm Bias: What Can Be Done About It?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.aei.org">American Enterprise Institute - AEI</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Some Context Behind Coming Calls for more Federal Stimulus</title>
		<link>https://www.aei.org/poverty-studies/some-context-behind-coming-calls-for-more-federal-stimulus/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[George Pierson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2022 18:38:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Poverty Studies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[benefits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[inflation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stimulus]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.aei.org/?p=1008663978</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>As fears of recession grow, some officials in Washington are making preparations for a new round of federal stimulus spending. Important context indicates specific relief policies in case of a recession.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.aei.org/poverty-studies/some-context-behind-coming-calls-for-more-federal-stimulus/">Some Context Behind Coming Calls for more Federal Stimulus</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.aei.org">American Enterprise Institute - AEI</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Far from the glare of the campaign stage, a subtle but distinct transition is going on in how Washington thinks about the economy. Contrary to President Joe Biden’s <a href="https://nypost.com/2022/10/16/joe-biden-insists-us-economy-is-strong-as-hell-as-he-munches-an-ice-cream-" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">assertion</a> that the US economy is “strong as hell,” a recent <em>Washington Post</em> <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/us-policy/2022/10/20/recession-inflation-white-house-fed/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">article</a> describes how, “as recession fears rise,” unnamed White House and congressional officials are making plans for a new round of federal stimulus spending:</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>Officials at the White House and the Federal Reserve say that they continue to believe a recession can be avoided and that they remain focused on fighting inflation, which is rising at rates not seen in four decades. But with Wall Street trembling, and many private forecasters<a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2022-10-17/forecast-for-us-recession-within-year-hits-100-in-blow-to-biden#xj4y7vzkg" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"> warning that recession is likely</a>, preliminary talks about policy options are underway around town.</p><p>On Capitol Hill, congressional officials have begun discussing the challenge of intervening to alleviate the pain of a recession in ways that do not exacerbate inflation. At the White House, aides have informally begun weighing hypothetical options, such as unemployment benefits and food stamp assistance.</p></blockquote>



<p>A recent <em>Politico</em> article <a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2022/10/24/biden-finances-liz-truss-recession-00063012" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">details</a> the constraints that high inflation and debt impose on those policy ambitions:</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>During recent downturns, Congress helped cushion the blow by flooding the economy with stimulus checks and other relief. But doing that now while inflation is raging — even if it were politically possible — would pile on even more debt and could rattle investors wary of policies that could stoke higher prices. That’s a lesson that outgoing British Prime Minister Liz Truss learned the hard way.</p><p>“Any more big additions to the deficit are really risky,” said Jason Furman, who served as chairman of the Council of Economic Advisers under President Barack Obama.</p></blockquote>



<p>That informs what policymakers shouldn’t do, such as reviving <a href="https://www.aei.org/poverty-studies/headed-for-900-billion-in-unemployment-benefits/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">extraordinarily costly</a> pandemic benefit programs, much less making them permanent, as some have <a href="https://www.aei.org/op-eds/beware-washingtons-new-plan-for-permanent-pandemic-style-stimulus/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">proposed</a>. Those temporary programs offered <a href="https://www.aei.org/research-products/report/unprecedented-a-brief-review-of-the-extraordinary-unemployment-benefit-response-to-the-coronavirus-crisis/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">unprecedented</a> unemployment benefits <a href="https://www.aei.org/op-eds/if-congress-extends-the-600-unemployment-bonus-now-it-may-never-go-away/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">exceeding former paychecks</a> for many, including <a href="https://www.aei.org/op-eds/claiming-benefits-like-legislating-benefit-expansions-is-a-learned-behavior/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">millions</a> who never paid into the unemployment insurance system. They also offered lengthy <a href="https://www.aei.org/research-products/report/extended-a-review-of-the-current-and-proposed-duration-of-pandemic-unemployment-benefits/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">extended benefits</a> even in states with <a href="https://www.aei.org/poverty-studies/bidens-american-rescue-plan-would-pay-more-federal-benefits-in-low-unemployment-states-than-ever-before/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">low unemployment rates</a>, and were subject to <a href="https://www.aei.org/research-products/testimony/lessons-from-the-unprecedented-fraud-and-abuse-of-the-unemployment-benefits-system-during-the-pandemic/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">staggering fraud and abuse</a>. In the end, half of the states decided that <a href="https://www.aei.org/op-eds/a-record-benefits-cliff-is-coming-thanks-to-democrats-american-rescue-plan/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">ending the programs</a> was better than letting them continue.</p>



<p>Policymakers should also recognize that, even without a new federal stimulus law, existing <a href="https://www.cbo.gov/system/files/2022-10/58495-automatic-stabilizers.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">automatic stabilizer</a> programs will provide growing relief if more lose their jobs or otherwise see their incomes shrink.</p>



<p>Laid-off workers will access up to 26 weeks of state unemployment checks, and tens of millions of low-income households will collect federal food stamp benefits, which remain <a href="https://www.fns.usda.gov/snap/covid-19-emergency-allotments-guidance" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">enlarged in many states</a> today. Those open-ended entitlements are always available to all who qualify. Additional assistance, and federal funds, also will be available to the long-term unemployed where finding new work is especially difficult, as reflected by their state’s elevated unemployment rate. In those places, extended benefit checks—lasting up to 20 extra weeks, or over 10 months when combined with state unemployment checks—are payable under the current law <a href="https://www.aei.org/poverty-studies/why-even-permanent-benefit-expansions-are-never-enough/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Extended Benefits (EB) program</a>.</p>



<p>Since its creation in 1970, the EB program has expected states to pay for half of program costs, with <a href="https://www.aei.org/poverty-studies/why-even-permanent-benefit-expansions-are-never-enough/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">two exceptions</a>—during the Great Recession and the pandemic, when its benefits were fully federally funded as part of costly stimulus legislation. If the US average unemployment rate stays below “5 or 6 percent” as analysts <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/us-policy/2022/10/20/recession-inflation-white-house-fed/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">cited</a> by the <em>Washington Post</em> expect, then unemployment may remain below 5 or even 4 percent in some states, balancing others where unemployment might reach 7 percent or more. The EB program offers additional assistance to the long-term unemployed in the latter states, but not the former, with eligible states contributing half of benefit costs. That’s more than appropriate, especially when states have been so flush with federal cash that some created new unemployment benefits for those <a href="https://www.aei.org/poverty-studies/flush-with-federal-stimulus-cash-new-york-creates-2-billion-fund-for-those-living-in-the-us-illegally/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">not authorized to work in the US</a> or sent out <a href="https://www.forbes.com/advisor/personal-finance/california-gas-rebate-stimulus-check/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">waves</a> <a href="https://www.kiplinger.com/taxes/new-york-stimulus-checks" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">of</a> <a href="https://wgntv.com/news/wgn-news-now/up-to-700-for-il-residents-how-to-get-your-tax-rebate-check/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">stimulus</a> checks in recent weeks.</p>



<p>Lawmakers should start any plans for relief in a coming recession by letting the EB program work as current law intends, instead of having the federal government again take on all responsibility for program benefits as it has in the past two recessions. Doing so will better target additional help where most needed, reduce the potential for <a href="https://www.aei.org/poverty-studies/federal-lawmakers-propose-paying-states-to-recover-unemployment-fraud/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">fraud and abuse</a>, and mitigate further “really risky” <a href="https://www.aei.org/poverty-studies/why-even-permanent-benefit-expansions-are-never-enough/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">big additions</a> to the federal deficit.</p>



<div class="related-items shortcode "><p><strong>Learn more: </strong><a href="https://www.aei.org/op-eds/will-big-blue-states-request-loan-forgiveness-too/">Will Big Blue States Request Loan Forgiveness, Too?</a> | <a href="https://www.aei.org/poverty-studies/new-york-times-inflation-has-made-large-stimulus-checks-too-politically-expensive-to-discuss/">New York Times: Inflation Has Made Large Stimulus Checks Too Politically Expensive to Discuss</a> | <a href="https://www.aei.org/poverty-studies/the-pandemic-is-over-but-the-public-health-emergency-continues-along-with-calls-for-more-federal-benefits-tied-to-it/">The Pandemic Is Over, but the Public Health Emergency Continues—Along with Calls for More Federal Benefits Tied to It</a> | <a href="https://www.aei.org/poverty-studies/why-even-permanent-benefit-expansions-are-never-enough/">Why Even Permanent Benefit Expansions Are Never Enough</a></p></div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.aei.org/poverty-studies/some-context-behind-coming-calls-for-more-federal-stimulus/">Some Context Behind Coming Calls for more Federal Stimulus</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.aei.org">American Enterprise Institute - AEI</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>All Tricks, No Treats When It Comes to Cyber Scams</title>
		<link>https://www.aei.org/technology-and-innovation/all-tricks-no-treats-when-it-comes-to-cyber-scams/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Matthew Glavish]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2022 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Technology and Innovation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[consumers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cybersecurity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Federal Trade Commission (FTC)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fraud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Smartphones]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.aei.org/?p=1008663844</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The prevalence of phishing and other online scams highlights the importance of implementing frontline cybersecurity measures and the need for consumers to be more cognizant of cyber threats to our digital world.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.aei.org/technology-and-innovation/all-tricks-no-treats-when-it-comes-to-cyber-scams/">All Tricks, No Treats When It Comes to Cyber Scams</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.aei.org">American Enterprise Institute - AEI</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Has “Amazon” been trying to send you gift cards via text message lately? Funny, me too!</p>



<p>This trick is known as &#8220;<a href="https://us.norton.com/blog/emerging-threats/smishing" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">smishing</a>,&#8221; a form of phishing done via text messaging. It’s also referred to as Short Message Service or SMS phishing. Traditional <a href="https://consumer.ftc.gov/articles/how-recognize-and-avoid-phishing-scams" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">phishing</a> is when a cybercriminal masquerading as a known trusted entity, usually a well-established shopping site or a well-known consumer website, sends an unsolicited message (usually via email) to a user.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img loading="lazy" width="1169" height="1306" src="https://www.aei.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Scammers-scammers-scammer.jpg?x91208" alt="" class="wp-image-1008663817"/><figcaption>An example of a &#8220;smishing&#8221; message sent to an AEI staff member.</figcaption></figure>



<p>If the user clicks the fake link, they are redirected to a phony website. Here, two criminal acts usually happen. The first is deceiving the user to divulge sensitive personal information, such as personally identifiable information (passwords, usernames, etc.), credit card information, or personal finance details. The second occurs in the background when the user opens the link. These fake websites are often programmed to download malicious malware onto the user&#8217;s mobile device or computer.</p>



<p>It&#8217;s hard to believe that these scams work, but they do. A consumer is more <a href="https://www.business2community.com/infographics/text-marketing-vs-email-marketing-one-packs-bigger-punch-infographic-01249186#HlYebylMl1Z5Uwke.97" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">apt</a> to open a text message than an email in today’s market. While the trustworthiness of a spontaneous text message has gone down, it’s still an effective way of reaching a target audience for both businesses and scammers. Unfortunately, today’s inundation of text scams shows how easily users are still duped into getting defrauded. One reason is that criminals play on a user&#8217;s emotions by suggesting there is a tight time frame to claim a prize, the user is under investigation by law enforcement, or the user’s banking information has been compromised.</p>



<p>Purporting to be <a href="https://www.infosecurity-magazine.com/news/amazon-customers-receive-smishing/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Amazon</a> has been one of these con artists’ most prominent backstories for smishing lately. A text scam sends a link to an inauthentic replica of Amazon’s website for the user to claim a fake Amazon gift card. Once the user interacts on the webpage to access the cash value, smishers deploy various malware tools onto their device.</p>



<p>To deter consumers from participating in fraudulent activity, Amazon, like many others, have been proactive about informing consumers about this potential activity and how these scams work. Many federal authorities and consumer groups track these scams and share information with potential victims and the broader public. The Federal Trade Commission issued a consumer <a href="https://consumer.ftc.gov/consumer-alerts/2022/08/dont-click-random-text-its-scam" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">alert</a> recently on smishing scams, noting that scammers have been impersonating Costco, Home Depot, and the US Postal System. FedEx, Netflix, and UPS are also being used as <a href="https://gizmodo.com/smishing-scams-are-on-the-rise-1848819274" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">popular</a> cover stories. And with the Biden administration’s recent student loan debt relief plan, <a href="https://www.ic3.gov/Media/Y2022/PSA221018" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">scams</a> posing as the entry point to the program with the intent of extracting applicants’ personal financial information are on the rise. The <a href="https://www.fbi.gov/how-we-can-help-you/safety-resources/scams-and-safety/common-scams-and-crimes/spoofing-and-phishing" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">FBI</a> also warns citizens not to send payments or interact with organizations urging and seeking immediate monetary support.</p>



<p>Despite the uptick in smishing and other cyber-threats, there are remedies—some easier to implement than others. For starters, using strong passwords and two-factor authentication, actively updating software from known sources, and being cognizant of phishing links are the fundamentals of frontline cybersecurity protection. Every time one of these scammers has success, there are more compromised devices on our networks spreading more malware to more users.</p>



<p>However, these frontline fundamentals are simply not enough. We need a more holistic cybersecurity approach to better manage the evolution and protection of our great digital economy and its everyday users. Because devices typically conform to “<a href="https://www.lifewire.com/plug-and-play-4152995" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">plug and play</a>”—a standard in which software and hardware companies design things in a way that the user doesn’t need to reconfigure, adjust, or understand their devices’ inner mechanisms for them to work as intended—it can be easy to forget that you still need to be vigilant and have security front of mind when using your devices.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As we near the end of <a href="https://www.cisa.gov/cybersecurity-awareness-month" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Cybersecurity Awareness Month</a>, this post serves as a reminder to be a conscious consumer and use devices provided by technology companies with a level of personal responsibility. The devices and applications these companies produce allow us to have a robust digital economy that enables society to live with better communication, conduct business quicker, and enjoy life online. As technology, and especially mobile devices, continues to be a powerful economic tool that allows us to engage with each other, stay informed, and organize our lives, we need to educate each other on needing to think about security and protecting our data while we interact in our digital world.</p>


<div class="related-items shortcode "><p><strong>See also:  </strong><a href="https://www.aei.org/technology-and-innovation/this-valentines-day-protect-yourself-from-dating-app-scams/">This Valentine’s Day, Protect Yourself from Dating App Scams</a> | <a href="https://www.aei.org/op-eds/mobile-security-risks-are-at-an-all-time-high/">Mobile Security Risks Are at an All-Time High.</a> | <a href="https://www.aei.org/technology-and-innovation/building-a-trusted-future-online-highlights-from-my-conversation-with-adam-golodner/">Building a "Trusted Future" Online: Highlights from My Conversation with Adam Golodner</a> | <a href="https://www.aei.org/technology-and-innovation/cybersecurity-in-agriculture-dont-forget-about-mobile/">Cybersecurity in Agriculture: Don’t Forget About Mobile</a></p></div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.aei.org/technology-and-innovation/all-tricks-no-treats-when-it-comes-to-cyber-scams/">All Tricks, No Treats When It Comes to Cyber Scams</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.aei.org">American Enterprise Institute - AEI</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Passing of Our Friend and Colleague Bob Helms</title>
		<link>https://www.aei.org/health-care/the-passing-of-our-friend-and-colleague-bob-helms/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Josiah Johnson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2022 22:19:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Health Care]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.aei.org/?p=1008663875</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The AEI community mourns the passing of our colleague and friend Robert B. Helms.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.aei.org/health-care/the-passing-of-our-friend-and-colleague-bob-helms/">The Passing of Our Friend and Colleague Bob Helms</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.aei.org">American Enterprise Institute - AEI</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The AEI community mourns the passing of our colleague and friend Robert B. Helms. Bob passed away on Thursday afternoon after a long fight with cancer.</p>



<p>Bob became AEI’s director of health policy studies in 1974. In that role, he pioneered AEI’s research on health policy and related areas. Specifically, Bob conducted and supervised influential research on pharmaceutical economics and regulation, health care financing, hospital regulation, medical malpractice issues, and other key policy issues. Under Bob’s leadership, AEI published studies by the top experts in the field, including Mark Pauly, Patricia Danzon, Clark Havighurst, Henry Grabowski, Roger Feldman, Brian Dowd, and Gail Wilensky. Bob’s legacy at AEI also includes the many distinguished health scholars in residence who joined AEI in part thanks to Bob’s reputation and the quality and impact of his work.</p>



<p>Outside AEI, Bob had a distinguished career. He took a leave of absence from AEI in 1981 to become deputy assistant secretary for planning and evaluation in the US Department of Health and Human Services (HHS). He was confirmed as the assistant secretary in 1984 and served in that position until 1989. He was executive director of the American Pharmaceutical Institute in 1989 and 1990 before returning to AEI. While an AEI scholar, Bob was named to the HHS Medicaid Commission in 2005–06, where he argued for financing reforms to put Medicaid on a more stable fiscal path.</p>



<p>Although the list of Bob Helms’s accomplishments is long, it does not fully capture his contribution to health policy and to his colleagues—at AEI and elsewhere. He was a kind and gentle person and a leader in every sense of the term. He will be greatly missed.</p>



<p></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.aei.org/health-care/the-passing-of-our-friend-and-colleague-bob-helms/">The Passing of Our Friend and Colleague Bob Helms</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.aei.org">American Enterprise Institute - AEI</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Elections and Demography: Undecideds Break for Republicans</title>
		<link>https://www.aei.org/politics-and-public-opinion/elections-and-demography-undecideds-break-for-republicans/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[George Pierson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2022 18:53:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Politics and Public Opinion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Polls]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Elections]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Midterm elections]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.aei.org/?p=1008663822</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>With Republicans taking the lead in the generic ballot for the first time in months, Democrats fear greater-than-expected losses with undecideds continuing to break for Republicans in the latest polling.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.aei.org/politics-and-public-opinion/elections-and-demography-undecideds-break-for-republicans/">Elections and Demography: Undecideds Break for Republicans</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.aei.org">American Enterprise Institute - AEI</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img loading="lazy" width="2554" height="546" src="https://www.aei.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/AEI-Elections-Demography-banner.jpg?x91208" alt="" class="wp-image-1008662428"/></figure>



<p>This is the penultimate issue of an AEIdeas series that focuses on the 2022 elections and demographic voting patterns. During the 2022 campaign, we have looked weekly at demographic subgroup averages from a month of polls.</p>



<p>With less than two weeks to go until Election Day, Republicans continue to gain in the polls. For the first time since this series began, Republicans lead on the generic ballot, picking up almost a full point since our last snapshot. A fundamental midterm trend is taking hold: undecided voters breaking against the party in power. The recent swing has almost entirely consisted of a rise in Republican vote share, rather than a dip in Democratic vote share. Since August, Democrats have remained stuck around 45 percent, while in recent weeks the Republican share has shot up from 43 percent to 46 percent. As the momentum has swung towards the GOP, the number of undecideds has dropped considerably. If the remaining undecided voters continue to break hard to the right, Democrats may encounter worse losses than anticipated. The Democratic vote share in generic ballot averages will be a prime indicator in the home stretch.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full"><img loading="lazy" width="677" height="755" src="https://www.aei.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/image-3.png?x91208" alt="" class="wp-image-1008663836"/></figure></div>


<p><strong>Key Findings</strong></p>



<ul><li>Though up slightly from last week, Democrats still hold just a 17.5-point advantage with Hispanic voters. Since the beginning of October—just as Republicans began moving up in the polls—the Democratic advantage among Hispanics has been stuck below 20 points. If the final margin is reflective of our averages, it would represent yet another sizeable drop in Hispanic Democratic support.</li><li>Democratic hopes of a surge in support among women appear to have fallen flat. The recent <a href="https://www.monmouth.edu/polling-institute/reports/monmouthpoll_us_102022/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Monmouth poll</a> has Republicans ahead by a point among women. A new <a href="https://emersoncollegepolling.com/national-poll-biden-approval-drops-as-republicans-congressional-control-chances-improve/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Emerson poll</a> finds Democrats up just three points with women.</li><li>Abortion continues to recede as one of the most important issues in the midterms. Monmouth finds abortion is “extremely important” to 30 percent of voters—actually a slight decline from their September poll. Inflation, voting, crime, immigration, and jobs all ranked as more important to the American electorate. In blue states, many of which have enacted abortion protections, reproductive rights may prove far less salient issue than Democrats hope.</li><li>The latest <a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/meet-the-press/first-read/anger-minds-nbc-news-poll-finds-sky-high-interest-polarization-ahead-m-rcna53512" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">NBC News poll</a> has more bad news for Democrats. The issue preferences of persuadable and undecided voters closely align with Republican voters. For example, 43 percent of Democrats list “threats to democracy” as a top-two issue, but only 17 percent of undecided voters do the same.</li><li>Bill McInturff of Public Opinion Strategies provides historical analysis of the “Direction of Country” and “Direction of Economy” polling questions, placing the 2022 midterm fundamentals in line with the wave years of 1994, 2006, 2010, and 2018, particularly when combined with President Joe Biden’s underwater approval rating. While wrong track almost always wins a majority, the right track/wrong track difference is the largest since NBC began asking the question.</li><li>If our averages are filtered to include only live-caller polls—generally considered the gold standard of polling—the Republican lead jumps up another point. A similar increase occurs when only likely voter polls are included. Both are indications that our cumulative average may be slightly understating the Republican generic ballot lead.</li></ul>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full"><img loading="lazy" width="813" height="834" src="https://www.aei.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/image-4.png?x91208" alt="" class="wp-image-1008663839"/></figure></div>


<p><em>Previous election data is drawn from </em><a href="https://catalist.us/wh-national/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><em>Catalist crosstab estimates</em></a><em>. Catalist is a Democratic data analytics organization.</em></p>



<p>*<em>How we did this: This month-long average is a compilation of online and live-caller polls that release crosstabs. Internal and explicitly partisan polls are excluded. This edition averages polls from Monmouth University, Grinnell College/Selzer &amp; Company, Washington Post/ABC News, Economist/YouGov, Morning Consult/Politico, Harvard/Harris, CBS News, Emerson, Yahoo News, Rasmussen, Echelon Insights, Marist College/NPR/PBS NewsHour, New York Times/Siena College, and Fox News.</em></p>



<div class="related-items shortcode "><p><strong>Learn more: </strong><a href="https://www.aei.org/politics-and-public-opinion/elections-and-demography-democrats-lose-ground-need-strong-turnout/">Elections and Demography: Democrats Lose Ground, Need Strong Turnout</a> | <a href="https://www.aei.org/politics-and-public-opinion/elections/elections-and-demography-one-month-to-go/">Elections and Demography: One Month to Go</a> | <a href="https://www.aei.org/politics-and-public-opinion/elections-and-demography-signs-of-a-tightening-race/">Elections and Demography: Signs of a Tightening Race</a> | <a href="https://www.aei.org/politics-and-public-opinion/elections-and-demography-who-are-the-likely-voters/">Elections and Demography: Who Are the Likely Voters?</a></p></div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.aei.org/politics-and-public-opinion/elections-and-demography-undecideds-break-for-republicans/">Elections and Demography: Undecideds Break for Republicans</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.aei.org">American Enterprise Institute - AEI</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Saved by the Cell: How South Africa Is Bridging the Digital Divide</title>
		<link>https://www.aei.org/technology-and-innovation/saved-by-the-cell-how-south-africa-is-bridging-the-digital-divide/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Matthew Glavish]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2022 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Technology and Innovation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Telecommunications]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[broadband]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[consumers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[internet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Regulation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[South Africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[subsidies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Telecommunications regulatory policy]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.aei.org/?p=1008663759</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>As the United States contemplates the distribution of $65 billion of federal funding to address broadband access and usage divides, let’s take some time to consider what is occurring in South Africa to address the same questions and how that might inform US policy and regulation. South Africa demonstrates some of the broadest economic, social, [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.aei.org/technology-and-innovation/saved-by-the-cell-how-south-africa-is-bridging-the-digital-divide/">Saved by the Cell: How South Africa Is Bridging the Digital Divide</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.aei.org">American Enterprise Institute - AEI</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>As the United States contemplates the <a href="https://www.congress.gov/bill/117th-congress/house-bill/3684/text" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">distribution</a> of $65 billion of federal funding to address broadband access and usage divides, let’s take some time to consider what is occurring in South Africa to address the same questions and how that might inform US policy and regulation.</p>



<p>South Africa demonstrates some of the broadest economic, social, and broadband divides in the world. The millions living in cosmopolitan cities such as Cape Town, Johannesburg, and Pretoria lead very different lives than those living in abject poverty in urban townships like Khayelitsha and rural enclaves like Phuthaditjhaba or Bushbuckridge. Yet this diversity has proved a boon for mobile-phone product variety.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img loading="lazy" width="4608" height="3456" src="https://www.aei.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Cellphone-Bill-Stock-Photo.jpeg?x91208" alt="" class="wp-image-1008663760"/><figcaption>via Adobe open commons</figcaption></figure>



<p>South Africa is a world leader in the <a href="https://www.statista.com/statistics/1074422/prepaid-vs-post-paid-mobile-cellular-voice-subscriptions-in-south-africa/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">provision of prepaid cellular subscriptions</a>—having first brought them to market before other countries. These connections amounted in 2021 to over 84 percent of more <a href="https://prepaid-data-sim-card.fandom.com/wiki/South_Africa" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">than 90 million connections</a>. Prepaid subscriptions offer significant flexibility for consumers with constrained and irregular incomes—in the same way as coin-in-the-slot electricity meters were commonly used in low-income areas in the pre-Thatcher United Kingdom. Freedom from restrictive contract terms allows consumers to purchase voice minutes and data when needed and without penalty. </p>



<p>Furthermore, data is sold by the three main network operators in a huge variety of bundles, both in terms of volume and time. Packages range from 25 megabytes to 100 gigabytes and beyond. Data can be bought for use within the hour, one day (up to midnight), week, month, 90 days, six months, a year, or even longer. At least one operator offers night packages, valid from 1:00–7:00 a.m., at significant discounts compared to all-day data, allowing consumers to take advantage of otherwise idle off-peak capacity. Unused data can often be rolled over or passed to another account on the same network. To prevent unexpected billing, network operators are required to send notices to customers as the data depletes and must obtain an opt-in from subscribers to continue charging for the services. Out-of-bundle fees cannot be charged without first obtaining consent from the subscriber.</p>



<p>This vast range of products and consumer protection measures overseen by the <a href="https://www.icasa.org.za/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Independent Communications Authority of South Africa</a> (ICASA) has enabled all South African consumers—especially those in the most precarious financial positions—to participate as best they can in the digital economy. This does not mean that divides don’t exist; operators have just made the threshold for participation much lower. And while there may still be <a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/abs/pii/S0308596122000209" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">concerns</a> about South Africa’s price levels, ICASA has endeavored to provide a set of rules that provide certainty and confidence for consumers to purchase services as needed. </p>



<p>These features of the South African cellular market provide food for thought for United States policymakers and regulators addressing the connectivity of low-income consumers in urban environments. Rather than focusing on the provision of subsidized connections with tightly prescribed, postpaid provisions, perhaps there is some benefit in relaxing these minimum provisions and allowing creative prepaid bundles to emerge. Providing consumers with prepaid vouchers to buy the services that best meet their needs will encourage this form of product innovation by operators.</p>



<p>However, as we testified recently in a <a href="https://www.icasa.org.za/legislation-and-regulations/regulations-underway/end-user-and-subscriber-service-charter-amendment-regulations" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">hearing</a> at ICASA, there may be one more consumer protection measure for consideration that will enhance consumer welfare, especially for consumers with low data volume usage. Typically, operators record and bill for data usage in <a href="https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/full/10.1177/1094670519895581" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">predetermined increments</a>, say 10 or 100 kilobytes (KB). Consumers using 51 KB and 58 KB will both be debited for using 60 KB. This is similar to the practice previously observed in voice calls, where calls were billed in increments of two minutes. Such practices lead to systematic overbilling of consumers—something ill afforded by the most cost-conscious consumers. For consumers accessing data for small, short bursts of activity, these overcharges can potentially mount up, leading to higher effective charges than for consumers who consume data in larger chunks.</p>



<p>In the late 2000s, regulators placed considerable <a href="https://www.icasa.org.za/legislation-and-regulations/regulations-underway/end-user-and-subscriber-service-charter-amendment-regulations" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">pressure</a> on operators to replace the two-minute billing increment with one-minute increments, reflecting the number of seconds a call used. Nowadays, call times are recorded sometimes even to fractions of a second for decrements from bundle allowances. But what is occurring with data? <a href="https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/full/10.1177/1094670519895581" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Evidence</a> from Germany suggests that the minimum billing increment is increasing, with the share of operators using a 100 KB minimum growing from 27 percent to 36 percent between 2008 and 2014. This is likely leading to significant overbilling for low-volume consumers.</p>



<p>We suggest that all telecommunications regulators—in both developed and developing countries—consider the extent to which data usage schedules are influencing billing in their jurisdictions. The United States should also consider enabling more options when it comes to cell phones and mobile data in its broadband plans. Not doing so is likely harming those least able to afford data in the first place and only widens the divide.</p>


<div class="related-items shortcode "><p><strong>See also:  </strong><a href="https://www.aei.org/technology-and-innovation/will-banning-data-caps-be-a-win-for-us-consumers/">Will Banning “Data Caps” Be a Win for US Consumers?</a> | <a href="https://www.aei.org/technology-and-innovation/the-innovation-implications-of-mandated-data-siloing-and-sharing/">The Innovation Implications of Mandated Data Siloing and Sharing</a> | <a href="https://www.aei.org/technology-and-innovation/usage-based-broadband-tariffs-closing-digital-divides-with-pricing-competition/">Usage-based Broadband Tariffs: Closing Digital Divides with Pricing Competition</a> | <a href="https://www.aei.org/technology-and-innovation/dont-call-them-data-caps-a-deep-dive-on-usage-based-broadband-pricing/">Don’t Call Them Data Caps: A Deep Dive on Usage-based Broadband Pricing</a></p></div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.aei.org/technology-and-innovation/saved-by-the-cell-how-south-africa-is-bridging-the-digital-divide/">Saved by the Cell: How South Africa Is Bridging the Digital Divide</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.aei.org">American Enterprise Institute - AEI</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>When It Comes to Reducing Global Poverty, Bono Is Right and the Anti-Capitalists Are Wrong</title>
		<link>https://www.aei.org/economics/when-it-comes-to-reducing-global-poverty-bono-is-right-and-the-anti-capitalists-are-wrong/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Josiah Johnson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 14:00:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Economic Fluctuations and Growth]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Economics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pethokoukis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Capitalism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Globalization]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Poverty]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.aei.org/?p=1008663734</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Maybe you find U2 lead singer Bono to be a bit much, even for a rock star. That's fine, but to dislike Bono for his views on the best way to ameliorate global poverty is to run afoul of an objective truth: capitalist trade and globalization are the keys to lifting billions out of poverty.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.aei.org/economics/when-it-comes-to-reducing-global-poverty-bono-is-right-and-the-anti-capitalists-are-wrong/">When It Comes to Reducing Global Poverty, Bono Is Right and the Anti-Capitalists Are Wrong</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.aei.org">American Enterprise Institute - AEI</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The rock group U2 has sold some 175 million records globally, but I get that they might not be everybody’s cup of Irish tea. Maybe you don’t like their post-punk, anthemic music style. Maybe you think too many of their songs sound the same. Maybe you find lead singer Bono to be a bit much, even for a rock star. Whatever, one’s take in music is subjective. But to dislike Bono for his views on the best way to ameliorate global poverty is to run afoul of an objective truth and provable facts. The anti-capitalists on social media are all in a tizzy over these comments in a new <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/interactive/2022/10/24/magazine/bono-interview.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">interview </a>with the <em>New York Times</em>:</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>There’s a funny moment when you realize that as an activist: The off-ramp out of extreme poverty is, ugh, commerce, it’s entrepreneurial capitalism. I spend a lot of time in countries all over Africa, and they’re like, “Eh, we wouldn’t mind a little more globalization actually. I would point out that there has been a lot of progress over the years.” . . .&nbsp;Capitalism is a wild beast. We need to tame it. But globalization has brought more people out of poverty than any other -ism. If somebody comes to me with a better idea, I’ll sign up. I didn’t grow up to like the idea that we’ve made heroes out of businesspeople, but if you’re bringing jobs to a community and treating people well, then you are a hero.</p></blockquote>



<p>This should be an uncontroversial view, and it is among most economists. As the World Bank <a href="https://blogs.worldbank.org/developmenttalk/trade-has-been-global-force-less-poverty-and-higher-incomes" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">noted</a> in 2017,&nbsp;“Trade and global integration have raised incomes across the world, while dramatically cutting poverty and global inequality.” And now this beautiful chart from Our World In Data:</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/XBqz4vQThYdMKMr48DtGaLMKDCR7zBZFOpFHinYhcTiW66C4rR076iinlsQQJC4ClaKUssMXllpNajah-qqf3ZRk8X7iPUAi0QH8JA3I5O8jquAxzTNZDNoTIT1vxb0TBYEvBUQEw8zzgItLd2dvCZLIkniRUw_WKjwy5cmHcAlmAbqu4vLykrmEww" alt=""/></figure>



<p>I love this bit from economist Deirdre McCloskey in<em> </em><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Bourgeois-Dignity-Economics-Explain-Modern/dp/0226556654/ref=tmm_hrd_swatch_0?_encoding=UTF8&amp;qid=&amp;sr="><em>Bourgeois Dignity: Why Economics Can&#8217;t Explain the Modern World</em></a>:</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>Innovation backed by liberal economic ideas has made billions of poor people pretty well off, without hurting other people.&nbsp;By now the pretty good innovation has helped quite a few people even in China and India. . . . The Big Economic Story of our own times is that the Chinese in 1978 and then the Indians in 1991 adopted opted liberal ideas in the economy, and came to attribute a dignity and a liberty to the bourgeoisie formerly denied. And then China and India exploded in economic growth. The important moral, therefore, is that in achieving a pretty good life for the mass of humankind, and a chance at a fully human existence, ideas have mattered more than the usual material causes. As the economic historian Joel Mokyr put it recently in the opening sentence of one of his luminous books, &#8220;Economic change in all periods depends, more than most economists think, on what people believe.&#8221;5 The Big Story of the past two hundred years is the innovation after 1700 or 1800 around the North Sea, and recently in once poor places like Taiwan or Ireland, and most noticeably now in the world&#8217;s biggest tyranny and the world&#8217;s biggest democracy. It has given many formerly poor and ignorant people the scope to flourish. And contrary to the usual declarations of the economists since Adam Smith or Karl Marx, the Biggest Economic Story was not caused by trade or investment or exploitation. It was caused by ideas.</p></blockquote>



<p>One could be deliberately obtuse and ignore these facts, of course. But polling shows that many people <a href="https://www.aei.org/economics/extreme-poverty-declining-americans-have-no-idea/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">really don’t know</a> about both the decline in global poverty and why it happened. Then again, it’s been happening for decades. So everybody probably should know by this time. Bono obviously does. And so should you.</p>



<div class="related-items shortcode "><p><strong>Learn more: </strong><a href="https://www.aei.org/economics/some-thoughts-on-moving-beyond-neoliberal-globalization/">Some Thoughts on Moving Beyond "Neoliberal Globalization"</a> | <a href="https://www.aei.org/economics/a-few-thoughts-about-capitalism-and-inequality/"><strong>A Few Thoughts About Capitalism and Inequality&nbsp;</strong></a> | <a href="https://www.aei.org/pethokoukis/more-on-the-trade-offs-of-rejecting-nuclear-energy/">More on the Trade-Offs of Rejecting Nuclear Energy</a> | <a href="https://www.aei.org/economics/housing-prices-and-elections/">Housing Prices and Elections</a></p></div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.aei.org/economics/when-it-comes-to-reducing-global-poverty-bono-is-right-and-the-anti-capitalists-are-wrong/">When It Comes to Reducing Global Poverty, Bono Is Right and the Anti-Capitalists Are Wrong</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.aei.org">American Enterprise Institute - AEI</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Federal Regulators Should Approve Election Prediction Markets</title>
		<link>https://www.aei.org/technology-and-innovation/prediction-markets-are-facing-a-key-regulatory-test/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Matthew Glavish]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Technology and Innovation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Elections]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Innovation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[markets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Midterm elections]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Public opinion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Stock market]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.aei.org/?p=1008663640</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Election prediction markets, if allowed, offer a financial tech solution that could clear up much of the uncertainty surrounding the election cycle for the budgets of both businesses and bureaucracies. </p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.aei.org/technology-and-innovation/prediction-markets-are-facing-a-key-regulatory-test/">Federal Regulators Should Approve Election Prediction Markets</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.aei.org">American Enterprise Institute - AEI</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The US Commodity Futures Trading Commission (CFTC) continues to wrestle with how to best regulate prediction markets. The commission is expected to make a decision as soon as this week on whether the startup <a href="https://kalshi.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Kalshi</a> can offer a market on the outcome of the upcoming midterms. Approving Kalshi’s submission would be a step in the right direction for the commission and promotes the public interest. Election prediction markets have <a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/abs/pii/S0169207008000320" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">proven</a> to be a powerful tool for forecasting elections and are typically more accurate, timely, and complete than conventional methods.</p>



<p>Kalshi was designated by the CFTC in 2020 as a <a href="https://kalshi.com/blog/kalshi-designation" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Designated Contract Market</a>. The company facilitates the trading of a <a href="https://kalshi.com/events" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">wide range of contracts</a> for predictions on phenomena such as peak inflation, the results of the Federal Reserve’s December interest rate–setting meeting, China’s gross domestic product growth, and new COVID-19 variants emerging in the near future. In July, Kalshi <a href="https://www.cftc.gov/sites/default/files/filings/ptc/22/08/ptc082422kexdcm001.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">asked the CFTC for permission</a> to launch two contracts related to the outcome of this fall’s midterm elections.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img loading="lazy" width="4798" height="3205" src="https://www.aei.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/I-Would-Bet-100-That-Nevada-Goes-Red.jpg?x91208" alt="" class="wp-image-1008663642"/><figcaption>via Reuters</figcaption></figure>



<p>The CFTC has previously denied similar requests, <a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/cftc-election-futures/futures-regulator-rejects-gambling-on-obamas-future-idUSL2E8F307W20120403" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">ruling that</a> election prediction markets are online gambling and do not serve the public interest. This time, the CFTC launched a <a href="https://www.cftc.gov/sites/default/files/filings/documents/2022/orgkexpublicquestions220829.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">public comment process</a> to inform its decision on whether an election market creates more risks or actually helps hedge against them.</p>



<p>It would be a mistake for the CFTC to limit these markets and the valuable forecasting information they provide. In typical financial markets, the price of a stock, bond, or commodity future is in a sense a forecast of the value of an unknown future, be it the value of a commodity or a business’s expected revenues. The forecasts represented by these prices provide information that drives decisions in a variety of sectors. Farmers, for example, routinely use futures markets to decide which crops to plant. Political prediction markets can do the same for those who are navigating a constantly evolving political landscape to manage risk and maximize their organization’s impact.</p>



<p>Prediction markets offer several <a href="https://www.nber.org/papers/w18222" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">benefits</a> across the private and public sectors. First, tools such as public polling offer a snapshot in time and often lag in reflecting consequential shifts in public sentiment as conditions change. In contrast, prediction markets allow for real-time incorporation of new information signaled by the price of the contract.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Second, the market mechanism creates a financial incentive for individuals to express what they <em>believe</em> will happen, not what they <em>hope</em> will happen. Participants are only paid for being right, even if that outcome is not necessarily what they wanted. This too is better than solely relying on many of the alternatives. For example, political analysts provide important insight but may have financial incentives to generate support for a particular position or have their own biases incorporated into the analysis. As a <a href="https://populace.org/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Populace</a> survey recently <a href="https://static1.squarespace.com/static/59153bc0e6f2e109b2a85cbc/t/62fd07b49271c657d243505d/1660749762686/Private+Opinion+in+America" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">found</a>, social pressure can sometimes lead individuals to share what they believe is the “right” opinion even if it differs from their private views, which can complicate responses in polling and focus groups.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Finally, participants may not individually have all the information, but the market mechanism creates an incentive to reveal what they know, which is then pooled to produce the best estimate or forecast, reflected in the price. This kind of information is useful for making better strategic decisions in both the private and public sectors, particularly in heavily regulated sectors that need to navigate dynamic policy and political environments. Reducing even a little uncertainty can unlock the capital to support entrepreneurs tackling climate change, improving student education outcomes, or expanding access to health care.</p>



<p>Far from undermining election integrity, these markets can help strengthen it. Jason Furman, the chair of President Obama’s Council of Economic Advisers, <a href="https://comments.cftc.gov/PublicComments/ViewComment.aspx?ID=69708&amp;GUID=264324ac-75cb-4c97-9d45-62baa1877335" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">noted</a> in his comments to the CFTC that “election markets can also allow businesses and others to participate directly and hedge against the consequences of elections. Absent prediction markets businesses have no simple and transparent way to hedge against these risks.”</p>



<p>We need a clearer regulatory road map that would allow for more, not fewer, prediction markets covering not only election outcomes but other events. For example, we should leverage prediction markets to better manage our pandemic response. A 2005 prediction market correctly <a href="https://academic.oup.com/cid/article/44/2/272/330878" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">predicted</a> seasonal flu activity 71 percent of the time nearly two weeks ahead of clinical data that year. Such a market would have been invaluable to inform our nation’s pandemic response and indeed could still be valuable information given the uncertainty of future COVID-19 waves and variants as <a href="https://www.statnews.com/2022/09/02/prediction-markets-and-the-future-of-covid-19/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">COVID Collaborative&#8217;s</a> Steven Phillips has suggested.</p>



<p>Kalshi’s proposal does not pose a risk to the integrity of the US election system. Election futures trading is a normal procedure in other established, strong democracies such as Australia, Ireland, and the UK. The valuable insights provided through a regulated election market far outweigh any of the potential risks.</p>


<div class="related-items shortcode "><p><strong>See also:  </strong><a href="https://www.aei.org/politics-and-public-opinion/elections/elections-and-demography-one-month-to-go/">Elections and Demography: One Month to Go</a> | <a href="https://www.aei.org/politics-and-public-opinion/elections-and-demography-signs-of-a-tightening-race/">Elections and Demography: Signs of a Tightening Race</a> | <a href="https://www.aei.org/politics-and-public-opinion/elections-and-demography-who-are-the-likely-voters/">Elections and Demography: Who Are the Likely Voters?</a> | <a href="https://www.aei.org/politics-and-public-opinion/elections-and-demography-small-shifts-big-implications/">Elections and Demography: Small Shifts, Big Implications?</a></p></div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.aei.org/technology-and-innovation/prediction-markets-are-facing-a-key-regulatory-test/">Federal Regulators Should Approve Election Prediction Markets</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.aei.org">American Enterprise Institute - AEI</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>

<!--
Performance optimized by W3 Total Cache. Learn more: https://www.boldgrid.com/w3-total-cache/

Page Caching using memcache 

Served from: php.aei.org @ 2022-11-05 11:30:23 by W3 Total Cache
-->