<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><rss xmlns:a10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>News (English) - World Health Organization</title><link>https://www.who.int/</link><description>Corporate news releases, statements, and notes for media issued by the World Health Organization.</description><a10:contributor><a10:name> </a10:name></a10:contributor><a10:contributor><a10:name> </a10:name></a10:contributor><a10:contributor><a10:name> </a10:name></a10:contributor><a10:contributor><a10:name> </a10:name></a10:contributor><a10:contributor><a10:name> </a10:name></a10:contributor><a10:contributor><a10:name> </a10:name></a10:contributor><a10:contributor><a10:name> </a10:name></a10:contributor><a10:contributor><a10:name> </a10:name></a10:contributor><a10:contributor><a10:name> </a10:name></a10:contributor><a10:link rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="https://www.who.int/rss-feeds/news-english.xml" /><item><guid isPermaLink="false">urn:uuid:486017dd-79c1-43ab-8b39-11626c9d6cb8</guid><link>https://www.who.int/news/item/03-11-2022-global-health-agencies-outline-plan-to-support-ugandan-government-led-response-to-outbreak-of-ebola-virus-disease</link><a10:author><a10:name> </a10:name></a10:author><title>Global health agencies outline plan to support Ugandan government-led response to outbreak of ebola virus disease</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Following the declaration of an Ebola outbreak in Uganda on 20 September 2022, the outbreak has now spread to seven districts (Kasanda, Kyegegwa, Bunyangabu and Kagadi districts beyond the original epicenter in Mubende district, and then to Kampala City and Wakiso). The government-led response has activated&amp;nbsp;the Incident Management System in order to control the outbreak. In support of the Ministry of Health-led efforts, CEPI, Gavi and WHO have outlined a plan to accelerate research during the outbreak, to ensure access to investigational doses, and to facilitate scaling up and access to any subsequent licensed vaccine.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Vaccination is usually one of the response interventions in such an outbreak, however, there are currently no licensed vaccines (or therapeutics) for Ebola disease caused by the Sudan ebolavirus (SUDV), though there are several candidate vaccines which appear to be suitable for evaluation in a clinical trial during this outbreak.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;By embedding research at heart of the outbreak response, we can achieve two goals: to evaluate potentially efficacious candidate vaccines, and to potentially contribute to end this outbreak, and protect populations at risk in the future.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Ministry of Health has designated the Makerere University Lung Institute to conduct vaccine and therapeutics clinical trials. The clinical trial to evaluate candidate vaccines against this ebolavirus is co-sponsored by the Ministry of Health in Uganda and WHO, and involves support from partners. A Principal investigator from Makerere University Lung Institute will lead the vaccine trial.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;WHO, CEPI and Gavi are providing support to ensure that sufficient doses of candidate vaccines are available for the trial and beyond.&amp;nbsp; If sufficient doses can be made available, the aim of the vaccine trial would be to establish how effective the candidate vaccines are in diverse populations. The vaccine developers and funders who will make the candidate vaccines available include the University of Oxford and the Serum Institute of India, the Sabin Vaccine Institute and the US government institutions Biomedical Advanced Research and Development Authority (BARDA) and National Institutes of Health (NIH), as well as International AIDS Vaccine Initiative (IAVI) and MSD.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Moreover, there are other organisations committed to supporting the overall response, including Africa Centres for Disease Control and Prevention (Africa CDC), UNICEF, non-governmental organizations, donors, and regulators including the African Vaccine Regulatory Forum (AVAREF).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Goals of the collaboration&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The following goals have been identified for the organizations&amp;rsquo; efforts; these are likely to evolve in response to the outbreak.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;In the short term, supporting the Ministry of Health of Uganda&amp;rsquo;s outbreak response efforts as needed to control SUDV and, under their leadership, support a randomized clinical trial to evaluate one or more candidate vaccines as part of the response to the outbreak.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;In the mid-term, allocating resources to plan for and to reserve sufficient manufacturing capacity to scale up the production of candidate vaccines (even before they are licensed), potentially by establishing a risk-sharing mechanism. This may also involve manufacture of additional vaccines at risk during the trial to ensure that doses of a vaccine found to be efficacious vaccine can be made available to end the outbreak as quickly as possible.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Over the longer term, exploring pathways to ensure that licensed SUDV vaccine(s) are available via the Ebola stockpile, which is enabled and funded by Gavi and managed by UNICEF on behalf of the WHO-coordinated International Coordinating Group (ICG) mechanism on Vaccine Provision, potentially using innovative market shaping mechanisms.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Furthermore, committing to developing a mechanism to ensure equitable access and funding for SUDV vaccines research, outbreak response and preventive vaccination. Also, to provide support for development and evaluation of next generation vaccines.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;The signatories commit to be guided by the following principles:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Leverage organisational strengths towards a common goal:&lt;/strong&gt; Considering each institutions&amp;rsquo; mandate and mission and its expertise, all pledged to increase coordination and support the overarching agreed goals which cut across the remit of any one institution&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Country driven and country engaged&lt;/strong&gt;: Commit to support the Ministries of Health experiencing the outbreaks and ensure any engagement with the countries is coordinated and aligned with the Ministry of Health and responds to locally identified needs&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Decision making which is evidence-informed and considers access&lt;/strong&gt;: Commit to ensure decision making builds on robust scientific assessment of candidate vaccines and considers implications for future equitable access to a licensed vaccine&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;End-to-end approach based on access and equity&lt;/strong&gt;: Achieve development and delivery goals by accelerating research and development, as well as push and pull mechanisms and other innovative financing &amp;ndash; with access and equity centred at each stage&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Efficient resource allocation&lt;/strong&gt;: Ensure adequate funding and resources are available in a timely manner and aligned with national research and response priorities&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Research integrity and ethics&lt;/strong&gt;: Conduct research integrated in the response to outbreaks and in accordance with Good Clinical Practices.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Global research and development collaboration in response to Ebola outbreaks &amp;nbsp;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The actions taken by the Ministry of Health in Uganda and its partners build on past collaboration and experiences responding to Zaire ebolavirus outbreaks (another Ebola virus species), on COVAX lessons learned, and on working on other vaccine stockpile mechanisms.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A commitment to encourage availability of doses for the candidate vaccines for clinical trial and beyond. &lt;/strong&gt;In 2014, the Gavi Board approved a funding envelope for accelerated access to Ebola vaccines including eventual procurement of licensed vaccines, vaccine delivery and support for recovery in affected countries. Gavi subsequently signed an Advance Purchase Commitment (APC) agreement with Merck, securing the commitment to achieve and maintain availability of 300,000 doses of investigational vaccine doses until licensure and WHO recommendation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Integrating clinical research in the outbreak response&lt;/strong&gt;. Together with the Ministry of Health in Guinea, WHO was part of a broader coalition of countries and partners which worked to assess candidate Ebola vaccines in the context of the West Africa Ebola outbreak caused by Zaire ebolavirus species.&amp;nbsp; In 2014, a WHO-led global consortium rapidly initiated the necessary Phase 1 trials (VEBCON) and a randomized Phase 3 clinical trial in Guinea led by the Ministry of Health and WHO with several other partners which generated the evidence on the efficacy of the rVSV- ZEBOV Ebola vaccine. Additional clinical trials to evaluate various vaccines were conducted in 2015 by the Ministries of Health of Liberia and Sierra Leone and with the support of the US National Institutes of Health, The US Centers for Disease Control and the London School of Hygiene and Public Health among others. The experience of the West Africa Ebola outbreak catalysed the establishment of the WHO R&amp;amp;D Blueprint for epidemics by the World Health Assembly in 2015 after CEPI in 2016.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Deploying vaccines with proven efficacy yet unlicensed as part of the outbreak response&lt;/strong&gt;. After 2015 and before its licensure, the proven effective yet unlicensed vaccine was successfully deployed as part of the response to Ebola outbreaks until 2021 under the leadership of the Ministries of health and with support from WHO, Gavi, UNICEF and other partners. In all the outbreaks since 2016 Ministries of Health, WHO, and several partners have also collected additional evidence on the efficacy of the rVSV-ZEBOV Ebola vaccine. Despite the challenges, during the 2018-2020 outbreaks in Equateur, North Kivu and Ituri provinces of the Democratic Republic of the Congo, over 320,000 people at risk of Ebola (contacts, contacts of contacts, and health care and front-line workers in affected areas) received a safe and effective vaccine.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Creating a mechanism to ensure availability and access to licensed vaccines&lt;/strong&gt;. In 2019, the Gavi Board approved funding for the establishment of a global stockpile of licensed Ebola vaccines, administered via the ICG mechanism &amp;ndash; initially with investigational doses and then licensed vaccine for Ebola Zaire &amp;ndash; but with potential to include other vaccines, depending vaccine availability and following WHO recommendations. Stockpile of licensed doses have since been used to combat recent smaller outbreaks in the Democratic Republic of the Congo and Guinea.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A global, end-to-end collaboration to promote equitable access in support of countries&amp;rsquo; strategies and needs.&lt;/strong&gt; Beyond Ebola, the lessons from the COVID-19 response, including the establishment of the Access to COVID-19 Tools (ACT) Accelerator and key learnings from the vaccine pillar COVAX, are particularly important for the field of vaccine R&amp;amp;D, manufacturing, delivery and country and community engagement.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong style="background-color:transparent;text-align:inherit;text-transform:inherit;white-space:inherit;word-spacing:normal;caret-color:auto;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family:Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif;"&gt;Notes to editors&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;About CEPI&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://eur01.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fcepi.net%2F&amp;amp;data=05%7C01%7Cmsharafudeen%40gavi.org%7Cb7503e23d70d43565fd208dab73f3617%7C1de6d9f30daf4df6b9d65959f16f6118%7C0%7C0%7C638023779374726713%7CUnknown%7CTWFpbGZsb3d8eyJWIjoiMC4wLjAwMDAiLCJQIjoiV2luMzIiLCJBTiI6Ik1haWwiLCJXVCI6Mn0%3D%7C3000%7C%7C%7C&amp;amp;sdata=sJLB09ypXvm0MLunoBV9zBuhNv6kPE5aoS6oRexSDMo%3D&amp;amp;reserved=0"&gt;CEPI&lt;/a&gt; is an innovative partnership between public, private, philanthropic, and civil organizations, launched in 2017, to develop vaccines against future epidemics. Its mission is to accelerate the development of vaccines and other biologic countermeasures against epidemic and pandemic threats so they can be accessible to all people in need. Prior to COVID-19, CEPI&amp;rsquo;s work focused on developing vaccines against Ebola virus, Lassa virus, Middle East Respiratory Syndrome coronavirus, Nipah virus, Rift Valley Fever virus and Chikungunya virus &amp;ndash; it has over 20 vaccine candidates against these pathogens in development. CEPI has also invested in new platform technologies for rapid vaccine development against unknown pathogens (Disease X).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;CEPI has played a central role in the global response to COVID-19, supporting the development of the world&amp;rsquo;s largest portfolio of vaccines against SARS-CoV-2 and its variants with a focus on speed, scale and access, as well as co-leading COVAX, the global initiative to deliver fair and equitable access to COVID-19 vaccines. CEPI is also the world&amp;rsquo;s leading funder of R&amp;amp;D for broadly protective coronavirus vaccines which could protect against future variants of COVID-19 as well as other coronaviruses with epidemic and pandemic potential.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;CEPI has embarked upon an ambitious US$3.5bn five-year plan &amp;ndash; called CEPI 2.0 - to dramatically reduce or even eliminate the future risk of pandemics and epidemics. Central to the plan is CEPI&amp;rsquo;s goal &amp;ndash; supported by the G7 and G20 - to compress the time taken to develop safe, effective, globally accessible vaccines against new threats to just 100 days. Achieving this &amp;lsquo;&lt;a href="https://eur01.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url=https%3A%2F%2F100days.cepi.net%2F&amp;amp;data=05%7C01%7Cmsharafudeen%40gavi.org%7Cb7503e23d70d43565fd208dab73f3617%7C1de6d9f30daf4df6b9d65959f16f6118%7C0%7C0%7C638023779374726713%7CUnknown%7CTWFpbGZsb3d8eyJWIjoiMC4wLjAwMDAiLCJQIjoiV2luMzIiLCJBTiI6Ik1haWwiLCJXVCI6Mn0%3D%7C3000%7C%7C%7C&amp;amp;sdata=KgwWFRexxvFTevCITMKjwcsztAZ%2BYhs2n%2FlMk7xWvWQ%3D&amp;amp;reserved=0"&gt;100 Days Mission&amp;rsquo;&lt;/a&gt; would give the world a fighting chance of containing a future outbreak before it spreads to become a global pandemic. Read the plan at &lt;a href="https://eur01.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fendpandemics.cepi.net%2F&amp;amp;data=05%7C01%7Cmsharafudeen%40gavi.org%7Cb7503e23d70d43565fd208dab73f3617%7C1de6d9f30daf4df6b9d65959f16f6118%7C0%7C0%7C638023779374726713%7CUnknown%7CTWFpbGZsb3d8eyJWIjoiMC4wLjAwMDAiLCJQIjoiV2luMzIiLCJBTiI6Ik1haWwiLCJXVCI6Mn0%3D%7C3000%7C%7C%7C&amp;amp;sdata=814nvFrzd9x5B88Pg8t2ulW0t%2Bv%2FP%2FS5EpfZRRSrQR8%3D&amp;amp;reserved=0"&gt;endpandemics.cepi.net/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;About Gavi&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Gavi, the Vaccine Alliance is a public-private partnership that helps vaccinate half the world&amp;rsquo;s children against some of the world&amp;rsquo;s deadliest diseases. Since its inception in 2000, Gavi has helped to immunise a whole generation &amp;ndash; over 981 million children &amp;ndash; and prevented more than 16.2 million future deaths, helping to halve child mortality in 73 lower-income countries. Gavi also plays a key role in improving global health security by supporting health systems as well as funding global stockpiles for Ebola, cholera, meningococcal and yellow fever vaccines. After two decades of progress, Gavi is now focused on protecting the next generation, above all the zero-dose children who have not received even a single vaccine shot. The Vaccine Alliance employs innovative finance and the latest technology &amp;ndash; from drones to biometrics &amp;ndash; to save millions more lives, prevent outbreaks before they can spread and help countries on the road to self-sufficiency. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Gavi is a co-convener of COVAX, the vaccines pillar of the Access to COVID-19 Tools (ACT) Accelerator, together with the Coalition for Epidemic Preparedness Innovations (CEPI), the World Health Organization (WHO) and UNICEF. In its role, Gavi is focused on procurement and delivery for COVAX: coordinating the design, implementation and administration of the COVAX Facility and the Gavi COVAX AMC and working with its Alliance partners UNICEF and WHO, along with governments, on country readiness and delivery.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Vaccine Alliance brings together developing country and donor governments, the World Health Organization, UNICEF, the World Bank, the vaccine industry, technical agencies, civil society, the Bill &amp;amp; Melinda Gates Foundation and other private sector partners. View the full list of donor governments and other leading organisations that fund Gavi&amp;rsquo;s work &lt;a href="https://www.gavi.org/investing-gavi/funding/donor-profiles" target="_blank"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;Learn more&amp;nbsp;at &lt;a href="https://www.gavi.org/homepage" target="_blank"&gt;www.gavi.org&lt;/a&gt; and connect with us on &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/GAVI/" target="_blank"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/gavi" target="_blank"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;About WHO&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dedicated to the well-being of all people and guided by science, the World Health Organization leads and champions global efforts to give everyone, everywhere an equal chance at a safe and healthy life. We are the UN agency for health that connects nations, partners and people on the front lines in 150+ locations &amp;ndash; leading the world&amp;rsquo;s response to health emergencies, preventing disease, addressing the root causes of health issues and expanding access to medicines and health care. Our mission is to promote health, keep the world safe and serve the vulnerable.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 13:40:17 Z</pubDate></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">urn:uuid:f7c21679-98d4-4464-96cd-0994556ceab5</guid><link>https://www.who.int/news/item/03-11-2022-act-now--migrant-inclusion-in-climate-action-is-an-obligation--not-an-option</link><a10:author><a10:name> </a10:name></a10:author><title>Act now: migrant inclusion in climate action is an obligation, not an option</title><description>On the occasion of the 27th Conference of the Parties of the UNFCCC (COP27), the United Nations Network on Migration calls on Member States to recognize the opportunities to work towards sustainable, rights-based mitigation and adaptation to climate change in order to address human mobility(1) in this context in line with the recommendations of the UNFCCC Taskforce on Displacement.</description><pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 11:44:05 Z</pubDate><a10:content type="text">&lt;p&gt;The adverse effects of climate change and environmental degradation are increasingly driving human mobility the world over, particularly in countries with high exposure and low adaptive capacity. While most climate-related mobility currently occurs within
    countries, desperation and deteriorating environments can also compel people to seek a livelihood elsewhere through irregular migration. While climate change negatively impacts everyone, everywhere, those already in vulnerable situations due to geography,
    poverty, gender, age, disability, origin or other status, including migrant women who depend on climate-sensitive livelihoods, and children who are less able to survive extreme weather events, are at the greatest risk of suffering harm. It is imperative
    to recognize this reality and take meaningful action to protect the human rights of those most affected by climate change, including migrants.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On the occasion of the 27th Conference of the Parties of the UNFCCC (COP27), the United Nations Network on Migration calls on Member States to recognize the opportunities to work towards sustainable, rights-based mitigation and adaptation to climate change
    in order to address human mobility(1) in this context in line with the recommendations of the UNFCCC Taskforce on Displacement.&amp;nbsp;&lt;em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Network urges States, working in cooperation with relevant UN entities and all partners, to address and seek inclusive solutions for the most affected people, including those staying in place, moving internally, and migrating internationally, while
    fully recognizing the adaptation role that migration plays in this context. While progress has already been achieved in mainstreaming migration into adaptation strategies and policies for climate action, much more needs to be done. As acknowledged
    at COP26, inadequacies in anticipating and planning for situations that could induce climate-related mobility remain and efforts to mitigate and adapt to the adverse effects of climate change, including through resource mobilization, are insufficient.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Network encourages States to include pathways for regular migration in their climate change mitigation and adaptation strategies, which enable labour mobility and decent work, human rights and humanitarian admission and stay, family reunification,
    education, private sponsorships, and visa waivers, to support communities in building resilience to climate change and adapting through mobility. In this regard, improvements have been made in the conclusion of bilateral and regional labour migration
    agreements or the creation of special visa categories to enable people affected by climate change to move regularly or to remain in countries of destination.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Pursuant to the commitments made in the Global Compact for Safe, Orderly and Regular Migration (GCM) and renewed in the Progress Declaration of the first International Migration Review Forum in New York in May 2022, the Network reiterates its call for
    States to develop inclusive climate change and migration policies and action plans that ensure migrants&amp;rsquo; full and effective participation as rights holders. The Network also reminds States that any policy measure or legislation that governs
    or directly impacts human mobility in the context of climate change should uphold human rights obligations.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;States can ensure that this objective is effectively achieved through recognizing that the Paris Agreement, the Sendai Framework for Disaster Risk Reduction 2015-2030, the 2030 Agenda for Sustainable Development, and the Global Compacts for Migration
    and Refugees are interlinked and should be implemented simultaneously and in a mutually reinforcing manner.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;To uphold human rights, strengthen the adaptive capacities of migrants and harness the potential of climate mobility the Network calls on governments, in collaboration with one another and all relevant stakeholders, to:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Strengthen support to countries and people affected by effectively mobilizing adequate finance to support climate action, including through investing in early warning systems and preparedness, and addressing the impacts of both economic and non-economic
        loss and damage, including for migrants;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Facilitate a just transition to environmentally sustainable, green economies and societies, including by building climate-resilient health systems, promoting resilience and equitable development and advancing social justice and decent work creation,
        tapping into the skills and experiences of migrants, with the support of business, employers, trade unions and workers organizations, and harnessing their contributions towards sustainable development;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Enhance and diversify the availability of climate-sensitive pathways for regular migration, including by creating regular pathways for labour mobility, ensuring they are accessible to all, including women and children as an adaptation option and a
        way to prevent and address situations of vulnerability;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Enhance regional and international action and cooperation to effectively address climate-related migration at local, national, regional and global levels through dedicated and coordinated climate change and migration policies and action plans, including
        by working coherently across all relevant multilateral fora; and,&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Foster evidence-based decisions and disaggregated data which inform cooperation and scaled up climate action.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Our shared future depends on realizing the human right to a clean, healthy and sustainable environment for all. The interlinkages between climate change, human rights and migration are clear and the international community can no longer delay taking action
    to protect the environment, for present and future generations.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Every step taken towards safe, orderly and regular migration would make a step forwards in the context of our changing climate.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(1)&amp;nbsp;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;Climate change-related human mobility is understood as encompassing migration, displacement and planned relocation as reflected in GCM Objectives 2 (18 j) and 5 (21 h) and agreed under relevant UNFCCC processes such as the Executive Committee of the Warsaw International Mechanism for Loss and Damage and the Task Force on Displacement recommendations. &lt;/em&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;The United Nations Network on Migration was established to ensure effective, timely and coordinated system-wide support to Member States in their implementation, follow-up and review of the Global Compact for Safe, Orderly and Regular Migration. While the Network&amp;rsquo;s mandate is focused on migration, States are called to also implement these recommendations to displaced persons, refugees and asylum-seekers as well and to protect the human rights of everyone equally, regardless of status.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</a10:content></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">urn:uuid:5aeeba4f-8268-4ddd-bd18-166d94a01132</guid><link>https://www.who.int/news/item/01-11-2022-third-meeting-of-the-international-health-regulations-(2005)-(ihr)-emergency-committee-regarding-the-multi-country-outbreak-of-monkeypox</link><a10:author><a10:name> </a10:name></a10:author><title>Third meeting of the International Health Regulations (2005) (IHR) Emergency Committee regarding the multi-country outbreak of monkeypox</title><description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The WHO Director-General transmits the report of the third meeting of the International Health Regulations (2005) (IHR) Emergency Committee regarding the multi-country outbreak of monkeypox, held on Thursday, 20 October 2022, from 12:00 to 17:00 CEST.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Emergency Committee acknowledged that some progress has been made in the global response to the multi-country outbreak of monkeypox since the last meeting, including the emerging information on the effectiveness of behavioural interventions and vaccines. The Committee held the consensus view that the event continues to meet the IHR criteria for a Public Health Emergency of International Concern (PHEIC) and highlights the primary reasons for ongoing concern. These include ongoing&amp;nbsp;transmission in some regions, continuing preparedness and response inequity within and between WHO Member States, an emerging potential for greater health impact in vulnerable populations, continuing risk of stigma and discrimination, weak health systems in some developing countries leading to under-reporting, ongoing lack of equitable access to diagnostics, antiviral and vaccines, and research gaps needing to be addressed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The WHO Director-General expresses&amp;nbsp;his gratitude to the Chair,&amp;nbsp;Members, and Advisors for their advice and concurs with this advice that the event continues to constitute a PHEIC for the reasons detailed in the proceedings of the meeting below. The Director-General issues revised Temporary Recommendations in relation to this PHEIC, which are presented at the end of this document.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a name="_Hlk109592327" data-sf-ec-immutable=""&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Proceedings of the third meeting&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;of the IHR Emergency Committee&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The third meeting of the IHR Emergency Committee on the multi-country outbreak of monkeypox was convened by videoconference, with the Chair and Vice-Chair being present in person on the premises of WHO headquarters, Geneva, Switzerland. Members and Advisors joined by videoconference. Eleven of the 15 Members and 6 of the 9 Advisors to the Committee participated in the meeting. The WHO Director-General, in his &lt;a href="https://www.who.int/director-general/speeches/detail/who-director-general-s-opening-remarks-at-3rd-meeting-of-the-ihr-emergency-committee--multi-country-outbreak-of-monkeypox---20-october-2022"&gt;opening remarks&lt;/a&gt;, welcomed the Committee, noting a promising decline in cases globally, although progress in the regions of the Americas and Africa is less certain, where cases are rising in some countries, and underreporting is likely in others.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Representative of the Office of Legal Counsel reminded the Members and Advisors of their roles and responsibilities and the mandate of the Emergency Committee under the relevant articles of the IHR.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Ethics Officer from the Department of Compliance, Risk Management, and Ethics also reminded Members and Advisors of their roles and responsibilities, including their duty of confidentiality as to the meeting discussions and the work of the Committee; as well as of their individual responsibility to disclose to WHO, in a timely manner, any interests of a personal, professional, financial, intellectual or commercial nature that may give rise to a perceived or direct conflict of interest. Each Member and Advisor who was&amp;nbsp;present was surveyed. No conflicts of interest were noted.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It was noted that one Member has withdrawn from the Committee on account of other commitments&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The meeting was handed over to the Chair of the Emergency Committee, Dr Jean-Marie Okwo-Bele, who introduced the objectives of the meeting: to provide views to the WHO Director-General as to whether the multi-country outbreak of monkeypox continues to constitute&amp;nbsp;a PHEIC, and, if so,&amp;nbsp;to review the proposed temporary recommendations to States Parties.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Presentations&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Representatives of Brazil, Ghana, and Sudan updated the Committee on the epidemiological situation in their countries and their current response efforts. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The WHO Secretariat updated the Committee on the global epidemiological situation as well as on the rapidly evolving knowledge in understanding the clinical manifestation and evolution of the disease. Details can be found in the &lt;a href="https://www.who.int/publications/m/item/weekly-epidemiological-update-on-covid-19---19-october-2022"&gt;weekly epidemiological update&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and in the &lt;a href="https://www.who.int/publications/m/item/multi-country-outbreak-of-monkeypox--external-situation-report--8---19-october-2022"&gt;8&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; External situation report&lt;/a&gt;; WHO updates the information regularly through the &lt;a href="https://www.who.int/emergencies/situation-reports"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.who.int/emergencies/situation-reports"&gt;external situation reports&lt;/a&gt;. All data are also available and case counts are updated daily at this link: &lt;a href="https://worldhealthorg.shinyapps.io/mpx_global/"&gt;2022 Monkeypox Outbreak: Global Trends (shinyapps.io)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Secretariat noted that, since the determination of the PHEIC on 23 July 2022, many more countries have promptly responded to the outbreak with a range of public health interventions and cases are declining globally. Nonetheless, the picture is mixed and, overall, the risk assessment conducted by the WHO Secretariat concludes that as of 18 October 2022 the public health risk remains moderate globally; at regional level, risk was assessed as high in the WHO region of the Americas, declining from high to moderate in the European region, remaining moderate for the WHO Regions of Africa, Eastern Mediterranean, and South-East Asia, and remaining low in the Western Pacific Region.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Secretariat presented its &lt;a href="https://www.who.int/publications/m/item/monkeypox-strategic-preparedness--readiness--and-response-plan-(sprp)"&gt;Strategic preparedness, readiness and response plan for monkeypox 2022&lt;/a&gt;, and the global funding appeal recently published. With a goal of stopping the global monkeypox outbreak, the plan articulates three objectives: to stop human-to-human transmission, protect the vulnerable, and minimize zoonotic transmission.&amp;nbsp; Five core components underpin the global response: emergency coordination, collaborative surveillance, community protection, safe and scalable care, and countermeasures and research. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;After the presentations, Committee Members and Advisors proceeded to engage the Secretariat and the presenting countries in a question-and-answer session. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Deliberative session&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Committee reconvened in a closed meeting to examine the questions in relation to whether the event continues to constitute a PHEIC, and if so, to consider the proposed Temporary Recommendations, drafted by the WHO Secretariat in accordance with IHR provisions. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Chair reminded the Committee Members and Advisors of the definition of a PHEIC under the IHR: an extraordinary event, which constitutes a public health risk to other States through international spread, and which potentially requires a coordinated international response.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Committee noted with concern that data from low-income settings are largely lacking, with scanty information available to determine whether transmission observed in Africa is mainly zoonotic or to determine the role of human-to-human transmission, including through intimate or sexual contact. Many low-income settings have inadequate diagnostic capacity and do not yet have access to vaccines or therapeutics, despite clearly having the highest reported case fatality of all regions, and little information is available as to whether authorities are considering their use or requesting supplies. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Committee noted that in high-income settings in which the outbreak was first experienced, preliminary information suggests significant declines in the number of newly reported cases of monkeypox. Data needed to determine the respective contributions of various factors to these declines have yet to be fully collected and analysed. These factors could include: the adoption of safer sexual behaviours among populations at higher risk; the seasonal reduction of large gatherings enhancing risk-taking sexual behaviours; the strong vaccine acceptance in affected communities and rising rates of pre- and post-exposure vaccination; possibly rising immunity following infection among populations at higher risk; and surveillance artifacts resulting from declining patient presentation and testing for less severe cases. While evaluation and research have established that lower participation in higher-risk activities has contributed to slowing the outbreak, the Committee expressed concerns about the sustainability of these trends, early signals of vaccine hesitancy in a few areas within an overall context of very high vaccine acceptance; and an increasing concentration of cases amongst minoritized communities. The Committee noted the need to gather evidence on the drivers and interventions that have led to positive behaviour change. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Committee noted the epidemiological concomitance of monkeypox, HIV and other Sexually Transmitted Infections, and expressed concern about the more frequent severe outcomes and deaths in people living with HIV who are immunocompromised and/or not receiving antiretroviral treatment, especially in underserved and low resource settings&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Committee expressed deep concern over continuing and emerging inequities in the response to the outbreak and noted the imperative for mechanisms, commitments and actions that will ensure equity in access to diagnostics, therapeutics, and vaccines. In addition, the Committee called for respect for human rights for all, including those in marginalized communities vulnerable to stigma; some Members reiterated their views that laws, policies and practices by state or non-state actors that criminalize or stigmatize consensual same-sex behaviour may hamper response interventions. It was advised that public health best practices include a harm reduction approach with efforts to overcome barriers caused by policies and laws which criminalize homosexuality or otherwise contribute to stigma and discrimination and impede efforts to control the outbreak. It was also recommended that global and national programmes should continue to engage with affected communities, work towards 1) integrating monkeypox outbreak response with HIV prevention and sexual health services where appropriate and 2) continue to strive for greater strategic support and research for most-affected countries.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Overall, the conditions that warranted the determination of the PHEIC still persist, as the monkeypox outbreak continues to constitute an extraordinary event which poses a public health risk through international spread, for which additional epidemic waves may yet be seen, and continues to require a coordinated international response to reduce the impact of the outbreak. While two members expressed views that the event did not and does not constitute a PHEIC, these were tempered by concern about the potential negative consequences of lifting the declaration at this time.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conclusions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Committee collectively advised the WHO Director-General that the multi-country outbreak of monkeypox continues to meet the criteria included in the definition of the PHEIC provide by Article 1 of the IHR. Although views were expressed that the event did not and does not constitute a PHEIC, the Committee collectively recognized that the criteria embedded in the definition of the PHEIC may not be adequate at this time to inform their advice to the WHO Director-General as to whether and when this PHEIC should be terminated. In that regard, the Committee noted the ongoing process related to amendments to the IHR. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Committee Members and Advisors provided their advice for the Temporary Recommendations to States Parties, which to a large extent continued those issued on 23 July 2022 by the WHO Director-General. The committee indicated the need to monitor the level of uptake and degree of implementation of Temporary Recommendations by States Parties, to complement the other modalities and programmatic approaches that are in place to support and monitor country outbreak response. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p align="center"&gt;===&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Temporary Recommendations issued by the WHO Director-General in relation to the&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;multi-country outbreak of monkeypox&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;These Temporary Recommendations extend, modify or add to those issued on &lt;a href="https://www.who.int/news/item/23-07-2022-second-meeting-of-the-international-health-regulations-(2005)-(ihr)-emergency-committee-regarding-the-multi-country-outbreak-of-monkeypox"&gt;23 July 2022&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;These Temporary Recommendations support the goal and objectives of the &lt;a href="https://www.who.int/publications/m/item/monkeypox-strategic-preparedness--readiness--and-response-plan-(sprp)"&gt;Strategic Preparedness, Readiness and Response Plan for Monkeypox 2022&amp;ndash;2032&lt;/a&gt; to stop the outbreak of monkeypox, interrupt human-to-human transmission of the virus, protect the vulnerable, and minimize zoonotic transmission of the virus. They apply to States Parties according to their epidemiological situation, patterns of transmission and capacities with respect to monkeypox outbreak response. It should be assumed that any State Party may experience importation or local human-to-human transmission of monkeypox. Thus, each State Party should undertake surveillance and be ready to engage in outbreak response for suspected cases, since any case from any source may lead to human-to-human transmission. Some States Parties may have a history of, or be experiencing, zoonotic transmission or may observe spillback of monkeypox from humans to animals. Finally, States Parties in a position to support scaling up access to vaccines, diagnostics and therapeutics, including through technology transfer, should make every effort to do so.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In implementing these temporary recommendations (defined under the IHR as &amp;ldquo;non-binding advice issued by WHO pursuant to Article 15 of the IHR for application on a time-limited, risk-specific basis, in response to a public health emergency of international concern, so as to prevent or reduce the international spread of disease and minimize interference with international traffic&amp;rdquo;), States Parties should do so in full respect for the dignity, human rights and fundamental freedoms of persons, in line with the principles set out in Article 3 of the IHR. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;WHO documents referenced below are current as of 20 October 2022.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MODIFIED&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;strong&gt;Readiness (1):&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;nbsp;These recommendations are meant to ensure a state of readiness for an outbreak of monkeypox and apply to ALL States Parties&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MODIFIED&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;strong&gt;1.a.&lt;/strong&gt; Activate or establish health and multi-sectoral coordination mechanisms to strengthen all aspects of readiness for responding to monkeypox and stop human-to-human transmission, including a comprehensive One Health approach&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.who.int/publications/m/item/monkeypox-strategic-preparedness--readiness--and-response-plan-(sprp)"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.who.int/publications/m/item/monkeypox-strategic-preparedness--readiness--and-response-plan-(sprp)"&gt;Monkeypox Strategic Preparedness, Readiness, and Response Plan (SPRP)&lt;/a&gt;; &lt;a href="https://www.who.int/publications/m/item/multi-country-outbreak-of-monkeypox--external-situation-report--8---19-october-2022"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.who.int/emergencies/situations/monkeypox-oubreak-2022"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.who.int/emergencies/situations/monkeypox-oubreak-2022"&gt;Monkeypox outbreak 2022 - Global (who.int)&lt;/a&gt;; &lt;a href="https://www.who.int/publications/m/item/multi-country-outbreak-of-monkeypox--external-situation-report--8---19-october-2022"&gt;Multi-country outbreak of monkeypox, External situation report #8 - 19 October 2022 (who.int)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MODIFIED&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;strong&gt;1.b.&lt;/strong&gt; Plan for, and/or implement, interventions to avoid the stigmatization and discrimination against any individual or population group that may be affected by monkeypox, with the goal of preventing further undetected transmission of monkeypox virus. The focus of these interventions should be: to promote voluntary self-reporting and care seeking behaviour; to support access to diagnostic services, vaccines and therapeutics; to facilitate timely access to quality clinical care; and to protect human rights to health, privacy and dignity of affected individuals and their contacts across all communities.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.who.int/publications/i/item/WHO-MPX-RCCE-2022.1"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.who.int/publications-detail-redirect/WHO-MPX-RCCE-2022.1"&gt;Risk communication and community engagement for monkeypox outbreaks, interim guidance&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.who.int/publications/m/item/communications-and-community-engagement-interim-guidance-on-using-inclusive-language-in-understanding--preventing-and-addressing-stigma-and-discrimination-related-to-monkeypox"&gt;Risk communication and community engagement public health advice on understanding, preventing and addressing stigma and discrimination related to monkeypox (who.int)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MODIFIED&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;strong&gt;1.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;c. &lt;/strong&gt;Noting that Clade II monkeypox virus is a sexually transmissible infection, establish and intensify epidemiological disease surveillance, including access to reliable, affordable and accurate diagnostic tests, for illness consistent with monkeypox as part of existing national surveillance and health care systems. For disease surveillance purposes, case definitions for suspected, probable and confirmed cases of monkeypox should be adopted, as well as the case definition for death related to monkeypox.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.who.int/publications-detail-redirect/WHO-MPX-Surveillance-2022.3"&gt;https://www.who.int/publications/i/item/WHO-MPX-Surveillance-2022.3&lt;/a&gt;; &lt;a href="https://www.who.int/publications/i/item/WHO-MPX-laboratory-2022.1"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.who.int/publications-detail-redirect/WHO-MPX-laboratory-2022.1"&gt;https://www.who.int/publications/i/item/WHO-MPX-laboratory-2022.1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EXTENDED&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;strong&gt;1.d.&lt;/strong&gt; Intensify the detection capacity by raising awareness and training health workers, including those in primary care, genitourinary and sexual health clinics, urgent care/emergency departments, dental practices, dermatology, paediatrics, HIV services, infectious diseases, maternity services, obstetrics and gynaecology, and other acute care facilities.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.who.int/publications/i/item/WHO-MPX-Surveillance-2022.3"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.who.int/publications-detail-redirect/WHO-MPX-Surveillance-2022.3"&gt;https://www.who.int/publications/i/item/WHO-MPX-Surveillance-2022.3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Online introductory training. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://openwho.org/courses/monkeypox-introduction"&gt;Monkeypox: Introduction | OpenWHO&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Online extended training.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href="https://openwho.org/courses/monkeypox-intermediate"&gt;Monkeypox epidemiology, preparedness and response | OpenWHO&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;These online trainings are available in many languages. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EXTENDED&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;strong&gt;1.e.&lt;/strong&gt; Raise awareness about monkeypox virus transmission, related prevention and protective measures, and symptoms and signs of monkeypox among communities that are currently affected in other countries (e.g., importantly, but not exclusively, gay, bisexual and other men who have sex with men (MSM) or individuals with multiple sexual partners) as well as among other population groups that may be at risk (e.g., male and female sex workers, transgender people).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.who.int/publications/i/item/WHO-MPX-RCCE-2022.1"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.who.int/publications-detail-redirect/WHO-MPX-RCCE-2022.1"&gt;https://www.who.int/publications/i/item/WHO-MPX-RCCE-2022.1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.who.int/news-room/public-advice/men-who-have-sex-with-men-preventing-monkeypox"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.who.int/news-room/public-advice/men-who-have-sex-with-men-preventing-monkeypox"&gt;Public advice for men who have sex with men on preventing monkeypox&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.who.int/publications/m/item/public-health-advice-for-sex-workers-on-monkeypox"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.who.int/publications/m/item/public-health-advice-for-sex-workers-on-monkeypox"&gt;Public health advice for sex workers on monkeypox (who.int)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EXTENDED&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;strong&gt; 1.f. &lt;/strong&gt;Engage key community-based groups, sexual health and civil society networks to increase the provision of reliable and factual information about monkeypox and its potential transmission to and within populations or communities that may be at increased risk of infection. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.who.int/publications/i/item/WHO-MPX-RCCE-2022.1"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.who.int/publications-detail-redirect/WHO-MPX-RCCE-2022.1"&gt;https://www.who.int/publications/i/item/WHO-MPX-RCCE-2022.1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.who.int/news-room/public-advice/protecting-yourself-from-monkeypox"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.who.int/news-room/public-advice/protecting-yourself-from-monkeypox"&gt;Public advice on protecting yourself from monkeypox (who.int)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EXTENDED&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;strong&gt; 1.g.&lt;/strong&gt; Focus risk communication and community support efforts on settings and venues where intimate encounters take place (e.g., gatherings focused on MSM, sex-on-premises venues). This includes engaging with and supporting community-led organizations, the organizers of large and smaller scale events, as well as with owners and managers of sex on premises venues to promote personal protective measures and risk-reducing behaviour.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.who.int/publications/i/item/WHO-MPX-Gatherings-2022.1"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.who.int/publications-detail-redirect/WHO-MPX-Gatherings-2022.1"&gt;https://www.who.int/publications/i/item/WHO-MPX-Gatherings-2022.1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MODIFIED&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;strong&gt;1.h.&lt;/strong&gt; As soon as the first cases are detected, report probable and confirmed cases of monkeypox, and deaths related to monkeypox, to WHO through channels established under the provisions of the IHR using the minimum data set contained in the WHO Case Report Form (CRF).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.who.int/publications/i/item/WHO-MPX-Surveillance-2022.3"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.who.int/publications-detail-redirect/WHO-MPX-Surveillance-2022.3"&gt;https://www.who.int/publications/i/item/WHO-MPX-Surveillance-2022.3&lt;em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;; &lt;a href="https://www.who.int/publications/i/item/WHO-MPX-Clinical_CRF-2022.3"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.who.int/publications-detail-redirect/WHO-MPX-Clinical_CRF-2022.3"&gt;https://www.who.int/publications/i/item/WHO-MPX-Clinical_CRF-2022.3&amp;nbsp; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MODIFIED&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;strong&gt; 1.i.&lt;/strong&gt; Implement all actions necessary to be ready to apply or continue applying the set of Temporary Recommendations enumerated under Outbreak Response (2) below in the event of first-time or renewed detection of one or more suspected, probable or confirmed cases of monkeypox. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.who.int/publications/m/item/monkeypox-strategic-preparedness--readiness--and-response-plan-(sprp)"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.who.int/publications/m/item/monkeypox-strategic-preparedness--readiness--and-response-plan-(sprp)"&gt;https://www.who.int/publications/m/item/monkeypox-strategic-preparedness--readiness--and-response-plan-(sprp)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MODIFIED&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;Outbreak response (2):&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt; All &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;States Parties with one or more cases of monkeypox, regardless of the initial source, or experiencing human-to-human transmission, including in key population groups communities at high risk of exposure&amp;nbsp; &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EXTENDED&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;strong&gt;2.a.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Implementing coordinated response&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EXTENDED&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;strong&gt;2.a.i.&lt;/strong&gt; Implement response actions with the &lt;strong&gt;goal of stopping human-to-human transmission&lt;/strong&gt; of monkeypox virus, with a priority focus on communities at high risk of exposure, which may differ according to context and include gay, bisexual and other men who have sex with men (MSM). Those actions include: targeted risk communication and community engagement, case detection, supported isolation of cases and treatment, contact tracing, and targeted immunization for persons at high risk of exposure for monkeypox.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.who.int/publications/m/item/monkeypox-strategic-preparedness--readiness--and-response-plan-(sprp)"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.who.int/publications/m/item/monkeypox-strategic-preparedness--readiness--and-response-plan-(sprp)"&gt;https://www.who.int/publications/m/item/monkeypox-strategic-preparedness--readiness--and-response-plan-(sprp)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EXTENDED&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;strong&gt;2.a.ii.&lt;/strong&gt; Empower affected communities and enable and support their leadership in devising, contributing actively to, and monitoring the response to the health risk they are confronting. Extend technical, financial and human resources to the extent possible and maintain mutual accountability on the actions of the affected communities.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.who.int/publications/m/item/monkeypox-strategic-preparedness--readiness--and-response-plan-(sprp)"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.who.int/publications/m/item/monkeypox-strategic-preparedness--readiness--and-response-plan-(sprp)"&gt;https://www.who.int/publications/m/item/monkeypox-strategic-preparedness--readiness--and-response-plan-(sprp)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EXTENDED&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;strong&gt;2.a.iii.&lt;/strong&gt; Implement response actions with the goal of &lt;strong&gt;protecting vulnerable groups&lt;/strong&gt; (immunosuppressed individuals, children, pregnant women) who may be at increased risk of severe monkeypox disease. Those actions include: targeted risk communication and community engagement, case detection, supported isolation of cases, contact tracing, and treatment. These may also include targeted immunization, which takes into careful consideration the risks and benefits for the individual in shared clinical decision-making.&lt;a href="https://www.who.int/publications/m/item/monkeypox-strategic-preparedness--readiness--and-response-plan-(sprp)"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.who.int/publications/m/item/monkeypox-strategic-preparedness--readiness--and-response-plan-(sprp)"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.who.int/publications/m/item/monkeypox-strategic-preparedness--readiness--and-response-plan-(sprp)"&gt;https://www.who.int/publications/m/item/monkeypox-strategic-preparedness--readiness--and-response-plan-(sprp)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EXTENDED&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;strong&gt;2.b.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Engaging and protecting communities&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MODIFIED&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;strong&gt;2.b.i. &lt;/strong&gt;Raise awareness about monkeypox virus transmission, actions to reduce the risk of onward transmission to others and clinical presentation in communities affected by the outbreak, which may vary by context, and promote the uptake and appropriate use of prevention measures, including supporting equitable access to primary preventive vaccination for persons at risk of exposure, and adoption of other informed risk mitigation measures. In different contexts, these measures include limiting skin to skin contact or other forms of close contact with others while symptomatic, promoting the reduction of the number of sexual partners where relevant including with respect to events with venues for sex on premises, and use of personal protective measures and practices, including during, and related to, small or large gatherings of communities at high risk of exposure. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.who.int/publications-detail-redirect/WHO-MPX-RCCE-2022.1"&gt;https://www.who.int/publications/i/item/WHO-MPX-RCCE-2022.1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.who.int/publications-detail-redirect/WHO-MPX-Immunization-2022.2-eng"&gt;Vaccines and immunization for monkeypox: Interim guidance, 24 August 2022 (who.int)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.who.int/publications-detail-redirect/WHO-MPX-Gatherings-2022.1"&gt;https://www.who.int/publications/i/item/WHO-MPX-Gatherings-2022.1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MODIFIED&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;strong&gt;2.b.ii.&lt;/strong&gt; Engage with authorities and event organizers of gatherings (large and small), including those likely to be conducive for encounters of an intimate nature or that may include venues for sex-on-premises, to promote personal protective measures and behaviours, encourage organizers to apply the WHO-recommended risk-based approach to decision-making regarding the holding of such events. All necessary information should be provided for risk communication on personal choices around preventive measures including the role of vaccines and reduction in numbers of partners, and for infection prevention and control including regular cleaning of event venues and premises.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.who.int/publications-detail-redirect/WHO-MPX-Gatherings-2022.1"&gt;https://www.who.int/publications/i/item/WHO-MPX-Gatherings-2022.1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://extranet.who.int/ihr/eventinformation/all-announcements"&gt;https://extranet.who.int/ihr/eventinformation/all-announcements&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EXTENDED&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;strong&gt;2.b.iii.&lt;/strong&gt; Develop and target risk communication and community engagement interventions, including systematic social listening (e.g., through digital platforms), for emerging perceptions, concerns, and misinformation that might hamper response actions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.who.int/publications-detail-redirect/WHO-MPX-RCCE-2022.1"&gt;https://www.who.int/publications/i/item/WHO-MPX-RCCE-2022.1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.who.int/news-room/public-advice"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.who.int/news-room/public-advice"&gt;Public Advice (who.int)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.who.int/teams/epi-win"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.who.int/teams/epi-win"&gt;EPI-WIN (who.int)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.who.int/news/item/26-09-2022-who-releases-a-public-health-taxonomy-for-social-listening-on-monkeypox-conversations"&gt;WHO releases a public health taxonomy for social listening on monkeypox conversations&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EXTENDED&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;strong&gt;2.b.iv.&lt;/strong&gt; Engage with representatives of affected communities, non-government organizations, elected officials and civil society, and behavioural scientists to advise on approaches and strategies to avoid stigmatization of any individual or population groups in the implementation of appropriate interventions, so that care seeking behaviour, testing and access to preventive measures and clinical care are equitable and timely, and to prevent undetected transmission of monkeypox virus. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.who.int/publications-detail-redirect/WHO-MPX-RCCE-2022.1"&gt;https://www.who.int/publications/i/item/WHO-MPX-RCCE-2022.1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.who.int/publications/m/item/communications-and-community-engagement-interim-guidance-on-using-inclusive-language-in-understanding--preventing-and-addressing-stigma-and-discrimination-related-to-monkeypox"&gt;Risk communication and community engagement public health advice on understanding, preventing and addressing stigma and discrimination related to monkeypox (who.int)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EXTENDED&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;strong&gt;2.c. Surveillance and public health measures&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EXTENDED&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;strong&gt;2.c.i. &lt;/strong&gt;Intensify surveillance for illness compatible with monkeypox as part of existing national surveillance schemes, including access to reliable, affordable and accurate diagnostic tests.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.who.int/publications-detail-redirect/WHO-MPX-Surveillance-2022.3"&gt;https://www.who.int/publications/i/item/WHO-MPX-Surveillance-2022.3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EXTENDED&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;strong&gt;2.c.ii. &lt;/strong&gt;Report to WHO, on a weekly basis and through channels established under the provision of the IHR, probable and confirmed cases of monkeypox, including using the minimum data set contained in the WHO Case Report Form (CRF).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.who.int/publications-detail-redirect/WHO-MPX-Surveillance-2022.3"&gt;https://www.who.int/publications/i/item/WHO-MPX-Surveillance-2022.3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.who.int/tools/global-clinical-platform/monkeypox"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.who.int/tools/global-clinical-platform/monkeypox"&gt;The WHO Global Clinical Platform for monkeypox&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.who.int/publications/i/item/WHO-MPX-Clinical_CRF-2022.3"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.who.int/publications-detail-redirect/WHO-MPX-Clinical_CRF-2022.3"&gt;https://www.who.int/publications/i/item/WHO-MPX-Clinical_CRF-2022.3&amp;nbsp; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MODIFIED&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;strong&gt;2.c.iii.&lt;/strong&gt; Strengthen laboratory capacity (including through international specimen referral as needed), and support within-country decentralized access to testing, wherever feasible, for the diagnosis of monkeypox virus infection, and related surveillance, based on the use of nucleic acid amplification testing (NAAT), such as real time or conventional polymerase chain reaction (PCR).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.who.int/publications-detail-redirect/WHO-MPX-laboratory-2022.1"&gt;https://www.who.int/publications/i/item/WHO-MPX-laboratory-2022.1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EXTENDED&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;strong&gt;2.c.iv.&lt;/strong&gt; Strengthen genomic sequencing, and international specimen referral capacities, building on existing sequencing capacities worldwide, to determine circulating virus clades and their evolution, and share genetic sequence data through publicly accessible databases. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.who.int/publications-detail-redirect/WHO-MPX-laboratory-2022.1"&gt;https://www.who.int/publications/i/item/WHO-MPX-laboratory-2022.1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MODIFIED&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;strong&gt;2.c.v.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;Isolate cases for the duration of the infectious period. Policies related to the isolation of cases should encompass health, psychological, material and essential support to adequate living. Any adjustment of isolation policies late in the isolation period should entail the mitigation of any residual public health risk. Advise cases,&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;during the isolation period, on how to minimise the risk of onward transmission.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.who.int/publications-detail-redirect/WHO-MPX-Clinical-and-IPC-2022.1"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.who.int/publications-detail-redirect/WHO-MPX-Clinical-and-IPC-2022.1"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.who.int/publications/i/item/WHO-MPX-Clinical-and-IPC-2022.1"&gt;https://www.who.int/publications/i/item/WHO-MPX-Clinical-and-IPC-2022.1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.who.int/news-room/public-advice/protecting-yourself-from-monkeypox"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.who.int/news-room/public-advice/protecting-yourself-from-monkeypox"&gt;Public advice on protecting yourself from monkeypox (who.int)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.who.int/news-room/public-advice/recovering-from-monkeypox-at-home"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.who.int/news-room/public-advice/recovering-from-monkeypox-at-home"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.who.int/news-room/public-advice/recovering-from-monkeypox-at-home"&gt;Public advice on recovering from monkeypox at home (who.int)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;REMOVED (merged with previous)&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;strong&gt;2.c.vi.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt; D&lt;/strong&gt;uring the isolation period, cases should be advised on how to minimise the risk of onward transmission.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EXTENDED&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;strong&gt;2.c.vii.&lt;/strong&gt; Conduct contact tracing among individuals in contact with anyone who may be a suspected, probable, or confirmed case of monkeypox, including: contact identification (protected by confidentiality), management, and follow-up for 21 days through health monitoring that may be self-directed or supported by public health officers. Policies related to the management of contacts should encompass health, psychological, material and essential support to adequate living.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.who.int/publications-detail-redirect/WHO-MPX-Surveillance-2022.3"&gt;https://www.who.int/publications/i/item/WHO-MPX-Surveillance-2022.3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EXTENDED&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;strong&gt;2.c.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;viii.&lt;/strong&gt; Consider the targeted use of second- or third-generation smallpox or monkeypox vaccines (hereafter referred to as vaccine(s)) for post-exposure prophylaxis in contacts, including household, sexual and other contacts of community cases and health workers where there may have been a breach of personal protective equipment (PPE). &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.who.int/publications/i/item/WHO-MPX-Immunization-2022.2-eng"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.who.int/publications-detail-redirect/WHO-MPX-Immunization-2022.2-eng"&gt;https://www.who.int/publications/i/item/WHO-MPX-Immunization-2022.2-eng&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://cdn.who.int/media/docs/default-source/immunization/sage/2022/october/highlights_sage_oct_2022.pdf?sfvrsn=69f947c4_5"&gt;highlights_sage_oct_2022.pdf (who.int)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MODIFIED&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;strong&gt;2.c.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;vix.&lt;/strong&gt; Consider the use of vaccines for primary preventive (pre-exposure) vaccination, particularly for persons and communities at high risk of exposure. Persons at highest risk of exposure in the multi-country outbreak are gay, bisexual or other MSM with multiple partners. Others at risk may include individuals with multiple casual sexual partners, sex workers, and those who may be exposed and at risk for more severe disease. Those at risk may also include health workers at risk of repeated exposure, laboratory personnel working with orthopoxviruses, and clinical laboratory personnel performing diagnostic testing for monkeypox. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.who.int/publications/i/item/WHO-MPX-Immunization-2022.2-eng"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.who.int/publications-detail-redirect/WHO-MPX-Immunization-2022.2-eng"&gt;https://www.who.int/publications/i/item/WHO-MPX-Immunization-2022.2-eng&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://cdn.who.int/media/docs/default-source/immunization/sage/2022/october/highlights_sage_oct_2022.pdf?sfvrsn=69f947c4_5"&gt;highlights_sage_oct_2022.pdf (who.int)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.who.int/publications/m/item/public-health-advice-for-sex-workers-on-monkeypox"&gt;Public health advice for sex workers on monkeypox (who.int)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EXTENDED&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;strong&gt;2.c.ix.&lt;/strong&gt; Convene the National Immunization Technical Advisory Group for any decision about immunization policy and the use of vaccines. These should be informed by risks-benefits analysis. In all circumstances, vaccinees should be informed of the time required for protective immunity potentially offered by vaccination to be effective. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.who.int/publications/i/item/WHO-MPX-Immunization-2022.2-eng"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.who.int/publications-detail-redirect/WHO-MPX-Immunization-2022.2-eng"&gt;https://www.who.int/publications/i/item/WHO-MPX-Immunization-2022.2-eng&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EXTENDED&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;strong&gt;2.c.xi.&lt;/strong&gt; Engage the communities at high risk of exposure in the decision-making process regarding any vaccine roll out.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.who.int/publications/i/item/WHO-MPX-Immunization-2022.2-eng"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.who.int/publications-detail-redirect/WHO-MPX-Immunization-2022.2-eng"&gt;https://www.who.int/publications/i/item/WHO-MPX-Immunization-2022.2-eng&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ADDED&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;strong&gt;2.c.xii.&lt;/strong&gt; Undertake thorough risk assessments, prepare for, and rapidly respond to any case or outbreak of monkeypox in congregate settings including hospitals, prisons, migrant worker residences, or other situations where population density may be high, including facilities for internally displaced persons or refugees. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-sf-ec-immutable=""&gt;20221019_Monkeypox_external_sitrep-8.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EXTENDED&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;strong&gt;2.d. Clinical management and infection prevention and control&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MODIFIED&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;strong&gt;2.d.i.&lt;/strong&gt; Establish and use recommended clinical care pathways and protocols for the screening, triage, isolation, testing, and clinical assessment of suspected cases of persons with monkeypox in all clinical settings where persons with compatible clinical syndromes may present, including but not limited to urgent or primary care, sexual health services and dermatology clinics; provide training to health care providers accordingly and monitor implementation of those protocols.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.who.int/publications/i/item/WHO-MPX-Clinical-and-IPC-2022.1"&gt;https://www.who.int/publications/i/item/WHO-MPX-Clinical-and-IPC-2022.1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EXTENDED&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;strong&gt;2.d.ii.&lt;/strong&gt; Establish and implement protocols related to infection prevention and control (IPC) measures, encompassing engineering and administrative and the use of PPE; provide training to health care providers accordingly, and monitor the implementation of those protocols.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.who.int/publications/i/item/WHO-MPX-Clinical-and-IPC-2022.1"&gt;https://www.who.int/publications/i/item/WHO-MPX-Clinical-and-IPC-2022.1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EXTENDED&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;strong&gt;2.d.iii.&lt;/strong&gt; Provide health and laboratory workers with adequate PPE, as appropriate for health facility and laboratory settings, and provide all personnel with training in the use of PPE.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.who.int/publications/i/item/WHO-MPX-Clinical-and-IPC-2022.1"&gt;https://www.who.int/publications/i/item/WHO-MPX-Clinical-and-IPC-2022.1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MODIFIED&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;strong&gt;2.d.iv.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;Establish, update, and implement evidence-based clinical protocols for the care and management of patients with uncomplicated monkeypox (e.g., keeping lesions clean, pain control, and maintaining adequate hydration and nutrition) and the various manifestations of severe disease; prevention and treatment of acute complications; and monitoring and management of mid- or long-term sequelae, including provision of social and psychological support where needed. Establish monkeypox case detection and care through integrated approaches with established sexual health and HIV prevention and care services, including through community engagement with civil society organizations.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.who.int/publications/i/item/WHO-MPX-Clinical-and-IPC-2022.1"&gt;https://www.who.int/publications/i/item/WHO-MPX-Clinical-and-IPC-2022.1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://cms.who.int/news-room/public-advice/recovering-from-monkeypox-at-home"&gt;Public advice on recovering from monkeypox at home (who.int)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EXTENDED&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;strong&gt;2.d.v.&lt;/strong&gt; Harmonise data collection and report clinical outcomes, using the WHO Global Clinical Platform for Monkeypox.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.who.int/tools/global-clinical-platform/monkeypox"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.who.int/tools/global-clinical-platform/monkeypox"&gt;https://www.who.int/tools/global-clinical-platform/monkeypox&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EXTENDED&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;strong&gt;2.e. Medical countermeasures and research&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EXTENDED&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;strong&gt;2.e.i.&lt;/strong&gt; Make all efforts to use existing or new vaccines against monkeypox within a framework of collaborative clinical efficacy studies, using standardized design methods and data collection tools for clinical and outcome data, to rapidly increase evidence generation on efficacy and safety, collect data on effectiveness of vaccines (e.g., such as comparison of one or two dose vaccine regimens), and conduct vaccine effectiveness studies.&lt;a href="https://www.who.int/publications/i/item/WHO-MPX-Immunization-2022.2-eng"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.who.int/publications-detail-redirect/WHO-MPX-Immunization-2022.2-eng"&gt;Vaccines and immunization for monkeypox: Interim guidance&lt;/a&gt;; &lt;a href="https://www.who.int/news-room/events/detail/2022/08/02/default-calendar/who-monkeypox-research---what-study-designs-can-be-used-to-address-the-remaining-knowledge-gaps-for-monkeypox-vaccines"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.who.int/news-room/events/detail/2022/08/02/default-calendar/who-monkeypox-research---what-study-designs-can-be-used-to-address-the-remaining-knowledge-gaps-for-monkeypox-vaccines"&gt;WHO Monkeypox research - Study designs to address knowledge gaps for monkeypox vaccines&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EXTENDED&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;strong&gt;2.e.ii.&lt;/strong&gt; Make all efforts to use existing or new therapeutics and antiviral agents for the treatment of monkeypox cases within a framework of collaborative clinical efficacy studies, using standardized design methods and data collection tools for clinical and outcome data, to rapidly increase evidence generation on efficacy and safety.&lt;sup&gt; &lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.who.int/publications/i/item/WHO-MPX-Clinical-and-IPC-2022.1"&gt;https://www.who.int/publications/i/item/WHO-MPX-Clinical-and-IPC-2022.1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.who.int/tools/global-clinical-platform/monkeypox"&gt;The WHO Global Clinical Platform for Monkeypox&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.who.int/publications/m/item/core-protocol---an-international-adaptive-multi-country-randomized-placebo-controlled--double-blinded-trial-of-the-safety-and-efficacy-of-treatments-for-patients-with-monkeypox-virus-disease"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.who.int/publications/m/item/core-protocol---an-international-adaptive-multi-country-randomized-placebo-controlled--double-blinded-trial-of-the-safety-and-efficacy-of-treatments-for-patients-with-monkeypox-virus-disease"&gt;WHO CORE PROTOCOL - An international adaptive multi-country randomized, placebo-controlled, double-blinded trial of the safety and efficacy of treatments for patients with monkeypox virus disease&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EXTENDED&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;strong&gt;2.e.iii.&lt;/strong&gt; When the use of vaccines and antivirals for monkeypox in the context of a collaborative research framework is not possible, use under expanded access protocols can be considered, such as the Monitored Emergency Use of Unregistered and Investigational Interventions (MEURI), under certain circumstances, using harmonized data collection for clinical outcomes (such as &lt;a href="https://cms.who.int/tools/global-clinical-platform/monkeypox"&gt;the WHO Global Clinical Platform for Monkeypox&lt;/a&gt;). &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.who.int/publications/i/item/9789240041745"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.who.int/publications-detail-redirect/9789240041745"&gt;https://www.who.int/publications/i/item/9789240041745&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ADDED&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;strong&gt;2.e.iv.&lt;/strong&gt; Encourage, support and facilitate data gathering and priority research in areas of work relevant to monkeypox, including but not limited to disease transmission and the natural history of disease; diagnostics and innovative technologies including point-of-care tests, viral kinetics across specimen types and animal diagnostics; behavioural insights research and studies on effectiveness of interventions; exposure risk for health workers and&amp;nbsp;pre- and post-exposure management; research on zoonotic transmission of monkeypox at the human-animal-environment interface, including, socio-economic and behavioural risk factors, and&amp;nbsp; indications for environmental surveillance in wastewater. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.who.int/publications/m/item/monkeypox-strategic-preparedness--readiness--and-response-plan-(sprp)"&gt;https://www.who.int/publications/m/item/monkeypox-strategic-preparedness--readiness--and-response-plan-(sprp)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.who.int/teams/blueprint/monkeypox"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.who.int/teams/blueprint/monkeypox"&gt;WHO R&amp;amp;D blueprint and monkeypox&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.who.int/news/item/17-10-2022-one-health-joint-plan-of-action-launched-to-address-health-threats-to-humans--animals--plants-and-environment"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.who.int/news/item/17-10-2022-one-health-joint-plan-of-action-launched-to-address-health-threats-to-humans--animals--plants-and-environment"&gt;One Health Joint Plan of Action to address health threats to humans, animals, plants and environment &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.woah.org/en/disease/monkeypox/"&gt;Monkeypox - World Organisation for Animal Health&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MODIFIED&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;strong&gt; 2.f. Domestic and international travel &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MODIFIED&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;strong&gt; 2.f.i.&lt;/strong&gt; Adopt and apply the following measures:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p data-list="24" data-level="1"&gt;-&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Any individual who is considered a suspected, probable, or confirmed case of monkeypox by jurisdictional health authorities should avoid undertaking any travel, including international travel, until they are cleared to do so. Anyone who is unwell should be advised to seek medical attention prior to travel. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p data-list="24" data-level="1"&gt;-&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Any individual who has been identified as a contact of a monkeypox case, and is therefore subject to health monitoring, should avoid undertaking any travel, including international travel, while under the health monitoring period, except for contacts for whom pre-departure arrangements to ensure continuity of health monitoring are agreed upon by the health authorities concerned, or, in the case of international travel, between national health authorities. &lt;a href="https://www.who.int/publications-detail-redirect/WHO-MPX-Surveillance-2022.3"&gt;https://www.who.int/publications/i/item/WHO-MPX-Surveillance-2022.3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Exemptions apply for any person who is a case or contact and who may need to undertake travel to seek urgent medical care or flee from life threatening situations, such as conflict or natural disasters. &lt;em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.who.int/publications-detail-redirect/WHO-MPX-Surveillance-2022.3"&gt;https://www.who.int/publications/i/item/WHO-MPX-Surveillance-2022.3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p data-list="24" data-level="1"&gt;-&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Cross-border workers, who are identified as contacts of a monkeypox case, and, hence, under health monitoring, can continue their routine daily activities provided that health monitoring is duly coordinated by the jurisdictional health authorities from both/all sides of the border.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EXTENDED&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;strong&gt;2.f.ii.&lt;/strong&gt; Establish operational channels between health authorities, transportation authorities, and conveyances and points of entry operators to:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p data-list="15" data-level="1"&gt;-&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Facilitate international contact tracing in relation to individuals who have developed signs and symptoms compatible with monkeypox virus infection during travel or upon return;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p data-list="15" data-level="1"&gt;-&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Provide communication materials at points of entry on signs and symptoms consistent with monkeypox; infection prevention and control; and on how to seek medical care at the place of destination;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EXTENDED&lt;/strong&gt;: WHO advises against any additional general or targeted international travel-related measures other than those specified in paragraphs &lt;strong&gt;2.f.i and 2.f.ii&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MODIFIED&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;strong&gt;Zoonotic transmission (3):&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;States Parties, with known or suspected zoonotic transmission of monkeypox, including those where zoonotic transmission is known to occur or has been reported in the past, those where presence of monkeypoxvirus has been documented in any animal species, and those where infection of animals may be suspected or anticipated including in domestic pets, livestock or wildlife in newly affected countries. These recommendations apply to all States Parties.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EXTENDED&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;strong&gt;3.a. &lt;/strong&gt;Establish or activate collaborative One Health coordination or other mechanisms at federal, national, subnational and/or local level, as relevant, between public health, veterinary, and wildlife authorities for understanding, monitoring and managing the risk of animal-to-human and human-to-animal transmission in natural habitats, forested and other wild or managed environments, wildlife reserves, domestic and peri-domestic settings, zoos, pet shops, animal shelters and any settings where animals may come into contact with domestic waste.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.who.int/news/item/17-10-2022-one-health-joint-plan-of-action-launched-to-address-health-threats-to-humans--animals--plants-and-environment"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.who.int/news/item/17-10-2022-one-health-joint-plan-of-action-launched-to-address-health-threats-to-humans--animals--plants-and-environment"&gt;One Health Joint Plan of Action to address health threats to humans, animals, plants and environment &lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.woah.org/en/disease/monkeypox/"&gt;Monkeypox - WOAH - World Organisation for Animal Health&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MODIFIED&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;strong&gt;3.b.&lt;/strong&gt; Undertake detailed case investigations and studies to characterize transmission patterns, including suspected or documented spillovers from, and spillback, to animals. In all settings, and particularly for States Parties in the African and Eastern Mediterranean Regions, case investigation forms should be updated and adapted to elicit information on the full range of possible exposures and modes of both zoonotic and human-to-human transmission, including through sexual contact. Share the findings of these endeavours including ongoing case reporting with WHO.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.who.int/publications/i/item/WHO-MPX-Clinical_CRF-2022.3"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.who.int/publications-detail-redirect/WHO-MPX-Clinical_CRF-2022.3"&gt;https://www.who.int/publications/i/item/WHO-MPX-Clinical_CRF-2022.3&amp;nbsp; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MODIFIED&lt;/strong&gt;: Development and deployment of &lt;strong&gt;medical countermeasures (4):&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt; These recommendations applies to all &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;States Parties, and particularly including those with capacity to innovate, develop and/or manufacture medical countermeasures&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MODIFIED&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;strong&gt;4.a.&lt;/strong&gt; States Parties should pursue and/or support research, development and manufacturing capacity for monkeypox diagnostics, vaccines or therapeutics to enhance availability in an equitable manner and raise production. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.who.int/publications/m/item/monkeypox-strategic-preparedness--readiness--and-response-plan-(sprp)"&gt;https://www.who.int/publications/m/item/monkeypox-strategic-preparedness--readiness--and-response-plan-(sprp)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.who.int/publications/m/item/who-emergency-appeal--monkeypox---july-2022---june-2023"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.who.int/publications/m/item/who-emergency-appeal--monkeypox---july-2022---june-2023"&gt;WHO Emergency Appeal: Monkeypox - July 2022 &amp;ndash; June 2023&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EXTENDED&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;strong&gt;4.b.&lt;/strong&gt; States Parties and manufacturers should work with WHO to ensure diagnostics, vaccines, therapeutics, and other necessary supplies are made available based on equity, public health needs, solidarity and at reasonable cost to countries where they are most needed to support efforts to stop the onward spread of monkeypox.&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.who.int/publications/m/item/monkeypox-strategic-preparedness--readiness--and-response-plan-(sprp)"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.who.int/publications/m/item/monkeypox-strategic-preparedness--readiness--and-response-plan-(sprp)"&gt;https://www.who.int/publications/m/item/monkeypox-strategic-preparedness--readiness--and-response-plan-(sprp)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;; &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.who.int/publications/m/item/who-emergency-appeal--monkeypox---july-2022---june-2023"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.who.int/publications/m/item/who-emergency-appeal--monkeypox---july-2022---june-2023"&gt;WHO Emergency Appeal: Monkeypox - July 2022 &amp;ndash; June 2023&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p align="center"&gt;===&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2022 13:01:29 Z</pubDate></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">urn:uuid:995e8b29-193f-4b19-9721-20aad52ce59e</guid><link>https://www.who.int/news/item/28-10-2022-act-accelerator-launches-six-month-plan-as-world-transitions-to-long-term-covid-19-control</link><a10:author><a10:name> </a10:name></a10:author><title>ACT-Accelerator launches six month plan as world transitions to long-term COVID-19 control</title><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Plan sets out the partnership&amp;rsquo;s key priorities and ways of working, as countries transition to managing COVID-19 as a long-term public health issue&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;The plan&amp;rsquo;s focus is on vaccinating high-risk populations, introducing new treatments, boosting testing and securing sustained access to COVID-19 tools&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;The Access to COVID-19 Tools Accelerator is a global collaboration to accelerate development, production, and equitable access to COVID-19 tests, treatments, and vaccines.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Access to COVID-19 Tools (ACT) Accelerator today launches its plan for the next six months, setting out how, as a partnership of global health agencies working alongside government, civil society and other partners, it will support countries as the world transitions to long-term COVID-19 control.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Recognizing the evolving nature of the COVID-19 virus and pandemic, the plan outlines changes to ACT-A&amp;rsquo;s set-up and ways of working, to ensure countries continue to have access to COVID-19 tools in the longer term, while maintaining the coalition&amp;rsquo;s readiness to help address future disease surges.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Developed through a consultative process with ACT-A agencies, donors, industry partners, civil society organizations (CSOs) and Facilitation Council members, the plan summarizes priority areas of focus for the partnership&amp;rsquo;s pillars, coordination mechanisms and other core functions, and highlights the work to be maintained, transitioned, sunset, or kept on standby. The transition plan supports the work of ACT-A agencies as they evolve the financing, implementation and mainstreaming of their COVID-19 efforts.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The next phase of ACT-A partners&amp;rsquo; work will centre on three overarching areas:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Focusing research and development (R&amp;amp;D) and market shaping activities &lt;/strong&gt;to ensure a pipeline for new and enhanced COVID-19 tools&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Securing institutional arrangements &lt;/strong&gt;for sustained access for all countries to COVID-19 vaccines, tests and treatments, including oxygen&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Concentrating in-country &lt;/strong&gt;work on new product introduction (e.g., new oral antivirals for those at highest risk) and protection of priority populations (e.g., full vaccination of health care workers and older populations), in support of national and international targets&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;As the world moves towards managing COVID-19 over the long-term, ACT-A will continue to support countries by providing access to vaccines, tests, and treatments," said WHO Director-General Dr Tedros Adhanom Ghebreyesus. "But as this plan lays out, we still have a lot of work to do to achieve equitable access to these life-saving tools, with health workers and at-risk populations as our top priority.&amp;rdquo; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Other changes outlined in the plan include the transition to a new ACT-A Tracking and Monitoring Taskforce, co-chaired by senior officials of India and the US, with the political-level Facilitation Council going into &amp;lsquo;standby&amp;rsquo; mode, with the capacity to reactivate if needed due to a surge in severe disease.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;ACT-A agencies have driven resource mobilization efforts and this plan sets out the shift to mainstream partnership-level financing and resource mobilization into the regular work of each agency going forward. Based on the three over-arching areas of work outlined above, existing financial commitments and country demand for tools, the ACT-A agencies require an estimated US$400 million for their transition work over the next six months. &amp;nbsp;The ACT-A hub will continue to provide a transparent view of ACT-A agencies&amp;rsquo; financing situation during this period.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The ACT-Accelerator is the world&amp;rsquo;s only end-to-end solution for accelerating the development of, and equitable access to, COVID-19 vaccines, tests and treatments. This partnership has played a key role in facilitating access to COVID-19 countermeasures for low- and lower-middle-income countries throughout the pandemic, most notably:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Providing more than 1.8 billion doses of vaccine to 146 countries and territories &amp;ndash; including 75% of the vaccines deployed in low-income countries and the majority of doses supplied to Africa &amp;ndash; through COVAX, the vaccines pillar led by CEPI, Gavi, WHO and UNICEF.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Delivering over 161 million tests, more than halving the cost of rapid tests to under $1 per test, and supplying around 80% of tests used in Africa in the first year of the pandemic through the Diagnostics Pillar led by FIND and the Global Fund. &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Delivering over 40 million COVID-19 treatment courses, investing an unprecedented US$ 1 billion in expanding sustainable oxygen access in LMICs, and initiating the delivery of new antivirals, through the Therapeutics Pillar, led by the Global Fund, Unitaid and Wellcome.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Delivering over 2 billion items of personal protective equipment (PPE), supporting health systems to deliver COVID-19 tools, and boosting their laboratory, waste management and treatment capacities, through the Health Systems and Response Connector, led by the Global Fund, WHO and the World Bank. &lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Transition Plan can be accessed &lt;a href="https://www.who.int/publications/m/item/act-accelerator-transition-plan-(1-oct-2022-to-31-mar-2023)"&gt;here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong style="background-color:transparent;text-align:inherit;text-transform:inherit;white-space:inherit;word-spacing:normal;caret-color:auto;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong style="background-color:transparent;text-align:inherit;text-transform:inherit;white-space:inherit;word-spacing:normal;caret-color:auto;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;QUOTE SHEET&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Seth Berkley, CEO of Gavi, the Vaccine Alliance: &lt;/strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;As the lead agencies of COVAX, our goal is to continually evolve to meet the needs of the communities we serve. This ability to adapt to the changing pandemic environment and its challenges has helped COVAX enable a historic global rollout at scale in the face of an unprecedented emergency. Through 2023, COVAX will continue to support lower-income countries to protect their populations. In parallel, we will be supporting countries to integrate COVID-19 vaccination into routine national immunization programs, while also preparing for surges and other worst-case scenarios.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ted Chaiban, Global Lead Coordinator for COVID Vaccine Country Readiness and Delivery, said: &amp;ldquo;&lt;/strong&gt;COVID-19 vaccine delivery is most successful when it is country-driven and partners align to support government ownership by accelerating funding disbursement, leveraging political engagement, and providing technical advice and assistance. Looking to the future, it's important to have a mechanism in place grounded in the multilateral system that ensures equity in all phases of future pandemics (prevention, preparation, and response) and strengthens essential health systems.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dr Philippe Duneton, Executive Director of Unitaid, said: &lt;/strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;As part of the global response to COVID-19, Unitaid, co-leader of the ACT-Accelerator's therapeutics pillar, and partners have improved access to critical oxygen supplies and facilitated adoption of life-saving therapeutics alongside vital diagnostic tests. But this is not the end of it, much work remains to be done. Despite uncertainties on how the pandemic will evolve, we must focus on building resilience at market and country level in light of unpredictable and fast evolving scenarios. COVID-19 has shown us that reaching equitable global access to medical countermeasures requires a continuum between pandemic preparedness and response efforts.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sir Jeremy Farrar, Director of Wellcome, said: &lt;/strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s now almost three years since Covid-19 was first discovered and no one can say for certain what will happen next. What we do know is that we can&amp;rsquo;t afford to be complacent. This pandemic is not over. We still need to improve access to vaccines, treatments and tests globally, which means fully funding the ACT-Accelerator. The Accelerator has played a pivotal, and at times lonely, role in pushing for global equity and access to be at the heart of the pandemic response, despite many of the world&amp;rsquo;s advanced economies taking a very nationalistic approach to the sharing of these lifesaving tools.&lt;em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s vital we maintain an integrated and equitable approach to this phase of the pandemic through ACT-A, invest in developing new vaccines &amp;ndash; ones that can block infection and transmission &amp;ndash; and better treatments, and continue testing and sequencing the virus globally. Only then can we stop Covid-19 circulating and avoid a new variant emerging that overcomes our hard-won defences.&amp;rdquo;&amp;nbsp; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dr Richard Hatchett, CEO of CEPI, said: &lt;/strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;Much of the world has moved into a phase of coexisting with COVID-19, but we must remain vigilant against the persistent and evolving threat that the virus represents and continue to strive for equity in terms of access to vaccines and other countermeasures. In parallel, we must continue to evolve new and better countermeasures, which provide broader immunity and can be more easily produced, while building sustainable platforms to manufacture them. For that reason global leaders must sustain their support for COVAX, ACT-A and their constituent agencies.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dr Bill Rodriguez, CEO of FIND, said:&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;ldquo;Diagnostics are a critical enabler of health for all and were among the first tools deployed via ACT-A in collaboration with in-country partners. We are now entering a new phase of managing COVID-19 and stand ready to work alongside countries to integrate testing into routine health programmes, ensuring that those in need can be linked to timely treatment, while maintaining vigilance and readiness for potential new waves.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Catherine Russell, Executive Director of UNICEF, said: &lt;/strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;The impact of the pandemic continues to threaten decades of progress for children, so the work of the ACT-A partnership is as important as ever. UNICEF will continue working with our ACT-A partners to ensure that every country and community has equitable access to the vaccines and tools they need to combat the COVID-19 virus &amp;ndash; and to strengthen primary health systems and other vital services like routine immunization that can save children&amp;rsquo;s lives and help them fulfil their potential.&amp;rdquo;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Peter Sands, Executive Director of the Global Fund, said: &lt;/strong&gt;"As the world transitions towards managing COVID-19 in the longer term and preparing for the next pandemics, the Global Fund will continue working with its ACT-Accelerator partners towards building stronger health systems and ensuring equitable and efficient procurement of life-saving products.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2022 09:51:29 Z</pubDate></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">urn:uuid:7d3b2d98-ebd0-4f50-ad09-b0c351bae115</guid><link>https://www.who.int/news/item/28-10-2022-on-world-cities-day-2022--who-calls-on-countries-to--act-local-to-go-global</link><a10:author><a10:name> </a10:name></a10:author><title>On World Cities Day 2022, WHO calls on countries to “Act Local to Go Global”</title><description>&lt;p&gt;By 2050, nearly 7 out of 10 people globally will live in cities and other urban settings. While cities face many health challenges, on World Cities Day 2022 WHO and partners examine how city leaders are uniquely positioned to understand local needs and respond rapidly to changing conditions to safeguard health. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Although living in cities brings many advantages, rapid and unplanned urbanization can have negative social and environmental health impacts. These include not only issues linked to climate change, pandemics and noncommunicable diseases, but also to malaria and other vector-borne diseases. While the burden of malaria is currently still higher in rural areas, current trends in urbanization mean that in a few years most people living in malaria-endemic countries will reside in urban areas.&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this regard, and on the occasion of World Cities Day 2022, WHO and UN Habitat have produced the &lt;em&gt;Global f&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;ramework for the response to malaria in urban areas&lt;/em&gt;. The Framework provides guidance to city government officials, health professionals and urban planners for a comprehensive malaria response specifically in urban areas, where the dynamics of transmission and burden of vector-borne diseases can be different from that of rural areas. The Framework acknowledges that the global fight against malaria and other vector-borne diseases requires strong action from local governments, in areas such as health, housing and infrastructure.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;By offering specific guidance to local officials, this new Framework can help ensure that malaria control forms an integral part of the broader urban planning, policy-making and budgeting processes,&amp;rdquo; explains Dr Abdisalan Noor, Head of the Strategic Information for Response Unit in the WHO Global Malaria Programme. &amp;ldquo;For each urban context, the strategic use of data can inform effective, tailored responses and help build resilience against the threat of malaria and other vector-borne diseases.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On World Cities Day 2022, WHO is also launching the &lt;em&gt;Urban health research agenda&lt;/em&gt;, a comprehensive strategy to help cities build better evidence around what works to address urban health challenges. The agenda calls for building evidence on the environmental, economic and social impacts of urban health policies, so that they can be addressed through a coordinated approach that involves the different sectors working together to improve the health of their residents. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We desperately need to get ahead of the challenges that are impacting the health and well-being of people living in cities,&amp;rdquo; notes Dr Etienne Krug, Director of the Department of Social Determinants of Health at WHO. &amp;ldquo;Strong urban policies must prioritize health, to ensure resilient and vibrant communities for people to live, work, go to school and play, all while protecting those who are most vulnerable.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Urban health is a growing priority for WHO, which addresses the issue in multiple cross-cutting ways, such as better air quality, a safe water supply and improved sanitation; healthy urban planning; smoke-free environments; road safety; prevention of violence and injuries; healthy food systems and diets; environmental management of vector-borne diseases; and preparedness for health and humanitarian emergencies. Addressing the needs of specific population groups, such as children and older people and migrants, is also a priority.&amp;nbsp;The interlinked nature of urban health challenges means that action in one sector can have benefits for many others.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;To help Member States address the above priorities, WHO is supporting the strengthening of the evidence base to allow policy-makers to make informed decisions when addressing health risks. We provide tools and guidance on what works and support monitoring of key health-related indicators. In addition, we lead and engage in partnership activities that foster city-to-city exchanges and help develop institutional and policy frameworks for good governance for health and well-being in cities.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2022 08:59:26 Z</pubDate></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">urn:uuid:da88f60f-7448-4878-8ef0-306ff20bd331</guid><link>https://www.who.int/news/item/28-10-2022-who-launches-4th-health-for-all-film-festival</link><a10:author><a10:name> </a10:name></a10:author><title>WHO launches 4th Health for All Film Festival</title><description>&lt;p&gt;WHO has launched a call for short films for the 4th edition of the Health for All Film Festival.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The WHO Health for All Film Festival has become an incredible platform for telling powerful stories from around the world about people who face all kinds of health challenges, and those who devote their lives to improving health,&amp;rdquo; said WHO Director-General, Dr Tedros Adhanom Ghebreyesus. &amp;ldquo;Films provide an authentic way for affected people to connect with others and contribute to a better understanding of the communities we serve.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The call for short films (up to 8 minutes long) opens on 31 October 2022 and will close on 31 January 2023. WHO invites public institutions, nongovernmental organizations, communities of patients and of health workers, students in public health and film schools from around the world to submit their original short film. The festival is also open to independent film-makers, production companies and TV broadcasters.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Around 70 shortlisted films will be presented to the public in April 2023 via WHO&amp;rsquo;s Youtube channel and &lt;a href="https://www.who.int/initiatives/the-health-for-all-film-festival"&gt;website&lt;/a&gt;. From this list, a jury of distinguished professionals, artists, activists and senior experts at WHO will select the award-winning films. Sharon Stone, critically acclaimed actress from the USA and public advocate of health and humanitarian issues, has confirmed that she will join the jury again in 2023, having participated in the 2022 festival. (&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/ahM7dwXZs8k"&gt;https://youtu.be/ahM7dwXZs8k&lt;/a&gt;). &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Three &amp;ldquo;GRAND PRIX&amp;rdquo; will be awarded, one for each main category, aligned with WHO&amp;rsquo;s major global public health goals: universal health coverage, health emergencies, better health and wellbeing. There will also be special prizes for films about climate change and health, sexual and reproductive health and rights, a student-produced film, and a very short film (1&amp;rsquo; to 2&amp;rsquo;30&amp;rdquo; in length).&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Winning films from the festival are helping to increase awareness and support for key health issues worldwide. With an average of&amp;nbsp;1150 submissions each year from 110 countries, the films are increasingly being used by other institutions and partners for health promotion and education, and future synergies are being explored with WHO Academy and &lt;a href="https://www.who.int/initiatives/behavioural-sciences"&gt;WHO Behavioural Insights programme&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Storytelling is an engagement between people. It&amp;rsquo;s not just someone making a film, it&amp;rsquo;s someone watching a film,&amp;rdquo; said WHO Executive Director of Health Emergencies Programme, Dr Mike Ryan, film festival juror in 2021.&amp;nbsp;&amp;ldquo;This is exactly how WHO should be transforming: Transforming how we engage with the world and this festival is just one example of how we can change our mindset.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In honour of WHO&amp;rsquo;s 75th anniversary in 2023, this call for films is also exceptionally open to historical films and to recent films by students sharing their vision about current challenges and&amp;nbsp; future solutions to improve health. A special playlist will be created to highlight these testimonies.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p align="center"&gt;* * *&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For more details, visit the multilingual festival website:&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://www.who.int/film-festival" target="_blank"&gt;https://www.who.int/film-festival&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2022 17:17:19 Z</pubDate></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">urn:uuid:4b52623f-cea1-4ce2-a590-781f359f3cae</guid><link>https://www.who.int/news/item/27-10-2022-tag-ve-statement-on-omicron-sublineages-bq.1-and-xbb</link><a10:author><a10:name> </a10:name></a10:author><title>TAG-VE statement on Omicron sublineages BQ.1 and XBB</title><description>&lt;p&gt;As part of its ongoing work to track variants, WHO's Technical Advisory Group on SARS-CoV-2 Virus Evolution (&lt;a href="https://www.who.int/groups/technical-advisory-group-on-sars-cov-2-virus-evolution"&gt;TAG-VE&lt;/a&gt;) met on the 24 October 2022 to discuss the latest evidence on the Omicron variant of concern, and how its evolution is currently unfolding, in light of high levels of population immunity in many settings and country differences in the immune landscape. In particular, the public health implications of the rise of some Omicron variants, specifically XBB and its sublineages (indicated as XBB*), as well as BQ.1 and its sublineages (indicated as BQ.1*), were discussed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Based on currently available evidence, the TAG-VE does not feel that the overall phenotype of XBB* and BQ.1* diverge sufficiently from each other, or from other Omicron lineages with additional immune escape mutations, in terms of the necessary public health response, to warrant the designation of new variants of concern and assignment of a new label.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The two sublineages remain part of Omicron, which continues to be a variant of concern.&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This decision will be reassessed regularly. If there is any significant development that warrant a change in public health strategy, WHO will promptly alert Member States and the public.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;XBB*&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;XBB* is a recombinant of BA.2.10.1 and BA.2.75 sublineages. As of epidemiological week 40 (3 to 9 October), from the sequences submitted to GISAID, XBB* has a global prevalence of 1.3% and it has been detected in 35 countries. The TAG-VE discussed the available data on the growth advantage of this sublineage, and some early evidence on clinical severity and reinfection risk from Singapore and India, as well as inputs from other countries. There has been a broad increase in prevalence of XBB* in regional genomic surveillance, but it has not yet been consistently associated with an increase in new infections.&amp;nbsp; While further studies are needed, the current data do not suggest there are substantial differences in disease severity for XBB* infections. There is, however, early evidence pointing at a higher reinfection risk, as compared to other circulating Omicron sublineages. Cases of reinfection were primarily limited to those with initial infection in the pre-Omicron period. As of now, there are no data to support escape from recent immune responses induced by other Omicron lineages. Whether the increased immune escape of XBB* is sufficient to drive new infection waves appears to depend on the regional immune landscape as affected by the size and timing of previous Omicron waves, as well as the COVID-19 vaccination coverage. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BQ.1*&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;BQ.1* is a sublineage of BA.5, which carries spike mutations in some key antigenic sites, including K444T and N460K. In addition to these mutations, the sublineage BQ.1.1 carries an additional spike mutation in a key antigenic site (i.e. R346T). As of epidemiological week 40 (3 to 9 October), from the sequences submitted to GISAID, BQ.1* has a prevalence of 6% and it has been detected in 65 countries. While there are no data on severity or immune escape from studies in humans, BQ.1* is showing a significant growth advantage over other circulating Omicron sublineages in many settings, including Europe and the US, and therefore warrants close monitoring. It is likely that these additional mutations have conferred an immune escape advantage over other circulating Omicron sublineages, and therefore a higher reinfection risk is a possibility that needs further investigation. At this time there is no epidemiologic data to suggest an increase in disease severity. The impact of the observed immunological changes on vaccine escape remains to be established. Based on currently available knowledge, protection by vaccines (both the index and the recently introduced bivalent vaccines) against infection may be reduced but no major impact on protection against severe disease is foreseen.&amp;nbsp; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Overall summary&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Omicron variant of concern remains the dominant variant circulating globally, accounting for nearly all sequences reported to GISAID&lt;a href="file:///C:/Users/areid/AppData/Local/Microsoft/Windows/INetCache/Content.Outlook/8U5EFZ4N/2802022StatementonBQ1andXBB_final.docx#_ftn1" name="_ftnref1"&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt;. While we are looking at a vast genetic diversity of Omicron sublineages, they currently display similar clinical outcomes, but with differences in immune escape potential. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The potential impact of these variants is strongly influenced by the regional immune landscape. While reinfections have become an increasingly higher proportion of all infections, this is primarily seen in the background of non-Omicron primary infections. With waning immune response from initial waves of Omicron infection, and further evolution of Omicron variants, it is likely that reinfections may rise further. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The role of the TAG-VE is to alert WHO if a variant with a substantially different phenotype (e.g. a variant that can cause a more severe disease or lead to large epidemic waves causing increased burden to the healthcare system) is emerging and likely to pose a significant threat. &amp;nbsp;Based on currently available evidence, the TAG-VE does not feel that the overall phenotype of XBB* and BQ.1* diverge sufficiently from each other, or from other Omicron sublineages with additional immune escape mutations, in terms of the necessary public health response, to warrant the designation of a new variant of concern and assignment of a new label, but the situation will be reassessed regularly. We note these two sublineages remain part of Omicron, which is a variant of concern with very high reinfection and vaccination breakthrough potential, and surges in new infections should be handled accordingly. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;While so far there is no epidemiological evidence that these sublineages will be of substantially greater risk compared to other Omicron sublineages, we note that this assessment is based on data from sentinel nations and may not be fully generalizable to other settings. &amp;nbsp;Wide-ranging, systematic laboratory-based efforts are urgently needed to make such determinations rapidly and with global interpretability. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;WHO will continue to closely monitor the XBB* and BQ.1* lineages as part of Omicron and requests countries to continue to be vigilant, to monitor and report sequences, as well as to conduct independent and comparative analyses of the different Omicron sublineages.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The TAG-VE meets regularly and continues to assess the available data on the transmissibility, clinical severity, and immune escape potential of variants, including the potential impact on diagnostics, therapeutics, and the effectiveness of vaccines in preventing infection and/or severe disease.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br clear="all" /&gt;&lt;div id="ftn1"&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="file:///C:/Users/areid/AppData/Local/Microsoft/Windows/INetCache/Content.Outlook/8U5EFZ4N/2802022StatementonBQ1andXBB_final.docx#_ftnref1" name="_ftn1"&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.who.int/publications/m/item/weekly-epidemiological-update-on-covid-19---26-october-2022"&gt;Weekly epidemiological update on COVID-19 - 26 October 2022 (who.int)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2022 17:03:00 Z</pubDate></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">urn:uuid:274fdf07-7c6a-4db7-b7a3-9574f3c84308</guid><link>https://www.who.int/news/item/25-10-2022-who-releases-first-ever-list-of-health-threatening-fungi</link><a10:author><a10:name> </a10:name></a10:author><title>WHO releases first-ever list of health-threatening fungi</title><description>WHO today published a report highlighting the first-ever list of fungal "priority pathogens" – a catalogue of the 19 fungi that represent the greatest threat to public health.  The WHO fungal priority pathogens list (FPPL) is the first global effort to systematically prioritize fungal pathogens, considering the unmet research and development (R&amp;D) needs and the perceived public health importance.</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2022 14:49:44 Z</pubDate><a10:content type="text">&lt;p&gt;WHO today published a report highlighting the first-ever list of fungal "priority pathogens" &amp;ndash; a catalogue of the 19 fungi that represent the greatest threat to public health.&amp;nbsp; The WHO fungal priority pathogens list (FPPL) is the first global effort to systematically prioritize fungal pathogens, considering the unmet research and development (R&amp;amp;D) needs and the perceived public health importance. The WHO FPPL aims to focus and drive further research and policy interventions to strengthen the global response to fungal infections and antifungal resistance.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fungal pathogens are a major threat to public health as they are becoming increasingly common and resistant to treatment with only four classes of antifungal medicines currently available, and few candidates in the clinical pipeline. Most fungal pathogens lack rapid and sensitive diagnostics and those that exist are not widely available or affordable globally. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The invasive forms of these fungal infections often affect severely ill patients and those with significant underlying immune system related conditions. Populations at greatest risk of invasive fungal infections include those with cancer, HIV/AIDS, organ transplants, chronic respiratory disease, and post-primary tuberculosis infection.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Emerging evidence indicates that the incidence and geographic range of fungal diseases are both expanding worldwide due to global warming and the increase of international travel and trade. During the COVID-19 pandemic, the reported incidence of invasive fungal infections increased significantly among hospitalized patients. As the fungi that cause common infections (such as candida oral and vaginal thrush) become increasingly resistant to treatment, risks for the development of more invasive forms of infections in the general population are also growing. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;Emerging from the shadows of the bacterial antimicrobial resistance pandemic, fungal infections are growing, and are ever more resistant to treatments, becoming a public health concern worldwide&amp;rdquo; &lt;/em&gt;said Dr Hanan Balkhy, WHO Assistant Director-General, Antimicrobial Resistance (AMR).&amp;nbsp; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Despite the growing concern, fungal infections receive very little attention and resources, leading to a scarcity of quality data on fungal disease distribution and antifungal resistance patterns. As a result, the exact burden of fungal diseases and antifungal resistance, are unknown, and the response is therefore undermined. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Three priority categories &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The WHO FPPL list is divided into three categories: critical, high and medium priority. The fungal pathogens of &lt;em&gt;in each priority&lt;/em&gt; category are so ranked primarily due to their public health impact and/or emerging antifungal resistance risk. While recognizing these critical pathogens as of public health concern globally, WHO emphases that the FPPL must be interpreted and contextualized carefully, as some endemic pathogens could be of more concern in their respective regional or local contexts.&lt;em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Need for more evidence and priority areas for action&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The authors of the report stress the need for more evidence to inform the response to this growing threat and to better understand the burden &amp;ndash; both of disease and antifungal resistance. The report also highlights the urgent need for coordinated action to address the impact of antifungal use on resistance across the One Health spectrum and calls for expanding equitable access to quality diagnostics and treatments.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;We need more data and evidence on fungal infections and antifungal resistance to inform and improve response to these priority fungal pathogens&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt; said Dr Haileyesus Getahun, WHO Director, AMR Global Coordination Department. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The FPPL report underscores strategies for policymakers, public health professionals and other stakeholders. The strategies proposed in the report are collectively aimed at generating evidence and improving response to these fungal priority pathogens including preventing the development of antifungal drug resistance. The primary recommended actions are focused on: (1) strengthening laboratory capacity and surveillance; (2) sustaining investments in research, development, and innovation; and (3) enhancing public health interventions for prevention and control. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Countries are encouraged to follow a stepwise approach, starting with strengthening their fungal disease laboratory and surveillance capacities, and ensuring equitable access to existing quality therapeutics and diagnostics, globally&amp;rdquo; &lt;/em&gt;added Dr Haileyesus Getahun. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Resistance to antifungal medicines is partly driven by inappropriate antifungal use across the One Health spectrum. For example, injudicious use of antifungals in agriculture was linked to the rising rates of azole-resistant &lt;em&gt;Aspergillus fumigatus&lt;/em&gt; infections. The report also calls for fostering WHO&amp;rsquo;s collaborative effort with the Quadripartite organizations and other partners, to address the impact of antifungal use on resistance across the One Health spectrum.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://cms.who.int/publications/i/item/9789240060241?sf-lc-status=Master&amp;amp;sf-content-action=preview&amp;amp;sf-auth=VzW0tRdljlGGYHFZBJMEV%2f2giy9vbyudj5sOjTE0nxHOIsVlZtWJ5HsT1D3Ik9lY1rAR4FQdQMR4hkFupvU7%2f1lSsKTGW3Lq57Yej6oDhxDNGDHFv61SBVQM8sSjF%2fbTxxAsRF7HMKWHnNlar4Fl07UIHxlsBdeDaVP30kLtFaikr8bSncDluj6M%2b%2fRajG8oWE%2fASv8vReqySjp6bof0HZrd%2fFP4KRI5YzOePRASBx3SunkNFYzM3%2fZLjJX3Uggg0%2bbS9Rmfn3L14y10S2ddVFBDCbv%2ftVZdmvZpFfd%2bWLxgNqVMlD5s4AuyMyMf4UzR4gAAAA%3d%3d" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="https://www.who.int/publications-detail-redirect/9789240060241?sf-lc-status=Master&amp;amp;sf-content-action=preview&amp;amp;sf-auth=VzW0tRdljlGGYHFZBJMEV%2f2giy9vbyudj5sOjTE0nxHOIsVlZtWJ5HsT1D3Ik9lY1rAR4FQdQMR4hkFupvU7%2f1lSsKTGW3Lq57Yej6oDhxDNGDHFv61SBVQM8sSjF%2fbTxxAsRF7HMKWHnNlar4Fl07UIHxlsBdeDaVP30kLtFaikr8bSncDluj6M%2b%2fRajG8oWE%2fASv8vReqySjp6bof0HZrd%2fFP4KRI5YzOePRASBx3SunkNFYzM3%2fZLjJX3Uggg0%2bbS9Rmfn3L14y10S2ddVFBDCbv%2ftVZdmvZpFfd%2bWLxgNqVMlD5s4AuyMyMf4UzR4gAAAA%3d%3d"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.who.int/publications/i/item/9789240060241"&gt;WHO fungal priority pathogens list to guide research, development and public health action report&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</a10:content></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">urn:uuid:4ac77158-2a0b-4b32-b66b-6a9c57386953</guid><link>https://www.who.int/news/item/21-10-2022-world-health-organization-(who)-response-to-the-external-evaluation-of-the-access-to-covid-19-tools-accelerator-(act-a)</link><a10:author><a10:name> </a10:name></a10:author><title>World Health Organization (WHO) response to the External Evaluation of the Access to COVID-19 Tools Accelerator (ACT-A)</title><description>&lt;p&gt;WHO appreciates the broad range of views on the ACT-Accelerator (ACT-A) setup, operations and results that are captured in the External Evaluation, which was commissioned by the ACT-A Facilitation Council. Of particular value in this report are the perspectives expressed by a number of countries in Africa, South America and Asia that used ACT-A processes and services during the pandemic, but whose voices have not always been heard in such reviews.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;While acknowledging the limitations that have been cited by the authors and other commentators, this report does provide important perspectives that add to the growing number of evaluations, reports, reviews and recommendations that aim to inform the establishment of a stronger countermeasures platform. Collectively, this work will help shape efforts to build on the experience of ACT-A and other instruments and initiatives (e.g. the Pandemic Influenza Preparedness (PIP) Framework, the &amp;lsquo;100 Day Mission&amp;rsquo;) to ensure the world can rely on a more robust platform for accelerating the development, and equitable allocation and delivery of countermeasures in future pandemics.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Of particular note in this report is the strong, majority position of survey respondents that the innovative and collaborative ACT-A arrangement was the right approach for accelerating access to COVID-19 countermeasures at a time when the global community needed to act quickly and decisively to combat a poorly understood threat. &amp;nbsp;The report also documents important results that were achieved through the ACT-A approach, including the unprecedented speed of its core agencies in delivering vaccines and diagnostics to the lowest income countries, as compared to previous pandemics, and in driving crucial market interventions that substantially reduced prices and enhanced access to diagnostics, oxygen and antivirals at a critical time. The counterfactual is that in the absence of ACT-A, equity in access to countermeasures would have been much worse.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;WHO concurs with the challenges identified in the areas of the Health Systems Connector (vs. the HSRC) and the quality assurance of rapid diagnostics. With respect to the former, this lesson was learned and corrected in the course of ACT-A, with the Connector being substantially revamped and relaunched in 2021 (a point that is not fully reflected in the report). Addressing gaps in WHO&amp;rsquo;s capacity to assess the very high volume of diagnostics submissions during the course of the pandemic was inherently more challenging and signals the vital need for additional financing and personnel for this area, adjustments to the assessment process for emergency situations, and greater support from collaborating agencies.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The report also reinforces previously identified shortcomings in the ACT-A operating model that were largely the result of the urgency and speed with which ACT-A had to be established.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;These findings support the existing consensus on the vital need to ensure the future countermeasures platform is more inclusive, has greater transparency in its operations and establishes robust mechanisms for collective accountability.&amp;nbsp; The report particularly highlights the need to completely rethink and rework key processes with low- and lower-middle income countries to ensure their full and meaningful engagement.&amp;nbsp; An important omission in this evaluation is an assessment of the role and impact of industry in ACT-A through its participation in the Facilitation Council, Principals Group and some Pillars, and the degree to which this did or did not facilitate the coalition&amp;rsquo;s core objective of ensuring equitable access to vaccines, tests and treatments in real time.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In formulating other recommendations on the way forward, however, the report seems to have based some important conclusions on incomplete information or a misunderstanding of key aspects of the ACT-A collaboration. This appears to be the case in areas such as how targets for product volumes were established, the original ambition for the COVAX Facility, the nature of the COVID Vaccines Delivery Platform (CoVDP) and its mode of operations, and the key role of individual ACT-A agencies in resource mobilization. Most importantly, and contrary to the data presented, the report could inadvertently lead readers to conclude that creating a more robust countermeasures platform is best achieved by starting from scratch, rather than building on the considerable, documented strengths of the ACT-A collaboration and its three product pillars. The framing of an important survey question(s) may have contributed to this perspective. From a pragmatic perspective, it would seem more advantageous to harness and build on the substantial experience that international health agencies and partners have gained through their work in ACT-A, while also addressing the shortcomings of this model.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Notwithstanding these issues, the perspectives captured in this report strongly reinforce the need for an inclusive, robust process that engages countries, relevant international health agencies and organizations, civil society and community organizations, donors, industry and other stakeholders, to co-create a countermeasures platform that is anchored in the principles of speed and equity. This process will need to be informed by all such reviews and experience to optimize upstream operations (e.g. R&amp;amp;D, market shaping), downstream work (e.g. procurement, delivery), collective accountability and financing. WHO will take such a process forward with partners and stakeholders and with urgency, because, as the evaluation report again emphasizes, this cannot wait for the next pandemic.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;WHO is deeply grateful for the extraordinary role that Norway and South Africa have played in co-chairing the ACT-A Facilitation Council throughout these turbulent times, and for commissioning this External Evaluation that is an important contribution to our collective efforts to build a safer, fairer world, together.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2022 14:49:13 Z</pubDate></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">urn:uuid:68358529-fd62-4440-848d-b3e23c438345</guid><link>https://www.who.int/news/item/18-10-2022-statement-on-the-thirteenth-meeting-of-the-international-health-regulations-(2005)-emergency-committee-regarding-the-coronavirus-disease-(covid-19)-pandemic</link><a10:author><a10:name> </a10:name></a10:author><title>Statement on the thirteenth meeting of the International Health Regulations (2005) Emergency Committee regarding the coronavirus disease (COVID-19) pandemic</title><description>The WHO Director-General has the pleasure of transmitting the Report of the thirteenth meeting of the International Health Regulations (2005) (IHR) Emergency Committee regarding the coronavirus 2019 disease (COVID-19) pandemic, held on Thursday, 13 October 2022, from 12:00 to 16:00 CEST.</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 14:23:03 Z</pubDate><a10:content type="text">&lt;p&gt;The WHO Director-General has the pleasure of transmitting the Report of the thirteenth meeting of the International Health Regulations (2005) (IHR) Emergency Committee regarding the coronavirus 2019 disease (COVID-19) pandemic, held on Thursday, 13 October
    2022, from 12:00 to 16:00 CEST.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The WHO Director-General concurs with the advice offered by the Committee regarding the ongoing COVID-19 pandemic and determines that the event continues to constitute a Public Health Emergency of International Concern (PHEIC).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The WHO Director-General considered the advice provided by the Committee regarding the proposed Temporary Recommendations. The set of Temporary Recommendations issued by the WHO Director-General is presented at the end of this statement.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The WHO Director-General expresses his sincere gratitude to the Chair, and Members of the Committee, as well as to the Committee&amp;rsquo;s Advisors.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;===&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Proceedings of the meeting&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The WHO Director-General, Dr Tedros Adhanom Ghebreyesus, welcomed Members and Advisors of the Emergency Committee, all of whom were convened by videoconference.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dr Tedros highlighted that weekly reported COVID-19 deaths have reached levels comparable to the beginning of the pandemic and that almost two-thirds of the world&amp;rsquo;s population has completed a primary course of COVID-19 vaccination. However, he expressed
    concern over persistent inequities in vaccine coverage and access to antiviral and therapeutic treatments between countries, reductions in epidemiological and laboratory surveillance activities for COVID-19 that are necessary to monitor the evolution
    and impact of the virus, and the removal of many public health and social measures ahead of the expected increase in transmission over the coming months, particularly during the approaching winter in the Northern hemisphere.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Representative of the Office of Legal Counsel briefed the Members and Advisors on their roles and responsibilities and the mandate of the Emergency Committee under the relevant articles of the IHR.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Ethics Officer from the Department of Compliance, Risk Management, and Ethics briefed Members and Advisers on their roles and responsibilities. Members and Advisors were also reminded of their duty of confidentiality as to the meeting discussions
    and the work of the Committee, as well as their individual responsibility to disclose to WHO, in a timely manner, any interests of a personal, professional, financial, intellectual or commercial nature that may give rise to a perceived or direct conflict
    of interest. Each Member and Advisor who was present was surveyed. No conflicts of interest were identified.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The meeting was handed over to the Chair of the Emergency Committee regarding the COVID-19 pandemic, Professor Didier Houssin. The Chair introduced the objectives of the meeting: to provide views to the WHO Director-General on whether the COVID-19 pandemic
    continues to constitute a PHEIC, and to review temporary recommendations to States Parties.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The WHO Secretariat presented a global overview of status of the COVID-19 pandemic and highlighted several challenges to the ongoing response. The presentation focused on the global COVID-19 epidemiological situation; the ongoing evolution and unpredictability
    of the virus and the impact of current and future SARS-CoV-2 variants of concern, including descendent lineages of these variants; concurrent circulation of other respiratory viruses including influenza; progress towards WHO COVID-19 vaccination targets,
    including targets for the highest priority groups in all countries; and planning scenarios for the ongoing response to COVID-19 and ending the emergency globally.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Deliberative session&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Committee acknowledged progress in controlling the outbreak in many countries with the number of severe cases and deaths substantially decreased and high levels of population immunity achieved in many countries through vaccination and/or infection,
    leading to resumption of economic and social life and lifting of most COVID-19-related restrictions.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;However, the Committee was concerned that despite being well into the third year of the pandemic, there remained considerable uncertainties as to the further trajectory of the virus as well as to the genetic and antigenic characteristics and clinical
    impact of future variants. The Committee also remained concerned over the increasing challenges in quantifying the broader COVID-19 burden on health systems including thrombotic and endocrine complications as well as the extent and burden of Post
    COVID-19 condition. More broadly, Committee members recognized that many health systems remain under pressure because of other health emergencies and competing health priorities, in addition to the challenges posed by COVID-19. In this context, the
    Committee expressed concern about the heavy workload and associated burnout being experienced by health care workers worldwide, leading to an increased deficit in the workforce.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Committee also expressed concern over the reduction in epidemiological and laboratory surveillance for SARS-CoV-2. This impedes assessments of currently circulating and emerging variants of the virus, including genomic and phenotypic assessments,
    and hinders abilities to interpret trends in transmission and burden of disease. The Committee continued to highlight the importance of expediting the integration of COVID-19 surveillance into other routine surveillance systems, including the integration
    of COVID-19 surveillance with the surveillance of other respiratory pathogens, community-based surveillance, and the potential value of supplementing it with wastewater surveillance.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Committee acknowledged the ongoing work of WHO and partners to achieve WHO- and SAGE-recommended vaccination targets, particularly reaching 100% vaccination coverage among those in the highest priority groups. Nonetheless, concern remained as to the
    lack of sharing of data needed to monitor progress of vaccination campaigns, and&amp;ndash;where data is available&amp;ndash;the persistent inequities in access to vaccines as well as to WHO-recommended therapeutics. These inequities in access have resulted
    in many COVID-19 deaths that may have otherwise been avoided. The Committee acknowledged the disruption the pandemic continues to have on routine (non&amp;ndash;COVID-19) immunization activities, which has repeatedly manifested as outbreaks of vaccine-preventable
    diseases in areas where essential immunization activities have lapsed since early 2020.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Committee recognized that many national COVID-19 policies reflect a perception that the emergency may be over and that governments, healthcare workers and societies in general are experiencing "COVID-19 fatigue." The Committee therefore emphasized
    the need to enhance social listening and community engagement as means to better tailor risk communications and contextualize policies, that will help people to continue to take the actions needed to protect their health. The Committee highlighted
    persistent misinformation related to many aspects of the COVID-19 response, particularly the dangers posed by pervasive disinformation on vaccination, vaccine hesitancy and the convergence of organized anti-vaccination efforts in many countries.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Status of the Public Health Emergency of International Concern&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Committee noted a clear decoupling of case incidence from severe disease, and the high seroprevalence estimates resulting from combined infection and/or vaccination across all WHO regions. &amp;nbsp;Seroprevalence data may not necessarily reflect true
    immune protection but seems to reflect protection against severe disease, and such studies continue to be important to monitor immune response over time.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In assessing the criteria for a public health emergency of international concern, the Committee agreed that, &amp;nbsp;although the public perception is that the pandemic is over in some parts of the world, it remains a public health event that continues
    to adversely and strongly affect the health of the world&amp;rsquo;s population, that there remains a risk of new variants exacerbating the ongoing health impact, particularly as winter approaches in the Northern hemisphere (and learning from the Southern
    Hemisphere), and there is still a need for a coordinated international response to address the inequalities in access to life-saving tools.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In advising the WHO Director-General that the event still constitutes a PHEIC, the Committee developed the following arguments underpinning its advice.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;First, the clear decoupling in incident cases and severe disease has led to a perception in communities that the emergency may be over and that measures to reduce transmission are no longer warranted. Although the number of weekly deaths reported to WHO
    is near the lowest since the pandemic began, it remains high compared with other respiratory viruses, and the added burden of COVID-19 related complications and Post COVID-19 Condition is also high and its full impact not completely understood. The
    evolution of the outbreak during the upcoming winter season in the Northern hemisphere must also be considered.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Second, although ongoing evolution of the virus is expected to continue, the genetic and antigenic characteristics of future variants cannot yet be reliably predicted, partly due to the current gaps in global surveillance that hinder identifying and evaluating
    these changes early. In addition, the ongoing virus evolution, with potentially increased properties of immune escape, may pose challenges to current vaccines and therapeutics.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Finally, inequities in access to COVID-19 vaccines and therapeutics persist between and within countries, such that the highest priority groups do not currently have access to safe and effective vaccine and therapeutics everywhere.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Given the above considerations, the Committee concurred that continued coordination of the international response is necessary to reliably evaluate the health impact of the pandemic, monitor and assess the evolution of the virus and the impact of future
    variants, to intensify efforts to ensure access to safe and effective countermeasures, and to enhance tailored risk communication and community engagement activities.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Overall, the Committee considered that the situation remains dynamic and requires frequent reassessments, and that the termination of the PHEIC, when considered feasible, should be implemented as safely as possible. To this end, the Committee requested
    the WHO Secretariat to provide additional assessment and analysis for an intersessional discussion to further support the Committee&amp;rsquo;s deliberations. The Committee also recommended to review the potential negative consequences of terminating
    the PHEIC, as well as to consider the relevant provisions of the IHR (2005) in relation to temporary recommendations, which can continue to be formally issued after the termination of a PHEIC, or to standing recommendations. &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Committee considered that, in view of the current situation, whereby the response efforts in many countries have reduced the burden of COVID-19, but at the same time inequalities in access to life-saving interventions and uncertainties with regard
    to the evolution of the virus still persist, the Temporary Recommendations require an enhanced focus on three key priorities: strengthen integrated surveillance and achieve vaccination targets for at risk-groups; continue to develop strategies to
    increase access to affordable therapeutics; strengthen pandemic preparedness planning, while continuing to protect the most-at risk populations.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The rationale for these priority recommendations is to ensure that the following occur:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;the appropriate strategies, systems and resources are in place to detect any adverse change in the epidemiology of COVID-19, due, for example, to the emergence of a new more transmissible variant with more immune escape, capable of causing more severe
        disease;
    &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Member States have the necessary capacity to surge public health and social measures in response to a new event;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;the global population is appropriately protected by an effective and equitable vaccination programme;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;strategies continue to be developed that increase equitable access to affordable therapeutics, and&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;progress towards a robust global pandemic preparedness architecture is maintained.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Committee anticipates that meaningful progress with implementing these measures would create a situation compatible with terminating the PHEIC related to the COVID-19 pandemic at a future meeting, and that the situation could continue to be characterized
    as pandemic even if the PHEIC is terminated. The Committee further believes that these recommendations will support appropriate public health messaging on the evolving risk of COVID-19, despite community and political &amp;ldquo;pandemic fatigue.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;===&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Temporary Recommendations issued by the WHO Director-General to all States Parties&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Strengthen SARS-CoV-2 surveillance in humans to maintain (or, where needed, enhance) capacity to detect and assess emerging variants and significant changes to COVID-19 epidemiology and &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;to focus on better understanding the burden of COVID-19 in all regions, and its impact on health and public health services.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;It
 is recommended that States Parties prepare for sustainable integration of SARS-CoV-2 surveillance with other surveillance systems, and implement the WHO&amp;rsquo;s guidance on &lt;a href="https://www.who.int/publications-detail-redirect/WHO-2019-nCoV-SurveillanceGuidance-2022.2"&gt;Public health surveillance for COVID-19&lt;/a&gt; &amp;ndash; interim guidance. With the upcoming Northern
    hemisphere influenza season and in view of the return of seasonal influenza epidemics, States Parties should further integrate disease surveillance of SARS-CoV-2 and influenza by leveraging and enhancing the Global Influenza Surveillance and Response
    System (GISRS), complemented with other surveillance models or studies, to monitor the relative co-circulation of these viruses to inform responses.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Strengthen (or where needed, implement) surveillance &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;to monitor presence and evolution of SARS-COV-2 in animal populations. &lt;/strong&gt;Continue to conduct epidemiological investigations of SARS-CoV-2 transmission at the human-animal
    interface and implement targeted surveillance on potential animal hosts and reservoirs. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.woah.org/app/uploads/2022/01/statement-agve-omicron.pdf"&gt;Statement from the Advisory Group on SARS-CoV-2 Evolution in Animals&lt;/a&gt;;
 &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.who.int/news/item/07-03-2022-joint-statement-on-the-prioritization-of-monitoring-sars-cov-2-infection-in-wildlife-and-preventing-the-formation-of-animal-reservoirs"&gt;Joint statement on the prioritization of monitoring SARS-CoV-2 infection in wildlife and preventing the formation of animal reservoirs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Achieve national COVID-19 vaccination targets in accordance with &lt;/strong&gt;the updated WHO Global COVID-19 Vaccine Strategy, and the WHO SAGE Prioritization Roadmap, which both emphasize fully protecting those in high priority groups.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.who.int/publications/m/item/global-covid-19-vaccination-strategy-in-a-changing-world--july-2022-update"&gt;Global COVID-19 Vaccination Strategy in a Changing World: July 2022 update;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.who.int/news/item/21-01-2022-updated-who-sage-roadmap-for-prioritizing-uses-of-covid-19-vaccines"&gt;Updated WHO SAGE Roadmap for prioritizing uses of COVID-19 vaccines&lt;/a&gt;;
 &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.who.int/news/item/17-05-2022-interim-statement-on-the-use-of-additional-booster-doses-of-emergency-use-listed-mrna-vaccines-against-covid-19"&gt;Interim statement on the use of additional booster doses of Emergency Use Listed mRNA vaccines against COVID-19&lt;/a&gt;;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.who.int/publications-detail-redirect/WHO-2019-nCoV-vaccines-SAGE_recommendation-coadministration-influenza-vaccines"&gt;Coadministration of seasonal inactivated influenza and COVID-19 vaccines&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.who.int/publications-detail-redirect/9789240049680"&gt;Behavioural and social drivers of vaccination: tools and practical guidance for achieving high uptake&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Support timely uptake of accurate therapeutics and timely SARS-CoV-2 testing, linked to WHO recommended therapeutics&lt;/strong&gt;. States Parties should provide access to COVID-19 treatments for vulnerable populations, particularly immunosuppressed
    people, and improve access to specific early treatments for patients at higher risk for severe disease outcomes. Global efforts to increase access to affordable therapeutics should be enhanced. &amp;nbsp;Local production and technology transfer related
    to vaccines, other therapeutics and diagnostics should be encouraged and supported, as increased production capacity can contribute to global equitable access to therapeutics.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.who.int/publications-detail-redirect/WHO-2019-nCoV-therapeutics-2022.4"&gt;Therapeutics and COVID-19: living guideline&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.who.int/tools/covid-19-clinical-care-pathway"&gt;COVID-19 Clinical Care Pathway&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Maintain the strong national response to the COVID-19 pandemic&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;by updating national preparedness and response plans in line with the priorities and potential scenarios outlined in the &lt;a href="https://www.who.int/publications-detail-redirect/WHO-WHE-SPP-2022.1"&gt;2022 WHO Strategic Preparedness, Readiness and Response Plan&lt;/a&gt; and the recently published
    &lt;a href="https://www.who.int/emergencies/diseases/novel-coronavirus-2019/covid-19-policy-briefs"&gt;WHO COVID-19 policy briefs&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6. Address the infodemic, risk communications and community engagement challenges, and the divergent perceptions in risk between scientific communities, political leaders and the general public.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.who.int/teams/epi-win"&gt;WHO risk communications resources&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7. Continue to adapt the use of appropriate effective, individual-level protective measures to reduce transmission&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;, &lt;/strong&gt;appropriately tailored to the changing epidemiological context including changing risks associated with
    future variants of concern, and the need to tailor public health and social measure with such changes, including as relevant for mass gathering events. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.who.int/publications-detail-redirect/WHO-2019-nCoV-Mass-gathering-RAtool-2022.1"&gt;WHO mass gathering COVID-19 risk assessment tool: generic events; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="background-color:transparent;color:inherit;font-family:inherit;text-align:inherit;text-transform:inherit;white-space:inherit;word-spacing:normal;caret-color:auto;font-size:inherit;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.who.int/publications-detail-redirect/considerations-in-adjusting-public-health-and-social-measures-in-the-context-of-covid-19-interim-guidance"&gt;Considerations for implementing and adjusting PHSM in the context of COVID-19&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8. Maintain essential health, social, and education services&lt;/strong&gt;, in particular access to essential immunization services.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.who.int/publications-detail-redirect/WHO-2019-nCoV-Policy_brief-IPC-HCF-2022.1"&gt;Maintaining infection prevention and control measures for COVID-19 in health care facilities: Policy brief; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a style="font-family:inherit;text-align:inherit;text-transform:inherit;white-space:inherit;word-spacing:normal;font-size:inherit;" href="https://www.who.int/publications-detail-redirect/WHO-2019-nCoV-clinical-2022-1"&gt;Clinical management of COVID-19: Living guideline;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.who.int/publications-detail-redirect/WHO-UHL-PHC-SP-2021.01"&gt;Building health systems resilience for universal health coverage and health security during the COVID-19 pandemic and beyond: WHO position paper;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.unicef.org/reports/state-global-education-crisis"&gt;The State of the Global Education Crisis | UNICEF&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;9. Continue to adjust any remaining international travel-related measures&lt;/strong&gt;, based on risk assessments, and to not require proof of vaccination against COVID-19 as a prerequisite for international travel. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.who.int/news-room/articles-detail/interim-position-paper-considerations-regarding-proof-of-covid-19-vaccination-for-international-travellers"&gt;Interim position paper: considerations regarding proof of COVID-19 vaccination for international travellers; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="background-color:transparent;color:inherit;font-family:inherit;text-align:inherit;text-transform:inherit;white-space:inherit;word-spacing:normal;caret-color:auto;font-size:inherit;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.who.int/publications-detail-redirect/WHO-2019-nCoV-Policy-Brief-Risk-based-international-travel-2021.1"&gt;Policy considerations for implementing a risk-based approach to international travel in the context of COVID-19&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</a10:content></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">urn:uuid:01bce2c7-3472-4487-bac4-c81099065e7e</guid><link>https://www.who.int/news/item/19-10-2022-shortage-of-cholera-vaccines-leads-to-temporary-suspension-of-two-dose-strategy--as-cases-rise-worldwide</link><a10:author><a10:name> </a10:name></a10:author><title>Shortage of cholera vaccines leads to temporary suspension of two-dose strategy, as cases rise worldwide</title><description>A strained global supply of cholera vaccines has obliged the International Coordinating Group (ICG) — the body which manages emergency supplies of vaccines — to temporarily suspend the standard two-dose vaccination regimen in cholera outbreak response campaigns, using instead a single-dose approach.</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 11:44:56 Z</pubDate><a10:content type="text">&lt;p&gt;A strained global supply of cholera vaccines has obliged the International Coordinating Group (ICG) &amp;mdash; the body which manages emergency supplies of vaccines &amp;mdash; to temporarily suspend the standard two-dose vaccination regimen in cholera outbreak response campaigns, using instead a single-dose approach. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The pivot in strategy will allow for the doses to be used in more countries, at a time of unprecedented rise in cholera outbreaks worldwide.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Since January this year, 29 countries have reported cholera cases, including Haiti, Malawi and Syria which are facing large outbreaks. In comparison, in the previous 5 years, fewer than 20 countries on average reported outbreaks. The global trend is moving towards more numerous, more widespread and more severe outbreaks, due to floods, droughts, conflict, population movements and other factors that limit access to clean water and raise the risk of cholera outbreaks.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The one-dose strategy has proven to be effective to respond to outbreaks, even though evidence on the exact duration of protection is limited, and protection appears to be much lower in children. &amp;nbsp;With a two-dose regimen, when the second dose is administrated within 6 months of the first, immunity against infection lasts for 3 years.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The benefit of supplying one dose still outweighs no doses: although the temporary interruption of the two-dose strategy will lead to a reduction and shortening of immunity, this decision will allow more people to be vaccinated and provide them protection in the near term, should the global cholera situation continue deteriorating.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The current supply of cholera vaccines is extremely limited. Its use for emergency response is &amp;nbsp;coordinated by the ICG which manages the global stockpile of oral cholera vaccines. Of the total 36 million doses forecast to be produced in 2022, 24 million have already been shipped for preventive (17%) and reactive (83%) campaigns and an additional 8 million doses were approved by the ICG for the second round for emergency vaccination in 4 countries, illustrating the dire shortage of the vaccine. As vaccine manufactures are producing at their maximum current capacity, there is no short-term solution to increase production. The temporary suspension of the two-dose strategy will allow the remaining doses to be redirected for any needs for the rest of the year.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is a short-term solution but to ease the problem in the longer term, urgent action is needed to increase global vaccine production.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The ICG will continue to monitor the global epidemiological trends as well as the status of the cholera vaccine stockpile, and will review this decision regularly.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;About the ICG&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.who.int/groups/icg/about"&gt;ICG&lt;/a&gt; is an international group that manages and coordinates the provision of emergency vaccine supplies and antibiotics to countries during major disease outbreaks. &amp;nbsp;It manages the global stockpile of the oral cholera vaccine. The group is composed of members of WHO, M&amp;eacute;decins Sans Fronti&amp;egrave;res, UNICEF and the International Federation of Red Cross and Red Crescent Societies.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The ICG was established in 1997, following major outbreaks of meningitis in Africa, as a mechanism to manage and coordinate the provision of emergency vaccine supplies and antibiotics to countries during major outbreaks.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Since the establishment of the cholera vaccine stockpile in 2013, 120 million doses of oral cholera vaccine doses have been shipped to 23 countries, of which 73 million (60%) has been approved for emergency response.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.twitch.tv/who"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</a10:content></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">urn:uuid:7fa28933-a876-40d4-9012-084ee9a0910f</guid><link>https://www.who.int/news/item/19-10-2022-who-highlights-high-cost-of-physical-inactivity-in-first-ever-global-report</link><a10:author><a10:name> </a10:name></a10:author><title>WHO highlights high cost of physical inactivity in first-ever global report</title><description>The Global status report on physical activity 2022, published today by the World Health Organization, measures the extent to which governments are implementing recommendations to increase physical activity across all ages and abilities.</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 18:32:46 Z</pubDate><a10:content type="text">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Almost 500 million people will develop heart disease, obesity, diabetes or other noncommunicable diseases (NCDs) attributable to physical inactivity, between 2020 and 2030, costing &lt;/em&gt;US$ 27 billion annually,&lt;em&gt; if governments don&amp;rsquo;t take urgent action to encourage more physical activity among their populations.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.who.int/publications-detail-redirect/9789240059153"&gt;Global status report on physical activity 2022&lt;/a&gt;, published today by the World Health Organization, measures the extent to which governments are implementing recommendations to increase
    physical activity across all ages and abilities.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Data from 194 countries show that overall, progress is slow and that countries need to accelerate the development and implementation of policies to increase levels of physical activity and thereby prevent disease and reduce burden on already overwhelmed
    health care systems.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Less than 50% of countries have a national physical activity policy, of which less than 40% are operational&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Only 30% of countries have national physical activity guidelines for all age groups&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;While nearly all countries report a system for monitoring physical activity in adults, 75% of countries monitor physical activity among adolescents, and less than 30% monitor physical activity in children under 5 years&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;In policy areas that could encourage active and sustainable transport, only just over 40% of countries have road design standards that make walking and cycling safer. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;"We need more countries to scale up implementation of policies to support people to be more active through walking, cycling, sport, and other physical activity.&amp;nbsp;The benefits are huge, not only for the physical and mental health of individuals, but
    also for societies, environments, and economies...&amp;rdquo; said Dr Tedros Adhanom Ghebreyesus, WHO Director-General, &amp;ldquo;We hope countries and partners will use this report to build more active, healthier, and fairer societies for all.&amp;rdquo; &amp;nbsp;&lt;s&gt;&lt;/s&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The economic burden of physical inactivity is significant and the cost of treating new cases of preventable non-communicable diseases (NCDs) will reach nearly US$ 300 billion by 2030, around US$ 27 billion annually.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Whilst national policies to tackle NCDs and physical inactivity have increased in recent years, currently 28% of policies are reported to be not funded or implemented. Considered a &amp;ldquo;best buy&amp;rdquo; for motivating populations to combat NCDs, the
    report showed that only just over 50% of countries ran a national communications campaign, or organised mass participation physical activity events in the last two years. The COVID-19 pandemic has not only stalled these initiatives, but it also affected
    other policy implementation which has widened inequities in access to and, opportunities for, engaging in physical activity for many communities.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;To help countries increase physical activity, WHO&amp;rsquo;s Global action plan on physical activity 2018-2030 (GAPPA) sets out 20 policy recommendations &amp;ndash; including policies to create safer roads to encourage more active transport, provide more programmes
    and opportunities for physical activity in key settings, such as childcare, schools, primary health care and the workplace. Today&amp;rsquo;s Global Status report assesses country progress against those recommendations, and shows that much more needs
    to be done. &amp;nbsp;One critical finding in the Global status report on physical activity is the existence of significant gaps in global data to track progress on important policy actions &amp;ndash; such as provision of public open space, provision of
    walking and cycling infrastructure, provision of sport and physical education in schools. The report also calls for weaknesses in some existing data to also be addressed. &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We are missing globally approved indicators to measure access to parks, cycle lanes, foot paths &amp;ndash; even though we know that data do exist in some countries. Consequently, we cannot report or track the global provision of infrastructure that
    will facilitate increases in physical activity, &amp;ldquo;said Fiona Bull, Head of WHO Physical Activity Unit. &amp;nbsp;&amp;ldquo;It can be a vicious circle, no indicator and no data leads to no tracking and no accountability, and then too often, to no policy
    and no investment. What gets measured gets done, and we have some way to go to comprehensively and robustly track national actions on physical activity.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The report calls for countries to prioritize physical activity as key to improving health and tackling NCDs, integrate physical activity into all relevant policies, and develop tools, guidance and training to improve implementation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It is good for public health and makes economic sense to promote more physical activity for everyone,&amp;rdquo; said Dr Ruediger Krech, Director Department of Health Promotion, WHO. &amp;ldquo;We need to facilitate inclusive programmes for physical activity
    for all and ensure people have easier access to them. &amp;nbsp;This report issues a clear call to all countries for stronger and accelerated action by all relevant stakeholders working better together to achieve the global target of a 15% reduction in
    the prevalence of physical inactivity by 2030.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Data for the report are drawn from the &lt;a href="https://apps.who.int/iris/handle/10665/331452"&gt;WHO Noncommunicable Disease Country Capacity Survey (2019 and 2022)&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href="https://apps.who.int/iris/handle/10665/276462"&gt;WHO Global status report on road safety (2018).&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The cost of inaction on physical inactivity to healthcare systems manuscript at &lt;a href="https://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=4248284"&gt;Preprints with The Lancet&lt;/a&gt; (peer-reviewed version forthcoming in The Lancet Global Health)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</a10:content></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">urn:uuid:4476c777-186a-4d3f-b122-0f531eaf7984</guid><link>https://www.who.int/news/item/18-10-2022-parliamentarians-commit-to-support-global-health</link><a10:author><a10:name> </a10:name></a10:author><title>Parliamentarians commit to support global health</title><description>Today, WHO signed a Memorandum of Understanding with UNITE, Parliamentarians Network for Global Health. This represents a new step in strengthening WHO engagement with parliaments.</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 12:44:47 Z</pubDate><a10:content type="text">&lt;p&gt;Today at the World Health Summit, in front of an audience including more than 40 parliamentarians from 30 different countries, WHO signed a Memorandum of Understanding with UNITE, Parliamentarians Network for Global Health. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This represents a new step in strengthening WHO engagement with parliaments. With this agreement, UNITE commits to support WHO in raising awareness and building capacity of parliamentarians in three strategic areas of global public health: &lt;strong&gt;equitable access to health&lt;/strong&gt;, with a focus on universal health coverage; &lt;strong&gt;health system strengthening&lt;/strong&gt;, with a focus on supporting sustainable financing for global health; and &lt;strong&gt;efficient global health architecture and security&lt;/strong&gt;, with a focus on the creation of the global health architecture and security, and the promotion of the pandemic treaty.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Parliaments play a vital role in promoting and protecting health, by&amp;nbsp;putting in place the legislative, regulatory and budgetary measures that can prevent diseases, and create the conditions for health to thrive,&amp;rdquo; said Dr Tedros Adhanom Ghebreyesus, WHO Director-General. &amp;ldquo;WHO is committed to working with parliaments and parliamentary platforms. We welcome the collaboration with UNITE, which will be instrumental in mobilizing parliamentary support, in particular for sustainable financing and strengthening the global health architecture."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dr Ricardo Baptista Leite, President and Founder of UNITE added: &amp;ldquo;For the last five years, the UNITE Parliamentarians Network for Global Health has been actively promoting evidence-based policy making, in an effort led by our members from more than 85 countries. As current and former members of parliaments, congresses and senates from around the world, we are committed to ensuring that our actions, as politicians and agents for change, lead to a more equitable society in which no one is left behind. UNITE envisions this collaboration as an opportunity to ensure that trustworthy scientific recommendations are delivered to parliamentarians, leading towards new laws and policies that ensure Health is a reality for all. This partnership will empower both UNITE and WHO in achieving our ambitions goals together.&amp;rdquo;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For more information about UNITE: &lt;a href="https://www.unitenetwork.org/" target="_blank"&gt;https://www.unitenetwork.org/&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For more information about WHO parliamentary engagement: Elisa Scolaro, External Relations officer, parliamentary engagement, WHO. &lt;a href="mailto:scolaroe@who.int"&gt;scolaroe@who.int&lt;/a&gt; &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</a10:content></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">urn:uuid:fc73d007-6639-42a8-a108-5b6788bd435f</guid><link>https://www.who.int/news/item/18-10-2022-global-leaders-commit-usd-2.6-billion-at-world-health-summit-to-end-polio</link><a10:author><a10:name> </a10:name></a10:author><title>Global leaders commit US$ 2.6 billion at World Health Summit to end polio</title><description>The funding will support global efforts to overcome the final hurdles to polio eradication, vaccinate 370 million children annually over the next five years and continue disease surveillance across 50 countries.</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 10:12:07 Z</pubDate><a10:content type="text">&lt;p&gt;Today, global leaders confirmed US$&amp;nbsp;2.6 billion in funding toward the Global Polio Eradication Initiative&amp;rsquo;s (GPEI) &lt;a href="https://polioeradication.org/gpei-strategy-2022-2026/" target="_blank"&gt;2022-2026 Strategy&lt;/a&gt; to end polio at a pledging moment co-hosted by Germany&amp;rsquo;s Federal Ministry for Economic Cooperation and Development (BMZ) at the World Health Summit in Berlin.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The funding will support global efforts to overcome the final hurdles to polio eradication, vaccinate 370&amp;nbsp;million children annually over the next five years and continue disease surveillance across 50 countries. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;No place is safe until polio has been eradicated everywhere. As long as the virus still exists somewhere in the world, it can spread &amp;ndash; including in our own country. We now have a realistic chance to eradicate polio completely, and we want
    to jointly seize that chance,&amp;rdquo; said Svenja Schulze, Federal Minister for Economic Cooperation and Development, Germany. &amp;ldquo;Germany will remain a strong and committed partner in the global fight against polio. This year, it is providing EUR&amp;nbsp;35
    million for this cause. And next year we plan to further strengthen our efforts and support GPEI with EUR&amp;nbsp;37 million &amp;ndash; pending parliamentary approval. By supporting the GPEI, we are also strengthening national health systems. That leads
    to healthier societies, far beyond the polio response.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Wild poliovirus is endemic in just two countries &amp;ndash; Pakistan and Afghanistan. However, after just six cases were recorded in 2021, 29 cases have been recorded so far this year, including a small number of new detections in southeast Africa linked
    to a strain originating in Pakistan. Additionally, outbreaks of &lt;a href="https://polioeradication.org/polio-today/polio-now/this-week/circulating-vaccine-derived-poliovirus/" target="_blank"&gt;cVDPV&lt;/a&gt;, variants of the poliovirus
    that can emerge in places where not enough people have been immunized, continue to spread across parts of Africa, Asia and Europe, with new outbreaks detected in the United States, Israel and the United Kingdom in recent months. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The new detections of polio this year in previously polio-free countries are a stark reminder that if we do not deliver our goal of ending polio everywhere, it may resurge globally,&amp;rdquo; said Dr. Tedros Adhanom Ghebreyesus, WHO Director-General.
    &amp;ldquo;We are grateful for donors&amp;rsquo; new and continued support for eradication, but there is further work to do to fully fund the 2022-2026 Strategy. We must remember the significant challenges we have overcome to get this far against polio, stay
    the course and finish the job once and for all.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;At a challenging time for countries around the world, governments and partners have stepped forward to demonstrate their collective resolve to eradicate the second human disease ever. In addition to existing pledges, new commitments to the 2022-2026 Strategy
    this fall include: &lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Australia &lt;/strong&gt;pledged AU$ 43.55 million &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;France&lt;/strong&gt; pledged EUR 50&amp;nbsp;million&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Germany&lt;/strong&gt; pledged EUR&amp;nbsp;72 million&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Japan&lt;/strong&gt; pledged US$&amp;nbsp;11 million&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Republic of Korea &lt;/strong&gt;pledged&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;KRW&amp;nbsp;4.5 billion&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Luxembourg &lt;/strong&gt;pledged EUR&amp;nbsp;1.7 million&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Malta &lt;/strong&gt;pledged EUR&amp;nbsp;30&amp;nbsp;000&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Monaco &lt;/strong&gt;pledged EUR&amp;nbsp;450&amp;nbsp;000&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Spain &lt;/strong&gt;pledged EUR&amp;nbsp;100&amp;nbsp;000&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Turkey &lt;/strong&gt;pledged US$&amp;nbsp;20&amp;nbsp;000&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;United States &lt;/strong&gt;pledged US$&amp;nbsp;114 million&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bill &amp;amp; Melinda Gates Foundation&lt;/strong&gt; pledged US$S&amp;nbsp;1.2 billion&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bloomberg Philanthropies&lt;/strong&gt; pledged US$&amp;nbsp;50&amp;nbsp;million&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Islamic Food and Nutrition Council of America&lt;/strong&gt; pledged US$&amp;nbsp;1.8 million&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Latter-day Saint Charities&lt;/strong&gt; pledged US$&amp;nbsp;400&amp;nbsp;000&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rotary International &lt;/strong&gt;pledged US$&amp;nbsp;150 million&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UNICEF &lt;/strong&gt;pledged US$&amp;nbsp;5 million&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The pledging moment in Berlin marked the first major opportunity to pledge support toward the US$&amp;nbsp;4.8 billion needed to fully implement the 2022-2026 Strategy. If the Strategy is fully funded and eradication achieved, it is estimated that it would
    result in &lt;a href="https://polioeradication.org/financing/financial-needs/investment-case-2022-2026/" target="_blank"&gt;US$&amp;nbsp;33.1 billion in health cost savings&lt;/a&gt; this century compared
    to the price of controlling outbreaks. Further, continued support for GPEI will enable it to deliver additional health services and immunizations alongside polio vaccines to underserved communities. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"Children deserve to live in a polio-free world, but as we have seen this year with painful clarity, until we reach every community and vaccinate every child, the threat of polio will persist," said UNICEF Executive Director Catherine Russell. "UNICEF
    is grateful for the generosity of our donors and the pledges made today, which will help us finish the job of eradicating polio.&amp;nbsp; When we invest in immunization and health systems, we are investing in a safer, healthier future for everyone, everywhere.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In addition to the funding for GPEI announced today, a group of more than 3&amp;nbsp;000 influential scientists, physicians, and public health experts from around the world &lt;a href="https://www.poliodeclaration.org/" target="_blank"&gt;released a declaration&lt;/a&gt; endorsing the 2022-2026 Strategy and calling on donors to stay committed to eradication and ensure GPEI is fully funded. The group points to new tactics contained in the program&amp;rsquo;s strategy, like the continued roll-out of the novel oral polio
    vaccine type 2 (nOPV2), that make them confident in GPEI&amp;rsquo;s ability to end polio. Five hundred million doses of nOPV2 have already been administered across 23 countries, and field data continue to show its promise as a tool to more sustainably
    stop outbreaks of type 2 cVDPV. The group further asserts that support for eradication significantly strengthens immunization systems and pandemic preparedness around the world&amp;mdash;pointing to GPEI&amp;rsquo;s support for the COVID-19 response&amp;mdash;and
    urges endemic and polio-affected country leadership to stay committed to expanded vaccination and disease surveillance activities.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Pakistan has made incredible progress against polio, but recent challenges have allowed the virus to persist,&amp;rdquo; says Dr. Zulfi Bhutta (Chair of Child Global Health, Hospital for Sick Children, Canada, and Distinguished University Professor,
    Aga Khan University, Pakistan). &amp;ldquo;Polio, like any virus, knows no borders; its continued transmission threatens children everywhere. Stopping this disease is not just urgently needed now, it&amp;rsquo;s within our grasp. That&amp;rsquo;s why I&amp;rsquo;ve
    joined more than three thousand health experts from around the world to launch the 2022 Scientific Declaration on Polio Eradication. With strong financial and political commitments, our long-awaited vision of a polio-free world can become a reality.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Additional quotes from the pledging moment&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mark Suzman, CEO, Bill &amp;amp; Melinda Gates Foundation, said: &lt;/strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;The question is not whether it&amp;rsquo;s possible to eradicate polio&amp;mdash;it&amp;rsquo;s whether we can summon the will and the resources to finish the job. The Bill &amp;amp;
    Melinda Gates Foundation is grateful to Germany, Rotarians, donors, countries, scientists, and partners who stood together today to show that we are united in this goal. We look forward to working together to create a polio-free future and build more
    equitable and resilient health systems for all."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Seth Berkley, CEO, Gavi, the Vaccine Alliance, said: &lt;/strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;As we work together to stop the transmission of all polioviruses globally, we are more grateful than ever for the generosity of our donors, the leadership of governments and
    the mobilization of communities. Today&amp;rsquo;s pledges will support GPEI&amp;rsquo;s new strategy which correctly focuses on mass vaccination campaigns, concerted efforts by partners to strengthen essential immunization and integration with other critical
    health interventions and a further roll out of next-generation oral polio vaccines. These three measures combined are essential if we are to eradicate polio once and for all.&amp;rdquo;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Franz Fayot, Minister for Development Cooperation and Humanitarian Affairs, Luxembourg, said: &lt;/strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;Luxembourg is proud to be a longstanding supporter of global efforts to eradicate polio. Building on the remarkable progress achieved
    so far, Luxembourg will continue to support the fight against polio until we ensure the protection of every child.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ian Riseley, Chair, Rotary Foundation, said: &lt;/strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;While polio exists anywhere, it is a threat everywhere. This is an opportune moment for the global community to recommit to the goal and ensure the resources and political will are fully
    available to protect children from polio paralysis while building stronger health systems. That is why today, Rotary is reaffirming its commitment of an additional USD 150 million to the global effort to eradicate&amp;nbsp;polio.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;His Excellency Abdul Rahman Al Owais, Minister of Health and Prevention, United Arab Emirates, said:&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;ldquo;Polio outbreaks this year have emphasized that polio anywhere is a threat to communities everywhere. While we are encouraged
    by steady progress in Pakistan and Afghanistan in the drive towards polio eradication, we know that there is a ways to go to finish the job. We also know that this progress would not have been possible without the courageous contributions of frontline
    health workers, who have remained steadfast in their commitment to protecting their communities from polio in the face of the pandemic, natural disasters and threats to their physical safety. Under the leadership of His Highness Sheikh Mohamed bin
    Zayed Al Nahyan, President of the UAE, we join our international partners in reiterating our commitment to a polio free world."&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Notes for editors&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Global Polio Eradication Initiative is a public-private partnership led by national governments with six core partners &amp;ndash; Rotary International, the World Health Organization (WHO), the US Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC), UNICEF,
    the Bill &amp;amp; Melinda Gates Foundation and Gavi, the Vaccine Alliance. For more information on the global effort to end polio, visit &lt;a href="http://polioeradication.org" target="_blank"&gt;polioeradication.org&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</a10:content></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">urn:uuid:e4bae304-fa2c-4c53-bea8-724598b73dd6</guid><link>https://www.who.int/news/item/18-10-2022-staggering-backsliding-across-women-s--children-s-and-adolescents--health-revealed-in-new-un-analysis</link><a10:author><a10:name> </a10:name></a10:author><title>Staggering backsliding across women’s, children’s and adolescents’ health revealed in new UN analysis</title><description>&lt;p&gt;A new UN report shows that women&amp;rsquo;s and children&amp;rsquo;s health has suffered globally, as the impacts of conflict, the COVID-19 pandemic and climate change converge with devastating effects on prospects for children, young people and women. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Data presented in the report show a critical regression across virtually every major measure of childhood well-being, and many key indicators of the Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs). Since the last Every Woman Every Child Progress Report published in 2020, food insecurity, hunger, child marriage, risks from intimate partner violence, and adolescent depression and anxiety have all increased. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;An estimated 25 million children were un- or under-vaccinated in 2021 &amp;ndash; 6 million more than in 2019 - increasing their risk of contracting deadly and debilitating diseases. Millions of children missed out on school during the pandemic, many for more than a year, while approximately 80% of children in 104 countries and territories experienced learning-loss because of school closures. Since the start of the global pandemic, 10.5 million children lost a parent or caregiver to COVID-19.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;At the core of our unkept promise is the failure to address the gaping inequities at the root of global crises, from the COVID-19 pandemic to conflicts and the climate emergency. The report describes the impacts of these crises on women, children and adolescents, from maternal mortality to education losses to severe malnutrition,&amp;rdquo; said Antonio Guterres, United Nations Secretary-General. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The report provides wide-ranging evidence that children and adolescents face wildly divergent chances of leading a healthy life simply based on where they are born, their exposure to conflict, and the economic circumstances of their families. For example:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;A child born in a low-income country has an average life expectancy at birth of around 63 years, compared to 80 in a high-income country. This devastating 17-year survival gap has changed little over recent years. In 2020, 5 million children died even before the age of 5, mostly from preventable or treatable causes. Meanwhile, most maternal, child, and adolescent deaths and stillbirths are concentrated in just two regions &amp;ndash; sub-Saharan Africa and South Asia.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;More than 45 million children had acute malnutrition in 2020, a life-threatening condition which leaves them vulnerable to death,&amp;nbsp;developmental delays and disease. Nearly three-quarters of these children live in lower-middle-income countries. A staggering 149 million children were stunted in 2020. Africa is the only region where the numbers of children affected by stunting increased over the past 20 years, from 54.4 million in 2000 to 61.4 million in 2020. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;The six countries with the highest numbers of internally displaced persons &amp;ndash; Afghanistan, the Democratic Republic of the Congo, Ethiopia, Sudan, the Syrian Arab Republic and Yemen &amp;ndash; are also among the top 10 food insecure countries.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;A woman in sub-Saharan Africa has around a 130 times higher risk of dying from causes relating to pregnancy or childbirth than a woman in Europe or North America. Coverage of antenatal care, skilled birth attendance, and postnatal care is far from reaching all women in low- and middle- income countries, leaving them at elevated risk of death and disability.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Millions of children and their families are experiencing poor physical and mental health from recent humanitarian disasters in Afghanistan, Ethiopia, Pakistan, Somalia, Ukraine and Yemen. In 2021, a record 89.3 million people worldwide were driven from their homes by war, violence, persecution, and human rights abuse.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;The report calls upon the global community to address this damaging trajectory and protect the promises made to women, children, and adolescents in the Sustainable Development Goals. In particular, it advocates for countries to continue investing in health services, to address all crises and food insecurity, and empower women and young people around the world.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The report, titled &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.who.int/publications-detail-redirect/9789240060104"&gt;Protect the Promise&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;, &lt;/em&gt;is published by global partners, including WHO, UNICEF, UNFPA, Partnership for Maternal, Newborn &amp;amp; Child Health (PMNCH) and Countdown to 2030, as a bi-annual summary of progress in response to the UN Secretary General's Every Woman Every Child Global Strategy for Women, Children's and Adolescents' Health. The most comprehensive synthesis of evidence on the current state of maternal, newborn, child and adolescent health, it updates the last Every Woman Every Child Global Strategy Progress Report published in 2020.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Quote sheet:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Almost three years on from the onset of COVID-19, the pandemic&amp;rsquo;s long-term impact on the health and well-being of women, children and adolescents is becoming evident: their chances for healthy and productive lives have declined sharply,&amp;rdquo; said Dr Tedros Adhanom Ghebreyesus, WHO Director-General. &amp;ldquo;As the world emerges from the pandemic, protecting and promoting the health of women, children and young people is essential for supporting and sustaining the global recovery.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The impacts of COVID-19, conflicts, and climate crises have raised the stakes for vulnerable communities, revealing the weaknesses and inequities in health care systems and reversing hard-won progress for women, children, and adolescents &amp;ndash; but we are not powerless to change this,&amp;rdquo; said UNICEF Executive Catherine Russell. &amp;ldquo;By investing in resilient, inclusive primary health care systems, jumpstarting routine immunization programmes, and strengthening the health workforce, we can make sure that every woman and every child can access the care they need to survive and thrive.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;There is a crisis of inequity that is piling on already increasing and compounding threats. In a world where too many children, adolescents and women are dying, equity, empowerment and access are what needs urgent focus,&amp;rdquo; said H.E. Ms. Kersti Kaljulaid, Global Advocate for Every Woman Every Child and President of the Republic of Estonia, 2016-2021. &amp;ldquo;We are calling on all to think and act broadly and profoundly to protect the promise. This promise refers not only to the commitments made in the Sustainable Development Goals, and all of the campaigns that followed, but also to the larger promise of potential that everyone is born with. Too often this promise remains unclaimed, or even denied.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;In the face of increasing political pushback against sexual and reproductive health and rights in many countries, women, children and adolescents today are left without many of the protections of just a decade ago, and many others still have not seen the progress they need,&amp;rdquo; said Dr. Natalia Kanem, UNFPA Executive Director. &amp;ldquo;Access to sexual and reproductive health services, including contraception, is a fundamental right that directly and acutely affects the ability of women and adolescent girls to thrive. We need to expand these rights and services to the most marginalized, leaving no one behind.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The report advocates for countries to continue investing in health services, in all crises, and to re-imagine health systems that can truly reach every woman, child, and adolescent, no matter who they are or where they live,&amp;rdquo; said the Rt. Hon Helen Clark, Board Chair of PMNCH (The Partnership for Maternal, Newborn &amp;amp; Child Health) and former Prime Minister of New Zealand. &amp;ldquo;Experts and world leaders are calling for more women in policy- and decision-making at every level, meaningful engagement with young people, and primary health care systems which deliver what people need when and where they need it most.&amp;rdquo; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;###&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Notes to editor:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Download multimedia content &lt;a href="https://weshare.unicef.org/Package/2AMZIF7A6BD6"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Access infographics and data &lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/drive/folders/1qi1Q5WjV8FZJ2Nh_DTQHd9y5v1J277wq?usp=sharing"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The report will be launched at the World Health Summit in Berlin on 18 October 2022 at 9 AM GMT+2 at a session where the findings will be discussed by world leaders and young people. The session can be joined in person or &lt;a href="https://www.conference.worldhealthsummit.org/Program/Session/WHS2022/WS-22"&gt;virtually&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Speakers include:&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Rt. Hon. Helen Clark, Former Prime Minister of New Zealand and Board Chair of PMNCH (&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/HelenClarkNZ"&gt;@HelenClarkNZ&lt;/a&gt;) &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;H.E. Kersti Kaljulaid, Former President of Estonia and UN SG&amp;rsquo;s Global Advocate for Every Woman Every Child (&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/KerstiKaljulaid"&gt;@KerstiKaljulaid&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Dr. Austin Demby, Minister of Health and Sanitation, Sierra Leone &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/mohs_sl"&gt;(@mohs_sl&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Tedros Adhanom Ghebreyesus, Director General, WHO (&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/DrTedros"&gt;@DrTedros&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Aboubacar Kampo, Director of Health, UNICEF (&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/AbouKampo"&gt;@AbouKampo&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Natalia Kanem, Executive Director, UNFPA (&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Atayeshe"&gt;@Atayeshe&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Anshu Banerjee, Director, Department of Maternal, Newborn, Child and Adolescent Health &amp;amp; Ageing, WHO (&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ABanerjeeWHO"&gt;@ABanerjeeWHO&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Yana Panfilova, Founder of Teenergizer, Activist and Ukrainian refugee (&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/YPanfilova"&gt;@YPanfilova&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Elhadj As Sy, Board Chair, Kofi Annan Foundation (&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Elhadj_As_Sy"&gt;@Elhadj_As_Sy&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Inger Ashing, CEO, Save the Children International (&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/SaveCEO_Intl"&gt;@SaveCEO_Intl&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Maziko Matemvu, President and Founder, Uwale (&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/mazikospeaks"&gt;@mazikospeaks&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Loyce Pace, Assistant Secretary for Global Affairs, Department of Health and Human Services, USA&amp;nbsp;(&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/HHS_ASGA" target="_blank"&gt;@HHS_ASGA&lt;/a&gt;)&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 07:14:46 Z</pubDate></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">urn:uuid:9dac9e26-3cb2-4202-a646-da361fc60181</guid><link>https://www.who.int/news/item/17-10-2022-unicef-and-who-welcome-ksrelief-funding-for-measles-and-polio-epidemics-prevention</link><a10:author><a10:name> </a10:name></a10:author><title>UNICEF and WHO welcome KSrelief funding for measles and polio epidemics prevention</title><description>&lt;p&gt;The World Health Organization (WHO) and UNICEF welcomed today funding agreements from the King Salman Humanitarian Aid and Relief Centre (KSrelief) valued at US$ 10 million to further bolster polio and measles programmes in eight countries. The agreement was signed on the sidelines of the World Health Summit in Berlin.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The new funding will provide UNICEF and WHO with US$ 5 million each in response to a call for emergency action by WHO and UNICEF to avert major polio and measles epidemics. WHO and UNICEF have urged countries to prioritize&amp;nbsp;vaccination for children&amp;nbsp;as they rebuild&amp;nbsp;their immunization systems following major global immunization disruptions caused by COVID-19. The pandemic has left millions of vulnerable children at heightened risk of preventable childhood diseases. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;With this generous contribution from KSrelief, WHO will support the polio and measles programmes in&amp;nbsp; Somalia, Iraq, and Sudan through the procurement of laboratory equipment; enhancing surveillance; digitalisation of EPI; strengthening the cold chain; and trainings of campaign vaccinators. UNICEF will support the five high-risk countries of Afghanistan, Central African Republic, Democratic Republic of the Congo, Guinea, and Pakistan with the procurement and in-country distribution of polio and measles vaccines and supplies like cold chain equipment and syringes; recruitment and training of vaccinators; and sustainably strengthening immunization systems.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;ldquo;COVID-19 has had a devastating effect on immunisation services globally," said Dr Tedros Adhanom Ghebreyesus, Director-General of WHO. "KSrelief's generous support will help WHO to save children&amp;rsquo;s lives, benefiting an estimated 50 million people and averting major outbreaks of vaccine-preventable diseases including polio and measles in Somalia, Iraq and Sudan."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We can't let COVID-19 drive new epidemics of childhood disease, " said UNICEF Executive Director Catherine Russell. "The pandemic disrupted routine immunization services around the world, leaving millions of vulnerable children at heightened risk of polio, measles and other preventable childhood diseases. This new agreement will translate into lives saved and stronger immunization systems that will benefit millions of children.&amp;rdquo; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dr Abdullah Al Rabeeah, Supervisor General of King Salman Humanitarian Aid and Relief Centre (KSrelief) stated: &amp;ldquo;This cooperation agreement will strengthen global action to protect vulnerable children at increased risk from preventable childhood diseases; it also affirms the Kingdom of Saudi Arabia's dedication to saving lives and safeguarding futures. The agreement is the result of the Kingdom&amp;rsquo;s commitment to working with the WHO and UNICEF to jointly address global health challenges.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;----------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;At the World Health Summit, which brings together governments, donors, civil society and advocates, UNICEF and WHO renewed calls for urgent action to avert measles and polio epidemics and reaffirm commitments to eradicate vaccine-preventable diseases.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 15:51:48 Z</pubDate></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">urn:uuid:04bbf394-74b5-4d7f-af89-5a7cd3a52d7a</guid><link>https://www.who.int/news/item/18-10-2022-who-launches-new-campaign-to-amplify-the-lived-experience-of-people-affected-by-cancer</link><a10:author><a10:name> </a10:name></a10:author><title>WHO launches new campaign to amplify the lived experience of people affected by cancer</title><description>WHO is launching the first global survey to better understand and address the needs of all those affected by cancer.</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 13:47:03 Z</pubDate><a10:content type="text">&lt;p&gt;Today, WHO is launching the first &lt;a href="https://extranet.who.int/dataformv3/index.php/933528?lang=en"&gt;global survey&lt;/a&gt; to better understand and address the needs of all those affected by cancer. The survey is part of a broader campaign, designed with and intended to amplify the voices of those
    affected by cancer &amp;ndash; survivors, caregivers and the bereaved &amp;ndash; as part of WHO&amp;rsquo;s Framework for Meaningful Engagement of People Living with Noncommunicable diseases (PLWNCDs). This Framework is a commitment to respectfully and meaningfully
    engage PLWNCDs in co-designing policies, programmes, and solutions. The survey results will feed into the design of policies and programmes to offer better well-being in the context of a cancer diagnosis and co-create solutions for the future.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nearly every family globally is affected by cancer, either directly &amp;ndash; 1 in 5 people are diagnosed with cancer during their lifetime &amp;ndash; or as caregivers or family-members. A cancer diagnosis triggers a broad and profound effect on the health
    and well-being of all those involved. &amp;ldquo;For too long, the focus in cancer control has been on clinical care and not on the broader needs of people affected by cancer,&amp;rdquo; said Dr Tedros Adhanom Ghebreyesus, Director-General of the World Health
    Organization. &amp;ldquo;Global cancer policies must be shaped by more than data and scientific research, to include the voices and insight of people impacted by the disease."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Recent studies have shown that nearly half of people diagnosed with cancer experience anxiety and loss of faith and may be abandoned by their intimate partners. In low- and middle-income countries, financial hardship and loss of assets can be experienced
    by 70% or more of those affected. &amp;ldquo;When my daughter was diagnosed with cancer, our lives changed drastically and in ways that we did not expect. The effects of cancer last a lifetime,&amp;rdquo; said Ruth Hoffman, President of the American Childhood
    Cancer Organization.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Understanding and amplifying the lived experiences of people affected by cancer can create more effective and supportive systems. Yet, the needs and preferences of people with cancer and their caregivers remain unknown to many providers and policy-makers.
    &amp;ldquo;We are making a long-term commitment to place people affected by cancer properly at the center of the agenda, to co-create better solutions&amp;rdquo; explained Dr Bente Mikkelsen, Director of the Department of Noncommunicable Diseases at WHO.
    &amp;ldquo;This campaign will include four phases: releasing the global survey, hosting national consultations, presenting best practices and implementing community-led initiatives. We are ready to open a new chapter and improve the well-being of people
    affected by cancer.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The ambition of the global survey is to reach more than 100&amp;nbsp;000 responders from 100 countries, a majority of whom live in low- and middle-income countries. The survey results are expected in early 2023 and, thereafter, used to shape policies, programmes
    and services for people affected by cancer globally.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="button button-dark-border"&gt;&lt;a href="https://extranet.who.int/dataformv3/index.php/933528?lang=en"&gt;Take the global survey&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</a10:content></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">urn:uuid:ef31e75b-d2e7-4013-a17a-1bd7e207c544</guid><link>https://www.who.int/news/item/16-10-2022-international-association-of-national-public-health-institutes-partners-with-who</link><a10:author><a10:name> </a10:name></a10:author><title>International Association of National Public Health Institutes partners with WHO</title><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;At the World Health Summit today in Berlin, WHO and the International Association of National Public Health Institutes (IANPHI) signed a Memorandum of Understanding outlining their joint efforts to achieve their common objectives to strengthen public health functions and health emergency preparedness.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;WHO and IANPHI share the same vision that essential public health functions are a comprehensive and cost-effective approach to advance universal health coverage, health security and healthier populations. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The COVID-19 pandemic underlined the key role of national public health institutes. These institutes are at the forefront of preparedness, detection and response efforts in their respective countries. Through this new agreement, WHO and IANPHI will work together to establish or strengthen the role of national institutes, particularly in emergency preparedness and response.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Today&amp;rsquo;s agreement is an historic moment for both organizations," said&amp;nbsp;Professor Duncan Selbie, President of the IANPHI. "Formalizing this aims to&amp;nbsp;strengthen national public health capacity and capability to deliver health gains through prevention and promotion measures, and emergency preparedness and response. IANPHI with its member national public health institutes look forward to this agreement making a real difference to the public&amp;rsquo;s health."&lt;p&gt;The strengthened alliance between WHO and IANPHI is critical to ensure that global and regional structures are designed to support national and local capacities and provide the right avenues for collaboration and coordination. Together WHO and IANPHI can leverage each other&amp;rsquo;s capacities to strengthen essential public health functions and emergency preparedness at national level and ultimately promote and protect the health and well-being of people. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The IANPHI is a network of 111 members in 94 countries and regions. It links and strengthens the government agencies responsible for public health. IANPHI leverages its members&amp;rsquo; expertise to build robust public health systems, promote universal health coverage, address communicable and non-communicable diseases, and strengthen preparedness and response. IANPHI supports strengthening existing national public health institutes and development of new ones in every country.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 16 Oct 2022 09:31:03 Z</pubDate></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">urn:uuid:93f45fc4-0052-4a31-a41a-61ae590568c4</guid><link>https://www.who.int/news/item/17-10-2022-one-health-joint-plan-of-action-launched-to-address-health-threats-to-humans--animals--plants-and-environment</link><a10:author><a10:name> </a10:name></a10:author><title>One Health Joint Plan of Action launched to address health threats to humans, animals, plants and environment</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Today, a new One Health Joint Plan of Action was launched by the Quadripartite &amp;ndash; the Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations (FAO), the United Nations Environment Programme (UNEP), the World Health Organization (WHO), and the World Organisation for Animal Health (WOAH, founded as OIE). &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This first joint plan on One Health aims to create a framework to integrate systems and capacity so that we can collectively better prevent, predict, detect, and respond to health threats. Ultimately, this initiative seeks to improve the health of humans, animals, plants, and the environment, while contributing to sustainable development. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The One Health Joint Plan of Action, developed through a participatory process, provides a set of activities that aim to strengthen collaboration, communication, capacity building, and coordination equally across all sectors responsible for addressing health concerns at the human-animal-plant-environment interface. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;One Health Joint Plan of Action (OH JPA) &lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The five-year plan (2022-2026) focuses on supporting and expanding capacities in six areas: One Health capacities for health systems, emerging and re-emerging zoonotic epidemics, endemic zoonotic, neglected tropical and vector-borne diseases, food safety risks, antimicrobial resistance and the environment.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This technical document is informed by evidence, best practices, and existing guidance. It covers a set of actions which endeavour to advance One Health at global, regional and national levels. These actions notably include the development of an upcoming implementation guidance for countries, international partners, and non-State actors such as civil society organizations, professional associations, academia and research institutions. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The plan sets out operational objectives, which include: providing a framework for collective and coordinated action to mainstream the One Health approach at all levels; providing upstream policy and legislative advice and technical assistance to help set national targets and priorities; and promoting multinational, multi-sector, multidisciplinary collaboration, learning and exchange of knowledge, solutions and technologies. It also fosters the values of cooperation and shared responsibility, multisectoral action and partnership, gender equity, and inclusiveness.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why One Health?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;One Health is the main approach for addressing the complex health challenges facing our society, such as ecosystem degradation, food system failures, infectious diseases and antimicrobial resistance. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Using a One Health lens that brings all relevant sectors together is critical to tackle global health threats, like monkeypox, COVID-19 and Ebola.&amp;rdquo; WOAH Director General Dr Monique Eloit&amp;nbsp;highlights the need for enhanced disease prevention capacity in all sectors. &amp;ldquo;It all starts with ensuring the health of animals. Animal health is our health, it is everyone&amp;rsquo;s health.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;FAO Director-General QU Dongyu&amp;nbsp;adds, &amp;ldquo;&lt;w:sdt sdttag="goog_rdk_0" id="-1244338695"&gt;One Health should start from proper land management and  stopping deforestation, which will help people and their animals in the  surrounding environment. We need all sectors working closely together to  identify and implement adaptation and mitigation measures.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/w:sdt&gt;&lt;w:sdt showingplchdr="t" sdttag="goog_rdk_1" id="-100491397"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &lt;/w:sdt&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;UNEP Executive&amp;nbsp;Director Inger Andersen says that &amp;ldquo;Everyone has the right to a clean and healthy environment - the foundation of all life on Earth. The current pandemic unequivocally demonstrates that the degradation of nature is driving up health risks across the board.&amp;rdquo; Efforts by just one sector or specialty cannot prevent or eliminate infectious disease and other complex threats to One Health. She continued: &amp;ldquo;Vulnerable populations of all species, including the most poor and marginalized humans, bear the heaviest costs. The Joint Plan of Action will drive down health risks through an integrated approach to human, animal and environment health.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s clear that a One Health approach must be central to our shared work to strengthen the world&amp;rsquo;s defences against epidemics and pandemics such as COVID-19. That&amp;rsquo;s why One Health is one of the guiding principles of the new international agreement for pandemic prevention, preparedness and response, which our Member States are now negotiating.&amp;rdquo; WHO Director-General Dr Tedros Adhanom Ghebreyesus said. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Building on existing structures and agreements, mechanisms for coordinated financing are under development to support the plan&amp;rsquo;s implementation. The Quadripartite will join forces to leverage the needed resources in support of the common approach to address critical health threats and promote the health of people, animals, plants and the environment.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 16:15:46 Z</pubDate></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">urn:uuid:7f2d56e5-174d-4a57-a38e-c2132972efde</guid><link>https://www.who.int/news/item/16-10-2022-henrietta-lacks--family-appointed-world-health-organization-goodwill-ambassadors-for-cervical-cancer-elimination</link><a10:author><a10:name> </a10:name></a10:author><title>Henrietta Lacks’ family appointed World Health Organization Goodwill Ambassadors for Cervical Cancer Elimination</title><description>&lt;p&gt;WHO&amp;rsquo;s Director-General Dr Tedros Adhanom Ghebreyesus today appointed the Lacks family as WHO Goodwill Ambassadors for Cervical Cancer Elimination. The appointment recognizes their efforts to champion cervical cancer prevention and to preserve the memory of Henrietta Lacks, who died from cervical cancer in 1951.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Henrietta Lacks&amp;rsquo; story is one of injustice, with the vast contribution she made to science hidden from the world for many years. While she sought treatment for her cancer, researchers took biopsies from her body without her knowledge or consent. The cells they took, known as HeLa cells, subsequently became the first &amp;ldquo;immortal&amp;rdquo; cell line - meaning they are the only cells which have continued to live outside the human body and replicate. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Since the procedure was undertaken, these HeLa cells have contributed to countless medical breakthroughs, including the development of the human papillomavirus (HPV) vaccine, as well as COVID-19 research.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Much like the injustice of Henrietta Lacks&amp;rsquo; story, women all over the world from racial and minority ethnic groups face disproportionately higher risks from cervical cancer,&amp;rdquo; said Dr Tedros. &amp;ldquo;WHO&amp;rsquo;s goal is to eliminate cervical cancer, which means the innovations created with Henrietta Lacks&amp;rsquo; cells must be made available equitably to all women and girls. We look forward to working with the Lacks family to raise awareness on cervical cancer and advance racial equity in health and science.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The family, represented by Henrietta Lacks' son Lawrence Lacks, Sr., and his granddaughters, Victoria Baptiste and Veronica Robinson; and Alfred Lacks Carter, Jr., Henrietta Lacks&amp;rsquo; grandson, accepted the appointment at the World Health Summit in Berlin, during a session titled, &amp;ldquo;A Next Era for Women's Cancer Control.&amp;rdquo; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On behalf of the Lacks family, Alfred Lacks Carter, Jr. said, "Today, I humbly accept this honour to serve as a WHO Goodwill Ambassador for Cervical Cancer Elimination in the spirit of my mother - Deborah Lacks, who lost her mother, Henrietta, to Cervical Cancer, and worked to make certain the world recognizes her impact. Our Hennie's legacy lives on in us, and we will continue to stand in solidarity with WHO, patients, survivors, and families around the world to ensure that no other wife, mother, or sister dies needlessly from cervical cancer."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The appointment of the Lacks family as WHO Goodwill Ambassadors for Cervical Cancer Elimination adds momentum to the &lt;a href="https://www.who.int/initiatives/cervical-cancer-elimination-initiative#:~:text=Achieving%20elimination&amp;amp;text=Vaccination%3A%2090%25%20of%20girls%20fully,women%20with%20invasive%20cancer%20managed."&gt;global strategy to eliminate cervical cancer&lt;/a&gt;, launched by WHO in 2020. The global effort represents the first time ever that WHO Member States have collectively committed to eliminate a cancer.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The strategy lists three goals that countries should reach by the year 2030: First, 90% of eligible girls should be fully vaccinated with the HPV vaccine. Second, 70% of women should be screened using a high-performance test. And third, 90% of women with pre-cancer should have access to treatment and 90% of women with invasive cancer should be managed appropriately, including access to palliative care.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Currently, a woman dies of cervical cancer every two minutes. Nearly 90% of these deaths occur in low- and middle-income countries due to inadequate access to cancer prevention, diagnosis and care. In all geographies, women in marginalized communities are disproportionately affected.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Lacks family joins other ambassadors from WHO, including Ivorian footballer Didier Drogba, Brazilian world champion footballer Alisson Becker, Michael Bloomberg, founder of Bloomberg Philanthropies and three-term Mayor of the City of New York, Cynthia Germanotta, President of the Born This Way Foundation, and former UK Prime Minister Gordon Brown. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Ambassadorship follows the bestowment of a special posthumous award to Henrietta Lacks from the   &lt;a href="https://www.who.int/news/item/13-10-2021-who-director-general-bestows-posthumous-award-on-the-late-henrietta-lacks"&gt;WHO Director-General,&lt;/a&gt; given to her family on her behalf in 2021. It reflects WHO&amp;rsquo;s ongoing commitment to the active participation of people affected by cervical cancer as central to the elimination effort.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;About Henrietta Lacks&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As a young mother, Henrietta Lacks and her husband were raising five children near Baltimore when she fell ill.&amp;nbsp; She went to Johns Hopkins after experiencing extensive vaginal bleeding and was diagnosed with cervical cancer.&amp;nbsp; Despite treatment, it cut her life short on 4 October 1951. She was only 31 years old.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;During treatment, researchers took samples of her tumour. That &amp;ldquo;HeLa&amp;rdquo; cell line became a scientific breakthrough: the first immortal line of human cells to divide indefinitely in a laboratory.&amp;nbsp; The cells were mass produced, for profit, without recognition to her family. Over 50 million metric tonnes of HeLa cells have been distributed around the world.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In addition to the HPV vaccine, HeLa cells allowed for development of the polio vaccine; drugs for HIV, haemophilia, leukaemia, and Parkinson&amp;rsquo;s disease; breakthroughs in reproductive health, including in vitro fertilization; research on chromosomal conditions, cancer, gene mapping, and precision medicine; and are used in studies responding to the COVID-19 pandemic.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lawrence Lacks, Mrs. Lacks&amp;rsquo; 87-year-old son, is one of the last living relatives who personally knew her. Mr. Lacks shares this honor with his granddaughters Victoria Baptiste and Veronica Robinson, and his nephew Alfred Lacks Carter, Jr.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Quotes from the Lacks family&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lawrence Lacks, Sr.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Son of Henrietta Lacks&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Thank you to the World Health Organization for the honour of appointing us as WHO Goodwill Ambassadors for Cervical Cancer Elimination. I am humbled to join my granddaughters Victoria and Veronica and my nephew Alfred in accepting this commitment in honour of my mother, Henrietta Lacks. I want to thank Dr Tedros, Dr Nono, and WHO for recognizing all the good my mother has done for the world."&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Victoria Baptiste, BSN, RN&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lacks Family Descendant&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;As a Registered Nurse, I am deeply moved to accept this honour today to serve as a World Health Organization Goodwill Ambassador for Cervical Cancer Elimination. We know Cervical Cancer can be prevented and treated if caught early - that's why I remain committed to this mission in honour of Henrietta Lacks, who has helped make these breakthroughs possible. Together, we can end cervical cancer by educating, empowering, and mobilizing patient advocates, health-care providers, clinicians, researchers, community leaders, and policy-makers to increase prevention, screening, and treatment worldwide."&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Veronica Robinson&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lacks Family Descendant&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"As a patient advocate, I am dedicated to working with WHO to advance the Global Strategy to Eliminate Cervical Cancer and am grateful for the opportunity to serve as a Goodwill Ambassador. From our home in Baltimore, Maryland, to communities around the world, we are resolute in taking action to end Cervical Cancer disparities. Henrietta's HeLa cells contributed to life-saving innovations like the HPV vaccine and cervical cancer treatment. As advocates, we call upon global leaders, policy-makers, and civil society organisations to honour her legacy by providing equal access to cervical cancer education, screening, vaccination, and treatment for all people."&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 08:34:47 Z</pubDate></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">urn:uuid:71715422-7c65-4c01-bfdf-de5521ba3117</guid><link>https://www.who.int/news/item/17-10-2022-towards-stronger-food-safety-systems-and-global-cooperation</link><a10:author><a10:name> </a10:name></a10:author><title>Towards stronger food safety systems and global cooperation</title><description>Today WHO launches the WHO Global Strategy for Food Safety 2022-2030, adopted by Member States at the 75th Session of the World Health Assembly - Resolution WHA75(22). The launch marks a milestone in WHO work to promote health, keep the world safe and protect the vulnerable.</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2022 10:15:34 Z</pubDate><a10:content type="text">&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Today WHO launches the WHO Global Strategy for Food Safety 2022-2030, adopted by Member States at the 75th Session of the World Health Assembly - &lt;a href="https://apps.who.int/gb/ebwha/pdf_files/WHA75/A75(22)-en.pdf"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://apps.who.int/gb/ebwha/pdf_files/WHA75/A75(22)-en.pdf" target="_blank"&gt;Resolution WHA75(22)&lt;/a&gt;. The launch marks a milestone in WHO work to promote health, keep the world safe and protect the vulnerable.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Every year, one in ten people globally fall ill due to foodborne diseases. Contaminated food can cause over 200 diseases, and the magnitude of public health burden is comparable to malaria or HIV AIDS. Children under five are at higher risk, as one in six deaths from diarrhoea are caused by unsafe food. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The updated WHO Global Strategy for Food Safety is a step towards a safer and healthier world, but also towards strengthening multisectoral collaboration and innovative public health approaches. The Global Food Safety Strategy has been developed to guide and support Member States in their efforts to prioritize, plan, implement, monitor and regularly evaluate actions towards the reduction of the burden of foodborne diseases (FBD) by continuously strengthening food safety systems and promoting global cooperation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Strategy&amp;rsquo;s vision is that all people, everywhere, consume safe and healthy food so as to reduce the burden of FBDs. This strategy gives stakeholders the tools they need to strengthen their national food safety systems and collaborate with partners around the world.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This new WHO Global Strategy for Food Safety 2022-2030 addresses current and emerging challenges, incorporates new technologies and includes innovative approaches for strengthening food safety systems. It also reflects feedback received through a comprehensive consultation process with Member States and governmental institutions, United Nations agencies and other intergovernmental organizations, academic institutions, non-governmental organizations, private sector entities, and individuals working in public health and food safety.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The strategy also sets concrete targets and aims to reduce the burden of foodborne diseases by reducing 40% the number of cases of foodborne diarrheal diseases incidence that affects most the children under 5 and other vulnerable populations. It also has a target of 100% of functional coordination mechanisms to manage foodborne events and enhanced laboratory capacity for foodborne disease surveillance.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The strategy has identified five interlinked and mutually reinforcing strategic priorities with respective strategic objectives. Using the identified five strategic priorities and respective strategic objectives, the strategy aims to build proactive, forward-looking, evidence-based, people-centred, and cost-effective food safety systems with coordinated governance and adequate infrastructures. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Strategic priorities:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Strengthening national food control systems. &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Identifying and responding to food safety challenges resulting from global changes and food systems transformation.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Improving the use of food chain information, scientific evidence and risk assessment in making risk management decisions.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Strengthening stakeholder engagement and risk communication.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Promoting food safety as an essential component in domestic, regional and international food trade.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;WHO and the members of the &lt;a href="https://www.who.int/groups/technical-advisory-group-on-food-safety-safer-food-for-better-health/about"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="https://www.who.int/groups/technical-advisory-group-on-food-safety-safer-food-for-better-health"&gt;Technical Advisory Group on Food Safety&lt;/a&gt; are working on tools to complement the existing sources from WHO, FAO and other organizations to support Member States in the implementation of the strategy over 2022-2030. The collaboration among different sectors and stakeholders is key for the implementation of the strategy, and the implementation plan of the strategy is aligned with the FAO food safety strategic priorities through a joint coordination framework.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Background&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In 2020, the Resolution 73.5 titled &amp;lsquo;&amp;lsquo;Strengthening efforts on food safety&amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo; was adopted by the Seventy-third World Health Assembly. In the resolution, Member States requested WHO to update the WHO Global Strategy for Food Safety to address current and emerging challenges, incorporate new technologies and include innovative approaches for strengthening food safety systems.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In response to this request, the WHO Secretariat has prepared a WHO Global Strategy for Food Safety with the advice of the Technical Advisory Group (TAG) on Food Safety: Safer food for better health. The current strategy reflects feedback received through a comprehensive consultation process with Member States and governmental institutions, United Nations agencies and other intergovernmental organizations, academic institutions, non-governmental organizations, private sector entities, and individuals working in public health and food safety.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;WHO Global Strategy for Food Safety 2022-2030, adopted by Resolution 75(22) during the 75th World Health Assembly, is available  &lt;a href="https://www.who.int/publications-detail-redirect/9789240057685" target="_blank"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For more information about the strategy, join the launch webinar on October 17 at 12:00 CET. Register &lt;a href="https://who.zoom.us/webinar/register/WN_fJl9E3MDTAiG8dALx9bTkQ"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://who.zoom.us/webinar/register/WN_fJl9E3MDTAiG8dALx9bTkQ" target="_blank"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</a10:content></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">urn:uuid:c92aa93e-cf5e-451a-8b75-88e0245cf949</guid><link>https://www.who.int/news/item/10-10-2022-unique-friendship-benches-initiative-inaugurated-to-promote-mental-health--featuring-competing-fifa-world-cup-nations</link><a10:author><a10:name> </a10:name></a10:author><title>Unique Friendship Benches initiative inaugurated to promote mental health, featuring competing FIFA World Cup nations</title><description>&lt;ul data-list="0" data-level="1"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;32 benches &amp;ndash; representing each participating FIFA World Cup nation &amp;ndash; are being built to promote mental health. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Benches announcement coincides with today&amp;rsquo;s World Mental Health Day and symbolic inauguration event at 974 Stadium, Doha&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;H.E. Sheikha Hind and Sir Mo Farah unveiled England bench during World Innovation Summit for Health&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A unique project involving custom-made public benches to promote the critical importance of mental health, and the role that football and sport more broadly can play to promote mental well-being, was announced today. Thirty-two &amp;ldquo;Friendship Benches&amp;rdquo; &amp;ndash; one for each nation competing in the&amp;nbsp;FIFA World Cup Qatar 2022&amp;trade; &amp;ndash; are being built for installation in prominent Doha locations, including the precincts of tournament stadiums.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The project is part of the &lt;a href="https://www.who.int/initiatives/sports-and-health/healthy-2022-world-cup"&gt;Sport for Health partnership&lt;/a&gt;, led by the World Health Organization and Qatar&amp;rsquo;s Ministry of Public Health. Its goal is to demonstrate the importance of mental health and offer advice on ways to promote mental well-being, including through the importance of physical activity and sport. The initiative is supported by FIFA, the Supreme Committee for Delivery &amp;amp; Legacy, &lt;a href="https://2022.wish.org.qa/"&gt;WISH&lt;/a&gt;, the &lt;a href="https://www.friendshipbenchzimbabwe.org/"&gt;Friendship Benches&lt;/a&gt; NGO and the &lt;a href="https://extranet.who.int/uhcpartnership/"&gt;WHO Universal Health Coverage Partnership.&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In conjunction with &lt;a href="https://www.who.int/campaigns/world-mental-health-day/2022"&gt;World Mental Health Day&lt;/a&gt;, a selection of the first benches is being &amp;nbsp;presented today at 974 Stadium, in Doha, one of the venues for this year&amp;rsquo;s FIFA World Cup. The bench initiative was symbolically inaugurated with the preview of the England bench at Qatar Foundation&amp;rsquo;s global health event, the World Innovation Summit for Health (WISH) in the lead-up a larger reveal of the benches on &lt;a href="https://www.who.int/campaigns/world-mental-health-day/2022"&gt;World Mental Health Day&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;English athlete Sir Mo Farah, whose ten Olympic and World Championship gold medals make him the most successful male track distance runner ever, inaugurated the England bench, where he was joined by Her Excellency Sheikha Hind bint Hamad Al Thani, Vice Chairperson and CEO of Qatar Foundation, for a conversation about sport and mental health &amp;ndash; a symbolic recognition of the initiative.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Meeting Sir Mo and hearing the compelling story of how he left Mogadishu for London as a young boy and the mental health challenges he faced highlighted the importance of sitting down and talking about our mental health,&amp;rdquo; H.E. Sheikha Hind said. &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m proud that Qatar Foundation&amp;rsquo;s global health initiative is among those helping shine a spotlight on mental health in such an innovative and practical way.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The benches project aligns with common goals and campaigns of each of partner organization, including the &lt;a href="https://www.fifa.com/about-fifa/medical/news/fifa-launches-reach-out-campaign-for-better-mental-health"&gt;FIFA-WHO #REACHOUT campaign&lt;/a&gt;, the &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href="https://sehanafsia.moph.gov.qa/English/Pages/AreYouOk.aspx"&gt;Are You OK?&amp;rdquo; project&lt;/a&gt; of the Qatar&amp;rsquo;s Ministry of Public Health, and the groundbreaking Friendship Benches project itself, originally developed in Zimbabwe and supported by WHO. The WISH event has in the past also been used as a platform to promote the Friendship Benches concept. This initiative also aims at promoting physical activity as one of the key outcomes of the Sport and Health project.&amp;nbsp; To this end a special feature appearing on each bench are illustrations with advice describing easy and effective exercises that visitors can practice for their physical health.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The bench is a simple yet powerful vehicle for promoting mental health, from park benches&amp;nbsp; to football stadiums,&amp;rdquo; said Dr Tedros Adhanom Ghebreyesus, WHO Director-General. &amp;ldquo;The Friendship Benches project is a reminder of how the simple act of sitting down to talk can make a huge difference to mental health.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;H.E. Dr Hanan Al Kuwari, Minister of Public Health, Qatar, said the benches project was a tangible, lasting symbol of the importance of the Sport for Health partnership and the goals it is striving to achieve for the upcoming FIFA World Cup&amp;trade; in Qatar &amp;ndash; the first held in the Middle East and Arab world &amp;ndash; and the legacy WHO and the Qatar&amp;rsquo;s Ministry of Public Health are working to leave.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Mental health is a core component of the Sport For Health partnership and our goal is for the Friendship Benches to provide a place, during and after the FIFA World Cup, for residents and visitors to Qatar to come together and ask each other &amp;lsquo;Are You OK?&amp;rsquo; and use the opportunity to engage in dialogue and physical activities,&amp;rdquo; H.E. Dr Al Kuwari said.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;H.E. Hassan Al Thawadi, Secretary General, SC, said: &amp;ldquo;We are proud to support this project and further leverage our hosting of the FIFA World Cup. The benches will provide a permanent reminder of the first World Cup in the Middle East and Arab world, while promoting the importance of mental health in communities throughout the country.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;FIFA President Gianni Infantino said: &amp;ldquo;Through the #REACHOUT campaign, we acknowledged the importance of speaking with family and friends to foster positive mental health. The Friendship Benches project is another vehicle to raise awareness about mental health conditions and to encourage a conversation, which could save a life. FIFA is proud to partner with the World Health Organization, and Qatar&amp;rsquo;s Ministry of Public Health to put football at the service of society, and to leave a lasting legacy in Qatar for residents and visitors.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Final locations of each of the 32 benches will be announced shortly. Once installed, information will be shared on how residents of Qatar and visitors will be able to visit their national benches, and others, in a show of support for mental health promotion.&amp;nbsp; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;---------------------------------------------------&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Editor&amp;rsquo;s note:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Video footage and photographs will be shared with media from the Friendship Benches inauguration event on 10 October.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;At 4pm Doha time, a live discussion hosted by WHO will be broadcast on its Facebook channel &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/WHO"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/WHO&lt;/a&gt; &lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Contacts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Interviews and other information:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul data-list="0" data-level="1"&gt;&lt;li&gt;Supreme Committee for Delivery &amp;nbsp;&amp;amp; Legacy: &lt;a href="mailto:media@sc.qa"&gt;media@sc.qa&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2022 07:40:37 Z</pubDate></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">urn:uuid:d5fd3524-514c-4c55-81fe-1513082642b5</guid><link>https://www.who.int/news/item/28-09-2022-in-strategic-dialogues--the-united-states-and-who-seek-to-maximize-their-longstanding-partnership</link><a10:author><a10:name> </a10:name></a10:author><title>In strategic dialogues, the United States and WHO seek to maximize their longstanding partnership</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Washington &amp;ndash; WHO Director-General Dr Tedros Adhanom Ghebreyesus&amp;nbsp;and United States Secretary of Health and Human Services Xavier Becerra agreed Tuesday to develop a work plan in 2023 to tackle shared priorities, chief among them the world&amp;rsquo;s
    health security and pandemic preparedness.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;As always, good to see Dr Tedros and discuss how we can promote the health of all people across the globe,&amp;rdquo; Secretary Becerra tweeted after the meeting.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The strategic dialogue focused on universal health coverage, primary health care, equity, and the global health workforce.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;While in Washington, Dr Tedros also met with US Surgeon General Dr Vivek Murthy, White House COVID-19 Response Coordinator Dr Ashish K. Jha, US Rep. Barbara Lee, US Sen. Bob Menendez, Deputy Secretary of State for Management and Resources Brian McKeon
    and USAID Administrator Samantha Power.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dr Tedros said he was grateful to Secretary Becerra for the &amp;ldquo;very productive strategic dialogue on how to strengthen WHO and reinforce global health security, including via a pandemic accord, investment in health-systems strengthening and prioritizing
    primary health care across the world.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dr Tedros and the Surgeon General discussed ways that the United States and WHO could collaborate on mental health and touched upon the impact of loneliness on people&amp;rsquo;s health.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.who.int/news/item/27-09-2022-joint-statement-of-the-united-states-of-america-and-the-world-health-organization-on-the-u.s.-who-strategic-dialogue"&gt;WHO and the United States released a joint statement following the meetings&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For many years, the United States has been one of WHO&amp;rsquo;s largest donors. It was the third largest in 2020-21, investing about US$ 700 million. In December 2021, the United States announced a US$ 280 million contribution to support critical work to
    help end the COVID-19 pandemic, strengthen public health systems and provide urgent relief.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The United States is a longtime supporter of WHO&amp;rsquo;s fight against polio, HIV/AIDS, tuberculosis and malaria, while helping advance global health priorities such as primary care for women and children, food and drug safety, and global health security.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The United States maintains a strong presence in WHO collaborating centres, lending its expertise across areas such as &amp;nbsp;addressing cancer, occupational health, communicable diseases, nutrition, mental health, chronic diseases and improving health
    technologies.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The next strategic dialogues between the United States and WHO are tentatively planned for late 2023.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note to readers:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This news piece was edited on 29 September 2022 to improve clarity.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2022 14:25:21 Z</pubDate></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">urn:uuid:927ea549-8eba-4008-b5f2-e17a8fa08fd1</guid><link>https://www.who.int/news/item/27-09-2022-joint-statement-of-the-united-states-of-america-and-the-world-health-organization-on-the-u.s.-who-strategic-dialogue</link><a10:author><a10:name> </a10:name></a10:author><title>Joint statement of the United States of America and the World Health Organization on the U.S.-WHO strategic dialogue</title><description>U.S. Department of Health and Human Services Secretary Xavier Becerra and World Health Organization (WHO) Director-General Dr Tedros Adhanom Ghebreyesus held the first U.S.-WHO Strategic Dialogue.</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2022 20:28:43 Z</pubDate><a10:content type="text">&lt;p&gt;U.S. Department of Health and Human Services Secretary Xavier Becerra and World Health Organization (WHO) Director-General Dr Tedros Adhanom Ghebreyesus held the first U.S.-WHO Strategic Dialogue. Convened under the Biden-Harris Administration, the U.S.-WHO Strategic Dialogue provides a platform to maximize the longstanding U.S. government-WHO partnership, and to protect and promote the health of all people around the globe, including the American people.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Representatives from across the United States Government and WHO leadership discussed several priority global public health issues and areas of collaboration and partnership, including ongoing WHO strengthening efforts. The U.S. and WHO welcomed the creation of the historic new financial intermediary fund for pandemic prevention, preparedness, and response, and called on countries to help ensure it is sustainably financed and supported.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As the world looks to emerge stronger from the COVID-19 pandemic, it is clear that we must be better prepared going forward, something highlighted by recent outbreaks of monkeypox, ebola, and polio. The global health architecture comprises important entities, policies, and legal tools that assist countries to improve national, regional, and global health. An essential aspect of this architecture is the ability to prevent, detect, and respond to pandemics and other health security threats. Secretary Becerra and Director-General Tedros agreed that national and global capacities must be strong, agile, ever improving, and always fit-for-purpose. They discussed efforts underway to improve the global health architecture, to support resilient health systems, and to advance health equity.&amp;nbsp; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The discussion also addressed efforts to develop a new pandemic instrument, strengthening the International Health Regulations (IHR), including through targeted amendments, as well as scaling-up of Universal Health Preparedness Review, including the Joint External Evaluation and other relevant tools, and updating global, regional, and national epidemic and One Health surveillance capabilities. It is also vital to take forward opportunities for advancing health security and primary health care, including by leveraging the extensive global health data infrastructure supported by a number of U.S. Government programs. In promoting rapid and transparent data sharing, and coordination, strengthened IHRs, and a new pandemic instrument can provide important tools to WHO Member States, including the United States, to prevent, detect, and rapidly respond to new events with pandemic potential and monitor disease control measures. This reinforcing of global health security is essential to protect the health of the world and the American people.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;In addition to strengthening health emergency preparedness and response, the United States and WHO recommitted to strengthening our partnership in key areas for the world to reach the Sustainable Development Goals by 2030, progress towards is a quarter of the pace needed. Accelerated progress will require resilient health systems capable of handling future health emergencies, reorienting towards &lt;w:sdt sdttag="goog_rdk_29" id="572397206"&gt;integrated&lt;/w:sdt&gt; primary health care as a means to achieve universal health coverage, investing in comprehensive health and care workforce development and community engagement, and promoting policies that recognize the links between the environment and health to improve quality of life. Accelerating progress towards the SDGs also requires leveraging progress made in addressing HIV, TB, polio, and malaria, advancing sexual and reproductive health and rights, and empowering marginalized and vulnerable communities in global health.&amp;nbsp; Furthermore, U.S. and WHO leadership also discussed progress made on budgetary and governance reform as well as WHO&amp;rsquo;s work to prevent and respond to sexual exploitation and abuse and sexual harassment.&amp;nbsp; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Recognizing there is much more to do together to improve and promote global public health, the United States and the WHO decided to task technical experts with further development of their collaboration in 2023, including a joint work plan with a focus on activities in support of these shared leadership objectives.&amp;nbsp; Secretary Becerra and Director-General Tedros will continue their positive engagement and guide the work of the technical teams with an expected update and reassessment by the next U.S.-WHO Strategic Dialogue to be held in late 2023.&lt;/p&gt;</a10:content></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">urn:uuid:275bb930-975c-451f-8cb8-073b85dd3420</guid><link>https://www.who.int/news/item/28-09-2022-who-and-ilo-call-for-new-measures-to-tackle-mental-health-issues-at-work</link><a10:author><a10:name> </a10:name></a10:author><title>WHO and ILO call for new measures to tackle mental health issues at work</title><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;New global WHO guidelines on mental health at work are reinforced by practical strategies outlined in a joint WHO/ILO policy brief.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;WHO and the International Labour Organization (ILO) have called for concrete actions to address mental health concerns in the working population.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;An estimated 12 billion workdays are lost annually due to depression and anxiety costing the global economy nearly US$ 1 trillion. Two new publications which aim to address this issue are published today - WHO Guidelines on mental health at work and a
    derivative WHO/ILO policy brief. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;WHO&amp;rsquo;s global guidelines on mental health at work recommend actions to tackle risks to mental health such as heavy workloads, negative behaviours, and other factors that create distress at work. For the first time WHO recommends manager training,
    to build their capacity to prevent stressful work environments and respond to workers in distress. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;WHO&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href="https://www.who.int/publications-detail-redirect/9789240049338"&gt;World Mental Health Report&lt;/a&gt;,
 published in June 2022, showed that of one billion people living with a mental disorder in 2019, 15% of working-age adults experienced a mental disorder. Work amplifies wider societal issues that negatively affect mental health, including discrimination
    and inequality. Bullying and psychological violence (also known as &amp;ldquo;mobbing&amp;rdquo;) is a key complaint of workplace harassment that has a negative impact on mental health. Yet discussing or disclosing mental health remains a taboo in work settings
    globally. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The guidelines also recommend better ways to accommodate the needs of workers with mental health conditions, propose interventions that support their return to work and, for those with severe mental health conditions, provide interventions that facilitate
    entry into paid employment. Importantly, the guidelines call for interventions aimed at the protection of health, humanitarian, and emergency workers. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s time to focus on the detrimental effect work can have on our mental health,&amp;rdquo; said Dr Tedros Adhanom Ghebreyesus, WHO Director-General. &amp;ldquo;The well-being of the individual is reason enough to act, but poor mental health can
    also have a debilitating impact on a person&amp;rsquo;s performance and productivity. These new guidelines can help prevent negative work situations and cultures and offer much-needed mental health protection and support for working people.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A separate WHO/ILO policy brief explains the WHO guidelines in terms of practical strategies for governments, employers and workers, and their organizations, in the public and private sectors. The aim is to support the prevention of mental health risks,
    protect and promote mental health at work, and support those with mental health conditions, so they can participate and thrive in the world of work. Investment and leadership will be critical to the implementation of the strategies.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;As people spend a large proportion of their lives in work &amp;ndash; a safe and healthy working environment is critical. We need to invest to build a culture of prevention around mental health at work, reshape the work environment to stop stigma and
    social exclusion, and ensure employees with mental health conditions feel protected and supported,&amp;rdquo; said, Guy Ryder, ILO Director-General.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.ilo.org/dyn/normlex/en/f?p=NORMLEXPUB:12100:0::NO::P12100_ILO_CODE:C155" target="_blank"&gt;ILO Occupational Safety and Health Convention (No. 155)&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.ilo.org/dyn/normlex/en/f?p=NORMLEXPUB:12100:0::NO::P12100_ILO_CODE:R164" target="_blank"&gt;Recommendation (No. 164)&lt;/a&gt; provides legal frameworks to protect the health and safety of workers. However, the &lt;a href="https://www.who.int/publications-detail-redirect/9789240036703"&gt;WHO Mental Health Atlas&lt;/a&gt; found that only 35% of countries reported having national programmes for work-related mental health promotion and prevention.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.who.int/news/item/02-03-2022-covid-19-pandemic-triggers-25-increase-in-prevalence-of-anxiety-and-depression-worldwide"&gt;COVID-19 triggered a 25% increase in general anxiety and depression worldwide&lt;/a&gt;, exposing how unprepared governments were for its impact on mental health, and revealing a chronic global shortage of mental health resources. In 2020, governments worldwide
    spent an average of just 2% of health budgets on mental health, with lower-middle income countries investing less than 1%.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2022 10:07:13 Z</pubDate></item></channel></rss>