<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:rdau="http://rdaregistry.info/Elements/u/#" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:swpo="http://sw-portal.deri.org/ontologies/swportal#" xmlns:identifiers="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/identifiers/" xmlns:ebucore="http://www.ebu.ch/metadata/ontologies/ebucore/ebucore#">
<channel>
<title>Federal Reserve Bank of Chicago publications</title>
<description>Economic research and commentary from Federal Reserve Bank of Chicago</description>
<link>https://fedinprint.org/search?facets[]=provider_literal_array:Federal+Reserve+Bank+of+Chicago</link>
<atom:link href="https://fedinprint.org/search?facets[]=provider_literal_array:Federal+Reserve+Bank+of+Chicago" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2022 16:19:40 +0000</pubDate>
<item>
<title>(Trade) War and Peace: How to Impose International Trade Sanctions</title>
<link>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedhwp/94958/original</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[Trade sanctions are a common instrument of diplomatic retaliation. To guide current and future policy, we ask: What is the most cost-efficient way to impose trade
sanctions against Russia? To answer this question, we build a quantitative model of international trade with input-output connections. Sanctioning countries simultaneously choose import tariffs to maximize their income and to minimize Russia’s income, with different weights placed on these objectives. We find, first, that for countries with a small willingness to pay for sanctions against Russia, the most cost-efficient sanction is a uniform, about 20% tariff against all Russian products. Second, if countries are willing to pay at least US$0.7 for each US$1 drop in Russian welfare, an embargo on Russia’s mining and energy products - with tariffs above 50% on other products - is the most cost-efficient policy. Finally, if countries target politically relevant sectors, an embargo against Russia’s mining and energy sector is the cost-efficient policy even when there is a small willingness to pay for sanctions.]]>
</description>
<guid>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedhwp/94958/original</guid>
<dc:creator>Mei, Yuan; Hu, Naiyuan; Li, Haishi; de Souza, Gustavo</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2022-10-05</dc:date>
<rdau:hasExtent>74</rdau:hasExtent>
<dc:subject>trade sanctions; Tariff; tariff competition</dc:subject>
<swpo:hasNumber>WP 2022-49</swpo:hasNumber>
<bibo:series>Working Paper Series</bibo:series>
</item>
<item>
<title>Optimal Unemployment Insurance Requirements</title>
<link>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedhwp/94916/original</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[In the U.S., workers must satisfy two requirements to receive unemployment insurance (UI): a tenure requirement of a minimum work spell and a monetary requirement of a past minimum earnings. Using discontinuity of UI rules at state borders, we find that the monetary requirement decreases the number of employers and the share of part-time workers, while the tenure requirement has the opposite effect. In a quantitative model, the monetary requirement induce workers to search longer because low paying jobs are not covered by UI. Since it mitigates moral hazard, the optimal UI design has a high monetary requirement.]]>
</description>
<guid>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedhwp/94916/original</guid>
<dc:creator>de Souza, Gustavo; Luduvice, Andre</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2022-04-01</dc:date>
<rdau:hasExtent>52</rdau:hasExtent>
<dc:subject>Unemployment Insurance; UI Eligibility; Optimal UI</dc:subject>
<swpo:hasNumber>WP 2022-45</swpo:hasNumber>
<bibo:series>Working Paper Series</bibo:series>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Employment Consequences of Anti-Dumping Tariffs: Lessons from Brazil</title>
<link>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedhwp/94915/original</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[Can anti-dumping tariffs increase employment? We compile data on all antidumping (AD) investigations in Brazil matching it to firm-level administrative employment information. Using difference-in-differences, we find that an AD tariff decreases imports and increases employment in the protected sector. Moreover, downstream firms decrease employment, while upstream ones are not affected. To quantify the aggregate effect of these tariffs, we build a model with international trade, input-output linkages, and labor force participation. We show that the Brazilian AD policy increased employment by 0.06%, but decreased welfare by 2.4%. Using tariffs, the government can increase employment by as much as 2.8%.]]>
</description>
<guid>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedhwp/94915/original</guid>
<dc:creator>de Souza, Gustavo; Li, Haishi</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2022-10-05</dc:date>
<rdau:hasExtent>102</rdau:hasExtent>
<dc:subject>Employment; Tariffs; Anti-Dumping; International Trade</dc:subject>
<swpo:hasNumber>WP 2022-46</swpo:hasNumber>
<bibo:series>Working Paper Series</bibo:series>
</item>
<item>
<title>On Political and Economic Determinants of Redistribution: Economic Gains, Ideological Gains, or Institutions?</title>
<link>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedhwp/94914/original</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[I describe a structural method to quantify the contribution of different elements of social choice to the level of redistribution. Estimating a DSGE model with microdata on the support for redistribution, I find that if voters disregarded their ideological views on welfare policies, redistribution in the U.S. would increase 117%. Because ideology is a more important determinant of voting behavior than income, increasing voter turnout or capping campaign contributions would have a small effect on redistribution. Among the drivers of ideology, I find that racial animosity and distrust of the government contributes to an 80% and 44% smaller redistribution, respectively.]]>
</description>
<guid>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedhwp/94914/original</guid>
<dc:creator>de Souza, Gustavo</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2022-10-05</dc:date>
<rdau:hasExtent>48</rdau:hasExtent>
<dc:subject>Redistribution; Prefereces for Redistribution; Dynamic Macro Models of Political-Economoy</dc:subject>
<swpo:hasNumber>WP 2022-47</swpo:hasNumber>
<bibo:series>Working Paper Series</bibo:series>
</item>
<item>
<title>Inflation as a Fiscal Limit</title>
<link>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedhwp/94748/original</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[Low and stable inflation requires an appropriate fiscal framework aimed at stabilizing government debt. Historically, trend inflation is critically influenced by actual or perceived changes to this framework, while cost-push shocks only account for short-lasting movements in inflation. Before the pandemic, a moderate level of fiscal inflation has counteracted deflationary pressures, helping the central bank to avoid deflation. The recent fiscal interventions in response to the Covid pandemic have altered the private sector’s beliefs about the fiscal framework, accelerating the recovery, but also determining an increase in fiscal inflation. This increase in inflation could not have been averted by simply tightening monetary policy. The conquest of post-pandemic inflation requires mutually consistent monetary and fiscal policies to avoid fiscal stagflation.]]>
</description>
<guid>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedhwp/94748/original</guid>
<dc:creator>Melosi, Leonardo; Bianchi, Francesco</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2022-29-08</dc:date>
<dc:subject>fiscal limits; Monetary policy; Fiscal policy; Inflation (Finance) - United States; Government Debt; fiscal staglation</dc:subject>
<swpo:hasNumber>WP 2022-37</swpo:hasNumber>
<bibo:series>Working Paper Series</bibo:series>
</item>
<item>
<title>What Is the Impact of Monetary Policy on Households’ Desired Labor Supply?</title>
<link>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedhle/94742</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[Do people adjust how much they want to work when the central bank’s monetary policy stance shifts? More specifically, does an interest rate hike induce individuals to work more or fewer hours? And does this effect differ across households with different levels of income (or earnings)? In this article, we discuss our recent research that explores these and related questions. One notable finding is that employed individuals at the bottom of the income distribution want to work more when monetary policy tightens.]]>
</description>
<guid>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedhle/94742</guid>
<dc:creator>Mumtaz, Haroon; Theophilopoulou, Angeliki; Cantore, Cristiano; Ferroni, Filippo</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2022-09-08</dc:date>
<dc:subject>Macroeconomics; Monetary Economics</dc:subject>
<bibo:series>Chicago Fed Letter</bibo:series>
</item>
<item>
<title>What Is Driving U.S. Inflation amid a Global Inflation Surge?</title>
<link>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedhle/94682</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[In June 2022, the 12-month inflation rate of the U.S. Consumer Price Index (CPI) hit 9.1%, its highest level in over 40 years. The U.S. is not alone: Across the industrialized world, inflation is accelerating during the recovery from the pandemic recession. Although inflation is surging globally, the sources of inflation are different in each country.]]>
</description>
<guid>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedhle/94682</guid>
<dc:creator>Royal, James; Zhang, Jing; Miles, Russell; Hobijn, Bart</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2022-08</dc:date>
<bibo:series>Chicago Fed Letter</bibo:series>
</item>
<item>
<title>Sources of Fluctuation in Short-Term Yields and Recession Probabilities</title>
<link>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedhle/94681</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[An inverted yield curve—defined as an episode in which long-maturity Treasury yields fall below their short-maturity counterparts—is a powerful near-term predictor of recessions. While most previous studies focus on the predictive power of the spread between the long- and short-term Treasury yields, Engstrom and Sharpe (2019) have recently shown that a measure of the nominal near-term forward spread (NTFS), given by the difference 
between the six-quarter-ahead forward Treasury yield and the current three-month Treasury bill rate, dominates long-term spreads as a leading indicator of economic activity.]]>
</description>
<guid>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedhle/94681</guid>
<dc:creator>Ajello, Andrea; Timmer, Yannick; Schwinn, Makena; Vazquez-Grande, Francisco; Benzoni, Luca</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2022-08</dc:date>
<bibo:series>Chicago Fed Letter</bibo:series>
</item>
<item>
<title>How Common Was Blockbusting in the Postwar U.S.?</title>
<link>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedhle/94459</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[This article documents the prevalence of blockbusting—the orchestration of racial 
turnover in urban neighborhoods—throughout many major U.S. cities from the 1950s 
through the 1970s.]]>
</description>
<guid>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedhle/94459</guid>
<dc:creator>Bennett, Katherine; Rose, Jonathan D.; Hartley, Daniel</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2022-07-01</dc:date>
<rdau:hasExtent>6</rdau:hasExtent>
<bibo:issue>468</bibo:issue>
<bibo:series>Chicago Fed Letter</bibo:series>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Effects of the “Great Resignation” on Labor Market Slack and Inflation</title>
<link>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedhle/94269</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[The fraction of Americans switching their jobs has been increasing at a fast pace in the 
past 18 months, reaching its highest level on record. According to the U.S. Department of 
Labor, more than 4.5 million people voluntarily left their jobs in November 2021—the 
largest figure in the past two decades. This period has been dubbed the Great Resignation. 
At the same time, wages and salaries have accelerated considerably and by the end of 
2021, inflation had hit its highest level since 1982.]]>
</description>
<guid>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedhle/94269</guid>
<dc:creator>Melosi, Leonardo; Miles, Russell; Faccini, Renato</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2022-02-01</dc:date>
<rdau:hasExtent>7</rdau:hasExtent>
<dc:subject>Labor Market; Inflation; Great Resignation; Pandemic; Unemployment</dc:subject>
<bibo:issue>465</bibo:issue>
<bibo:series>Chicago Fed Letter</bibo:series>
</item>
<item>
<title>How Interconnected Are Cryptocurrencies and What Does This Mean for Risk Management</title>
<link>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedhle/93855</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[In the past couple of years, the market for digital currencies, commonly known as cryptocurrencies because transactions are verified using cryptography, has expanded significantly in terms of transaction volumes, market capitalization, and the number of digital currencies in existence. On January 1, 2018, the market capitalizations (market caps1) of Bitcoin and Ethereum were $226 billion and $75 billion, respectively. By May 10, 2021, Bitcoin’s market cap had reached almost $1 trillion and Ethereum’s $478 billion.
In this article, I measure the market’s interconnections in term of prices and volatility. Measuring 
interconnection (or connectedness) is important for both measuring and managing risk. The more the 
market is connected, the more sensitive it is to shocks. While the cryptocurrency market is not very 
large relative to the other markets studied in the literature, it is growing at a fast pace and a preliminary 
assessment might be useful. Moreover, the risk associated with a portfolio of cryptocurrencies is 
not simply a weighted sum of the risks of its components; rather, the overall risk depends on how the 
pieces interact—whether and how they are connected. Similarly, in an interconnected market, the 
risk of a single currency does not depend only on its own idiosyncratic characteristics, but also on 
the volatility of other currencies and on the extent to which they are interconnected.]]>
</description>
<guid>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedhle/93855</guid>
<dc:creator>Ferroni, Filippo</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2022-03-01</dc:date>
<rdau:hasExtent>5</rdau:hasExtent>
<dc:subject>Cryptocurrencies; Market integration; Connectedness and Spillover; VAR; Portfolio Choice; investment decisions; Financial Forecasting and Simulation; Federal Reserve Bank of Chicago; Chicago Fed; Federal Reserve System</dc:subject>
<bibo:issue>466</bibo:issue>
<bibo:series>Chicago Fed Letter</bibo:series>
</item>
<item>
<title>Has the Willingness to Work Fallen During the Pandemic?</title>
<link>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedhwp/93800/original</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[We examine the effect of the Covid pandemic on willingness to work along both the extensive and 
intensive margins of labor supply. Special survey questions in the Job Search Supplement of the 
Survey of Consumer Expectations (SCE) allow us to elicit information about individuals’ desired 
work hours for the 2013-2021 period. Using these questions, along with workers’ actual labor 
market participation, we construct a labor market underutilization measure, the Aggregate Hours 
Gap (AHG), following Faberman et al. (2020). The AHG captures changes in labor market 
underutilization for the full population along both the extensive and intensive margins using data 
on desired work hours as a measure of their potential labor supply. We find that the sharp increase 
in the AHG during the Covid pandemic essentially disappeared by the end of 2021. We also 
document a sharp decline in desired work hours during the pandemic that persists through the end 
of 2021 and is roughly double the drop in the labor force participation rate. Ignoring the decline in 
desired hours overstates the degree of underutilization by 2.5 percentage points (12.5%). Our 
findings suggest that, as of 2021Q4, the labor market is tighter than suggested by the 
unemployment rate and the adverse labor supply effect of the pandemic is more pronounced than 
implied by the labor force participation rate. These discrepancies underscore the importance of 
taking into account the intensive margin for both labor market underutilization and potential labor 
supply.]]>
</description>
<guid>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedhwp/93800/original</guid>
<dc:creator>Mueller, Andreas I.; Sahin, Aysegul; Faberman, R. Jason</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2022-02-01</dc:date>
<rdau:hasExtent>51</rdau:hasExtent>
<dc:subject>labor market slack; Covid pandemic; desired work hours; potential labor supply</dc:subject>
<swpo:hasNumber>WP 2022-08</swpo:hasNumber>
<identifiers:doi>10.21033/wp-2022-08</identifiers:doi>
<bibo:series>Working Paper Series</bibo:series>
</item>
<item>
<title>New Evidence on Redlining by Federal Housing Programs in the 1930s</title>
<link>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedhwp/93620/original</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[We show that the Federal Housing Administration (FHA), from its inception in the 1930s, did not insure mortgages in low income urban neighborhoods where the vast majority of urban Black Americans lived. The agency evaluated neighborhoods using block-level information collected by New Deal relief programs and the Census in many cities. The FHA's exclusionary pattern predates the advent of the infamous maps later made by the Home Owners' Loan Corporation (HOLC) and shows little change after the drafting of those maps. In contrast, the HOLC itself broadly loaned to such neighborhoods and to Black homeowners. We conclude that the HOLC's redlining maps had little effect on the geographic distribution of either program's mortgage market activity, and that the FHA crafted and implemented its own redlining methodology prior to the HOLC.]]>
</description>
<guid>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedhwp/93620/original</guid>
<dc:creator>Fishback, Price; Rose, Jonathan D.; Storrs, Thomas; Snowden, Kenneth A.</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2022-01-03</dc:date>
<rdau:hasExtent>42</rdau:hasExtent>
<dc:subject>Redlining; mortgage history</dc:subject>
<identifiers:doi>10.21033/wp-2022-01</identifiers:doi>
<bibo:series>Working Paper Series</bibo:series>
</item>
<item>
<title>Heterogeneous Impacts of Sentencing Decisions</title>
<link>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedhwp/93619/original</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[We examine 70,581 felony court cases filed in Chicago, IL during the period 1990-2007. We exploit case randomization to assess the impact of judge assignment and sentencing decisions on the arrival rates of new charges. Relative to prior research, we document an important source of heterogeneity in the impact of incarceration on recidivism. Incarceration creates lasting reductions in recidivism among first offenders but not repeat offenders. We present suggestive evidence that these reductions among first offenders primarily reflect outcomes for offenders who live in lower-crime areas of the city and are not involved in the drug trade. During our sample period, Illinois parole officers were able to issue arrest warrants for former inmates under their supervision. These powers place former inmates at significant risk of returning to prison as punishment for violations of technical conditions of their supervision. However, we find no evidence that these police powers increased the arrival rate of new charges against formerly incarcerated offenders. Incarceration does not reduce the arrival of new criminal charges among repeat offenders, and this outcome is not the result of parole officers over-policing repeat offenders.]]>
</description>
<guid>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedhwp/93619/original</guid>
<dc:creator>Jordan, Andrew; Neal, Derek; Karger, Ezra</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2021-10-26</dc:date>
<rdau:hasExtent>62</rdau:hasExtent>
<swpo:hasNumber>WP 2022-02</swpo:hasNumber>
<identifiers:doi>10.21033/wp-2022-02</identifiers:doi>
<bibo:series>Working Paper Series</bibo:series>
</item>
<item>
<title>A Fair Day's Pay for a Fair Day's Work: Optimal Tax Design as Redistributional Arbitrage</title>
<link>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedhwp/93617/original</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[We study optimal tax design based on the idea that policy-makers face trade-offs between
multiple margins of redistribution. Within a Mirrleesian economy with earnings, consumption
and retirement savings, we derive a novel formula for optimal income and savings distortions
based on redistributional arbitrage. We establish a sufficient statistics representation of the
labor income and capital tax rates on top income earners in dynamic environments, which relies
on the observed distributions of both income and consumption. Because consumption has a
thinner Pareto tail than income, our quantitative results suggest that it is optimal to shift a
substantial fraction of the top earners' tax burden from income to savings.]]>
</description>
<guid>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedhwp/93617/original</guid>
<dc:creator>Hellwig, Christian; Werquin, Nicolas</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2022-01-06</dc:date>
<rdau:hasExtent>58</rdau:hasExtent>
<dc:subject>Capital Taxation; Income Taxation; Consumption Inequality</dc:subject>
<swpo:hasNumber>WP 2022-03</swpo:hasNumber>
<identifiers:doi>10.21033/wp-2022-03</identifiers:doi>
<bibo:series>Working Paper Series</bibo:series>
</item>
<item>
<title>A CCP Is a CCP Is a CCP</title>
<link>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedhpd/93561</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[Central counterparties (CCPs) are an important part of contemporary financial market infrastructure. The orderly risk management operations and financial resilience of CCPs and other market infrastructures are essential for financial stability.
Regulators and other policymakers face a major challenge constructing appropriate regulatory 
frameworks for central clearing, given unique features of CCP risk profiles and, in particular, the 
mutualization of default losses. While CCPs may have superficial similarities to other infrastructures and exposed to risks like those borne by banks and other participants in the financial system, CCPs are best seen as “commitment mechanisms” that assure the performance of financial contract obligations. How they perform that function sets them apart from other infrastructures, intermediaries and financial institutions.
The challenge of establishing standards for CCP risk management and resilience is even more difficult 
when policymakers view CCPs through the lens of bank regulation. CCPs are not banks. Their function 
as commitment mechanisms bears little resemblance to the risk-taking function of banks. Nor are CCPs depositories, payment systems, insurance companies or exchanges, although they have features that resemble insurance and may have connections to other market infrastructures
This paper discusses many differences between CCPs and banks and the significance of those differences, including their business models and risk profiles, with CCPs acting as risk managers that are uniquely subject to the credit and liquidity risk of clearing member default. In particular, we focus on differences in the roles that capital and collateral play in connection with CCP and bank risk management. From this discussion, we draw the following policy conclusions: (1) a CCP’s capital cannot be the primary (or a significant) resource for loss absorption without fundamentally altering the incentive structure embedded in the default “waterfall” through which losses are mutualized, if not the business model of the CCP itself; (2) accordingly, capital analysis alone tells us little or nothing about CCP resilience or ability to recover from threats to the viability of the CCP; and (3) stress testing for CCPs must focus on features that are unique to central clearing, principally the possibility and consequences of member default.]]>
</description>
<guid>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedhpd/93561</guid>
<dc:creator>Cox, Robert; Steigerwald, Robert</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2017-04-01</dc:date>
<rdau:hasExtent>21</rdau:hasExtent>
<dc:subject>Central Counterparties; Risk Management; Credit; Liquidity</dc:subject>
<bibo:series>Policy Discussion Paper Series</bibo:series>
</item>
<item>
<title>Non-Default Loss Allocation at CCPs</title>
<link>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedhpd/93560</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[In this paper, we answer three questions about the appropriate allocation of non-default losses at central counterparties (CCPs): 1) “Who should assume financial responsibility for a non-default loss?”, 2) “What portion of a non-default loss should each party pay?”, and 3) “How should CCPs and clearing members address catastrophic non-default losses?”. To answer the first question, we argue that financial responsibility should be shared among the parties whose decisions contributed to the loss. Determining whose decisions contributed to a loss requires an understanding of the type of loss involved. To answer the second question, we argue that the CCP and clearing members should establish a loss-sharing formula that takes into account the CCP’s ownership structure and the particular needs of the CCP and its clearing members. The third question concerns what we term catastrophic losses – losses so large that those responsible for absorbing them cannot do so. We argue that to address catastrophic losses, the CCP and clearing members should consider not the cause of the loss, but whether the value of continuing the CCP’s operations justifies covering it.]]>
</description>
<guid>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedhpd/93560</guid>
<dc:creator>Lewis, Rebecca; McPartland, John</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2017-04-01</dc:date>
<rdau:hasExtent>15</rdau:hasExtent>
<dc:subject>Central Counterparties; Non-Default Loss; Loss Allocation</dc:subject>
<bibo:series>Policy Discussion Paper Series</bibo:series>
</item>
<item>
<title>Blockchain and Financial Market Innovation</title>
<link>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedhpd/93559</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[Blockchain technology is likely to be a key source of future financial market innovation. It allows the 
creation of immutable records of transactions accessible by all participants in a network. A blockchain
database is made up of a number of blocks “chained” together through a reference in each block to the 
previous block. Each block records one or more transactions, which are essentially changes in the listed owner of assets. New blocks are added to the existing chain through a consensus mechanism in which members of the blockchain network confirm transactions as valid.
While all are in the early stages of development, there are many promising applications of blockchain 
technology in financial markets. This paper seeks to give the reader an overview of what the technology is, how it works, and some potential applications for and challenges posed by blockchain technology.]]>
</description>
<guid>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedhpd/93559</guid>
<dc:creator>Ranjan, Rajeev; Lewis, Rebecca; McPartland, John</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2017-06-01</dc:date>
<rdau:hasExtent>18</rdau:hasExtent>
<dc:subject>Blockchain; Cryptocurrency; Financial Market</dc:subject>
<bibo:series>Policy Discussion Paper Series</bibo:series>
</item>
<item>
<title>Small-Dollar Mortgages for Single-Family Residential Properties</title>
<link>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedhpd/93558</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[There is a significant lack of financing available for low-cost homes, which many first-time homebuyers and low- and middle-income families rely on to move from renting to homeownership. This brief examines the availability of small-dollar mortgages (up to $70,000) for home purchases, refinances, and improvements, presenting a wealth of information on borrower and loan characteristics, production channels, and the geographic distribution of low-cost homes. We find that there is limited mortgage availability for the small loans needed to support the significant number of low-cost property sales and determine that low-cost properties could be a larger source of affordable housing if credit access for purchasing and rehabilitating these properties was expanded and improved.]]>
</description>
<guid>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedhpd/93558</guid>
<dc:creator>Strochak, Sarah; McCargo, Alanna; Bai, Bing; George, Taz</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2018-04-01</dc:date>
<rdau:hasExtent>40</rdau:hasExtent>
<dc:subject>Homebuyers; Homeownership; Low Income; Middle Income; Mortgages</dc:subject>
<bibo:series>Policy Discussion Paper Series</bibo:series>
</item>
<item>
<title>Measuring Detroit's Economic Progress with the DEAI</title>
<link>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedhle/93529</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[This article explains what the Detroit Economic Activity Index (DEAI) tells us about Detroit’s 
economic progress as of late 2019. Although the rate of progress had slowed some since 2016, 
the city continued to make headway last year in its recovery from bankruptcy.]]>
</description>
<guid>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedhle/93529</guid>
<dc:creator>Cole, Ross; Brave, Scott A.; Traub, Paul</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2020-03-01</dc:date>
<rdau:hasExtent>6</rdau:hasExtent>
<dc:subject>Detroit Economic Activity Index; Private Investment; Employment; Unemployment; Bankruptcy</dc:subject>
<bibo:issue>434</bibo:issue>
<bibo:series>Chicago Fed Letter</bibo:series>
</item>
<item>
<title>How Central Bank Swap Lines Affect the Leveraged Loan Market</title>
<link>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedhle/93528</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[The cost of borrowing U.S. dollars through foreign exchange (FX) swap markets increased 
significantly at the beginning of the Covid-19 pandemic in February 2020, indicated by 
larger deviations from covered interest rate parity (CIP). CIP deviations narrowed again when 
the Federal Reserve expanded its swap lines to support U.S. dollar liquidity globally—
by enhancing and extending its swap facility with foreign central banks and introducing the 
new temporary Foreign and International Monetary Authorities (FIMA) repurchase agreement 
facility for foreign and international monetary authorities. Recent research by Meisenzahl, 
Niepmann, and Schmidt-Eisenlohr (2020) shows how wider CIP deviations result in higher 
borrowing costs for U.S. corporations in the leveraged loan market. In this article, we discuss 
this finding, which suggests that, besides other channels, the Federal Reserve’s initiatives 
to provide global U.S. dollar liquidity contributed to easier financial conditions for U.S. 
corporate borrowers.]]>
</description>
<guid>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedhle/93528</guid>
<dc:creator>Meisenzahl, Ralf R.; Niepmann, Friederike; Schmidt-Eisenlohr, Tim; McCrone, Annie</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2020-09-01</dc:date>
<rdau:hasExtent>7</rdau:hasExtent>
<dc:subject>CIP Deviations; U.S. Dollar; Cross-Currency; Mutual Fund; Collateralized Loan Obligations; Foreign Currency</dc:subject>
<bibo:issue>446</bibo:issue>
<bibo:series>Chicago Fed Letter</bibo:series>
</item>
<item>
<title>What's the Potential Impact of Force Majeure Claims on Financial Stability</title>
<link>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedhle/93486</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[This article examines the potential aggregate impact on financial stability of several bilateral force majeure claims filed at approximately the same time in one or more markets. One and a half years after the pandemic started, I take stock of the developments involving force majeure claims thus far, and conclude that the likelihood of these claims creating a systemic threat to financial stability is low.]]>
</description>
<guid>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedhle/93486</guid>
<dc:creator>Cocco, Alessandro</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2021-09-01</dc:date>
<rdau:hasExtent>7</rdau:hasExtent>
<dc:subject>Force Majeure; Mortgage-Backed Securities; Derivative Contracts; Covid-19</dc:subject>
<bibo:issue>459</bibo:issue>
<bibo:series>Chicago Fed Letter</bibo:series>
</item>
<item>
<title>Perceived Competition in Agricultural Lending: Stylized Facts and an Agenda for Future Research</title>
<link>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedhwp/93419/original</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[This study examines agricultural lending by commercial banks and the competition they face from the Farm Credit System and non-traditional lenders, including merchants, dealers, and other input suppliers. We construct a measure of commercial banks’ perceived competition with FCS or non-traditional lenders using the individual responses to the Federal Reserve Bank of Chicago's Land Values and Credit Conditions Survey between 1999 and 2019. Our analysis shows that the two sources of competition have very different effects on commercial bank lending terms, loan portfolio riskiness, and expected loan volumes. With these results in mind, we offer a number of suggestions for future research.]]>
</description>
<guid>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedhwp/93419/original</guid>
<dc:creator>Oppedahl, David B.; Kuethe, Todd; Fiechter, Chad</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2021-10-01</dc:date>
<rdau:hasExtent>25</rdau:hasExtent>
<dc:subject>competition; agricultural lending; non-traditional lenders</dc:subject>
<swpo:hasNumber>WP-2021-16</swpo:hasNumber>
<identifiers:doi>10.21033/wp-2021-16</identifiers:doi>
<bibo:series>Working Paper Series</bibo:series>
</item>
<item>
<title>Bank Exposure to Commercial Real Estate and the Covid-19 Pandemic</title>
<link>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedhle/93408</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[The Covid-19 pandemic had an immediate and substantial impact on the commercial real estate (CRE) market—emptying workplaces, shopping centers, and hotels, thus affecting the cash flows of businesses occupying commercial space and in turn the ability of commercial space owners to meet their debt obligations.

Delinquent CRE loans began to surface soon after the pandemic started and remain elevated in 2021. Broad loan delinquencies would represent a potential threat to bank capitalization and solvency, particularly for smaller banks that tend to have higher concentrations in CRE lending. Collateral and loan performance have varied significantly by property type during the pandemic. However, regulators do not collect information on CRE exposures by property type at smaller banks, which limits our insight into the systemic implications of CRE exposures at these firms.]]>
</description>
<guid>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedhle/93408</guid>
<dc:creator>Drexler, Alejandro; Greenwald, Emily; Schulhofer-Wohl, Sam; Binder, Kyle</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2021-11-01</dc:date>
<rdau:hasExtent>7</rdau:hasExtent>
<dc:subject>Financial Economics</dc:subject>
<bibo:issue>463</bibo:issue>
<bibo:series>Chicago Fed Letter</bibo:series>
</item>
<item>
<title>Managing Climate Risk in Mortgage Markets: A Role for Derivatives</title>
<link>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedhle/93407</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[The world’s communities and economies are already feeling significant effects from global warming and related climate and extreme weather events, as the latest United Nations Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change (IPCC) world climate report published in August 2021 makes clear. In some industry sectors, such as insurance and energy, financial market tools have been developed specifically to mitigate the risk of financial loss related to climate. Such tools have yet to be developed for the U.S. mortgage market—one of the world’s largest at roughly $11 trillion as of the end of 2020.]]>
</description>
<guid>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedhle/93407</guid>
<dc:creator>Patel, Ketan B.</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2021-10-01</dc:date>
<rdau:hasExtent>6</rdau:hasExtent>
<dc:subject>Financial Economics</dc:subject>
<bibo:issue>462</bibo:issue>
<bibo:series>Chicago Fed Letter</bibo:series>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>