<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<rdf:RDF
 xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
 xmlns="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/"
 xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
 xmlns:taxo="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/taxonomy/"
 xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
 xmlns:syn="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
 xmlns:admin="http://webns.net/mvcb/"
>

<channel rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/">
<title>cond-mat.mes-hall updates on arXiv.org</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">Condensed Matter -- Mesoscale and Nanoscale Physics (cond-mat.mes-hall) updates on the arXiv.org e-print archive</description>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:date>2022-11-03T20:30:00-05:00</dc:date>
<dc:publisher>help@arxiv.org</dc:publisher>
<dc:subject>Condensed Matter -- Mesoscale and Nanoscale Physics</dc:subject>
<syn:updateBase>1901-01-01T00:00+00:00</syn:updateBase>
<syn:updateFrequency>1</syn:updateFrequency>
<syn:updatePeriod>daily</syn:updatePeriod>
<items>
 <rdf:Seq>
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01490" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01501" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01617" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01685" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01707" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01714" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01735" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01876" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01895" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01898" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.02026" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.02033" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2110.08304" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2204.13945" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2205.14993" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2206.09922" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2206.13427" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2207.00889" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2208.07454" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2209.10769" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2209.15155" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2209.15187" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.01259" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.05053" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.16762" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.00560" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.00679" />
 </rdf:Seq>
</items>
<image rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif" />
</channel>
<image rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif">
<title>arXiv.org</title>
<url>http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif</url>
<link>http://arxiv.org/</link>
</image>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01490">
<title>Deep Learning Hamiltonians from Disordered Image Data in Quantum Materials. (arXiv:2211.01490v1 [cond-mat.str-el])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01490</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The capabilities of image probe experiments are rapidly expanding, providing
new information about quantum materials on unprecedented length and time
scales. Many such materials feature inhomogeneous electronic properties with
intricate pattern formation on the observable surface. This rich spatial
structure contains information about interactions, dimensionality, and disorder
-- a spatial encoding of the Hamiltonian driving the pattern formation. Image
recognition techniques from machine learning are an excellent tool for
interpreting information encoded in the spatial relationships in such images.
Here, we develop a deep learning framework for using the rich information
available in these spatial correlations in order to discover the underlying
Hamiltonian driving the patterns. We first vet the method on a known case,
scanning near-field optical microscopy on a thin film of VO2. We then apply our
trained convolutional neural network architecture to new optical microscope
images of a different VO2 film as it goes through the metal-insulator
transition. We find that a two-dimensional Hamiltonian with both interactions
and random field disorder is required to explain the intricate, fractal
intertwining of metal and insulator domains during the transition. This
detailed knowledge about the underlying Hamiltonian paves the way to using the
model to control the pattern formation via, e.g., tailored hysteresis
protocols. We also introduce a distribution-based confidence measure on the
results of a multi-label classifier, which does not rely on adversarial
training. In addition, we propose a new machine learning based criterion for
diagnosing a physical system&apos;s proximity to criticality.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Basak_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;S. Basak&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Banguero_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;M. Alzate Banguero&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Burzawa_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;L. Burzawa&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Simmons_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;F. Simmons&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Salev_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;P. Salev&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Aigouy_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;L. Aigouy&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Qazilbash_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;M. M. Qazilbash&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Schuller_I/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;I. K. Schuller&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Basov_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;D. N. Basov&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Zimmers_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;A. Zimmers&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Carlson_E/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;E. W. Carlson&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01501">
<title>A light-induced Weyl semiconductor-to-metal transition mediated by Peierls instability. (arXiv:2211.01501v1 [cond-mat.str-el])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01501</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Elemental tellurium is a strongly spin-orbit coupled Peierls-distorted
semiconductor whose band structure features topologically protected Weyl nodes.
Using time-dependent density functional theory calculations, we show that
impulsive optical excitation can be used to transiently control the amplitude
of the Peierls distortion, realizing a mechanism to switch tellurium between
three states: Weyl semiconductor, Weyl metal and non-Weyl metal. Further, we
present experimental evidence of this inverse-Peierls distortion using
time-resolved optical second harmonic generation measurements. These results
provide a pathway to multifunctional ultrafast Weyl devices and introduce
Peierls systems as viable hosts of light-induced topological transitions.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Ning_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;H. Ning&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Mehio_O/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;O. Mehio&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Lian_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;C. Lian&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Li_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;X. Li&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Zoghlin_E/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;E. Zoghlin&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Zhou_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;P. Zhou&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Cheng_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;B. Cheng&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Wilson_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;S. D. Wilson&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Wong_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;B. M. Wong&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Hsieh_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;D. Hsieh&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01617">
<title>Nano-beam clamping revisited. (arXiv:2211.01617v1 [cond-mat.mes-hall])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01617</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Within recent years, the field of nano-mechanics has diversified in a variety
of applications, ranging from quantum information processing to biological
molecules recognition. Among the diversity of devices produced these days, the
simplest (but versatile) element remains the doubly-clamped beam: it can store
very large tensile stresses (producing high resonance frequencies $f_0$ and
quality factors $Q$), is interfaceable with electric setups (by means of
conductive layers), and can be produced easily in clean rooms (with scalable
designs including multiplexing). Besides, its mechanical properties are the
simplest to describe. Resonance frequencies and $Q$s are being modeled, with as
specific achievement the ultra-high quality resonances based on ``soft
clamping&apos;&apos; and ``phonon shields&apos;&apos;. Here, we demonstrate that the fabrication
undercut of the clamping regions of basic nano-beams produces a ``natural soft
clamping&apos;&apos;, given for free. We present the analytic theory that enables to fit
experimental data, which can be used for $\{ Q , f_0 \}$ design.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Golokolenov_I/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ilya Golokolenov&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Kumar_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Sumit Kumar&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Alperin_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Baptiste Alperin&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Fernandez_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Bruno Fernandez&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Fefferman_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Andrew Fefferman&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Collin_E/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Eddy Collin&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01685">
<title>Generalized topological bulk-edge correspondence in continuous systems with non-Hermitian boundary conditions. (arXiv:2211.01685v1 [cond-mat.mes-hall])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01685</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The bulk-edge correspondence (BEC) is the hallmark of topological systems. In
continuous (non-lattice) Hermitian systems with unbounded wavevector it was
recently shown that the BEC is modified. How would it be further affected in
non-Hermitian systems, experiencing loss and/or gain? In this work we take the
first step in this direction, by studying a Hermitian continuous system with
non-Hermitian boundary conditions. We find in this case that edge modes emerge
at roots of the scattering matrix, as opposed to the Hermitian case, where they
emerge at poles (or, more accurately, coalescence of roots and poles). This
entails a nontrivial modification to the relative Levinson&apos;s theorem. We then
show that the topological structure remains the same as in the Hermitian case,
and the generalized BEC holds, provided one employs appropriate modified
contours in the wavevector plane, so that the scattering matrix phase winding
counts the edge modes correctly. We exemplify all this using a paradigmatic
model of waves in a shallow ocean or active systems in the presence of odd
viscosity, as well as 2D electron gas with Hall viscosity. We use this
opportunity to examine the case of large odd viscosity, where the scattering
matrix becomes $2\times2$, which has not been discussed in previous works on
the Hermitian generalized BEC.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Rapoport_O/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Orr Rapoport&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Goldstein_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Moshe Goldstein&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01707">
<title>Electrostatic effects of the MnBi2Te4-superconductor hetero-structures in chiral Majorana search. (arXiv:2211.01707v1 [cond-mat.supr-con])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01707</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The realization of chiral Majorana modes is a challenging task. We aim to
comprehend the phase diagrams and parameter control capabilities of the actual
devices used in the chiral Majorana search. Beyond the well-known minimal
models, we develop a numerical simulation scheme using a self-consistent
Schrodinger-Poisson approach to study, as an example, the MnBi2Te4 thin film
coupled to an s-wave superconductor. We show that both the superconducting
proximity effect and the tunability of the chemical potential for the
topological surface states are significantly influenced by the gate-induced
electrostatic potential. This complicates the implementation in experiments,
and the actual topological region will be narrowed in stark contrast to those
predicted in the previous minimal models. Nevertheless, we demonstrate that the
chiral Majorana mode still exists in a wide range of experimental parameters
with practical tunability.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Chen_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Li Chen&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Cao_Z/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Zhan Cao&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+He_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ke He&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Liu_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xin Liu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Liu_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Dong E. Liu&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01714">
<title>Skyrmion Jellyfish in Driven Chiral Magnets. (arXiv:2211.01714v1 [cond-mat.mes-hall])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01714</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Chiral magnets can host topological particles known as skyrmions which carry
an exactly quantised topological charge $Q=-1$. In the presence of an
oscillating magnetic field ${\bf B}_1(t)$, a single skyrmion embedded in a
ferromagnetic background will start to move with constant velocity ${\bf
v}_{\text{trans}}$. The mechanism behind this motion is similar to the one used
by a jellyfish when it swims through water. We show that the skyrmion&apos;s motion
is a universal phenomenon, arising in any magnetic system with translational
modes. By projecting the equation of motion onto the skyrmion&apos;s translational
modes and going to quadratic order in ${\bf B}_1(t)$ we obtain an analytical
expression for ${\bf v}_{\text{trans}}$ as a function of the system&apos;s linear
response. The linear response and consequently ${\bf v}_{\text{trans}}$ are
influenced by the skyrmion&apos;s internal modes and scattering states, as well as
by the ferromagnetic background&apos;s Kittel mode. The direction and speed of ${\bf
v}_{\text{trans}}$ can be controlled by changing the polarisation, frequency
and phase of the driving field ${\bf B}_1(t)$. For systems with small Gilbert
damping parameter $\alpha$, we identify two distinct physical mechanisms used
by the skyrmion to move. At low driving frequencies, the skyrmion&apos;s motion is
driven by friction, and $v_{\text{trans}}\sim\alpha$, whereas at higher
frequencies above the ferromagnetic gap the skyrmion moves by magnon emission
and $v_{\text{trans}}$ becomes independent of $\alpha$.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Ser_N/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Nina del Ser&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Lohani_V/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Vivek Lohani&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01735">
<title>Electronic Coherent Control of an Insulator-to-Metal Mott Transition. (arXiv:2211.01735v1 [cond-mat.str-el])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01735</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Managing light-matter interaction on timescales faster than the loss of
electronic coherence is key for achieving the full quantum control of final
products in solid-solid transformations. In this work, we demonstrate coherent
electronic control of the photoinduced insulator-to-metal transition in the
prototypical Mott insulator V$_2$O$_3$. Selective excitation of a specific
interband transition with two phase-locked light pulses manipulates the orbital
occupation of the correlated bands in a way that depends on the coherent
evolution of the photoinduced superposition of states. Comparison between
experimental results and numerical solutions of the optical Bloch equations
provides an electronic coherence time on the order of 5 fs. Temperature
dependent experiments suggest that the electronic coherence time is enhanced in
the vicinity of the insulator-to-metal transition critical temperature, thus
highlighting the role of fluctuations in determining the electronic coherence.
These results open new routes to selectively switch functionalities of quantum
materials and coherently control solid-solid electronic transformations.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Franceschini_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Paolo Franceschini&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Policht_V/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Veronica R.Policht&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Milloch_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Alessandra Milloch&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Ronchi_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Andrea Ronchi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Mor_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Selene Mor&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Mellaerts_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Simon Mellaerts&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Hsu_W/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Wei-Fan Hsu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Pagliara_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Stefania Pagliara&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Ferrini_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Gabriele Ferrini&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Banfi_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Francesco Banfi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Fabrizio_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Michele Fabrizio&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Menghini_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Mariela Menghini&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Locquet_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jean-Pierre Locquet&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Conte_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Stefano Dal Conte&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Cerullo_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Giulio Cerullo&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Giannetti_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Claudio Giannetti&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01876">
<title>Artificial kagome spin ice magnetic phase recognition from the initial magnetization curve. (arXiv:2211.01876v1 [cond-mat.mes-hall])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01876</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Artificial spin ices (ASIs) are designable arrays of interacting nanomagnets
that span a wide range of magnetic phases associated with a number of spin
lattice models. Here, we demonstrate that the phase of an artificial kagome
spin ice can be determined from its initial magnetization curve. As a proof of
concept, micromagnetic simulations of these curves were performed starting from
representative microstates of different phases of the system. We show that the
curves are characterized by phase-specific features in such a way that a
pattern recognition algorithm predicts the phase of the initial microstate with
good reliability. This achievement represents a new strategy to identify phases
in ASIs, easier and more accessible than magnetic imaging techniques normally
used for this task.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Cecchi_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Breno Cecchi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Cruz_N/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Nathan Cruz&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Knobel_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Marcelo Knobel&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Pirota_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Kleber Roberto Pirota&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01895">
<title>Quantum kinetic theory of nonlinear thermal current. (arXiv:2211.01895v1 [cond-mat.mes-hall])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01895</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We investigate the second-order nonlinear electronic thermal transport
induced by temperature gradient. We develop the quantum kinetic theory
framework to describe thermal transport in presence of a temperature gradient.
Using this, we predict an intrinsic scattering time independent nonlinear
thermal current in addition to the known extrinsic nonlinear Drude and Berry
curvature dipole contributions. We show that the intrinsic thermal current is
determined by the band geometric quantities and is non-zero only in systems
where both the space inversion and time-reversal symmetries are broken. We
employ the developed theory to study the thermal response in tilted massive
Dirac systems. We show that besides the different scattering time dependence,
the various current contributions have distinct temperature dependence in the
low temperature limit. Our systematic and comprehensive theory for nonlinear
thermal transport paves the way for future theoretical and experimental studies
on intrinsic thermal responses.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Varshney_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Harsh Varshney&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Das_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Kamal Das&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Bhalla_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Pankaj Bhalla&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Agarwal_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Amit Agarwal&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01898">
<title>Disentangling complex current pathways in a metallic Ru/Co bilayer nanostructure using THz spectroscopy. (arXiv:2211.01898v1 [cond-mat.mes-hall])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01898</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Many modern spintronic technologies, such as spin valves, spin Hall
applications, and spintronic THz emitters, are based on electrons crossing
buried internal interfaces within metallic nanostructures. However, the complex
current pathways within such nanostructures are difficult to disentangle using
conventional experimental methods. Here, we measure the conductivity of a
technologically relevant Ru/Co bilayer nanostructure in a contact-free fashion
using THz time-domain spectroscopy. By applying an effective resistor network
to the data, we resolve the complex current pathways within the nanostructure
and determine the degree of electronic transparency of the internal interface
between the Ru and Co nanolayers.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Beermann_N/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Nicolas S. Beermann&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Fabretti_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Savio Fabretti&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Rott_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Karsten Rott&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Hafez_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Hassan A. Hafez&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Reiss_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;G&amp;#xfc;nter Reiss&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Turchinovich_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Dmitry Turchinovich&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.02026">
<title>On the dielectric response function and phonon self energy of acoustic phonons in 2D Dirac crystals. (arXiv:2211.02026v1 [cond-mat.mes-hall])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.02026</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The unique structure of two-dimensional (2D) Dirac crystals, with electronic
bands linear in the proximity of the Brillouin-zone boundary and the Fermi
energy, creates anomalous situations where small Fermi-energy perturbations are
known to critically affect the electron-related lattice properties of the
system. The Fermi-surface nesting (FSN) conditions determining such effects via
electron-phonon interaction, require accurate estimates of the crystal&apos;s
response function $(\chi)$ as a function of the phonon wavevector q for any
values of temperature. Numerous analytical estimates of $\chi(q)$ for 2D Dirac
crystals beyond the Thomas-Fermi approximation have been so far carried out
only in terms of dielectric response function $\chi(q,\omega)$, for photon and
optical-phonon perturbations, due to relative ease of incorporating a
q-independent oscillation frequency in their calculation. However, models
accounting for Dirac-electron interaction with ever-existing acoustic phonons,
for which $\omega$ does depend on q and is therefore dispersive, are essential
to understand many critical crystal properties. The lack of such models has
often led to assume that the dielectric response function $\chi(q)$ in these
systems can be understood from free-electron behavior. Here, we show that,
different from free-electron systems, $\chi(q)$ calculated from acoustic
phonons in 2D Dirac crystals using the Lindhard model, exhibits a cuspidal
point at the FSN condition. Strong variability of $\frac{\partial\chi}{\partial
q}$ persists also at finite temperatures, while $\chi(q)$ may tend to infinity
in the dynamic case even where the speed of sound is small, albeit
nonnegligible, over the Dirac-electron Fermi velocity. The implications of our
findings for electron-acoustic phonon interaction and transport properties such
as the phonon line width derived from the phonon self energy will also be
discussed.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Kazemian_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Sina Kazemian&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Fanchini_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Giovanni Fanchini&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.02033">
<title>Optically Induced Picosecond Lattice Compression in the Dielectric Component of a Strongly Coupled Ferroelectric/Dielectric Superlattice. (arXiv:2211.02033v1 [cond-mat.mtrl-sci])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.02033</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Above-bandgap femtosecond optical excitation of a ferroelectric/dielectric
BaTiO3/CaTiO3 superlattice leads to structural responses that are a consequence
of the screening of the strong electrostatic coupling between the component
layers. Time-resolved x-ray free-electron laser diffraction shows that the
structural response to optical excitation includes a net lattice expansion of
the superlattice consistent with depolarization-field screening driven by the
photoexcited charge carriers. The depolarization-field-screening-driven
expansion is separate from a photoacoustic pulse launched from the bottom
electrode on which the superlattice was epitaxially grown. The distribution of
diffracted intensity of superlattice x-ray reflections indicates that the
depolarization-field-screening-induced strain includes a photoinduced expansion
in the ferroelectric BaTiO3 and a contraction in CaTiO3. The magnitude of
expansion in BaTiO3 layers is larger than the contraction in CaTiO3. The
difference in the magnitude of depolarization-field-screening-driven strain in
the BaTiO3 and CaTiO3 components can arise from the contribution of the oxygen
octahedral rotation patterns at the BaTiO3/CaTiO3 interfaces to the
polarization of CaTiO3. The depolarization-field-screening-driven polarization
reduction in the CaTiO3 layers points to a new direction for the manipulation
of polarization in the component layers of a strongly coupled
ferroelectric/dielectric superlattice.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Gyan_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Deepankar Sri Gyan&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Lee_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Hyeon Jun Lee&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Ahn_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Youngjun Ahn&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Carnis_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jerome Carnis&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Kim_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Tae Yeon Kim&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Unithrattil_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Sanjith Unithrattil&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Lee_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jun Young Lee&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Chun_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Sae Hwan Chun&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Kim_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Sunam Kim&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Eom_I/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Intae Eom&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Kim_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Minseok Kim&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Park_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Sang-Youn Park&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Kim_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Kyung Sook Kim&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Lee_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ho Nyung Lee&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Jo_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ji Young Jo&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Evans_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Paul G. Evans&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2110.08304">
<title>Nonlinear Landauer formula: Nonlinear response theory of disordered and topological materials. (arXiv:2110.08304v2 [cond-mat.mes-hall] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2110.08304</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The Landauer formula provides a general scattering formulation of electrical
conduction. Despite its utility, it has been mainly applied to the
linear-response regime, and a scattering theory of nonlinear response has yet
to be fully developed. Here, we extend the Landauer formula to the
nonlinear-response regime. We show that while the linear conductance is
directly related to the transmission probability, the nonlinear conductance is
given by its derivatives with respect to energy. This sensitivity to the energy
derivatives is shown to produce unique nonlinear transport phenomena of
mesoscopic systems including disordered and topological materials. By way of
illustration, we investigate nonlinear conductance of disordered chains and
identify their universal behavior according to symmetry. In particular, we find
large singular nonlinear conductance for zero modes, including Majorana zero
modes in topological superconductors. We also show the critical behavior of
nonlinear response around the mobility edges due to the Anderson transitions.
Moreover, we study nonlinear response of graphene as a prime example of
topological materials featuring quantum anomaly. Furthermore, considering the
geometry of electronic wave functions, we develop a scattering theory of the
nonlinear Hall effect. We establish a new connection between the nonlinear Hall
response and the nonequilibrium quantum fluctuations. We also discuss the
influence of disorder and Anderson localization on the nonlinear Hall effect.
Our work opens a new avenue in quantum physics beyond the linear-response
regime.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Kawabata_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Kohei Kawabata&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Ueda_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Masahito Ueda&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2204.13945">
<title>Symmetry-protected exceptional and nodal points in non-Hermitian systems. (arXiv:2204.13945v2 [quant-ph] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2204.13945</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;One of the unique features of non-Hermitian~(NH) systems is the appearance of
non-Hermitian degeneracies known as exceptional points~(EPs). The extensively
studied defective EPs occur when the Hamiltonian becomes non-diagonalizable.
Aside from this degeneracy, we show that NH systems may host two further types
of degeneracies, namely, non-defective EPs and ordinary (Hermitian) nodal
points. The non-defective EPs manifest themselves by i) the diagonalizability
of the NH Hamiltonian at these points, ii) the non-diagonalizability of the
Hamiltonian along certain intersections of these points and iii) instabilities
in the Jordan decomposition when approaching the points from certain
directions. We demonstrate that certain discrete symmetries, namely
parity-time, parity-particle-hole, and pseudo-Hermitian symmetry, guarantee the
occurrence of both defective and non-defective EPs. We extend this list of
symmetries by including the NH time-reversal symmetry in two-band systems.
Two-band and four-band models exemplify our findings. Through an example, we
further reveal that ordinary nodal points may coexist with defective EPs in NH
models when the above symmetries are relaxed.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Sayyad_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Sharareh Sayyad&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Stalhammar_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Marcus Stalhammar&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Rodland_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Lukas Rodland&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Kunst_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Flore K. Kunst&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2205.14993">
<title>Josephson junctions of 2D time-reversal invariant superconductors: signatures of the topological phase. (arXiv:2205.14993v3 [cond-mat.supr-con] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2205.14993</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We determine the current-phase relation (CPR) of two-terminal configurations
of Josephson junctions containing two-dimensional (2D) time-reversal invariant
topological superconductors (TRITOPS), including TRITOPS-TRITOPS, as well as
junctions between topological and non-topological superconductors (TRITOPS-S).
We focus on long junctions for which several channels intervene in the
tunneling coupling through the junction. We present a description of the
topological edge modes for different TRITOPS models including $p$-wave pairing
and the combination of $s$-wave pairing with spin-orbit coupling. We derive
effective low-energy Hamiltonians to describe the Josephson junction, which can
be solved analytically to explain the contribution of the edge states to the
Josephson current as a function of the phase bias. We find that edge-modes
yield singular corrections to the CPR for both junction types. The primary
effects occur for the response of the Majorana zero-modes at half-flux quantum
phase $\phi\approx \pi$ in TRITOPS-TRITOPS junctions and for integer flux
quantum phase $\phi \approx 0$ for TRITOPS-S junctions, respectively. The
former effect is particularly strong two-component nematic superconductors. The
latter effect leads to a spontaneously broken time-reversal symmetry in the
TRITOPS-S junction and to a breakdown of the bulk-boundary correspondence.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Ruiz_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Gabriel F. Rodr&amp;#xed;guez Ruiz&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Rampp_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Michael A. Rampp&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Aligia_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;A. A. Aligia&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Schmalian_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Joerg Schmalian&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Arrachea_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Liliana Arrachea&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2206.09922">
<title>Enhanced superconductivity through virtual tunneling in Bernal bilayer graphene coupled to WSe$_2$. (arXiv:2206.09922v3 [cond-mat.supr-con] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2206.09922</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Motivated by a recent experiment [&lt;a href=&quot;/abs/2205.05087&quot;&gt;arXiv:2205.05087&lt;/a&gt;], we investigate a
possible mechanism that enhances superconductivity in hole-doped Bernal bilayer
graphene due to a proximate WSe$_2$ monolayer. We show that the virtual
tunneling between WSe$_2$ and Bernal bilayer graphene, which is known to induce
Ising spin-orbit coupling, can generate an additional attraction between two
holes, providing a potential explanation for enhancing superconductivity in
Bernal bilayer graphene. Using microscopic interlayer tunneling, we derive the
Ising spin-orbit coupling and the effective attraction as functions of the
twist angle between Bernal bilayer graphene and the WSe$_2$ monolayer. Our
theory provides an intuitive and physical explanation for the intertwined
relation between Ising spin-orbit coupling and superconductivity enhancement,
which should motivate future studies.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Chou_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yang-Zhi Chou&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Wu_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Fengcheng Wu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Sarma_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Sankar Das Sarma&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2206.13427">
<title>Single exciton trapping in an electrostatically defined 2D semiconductor quantum dot. (arXiv:2206.13427v2 [cond-mat.mes-hall] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2206.13427</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Interlayer excitons (IXs) in 2D semiconductors have long lifetimes and
spin-valley coupled physics, with a long-standing goal of single exciton
trapping for valleytronic applications. In this work, we use a nano-patterned
graphene gate to create an electrostatic IX trap. We measure a unique
power-dependent blue-shift of IX energy, where narrow linewidth emission
exhibits discrete energy jumps. We attribute these jumps to quantized increases
of the number occupancy of IXs within the trap and compare to a theoretical
model to assign the lowest energy emission line to single IX recombination.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Shanks_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Daniel N. Shanks&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Mahdikhanysarvejahany_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Fateme Mahdikhanysarvejahany&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Koehler_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Michael R. Koehler&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Mandrus_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;David G. Mandrus&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Taniguchi_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Takashi Taniguchi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Watanabe_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Kenji Watanabe&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+LeRoy_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Brian J. LeRoy&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Schaibley_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;John R. Schaibley&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2207.00889">
<title>Lattice Fermionic Casimir effect in a Slab Bag and Universality. (arXiv:2207.00889v4 [hep-lat] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2207.00889</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We apply the physically more appealing MIT Bag boundary conditions to study
the Casimir effect on the lattice. Employing the formalism of &lt;a href=&quot;/abs/2005.10758&quot;&gt;arXiv:2005.10758&lt;/a&gt;
to calculate the Casimir energy for free lattice fermions, we show that the
results for the naive, Wilson and overlap fermions match the continuum
expressions precisely in the zero lattice spacing limit, as expected from
universality. In contrast to &lt;a href=&quot;/abs/2005.10758&quot;&gt;arXiv:2005.10758&lt;/a&gt; where the result for the naive
fermions rapidly oscillates with the lattice size for both, the periodic (P)
and anti-periodic (AP) boundary conditions, no oscillations are observed with
the lattice size. Furthermore, the apparent violation of the universality for
naive fermion in &lt;a href=&quot;/abs/2005.10758&quot;&gt;arXiv:2005.10758&lt;/a&gt; is shown to be cured by applying suitable
series extrapolation techniques, thus demonstrating that the Casimir energy for
the naive fermions with periodic/antiperiodic boundary conditions agrees with
the results for other free lattice fermions, and can as well be used to obtain
the results for the Dirac fermion in the zero limit of the lattice spacing.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-lat/1/au:+Mandlecha_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yash V. Mandlecha&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-lat/1/au:+Gavai_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Rajiv V. Gavai&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2208.07454">
<title>High frequency torsional motion transduction using optomechanical coupled oscillators. (arXiv:2208.07454v2 [physics.optics] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2208.07454</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Using light to measure an object&apos;s motion is central to operating mechanical
sensors that probe forces and fields. Cavity optomechanical systems embed
mechanical resonators inside optical resonators. This enhances the sensitivity
of optomechanical measurements, but only if the mechanical resonator does not
spoil the properties of the optical cavity. For example, cavity optomechanical
detection of resonators made from optically absorbing materials, or whose
geometry does not possess suitable spatial symmetry, is challenging. Here we
demonstrate a system that overcomes challenges in measuring high-frequency
twisting motion of a nanodisk by converting them to vibrations of a photonic
crystal cavity. Optomechanical readout of the cavity then enables measurement
of the nanodisk&apos;s torsional resonances with sensitivity $5.1\times
10^{-21}-1.2\times 10^{-19}\,\text{Nm}/\sqrt{\text{Hz}}$ for a mechanical
frequency range of 5--800 MHz. The nanodisk can be outfitted with magnetic
nanostructures or metasurfaces without affecting the optical properties of the
cavity, making the system suitable for torque magnetometry and structured light
sensing.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Kaviani_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Hamidreza Kaviani&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Behera_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Bishnupada Behera&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Hajisalem_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ghazal Hajisalem&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Luiz_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Gustavo de Oliveira Luiz&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Lake_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;David P. Lake&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Barclay_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Paul E. Barclay&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2209.10769">
<title>Ferroelectricity-driven phonon Berry curvature and non-linear phonon Hall transports. (arXiv:2209.10769v2 [cond-mat.mes-hall] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2209.10769</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Berry curvature (BC) governs topological phases of matter and generates
anomalous transport. When a magnetic field is applied, phonons can acquire BC
indirectly through spin-lattice coupling, leading to a linear phonon Hall
effect. Here, we show that polar lattice distortion directly couples to a
phonon BC dipole, which causes a switchable non-linear phonon Hall effect. In a
SnS monolayer, the in-plane ferroelectricity induces a phonon BC and leads to
the phononic version of the non-volatile BC memory effect. As a new type of
ferroelectricity-phonon coupling, the phonon Rashba effect emerges and opens a
mass-gap in tilted Weyl phonon modes, resulting in a large phonon BC dipole.
Furthermore, our ab initio non-equilibrium molecular dynamics simulations
reveal that non-linear phonon Hall transport occurs in a controllable manner
via ferroelectric switching. The ferroelectricity-driven phonon BC and
corresponding non-linear phonon transports provide a novel scheme for
constructing topological phononic transport/memory devices.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Im_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jino Im&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Kim_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Choong H. Kim&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Jin_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Hosub Jin&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2209.15155">
<title>Negative refraction in hyperbolic hetero-bicrystals. (arXiv:2209.15155v2 [cond-mat.mes-hall] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2209.15155</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We visualized negative refraction of phonon-polaritons in hetero-bicrystals
of two hyperbolic van der Waals materials: molybdenum oxide ($MoO_3$) and
isotopically pure hexagonal boron nitride ($h^{11}BN$). The polaritons -
hybrids of infrared photons and lattice vibrations - form collimated rays that
display negative refraction when passing through a planar interface between the
$h^{11}BN$ and $MoO_3$ crystals. At a special frequency $\omega_0$, these rays
can circulate along closed diamond-shaped trajectories. We show that polariton
eigenmodes display regions of both positive and negative dispersion interrupted
by multiple gaps resulting from polaritonic level repulsion.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Sternbach_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;A. J. Sternbach&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Moore_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;S. Moore&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Rikhter_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;A. Rikhter&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Zhang_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;S. Zhang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Jing_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;R. Jing&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Shao_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Y. Shao&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Kim_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;B. Kim&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Xu_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;S. Xu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Rubio_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;A. Rubio&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Dean_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;C. Dean&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Hone_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;J. Hone&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Fogler_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;M. M. Fogler&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Basov_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;D. N. Basov&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2209.15187">
<title>Perspectives on Antiferromagnetic Spintronics. (arXiv:2209.15187v2 [cond-mat.mtrl-sci] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2209.15187</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Although the development of spintronic devices has advanced significantly
over the past decade with the use of ferromagnetic materials, the extensive
implementation of such devices has been limited by the notable drawbacks of
these materials. Antiferromagnets claim to resolve many of these shortcomings
leading to faster, smaller, more energy-efficient, and more robust electronics.
Antiferromagnets exhibit many desirable properties including zero net
magnetization, imperviousness to external magnetic fields, intrinsic
high-frequency dynamics with a characteristic precession frequency on the order
of terahertz (THz), and the ability to serve as passive exchange-bias materials
in multiple magnetoresistance (MR)- based devices. In this Perspective article,
we will discuss the fundamental physics of magnetic structures in
antiferromagnets and their interactions with external stimuli such as spin
current, voltage, and magnons. A discussion on the challenges lying ahead is
also provided along with an outlook of future research directions of these
systems.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Wang_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Kang Wang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Bheemarasetty_V/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Vineetha Bheemarasetty&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Duan_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Junhang Duan&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Zhou_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Shiyu Zhou&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Xiao_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Gang Xiao&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.01259">
<title>A perspective on microscopic pressure (stress) tensor: history, current understanding, and future challenges. (arXiv:2210.01259v2 [physics.chem-ph] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.01259</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The pressure tensor (equivalent to the negative stress tensor) at both
microscopic and macroscopic levels is fundamental to many aspects of
engineering and science, including fluid dynamics, solid mechanics, biophysics,
and thermodynamics. In this perspective paper, we review methods to calculate
the microscopic pressure tensor. Connections between different pressure forms
for equilibrium and non-equilibrium systems are established. We also point out
several challenges in the field, including the historical controversies over
the definition of the microscopic pressure tensor; the difficulties with
many-body and long-range potentials; the insufficiency of software and
computational tools; and the lack of experimental routes to probe the pressure
tensor at the nanoscale. Possible future directions are suggested.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Shi_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Kaihang Shi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Smith_E/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Edward Smith&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Santiso_E/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Erik E. Santiso&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Gubbins_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Keith E. Gubbins&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.05053">
<title>Strong coupling of a Gd$^{3+}$ multilevel spin system to an on-chip superconducting resonator. (arXiv:2210.05053v2 [quant-ph] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.05053</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We report the realization of a strong coupling between a Gd$^{3+}$ spin
ensemble hosted in a scheelite (CaWO$_4$) single crystal and the resonant mode
of a coplanar stripline superconducting cavity leading to a large separation of
spin-photon states of 146 MHz. The interaction is well described by the Dicke
model and the crystal-field Hamiltonian of the multilevel spin system. We
observe a change of the crystal-field parameters due to the presence of photons
in the cavity that generates a significant perturbation of the crystal ground
state. Using finite-element calculations, we numerically estimate the cavity
sensing volume as well as the average spin-photon coupling strength of
$g_0\approx$ 620 Hz. Lastly, the dynamics of the spin-cavity states are
explored via pulsed measurements by recording the cavity ring-down signal as a
function of pulse length and amplitude. The results indicate a potential method
to initialize this multilevel system in its ground state via an active cooling
process.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Franco_Rivera_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Giovanni Franco-Rivera&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Cochran_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Josiah Cochran&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Miyashita_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Seiji Miyashita&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Bertaina_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Sylvain Bertaina&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Chiorescu_I/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Irinel Chiorescu&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.16762">
<title>Spin hydrodynamic generation in unsteady flows. (arXiv:2210.16762v2 [physics.flu-dyn] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.16762</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We theoretically investigate a spin-mediated conversion from fluid dynamics
to voltage, known as spin hydrodynamic generation (SHDG), in oscillatory and
transient unsteady flows. We consider unsteady flows of liquid metal between
two parallel infinite planes and then calculate its vorticity fields based on
the Navier--Stokes equation for an incompressible viscous fluid. The spin
accumulation and spin current generated by unsteady flows are derived using a
spin-diffusion equation, including spin-vorticity coupling, which is a couple
of angular momentum between electron spin and vorticity field in unsteady
flows. The estimation of SHDG in liquid mercury flow suggests that an
observable magnitude of voltage can be induced in unsteady flows. Our results
are expected to enable the realization of high-speed spin devices with unsteady
flows and broaden the range of fluid spintronics applicability.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Funato_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Takumi Funato&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Matsuo_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Mamoru Matsuo&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.00560">
<title>2D Janus Niobium Oxydihalide NbO$XY$: Multifunctional High-Mobility Piezoelectric Semiconductor for Electronics, Photonics and Sustainable Energy Applications. (arXiv:2211.00560v2 [cond-mat.mtrl-sci] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.00560</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Two-dimensional (2D) niobium oxydihalide NbOI$_2$ has been recently
demonstrated as an excellent in-plane piezoelectric and nonlinear optical
materials. Here we show that Janus niobium oxydihalide, NbO$XY$ (X, Y = Cl, Br,
I and X$\neq$Y), is a multifunctional anisotropic semiconductor family with
exceptional piezoelectric, electronic, photocatalytic and optical properties.
NbO$XY$ are stable and mechancially flexible monolayers with band gap around
the visible light regime of $\sim 1.9$ eV. The anisotropic carrier mobility of
NbO$XY$ lies in the range of $10^3 \sim 10^4$ cm$^2$V$^{-1}$s$^{-1}$, which
represents some of the highest among 2D semiconductors of bandgap $\gtrsim 2$
eV. Inversion symmetry breaking in Janus NbO$XY$ generates sizable out-of-plane
$d_{31}$ piezoelectric response while still retaining a strong in-plane
piezoelectricity. Remarkably, NbO$XY$ exhibits an additional out-of-plane
piezoelectric response, $d_{32}$ as large as 0.55 pm/V. G$_0$W$_0$-BSE
calculation further reveals the strong linear optical dichroism of NbO$XY$ in
the visible-to-ultraviolet regime. The optical absorption peaks with $14\sim18$
\% in the deep UV regime ($5\sim6$ eV), outperforming the vast majority of
other 2D materials. The high carrier mobility, strong optical absorption,
sizable built-in electric field and band alignment compatible with overall
water splitting further suggest the strengths of NbO$XY$ in energy conversion
application. We further propose a directional stress sensing device to
demonstrate how the out-of-plane piezoelectricity can be harnessed for
functional device applications. Our findings unveil NbO$XY$ as an exceptional
multifunctional 2D semiconductor for flexible electronics, optoelectronics, UV
photonics, piezoelectric and sustainable energy applications.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Su_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Tong Su&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Lee_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ching Hua Lee&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Guo_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;San-Dong Guo&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Wang_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Guangzhao Wang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Ong_W/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Wee-Liat Ong&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Zhao_W/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Weiwei Zhao&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Yang_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Shengyuan A. Yang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Ang_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yee Sin Ang&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.00679">
<title>Quantum phase transitions in non-Hermitian $\mathcal{P}\mathcal{T}$-symmetric transverse-field Ising spin chains. (arXiv:2211.00679v1 [quant-ph] CROSS LISTED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.00679</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We present a theoretical study of quantum phases and quantum phase
transitions occurring in non-Hermitian $\mathcal{P}\mathcal{T}$-symmetric
superconducting qubits chains described by a transverse-field Ising spin model.
A non-Hermitian part of the Hamiltonian is implemented via imaginary staggered
\textit{longitudinal } magnetic field, which corresponds to a local staggered
gain and loss terms. By making use of a direct numerical diagonalization of the
Hamiltonian for spin chains of a finite size $N$, we explore the dependencies
of the energy spectrum, including the energy difference between the first
excited and the ground states, the spatial correlation function of local
polarization ($z$-component of local magnetization) on the adjacent spins
interaction strength $J$ and the local gain (loss) parameter $\gamma$. A
scaling procedure for the coherence length $\xi$ allows us to establish a
complete quantum phase diagram of the system. We obtain two quantum phases for
$J&amp;lt;0$, namely, $\mathcal{P}\mathcal{T}$-symmetry broken antiferromagnetic state
and $\mathcal{P}\mathcal{T}$-symmetry preserved paramagnetic state, and the
quantum phase transition line between them is the line of exception points. For
$J&amp;gt;0$ the $\mathcal{P}\mathcal{T}$-symmetry of the ground state is retained in
a whole region of parameter space of $J$ and $\gamma$, and a system shows
\textit{two} intriguing quantum phase transitions between ferromagnetic and
paramagnetic states for a fixed parameter $\gamma &amp;gt; 1$. We also provide the
qualitative quantum phase diagram $\gamma-J$ derived in the framework of the
Bethe-Peierls approximation that is in a good accord with numerically obtained
results.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Starkov_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Grigory A. Starkov&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Fistoul_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Mikhail V. Fistoul&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Eremin_I/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ilya M. Eremin&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
</rdf:RDF>