<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns:yt="http://www.youtube.com/xml/schemas/2015" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
 <link rel="self" href="http://www.youtube.com/feeds/videos.xml?channel_id=UCrlZs71h3mTR45FgQNINfrg"/>
 <id>yt:channel:UCrlZs71h3mTR45FgQNINfrg</id>
 <yt:channelId>UCrlZs71h3mTR45FgQNINfrg</yt:channelId>
 <title>Mathemaniac</title>
 <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCrlZs71h3mTR45FgQNINfrg"/>
 <author>
  <name>Mathemaniac</name>
  <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCrlZs71h3mTR45FgQNINfrg</uri>
 </author>
 <published>2018-08-08T11:59:00+00:00</published>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:2n2XGNHsKjA</id>
  <yt:videoId>2n2XGNHsKjA</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCrlZs71h3mTR45FgQNINfrg</yt:channelId>
  <title>Can Oxford professor solve Cambridge math interview questions? (ft. @Tom Rocks Maths)</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2n2XGNHsKjA"/>
  <author>
   <name>Mathemaniac</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCrlZs71h3mTR45FgQNINfrg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-11-04T15:00:03+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-11-05T13:34:29+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Can Oxford professor solve Cambridge math interview questions? (ft. @Tom Rocks Maths)</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/2n2XGNHsKjA?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i3.ytimg.com/vi/2n2XGNHsKjA/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>To prove once and for all that Cambridge is better than O*ford 😤 (just kidding)

** Tom uses &quot;Oxford professor&quot; in his videos, so I am just following that. **

Tom's channel: https://www.youtube.com/c/TomRocksMaths/featured
100k Q and A Google form: https://forms.gle/WtpM3HqhkdPuwsbP9

You might recognize Tom from his Navier-Stokes equations on the Numberphile channel, and he is a tutor at Oxford teaching students at St. Edmund Hall college in Oxford. I just thought it was funny to have a Cambridge student to interview a teacher at Oxford.

**I HAVE TO EMPHASISE THAT THIS IS ON A MUCH MORE DIFFICULT LEVEL THAN THE OTHER QUESTIONS I HAVE HEARD FROM MY FRIENDS. THIS IS AGREED BY MY FRIENDS, SO IT'S NOT JUST ME SAYING MINE ARE HARDER.**

I am a fourth-year Cambridge math student, and so I thought I would share with you the interview questions that I have gone through! I have signed a sort of NDA for not disclosing the exact interview questions, but it has now been 4 years since my last interview, so it is fine!

Actually, my interviewer knows about this channel, but I am not sure whether he watches it or not. I hope I don't get into trouble, because in the spirit of the confidentiality agreement I signed, I should be able to disclose the details of the interview questions now. It has been 4 years since my interview, so unless they are so uncreative to come up with new interview questions, I think this should be fine.

A bit of notes:

(1) Sorry for a lot of the technical glitches - we were very unlucky, because Tom has also used the same setup in his exam series without any problems.

(2) There is an organ playing in the background - they are practising for the evening service at the college! If you don’t like it, I’m sorry; if you like it, consider it background music.

(3) For Cambridge applicants: the interview format differs from college to college. If you are interviewing for St John’s, there are separate pure and applied interviews; for Trinity (which I strongly discourage any potential applicants to apply to, simply due to the competitive nature), your interview will be based on some questions you’ve attempted in a test prior to the interview. However, because of COVID, I am not sure if all these have changed.

(4) For the people who are here for the maths: for the second question, what I meant to say was that because there are 999 consecutive integers, when you shift by one place, then you are either (a) adding an even number and deleting an odd number, or (b) adding an odd number and deleting an even number.

In the case of (a), adding an even number does not change the number of primes, but deleting an odd number might or might not decrease the number of primes by 1, so the number of primes in the interval either changes by 0 or -1.

In the case of (b), deleting an even number again does not change the number of primes, but adding an odd number might or might not increase the number of primes by 1, so the number of primes in the interval either changes by 0 or +1.

Actually, even if it is 1000 integers, a similar argument applies, though I would say this parity argument is slightly more complicated. Anyway, the idea is that initially you have more than 10 primes, and then you have also constructed an interval with exactly 0 prime, so somewhere in between, there must be an interval with exactly 10 primes, because every time you are only either changing the number of primes by +1,0, or -1.

Video chapters:
00:00 Introduction
01:24 First question: graph sketching
08:54 Second question (Part I): 0 prime
19:59 Second question (Part II): 10 primes
29:47 Third question: physics
50:04 Final point: SAQ (now called My Cambridge)

Other than commenting on the video, you are very welcome to fill in a Google form linked below, which helps me make better videos by catering for your math levels:
https://forms.gle/QJ29hocF9uQAyZyH6

If you want to know more interesting Mathematics, stay tuned for the next video!

SUBSCRIBE and see you in the next video!

If you are wondering how I made all these videos, even though it is stylistically similar to 3Blue1Brown, I don't use his animation engine Manim, but I will probably reveal how I did it in a potential subscriber milestone, so do subscribe!

Social media:

Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/mathemaniacyt
Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/_mathemaniac_/
Twitter: https://twitter.com/mathemaniacyt
Patreon: https://www.patreon.com/mathemaniac (support if you want to and can afford to!)
Merch: https://mathemaniac.myspreadshop.co.uk
Ko-fi: https://ko-fi.com/mathemaniac [for one-time support]

For my contact email, check my About page on a PC.

See you next time!</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="303" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="6736"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:iH2kATv49rc</id>
  <yt:videoId>iH2kATv49rc</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCrlZs71h3mTR45FgQNINfrg</yt:channelId>
  <title>Random walks in 2D and 3D are fundamentally different (Markov chains approach)</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=iH2kATv49rc"/>
  <author>
   <name>Mathemaniac</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCrlZs71h3mTR45FgQNINfrg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-10-04T14:00:24+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-10-26T21:39:28+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Random walks in 2D and 3D are fundamentally different (Markov chains approach)</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/iH2kATv49rc?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i2.ytimg.com/vi/iH2kATv49rc/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>Second channel video: https://youtu.be/KnWK7xYuy00
100k Q&amp;A Google form: https://forms.gle/BCspH33sCRc75RwcA

&quot;A drunk man will find his way home, but a drunk bird may get lost forever.&quot; What is this sentence about?

In 2D, the random walk is &quot;recurrent&quot;, i.e. you are guaranteed to go back to where you started; but in 3D, the random walk is &quot;transient&quot;, the opposite of &quot;recurrent&quot;. In fact, for the 2D case, that also means that you are guaranteed to go to ALL places in the world (the only constraint is, of course, time). [Think about why.]

Markov chains are also an important tool in modelling the real world, and so I feel like this is a good excuse for bringing it up.

At the end, I also compare this phenomenon to Stein's paradox - in both cases, there is a cutoff between 2 and 3 dimensions, and they have similar intuitive explanation - is that a coincidence?

Video chapters:
00:00 Introduction
00:59 Chapter 1: Markov chains
03:20 Chapter 2: Recurrence and transience
10:08 Chapter 3: Back to random walks

Further reading:
Larry Brown’s paper: http://stat.wharton.upenn.edu/~lbrown/Papers/1971b%20Admissible%20estimators,%20recurrent%20diffusions,%20and%20insoluble%20boundary%20value%20problems.pdf
Using electric circuits to prove recurrence / trasience: https://math.dartmouth.edu/~pw/math100w13/mare.pdf
More complicated, but more general proof: https://sites.math.washington.edu/~morrow/336_19/papers19/Legrand.pdf
Actual probability for 3D random walk to come back: https://mathworld.wolfram.com/PolyasRandomWalkConstants.html

Other than commenting on the video, you are very welcome to fill in a Google form linked below, which helps me make better videos by catering for your math levels:
https://forms.gle/QJ29hocF9uQAyZyH6

If you want to know more interesting Mathematics, stay tuned for the next video!

SUBSCRIBE and see you in the next video!

If you are wondering how I made all these videos, even though it is stylistically similar to 3Blue1Brown, I don't use his animation engine Manim, but I will probably reveal how I did it in a potential subscriber milestone, so do subscribe!

Social media:

Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/mathemaniacyt
Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/_mathemaniac_/
Twitter: https://twitter.com/mathemaniacyt
Patreon: https://www.patreon.com/mathemaniac (support if you want to and can afford to!)
Merch: https://mathemaniac.myspreadshop.co.uk
Ko-fi: https://ko-fi.com/mathemaniac [for one-time support]

For my contact email, check my About page on a PC.

See you next time!</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="12489" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="478509"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:cUqoHQDinCM</id>
  <yt:videoId>cUqoHQDinCM</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCrlZs71h3mTR45FgQNINfrg</yt:channelId>
  <title>The weirdest paradox in statistics (and machine learning)</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=cUqoHQDinCM"/>
  <author>
   <name>Mathemaniac</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCrlZs71h3mTR45FgQNINfrg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-08-30T14:00:18+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-09-09T20:41:44+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>The weirdest paradox in statistics (and machine learning)</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/cUqoHQDinCM?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i4.ytimg.com/vi/cUqoHQDinCM/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>🌏 AD: Get Exclusive NordVPN deal here ➼ https://nordvpn.com/mathemaniac. It's risk-free with Nord's 30-day money-back guarantee! ✌

Second channel video: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3ne9yghOtw8

Stein's paradox is of fundamental importance in modern statistics, introducing concepts of shrinkage to further reduce the mean squared error, especially in higher dimensional statistics that is particularly relevant nowadays, in the world of machine learning, for example. However, this is usually ignored, because it is mostly seen as a toy problem. Precisely because it is such a simple problem that illustrates the problem of maximum likelihood estimation! This paradox is the subject of many blogposts (linked below), but not really here on YouTube, except in some lecture recordings, so I have to bring this up to YouTube.

This is not to say that maximum likelihood estimator is not useful - in most situations, especially in lower dimensional statistics, it is still good, but to hold it to such a high place, as statisticians did before 1961? That is not a healthy attitude to this theory.

One thing I did not say, but perhaps a lot of people will want me to, is that this is an emprical Bayes estimator, but again, more links below.

Video chapters:
00:00 Introduction
04:38 Chapter 1: The &quot;best&quot; estimator
09:48 Chapter 2: Why shrinkage works
15:51 Chapter 3: Bias-variance tradeoff
18:45 Chapter 4: Applications

Further reading:
The “baseball paper”: https://efron.ckirby.su.domains//other/Article1977.pdf
Wikipedia: https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stein%27s_example
Dominating the (positive-part) James-Stein estimator: https://projecteuclid.org/journals/annals-of-statistics/volume-22/issue-3/Improving-on-the-James-Stein-Positive-Part-Estimator/10.1214/aos/1176325640.full
Wikipedia (Empirical Bayes): https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Empirical_Bayes_method

Other writeups:
http://www.ime.unicamp.br/~veronica/MI677/steinparadox.pdf
https://joe-antognini.github.io/machine-learning/steins-paradox
https://www.jchau.org/2021/01/29/demystifying-stein-s-paradox/
https://www.naftaliharris.com/blog/steinviz/
https://austinrochford.com/posts/2013-11-30-steins-paradox-and-empirical-bayes.html
https://duphan.wordpress.com/2016/07/10/steins-paradox-or-the-power-of-shrinkage/
http://www.statslab.cam.ac.uk/~rjs57/SteinParadox.pdf

(Philosophical implications) http://philsci-archive.pitt.edu/13303/1/Philosophical%20significance%20of%20Stein%20Preprint.pdf

Other than commenting on the video, you are very welcome to fill in a Google form linked below, which helps me make better videos by catering for your math levels:
https://forms.gle/QJ29hocF9uQAyZyH6

If you want to know more interesting Mathematics, stay tuned for the next video!

SUBSCRIBE and see you in the next video!

If you are wondering how I made all these videos, even though it is stylistically similar to 3Blue1Brown, I don't use his animation engine Manim, but I will probably reveal how I did it in a potential subscriber milestone, so do subscribe!

Social media:

Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/mathemaniacyt
Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/_mathemaniac_/
Twitter: https://twitter.com/mathemaniacyt
Patreon: https://www.patreon.com/mathemaniac (support if you want to and can afford to!)
Merch: https://mathemaniac.myspreadshop.co.uk
Ko-fi: https://ko-fi.com/mathemaniac [for one-time support]

For my contact email, check my About page on a PC.

See you next time!</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="15118" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="557288"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:zCU9tZ2VkWc</id>
  <yt:videoId>zCU9tZ2VkWc</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCrlZs71h3mTR45FgQNINfrg</yt:channelId>
  <title>Why you can't solve quintic equations (Galois theory approach) #SoME2</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zCU9tZ2VkWc"/>
  <author>
   <name>Mathemaniac</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCrlZs71h3mTR45FgQNINfrg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-07-03T14:00:23+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-09-05T00:08:36+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Why you can't solve quintic equations (Galois theory approach) #SoME2</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/zCU9tZ2VkWc?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i3.ytimg.com/vi/zCU9tZ2VkWc/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>An entry to #SoME2. It is a famous theorem (called Abel-Ruffini theorem) that there is no quintic formula, or quintic equations are not solvable; but very likely you are not told the exact reason why. Here is how traditionally we knew that such a formula cannot exist, using Galois theory.

Correction: At 08:09, I forgot to put ellipsis in between. 

Video chapters:

00:00 Introduction
00:23 Chapter 1: The setup
04:38 Chapter 2: Galois group
11:15 Chapter 3: Cyclotomic and Kummer extensions
19:43 Chapter 4: Tower of extensions
27:25 Chapter 5: Back to solving equations
35:23 Chapter 6: The final stretch (intuition)
43:25 Chapter 7: What have we done?

Notes:

I HAVE to simplify and not give every technical detail. This is made with the intent that everyone, regardless of their background in algebra, can take away the core message of the video. This can only be done if I cut out the parts that are not necessary for this purpose. As with my previous video series on “Average distance in a unit disc”, this is made to address the question I always had when I was small - treat this as a kind of a video message to my past self.

For the “making everything Galois extension” bit, we will need to show that the only things fixed by ALL automorphisms over Q must be in Q itself. This is intuitive, but difficult to justify rigorously. All proofs I know involve “degree of field extension”, and the very satisfying result called the “tower law”, which I deliberately avoided throughout the video because it turns out not to be necessary for the core part of the video. For instance, this proof: https://math.stackexchange.com/questions/962898/on-a-proof-that-the-splitting-field-of-a-separable-polynomial-is-galois

The reason we have this mess is that we defined Galois extension using the splitting field of a (separable, i.e. no repeated roots) polynomial. The usual definition given is exactly as above - only things fixed by ALL automorphisms over Q must be in Q itself. This typical definition will of course solve the problem above, but will now create the problem of why this definition implies the larger field is made by adjoining the roots of some polynomial. These two definitions are equivalent, but I just think that it makes much more sense to define it the way I did in the video, in the context of the video; and also I think this is an easier definition to accept.

Resources on Tower law: https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Degree_of_a_field_extension#The_multiplicativity_formula_for_degrees
https://artofproblemsolving.com/wiki/index.php/Tower_law

Quotients of solvable groups are solvable (the elementary proof): https://math.stackexchange.com/questions/2203250/quotient-of-solvable-groups-is-solvable-whats-wrong-with-this-proof
[The question is already the proof - it is a really elementary way to show the result that we want]

More resources on proofs that A_n is not solvable:
Sign of permutations: https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Parity_of_a_permutation
Alternating groups: https://mathworld.wolfram.com/AlternatingGroup.html
The proof that A_n is simple (i.e. no non-trivial normal subgroups): http://ramanujan.math.trinity.edu/rdaileda/teach/s19/m3362/alternating.pdf
[You need to only go up to Page 5 towards the end of the proof of Theorem 2, but you definitely need group theory lingo]

If you know a bit of group theory (orbit-stabiliser and Cauchy), then you can see that the polynomial x^5 - 6x + 3 has the full S5 Galois group, because it is (i) irreducible [this requires Eisenstein’s criterion, see link below], and (ii) exactly two complex roots [and hence the Galois group contains a transposition, i.e. complex conjugation]. Note that the Galois group is transitive. This again needs quite a bit of justification. For the proof assuming transitivity, see here: https://math.stackexchange.com/questions/3075225/f-irreducible-polynomial-with-p-2-real-roots-rightarrow-gal-mathbbq-f

Eisenstein’s criterion: https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Eisenstein%27s_criterion

Other than commenting on the video, you are very welcome to fill in a Google form linked below, which helps me make better videos by catering for your math levels:
https://forms.gle/QJ29hocF9uQAyZyH6

If you want to know more interesting Mathematics, stay tuned for the next video!

SUBSCRIBE and see you in the next video!

If you are wondering how I made all these videos, even though it is stylistically similar to 3Blue1Brown, I don't use his animation engine Manim, but I will probably reveal how I did it in a potential subscriber milestone, so do subscribe!

Social media:

Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/mathemaniacyt
Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/_mathemaniac_/
Twitter: https://twitter.com/mathemaniacyt
Patreon: https://www.patreon.com/mathemaniac (support if you want to and can afford to!)
Merch: https://mathemaniac.myspreadshop.co.uk
Ko-fi: https://ko-fi.com/mathemaniac [for one-time support]

For my contact email, check my About page on a PC.

See you next time!</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="6774" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="214813"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:0_eJlNVatsU</id>
  <yt:videoId>0_eJlNVatsU</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCrlZs71h3mTR45FgQNINfrg</yt:channelId>
  <title>The simplest reason why π/4 = 1 - 1/3 + 1/5 -...</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0_eJlNVatsU"/>
  <author>
   <name>Mathemaniac</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCrlZs71h3mTR45FgQNINfrg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-04-29T14:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-08-19T15:49:34+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>The simplest reason why π/4 = 1 - 1/3 + 1/5 -...</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/0_eJlNVatsU?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i1.ytimg.com/vi/0_eJlNVatsU/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>Without differentiation or integration, or number theory, could we still prove this infinite sum? | Visit http://brilliant.org/Mathemaniac/ to get started learning STEM for free, and the first 200 people will get 20% off their annual premium subscription.

π/4 = 1 - 1/3 + 1/5 -..., also called the Leibniz series, is quite famous, but the usual proof involves differentiation or integration. The more visual geometric proof still relies a lot on some advanced theorems from number theory, but given how simple the series is, is it possible to have an even simpler proof? Yes! And this video tries to explain this.

Actually, similar to the previous proof, this proof has been at the video ideas list for quite a long time - so it's good to finally see this out!

By the way, on second thought, this looks similar to Fourier coefficients, at least the time average bit - though I can't see whether this is the same proof as the one using Fourier series of sgn(x). It feels very connected, but also very different in the sense that we don't need to use the Cesàro sums of the Fourier series. Please let me know if you have any ideas regarding this.

Video chapters:
00:00 Intro
00:45 Chapter 1: The setup
03:16 Chapter 2: The main argument
14:55 Chapter 3: Making this rigorous
17:33 Sponsored segment

This video was sponsored by Brilliant.

Sources (in order of appearance in the video):

(1) Pi hiding in prime regularities (3Blue1Brown): https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=NaL_Cb42WyY

(2) Fermat’s Christmas Theorem (Mathologer): https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=00w8gu2aL-w

(3) The proof itself: https://www.quora.com/How-can-I-show-that-frac-pi-4-1-frac-1-3-frac-1-5-frac-1-7-cdots-perhaps-geometrically/answer/Sridhar-Ramesh

(4) Cesàro sums: https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ces%C3%A0ro_summation

A little more reading:

(1) Calculating pi by hand (Matt Parker): https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=HrRMnzANHHs

(2) Regular sum, if defined, equals Cesàro sum: https://math.stackexchange.com/questions/1134265/cesaro-summable-series
https://math.stackexchange.com/questions/514802/convergence-of-series-implies-convergence-of-cesaro-mean

(3) Wikipedia proof (involving integration): https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Leibniz_formula_for_%CF%80
(Worth noting that this requires a bit more than just plugging in x = 1 in arctangent series - this requires the justification from Abel’s theorem)

(4) If you want to prove the Cesàro sum of the positions to be 0 more rigorously, here is the justification:
https://www.wolframalpha.com/input?i=sum+from+k%3D1+to+n+%281-k%2F%28n%29%29*cos%28kx%29
and 
https://www.wolframalpha.com/input?i=lim+n+to+infty+sum+from+k%3D1+to+n+%281-k%2F%28n%29%29*cos%28kx%29&amp;assumption=%22LimitHead%22+-%3E+%7B%22Discrete%22%7D
(and the formula in the first link would only require repeatedly applying product to sum formulas and telescoping series - still no differentiation / integration involved. If you want even further assistance, I made a video on this: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=DzhK3UJj5IY )

Music:
Asher Fulero - Beseeched
Aakash Gandhi - Heavenly, Kiss the Sky, Lifting Dreams
(From YouTube audio library)

Other than commenting on the video, you are very welcome to fill in a Google form linked below, which helps me make better videos by catering for your math levels:
https://forms.gle/QJ29hocF9uQAyZyH6

If you want to know more interesting Mathematics, stay tuned for the next video!

SUBSCRIBE and see you in the next video!

If you are wondering how I made all these videos, even though it is stylistically similar to 3Blue1Brown, I don't use his animation engine Manim, but I will probably reveal how I did it in a potential subscriber milestone, so do subscribe!

Social media:

Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/mathemaniacyt
Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/_mathemaniac_/
Twitter: https://twitter.com/mathemaniacyt
Patreon: https://www.patreon.com/mathemaniac (support if you want to and can afford to!)
Merch: https://mathemaniac.myspreadshop.co.uk

For my contact email, check my About page on a PC.

See you next time!</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="2419" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="80595"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:x09IsbVZeXo</id>
  <yt:videoId>x09IsbVZeXo</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCrlZs71h3mTR45FgQNINfrg</yt:channelId>
  <title>The geometric interpretation of sin x = x - x³/3! + x⁵/5! -...</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=x09IsbVZeXo"/>
  <author>
   <name>Mathemaniac</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCrlZs71h3mTR45FgQNINfrg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-03-24T15:00:36+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-09-27T03:23:51+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>The geometric interpretation of sin x = x - x³/3! + x⁵/5! -...</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/x09IsbVZeXo?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i1.ytimg.com/vi/x09IsbVZeXo/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>We first learnt sin x as a geometric object, so can we make geometric sense of the Taylor series of the sine function? For a long time, I thought it was just my dream, but actually, it is not!

This proof only uses very elementary methods, and depending on your definition of calculus, doesn't actually use calculus. The most we are using is a limiting process, and definitely no differentiation or integration here.

This proof is very beautiful - not only that it unveils the geometric meaning of each term in the series very beautifully, but also understandable by a normal high-school student with a little bit of patience. I am very surprised that it has not appeared on YouTube before, and even if it does exist on the internet, it is far too unpopular, and so I have to bring this up!

Obviously this is not my proof. See the sources below.

Sources:
https://www.jstor.org/stable/2974881?seq=1#metadata_info_tab_contents
https://arxiv.org/pdf/1610.04825.pdf (equations of the involutes)
https://math.stackexchange.com/questions/2758418/deriving-the-power-series-for-cosine-using-basic-geometry?noredirect=1&amp;lq=1 (the StackExchange post)
https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Involute (More about involutes)
https://support.google.com/youtube/answer/6162278#zippy=%2Cguide-to-self-certification (Advertiser-friendly guidelines)
https://www.unicef.org.uk/donate/donate-now-to-protect-children-in-ukraine/ (UNICEF Ukraine Appeal)

Music:
Asher Fulero - Beseeched
Aakash Gandhi - White River, Heavenly, Lifting Dreams, Kiss the Sky

Video Chapters:
00:00 Introduction
00:50 Preliminaries
02:10 Main sketch
06:03 Details - Laying the ground work
09:42 The iteration process
11:11 Finding lengths of involutes
14:57 What? Combinatorics?
18:44 Final calculation
20:45 Fundraiser appeal

Other than commenting on the video, you are very welcome to fill in a Google form linked below, which helps me make better videos by catering for your math levels:
https://forms.gle/QJ29hocF9uQAyZyH6

If you want to know more interesting Mathematics, stay tuned for the next video!

SUBSCRIBE and see you in the next video!

If you are wondering how I made all these videos, even though it is stylistically similar to 3Blue1Brown, I don't use his animation engine Manim, but I will probably reveal how I did it in a potential subscriber milestone, so do subscribe!

Social media:

Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/mathemaniacyt
Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/_mathemaniac_/
Twitter: https://twitter.com/mathemaniacyt
Patreon: https://www.patreon.com/mathemaniac (support if you want to and can afford to!)
Merch: https://mathemaniac.myspreadshop.co.uk

For my contact email, check my About page on a PC.

See you next time!</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="10063" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="244034"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:EyBDtUtyshk</id>
  <yt:videoId>EyBDtUtyshk</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCrlZs71h3mTR45FgQNINfrg</yt:channelId>
  <title>Complex integration, Cauchy and residue theorems | Essence of Complex Analysis #6</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=EyBDtUtyshk"/>
  <author>
   <name>Mathemaniac</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCrlZs71h3mTR45FgQNINfrg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-01-22T15:00:07+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-02-16T12:14:17+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Complex integration, Cauchy and residue theorems | Essence of Complex Analysis #6</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/EyBDtUtyshk?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i2.ytimg.com/vi/EyBDtUtyshk/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>Unlock new career opportunities and become data fluent today! Use my link https://bit.ly/MathemaniacDCJan22  and check out the first chapter of any DataCamp course for FREE! 

I can't pronounce &quot;parametrisation&quot; lol

A crash course in complex analysis - basically everything leading up to the Residue theorem. This is a more intuitive explanation of complex integration using Pólya vector field.

You might notice that my explanation on parametrisation is a bit similar to the Jacobian, and you will be right! Jacobian is really important in this area (and also understanding complex differentiation and Cauchy-Riemann equations).

I have made this slower in comparison with some of my other videos, because when I myself watched some of my other videos that are faster, I couldn't comprehend if I was not paying too much attention on the screen, let alone the audience watching it for the first time. If somehow, miraculously, you think this is way too slow, feel free to speed it up!

I said the more general Cauchy integral formula is related, because in my original plan, I did want to say that Laurent coefficients take on exactly the same form, but it just occurred while I was finally editing the video that we don't find Laurent coefficients using integrals, and I don't want to send my Cauchy integral formula bit to waste, so here it is.

Throughout this video series, of course I have left out lots of theorems in complex analysis, only talking about the things that I find more &quot;applicable&quot; (read: more audience want to watch). Things like Fundamental theorem of algebra, or maximum modulus principle, or even winding numbers are not presented, but in my defense, they are not really &quot;essence of&quot; anymore, because they use the concepts that we have developed in this series instead - like Cauchy integral formula as seen here.

This video was sponsored by DataCamp.

📖📖MORE READING📖📖

(Simply connected version) https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cauchy%27s_integral_theorem

(Homologous to 0 version)
https://www-users.cse.umn.edu/~brubaker/docs/8701-F13/dixon.pdf

Surely, You’re Joking, Mr Feynman: https://www.amazon.co.uk/Surely-Youre-Joking-Feynman-Adventures/dp/009917331X

Math StackExchange thread: https://math.stackexchange.com/questions/253910/the-integral-that-stumped-feynman

Residue theorem example links:

Wikipedia: https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Residue_theorem#An_integral_along_the_real_axis
[The example that I nicked from]

You will need - estimation lemma (a.k.a. ML lemma): https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Estimation_lemma

If you want to watch other videos on the exact same integral instead (although I think the Wikipedia page is a more “elementary” way of finding residues), you might want to have a look at:

Classifying singularities: https://sites.oxy.edu/ron/math/312/14/ws/24.pdf (page 1)

More ways of calculating residues: https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Residue_(complex_analysis)#Calculating_residues

YouTube videos talking about exactly the same integral (though they all assume quite a bit of familiarity of the above):

Flammable maths: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=YWBdwYr6PGg
qncubed3: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=DvND8J32gOA
tahiri math science online teaching: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=oGEo_BxqZ3c

🎶🎶Music used🎶🎶
Aakash Gandhi - Heavenly / Kiss the Sky / Lifting Dreams / White River
Asher Fulero - The Closing of Summer

Video chapter:
00:00 Complex integration (first try)
06:01 Pólya vector field
08:18 Complex integration (second try)
12:27 Cauchy's theorem
18:39 Integrating 1/z
22:28 Other powers of z
28:26 Cauchy integral formula
31:43 Residue theorem
36:14 But why?

Other than commenting on the video, you are very welcome to fill in a Google form linked below, which helps me make better videos by catering for your math levels:
https://forms.gle/QJ29hocF9uQAyZyH6

If you want to know more interesting Mathematics, stay tuned for the next video!

SUBSCRIBE and see you in the next video!

If you are wondering how I made all these videos, even though it is stylistically similar to 3Blue1Brown, I don't use his animation engine Manim, but I will probably reveal how I did it in a potential subscriber milestone, so do subscribe!

Social media:

Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/mathemaniacyt
Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/_mathemaniac_/
Twitter: https://twitter.com/mathemaniacyt
Patreon: https://www.patreon.com/mathemaniac (support if you want to and can afford to!)
Merch: https://mathemaniac.myspreadshop.co.uk

For my contact email, check my About page on a PC.

See you next time!</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="5595" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="168542"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:hhI8fVxvmaw</id>
  <yt:videoId>hhI8fVxvmaw</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCrlZs71h3mTR45FgQNINfrg</yt:channelId>
  <title>What if we define 1/0 = ∞? | Möbius transformations visualized</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hhI8fVxvmaw"/>
  <author>
   <name>Mathemaniac</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCrlZs71h3mTR45FgQNINfrg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2021-12-17T15:00:16+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-08-19T15:48:15+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>What if we define 1/0 = ∞? | Möbius transformations visualized</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/hhI8fVxvmaw?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i1.ytimg.com/vi/hhI8fVxvmaw/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>Head to https://brilliant.org/Mathemaniac/ to get started for free with Brilliant's interactive lessons. The first 200 listeners will also get 20% off an annual membership.

Defining 1/0 = ∞ isn't actually that bad, and actually the natural definition if you are on the Riemann sphere - ∞ is just an ordinary point on the sphere! Here is the exposition on Möbius maps, which will explain why 1/0 = ∞ isn't actually something crazy. And this video will also briefly mention the applications of the Möbius map.

There will also be things like circular and spherical inversion, which are really neat tools in Euclidean geometry to help us establish lots of interesting results, this one included.

This video was sponsored by Brilliant.

Video chapters:
00:00 Intro
02:38 Chapter 1: The 2D perspective
08:43 Chapter 2: More about inversion
14:33 Chapter 3: The 3D perspective (1/z)
19:38 Chapter 4: The 3D perspective (general)
---------------------------------------------------
SOURCES:
[That 2012 paper] Rigid motion 1-1 Möbius map: https://scholar.rose-hulman.edu/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=1218&amp;context=rhumj
Möbius transformations revealed: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0z1fIsUNhO4
Accompanying paper: https://www-users.cse.umn.edu/~arnold//papers/moebius.pdf
Unitary iff rotation: https://users.math.msu.edu/users/shapiro/pubvit/Downloads/RS_Rotation/rotation.pdf
Möbius iff sphere: https://home.iitm.ac.in/jaikrishnan/MA5360/files/mobius.pdf
Rotation of Riemann sphere: https://people.reed.edu/~jerry/311/rotate.pdf
Circle-preserving implies Möbius: https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/epdf/10.1002/mana.19670330506
Problem of Apollonius video: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Z6GG8zsMWH8
Power of a point: https://www.nagwa.com/en/explainers/798164323509
--------------------------------------------------------
MORE CONNECTIONS OF MÖBIUS MAPS:
Sir Roger Penrose lecture on the book with Rindler (Spinors and space-time): https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fzYV6VrsHyQ
The book: https://www.cambridge.org/core/books/spinors-and-spacetime/B66766D4755F13B98F95D0EB6DF26526
Hyperbolic geometry: https://assets.cambridge.org/97811071/16740/excerpt/9781107116740_excerpt.pdf
Conformal mapping (fluid mechanics): https://math.berkeley.edu/~iliopoum/Topics_121A/Conformal%20mapping%20in%20fluid%20mechanics.pdf
--------------------------------------------------------
Music used:
Aakash Gandhi - Heavenly / Kiss the Sky / Lifting Dreams / White River
Asher Fulero - The Closing of Summer
--------------------------------------------------------

Other than commenting on the video, you are very welcome to fill in a Google form linked below, which helps me make better videos by catering for your math levels:
https://forms.gle/QJ29hocF9uQAyZyH6

If you want to know more interesting Mathematics, stay tuned for the next video!

SUBSCRIBE and see you in the next video!

If you are wondering how I made all these videos, even though it is stylistically similar to 3Blue1Brown, I don't use his animation engine Manim, but I will probably reveal how I did it in a potential subscriber milestone, so do subscribe!

Social media:

Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/mathemaniacyt
Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/_mathemaniac_/
Twitter: https://twitter.com/mathemaniacyt
Patreon: https://www.patreon.com/mathemaniac (support if you want to and can afford to!)
Merch: https://mathemaniac.myspreadshop.co.uk

For my contact email, check my About page on a PC.

See you next time!</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="4178" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="107623"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:TaWBXRaNEcc</id>
  <yt:videoId>TaWBXRaNEcc</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCrlZs71h3mTR45FgQNINfrg</yt:channelId>
  <title>What do complex functions look like? | Essence of complex analysis #4</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=TaWBXRaNEcc"/>
  <author>
   <name>Mathemaniac</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCrlZs71h3mTR45FgQNINfrg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2021-10-25T15:00:14+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-09-27T06:38:03+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>What do complex functions look like? | Essence of complex analysis #4</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/TaWBXRaNEcc?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i1.ytimg.com/vi/TaWBXRaNEcc/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>A compilation of plots of different complex functions, like adding and multiplying complex constants, exponentiation, the power function (including nth roots), and logarithm. Issues like branch cuts, branch points, and branches in general will also be discussed as the result of inability to construct the plots. Finally, we will do a 4D rotation (composed of two 4D reflections) to the typical Riemann surfaces pictures, and see that it should be the same as its inverse functions.

The video is going to be jam-packed with visuals and animations, so while it may sometimes be too quick, you can pause the video; or you can just simply appreciate the visuals, the plots, and the animations.

Some interesting plots are usually the vector plots, like for the power functions, we have different regions of flow. The formula of 2(n+1) when n is positive can be left as an exercise - it is not TOO difficult to see why, but it is not the focus of the video, or not the primary feature that I want to discuss; or for negative powers, we have dipole, quadrupole, and octupole, and in general multipole, which might be familiar to physicists, because in electromagnetism, we use multipole expansions to see the dominant effects of the electric field.

Watch the previous video to see what the 5 methods of visualisation I am referring to, and also watch the Problem of Apollonius video for the next video!

Video chapters:
00:00 Introduction
01:01 Adding constant
02:51 Multiplying constant
06:14 Exponentiation
09:47 Power function - integer powers
14:11 Power function - complex inversion
15:39 Power function - square root branches
20:37 Power function - Riemann surfaces
22:53 Logarithm
26:51 Logarithm - 4D rotation

Music used:
Recollections - Asher Fulero
Stinson - Reed Mathis
Beseeched - Asher Fulero
White River - Aakash Gandhi

Other than commenting on the video, you are very welcome to fill in a Google form linked below, which helps me make better videos by catering for your math levels:
https://forms.gle/QJ29hocF9uQAyZyH6

If you want to know more interesting Mathematics, stay tuned for the next video!

SUBSCRIBE and see you in the next video!

If you are wondering how I made all these videos, even though it is stylistically similar to 3Blue1Brown, I don't use his animation engine Manim, but I will probably reveal how I did it in a potential subscriber milestone, so do subscribe!

Social media:

Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/mathemaniacyt
Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/_mathemaniac_/
Twitter: https://twitter.com/mathemaniacyt
Patreon: https://www.patreon.com/mathemaniac (support if you want to and can afford to!)
Merch: https://mathemaniac.myspreadshop.co.uk

For my contact email, check my About page on a PC.

See you next time!</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="2407" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="71933"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:NtoIXhUgqSk</id>
  <yt:videoId>NtoIXhUgqSk</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCrlZs71h3mTR45FgQNINfrg</yt:channelId>
  <title>The 5 ways to visualize complex functions | Essence of complex analysis #3</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=NtoIXhUgqSk"/>
  <author>
   <name>Mathemaniac</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCrlZs71h3mTR45FgQNINfrg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2021-09-12T14:00:20+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-05-03T19:02:28+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>The 5 ways to visualize complex functions | Essence of complex analysis #3</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/NtoIXhUgqSk?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i3.ytimg.com/vi/NtoIXhUgqSk/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>Complex functions are 4-dimensional: its input and output are complex numbers, and so represented in 2 dimensions each, so how do we visualize complex functions if we are living in a 3D world? There are actually 5 different ways to visualize a complex function, and this video is going to explore a bit about each of them.

Some of you commented that you have already studied complex analysis in full, but hopefully there are still some things that you haven't seen before, because a typical university course on complex analysis wouldn't contain as many visuals as seen in this video.

I know this might not be recommended by YouTube as much simply because the video is not that long (less than 20 minutes), and it seems like YouTube only puts my videos in recommendations when my video is very long. Originally I wanted to put things that will be covered in the next video into this particular video, but I figured that it doesn't make sense to cram two quite separate things into one video just for the sake of watch time. So please consider sharing this video, liking and commenting so that more people can watch it!

LEARN A LITTLE BIT MORE HERE:
More about complex visualisation: http://www.nucalc.com/ComplexFunctions.html
Joukowsky transform: https://complex-analysis.com/content/joukowsky_airfoil.html
Joukowsky transform (NASA): https://www.grc.nasa.gov/www/k-12/airplane/map.html

Credits to Yehuda, there is an interactive tool to obtain the domain colouring plot for complex functions here: https://people.math.osu.edu/fowler.291/phase/

Music used:
Heavenly - Aakash Gandhi
from YouTube audio library

Video chapters:
00:00 Introduction
01:03 Domain colouring
03:35 3D plots
05:45 Vector fields
07:50 z-w planes
10:53 Riemann spheres

Other than commenting on the video, you are very welcome to fill in a Google form linked below, which helps me make better videos by catering for your math levels:
https://forms.gle/QJ29hocF9uQAyZyH6

If you want to know more interesting Mathematics, stay tuned for the next video!

SUBSCRIBE and see you in the next video!

If you are wondering how I made all these videos, even though it is stylistically similar to 3Blue1Brown, I don't use his animation engine Manim, but I will probably reveal how I did it in a potential subscriber milestone, so do subscribe!

Social media:

Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/mathemaniacyt
Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/_mathemaniac_/
Twitter: https://twitter.com/mathemaniacyt
Patreon: https://www.patreon.com/mathemaniac (support if you want to and can afford to!)

For my contact email, check my About page on a PC.

See you next time!</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="6303" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="150635"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:Rju2g-sExng</id>
  <yt:videoId>Rju2g-sExng</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCrlZs71h3mTR45FgQNINfrg</yt:channelId>
  <title>What are complex numbers? | Essence of complex analysis #2</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Rju2g-sExng"/>
  <author>
   <name>Mathemaniac</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCrlZs71h3mTR45FgQNINfrg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2021-08-18T14:00:09+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-06-05T18:07:10+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>What are complex numbers? | Essence of complex analysis #2</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/Rju2g-sExng?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i3.ytimg.com/vi/Rju2g-sExng/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>A complete guide to the basics of complex numbers. Feel free to pause and catch a breath if you feel like it - it's meant to be a crash course!

Complex numbers are useful in basically all sorts of applications, because even in the real world, making things complex sometimes, oxymoronically, makes things simpler. This is the basis for a lot of physical applications, like circuit analysis, as well as slightly more far-fetched like Fourier analysis or Laplace transforms. Even for pure mathematicians, this is very useful due to its algebraic closure, and the beautiful world of complex analysis. As said before in the previous video, complex analysis is an extremely powerful tool that everyone should be excited about!

This video will cover basically all of the topics you will ever learn in a normal course in complex numbers, or things considered basics in complex analysis, namely, Cartesian and polar ways of representation, Euler's formula and identity, the different operations of complex numbers, including complex exponentiation like i^i, de Moivre's theorem helping us find nth root of any complex numbers and so on. Even if you know a lot about complex numbers, maybe the proofs of Euler's formula is something that you might not have seen, or just maybe use this as a refresher! This video also touches on the argument issue, which could naturally lead to branch cuts, but this will be postponed to the next video.

This is a part of a video series on complex analysis. Next video is going to be about visualising complex functions, and of course, the messy stuff about it, like the branch points and branch cuts. Don't forget to subscribe with the bell icon on so that you can be notified of my new uploads in the series!

Video chapters:
00:00 Sarcastic and serious introductions
01:32 1.1 Complex plane - Cartesian way
02:47 1.2 Complex plane - Polar way (Intro)
03:25 1.3 Arguments about arguments
04:57 1.4 Interconversion 
07:48 2.1 Euler's formula - classic proof
09:22 2.2 Euler's formula - 2nd proof
13:03 3.1 Operations - addition/subtraction
14:12 3.2 Operations - multiplication
16:06 3.3 Operations - conjugation
17:45 3.4 Operations - division
19:23 3.5 Operations - exponentiation
20:11 3.6 Operations - logarithm
21:50 3.7 Operations - sine/cosine
23:56 4.1 de Moivre's theorem - intro
24:49 4.2 de Moivre's theorem - nth roots
28:53 4.3 de Moivre's theorem - Euler's formula 3rd proof
31:12 Outro

Music used:
Asher Fulero - Beseeched
Aakash Gandhi - Kiss the Sky
Asher Fulero - Night Snow
Asher Fulero - Renunciation
Asher Fulero - Unrequited

All obtained from YouTube audio library.

THINGS MENTIONED AND FURTHER READING/WATCHING:
https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=v0YEaeIClKY (3Blue1Brown video on the second proof)
https://youtu.be/xowA7Z5aee0 (My video on pi calculation)
https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gelfond%E2%80%93Schneider_theorem (Gelfond-Schneider theorem: why e^(-pi/2) is transcendental)
https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=N-KXStupwsc (Mathologer video on cubic formula)
https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cubic_equation (Cubic equation)
https://brilliant.org/wiki/de-moivres-theorem/ (More uses of de Moivre’s theorem; not sponsored)
https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-dhHrg-KbJ0 (Mathologer video on the final proof of Euler’s formula)
https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Brahmagupta%E2%80%93Fibonacci_identity (Originally wanted to put this in, but don’t know where to put it, so: a nice application of complex numbers)

Other than commenting on the video, you are very welcome to fill in a Google form linked below, which helps me make better videos by catering for your math levels:
https://forms.gle/QJ29hocF9uQAyZyH6

If you want to know more interesting Mathematics, stay tuned for the next video!

SUBSCRIBE and see you in the next video!

If you are wondering how I made all these videos, even though it is stylistically similar to 3Blue1Brown, I don't use his animation engine Manim, but I will probably reveal how I did it in a potential subscriber milestone, so do subscribe!

Social media:

Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/mathemaniacyt
Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/_mathemaniac_/
Twitter: https://twitter.com/mathemaniacyt
Patreon: https://www.patreon.com/mathemaniac (support if you want to and can afford to!)

For my contact email, check my About page on a PC.

See you next time!</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="5480" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="166553"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:LoTaJE16uLk</id>
  <yt:videoId>LoTaJE16uLk</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCrlZs71h3mTR45FgQNINfrg</yt:channelId>
  <title>Why care about complex analysis? | Essence of complex analysis #1</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=LoTaJE16uLk"/>
  <author>
   <name>Mathemaniac</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCrlZs71h3mTR45FgQNINfrg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2021-08-02T14:00:09+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-09-27T14:15:43+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Why care about complex analysis? | Essence of complex analysis #1</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/LoTaJE16uLk?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i1.ytimg.com/vi/LoTaJE16uLk/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>Complex analysis is an incredibly powerful tool used in many applications, specifically in solving differential equations (Laplace's and others via inverse Fourier / Laplace transforms), and of course, fundamental theorem of algebra, Riemann hypothesis, as well as solving complicated integrals to show off!

This is the start of a series on complex analysis, which focuses on the visual insights rather than the more traditional rigorous approach, so it is not very likely that we will touch upon more advanced, yet very remarkable theorems in complex analysis, like Riemann mapping theorem, or the Picard's theorems. This is more likely of more use to the applied mathematicians, physicists and engineers, at least in the first few videos, simply because the interesting theorems are most likely pushed towards the end, and grouped as &quot;applications of complex analysis&quot;, like FTA and RH.

This is only currently my plan, and things are likely to change, but hopefully this is the backbone of what's coming next. I might not be uploading like weekly, but hopefully as frequently as I hope. 

Videos mentioned:
https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLiaHhY2iBX9g6KIvZ_703G3KJXapKkNaF (Welch Labs complex numbers playlist)
https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0z1fIsUNhO4 (Möbius transformations video)
https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=b8_3PFjiJvY (Zach Star complex derivatives)
https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLSQl0a2vh4HC5feHa6Rc5c0wbRTx56nF7 (Khan academy playlist on vector calculus)
https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLHXZ9OQGMqxfW0GMqeUE1bLKaYor6kbHa (Dr Trefor Bazett’s playlist on vector calculus)

Some (sort of) unexpected applications / connections to complex analysis:
https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Joukowsky_transform (historical aerofoil application)
http://math.colorado.edu/~kstange/papers/notes-Spin.pdf (Relationship between Möbius map and special relativity)

Other than commenting on the video, you are very welcome to fill in a Google form linked below, which helps me make better videos by catering for your math levels:
https://forms.gle/QJ29hocF9uQAyZyH6

If you want to know more interesting Mathematics, stay tuned for the next video!

SUBSCRIBE and see you in the next video!

If you are wondering how I made all these videos, even though it is stylistically similar to 3Blue1Brown, I don't use his animation engine Manim, but I will probably reveal how I did it in a potential subscriber milestone, so do subscribe!

Social media:

Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/mathemaniacyt
Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/_mathemaniac_/
Twitter: https://twitter.com/mathemaniacyt
Patreon: https://www.patreon.com/mathemaniac (support if you want to and can afford to!)

For my contact email, check my About page on a PC.

See you next time!</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="2800" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="56438"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:ism2SfZgFJg</id>
  <yt:videoId>ism2SfZgFJg</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCrlZs71h3mTR45FgQNINfrg</yt:channelId>
  <title>Green's functions: the genius way to solve DEs</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ism2SfZgFJg"/>
  <author>
   <name>Mathemaniac</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCrlZs71h3mTR45FgQNINfrg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2021-07-20T14:00:15+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-06-02T02:24:37+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Green's functions: the genius way to solve DEs</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/ism2SfZgFJg?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i2.ytimg.com/vi/ism2SfZgFJg/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>Green's functions is a very powerful and clever technique to solve many differential equations, and since differential equations are the language of lots of physics, including both classical mechanics, electrodynamics, and even quantum field theory, so it is important to know how it works. Of course, this includes some explanation and perhaps a pretty different motivation for Dirac delta function, which is pretty weird, but also not really when you think about it a different way. 

Correction: in 19:11, the Green's function lacks a factor of 1/m.

This video simply aims to introduce the Green's functions, what it is supposed to do, how the motivation of it all comes to be, and why it works. If you do need a lot more than introductory knowledge on Green's functions, and you are comfortable in basic differential equation solving, here are some links:

https://brilliant.org/wiki/greens-functions-in-physics/ (not sponsored)
https://www.roe.ac.uk/japwww/teaching/fourier/fourier_lectures_part4.pdf
My further write-up on the examples of Green's functions (how to find): https://drive.google.com/file/d/1D6E857eTvqM1CQgS1vYwcLqhLeGFL-aV/view?usp=sharing

For those who want some answers for the exercise towards the end of Chapter 3, i.e. around 15:47:

Essentially, what I intended was that using that momentum change = integral of force over small period of time, you can obtain the first answer (by a similar definition of delta function in 1D), and I am expecting &quot;point impulse / impulse&quot; on Q2.

For Q3: It is supposed to be that &quot;applied force can be thought of as a 'continuous sum' of point impulses&quot;.

For Q4: the Green's function describes the displacement of the oscillator after we apply an impulse. For this reason, Green's function is usually called the &quot;impulse response&quot;.

For Q5: Exactly copying the &quot;adding different charge distributions (implies) adding up the electric potential&quot;, so in this case, &quot;adding different forces (implies) adding up the displacement&quot;

For Q6: From the formula that x(t) = int G(t, tau)*F(tau) d(tau), we can interpret that the displacement is a continuous sum of the impulse responses.

I stopped saying anything more because (1) the video is already very long, (2) this video assumes only basic knowledge of calculus (it is actually better if you don't know too much of the rigour in real analysis, since this is really hand-wavy - and it has to be! Otherwise this would be a lecture in distribution theory, which I am not quite well-versed in), and (3) this really just aims to provide motivation for Green's functions and doing examples would make this more &quot;textbook-y&quot; than it already is.

Of course, the link to the Wikipedia table of Green's functions:
https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Green%27s_function#Table_of_Green's_functions

Note: they don't state the boundary / initial conditions explicitly, and they don't even use x and xi, or t and tau, usually just their difference. Usually it is that the Green's functions vanish when the position is far away from the origin, and for those involving time, 0 before time tau, assuming that tau is greater than 0 (the so-called &quot;advanced&quot; Green's function)

A little bit of remark after viewing the video once again: in some places, it is a little bit quick, so please treat yourself by pausing if necessary: YouTube allows you to do so! In my defense, different people require different time to pause, and also I don't want too much of dead air, so... that is probably also how a lot of other math videos on YouTube are doing right now.

Video chapters:
00:00 Introduction
01:01 Linear differential operators
03:54 Dirac delta &quot;function&quot;
09:56 Principle of Green's functions
15:50 Sadly, DE is not as easy

Other than commenting on the video, you are very welcome to fill in a Google form linked below, which helps me make better videos by catering for your math levels:
https://forms.gle/QJ29hocF9uQAyZyH6

If you want to know more interesting Mathematics, stay tuned for the next video!

SUBSCRIBE and see you in the next video!

If you are wondering how I made all these videos, even though it is stylistically similar to 3Blue1Brown, I don't use his animation engine Manim, but I will probably reveal how I did it in a potential subscriber milestone, so do subscribe!

Social media:

Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/mathemaniacyt
Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/_mathemaniac_/
Twitter: https://twitter.com/mathemaniacyt
Patreon: https://www.patreon.com/mathemaniac (support if you want to and can afford to!)
Ko-fi: https://ko-fi.com/mathemaniac

For my contact email, check my About page on a PC.

See you next time!</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="11852" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="394346"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:o4ELd69ZgcI</id>
  <yt:videoId>o4ELd69ZgcI</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCrlZs71h3mTR45FgQNINfrg</yt:channelId>
  <title>From miller to entering Cambridge at age 40 - George Green</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=o4ELd69ZgcI"/>
  <author>
   <name>Mathemaniac</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCrlZs71h3mTR45FgQNINfrg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2021-06-30T15:00:12+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-09-26T17:08:57+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>From miller to entering Cambridge at age 40 - George Green</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/o4ELd69ZgcI?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i4.ytimg.com/vi/o4ELd69ZgcI/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>This is the legend of George Green (1793 - 1841), a mathematician / physicist, &quot;son of a miller&quot;. First time going outside to film, and I only have my phone, so I'm really sorry that the video quality is not very good.

Green's theorem, identities, and functions are immensely useful in 19th century physics, and even in the 20th century for quantum electrodynamics, but not a lot of people know who this person is, unless you have been to college or uni. When Albert Einstein, Julian Schwinger, Lord Kelvin, Sturm and Liouville all speak very highly of Green, yet not everyone knows who he is, is a little bit sad... This is really an injustice, so I hope to bring this mathematician to more attention so that people recognise his efforts in mathematical physics. 

This video was made because I remember my lecturer talked about George Green only being a miller while he discovered Green's theorem, so I decided to look more into the story and continued to be amazed. Hopefully you are as well!

(Please don't tell the Cambridge University Library about this, because I don't think posting stuff about the library on the internet is allowed. Shhhhh...)

This is hopefully a new side of Mathemaniac you haven't seen before, but the next video is going to be a more typical one. There are loads of stuff that I came across in the research, primarily by reading Cannell's biography, that I haven't put into the video, just because I don't feel like this is too relevant to the whole story, but this is just to tell you that there is a lot more history going on behind the scenes, e.g. why did Green use Leibniz notation throughout the paper, while the majority of the UK was still using Newton's notation? If you want to know, refer to the biography!

Correction: 9:25 The German journal name should be Klassiker der Exacten Wissenschaf*t*en instead.

SOURCES:
1) Cannell, D. M., and Society for Industrial Applied Mathematics, George Green, Mathematician &amp; Physicist, 1793-1841 : the Background to His Life and Work, 2nd ed. (Philadelphia: Society for Industrial and Applied Mathematics, 2001)

2) &quot;The Green of Green's functions&quot; from the University of Nottingham: https://www.nottingham.ac.uk/physics/documents/historical/greenphystoday1203.pdf

3) &quot;An Essay on the Application of Mathematical Analysis to the Theories of Electricity and Magnetism&quot; by George Green, online here: https://arxiv.org/pdf/0807.0088.pdf

WHAT'S USED IN THIS VIDEO:
1) Einstein in Nottingham (on YouTube): https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=161UNSza_qk
Note: This is not really the instance where he said &quot;Green was 20 years ahead of his time&quot;, but the only footage I could find that sort of represents Einstein's visit to Nottingham back then.

2) Music used: 
Nine Lives - Unicorn Heads
Night Run Away -  An Jone
Wolf Moon - Unicorn Heads
(All from YouTube Audio Library)

FURTHER READING:
1) George Green: An Enigmatic Mathematician, by D.M. Cannell: https://www.jstor.org/stable/2589050?seq=13#metadata_info_tab_contents

2) Einstein's Blackboard (Periodic Videos): https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=KIwpGEvmgvs
Other than commenting on the video, you are very welcome to fill in a Google form linked below, which helps me make better videos by catering for your math levels:
https://forms.gle/QJ29hocF9uQAyZyH6

3) Math/Maths History Tour of Nottingham - George Green: Miller, Mathematician, and Physicist: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vK9NQ6e6rng

4) Green's Functions (Sixty Symbols): https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ji-i6XCkgC0
Note: Yes, I know this is similar to what I did in this video, but hopefully slightly more researched, and a completely different style.

If you want to know more interesting Mathematics, stay tuned for the next video!

SUBSCRIBE and see you in the next video!

If you are wondering how I made all these videos, even though it is stylistically similar to 3Blue1Brown, I don't use his animation engine Manim, but I will probably reveal how I did it in a potential subscriber milestone, so do subscribe!

Social media:

Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/mathemaniacyt
Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/_mathemaniac_/
Twitter: https://twitter.com/mathemaniacyt
Patreon: https://www.patreon.com/mathemaniac (support if you want to and can afford to!)

For my contact email, check my About page on a PC.

See you next time!</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="927" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="14825"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:UB8N8wbUSWA</id>
  <yt:videoId>UB8N8wbUSWA</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCrlZs71h3mTR45FgQNINfrg</yt:channelId>
  <title>Solved simply: the impossible integral</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=UB8N8wbUSWA"/>
  <author>
   <name>Mathemaniac</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCrlZs71h3mTR45FgQNINfrg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2021-04-16T15:00:13+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-06-25T08:58:00+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Solved simply: the impossible integral</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/UB8N8wbUSWA?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i2.ytimg.com/vi/UB8N8wbUSWA/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>Yes, it can't be done using substitution, by parts or changing variables (and using the Jacobian); but there is a very clever trick to actually compute this integral, which is attributed to Crofton, an English mathematician.

This clever trick only requires the law of total expectation and some very simple algebraic manipulations, and is very elegant in solving this very complicated integral, and it is incredibly powerful in the sense that it can be used in much more general situations, not just this integral - when we want an average of some quantities (which needs to be a bounded symmetric function of n points), we can use the Crofton's differential equation already to convert the problem to the average quantity when 1 point is on the boundary of the domain. In this case, the differential equation is easy since we already know that the average distance is proportional to the radius.

The problem can be made even more interesting when we think of higher dimensions: what about the average distance in a unit ball, or an n-dimensional ball? The calculations might be a bit tedious, but doable, and it again simply relies on the Crofton's differential equation. The only difficult part would be to figure out the limits of integration and the Jacobian determinant when using higher-dimensional spherical polar coordinates, and you can see that in the sources below.

Even if you don't know the Jacobian, or multiple integrals, you can still at least understand the clever trick behind this, which is the more important message of this video.

I currently have plenty of video ideas, but none of them really forms fully into a plan yet, so if you do have any video ideas, drop a comment below!

SOURCE FOR THIS VIDEO SERIES:

https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/abs/10.1080/07468342.1997.11973860 [The paper that I'm following, with a bit of biological motivation of the problem]

https://www.jstor.org/stable/2589434?seq=1#metadata_info_tab_contents (a more technical version for Crofton's differential equation)

If you want to know the higher-dimensional analog of spherical polar coordinates, and possibly want to derive the average distance in n-dimensional ball yourself, you can see the exercise 5.19 in Chapter 4 (Multiple integrals) on page 268 of C.H. Edwards, Jr., Advanced Calculus of Several Variables, Academic Press, San Diego, 1973

Other than commenting on the video, you are very welcome to fill in a Google form linked below, which helps me make better videos by catering for your math levels:
https://forms.gle/QJ29hocF9uQAyZyH6

If you want to know more interesting Mathematics, stay tuned for the next video!

SUBSCRIBE and see you in the next video!

If you are wondering how I made all these videos, even though it is stylistically similar to 3Blue1Brown, I don't use his animation engine Manim, but I will probably reveal how I did it in a potential subscriber milestone, so do subscribe!

Social media:

Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/mathemaniacyt
Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/_mathemaniac_/
Twitter: https://twitter.com/mathemaniacyt
Patreon: https://www.patreon.com/mathemaniac (support if you want to and can afford to!)

For my contact email, check my About page on a PC.

See you next time!</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="1366" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="35158"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
</feed>
