<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<rdf:RDF
 xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
 xmlns="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/"
 xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
 xmlns:taxo="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/taxonomy/"
 xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
 xmlns:syn="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
 xmlns:admin="http://webns.net/mvcb/"
>

<channel rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/">
<title>physics.ins-det updates on arXiv.org</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">Physics -- Instrumentation and Detectors (physics.ins-det) updates on the arXiv.org e-print archive</description>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:date>2022-11-03T20:30:00-05:00</dc:date>
<dc:publisher>help@arxiv.org</dc:publisher>
<dc:subject>Physics -- Instrumentation and Detectors</dc:subject>
<syn:updateBase>1901-01-01T00:00+00:00</syn:updateBase>
<syn:updateFrequency>1</syn:updateFrequency>
<syn:updatePeriod>daily</syn:updatePeriod>
<items>
 <rdf:Seq>
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01505" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01606" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01655" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01913" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2205.01822" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2209.14111" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.16418" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.00764" />
 </rdf:Seq>
</items>
<image rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif" />
</channel>
<image rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif">
<title>arXiv.org</title>
<url>http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif</url>
<link>http://arxiv.org/</link>
</image>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01505">
<title>Implicit Neural Representation as a Differentiable Surrogate for Photon Propagation in a Monolithic Neutrino Detector. (arXiv:2211.01505v1 [physics.ins-det])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01505</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Optical photons are used as signal in a wide variety of particle detectors.
Modern neutrino experiments employ hundreds to tens of thousands of photon
detectors to observe signal from millions to billions of scintillation photons
produced from energy deposition of charged particles. These neutrino detectors
are typically large, containing kilotons of target volume, with different
optical properties. Modeling individual photon propagation in form of look-up
table requires huge computational resources. As the size of a table increases
with detector volume for a fixed resolution, this method scales poorly for
future larger detectors. Alternative approaches such as fitting a polynomial to
the model could address the memory issue, but results in poorer performance.
Both look-up table and fitting approaches are prone to discrepancies between
the detector simulation and the data collected. We propose a new approach using
SIREN, an implicit neural representation with periodic activation functions, to
model the look-up table as a 3D scene and reproduces the acceptance map with
high accuracy. The number of parameters in our SIREN model is orders of
magnitude smaller than the number of voxels in the look-up table. As it models
an underlying functional shape, SIREN is scalable to a larger detector.
Furthermore, SIREN can successfully learn the spatial gradients of the photon
library, providing additional information for downstream applications. Finally,
as SIREN is a neural network representation, it is differentiable with respect
to its parameters, and therefore tunable via gradient descent. We demonstrate
the potential of optimizing SIREN directly on real data, which mitigates the
concern of data vs. simulation discrepancies. We further present an application
for data reconstruction where SIREN is used to form a likelihood function for
photon statistics.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Lei_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Minjie Lei&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Tsang_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ka Vang Tsang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Gasiorowski_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Sean Gasiorowski&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Li_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Chuan Li&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Nashed_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Youssef Nashed&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Petrillo_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Gianluca Petrillo&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Piazza_O/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Olivia Piazza&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Ratner_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Daniel Ratner&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Terao_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Kazuhiro Terao&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01606">
<title>Study on the reusability of fluorescent nuclear track detectors using optical bleaching. (arXiv:2211.01606v1 [physics.ins-det])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01606</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Fluorescent nuclear track detectors (FNTDs) based on Al${_2}$O${_3}$:C,Mg
crystals are luminescent detectors that can be used for dosimetry and detection
of charged particles and neutrons. These detectors can be utilised for imaging
applications where a reasonably high track density, approximately of the order
of 1 $\times$ $10^4$ tracks in an area of 100 $\times$ 100 $\mu$m$^2$, is
required. To investigate the reusability of FNTDs for imaging applications, we
present an approach to perform optical bleaching under the required track
density conditions. The reusability was assessed through seven
irradiation-bleaching cycles. For the irradiation, the studied FNTD was exposed
to alpha-particles from an $^{241}$Am radioactive source. The optical bleaching
was performed by means of ultraviolet laser light with a wavelength of 355 nm.
Three dedicated regions on a single FNTD with different accumulated track
densities and bleaching conditions were investigated. After every
irradiation-bleaching cycle, signal-to-noise ratio was calculated to evaluate
FNTD performance. It is concluded that FNTDs can be reused at least seven times
for applications where accumulation of a high track density is required.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Muneem_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Abdul Muneem&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Yoshida_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Junya Yoshida&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Ekawa_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Hiroyuki Ekawa&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Hino_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Masahiro Hino&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Hirota_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Katsuya Hirota&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Ichikawa_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Go Ichikawa&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Kasagi_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ayumi Kasagi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Kitaguchi_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Masaaki Kitaguchi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Kodaira_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Satoshi Kodaira&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Mishima_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Kenji Mishima&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Nabi_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jameel-Un Nabi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Nakagawa_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Manami Nakagawa&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Sakashita_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Michio Sakashita&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Saito_N/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Norihito Saito&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Saito_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Takehiko R. Saito&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Wada_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Satoshi Wada&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Yasuda_N/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Nakahiro Yasuda&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01655">
<title>$B\rho$-defined isochronous mass spectrometry: a new approach for high-precision mass measurements of short-lived nuclei. (arXiv:2211.01655v1 [physics.ins-det])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01655</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;A novel technique for broadband high-precision mass measurements of
short-lived exotic nuclides is reported. It is based on the isochronous mass
spectrometry (IMS) and realizes simultaneous determinations of revolution time
and velocity of short-lived stored ions at the cooler storage ring CSRe in
Lanzhou. The new technique, named as the $B\rho$-defined IMS or $B\rho$-IMS,
boosts the efficiency, sensitivity, and accuracy of mass measurements, and is
applied here to measure masses of neutron-deficient $fp$-shell nuclides. In a
single accelerator setting, masses of $^{46}$Cr, $^{50}$Fe and $^{54}$Ni are
determined with relative uncertainties of (5~-~6)$\times10^{-8}$, thereby
improving the input data for testing the unitarity of the
Cabibbo-Kobayashi-Maskawa quark mixing matrix. This is the technique of choice
for future high-precision measurements of the most rarely produced
shortest-lived nuclides.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Wang_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;M. Wang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Zhang_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;M. Zhang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Zhou_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;X. Zhou&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Zhang_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Y. H. Zhang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Litvinov_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yu. A. Litvinov&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Xu_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;H. S. Xu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Chen_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;R. J. Chen&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Deng_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;H. Y. Deng&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Fu_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;C. Y. Fu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Ge_W/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;W. W. Ge&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Li_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;H. F. Li&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Liao_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;T. Liao&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Litvinov_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;S. A. Litvinov&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Shuai_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;P. Shuai&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Shi_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;J. Y. Shi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Si_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;M. Si&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Sidhu_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;R. S. Sidhu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Song_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Y. N. Song&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Sun_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;M. Z. Sun&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Suzuki_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;S. Suzuki&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Wang_Q/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Q. Wang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Xing_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Y. M. Xing&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Xu_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;X. Xu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Yamaguchi_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;T. Yamaguchi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Yan_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;X. L. Yan&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Yang_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;J. C. Yang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Yuan_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Y. J. Yuan&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Zeng_Q/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Q. Zeng&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Zhou_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;X. H. Zhou&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01913">
<title>Surface-barrier detector with smoothly tunable thickness of depleted layer for study of ionization loss and dechanneling length of negatively charged particles channeling in a crystal. (arXiv:2211.01913v1 [physics.ins-det])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01913</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;A new method for the experimental study of ionization loss of relativistic
negatively charged particles moving in a crystal in the channeling regime using
a semiconductor surface-barrier detector with smoothly tunable thickness of the
depleted layer is proposed. The ionization loss can only be measured in the
depleted layer of the detector. The thickness of the depleted layer in a flat
semiconductor detector can be smoothly regulated by the value of the bias
voltage of the detector. Therefore, the energy distribution of the ionization
loss of relativistic particles which cross the detector and move in the
channeling regime in the detector crystal can be measured along the path of the
particles at variation of the bias voltage of the detector. Ionization loss
spectra should be different for channeling and nonchanneling particles, and
both fractions can be determined. The application of a Si surface-barrier
detector-target is considered. Measurements with such a detector would make it
possible to study: the energy distribution of ionization loss of channeling
negatively and positively charged particles; spatial distribution of ionization
loss as a function of the path length of channeling particles; the dechanneling
length of negatively charged particles; and to clear up the role of
rechanneling of the particles in the crystal. Comparison of experimental data
with calculations can help to develop a description of the dynamics of motion
of negatively charged particles channeling in a crystal. A better understanding
of the dechanneling length properties can be useful in the production of
positrons and other particles such as neutrons by an electron beam in crystals,
and in the development of crystalline undulators, and at a crystal-based
extraction of electron beams from a synchrotron.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Shchagin_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;A.V. Shchagin&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Kube_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;G. Kube&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Strokov_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;S.A. Strokov&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Lauth_W/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;W. Lauth&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2205.01822">
<title>Study of Hybrid MicroPattern Gas Detector with CsI Photocathode For Super Tau-Charm Factory RICH. (arXiv:2205.01822v2 [physics.ins-det] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2205.01822</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Super tau-Charm facility(STCF) is a future electron-position collider
operating at tau-Charm energy region aimed to study hadron structure and
spectroscopy. The baseline design of the STCF barrel particle
identification(PID) detector in the momentum range up to 2 GeV/c is provided by
a Ring Imaging Cherenkov Counter(RICH). The architecture of the RICH is an
approximately focusing design with liquid perfluorohexane sealed in the quartz
container as radiator and a hybrid combination of a CsI coated layers of THGEMs
and a Micromegas as the photo-electron detector. A 16*16 cm^2 prototype with
quartz radiator has been built and tested at DESY. It was stably operated with
10^5 effective gain. In this paper, the design, the performance, the
reconstruction algorithm and the systematic error for single photon electron
angular resolution in the aspect of RICH detectors are discusses.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Li_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ping Li&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Liu_Q/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Qian Liu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Liu_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jianbei Liu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Shao_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ming Shao&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Zhang_Z/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Zhiyong Zhang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Feng_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jianxin Feng&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Wang_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Anqi Wang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Hou_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Baolin Hou&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Zhao_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Lei Zhao&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Liu_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Hongbang Liu&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2209.14111">
<title>Report of the Instrumentation Frontier Working Group for Snowmass 2021. (arXiv:2209.14111v3 [hep-ex] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2209.14111</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Detector instrumentation is at the heart of scientific discoveries. Cutting
edge technologies enable US particle physics to play a leading role worldwide.
This report summarizes the current status of instrumentation for High Energy
Physics (HEP), the challenges and needs of future experiments and indicates
high priority research areas. The Snowmass Instrumentation Frontier studies
detector technologies and Research and Development (R&amp;amp;D) needed for future
experiments in collider physics, neutrino physics, rare and precision physics
and at the cosmic frontier. It is divided into more or less diagonal areas with
some overlap among a few of them. We lay out five high-level key messages that
are geared towards ensuring the health and competitiveness of the US detector
instrumentation community, and thus the entire particle physics landscape.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ex/1/au:+Barbeau_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Phillip S. Barbeau&lt;/a&gt; (1), &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ex/1/au:+Merkel_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Petra Merkel&lt;/a&gt; (2), &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ex/1/au:+Zhang_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jinlong Zhang&lt;/a&gt; (3), &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ex/1/au:+Acosta_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Darin Acosta&lt;/a&gt; (4), &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ex/1/au:+Affolder_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Anthony A. Affolder&lt;/a&gt; (5), &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ex/1/au:+Apresyan_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Artur Apresyan&lt;/a&gt; (2), &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ex/1/au:+Artuso_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Marina Artuso&lt;/a&gt; (6), &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ex/1/au:+Bhopatkar_V/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Vallary Bhopatkar&lt;/a&gt; (7), &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ex/1/au:+Butalla_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Stephen Butalla&lt;/a&gt; (8), &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ex/1/au:+Carini_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Gabriella A. Carini&lt;/a&gt; (9), &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ex/1/au:+Cecil_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Thomas Cecil&lt;/a&gt; (3), &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ex/1/au:+Connolly_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Amy Connolly&lt;/a&gt; (8), &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ex/1/au:+Dahl_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;C. Eric Dahl&lt;/a&gt; (2, 10), &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ex/1/au:+Deiana_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Allison Deiana&lt;/a&gt; (11), &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ex/1/au:+Dunne_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Katherine Dunne&lt;/a&gt; (12), &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ex/1/au:+Escobar_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Carlos O. Escobar&lt;/a&gt; (2), &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ex/1/au:+Estrada_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Juan Estrada&lt;/a&gt; (2), &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ex/1/au:+Fahim_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Farah Fahim&lt;/a&gt; (2), &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ex/1/au:+Fast_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;James E. Fast&lt;/a&gt; (13), &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ex/1/au:+Garcia_Sciveres_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Maurice Garcia-Sciveres&lt;/a&gt; (14), &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ex/1/au:+Guenette_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Roxanne Guenette&lt;/a&gt; (15), &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ex/1/au:+Hedges_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Michael T. Hedges&lt;/a&gt; (16), &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ex/1/au:+Irwin_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Kent Irwin&lt;/a&gt; (17), &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ex/1/au:+Karle_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Albrecht Karle&lt;/a&gt; (18), &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ex/1/au:+Ketchum_W/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Wes Ketchum&lt;/a&gt; (2), &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ex/1/au:+Kravitz_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Scott Kravitz&lt;/a&gt; (14), &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ex/1/au:+Lippincott_W/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;W. Hugh Lippincott&lt;/a&gt; (19), &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ex/1/au:+Maruyama_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Reina H. Maruyama&lt;/a&gt; (20), &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ex/1/au:+McIver_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jess McIver&lt;/a&gt; (21), &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ex/1/au:+Newcomer_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;F. Mitchell Newcomer&lt;/a&gt; (22), &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ex/1/au:+Parsons_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;John Parsons&lt;/a&gt; (23), &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ex/1/au:+Pyle_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Matt Pyle&lt;/a&gt; (24), &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ex/1/au:+Raaf_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jennifer L. Raaf&lt;/a&gt; (2), &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ex/1/au:+Rogan_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Chris Rogan&lt;/a&gt; (25), &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ex/1/au:+Sanchez_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Mayly C. Sanchez&lt;/a&gt; (26), &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ex/1/au:+Shipsey_I/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ian Shipsey&lt;/a&gt; (27), &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ex/1/au:+Surrow_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Bernd Surrow&lt;/a&gt; (28), &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ex/1/au:+Titov_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Maxim Titov&lt;/a&gt; (29), &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ex/1/au:+Vahsen_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Sven E. Vahsen&lt;/a&gt; (30), et al. (6 additional authors not shown)</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.16418">
<title>First results from a multiplexed and massive instrument with sub-electron noise Skipper-CCDs. (arXiv:2210.16418v2 [physics.ins-det] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.16418</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We present a new instrument composed of a large number of sub-electron noise
Skipper-CCDs operated with a two stage analog multiplexed readout scheme
suitable for scaling to thousands of channels. New, thick, $1.35$ Mpix sensors,
from a new foundry, are glued into a Multi-Chip Module (MCM) printed circuit
board on a ceramic substrate which has 16 sensors each. The instrument, that
can hold up-to 16 MCMs, a total of 256 Skipper-CCD sensors (called a
Super-Module with $\approx 130$ grams of active mass and $346$ Mpix), is part
of the R$\&amp;amp;$D effort of the OSCURA experiment which will have $\approx 94$
super-modules. Experimental results with $10$ MCMs and $160$ Skipper-CCDs
sensors are presented in this paper. This is already the largest ever build
instrument with single electron sensitivity CCDs using nondestructive readout,
both, in terms of active mass and number of channels.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Chierchie_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;F. Chierchie&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Chavez_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;C.R. Chavez&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Haro_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;M. Sofo Haro&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Moroni_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;G. Fernandez Moroni&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Cervantes_Vergara_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;B.A. Cervantes-Vergara&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Perez_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;S. Perez&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Estrada_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;J. Estrada&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Tiffenberg_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;J. Tiffenberg&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Uemura_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;S. Uemura&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Botti_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;A. Botti&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.00764">
<title>Exploration of different parameter optimization algorithms within the context of ACTS software framework. (arXiv:2211.00764v2 [hep-ex] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.00764</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Particle track reconstruction, in which the trajectories of charged particles
are determined, is a critical and time consuming component of the full event
reconstruction chain. The underlying software is complex and consists of a
number of mathematically intense algorithms, each dealing with a particular
tracking sub-process. These algorithms have many input parameters that need to
be supplied in advance. However, it is difficult to determine the configuration
of these parameters that produces the best performance. Currently, the input
parameter values are decided on the basis of prior experience or by the use of
brute force techniques. A parameter optimization approach that is able to
automatically tune these parameters for high performance is greatly desirable.
In the current work, we explore various machine learning based optimization
methods to devise a suitable technique to optimize parameters in the complex
track reconstruction environment. These methods are evaluated on the basis of a
metric that targets high efficiency while keeping the duplicate and fake rates
small. We focus on derivative free optimization approaches that can be applied
to problems involving non-differentiable loss functions. For our studies, we
consider the tracking algorithms defined within A Common Tracking Software
(ACTS) framework. We test our methods using simulated data from ACTS software
corresponding to the ACTS Generic detector and the ATLAS ITk detector
geometries.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ex/1/au:+Garg_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Rocky Bala Garg&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ex/1/au:+Hofgard_E/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Elyssa Hofgard&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ex/1/au:+Tompkins_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Lauren Tompkins&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ex/1/au:+Gray_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Heather Gray&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
</rdf:RDF>