<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<rdf:RDF
 xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
 xmlns="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/"
 xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
 xmlns:taxo="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/taxonomy/"
 xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
 xmlns:syn="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
 xmlns:admin="http://webns.net/mvcb/"
>

<channel rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/">
<title>hep-ph updates on arXiv.org</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">High Energy Physics - Phenomenology (hep-ph) updates on the arXiv.org e-print archive</description>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:date>2022-11-03T20:30:00-05:00</dc:date>
<dc:publisher>www-admin@arxiv.org</dc:publisher>
<dc:subject>High Energy Physics - Phenomenology</dc:subject>
<syn:updateBase>1901-01-01T00:00+00:00</syn:updateBase>
<syn:updateFrequency>1</syn:updateFrequency>
<syn:updatePeriod>daily</syn:updatePeriod>
<items>
 <rdf:Seq>
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01379" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01380" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01387" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01397" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01398" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01420" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01421" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01470" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01543" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01616" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01647" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01673" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01693" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01711" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01728" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01729" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01789" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01816" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01846" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01854" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01896" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01906" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01935" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01949" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01971" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.02010" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.02027" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.02028" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.02029" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.02030" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2105.09686" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2201.11637" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2202.01578" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2202.04498" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2205.02861" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2206.11442" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2207.00889" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2207.09910" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2208.00013" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2208.00416" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2208.04085" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2208.06986" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2208.13037" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2209.08215" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2209.13409" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.00510" />
 </rdf:Seq>
</items>
<image rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif" />
</channel>
<image rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif">
<title>arXiv.org</title>
<url>http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif</url>
<link>http://arxiv.org/</link>
</image>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01379">
<title>Dipole operators in Fierz identities. (arXiv:2211.01379v1 [hep-ph])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01379</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We study the contribution from dipole operators to one-loop Fierz identities
and provide the resulting QCD and QED shifts to the tree-level relations for
all four-fermion operators. The results simplify one-loop basis changes as well
as matching computations and allow one to consistently eliminate operators from
an operator basis which give rise to complications, e.g. traces involving
$\gamma_5$.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Aebischer_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jason Aebischer&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Pesut_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Marko Pesut&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Polonsky_Z/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Zachary Polonsky&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01380">
<title>Large-Scale $2+1$D $\mathrm{U}(1)$ Gauge Theory with Dynamical Matter in a Cold-Atom Quantum Simulator. (arXiv:2211.01380v1 [cond-mat.quant-gas])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01380</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;A major driver of quantum-simulator technology is the prospect of probing
high-energy phenomena in synthetic quantum matter setups at a high level of
control and tunability, thereby offering a venue complementary to dedicated
particle colliders. Here, we propose an experimentally feasible realization of
a large-scale $2+1$D $\mathrm{U}(1)$ gauge theory with dynamical matter and
gauge fields in a cold-atom quantum simulator with spinless bosons. We present
the full mapping of the corresponding Gauss&apos;s law onto the bosonic
computational basis. We then show that the target gauge theory can be
faithfully realized and stabilized by an emergent gauge protection term in a
two-dimensional single-species Bose--Hubbard optical Lieb superlattice with two
spatial periods along either direction, thereby requiring only moderate
experimental resources already available in current cold-atom setups. Using
infinite matrix product states, we calculate numerical benchmarks for adiabatic
sweeps and global quench dynamics that further confirm the fidelity of the
mapping. Our work brings quantum simulators of gauge theories a significant
step forward in terms of investigating particle physics in higher spatial
dimensions, and is readily implementable in existing cold-atom platforms.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Osborne_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jesse Osborne&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+McCulloch_I/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ian P. McCulloch&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Yang_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Bing Yang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Hauke_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Philipp Hauke&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Halimeh_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jad C. Halimeh&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01387">
<title>The persistent nonperturbative charm enigma. (arXiv:2211.01387v1 [hep-ph])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01387</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The question of the existence and possible magnitude of nonperturbative
(often called &quot;intrinsic&quot;) charm in the proton has long confounded attempts to
cleanly isolate such a contribution in global analyses of high-energy
experiments. In this letter, we show that the available (non)perturbative QCD
theory and hadronic data have still not developed to a sufficient level to
clearly resolve this problem. We highlight a number of challenging aspects that
must be confronted in extracting nonperturbative charm in PDF fits, and in so
doing, present an updated next-to-next-to-leading order CT analysis of fitted
charm, CT18 FC, which we also compare to recent studies. We outline the theory
developments and future data needed to make progress on this subject.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Guzzi_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Marco Guzzi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Hobbs_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;T. J. Hobbs&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Xie_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Keping Xie&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Huston_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Joey Huston&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Nadolsky_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Pavel Nadolsky&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Yuan_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;C.-P. Yuan&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01397">
<title>The fate of discrete torsion on resolved heterotic Z2xZ2 orbifolds using (0,2) GLSMs. (arXiv:2211.01397v1 [hep-th])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01397</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;This paper aims to shed light on what becomes of discrete torsion within
heterotic orbifolds when they are resolved to smooth geometries. Gauged Linear
Sigma Models (GLSMs) possessing (0,2) worldsheet supersymmetry are employed as
interpolations between them. This question is addressed for resolutions of the
non-compact C3/Z2xZ2 and the compact T6/Z2xZ2 orbifolds to keep track of local
and global aspects. The GLSMs associated with the non-compact orbifold with or
without torsion are to a large extent equivalent: only when expressed in the
same superfield basis, a field redefinition anomaly arises among them, which in
the orbifold limit reproduces the discrete torsion phases. Previously unknown,
novel resolution GLSMs for T6/Z2xZ2 are constructed. The GLSM associated with
the torsional compact orbifold suffers from mixed gauge anomalies, which need
to be cancelled by appropriate logarithmic superfield dependent FI-terms on the
worldsheet, signalling H-flux due to NS5-branes supported at the exceptional
cycles.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Faraggi_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;A.E. Faraggi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Nibbelink_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;S. Groot Nibbelink&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Heredia_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;M. Hurtado Heredia&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01398">
<title>Connecting small-scale to large-scale structures of fast neutrino-flavor conversion. (arXiv:2211.01398v1 [astro-ph.HE])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01398</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We present a systematic study of fast neutrino-flavor conversion (FFC) with
both small-scale and large-scale numerical simulations in spherical symmetry.
We find that FFCs can, in general, reach in a quasi-steady state, and these
features in the non-linear phase are not characterized by the growth rate of
FFC instability but rather angular structures of electron neutrino lepton
number (ELN) and heavy one (XLN). Our result suggests that neutrinos can almost
reach a flavor equipartition even in cases with low growth rate of instability
(e.g., shallow ELN crossing) and narrow angular regions (in momentum space)
where flavor conversions occur vigorously. This exhibits that ELN and XLN
angular distributions can not provide a sufficient information to determine
total amount of flavor conversion in neutrinos and antineutrinos of all
flavors. Based on the results of our numerical simulations, we provide a new
approximate scheme of FFC that is designed so that one can easily incorporate
effects of FFCs in existing classical neutrino transport codes for the study of
core-collapse supernova (CCSN) and binary neutron star merger (BNSM). The
scheme has an ability to capture key features of quasi-steady state of FFCs
without solving quantum kinetic neutrino transport, which will serve to
facilitate access to FFCs for CCSN and BNSM theorists.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Nagakura_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Hiroki Nagakura&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Zaizen_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Masamichi Zaizen&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01420">
<title>A Complete Set of the Dimension-8 Green&apos;s Basis Operators in the Standard Model Effective Field Theory. (arXiv:2211.01420v1 [hep-ph])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01420</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We present a complete and independent off-shell Green&apos;s basis of the
dimension 8 operators in the Standard Model effective field theory (SMEFT). We
propose an off-shell amplitude formalism such that this new kind of amplitudes
has a one-to-one correspondence to general operators carrying all kinds of
redundancies. The advantage of such formalism is that all kinds of redundancies
can be formulated explicitly in terms of the off-shell spinors and thus be
removed systematically from the exhaustive list of the general off-shell
amplitudes. Following such procedure, redundant operators can be reduced to the
ones with the only redundancy from the equation of motion kept, the Green&apos;s
basis. We find there are (993+1649) independent (on-shell + off-shell)
operators for one generation of fermions and (44807+66197) ones for three
generations at the dimension 8. This systematic method can be applied to obtain
the Green&apos;s basis at any mass dimension for general EFTs.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Ren_Z/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Zhe Ren&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Yu_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jiang-Hao Yu&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01421">
<title>Modern Machine Learning for LHC Physicists. (arXiv:2211.01421v1 [hep-ph])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01421</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Modern machine learning is transforming particle physics, faster than we can
follow, and bullying its way into our numerical tool box. For young researchers
it is crucial to stay on top of this development, which means applying
cutting-edge methods and tools to the full range of LHC physics problems. These
lecture notes are meant to lead students with basic knowledge of particle
physics and significant enthusiasm for machine learning to relevant
applications as fast as possible. They start with an LHC-specific motivation
and a non-standard introduction to neural networks and then cover
classification, unsupervised classification, generative networks, and inverse
problems. Two themes defining much of the discussion are well-defined loss
functions reflecting the problem at hand and uncertainty-aware networks. As
part of the applications, the notes include some aspects of theoretical LHC
physics. All examples are chosen from particle physics publications of the last
few years. Given that these notes will be outdated already at the time of
submission, the week of ML4Jets 2022, they will be updated frequently.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Plehn_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Tilman Plehn&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Butter_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Anja Butter&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Dillon_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Barry Dillon&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Krause_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Claudius Krause&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01470">
<title>Invisible Charm Exotica. (arXiv:2211.01470v1 [hep-ph])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01470</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;One possible interpretation of two narrow $\Omega^0_c$ states reported by the
LHCb Collaboration at CERN in 2017 is that they are pentaquarks belonging to a
$\overline{\boldsymbol{15}}$ exotic SU(3) representation, as predicted by the
Chiral Quark--Soliton Model. If so, there must exist a number of other exotic
states since the model predicts three different $\overline{\boldsymbol{15}}$
multiplets of heavy baryons. We show, that depending on the soliton spin $J$,
these states are either very narrow or very broad. This explains why they might
have escaped experimental observation. Furthermore, we show that the lightest
members of these multiplets are stable against two body strong decays.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Praszalowicz_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Micha&amp;#x142; Prasza&amp;#x142;owicz&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Kucab_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Maciej Kucab&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01543">
<title>Custodial Symmetry Violation in Scalar Extensions of the Standard Model. (arXiv:2211.01543v1 [hep-ph])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01543</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The new measurement of the W boson mass from the CDF collaboration shows a
significant tension with the Standard Model prediction, which evidences
violation of custodial symmetry in the scalar sector. We study the scalar
extensions of the Standard Model, which can be categorized into two classes,
scalar sector with custodial symmetry (Georgi-Machacek model and its
generalizations) and scalar sector without custodial symmetry, and explore how
these extensions fit to the electroweak precision data and the CDF new $m_W$ .
The favored oblique parameters are coming from either the large mass splitting
in the multiplet via the loop contribution or the large vacuum expectation
value which breaks custodial symmetry at the tree level. In particular, we find
that $\mathcal{O}(100)$ GeV new particles are allowed in the scalar extension
scenarios.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Song_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Huayang Song&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Wan_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xia Wan&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Yu_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jiang-Hao Yu&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01616">
<title>Towards identifying the minimal flavor symmetry behind neutrino oscillations. (arXiv:2211.01616v1 [hep-ph])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01616</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Current neutrino oscillation data indicate that the $3\times 3$
Pontecorvo-Maki-Nakagawa-Sakata matrix $U$ exhibits a $\mu$-$\tau$ flavor
interchange symmetry $|U^{}_{\mu i}| = |U^{}_{\tau i}|$ (for $i = 1, 2, 3$) as
a good approximation. In particular, the T2K measurement implies that the
maximal neutrino mixing angle $\theta^{}_{23}$ and the CP-violating phase
$\delta$ should be close to $\pi/4$ and $-\pi/2$, respectively. Behind these
observations lies a minimal flavor symmetry -- - the effective Majorana
neutrino mass term keeps invariant under the transformations $\nu^{}_{e \rm L}
\to (\nu^{}_{e \rm L})^c$, $\nu^{}_{\mu \rm L} \to (\nu^{}_{\tau \rm L})^c$ and
$\nu^{}_{\tau \rm L} \to (\nu^{}_{\mu \rm L})^c$. Extending this flavor
symmetry to the canonical seesaw mechanism, we find that the $R$-matrix
describing the strength of weak charged-current interactions of heavy Majorana
neutrinos satisfies $|R^{}_{\mu i}| = |R^{}_{\tau i}|$ as a consequence of
$|U^{}_{\mu i}| = |U^{}_{\tau i}|$. This result can be used to set a new upper
bound, which is about three orders of magnitude more stringent than before, on
the flavor mixing factor associated with the charged-lepton-flavor-violating
decay mode $\tau^- \to e^- + \gamma$.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Xing_Z/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Zhi-zhong Xing&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01647">
<title>Harmonics of Parton Saturation in Lepton-Jet Correlations at the EIC. (arXiv:2211.01647v1 [hep-ph])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01647</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Parton saturation is one of the most intriguing phenomena in the high energy
nuclear physics research frontier, especially in the upcoming era of the
Electron-Ion Collider (EIC). The lepton-jet correlation in deep inelastic
scattering provides us with a new gateway to the parton saturation at the EIC.
In particular, we demonstrate that azimuthal angle anisotropies of the
lepton-jet correlation are sensitive to the strength of the saturation momentum
in the EIC kinematic region. In contrast to the predictions based on the
collinear framework calculation, significant nuclear modification of the
anisotropies is observed when we compare the saturation physics results in e +
p and e + Au scatterings. By measuring these harmonic coefficients at the EIC,
one can conduct quantitative analysis in different collisional systems and
unveil compelling evidence for saturation effects.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Tong_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xuan-Bo Tong&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Xiao_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Bo-Wen Xiao&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Zhang_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yuan-Yuan Zhang&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01673">
<title>The QCD topological susceptibility at high temperatures via staggered fermions spectral projectors. (arXiv:2211.01673v1 [hep-lat])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01673</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The QCD topological observables are essential inputs to obtain theoretical
predictions about axion phenomenology, which are of utmost importance for
current and future experimental searches for this particle. Among them, we
focus on the topological susceptibility, related to the axion mass. We present
lattice results for the topological susceptibility in QCD at high temperatures
obtained by discretizing this observable via spectral projectors on eigenmodes
of the staggered Dirac operator, and we compare them with those obtained with
the standard gluonic definition. The adoption of the spectral discretization is
motivated by the large lattice artifacts affecting the standard gluonic
susceptibility, related to the choice of non-chiral fermions in the lattice
action.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-lat/1/au:+Athenodorou_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Andreas Athenodorou&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-lat/1/au:+Bonanno_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Claudio Bonanno&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-lat/1/au:+Bonati_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Claudio Bonati&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-lat/1/au:+Clemente_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Giuseppe Clemente&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-lat/1/au:+DAngelo_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Francesco D&amp;#x27;Angelo&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-lat/1/au:+DElia_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Massimo D&amp;#x27;Elia&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-lat/1/au:+Maio_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Lorenzo Maio&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-lat/1/au:+Martinelli_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Guido Martinelli&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-lat/1/au:+Sanfilippo_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Francesco Sanfilippo&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-lat/1/au:+Todaro_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Antonino Todaro&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01693">
<title>Study on $\Lambda nn$ Bound State and Resonance. (arXiv:2211.01693v1 [nucl-th])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01693</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We perform the ab initio no-core shell model (NCSM) calculation to
investigate the bound state problem of the three-body $\Lambda nn$ system in
chiral next-to-next-to-leading-order NN and chiral leading-order YN
interactions. The calculations show that no $\Lambda nn$ bound state exists,
but predict a low-lying $\Lambda nn$ resonant state near the threshold with the
energy of $E_r= 0.124$ MeV and the width of about $\Gamma=1.161$ MeV. In
searching for $\Lambda nn$ resonances, we extend the NCSM calculation to the
continuum state by employing the J-matrix formalism in the scattering theory
with the hyperspherical oscillator basis.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/nucl-th/1/au:+Htun_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Thiri Yadanar Htun&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/nucl-th/1/au:+Yan_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yupeng Yan&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01711">
<title>Charmed-strange tetraquarks and their decays in the potential quark model. (arXiv:2211.01711v1 [hep-ph])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01711</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;In the framework of a nonrelativistic potential quark model, we investigate
the mass spectrum of the $1S$-wave charmed-strange tetraquark states of
$cn\bar{s}\bar{n}$ and $cs\bar{n}\bar{n}$ ($n=u$ or $d$) systems. The
tetraquark system is solved by a correlated Gaussian method. With the same
parameters fixed by the meson spectra, we obtained the mass spectra for the
$1S$-wave tetraquark states. Furthermore, based on the predicted tetraquark
spectra we estimate their rearrangement decays in a quark-exchange model. We
find that the resonances $X_0(2900)^0$ and $T^a_{c\bar{s}0}(2900)^{++/0}$
reported from LHCb may be assigned to be the lowest $1S$-wave tetraquark states
$\bar{T}_{cs0}^f(2818)$ and $T^{a}_{c\bar{s}0}(2828)$ classified in the quark
model, respectively. It also allows us to extract the couplings for the initial
tetraquark states to their nearby $S$-wave interaction channels. We find that
some of these couplings turn out to be sizeable. For $\bar{T}_{cs0}^f(2818)$
and $T^{a}_{c\bar{s}0}(2828)$ their couplings to $D^*\bar{K}^*$ and $D^*K^*$,
respectively, are found to be large. Following the picture of the wavefunction
renormalization for the near-threshold strong $S$-wave interactions, the
sizeable coupling strengths can be regarded as an indication of their dynamic
origins as candidates for hadronic molecules. Furthermore, our predictions
suggest that signals for the $1S$-wave charmed-strange tetraquark states can
also be searched in the other channels, such as $D^0K^+$, $D^+K^+$,
$D^{*+}K^-$, $D^{*+}K^+$, $D^{*0}K^+$, $D^0\bar{K}^{*0}$, $D_s^+\rho^0$, etc.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Liu_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Feng-Xiao Liu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Ni_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ru-Hui Ni&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Zhong_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xian-Hui Zhong&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Zhao_Q/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Qiang Zhao&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01728">
<title>Primordial non-gaussianity up to all orders: theoretical aspects and implications for primordial black hole models. (arXiv:2211.01728v1 [astro-ph.CO])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01728</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We develop an exact formalism for the computation of the abundance of
primordial black holes (PBHs) in the presence of local non-gaussianity (NG) in
the curvature perturbation field. For the first time, we include NG going
beyond the widely used quadratic and cubic approximations, and consider a
completely generic functional form. Adopting threshold statistics of the
compaction function, we address the computation of the abundance both for
narrow and broad power spectra. While our formulas are generic, we discuss
explicit examples of phenomenological relevance considering the physics case of
the curvaton field. We carefully assess under which conditions the conventional
perturbative approach can be trusted. In the case of a narrow power spectrum,
this happens only if the perturbative expansion is pushed beyond the quadratic
order (with the optimal order of truncation that depends on the width of the
spectrum). Most importantly, we demonstrate that the perturbative approach is
intrinsically flawed when considering broad spectra, in which case only the
non-perturbative computation captures the correct result. Finally, we describe
the phenomenological relevance of our results for the connection between the
abundance of PBHs and the stochastic gravitational wave (GW) background related
to their formation. As NGs modify the amplitude of perturbations necessary to
produce a given PBHs abundance and boost PBHs production at large scales for
broad spectra, modelling these effects is crucial to connect the PBH scenario
to its signatures at current and future GWs experiments.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Ferrante_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Giacomo Ferrante&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Franciolini_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Gabriele Franciolini&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Iovino_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Antonio Junior Iovino&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Urbano_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Alfredo Urbano&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01729">
<title>A seesaw model for large neutrino masses in concordance with cosmology. (arXiv:2211.01729v1 [hep-ph])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01729</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Cosmological constraints on the sum of the neutrino masses can be relaxed if
the number density of active neutrinos is reduced compared to the standard
scenario, while at the same time keeping the effective number of neutrino
species $N_{\rm eff}\approx 3$ by introducing a new component of dark
radiation. We discuss a UV complete model to realise this idea, which
simultaneously provides neutrino masses via the seesaw mechanism. It is based
on a $U(1)$ symmetry in the dark sector, which can be either gauged or global.
In addition to heavy seesaw neutrinos, we need to introduce $\mathcal{O}(10)$
generations of massless sterile neutrinos providing the dark radiation. Then we
can accommodate active neutrino masses with $\sum m_\nu \sim 1$ eV, in the
sensitivity range of the KATRIN experiment. We discuss the phenomenology of the
model and identify the allowed parameter space. We argue that the gauged
version of the model is preferred, and in this case the typical energy scale of
the model is in the 10 MeV to few GeV range.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Escudero_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Miguel Escudero&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Schwetz_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Thomas Schwetz&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Terol_Calvo_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jorge Terol-Calvo&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01789">
<title>Probing hadron mass spectrum in dense two-color QCD with linear sigma model. (arXiv:2211.01789v1 [hep-ph])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01789</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We investigate modifications of hadron masses at finite quark chemical
potential in two-flavor and two-color QCD, of which the data are available from
lattice simulations, within a linear sigma model based on approximate
Pauli-Gursey $SU(4)$ symmetry. The model describes not only ground-state scalar
diquarks and pseudo-scalar mesons but also the excited pseudo-scalar diquarks
and scalar mesons; each ground-state diquark (meson) has the corresponding
excited diquark (hadron) with opposite parity as a chiral partner. Effects of
chiral symmetry breaking and diquark condensates are incorporated by a
mean-field treatment. We show that various mixings among the hadrons, which are
triggered by the breakdown of baryon number conservation in the superfluid
phase, lead to a rich hadron mass spectrum. We discuss the influence of
$U(1)_A$ anomaly on the density dependence of the mass spectrum and also
manifestations of the chiral partner structures as density increases in the
superfluid phase. The predicted hadron masses are expected to provide future
lattice simulations with useful information on such symmetry properties in
dense two-color QCD.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Suenaga_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Daiki Suenaga&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Murakami_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Kotaro Murakami&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Itou_E/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Etsuko Itou&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Iida_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Kei Iida&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01816">
<title>Study of light sterile neutrino at the long-baseline experiment options at KM3NeT. (arXiv:2211.01816v1 [hep-ph])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01816</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;In this paper, we study the capability of different long-baseline experiment
options at the KM3NeT facility i.e., P2O, Upgraded P2O and P2SO to probe the
light sterile neutrino and compare their sensitivity with DUNE. The option P2O
will have neutrinos from a 90 KW beam at Protvino to be detected at the ORCA
detector, the Upgraded P2O will have neutrinos from the upgraded 450 KW beam to
be detected at the ORCA detector and the option P2SO will have neutrinos from a
450 KW beam to be detected at the upgraded Super-ORCA detector. All these
options will have a baseline around 2595 km. Our results show that the
experiments at the KM3NeT (DUNE) would be more sensitive if the value of
$\Delta m^2_{41}$ is around 10 (1) eV$^2$. Our results also show that the role
of near detector is very important for the study of sterile neutrinos and
addition of near detector improves the sensitivity as compared to only far
detector for 3+1 scenario. Among the three options at KM3NeT, the sensitivity
of P2O and updated P2O is limited and sensitivity of P2SO is either comparable
or better than DUNE.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Singha_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Dinesh Kumar Singha&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Ghosh_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Monojit Ghosh&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Majhi_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Rudra Majhi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Mohanta_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Rukmani Mohanta&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01846">
<title>Evidence for the molecular nature of $D_{s0}^*(2317)$ and $D_{s1}(2460)$ and the production yield of $K_{c\bar{c}}(4180)$ as a $D\bar{D}K$ bound state in inclusive $e^+e^-\to c\bar{c}$ collisions. (arXiv:2211.01846v1 [hep-ph])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01846</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Searching for exotic multiquark states and elucidating their nature remains a
central topic in understanding quantum chromo dynamics--the underlying theory
of the strong interaction. Two of the most studied such states are the
charmed-strange states $D_{s0}^*(2317)$ and $D_{s1}(2460)$. In this work, we
show for the first time that their production yields in inclusive $e^+e^-\to
c\bar{c}$ productions near $\sqrt{s}=10.6$ GeV measured by the BaBar
Collaboration can be well explained in the molecular picture, which provide a
highly nontrivial verification of their nature being $DK/D^*K$ molecules. In
addition, we predict the production yield of the $D\bar{D}K$ three-body bound
state, $K_{c\bar{c}}(4180)$, in $e^+e^-\to c\bar{c}$ collisions and find that
it is within the reach of the ongoing Belle II experiment.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Wu_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Tian-Chen Wu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Geng_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Li-Sheng Geng&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01854">
<title>Ultralight dark matter searches at the sub-Hz frontier with atom multi-gradiometry. (arXiv:2211.01854v1 [hep-ph])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01854</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Single-photon atom gradiometry is a powerful experimental technique that can
be employed to search for the oscillation of atomic transition energies induced
by ultralight scalar dark matter (ULDM). In the sub-Hz regime the background is
expected to be dominated by gravity gradient noise (GGN), which arises as a
result of mass fluctuations around the experiment. In this work we model the
GGN as surface Rayleigh waves and construct a likelihood-based analysis that
consistently folds GGN into the sensitivity estimates of vertical atom
gradiometers in the frequency window between 1 mHz and 1 Hz. We show that in
certain geological settings GGN can be significantly mitigated when operating a
multi-gradiometer configuration, which consists of three or more atom
interferometers in the same baseline. Multi-gradiometer experiments, such as
future versions of AION and MAGIS-100, have the potential to probe regions of
scalar ULDM parameter space in the sub-Hz regime that have not been excluded by
existing experiments.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Badurina_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Leonardo Badurina&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Gibson_V/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Valerie Gibson&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+McCabe_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Christopher McCabe&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Mitchell_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jeremiah Mitchell&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01896">
<title>The $X(3872)$, the $X(4014)$, and their bottom partners at finite temperature. (arXiv:2211.01896v1 [hep-ph])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01896</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The properties of the $X(3872)$ and its spin partner, the $X(4014)$, are
studied both in vacuum and at finite temperature. Using an effective hadron
theory based on the hidden-gauge Lagrangian, the $X(3872)$ is dynamically
generated from the $s$-wave rescattering of a pair of pseudoscalar and vector
charm mesons. By incorporating the thermal spectral functions of open charm
mesons, the calculation is extended to finite temperature. Similarly, the
properties of the $X(4014)$ are obtained out of the scattering of charm vector
mesons. By applying heavy-quark flavor symmetry, the properties of their bottom
counterparts in the axial-vector and tensor channels are also predicted. All
the dynamically generated states show a decreasing mass and acquire an
increasing decay width with temperature, following the trend observed in their
meson constituents. These results are relevant in relativistic heavy-ion
collisions at high energies, in analyses of the collective medium formed after
hadronization or in femtoscopic studies, and can be tested in lattice-QCD
calculations exploring the melting of heavy mesons at finite temperature.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Montana_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Gloria Monta&amp;#xf1;a&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Ramos_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Angels Ramos&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Tolos_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Laura Tolos&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Torres_Rincon_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Juan M. Torres-Rincon&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01906">
<title>$U(1)_{Y&apos;}$ universal seesaw. (arXiv:2211.01906v1 [hep-ph])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01906</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We extend the $SU(3)_c \times SU(2)_L \times U(1)_Y$ standard model by a
$U(1)_{Y&apos;}$ gauge symmetry. Three right-handed neutrinos are introduced to
cancel the gauge anomaly. One Higgs singlet is responsible for spontaneously
breaking the $U(1)_{Y&apos;}$ symmetry while the standard model Higgs doublet does
not carry any $U(1)_{Y&apos;}$ charges. The down-type quarks, up-type quarks,
charged leptons and neutral neutrinos obtain their Dirac masses through four
types of dimension-5 operators constructed by the fermion doublets and singlets
with the Higgs doublet and singlet. This effective theory is realized in three
renormalizable contexts with heavy fermion singlets, scalar doublets and
fermion doublets. The heavy fermion singlets and doublets for generating the
neutrino masses also accommodate a successful Dirac leptogenesis to explain the
baryon asymmetry in the universe.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Chen_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Su-Ping Chen&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Gu_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Pei-Hong Gu&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01935">
<title>Discovering a new well: Decaying dark matter with profile likelihoods. (arXiv:2211.01935v1 [astro-ph.CO])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01935</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;A large number of studies, all using Bayesian parameter inference from Markov
Chain Monte Carlo methods, have constrained the presence of a decaying dark
matter component. All such studies find a strong preference for either very
long-lived or very short-lived dark matter. However, in this letter, we
demonstrate that this preference is due to parameter volume effects that drive
the model towards the standard $\Lambda$CDM model, which is known to provide a
good fit to most observational data.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using profile likelihoods, which are free from volume effects, we instead
find that the best-fitting parameters are associated with an intermediate
regime where around $3 \%$ of cold dark matter decays just prior to
recombination. With two additional parameters, the model yields an overall
preference over the $\Lambda$CDM model of $\Delta \chi^2 \approx -2.8$ with
\textit{Planck} and BAO and $\Delta \chi^2 \approx -7.8$ with the SH0ES $H_0$
measurement, while only slightly alleviating the $H_0$ tension. Ultimately, our
results reveal that decaying dark matter is more viable than previously
assumed, and illustrate the dangers of relying exclusively on Bayesian
parameter inference when analysing extensions to the $\Lambda$CDM model.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Holm_E/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Emil Brinch Holm&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Herold_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Laura Herold&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Hannestad_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Steen Hannestad&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Nygaard_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Andreas Nygaard&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Tram_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Thomas Tram&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01949">
<title>Impact of multiple modes on the evolution of self-interacting axion condensate around rotating black holes. (arXiv:2211.01949v1 [gr-qc])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01949</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Ultra-light particles, such as axions, form a macroscopic condensate around a
highly spinning black hole by the superradiant instability. Due to its
macroscopic nature, the condensate opens the possibility of detecting the axion
through gravitational wave observations. However, the precise evolution of the
condensate must be known for the actual detection. For future observation, we
numerically study the influence of the self-interaction, especially interaction
between different modes, on the evolution of the condensate in detail. First,
we focus on the case when condensate starts with the smallest possible angular
quantum number. For this case, we perform the non-linear calculation and show
that the dissipation induced by the mode interaction is strong enough to
saturate the superradiant instability, even if the secondary cloud starts with
quantum fluctuations. Our result indicates that explosive phenomena such as
bosenova do not occur in this case. We also show that the condensate settles to
a quasi-stationary state mainly composed of two modes, one with the smallest
angular quantum number for which the superradiant instability occurs and the
other with the adjacent higher angular quantum number. We also study the case
when the condensate starts with the dominance of the higher angular quantum
number. We show that the dissipation process induced by the mode coupling does
not occur for small gravitational coupling. Therefore, bosenova might occur in
this case.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Omiya_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Hidetoshi Omiya&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Takahashi_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Takuya Takahashi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Tanaka_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Takahiro Tanaka&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Yoshino_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Hirotaka Yoshino&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01971">
<title>Detecting nuclear mass distribution in isobar collisions via charmonium. (arXiv:2211.01971v1 [hep-ph])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01971</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The collective properties of final state hadrons produced in the high
statistics $_{44}^{96}$Ru+$_{44}^{96}$Ru and $_{40}^{96}$Zr+$_{40}^{96}$Zr
collisions at $\sqrt{s_\mathrm{NN}} = 200~\mathrm{GeV}$ are found to be
significantly different. Such differences were argued to be precise probes of
the difference in nucleon distribution in the isobar nuclei. We investigate the
$J/\psi$ production in the isobar collision via a relativistic transport
approach. By comparing the isobar systems according to equal centrality bin and
equal multiplicity bin, we find that the yield ratio of $J/\psi$ is sensitive
to the differences in both the number of binary collisions and the medium
evolution. Besides, the elliptic flow $v_2$ of $J/\psi$ is qualitatively
different from the light hadrons, and the ratio between Ru+Ru and Zr+Zr
collisions is sensitive to the medium evolution. The charmonium production
provides an independent probe to study the nucleon distribution in the isobar
system.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Zhao_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jiaxing Zhao&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Shi_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Shuzhe Shi&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.02010">
<title>On ALP scenarios and GRB 221009A. (arXiv:2211.02010v1 [astro-ph.HE])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.02010</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The extraordinarily bright gamma-ray burst GRB 221009A was observed by a
large number of observatories, from radio frequencies to gamma-rays. Of
particular interest are the reported observations of photon-like air showers of
very high energy: an 18 TeV event in LHAASO and a 251 TeV event at Carpet-2.
Gamma rays at these energies are expected to be absorbed by pair-production
events on background photons when travelling intergalactic distances. Several
works have sought to explain the observations of these events, assuming they
originate from GRB 221009A, by invoking axion-like particles (ALPs). We
reconsider this scenario and account for astrophysical uncertainties due to
poorly known magnetic fields and background photon densities. We find that,
robustly, the ALP scenario cannot simultaneously account for an 18 TeV and a
251 TeV photon from GRB 221009A.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Carenza_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Pierluca Carenza&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Marsh_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;M.C. David Marsh&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.02027">
<title>Charged Higgs boson signatures via $pp \rightarrow H^\pm bj$ in 2HDM type-I. (arXiv:2211.02027v1 [hep-ph])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.02027</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;In this study, we investigate the light charged Higgs boson production via
$pp \rightarrow H^\pm bj$ in the type-I configuration of the Two-Higgs Doublet
Model (2HDM). In the viable parameter space, assuming either $h$ or $H$ is the
SM-like Higgs boson observed at the Large Hadron Collider (LHC), we focus on
the bosonic decays $H^\pm \rightarrow W^\pm A/h$ and examine the final states
arising from the above charged Higgs production and decay. We show here that
the suggested signatures can have sizable rates, reaching the pb level, when
the top quark is produced on-shell and $\tan\beta$ is small.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Benbrik_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;R. Benbrik&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Krab_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;M. Krab&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Manaut_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;B. Manaut&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Ouchemhou_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;M. Ouchemhou&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.02028">
<title>Neutrino Origin of LHAASO&apos;s 18 TeV GRB221009A Photon. (arXiv:2211.02028v1 [hep-ph])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.02028</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;LHAASO collaboration detected photons with energy above 10 TeV from the most
recent gamma-ray burst (GRB), GRB221009A. Given the redshift of this event,
$z\sim 0.15$, photons of such energy are expected to interact with the diffuse
extragalactic background light (EBL) well before reaching Earth. In this paper
we provide the first neutrino-related explanation of the most energetic 18 TeV
event reported by LHAASO. We find that the minimal viable scenario involves
both mixing and transition magnetic moment portal between light and sterile
neutrinos. The production of sterile neutrinos occurs efficiently via mixing
while the transition magnetic moment portal governs the decay rate in the
parameter space where tree-level decays via mixing to non-photon final states
are suppressed. Our explanation of this event, while being consistent with the
terrestrial constraints, points to the non-standard cosmology.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Brdar_V/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Vedran Brdar&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Li_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ying-Ying Li&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.02029">
<title>Optimal transport for a global event description at high-intensity hadron colliders. (arXiv:2211.02029v1 [hep-ph])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.02029</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The CERN Large Hadron Collider was built to uncover fundamental particles and
their interactions at the energy frontier. Upon entering its High Luminosity
phase at the end of this decade, the unprecedented interaction rates when
colliding two proton bunches will pose a significant challenge to the
reconstruction algorithms of experiments such as ATLAS and CMS. We propose an
algorithm with a greatly enhanced capability of disentangling individual proton
collisions to obtain a new global event description, considerably improving
over the current state-of-the-art. Employing a metric inspired by optimal
transport problems as the cost function of a graph neural network enhanced with
attention mechanisms, our algorithm is able to compare two particle collections
with different noise levels, thereby learning to correctly flag particles
originating from the main proton interaction amidst products from up to 200
simultaneous pileup collisions. The adoption of such an algorithm will lead to
a quasi-global sensitivity improvement for searches for new physics phenomena
and will enable precision measurements at the percent level in the High
Luminosity era of the Large Hadron Collider.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Gouskos_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Loukas Gouskos&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Iemmi_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Fabio Iemmi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Liechti_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Sascha Liechti&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Maier_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Benedikt Maier&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Mikuni_V/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Vinicius Mikuni&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Qu_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Huilin Qu&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.02030">
<title>Improved muon decay simulation with McMule and Geant4. (arXiv:2211.02030v1 [hep-ex])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.02030</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The physics programme of the MEG II experiment can be extended with the
search for new invisible particles produced in rare muon decays. The hunt for
such elusive signals requires accurate simulations to characterise the detector
response and estimate the experimental sensitivity. This work presents an
improved simulation of muon decay in MEG II, based on McMule and Geant4.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ex/1/au:+Gurgone_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;A. Gurgone&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ex/1/au:+Papa_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;A. Papa&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ex/1/au:+Schwendimann_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;P. Schwendimann&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ex/1/au:+Signer_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;A. Signer&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ex/1/au:+Ulrich_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Y. Ulrich&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ex/1/au:+Baldini_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;A. M. Baldini&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ex/1/au:+Cei_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;F. Cei&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ex/1/au:+Chiappini_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;M. Chiappini&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ex/1/au:+Francesconi_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;M. Francesconi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ex/1/au:+Galli_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;L. Galli&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ex/1/au:+Grassi_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;M. Grassi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ex/1/au:+Nicolo_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;D. Nicol&amp;#xf2;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ex/1/au:+Signorelli_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;G. Signorelli&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2105.09686">
<title>Contact Interactions at Future Circular Collider based Muon-Proton Colliders. (arXiv:2105.09686v4 [hep-ph] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2105.09686</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Recently proposed Future Circular Collider based muon-proton colliders will
allow investigating lepton-hadron interactions at the highest center-of-mass
energy. In this study, we investigate the potential of these colliders for a
four-fermion contact interactions search. Regarding the constructive and
destructive interferences of contact interactions, we estimated discovery,
observation, and exclusion limits on the compositeness scale for the left-left,
right-right, left-right, and right-left helicity structures. This study&apos;s
findings show that the FCC-based {\mu}p colliders have great potential for
investigating four-fermion contact interactions.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Aydin_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Gural Aydin&lt;/a&gt; (Hatay Mustafa Kemal University), &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Gunaydin_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yusuf Oguzhan G&amp;#xfc;naydin&lt;/a&gt; (Kahramanmaras S&amp;#xfc;tc&amp;#xfc; Imam University), &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Sahin_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Mehmet Sahin&lt;/a&gt; (Usak University), &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Sultansoy_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Saleh Sultansoy&lt;/a&gt; (TOBB ETU), &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Tarakcioglu_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Mehmet T&amp;#xfc;rker Tarakcioglu&lt;/a&gt; (Kahramanmaras S&amp;#xfc;tc&amp;#xfc; Imam University)</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2201.11637">
<title>Determining Feynman integrals with only input from linear algebra. (arXiv:2201.11637v3 [hep-ph] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2201.11637</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We find that all Feynman integrals (FIs), having any number of loops, can be
completely determined once linear relations between FIs are provided.
Therefore, FIs computation is conceptually changed to a linear algebraic
problem. Examples up to 5 loops are given to verify this observation. As a
byproduct, we get a powerful method to calculate perturbative corrections in
quantum field theory.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Liu_Z/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Zhi-Feng Liu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Ma_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yan-Qing Ma&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2202.01578">
<title>Projected Sensivity to Dimension-6 Triple Gauge Couplings at the FCC-hh. (arXiv:2202.01578v2 [hep-ph] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2202.01578</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;In this study, we investigate the process $pp \rightarrow W^{\pm} \gamma$ for
the physics potential of the FCC-hh with $\sqrt{s}=100$ TeV to examine the
anomalous $WW\gamma$ couplings defined by three CP-conserving and two
CP-violating effective operators of dimension-6. The analysis containing the
realistic detector effects is carried out in the mode where $W^{\pm}$ bosons in
the final state decay into the leptonic channel. The best sensitivities
obtained from the process $pp \rightarrow W^{\pm} \gamma$ on the anomalous
couplings $C_{WWW}/ \Lambda^{2}$ and $C_{W,B}/ \Lambda^{2}$ determined by
CP-conserving effective Lagrangians are $[-0.01; 0.01]$ TeV$^{-2}$ and $[-0.88;
0.88]$ TeV$^{-2}$, while $C_{\tilde{W}WW}/ \Lambda^{2}$ and $C_{\tilde{W}}/
\Lambda^{2}$ couplings defined by CP-violating effective Lagrangian are
obtained as $[-0.03; 0.03]$ TeV$^{-2}$ and $[-0.47; 0.47]$ TeV$^{-2}$ at the
FCC-hh with $\sqrt{s}=100$ TeV, $L_{int}=30$ ab$^{-1}$. However, if the
systematic uncertainty is included, we obtain reduced sensitivities on the
anomalous $WW\gamma$ coupling . The results are compared for assumed
systematics of $5\%$ and $10\%$.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Ari_V/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;V. Ari&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Cetinkaya_V/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;V. Cetinkaya&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Koksal_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;M. K&amp;#xf6;ksal&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Cakir_O/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;O. Cakir&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2202.04498">
<title>Analytic thin wall false vacuum decay rate. (arXiv:2202.04498v4 [hep-th] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2202.04498</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We derive a closed-form false vacuum decay rate at one loop in the thin wall
limit, where the true and false vacua are nearly degenerate. We obtain the
bounce configuration in $D$ dimensions, together with the Euclidean action with
a higher order correction, counter-terms and renormalization group running. We
extract the functional determinant via the Gel&apos;fand-Yaglom theorem for low and
generic orbital multipoles. The negative and zero eigenvalues appear for low
multipoles and the translational zeroes are removed. We compute the
fluctuations for generic multipoles, multiply and regulate the orbital modes.
We find an explicit finite renormalized decay rate in $D = 3, 4$ and give a
closed-form expression for the finite functional determinant in any dimension.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Ivanov_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Aleksandar Ivanov&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Matteini_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Marco Matteini&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Nemevsek_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Miha Nemev&amp;#x161;ek&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Ubaldi_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Lorenzo Ubaldi&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2205.02861">
<title>Lund and Cambridge multiplicities for precision physics. (arXiv:2205.02861v2 [hep-ph] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2205.02861</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We revisit the calculation of the average jet multiplicity in high-energy
collisions. First, we introduce a new definition of (sub)jet multiplicity based
on Lund declusterings obtained using the Cambridge jet algorithm. We develop a
new systematic resummation approach. This allows us to compute both the Lund
and the Cambridge average multiplicities to next-to-next-to-double (NNDL)
logarithmic accuracy in electron-positron annihilation, an order higher in
accuracy than previous works in the literature. We match our resummed
calculation to the exact NLO ($\mathcal{O}(\alpha_s^2)$) result, showing
predictions for the Lund multiplicity at LEP energies with theoretical
uncertainties up to $50\%$ smaller than the previous state-of-the-art. Adding
hadronisation corrections obtained by Monte Carlo simulations, we also show a
good agreement with existing Cambridge multiplicity data. Finally, to highlight
the flexibility of our method, we extend the Lund multiplicity calculation to
hadronic collisions where we reach next-to-double logarithmic accuracy for
colour singlet production.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Medves_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Rok Medves&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Soto_Ontoso_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Alba Soto-Ontoso&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Soyez_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Gregory Soyez&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2206.11442">
<title>Charmonium dissociation at high baryon chemical potential. (arXiv:2206.11442v2 [nucl-th] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2206.11442</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We study the charmonium dissociation in the hot medium with finite baryon
chemical potential $\mu_B$. Charmonium bound states are dissociated in the
medium by the color screening effect and the random scatterings with thermal
partons, which are included in the real and imaginary parts of the potential
respectively. $J/\psi$ fraction in the $c\bar c$ pair defined to be the quantum
overlap between the wave package and the wave function of $J/\psi$ eigenstate
decreases with time due to the complex potentials. When $\mu_B$ is large
compared with the medium temperature, the Deybe mass is increased evidently. We
consider $\mu_B$-dependent Deybe mass in both real and imaginary parts of the
potential to calculate the $J/\psi$ survival probability in the static medium
and the Bjorken medium. $J/\psi$ survival probability is reduced evidently by
the $\mu_B$ effect at low temperatures available in the medium produced in Beam
Energy Scan experiments, while this effect becomes not apparent at high
temperatures.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/nucl-th/1/au:+Tong_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Bo Tong&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/nucl-th/1/au:+Chen_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Baoyi Chen&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2207.00889">
<title>Lattice Fermionic Casimir effect in a Slab Bag and Universality. (arXiv:2207.00889v4 [hep-lat] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2207.00889</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We apply the physically more appealing MIT Bag boundary conditions to study
the Casimir effect on the lattice. Employing the formalism of &lt;a href=&quot;/abs/2005.10758&quot;&gt;arXiv:2005.10758&lt;/a&gt;
to calculate the Casimir energy for free lattice fermions, we show that the
results for the naive, Wilson and overlap fermions match the continuum
expressions precisely in the zero lattice spacing limit, as expected from
universality. In contrast to &lt;a href=&quot;/abs/2005.10758&quot;&gt;arXiv:2005.10758&lt;/a&gt; where the result for the naive
fermions rapidly oscillates with the lattice size for both, the periodic (P)
and anti-periodic (AP) boundary conditions, no oscillations are observed with
the lattice size. Furthermore, the apparent violation of the universality for
naive fermion in &lt;a href=&quot;/abs/2005.10758&quot;&gt;arXiv:2005.10758&lt;/a&gt; is shown to be cured by applying suitable
series extrapolation techniques, thus demonstrating that the Casimir energy for
the naive fermions with periodic/antiperiodic boundary conditions agrees with
the results for other free lattice fermions, and can as well be used to obtain
the results for the Dirac fermion in the zero limit of the lattice spacing.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-lat/1/au:+Mandlecha_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yash V. Mandlecha&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-lat/1/au:+Gavai_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Rajiv V. Gavai&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2207.09910">
<title>Analysis of the $X(3960)$ and related tetraquark molecular states via the QCD sum rules. (arXiv:2207.09910v3 [hep-ph] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2207.09910</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;In this work, we study the $D\bar{D}$, $DD$, $D\bar{D}_s$, $DD_s$,
$D_s\bar{D}_s$ and $D_sD_s$ tetraquark molecular states with the
$J^{PC}=0^{++}$ via the QCD sum rules. The prediction $M_{D_s\bar {D}_s} =
3.98\pm0.10\, \rm{GeV}$ is in very good agreement with the experimental value
$M_{X(3960)} = 3956 \pm 5\pm 10 \,\rm{MeV}$ from the LHCb collaboration and
supports assigning the $X(3960)$ as the $D_s^+D_s^-$ molecular state with the
$J^{PC}=0^{++}$. We take account of our previous works on the four-quark states
consisting of two color-neutral clusters, and acquire the mass spectrum of the
ground state hidden-charm and doubly-charm tetraquark molecular states.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Xin_Q/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Qi Xin&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Wang_Z/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Zhi-Gang Wang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Yang_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xiao-Song Yang&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2208.00013">
<title>Electroweak corrections and shower effects to Higgs production in association with two jets at the LHC. (arXiv:2208.00013v2 [hep-ph] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2208.00013</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We present an implementation of the full electroweak $H+2~\text{jets}$
production process at hadron colliders in the framework of the
$\tt{POWHEG~BOX}$, a public tool for the matching of fixed-order perturbative
calculations with parton shower generators. Our implementation allows for the
simultaneous description of vector-boson fusion and Higgsstrahlung
contributions. NLO-QCD and electroweak corrections are taken into account and
matched to QCD and QED showers, respectively. The size of the fixed-order QCD
and electroweak corrections is found to be moderate, but dependent on the
considered selection cuts. QCD shower effects slightly modify the NLO-QCD
predictions and are most pronounced for distributions of non-tagging jets. The
impact of QED shower effects is small.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Jager_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Barbara J&amp;#xe4;ger&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Scheller_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Johannes Scheller&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2208.00416">
<title>Blast from the past II: Constraints on heavy neutral leptons from the BEBC WA66 beam dump experiment. (arXiv:2208.00416v4 [hep-ph] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2208.00416</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We revisit the search for heavy neutral leptons with the Big European Bubble
Chamber in the 1982 proton beam dump experiment at CERN, focussing on those
heavier than the kaon and mixing only with the tau neutrino, as these are far
less constrained than their counterparts with smaller mass or other mixings.
Recasting the previous search in terms of this model and including additional
production and decay channels yields the strongest bounds to date, up to the
tau mass. This applies also to our updated bounds on the mixing of heavy
neutral leptons with the electron neutrino.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Barouki_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ryan Barouki&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Marocco_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Giacomo Marocco&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Sarkar_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Subir Sarkar&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2208.04085">
<title>Four-top quark physics at the LHC. (arXiv:2208.04085v4 [hep-ex] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2208.04085</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The production of four top quarks is a rare process in the Standard Model
that provides unique opportunities and sensitivity to Standard Model
observables including potential enhancement from many popular new physics
extensions. This article summarises the latest experimental measurements of the
four-top quark production cross section at the LHC. An overview of the
interpretations of the experimental results in terms of the top quark Yukawa
coupling and limits on physics beyond the Standard Model is also given as well
as prospects for future measurements and opportunities offered by this
challenging final state.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ex/1/au:+Blekman_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Freya Blekman&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ex/1/au:+Deliot_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Fr&amp;#xe9;deric D&amp;#xe9;liot&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ex/1/au:+Dutta_V/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Valentina Dutta&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ex/1/au:+Usai_E/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Emanuele Usai&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2208.06986">
<title>Relativistic correction to the dissociation temperature of B_c mesons in the hot medium. (arXiv:2208.06986v2 [nucl-th] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2208.06986</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;By solving two body Dirac equations with potentials at finite temperature, we
calculated the dissociation temperature T_d of B_c mesons in the quark-gluon
plasma. It is found that the T_d becomes higher with the relativistic
correction than the T_d from the Schroedinger equation. Both the short range
interaction and the constant term of the potential at the long-range scale have
a contribution to the shift of T_d, while the spin interaction is negligible.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/nucl-th/1/au:+Li_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Guangyu Li&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/nucl-th/1/au:+Chen_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Baoyi Chen&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/nucl-th/1/au:+Liu_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yunpeng Liu&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2208.13037">
<title>Beyond DGLAP improved saturation model. (arXiv:2208.13037v3 [hep-ph] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2208.13037</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We present a modification of the DGLAP improved saturation model with respect
to the nonlinear correction (NLC). The GLR-MQ improved saturation model is
considered by employing the parametrization of proton structure function due to
the Laplace transforms method, which preserves its behavior success in the low
and high $Q^{2}$ regions. We show that the geometric scaling holds for the
GLR-MQ improved model in a wide kinematic region $rQ_{s}$. These results are
comparable with other models in a wide kinematic region $rQ_{s}$. The behavior
of the dipole cross sections, with respect to the GLR-MQ improved saturation
model, are comparable with the Color Glass Condensate (CGC) model. The model
describes the dipole cross sections in the inclusive and diffractive processes.
We also compare the nonlinear corrections to the impact-parameter dependent
saturation (IP-Sat) model with the impact-parameter dependent color glass
condensate (b-CGC) dipole model. Finally, we consider the linear and nonlinear
corrections to the IP Non-Sat model. These results provide a benchmark for
further investigation of QCD at small $x$ in future experiments such as the
Large Hadron Collider and Future Circular Collider projects.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Boroun_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;G.R.Boroun&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2209.08215">
<title>Report of the Topical Group on Cosmic Probes of Dark Matter for Snowmass 2021. (arXiv:2209.08215v2 [hep-ph] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2209.08215</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Cosmological and astrophysical observations currently provide the the only
robust, positive evidence for dark matter. Cosmic probes of dark matter, which
seek to determine the fundamental properties of dark matter through
observations of the cosmos, have emerged as a promising means to reveal the
nature of dark matter. This report summarizes the current status and future
potential of cosmic probes to inform our understanding of the fundamental
nature of dark matter in the coming decade.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Drlica_Wagner_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Alex Drlica-Wagner&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Prescod_Weinstein_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Chanda Prescod-Weinstein&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Yu_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Hai-Bo Yu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Albert_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Andrea Albert&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Banerjee_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Arka Banerjee&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Baryakhtar_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Masha Baryakhtar&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Bechtol_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Keith Bechtol&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Bird_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Simeon Bird&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Birrer_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Simon Birrer&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Bringmann_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Torsten Bringmann&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Caputo_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Regina Caputo&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Chakrabarti_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Sukanya Chakrabarti&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Chen_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Thomas Y. Chen&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Croon_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Djuna Croon&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Cyr_Racine_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Francis-Yan Cyr-Racine&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Dawson_W/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;William A. Dawson&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Dvorkin_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Cora Dvorkin&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Gluscevic_V/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Vera Gluscevic&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Gilman_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Daniel Gilman&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Grin_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Daniel Grin&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Hlozek_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ren&amp;#xe9;e Hlo&amp;#x17e;ek&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Leane_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Rebecca K. Leane&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Li_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ting S. Li&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Mao_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yao-Yuan Mao&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Meyers_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Joel Meyers&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Mishra_Sharma_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Siddharth Mishra-Sharma&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Munoz_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Julian B. Mu&amp;#xf1;oz&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Munshi_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ferah Munshi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Nadler_E/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ethan O. Nadler&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Parikh_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Aditya Parikh&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Perez_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Kerstin Perez&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Peter_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Annika H. G. Peter&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Profumo_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Stefano Profumo&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Schutz_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Katelin Schutz&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Sehgal_N/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Neelima Sehgal&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Simon_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Joshua D. Simon&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Sinha_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Kuver Sinha&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Valluri_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Monica Valluri&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Wechsler_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Risa H. Wechsler&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2209.13409">
<title>Looking for the effects of New Physics in the $\Lambda_b \longrightarrow \Lambda_c(\to \Lambda \pi) \ell \nu $ decay mode. (arXiv:2209.13409v2 [hep-ph] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2209.13409</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;One of the most pragmatic ways to look for the effects of New Physics at low
energy scales is to study a detailed angular distribution of various decay
modes, and in particular those based on $b\to c\ell\bar \nu_\ell$. In this
paper we focus onto $\Lambda_b \longrightarrow \Lambda_c(\to \Lambda \pi) \ell
\nu$ in a generic effective theory setup in which, besides the Standard Model,
we allow for all the possible covariant dimension-six effective operators
capturing the contributions arising at high energy scales, beyond the Standard
Model. We list a number of observables that could be used as a diagnostic tool
to check for the presence of New Physics and to discriminate among its various
scenarios. We also briefly comment on $\Lambda_c \to \Lambda l\nu$.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Becirevic_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Damir Be&amp;#x10d;irevi&amp;#x107;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Jaffredo_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Florentin Jaffredo&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.00510">
<title>Systematic analysis of doubly charmed baryons $\Xi_{cc}$ and $\Omega_{cc}$. (arXiv:2211.00510v2 [hep-ph] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.00510</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;In this work, we perform a systematic study of the mass spectra, the root
mean square(r.m.s.) radii and the radial density distributions of the doubly
charmed baryons $\Xi_{cc}$ and $\Omega_{cc}$. The calculations are carried out
in the frame work of Godfrey-Isgur (GI) relativized quark model, where the
baryon is regarded as a real three-body system of quarks. Our results show that
the excited energy of doubly charmed baryon with $\rho$-mode is lower than
those of the $\lambda$-mode and $\lambda$-$\rho$ mixing mode, which indicates
that the lowest state is dominated by the $\rho$-mode. According to this
conclusion, we systematically investigate the mass spectra, the r.m.s. radii of
the ground and excited states($1S\sim4S$, $1P\sim4P$, $1D\sim4D$, $1F\sim4F$
and $1G\sim4G$) with $\rho$-mode. Using the wave functions obtained from quark
model, we also study the radial density distributions. Finally, with the
predicated mass spectra, the Regge trajectories of $\Xi_{cc}$ and $\Omega_{cc}$
in the ($J$,$M^{2}$) plane are constructed, and the slopes, intercepts are
determined by linear fitting. It is found that model predicted masses fit
nicely to the constructed Regge trajectories.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Yu_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Guo-Liang Yu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Li_Z/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Zhen-Yu Li&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Wang_Z/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Zhi-Gang Wang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Lu_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jie Lu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Yan_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Meng Yan&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
</rdf:RDF>