<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Center for Public Integrity</title>
	<atom:link href="https://publicintegrity.org/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://publicintegrity.org/</link>
	<description>Investigating inequality</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2022 14:02:24 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	

<image>
	<url>https://publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/CPI-columns-new-color.jpg</url>
	<title>Center for Public Integrity</title>
	<link>https://publicintegrity.org/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">201594328</site>	<item>
		<title>Anti-immigrant rhetoric spiked in this election. Here’s why it’s dangerous.</title>
		<link>https://publicintegrity.org/politics/elections/anti-immigrant-rhetoric-spiked-in-this-election-heres-why-its-dangerous/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kristian Hernández]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2022 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Elections]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Watchdog newsletter]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://publicintegrity.org/?p=116983</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<figure><img width="300" height="200" src="https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/GettyImages-1331666912-scaled.jpg?fit=300%2C200&amp;ssl=1" class="attachment-medium size-medium wp-post-image" alt="" decoding="async" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/GettyImages-1331666912-scaled.jpg?w=2560&amp;ssl=1 2560w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/GettyImages-1331666912-scaled.jpg?resize=300%2C200&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/GettyImages-1331666912-scaled.jpg?resize=1024%2C683&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/GettyImages-1331666912-scaled.jpg?resize=768%2C512&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/GettyImages-1331666912-scaled.jpg?resize=1536%2C1024&amp;ssl=1 1536w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/GettyImages-1331666912-scaled.jpg?resize=2048%2C1365&amp;ssl=1 2048w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/GettyImages-1331666912-scaled.jpg?resize=1200%2C800&amp;ssl=1 1200w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/GettyImages-1331666912-scaled.jpg?resize=1568%2C1045&amp;ssl=1 1568w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/GettyImages-1331666912-scaled.jpg?resize=400%2C267&amp;ssl=1 400w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/GettyImages-1331666912-scaled.jpg?resize=150%2C100&amp;ssl=1 150w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/GettyImages-1331666912-scaled.jpg?w=2340&amp;ssl=1 2340w" sizes="(max-width: 34.9rem) calc(100vw - 2rem), (max-width: 53rem) calc(8 * (100vw / 12)), (min-width: 53rem) calc(6 * (100vw / 12)), 100vw" /></figure>
<p>It was 100 years ago that Alexander Terrell, a former Confederate officer and Texas representative, claimed that “Mexicans are induced on election day to swim across the Rio Grande and are voted before their hair is dry.”  The Terrell Election Law of 1903, fueled by false claims that non-citizens from Mexico were voting in Texas [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://publicintegrity.org/politics/elections/anti-immigrant-rhetoric-spiked-in-this-election-heres-why-its-dangerous/">Anti-immigrant rhetoric spiked in this election. Here’s why it’s dangerous.</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://publicintegrity.org">Center for Public Integrity</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure><img width="300" height="200" src="https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/GettyImages-1331666912-scaled.jpg?fit=300%2C200&amp;ssl=1" class="attachment-medium size-medium wp-post-image" alt="" decoding="async" loading="lazy" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/GettyImages-1331666912-scaled.jpg?w=2560&amp;ssl=1 2560w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/GettyImages-1331666912-scaled.jpg?resize=300%2C200&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/GettyImages-1331666912-scaled.jpg?resize=1024%2C683&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/GettyImages-1331666912-scaled.jpg?resize=768%2C512&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/GettyImages-1331666912-scaled.jpg?resize=1536%2C1024&amp;ssl=1 1536w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/GettyImages-1331666912-scaled.jpg?resize=2048%2C1365&amp;ssl=1 2048w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/GettyImages-1331666912-scaled.jpg?resize=1200%2C800&amp;ssl=1 1200w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/GettyImages-1331666912-scaled.jpg?resize=1568%2C1045&amp;ssl=1 1568w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/GettyImages-1331666912-scaled.jpg?resize=400%2C267&amp;ssl=1 400w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/GettyImages-1331666912-scaled.jpg?resize=150%2C100&amp;ssl=1 150w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/GettyImages-1331666912-scaled.jpg?w=2340&amp;ssl=1 2340w" sizes="(max-width: 34.9rem) calc(100vw - 2rem), (max-width: 53rem) calc(8 * (100vw / 12)), (min-width: 53rem) calc(6 * (100vw / 12)), 100vw" /></figure><span class="rt-reading-time" style="display: block;"><span class="rt-label rt-prefix">Reading Time: </span> <span class="rt-time">5</span> <span class="rt-label rt-postfix">minutes</span></span>
<p>It was 100 years ago that <a href="https://www.tshaonline.org/handbook/entries/terrell-alexander-watkins">Alexander Terrell</a>, a former Confederate officer and Texas representative, claimed that “Mexicans are induced on election day to swim across the Rio Grande and are voted before their hair is dry.” </p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="alignleft size-full"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="450" height="582" src="https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/image-2.png?resize=450%2C582&#038;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-117008" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/image-2.png?w=450&amp;ssl=1 450w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/image-2.png?resize=232%2C300&amp;ssl=1 232w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/image-2.png?resize=400%2C517&amp;ssl=1 400w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/image-2.png?resize=150%2C194&amp;ssl=1 150w" sizes="(max-width: 450px) 100vw, 450px" data-recalc-dims="1" /><figcaption>A picture of Alexander Terrell, former Confederate officer and author of the 1903 Terrell Election Law which established “white primaries” in Texas. Photo courtesy of the <a href="https://cemetery.tspb.texas.gov/pub/user_form.asp?step=1&amp;pers_id=815" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Texas State Cemetery website</a>.</figcaption></figure></div>


<p>The Terrell Election Law of 1903, fueled by false claims that non-citizens from Mexico were voting in Texas elections, restricted primaries in Texas to white voters only.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Following the Civil War, the 15th Amendment of the Constitution in 1870 had banned states from restricting the right to vote on “account of race, color, or previous condition of servitude.” Political parties still had wide leeway in nominating candidates for office, however, and this was a workaround that was quickly adopted throughout the South to take the right to vote away from recently freed Black men and other people of color.</p>



<p>The U.S. Supreme Court ruled white primaries unconstitutional in 1944. Terrell’s rhetoric and unsubstantiated allegations of voter fraud and immigrants coming across the border illegally became a permanent tactic.</p>



<div class="is-layout-flow wp-block-group alignwide newspack-pattern subscribe__style-6 is-style-border compress-newsletter has-secondary-background-color has-background"><div class="wp-block-group__inner-container">
<div class="is-layout-flex wp-container-4 wp-block-columns are-vertically-aligned-center">
<div class="is-layout-flow wp-block-column is-vertically-aligned-center">
<p class="has-white-color has-text-color"><meta charset="utf-8"><strong>Watchdog delivered </strong></p>



<p class="has-white-color has-text-color has-small-font-size">Want our investigations in your inbox? Subscribe to our Watchdog newsletter.</p>
</div>



<div class="is-layout-flow wp-block-column is-vertically-aligned-center"><amp-layout id="n196">
	<div class="wp-block-jetpack-mailchimp" data-blog-id="201594328">
		<form
			aria-describedby="wp-block-jetpack-mailchimp_consent-text"
					>
			<p>
				<input
					aria-label="Enter your email"
					placeholder="Enter your email"
					required
					title="Enter your email"
					type="email"
					name="email"
				/>
			</p>
							<input
					name="interests[3f37dae637]"
					type="hidden"
					class="mc-submit-param"
					value="1"
				/>
									
<div class="wp-block-jetpack-button wp-block-button" style=""><button class="wp-block-button__link has-background has-primary-background-color" style="" data-id-attr="mailchimp-button-block-2" id="mailchimp-button-block-2" type="submit"><strong>Sign up</strong></button></div>
			<p id="wp-block-jetpack-mailchimp_consent-text">
							</p>

			
		</form>
		
			<div class="wp-block-jetpack-mailchimp_notification wp-block-jetpack-mailchimp_processing" role="status">
				Processing…			</div>
			<div class="wp-block-jetpack-mailchimp_notification wp-block-jetpack-mailchimp_success" role="status">
				Success! You&#039;re on the list.			</div>
			<div class="wp-block-jetpack-mailchimp_notification wp-block-jetpack-mailchimp_error" role="alert">
				Whoops! There was an error and we couldn&#039;t process your subscription. Please reload the page and try again.			</div>

			</div>
	</amp-layout></div>
</div>
</div></div>



<p>Anti-immigrant rhetoric has featured prominently in Republican candidates’ campaign ads and speeches ahead of the Nov. 8 midterm elections. But watchdogs say this election cycle is different because of how much the GOP has embraced and promoted a more sinister mix of fringed conspiracy theories rooted in xenophobia and white supremacy.</p>



<p>Experts and voting rights advocates worry history is repeating itself as<a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/outlook/2021/12/29/you-didnt-always-have-be-citizen-vote-america/"> red herrings about noncitizens voting</a> and<a href="https://www.npr.org/2022/08/03/1115175247/talk-of-invasion-moves-from-the-fringe-to-the-mainstream-of-gop-immigration-mess"> claims of an invasion at the border</a> are used while<a href="https://publicintegrity.org/politics/elections/who-counts/a-headlong-rush-by-states-to-attack-voting-access-or-expand-it/"> lawmakers curtail voting rights and ballot access</a> across most of the country. Immigration advocates worry the lies and hateful rhetoric brewing this election cycle could spur some to violence.&nbsp;</p>



<p>That became apparent when a 21-year-old man walked into a Walmart on Aug. 3, 2019, in the border city of El Paso and used an AK-47 to kill 22 people. The fear of a “<a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/history/2019/08/05/hispanic-invasion-white-nationalist-version-texas-that-never-existed/">Hispanic invasion of Texa</a>s” drove him more than 650 miles from his home. His mission: to kill Mexicans.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This and other racist massacres committed across the country in recent years have been inspired by a fringe conspiracy theory, widely known as the “Great Replacement Theory” — the claim that Western elites, often injected with anti-Semitic rhetoric about Jewish powerbrokers, want to replace and disempower white Americans.</p>



<p>Once confined to the dark fringes of the internet including white nationalist sites, aspects of replacement theory have gone mainstream on primetime Fox News shows and is front and center for many GOP candidates, according to<a href="https://americasvoice.org/staff/zachary-mueller/"> Zachary Mueller, political director of America&#8217;s Voice</a>, an immigrant advocacy group that’s been tracking GOP messaging in political ads since 2018.</p>



<p>The group has tracked more than<a href="http://gopadtracker.com/ads?field_candidate_targeted_target_id=&amp;field_sponsor_target_id=&amp;field_congressional_district_target_id=&amp;field_state_target_id=&amp;field_race_target_id=All&amp;field_cycle_target_id%5B%5D=1106&amp;field_cycle_target_id%5B%5D=2059&amp;field_topic_target_id=292&amp;field_medium_target_id=All"> 600 messages about an invasion at the border</a> from more than 100 GOP candidates, political action committees and right-wing media outlets this election season. More than 130 messages tracked by the group falsely claim Democrats are purposely allowing immigrants to enter the country illegally to gain voters.&nbsp;</p>



<p>There is <a href="https://www.brennancenter.org/our-work/analysis-opinion/non-citizens-are-not-voting-here-are-facts">no statistically meaningful evidence of non-citizens voting</a> in U.S. elections. And far from the border being “open,” record breaking numbers of migrants have been <a href="https://www.npr.org/2022/10/24/1130841306/new-record-in-border-patrol-apprehensions">stopped by border patrol</a> this year.&nbsp;</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="alignright size-full"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="315" height="500" src="https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/image-3.png?resize=315%2C500&#038;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-117010" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/image-3.png?w=315&amp;ssl=1 315w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/image-3.png?resize=189%2C300&amp;ssl=1 189w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/image-3.png?resize=150%2C238&amp;ssl=1 150w" sizes="(max-width: 315px) 100vw, 315px" data-recalc-dims="1" /><figcaption>A picture of the cover of a 1908 edition of the Terrell Election Law. Terrell’s law prompted the disenfranchisement of people of color throughout the South for more than four decades. Photo courtesy of <a href="http://openlibrary.org/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">OpenLibrary.org</a>.</figcaption></figure></div>


<p>“Democrats are actively ignoring laws on the book and allowing millions of migrants to come into our country illegally. Why? Because the thinking goes that if they’re given enough handouts, these migrants will eventually be Democrat voters,” an election campaign email sent by Monica De La Cruz in September reads. De La Cruz is a Trump-backed GOP candidate running for Congress in Texas’ 15th District.</p>



<p>The replacement and invasion rhetoric was mainly on the fringes of the Republican party in 2018, Mueller said, but this year the number of messages is about five times higher and it’s coming from the leadership all the way down.</p>



<p>“That’s dangerous because some segments of those folks that believe that racist lies are going to take it upon themselves to act as vigilantes to try to stop it,” Mueller said.</p>



<p>In the wake of a mass shooting at a Buffalo supermarket last fall, U.S. Rep. Elise Stefanik of New York, the third-highest ranking House Republican, faced criticism for a series of Facebook ads that warned of a “permanent election insurrection,” arguing that Democrats want to grant amnesty to millions of illegal immigrants and “overthrow our current electorate.”</p>



<p>In an interview rebutting the allegations that her ads echoed the conspiracy theory that inspired the Buffalo shooter, Stefanik said there’s nothing racist about wanting a secure border or opposing mass amnesty.</p>



<p>Stefanik’s office did not respond to multiple requests for comment.</p>



<p>Democrats and immigration rights advocates have also condemned Texas Gov. Greg Abbott and state Lt. Gov. Dan Patrick, both Republicans, for describing immigrants crossing the border as an invasion.</p>



<p>“We are being invaded,” Patrick said at a press conference this past year. “That term has been used in the past, but it has never been more true.”</p>



<p>Abbott said at the same presser that “homes are being invaded” as he announced the state would be spending an initial $250 million to construct a barrier at the state’s southern border with Mexico to fill in gaps that have remained since the border wall was first constructed nearly 30 years ago.</p>



<p>U.S. Rep. Veronica Escobar, a Democrat from El Paso, condemned Abbott’s and Patrick’s remarks in a tweet after the press conference.</p>



<p>“If people die again, blood will be on your hands,” Escobar wrote.</p>



<p>Abbott took it a step further: He issued an executive order in July that invoked the U.S. Constitution’s “Invasion Clause” and directed state law enforcement to arrest migrants and drop them off at ports of entry. Article IV Section 4 of the U.S. Constitution says the federal government “shall guarantee every state in this Union a republican form of government and shall protect each of them against invasion…”</p>



<p>(The term “republican” refers to a republic of representatives, not the Republican party.)</p>



<p>After years of former President Donald Trump demonizing undocumented immigrants and using the word invasion on a regular basis, more than half of Americans say there&#8217;s an “invasion” at the southern border, according to an August <a href="https://www.ipsos.com/en-us/news-polls/npr-immigration-perceptions-august-2022">poll by NPR and Ipsos</a>,</p>



<p>But experts say, “the current increase in apprehensions fits a predictable pattern of seasonal changes in undocumented immigration combined with a backlog of demand because of 2020’s coronavirus border closure,” according to a recent analysis by the <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/politics/2021/03/23/theres-no-migrant-surge-us-southern-border-heres-data/">Washington Post</a>.</p>



<p>As Texas politicians continue to attack immigrants and sound the alarm on border security, they have also ramped up efforts to restrict access to the ballot box.</p>



<p>Last year, Abbott signed into law one of the<a href="https://publicintegrity.org/politics/elections/who-counts/texas-limits-mail-voting-adds-id-requirements-after-surge-in-turnout/"> nation’s strictest voting bills</a>. The bill rolled back extended voting hours and drive-through voting, restricted voting by mail, added new voter ID requirements, banned some forms of organizing voter turnout and increased criminal penalties for violating election laws.</p>



<p>Abbott and Patrick did not respond to multiple requests for comment.</p>





<p>The reality is that Texas is not alone: Access to the ballot box has gotten worse in 26 states, and this has been particularly bad for people of color, according to a<a href="https://publicintegrity.org/politics/elections/who-counts/who-counts-in-voting/"> Center for Public Integrity report looking at voting inequalities in all 50 states and Washington D.C.</a></p>



<p>False claims that non-citizens are voting and influencing elections have been used to justify some of those new restrictions. In Arizona, Republican legislators passed a <a href="https://publicintegrity.org/politics/elections/who-counts/arizona-sued-by-doj-over-requiring-proof-of-citizenship-to-register-to-vote/">new law requiring proof of citizenship</a> to register to vote. It could have the most significant impact on the state’s elderly Indigenous population, who are less likely to have birth certificates or other documents proving citizenship.&nbsp;</p>



<p>“It’s not politically popular to say, ‘Hey, I just don’t want non-whites to vote, so we’re going to create these arbitrary barriers so that only more middle-class white folks and affluent whites can vote,’ that’s not going to win you an election that’s pretty on face,” Mueller said. “So they create these other kinds of boogeyman to do that sort of thing.”&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://publicintegrity.org/politics/elections/anti-immigrant-rhetoric-spiked-in-this-election-heres-why-its-dangerous/">Anti-immigrant rhetoric spiked in this election. Here’s why it’s dangerous.</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://publicintegrity.org">Center for Public Integrity</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">116983</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>It&#8217;s already too late for thousands of would-be voters: Why that matters</title>
		<link>https://publicintegrity.org/politics/elections/who-counts/its-already-too-late-for-thousands-of-would-be-voters-why-that-matters/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kimberly Cataudella]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2022 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Who Counts?]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://publicintegrity.org/?p=116989</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<figure><img width="300" height="200" src="https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/GettyImages-1240799112-scaled.jpg?fit=300%2C200&amp;ssl=1" class="attachment-medium size-medium wp-post-image" alt="A white sign with simple black lettering that says &quot;REGISTER HERE&quot; sits in the foreground of an image that shows two women sitting at a folding table with a cardboard office supplies box on it. A mural on the side of the building is shown in the top right background of the photo with an image of civil rights leader and late Congressman John Lewis and the quote, &quot;The right to vote is precious, almost sacred. It is the most powerful nonviolent tool or instrument we have in a democratic society.&quot;" decoding="async" loading="lazy" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/GettyImages-1240799112-scaled.jpg?w=2560&amp;ssl=1 2560w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/GettyImages-1240799112-scaled.jpg?resize=300%2C200&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/GettyImages-1240799112-scaled.jpg?resize=1024%2C683&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/GettyImages-1240799112-scaled.jpg?resize=768%2C512&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/GettyImages-1240799112-scaled.jpg?resize=1536%2C1024&amp;ssl=1 1536w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/GettyImages-1240799112-scaled.jpg?resize=2048%2C1365&amp;ssl=1 2048w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/GettyImages-1240799112-scaled.jpg?resize=1200%2C800&amp;ssl=1 1200w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/GettyImages-1240799112-scaled.jpg?resize=1568%2C1045&amp;ssl=1 1568w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/GettyImages-1240799112-scaled.jpg?resize=400%2C267&amp;ssl=1 400w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/GettyImages-1240799112-scaled.jpg?resize=150%2C100&amp;ssl=1 150w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/GettyImages-1240799112-scaled.jpg?w=2340&amp;ssl=1 2340w" sizes="(max-width: 34.9rem) calc(100vw - 2rem), (max-width: 53rem) calc(8 * (100vw / 12)), (min-width: 53rem) calc(6 * (100vw / 12)), 100vw" /></figure>
<p>In more than half the country, if you’re not already registered to vote, it’s already too late to cast a ballot in midterm elections that will decide control of Congress, state legislatures and numerous state and local offices on Nov. 8.&#160; Included in a slew of new restrictions on voting rights in 26 states controlled [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://publicintegrity.org/politics/elections/who-counts/its-already-too-late-for-thousands-of-would-be-voters-why-that-matters/">It&#8217;s already too late for thousands of would-be voters: Why that matters</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://publicintegrity.org">Center for Public Integrity</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure><img width="300" height="200" src="https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/GettyImages-1240799112-scaled.jpg?fit=300%2C200&amp;ssl=1" class="attachment-medium size-medium wp-post-image" alt="A white sign with simple black lettering that says &quot;REGISTER HERE&quot; sits in the foreground of an image that shows two women sitting at a folding table with a cardboard office supplies box on it. A mural on the side of the building is shown in the top right background of the photo with an image of civil rights leader and late Congressman John Lewis and the quote, &quot;The right to vote is precious, almost sacred. It is the most powerful nonviolent tool or instrument we have in a democratic society.&quot;" decoding="async" loading="lazy" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/GettyImages-1240799112-scaled.jpg?w=2560&amp;ssl=1 2560w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/GettyImages-1240799112-scaled.jpg?resize=300%2C200&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/GettyImages-1240799112-scaled.jpg?resize=1024%2C683&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/GettyImages-1240799112-scaled.jpg?resize=768%2C512&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/GettyImages-1240799112-scaled.jpg?resize=1536%2C1024&amp;ssl=1 1536w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/GettyImages-1240799112-scaled.jpg?resize=2048%2C1365&amp;ssl=1 2048w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/GettyImages-1240799112-scaled.jpg?resize=1200%2C800&amp;ssl=1 1200w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/GettyImages-1240799112-scaled.jpg?resize=1568%2C1045&amp;ssl=1 1568w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/GettyImages-1240799112-scaled.jpg?resize=400%2C267&amp;ssl=1 400w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/GettyImages-1240799112-scaled.jpg?resize=150%2C100&amp;ssl=1 150w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/GettyImages-1240799112-scaled.jpg?w=2340&amp;ssl=1 2340w" sizes="(max-width: 34.9rem) calc(100vw - 2rem), (max-width: 53rem) calc(8 * (100vw / 12)), (min-width: 53rem) calc(6 * (100vw / 12)), 100vw" /></figure><span class="rt-reading-time" style="display: block;"><span class="rt-label rt-prefix">Reading Time: </span> <span class="rt-time">6</span> <span class="rt-label rt-postfix">minutes</span></span>
<p>In more than half the country, if you’re not already registered to vote, it’s already too late to cast a ballot in midterm elections that will decide control of Congress, state legislatures and numerous state and local offices on Nov. 8.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Included in a slew of new restrictions on voting rights in <a href="https://publicintegrity.org/politics/elections/who-counts/a-headlong-rush-by-states-to-attack-voting-access--or-expand-it/">26 states controlled by Republicans since 2020</a>, at least five have made it more difficult to register to vote.&nbsp;</p>



<div class="is-layout-flow wp-block-group alignwide newspack-pattern subscribe__style-6 is-style-border compress-newsletter has-secondary-background-color has-background"><div class="wp-block-group__inner-container">
<div class="is-layout-flex wp-container-9 wp-block-columns are-vertically-aligned-center">
<div class="is-layout-flow wp-block-column is-vertically-aligned-center">
<p class="has-white-color has-text-color"><meta charset="utf-8"><strong>Watchdog delivered </strong></p>



<p class="has-white-color has-text-color has-small-font-size">Want our investigations in your inbox? Subscribe to our Watchdog newsletter.</p>
</div>



<div class="is-layout-flow wp-block-column is-vertically-aligned-center"><amp-layout id="nf55">
	<div class="wp-block-jetpack-mailchimp" data-blog-id="201594328">
		<form
			aria-describedby="wp-block-jetpack-mailchimp_consent-text"
					>
			<p>
				<input
					aria-label="Enter your email"
					placeholder="Enter your email"
					required
					title="Enter your email"
					type="email"
					name="email"
				/>
			</p>
							<input
					name="interests[3f37dae637]"
					type="hidden"
					class="mc-submit-param"
					value="1"
				/>
									
<div class="wp-block-jetpack-button wp-block-button" style=""><button class="wp-block-button__link has-background has-primary-background-color" style="" data-id-attr="mailchimp-button-block-7" id="mailchimp-button-block-7" type="submit"><strong>Sign up</strong></button></div>
			<p id="wp-block-jetpack-mailchimp_consent-text">
							</p>

			
		</form>
		
			<div class="wp-block-jetpack-mailchimp_notification wp-block-jetpack-mailchimp_processing" role="status">
				Processing…			</div>
			<div class="wp-block-jetpack-mailchimp_notification wp-block-jetpack-mailchimp_success" role="status">
				Success! You&#039;re on the list.			</div>
			<div class="wp-block-jetpack-mailchimp_notification wp-block-jetpack-mailchimp_error" role="alert">
				Whoops! There was an error and we couldn&#039;t process your subscription. Please reload the page and try again.			</div>

			</div>
	</amp-layout></div>
</div>
</div></div>



<p>A number of states controlled by Democrats are moving in the opposite direction — providing automatic registration systems at state agencies such as the Department of Motor Vehicles, adopting special outreach programs for students, adjusting registration processes to accommodate voters with disabilities, and allowing voters to register up to and on Election Day.</p>



<p>Inequality in the ability to register to vote is widening with these two divergent paths. Residents of Arizona, Florida, Georgia, Ohio and 11 other states must be registered <a href="https://www.ncsl.org/research/elections-and-campaigns/voter-registration-deadlines.aspx">28 to 30 days before an election</a>, while people who live in 18 states including Colorado, California and Michigan can register through Election Day.</p>



<p>Like other limits on voting, younger and lower-income voters and people of color are disproportionately disenfranchised by lengthy advance deadlines for registering to vote, strict documentation requirements and lack of flexibility for registering online or by mail.</p>



<p>And in states with strict documentation requirements or without online registration or the ability to register and vote on the same day, there can be disproportionate barriers in access for people of color, elderly voters and rural voters who live far from a local election office.</p>



<p>“Registering to vote and being on the voter rolls is a prerequisite to exercising the fundamental right to vote, and anything that’s a barrier to getting on, and staying on, the registration lists can act as a barrier to enfranchise,” said <a href="https://www.naacpldf.org/about-us/staff/steven-lance/">Steven Lance</a>, a policy counsel at the Legal Defense Fund.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This can include having “unnecessarily long deadlines” ahead of an election, he said.&nbsp;</p>



<p>“A lot of us aren&#8217;t actually thinking about an election more than a month before it,” Lance said. “If people aren’t registered in some of these states a full month before, by the time the election is on their radar and they’re ready to vote, it’s too late for their registration to become active so they can participate.”&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>


<h2 id="h-registration-is-a-key-factor-in-access-to-voting">Registration is a key factor in access to voting</h2>


<p>A <a href="https://newsroom.niu.edu/how-hard-is-it-to-vote-in-your-state/">2020 study from Northern Illinois University</a> found that three registration-related factors significantly help break down barriers to casting a ballot: online voter registration, Election Day (or same-day) registration and automatic voter registration.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Texas makes it <a href="https://www.liebertpub.com/doi/10.1089/elj.2020.0666">harder</a> than any other state, forcing voters to register over a month before Election Day and lacking an online registration system. And four other states – Mississippi, Arkansas, Oklahoma and South Dakota – also hit the trifecta, currently without <a href="https://www.ncsl.org/research/elections-and-campaigns/electronic-or-online-voter-registration.aspx">online</a>, <a href="https://www.ncsl.org/research/elections-and-campaigns/automatic-voter-registration.aspx">automatic</a> nor <a href="https://www.ncsl.org/research/elections-and-campaigns/same-day-registration.aspx">same-day</a> voter registration.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Automatic voter registration</strong> adds eligible voters to voter rolls whenever they interact with statewide databases. <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/politics/2022/09/23/voter-registration-fraud-suppression/">For example</a>, if you renew a driver’s license as a U.S. citizen, the computer checks if your name, address and age are in the voter rolls already. If they’re not, you’ll be added automatically.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In California, voter registration had been long available at the Department of Motor Vehicles. But when registration became automatic in 2018, registrations through the DMV <a href="https://static1.squarespace.com/static/57b8c7ce15d5dbf599fb46ab/t/5eb8fafa0e4d61663a1833f4/1589181180589/USC+CCEP+Summary+Brief+-+Effects+of+AVR+in+the+U.S.+FINAL.pdf">more than doubled</a>.&nbsp;</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity is-style-wide"/>



<div class="wp-block-media-text is-stacked-on-mobile is-vertically-aligned-center" style="grid-template-columns:38% auto"><figure class="wp-block-media-text__media"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="780" height="829" src="https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/Who-counts-logo.jpg?resize=780%2C829&#038;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-115659 size-medium" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/Who-counts-logo.jpg?resize=963%2C1024&amp;ssl=1 963w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/Who-counts-logo.jpg?resize=282%2C300&amp;ssl=1 282w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/Who-counts-logo.jpg?resize=768%2C817&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/Who-counts-logo.jpg?resize=1444%2C1536&amp;ssl=1 1444w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/Who-counts-logo.jpg?resize=1200%2C1276&amp;ssl=1 1200w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/Who-counts-logo.jpg?resize=1568%2C1668&amp;ssl=1 1568w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/Who-counts-logo.jpg?resize=400%2C425&amp;ssl=1 400w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/Who-counts-logo.jpg?resize=150%2C160&amp;ssl=1 150w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/Who-counts-logo.jpg?w=1682&amp;ssl=1 1682w" sizes="(max-width: 780px) 100vw, 780px" data-recalc-dims="1" /></figure><div class="wp-block-media-text__content">
<h2 class="has-text-color" id="h-about-this-series" style="color:#000000;font-size:32px"><strong>About this series</strong></h2>



<p class="has-text-color" style="color:#000000;font-size:17px">This project looks at the state of voting access, voting rights and inequities in political representation in all 50 states and Washington, D.C.</p>



<div class="is-layout-flex wp-block-buttons">
<div class="wp-block-button has-custom-width wp-block-button__width-100 is-style-fill"><a class="wp-block-button__link" href="https://publicintegrity.org/politics/elections/who-counts/who-counts-in-voting/">Read more</a></div>
</div>
</div></div>



<p><strong>Same-day registration</strong> has been <a href="https://www.umass.edu/news/article/new-study-finds-states-same-day-voter-registration-have-higher-black-and-latinx">proven</a> to boost turnout across all voters, but it especially drives higher turnout among Black and Latino communities.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Online voter registration</strong> has exponentially boosted registration rates. South Dakota’s voter registration rate increased over 500% after implementing online registration, according to <a href="https://www.naacpldf.org/naacp-publications/ldf-blog/online-voter-registration-good-for-states-good-for-voters/">the Legal Defense Fund</a>. Washington and Kansas also saw registration rates through DMVs double after creating online systems.&nbsp;</p>


<h2 id="h-it-s-harder-to-register-here">It’s harder to register here</h2>


<p>Since the 2020 presidential elections, these states have made it harder to register to vote:&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Arizona</strong>: A <a href="https://custom.statenet.com/public/resources.cgi?id=ID:bill:AZ2022000H2492&amp;ciq=ncsl15&amp;client_md=c758d8b6359adbd07385669f26c771af&amp;mode=current_text">new state law,</a> which is being challenged by the U.S. Department of Justice, requires residents to show proof of citizenship to register to vote, something that advocates say could <a href="https://publicintegrity.org/politics/elections/who-counts/arizona-sued-by-doj-over-requiring-proof-of-citizenship-to-register-to-vote/">disenfranchise elderly Indigenous residents</a> who are less likely to even have a birth certificate or similar documents used to prove it.</p>



<p><strong>Georgia</strong>: A <a href="https://www.ajc.com/politics/georgia-house-to-vote-on-election-restrictions-amid-staunch-opposition/46SNHMIYGZGMZDG5KLGHAB6NQ4/">2021 law</a> restricted the number of <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/03/06/us/politics/churches-black-voters-georgia.html">Sundays</a> where people can register to vote. Sunday was traditionally a time when Black congregations would register to vote together after church services wrapped up.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Kansas</strong>: A 2021 law made the League of Women Voters of Kansas and other nonprofits <a href="https://lawrencekstimes.com/2021/07/01/ks-groups-halt-voter-reg/">suspend voter registration drives</a>. One of the provisions of this new law makes it a crime to engage in activity that “gives the appearance of being an election official.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>“Kansans miss the opportunity to be engaged, our team misses its right to exercise free speech, and our democracy is undermined,” Davis Hammet, president of social justice group Loud Light, <a href="https://kansasreflector.com/2021/07/01/kansas-groups-halt-voter-registration-drives-to-avoid-being-jailed-under-new-law/">told the Kansas Reflector</a>.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Organizations argue in court filings that there’s a “serious risk” someone will mistake people hoping to help with voter registration as election officials. As a result, organizations traditionally responsible for managing a large portion of the state’s voter registration efforts have stopped.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Hammet <a href="https://publicintegrity.org/politics/elections/who-counts/in-kansas-inequality-in-voting-widens-with-new-limits/">told Public Integrity earlier this fall</a> that his organization registered more than 10,000 new voters prior to the 2020 election.</p>



<p><strong>Montana</strong>: <a href="https://custom.statenet.com/public/resources.cgi?id=ID:bill:MT2021000H176&amp;ciq=ncsl15&amp;client_md=b7c6c0a2eb7e3f65a0290b0b30837c64&amp;mode=current_text">HB 176</a>, passed last year, repealed the state&#8217;s Election Day registration law and moved the registration deadline to the day before Election Day. </p>



<p>The Montana Supreme Court <a href="https://montanafreepress.org/2022/09/21/montana-election-day-registration-back-on-per-supreme-court-ruling/">blocked</a> the law repealing Election Day registration in September, though a final ruling is still to come.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Texas</strong>: Voter roll purges are common practice in Texas. Just last year, the state tracked down and removed voters from voting rolls, flagging them as noncitizens. County workers found up to 17% of those individuals had legally registered to vote at their naturalization ceremonies, the Texas Tribune <a href="https://www.texastribune.org/2021/12/17/texas-voter-roll-review/">reported</a>.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>


<h2 id="h-but-it-s-easier-to-register-here">But it’s easier to register here</h2>


<p>These states have <a href="https://www.democracydocket.com/analysis/these-24-states-improved-access-to-voting-this-year/">made it easier</a> to register to vote since 2020:&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>California</strong>:&nbsp; A <a href="https://openstates.org/ca/bills/20212022/AB796/#:~:text=The%20bill%20would%20require%20the%20Department%20of%20Motor%20Vehicles%20and,the%20National%20Voter%20Registration%20Act.">new “motor voter” law</a>, passed in 2021, is improving the automatic voter registration process at the Department of Motor Vehicles.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Automatic voter registration through the DMV (passed in <a href="https://www.sos.ca.gov/administration/news-releases-and-advisories/2015-news-releases-and-advisories/california-new-motor-voter-act-passed-legislature">2015</a>) has <a href="https://www.ppic.org/blog/improving-californias-automatic-voter-registration/">significantly increased</a> the state’s registration rate.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Colorado</strong>: Senate Bill 250, passed last summer, made registering to vote <a href="https://www.democracydocket.com/news-alerts/colorado-gov-jared-polis-d-signs-voting-expansion-law/">easier</a> in a few ways: Automatic voter registration was expanded to Medicaid and other state agencies. Voters became eligible to register online using their social security number. Colleges became required to give information to students each semester about how to register to vote.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Connecticut</strong>: Automatic voter registration has recently been expanded, allowing eligible voters to register through <a href="https://my.lwv.org/connecticut/article/what-happened-during-2021-legislative-general-session-special-session">more state agencies</a>, as well as the DMV.</p>



<p><strong>Delaware</strong>: An automatic voter registration system was created at the Delaware Division of Motor Vehicles via <a href="https://legis.delaware.gov/BillDetail?legislationId=48446">Senate Bill 5</a>, passed in March 2021.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Hawaii</strong>: Senate Bill 159, passed in April 2021, <a href="https://www.democracydocket.com/news-alerts/hawaii-passes-automatic-voter-registration/">created</a> automatic voter registration, allowing Hawiians to choose if they wanted to register to vote or change their registration information while applying for identification or a driver’s license.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Illinois</strong>: High schools are now <a href="https://ilga.gov/legislation/billstatus.asp?DocNum=0825&amp;GAID=16&amp;GA=102&amp;DocTypeID=SB&amp;LegID=133452&amp;SessionID=110">required</a> to provide voter registration information to students. The schools also <a href="https://www.illinoispolicy.org/election-law-changes-may-be-coming-to-illinois-what-you-need-to-know/">can’t prohibit</a> nonpartisan voter registration on its premises.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Maine</strong>: Student IDs became <a href="https://www.democracydocket.com/news-alerts/maine-expands-student-id-options/">acceptable</a> as voter registration identification. By <a href="https://www.democracydocket.com/news-alerts/maine-enacts-online-voter-registration-law/">2023</a>, the secretary of state needs to create an online voter registration system.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Maryland</strong>: The state’s Department of Public Safety and Correctional Services needs to <a href="https://mgaleg.maryland.gov/2021RS/Chapters_noln/CH_734_hb0222e.pdf">provide</a> individuals released from correctional facilities with voter registration applications, and certain signs need to be displayed in parole offices to teach former inmates how to vote. The State Board of Elections and local boards have to provide eligible incarcerated voters the right to vote.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Nevada</strong>: Voters with disabilities recently became eligible to register to vote (as well as cast an absentee ballot) <a href="https://www.leg.state.nv.us/App/NELIS/REL/81st2021/Bill/7442/Overview">electronically</a>. Additionally, <a href="https://www.leg.state.nv.us/App/NELIS/REL/81st2021/Bill/8087/Votes">more state agencies</a> became eligible to register voters via the state’s automatic voter registration program.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Oregon</strong>: <a href="https://olis.oregonlegislature.gov/liz/2021R1/Measures/Overview/HB2681">House Bill 2681</a>, signed into law in June 2021, requires currently inactive voters to be notified and given instructions on reactivating their voter registration.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Virginia</strong>: Same-day registration was enacted in 2020, and it went into effect on <a href="https://www.virginiamercury.com/2022/07/13/same-day-voter-registration-is-coming-to-virginia-heres-how-itll-work/">Oct. 1</a>. Additionally, anyone 16 or older can preregister to vote thanks to <a href="https://lis.virginia.gov/cgi-bin/legp604.exe?212+sum+HB2125&amp;212+sum+HB2125">House Bill 2125</a>, signed into law in March 2021.&nbsp;</p>


<h2 id="h-change-is-slow-even-in-some-blue-states">Change is slow even in some blue states</h2>


<p>Change has been slow in some other states controlled by Democrats who tout their support for greater access to voting.</p>



<p>In Delaware, the state legislature <a href="https://www.democracydocket.com/news-alerts/delaware-passes-bill-to-enact-same-day-registration/">adopted</a> same-day voter registration following the 2020 election, but the state Supreme Court recently ruled that <a href="https://www.delawarepublic.org/politics-government/2022-10-07/delawares-supreme-court-tosses-out-vote-by-mail-and-same-day-registration">language in the state’s constitution prohibits it</a>.</p>



<p>In reliably Democratic Rhode Island, the registration deadline is the strictest allowed by federal law — 30 days before Election Day. This is “by far the biggest obstacle” for Rhode Island voters, John Marion, executive director of Common Cause Rhode Island, <a href="https://publicintegrity.org/politics/elections/who-counts/rhode-island-eases-absentee-ballot-restrictions-but-strict-voter-id-remains/">previously told</a> Public Integrity. </p>



<p>It’s been written into the state constitution as the longest time allowed, so advocates fear it’ll take a large, heavy-lift shake-up to change this.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In New York, which in many other ways takes a progressive approach to election access, voters <a href="https://www.npr.org/2021/11/03/1052198559/new-yorkers-vote-against-a-potential-expansion-of-ballot-access-for-the-state">rejected</a> same-day registration last November, following a “Just Say No” <a href="https://www.npr.org/2021/11/02/1051305287/new-york-voters-have-their-say-on-expanding-access-to-the-ballot">campaign</a> by conservative politicians and interest groups.&nbsp;<br>“The people of the state of New York voted — during a pandemic — to restrict their own rights,” <a href="https://www.jarretberg.com/">Jarret Berg</a>, co-founder of VoteEarlyNY, <a href="https://publicintegrity.org/politics/elections/who-counts/new-york-adopts-a-state-voting-rights-act-while-rejecting-wider-ballot-access/">previously told</a> Public Integrity. “<a href="https://www.elections.ny.gov/2021ElectionResults.html">More</a> people in Brooklyn left that question blank than voted no, whereas in Nassau County, far more people, proportionately, turned out and voted no.”</p>
<script type="text/javascript">//## toolTips('.classtoolTips10','<span style="font-weight: 400;">A tax or tax system where wealthier people pay a greater percentage of their income than poorer people. The federal system is progressive. The opposite of a progressive tax is a regressive one. </span>'); ##]]</script><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://publicintegrity.org/politics/elections/who-counts/its-already-too-late-for-thousands-of-would-be-voters-why-that-matters/">It&#8217;s already too late for thousands of would-be voters: Why that matters</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://publicintegrity.org">Center for Public Integrity</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">116989</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Costs to vote considered modern “poll taxes”</title>
		<link>https://publicintegrity.org/politics/elections/who-counts/costs-to-vote-considered-modern-poll-taxes/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ileana Garnand]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2022 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Who Counts?]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://publicintegrity.org/?p=116763</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<figure><img width="300" height="207" src="https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/GettyImages-1229443432-scaled.jpg?fit=300%2C207&amp;ssl=1" class="attachment-medium size-medium wp-post-image" alt="" decoding="async" loading="lazy" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/GettyImages-1229443432-scaled.jpg?w=2560&amp;ssl=1 2560w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/GettyImages-1229443432-scaled.jpg?resize=300%2C207&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/GettyImages-1229443432-scaled.jpg?resize=1024%2C706&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/GettyImages-1229443432-scaled.jpg?resize=768%2C529&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/GettyImages-1229443432-scaled.jpg?resize=1536%2C1058&amp;ssl=1 1536w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/GettyImages-1229443432-scaled.jpg?resize=2048%2C1411&amp;ssl=1 2048w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/GettyImages-1229443432-scaled.jpg?resize=1200%2C827&amp;ssl=1 1200w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/GettyImages-1229443432-scaled.jpg?resize=1568%2C1080&amp;ssl=1 1568w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/GettyImages-1229443432-scaled.jpg?resize=400%2C276&amp;ssl=1 400w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/GettyImages-1229443432-scaled.jpg?resize=150%2C103&amp;ssl=1 150w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/GettyImages-1229443432-scaled.jpg?w=2340&amp;ssl=1 2340w" sizes="(max-width: 34.9rem) calc(100vw - 2rem), (max-width: 53rem) calc(8 * (100vw / 12)), (min-width: 53rem) calc(6 * (100vw / 12)), 100vw" /></figure>
<p>Under a new law, thousands of Missouri voters could have to pay $15 to acquire the documents needed to get an ID to vote.  Wyoming voters also face their state’s new ID law, passed last year, which requires a government or student identification card to cast a ballot. Voters without one must present certain proof [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://publicintegrity.org/politics/elections/who-counts/costs-to-vote-considered-modern-poll-taxes/">Costs to vote considered modern “poll taxes”</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://publicintegrity.org">Center for Public Integrity</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure><img width="300" height="207" src="https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/GettyImages-1229443432-scaled.jpg?fit=300%2C207&amp;ssl=1" class="attachment-medium size-medium wp-post-image" alt="" decoding="async" loading="lazy" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/GettyImages-1229443432-scaled.jpg?w=2560&amp;ssl=1 2560w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/GettyImages-1229443432-scaled.jpg?resize=300%2C207&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/GettyImages-1229443432-scaled.jpg?resize=1024%2C706&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/GettyImages-1229443432-scaled.jpg?resize=768%2C529&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/GettyImages-1229443432-scaled.jpg?resize=1536%2C1058&amp;ssl=1 1536w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/GettyImages-1229443432-scaled.jpg?resize=2048%2C1411&amp;ssl=1 2048w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/GettyImages-1229443432-scaled.jpg?resize=1200%2C827&amp;ssl=1 1200w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/GettyImages-1229443432-scaled.jpg?resize=1568%2C1080&amp;ssl=1 1568w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/GettyImages-1229443432-scaled.jpg?resize=400%2C276&amp;ssl=1 400w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/GettyImages-1229443432-scaled.jpg?resize=150%2C103&amp;ssl=1 150w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/GettyImages-1229443432-scaled.jpg?w=2340&amp;ssl=1 2340w" sizes="(max-width: 34.9rem) calc(100vw - 2rem), (max-width: 53rem) calc(8 * (100vw / 12)), (min-width: 53rem) calc(6 * (100vw / 12)), 100vw" /></figure><span class="rt-reading-time" style="display: block;"><span class="rt-label rt-prefix">Reading Time: </span> <span class="rt-time">7</span> <span class="rt-label rt-postfix">minutes</span></span>
<p>Under a new <a href="https://custom.statenet.com/public/resources.cgi?id=ID:bill:MO2022000H1878&amp;ciq=ncsl15&amp;client_md=3ba30b13c331b837a62cce2dc487ff6e&amp;mode=current_text">law</a>, thousands of <a href="https://www.kansascity.com/news/politics-government/election/article265106799.html">Missouri voters</a> could have to pay $15 to acquire the documents needed to get an ID to vote. </p>



<p>Wyoming voters also face their state’s <a href="https://sos.wyo.gov/Elections/VoterID/Default.aspx">new ID law</a>, passed last year, which requires a government or student identification card to cast a ballot. Voters without one must present certain proof of identity to obtain the state’s free voter ID. A birth certificate there costs $25.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Voter rights advocates argue these costs amount to a poll tax, declared unconstitutional over 50 years ago, and point to an array of factors that can make casting a ballot more costly for some voters.&nbsp;</p>



<div class="is-layout-flow wp-block-group alignwide newspack-pattern subscribe__style-6 is-style-border compress-newsletter has-secondary-background-color has-background"><div class="wp-block-group__inner-container">
<div class="is-layout-flex wp-container-15 wp-block-columns are-vertically-aligned-center">
<div class="is-layout-flow wp-block-column is-vertically-aligned-center">
<p class="has-white-color has-text-color"><meta charset="utf-8"><strong>Watchdog delivered </strong></p>



<p class="has-white-color has-text-color has-small-font-size">Want our investigations in your inbox? Subscribe to our Watchdog newsletter.</p>
</div>



<div class="is-layout-flow wp-block-column is-vertically-aligned-center"><amp-layout id="nfd7">
	<div class="wp-block-jetpack-mailchimp" data-blog-id="201594328">
		<form
			aria-describedby="wp-block-jetpack-mailchimp_consent-text"
					>
			<p>
				<input
					aria-label="Enter your email"
					placeholder="Enter your email"
					required
					title="Enter your email"
					type="email"
					name="email"
				/>
			</p>
							<input
					name="interests[3f37dae637]"
					type="hidden"
					class="mc-submit-param"
					value="1"
				/>
									
<div class="wp-block-jetpack-button wp-block-button" style=""><button class="wp-block-button__link has-background has-primary-background-color" style="" data-id-attr="mailchimp-button-block-13" id="mailchimp-button-block-13" type="submit"><strong>Sign up</strong></button></div>
			<p id="wp-block-jetpack-mailchimp_consent-text">
							</p>

			
		</form>
		
			<div class="wp-block-jetpack-mailchimp_notification wp-block-jetpack-mailchimp_processing" role="status">
				Processing…			</div>
			<div class="wp-block-jetpack-mailchimp_notification wp-block-jetpack-mailchimp_success" role="status">
				Success! You&#039;re on the list.			</div>
			<div class="wp-block-jetpack-mailchimp_notification wp-block-jetpack-mailchimp_error" role="alert">
				Whoops! There was an error and we couldn&#039;t process your subscription. Please reload the page and try again.			</div>

			</div>
	</amp-layout></div>
</div>
</div></div>



<p>Voters today may not be charged a literal poll tax, the fees created in the late 1800s to keep Black men from voting, but ID requirements, transportation and lack of paid time off to vote all ultimately come with price tags. A flurry of new voting restrictions have made it even more costly, especially for voters of color.  </p>


<h2 id="h-voter-ids">Voter IDs</h2>


<p>A majority of states ask for some form of identification to vote. The type of acceptable ID ranges from a driver’s license to a utility bill. Some states offer alternative ways to prove one’s identity, including sworn affidavits and signature matching.&nbsp;</p>



<p>While many states require some form of identification to cast a ballot, they often have workarounds, such as a signed affidavit or signature matching, that still allow people to vote. Some also allow a variety of documents, such as utility bills or pay stubs.</p>



<p>But <a href="https://www.ncsl.org/research/elections-and-campaigns/voter-id.aspx">12 states</a> strictly require a government-issued ID. Some also accept an ID from a tribe or a university. While those states offer free identification cards for the purpose of voting, obtaining them can still be costly because the process usually requires documentation, such as a birth certificate.&nbsp;</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity is-style-wide"/>



<div class="wp-block-media-text is-stacked-on-mobile is-vertically-aligned-center" style="grid-template-columns:38% auto"><figure class="wp-block-media-text__media"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="780" height="829" src="https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/Who-counts-logo.jpg?resize=780%2C829&#038;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-115659 size-medium" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/Who-counts-logo.jpg?resize=963%2C1024&amp;ssl=1 963w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/Who-counts-logo.jpg?resize=282%2C300&amp;ssl=1 282w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/Who-counts-logo.jpg?resize=768%2C817&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/Who-counts-logo.jpg?resize=1444%2C1536&amp;ssl=1 1444w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/Who-counts-logo.jpg?resize=1200%2C1276&amp;ssl=1 1200w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/Who-counts-logo.jpg?resize=1568%2C1668&amp;ssl=1 1568w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/Who-counts-logo.jpg?resize=400%2C425&amp;ssl=1 400w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/Who-counts-logo.jpg?resize=150%2C160&amp;ssl=1 150w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/Who-counts-logo.jpg?w=1682&amp;ssl=1 1682w" sizes="(max-width: 780px) 100vw, 780px" data-recalc-dims="1" /></figure><div class="wp-block-media-text__content">
<h2 class="has-text-color" id="h-about-this-series" style="color:#000000;font-size:32px"><strong>About this series</strong></h2>



<p class="has-text-color" style="color:#000000;font-size:17px">This project looks at the state of voting access, voting rights and inequities in political representation in all 50 states and Washington, D.C.</p>



<div class="is-layout-flex wp-block-buttons">
<div class="wp-block-button has-custom-width wp-block-button__width-100 is-style-fill"><a class="wp-block-button__link" href="https://publicintegrity.org/politics/elections/who-counts/who-counts-in-voting/">Read more</a></div>
</div>
</div></div>



<p>People who are <a href="https://www.brennancenter.org/sites/default/files/legacy/d/download_file_39242.pdf">low-income,</a> <a href="https://www.npr.org/2012/02/01/146204308/why-millions-of-americans-have-no-government-id">older adults</a> and Indigenous Americans are less likely to have these papers on hand. </p>



<p>“This is more so the case with older Natives,” said Allison Neswood, a staff attorney at the Native American Rights Fund. “Maybe they weren’t born in a regular hospital and so [they] don’t have certain types of documents that are more common for other folks to have. That can definitely add to the cost of just that one piece of voting.”</p>



<p>As of 2018, state-issued birth certificates <a href="https://ballotpedia.org/Birth_certificate_costs_by_state,_2018">cost as much as</a> $34, with 22 states charging $20 or more.&nbsp;</p>



<p>When ID cards are required to vote and that identification “costs $20, that’s a poll tax,” said Scot Schraufnagel, professor of political science at Northern Illinois University and co-author of a <a href="https://www.liebertpub.com/doi/10.1089/elj.2022.0041">series of studies</a> on the cost of voting in the U.S.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This comparison is not new. A decade ago, then-Attorney General Eric Holder <a href="https://abcnews.go.com/blogs/politics/2012/07/eric-holder-dubs-texas-voter-id-law-a-poll-taxes">called</a> Texas’ strict voter ID requirement a poll tax, noting identification cards usually come with fees.</p>



<p>“Many of those without IDs would have to travel great distances to get them and some would struggle to pay for the documents they might need to obtain them,” Holder said in a speech to the NAACP in 2012. “We call those poll taxes.”</p>


<h2 id="transportation">Transportation</h2>


<p>Getting to the polls also can add costs, especially for voters without cars or who have to travel long distances to cast a ballot. The problem worsened after <a href="https://publicintegrity.org/politics/elections/ballotboxbarriers/new-data-tracks-polling-place-locations-for-37-states/">the closure</a> of thousands of polling places since 2013. Voters in rural areas face unique challenges, while Americans of color in even suburban and urban areas are more likely to pay for a ride on Election Day. When voters are required to take separate trips to register to vote and then cast their ballot, costs are doubled.</p>



<p>A federal<a href="https://www.democracydocket.com/news-alerts/federal-judge-keeps-michigan-voting-restrictions-in-place/"> judge in September</a> upheld the country’s only voter transportation ban. The Michigan law, originating in 1895 and updated in 1982, prohibits anyone from hiring a motor vehicle to bring voters to the polls unless they are physically unable to walk. Advocates argue it hinders get-out-the-vote efforts in communities without easy access to transportation.</p>



<p>People of color face higher rates of unreliable access to transportation, which can affect voter turnout. A recent <a href="https://maxwellpalmer.com/research/jdbk_mp_driving_turnout.pdf">study</a> of the 2018 midterm elections found 66% of people with access to a car voted, compared to 36% of those without a car.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Some local governments, nonprofit organizations and private companies stepped up to narrow the gap by offering free or reduced-rate transportation on Election Day. Rideshare apps like <a href="https://www.lyft.com/blog/posts/lyft-launches-2022-lyftup-voting-access-program">Lyft</a> will offer discounted trips this year and will donate rides to nonprofits like the League of Women Voters, Voto Latino Foundation and the NAACP.</p>



<p>However, these get-out-the-vote efforts are difficult to implement in some Indigenous communities, Neswood said, because of the long drive to the nearest voting location. About 95,000 Native American households do not have access to a vehicle, according to the <a href="https://nationalequityatlas.org/indicators/Car_access#/?breakdown=1">National Equality Atlas</a>.</p>



<p>“It takes a lot of resources if the voting location is an hour or two hours away from folks and you don’t have a big bus,” Neswood said. “You still got to go back and forth, it still takes a lot of time.”</p>



<p>Even some people who do have access to a car face high transportation costs when trying to vote. This includes rural voters who face 90-minute round trips to polling places “at a time when gas prices are significant,” said Johnathan Hladik, policy director for the Center for Rural Affairs.</p>



<p>“There is no question that even if you’re somebody who is considered a habitual voter, the constellation of problems that could come up when it’s time to vote is much greater here than if you could just walk a block to your polling place,” Hladik said.</p>



<p>While voting by mail can reduce costs for many, for some rural voters who do not receive mail directly to their homes, “even the post office is a real journey,” Hladik said.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Transportation costs are doubled in areas that require people to take multiple trips to both register to vote and then actually cast their ballot. <a href="https://www.ncsl.org/research/elections-and-campaigns/same-day-registration.aspx">Twenty-eight states</a> do not allow same-day voter registration on Election Day or during early voting.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The right to same-day registration has been argued in courts across the country this year, with Montana’s Supreme Court <a href="https://montanafreepress.org/2022/09/21/montana-election-day-registration-back-on-per-supreme-court-ruling/">temporarily legalizing</a> it in late September. Conversely, in October, the Delaware Supreme Court <a href="https://www.wdel.com/news/vote-by-mail-same-day-registration-ruled-unconstitutional-by-delaware-supreme-court/article_45579aa8-466d-11ed-9333-9be9a3348109.html">ruled</a> the state’s newly implemented same-day registration policy unconstitutional.&nbsp;</p>


<h2 id="time-off-to-vote%25c2%25a0">Time off to vote </h2>


<p>While some countries schedule their Election Day on the weekend or designate it as a national holiday, the U.S. left it to the states to decide if workers get time off to vote. The amount of time voters have to cast ballots and if they get paid while doing so also varies by state, leading some workers to choose between civic engagement and paying their bills.</p>



<p>Voters across the country reported conflicting schedules as the most common reason for not voting from 2008 to 2014 and in 2018, according to the <a href="https://www.census.gov/topics/public-sector/voting/data/tables.html">Census Bureau</a>.</p>



<p>In <a href="https://www.workplacefairness.org/voting-rights-time-off-work">29 states</a>, <a href="https://www.workplacefairness.org/voting-rights-time-off-work">employers must give</a> workers time off to vote on Election Day. Most have time limits ranging from one to three hours.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But in seven states, time off to vote does not have to be paid. Ohio requires compensation only for salaried employees. Oklahoma gives voters paid time off, but employers are allowed to change workers’ schedules to give them time to get to the polls on Election Day off company time.</p>



<p>Simply having the right to vote on a workday does not guarantee people can actually afford to take the time off, said Sabrina Khan, senior supervising attorney for voting rights at the Southern Poverty Law Center. Workers whose time off is unpaid have to decide whether to lose wages for the sake of voting. Even those who are compensated may have to forgo voting under their state’s time limits if they have to travel far to the polls or face hours-long lines once there.</p>



<p>Unpaid or limited time off to vote has become less feasible for workers because of the “constant moving, closing and consolidating of polling places” across the country, Khan said. This disproportionately affects communities of color, Khan said, who have been left waiting in lines up to five hours in states including Georgia and Florida.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Early voting can help address long lines on Election Day. For residents of the four states that <a href="https://www.ncsl.org/research/elections-and-campaigns/early-voting-in-state-elections.aspx">do not offer</a> in-person early voting — Alabama, Mississippi, Connecticut and New Hampshire — only Alabamans have the right to time off work to vote. They <a href="https://www.workplacefairness.org/voting-rights-time-off-work">have</a> up to one hour and are not paid.</p>



<p>“You might be working a job where yes, you have a protected right to take time off to cast your ballot, but for all practical reasons, maybe you only have an hour,” Khan said. “You need to make sure you make your wages, so you have a limited amount of time.”</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="780" height="520" src="https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/GettyImages-1180924528.jpg?resize=780%2C520&#038;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-116842" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/GettyImages-1180924528-scaled.jpg?resize=1024%2C683&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/GettyImages-1180924528-scaled.jpg?resize=300%2C200&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/GettyImages-1180924528-scaled.jpg?resize=768%2C512&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/GettyImages-1180924528-scaled.jpg?resize=1536%2C1024&amp;ssl=1 1536w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/GettyImages-1180924528-scaled.jpg?resize=2048%2C1365&amp;ssl=1 2048w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/GettyImages-1180924528-scaled.jpg?resize=1200%2C800&amp;ssl=1 1200w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/GettyImages-1180924528-scaled.jpg?resize=1568%2C1045&amp;ssl=1 1568w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/GettyImages-1180924528-scaled.jpg?resize=400%2C267&amp;ssl=1 400w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/GettyImages-1180924528-scaled.jpg?resize=150%2C100&amp;ssl=1 150w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/GettyImages-1180924528-scaled.jpg?w=2340&amp;ssl=1 2340w" sizes="(max-width: 780px) 100vw, 780px" data-recalc-dims="1" /><figcaption>Michael Monfluery stands in a courthouse corridor following a special hearing aimed at restoring the right to vote under Florida&#8217;s Amendment 4 in a Miami-Dade County courtroom on Nov. 8, 2019.  (Zak Bennett/AFP via Getty Images)</figcaption></figure>


<h2 id="felony-fines">Felony fines</h2>


<p>An estimated 5.2 million voting age adults cannot cast a ballot because they have a felony conviction, according to a <a href="https://www.sentencingproject.org/publications/locked-out-2020-estimates-of-people-denied-voting-rights-due-to-a-felony-conviction/">2020 report</a> from the Sentencing Project. Within the 27 states that <a href="https://www.ncsl.org/research/elections-and-campaigns/felon-voting-rights.aspx">do not immediately restore</a> the right to vote after release, some felons must pay all charges related to their conviction before they can vote again. These fees can stack up as a person goes through the criminal justice system, barring those who cannot afford it from the ballot.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Five states — Alabama, Arizona, Arkansas, Florida and Tennessee — have laws <a href="https://campaignlegal.org/sites/default/files/2019-07/CLC_CPCV_Report_Final_0.pdf">explicitly requiring payment</a> of all felony-related fines and fees to restore voting rights. Other states have more implicit policies with price tags, like parole periods or clemency requests that depend on similar payments.</p>



<p>Khan said felony disenfranchisement laws disproportionately affect people of color. As of 2020, one in 16 Black Americans of voting age are disenfranchised, a rate 3.7 times greater than those of other races, according to <a href="https://www.sentencingproject.org/publications/locked-out-2020-estimates-of-people-denied-voting-rights-due-to-a-felony-conviction/#III.%20Disenfranchisement%20in%202020">the Sentencing Project</a>.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Those coming out of the criminal justice system have a “hard transition” when having to pay to restore their voting rights, Khan said. “People have said it feels like there&#8217;s no end in sight and they’re just waiting to exercise their political voice.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>Florida has become a battleground for felony disenfranchisement. In 2018, voters approved the <a href="https://dos.elections.myflorida.com/initiatives/initdetail.asp?account=64388&amp;seqnum=1">Voting Rights Restoration for Felons Initiative</a>. This reinstated approximately 1.4 million people’s right to vote, including Neil Volz, deputy director of the Florida Rights Restoration Coalition.</p>



<p>“Many of us went out and registered to vote that day,” Volz said.</p>



<p>A few months later, the Florida Legislature passed provisions requiring people to pay any fee or fine associated with their sentence before they can vote. Almost 775,000 people — over half of the 1.4 million enfranchised felons — lost their newly restored rights, according to a University of Florida <a href="https://www.courthousenews.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/fla-expert-report.pdf">study</a>.</p>



<p>“You would go from a euphoric feeling, a celebration of democracy, to dejection and heartbreak relatively quickly,” Volz said.</p>



<p>While the Florida Rights Restoration Coalition supports the state requiring felons to pay sentenced restitution or punitive fines, Volz said, those are not the only costs incurred in the criminal justice system. Extra fees can come in the form of public attorney fees, incarceration costs, probation supervision charges and more — costs not unique to Florida.</p>



<p>Volz said these extra fees are about funding the state, not punishing someone for a crime. Various states and cities use this money to finance both their criminal justice systems and unrelated municipal services, according to the <a href="https://campaignlegal.org/sites/default/files/2019-07/CLC_CPCV_Report_Final_0.pdf">Campaign Legal Center</a>.</p>



<p>“We have hundreds of thousands of people in the state who are faced with paying money to be able to vote or paying money to put food on the table or pay their rent,” Volz said. “We just don’t think that is a morally right position for us to take.”&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://publicintegrity.org/politics/elections/who-counts/costs-to-vote-considered-modern-poll-taxes/">Costs to vote considered modern “poll taxes”</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://publicintegrity.org">Center for Public Integrity</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">116763</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>‘Chaos and confusion’: The campaign to stamp out ballot drop boxes</title>
		<link>https://publicintegrity.org/politics/elections/who-counts/campaign-to-stamp-out-ballot-drop-boxes/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aaron Mendelson and Pratheek Rebala]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 30 Oct 2022 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Integrity out loud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Who Counts?]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://publicintegrity.org/?p=116865</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<figure><img width="300" height="200" src="https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/GettyImages-1281302247-scaled.jpg?fit=300%2C200&amp;ssl=1" class="attachment-medium size-medium wp-post-image" alt="A voter wearing a mask puts a ballot into an election drop box." decoding="async" loading="lazy" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/GettyImages-1281302247-scaled.jpg?w=2560&amp;ssl=1 2560w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/GettyImages-1281302247-scaled.jpg?resize=300%2C200&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/GettyImages-1281302247-scaled.jpg?resize=1024%2C683&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/GettyImages-1281302247-scaled.jpg?resize=768%2C512&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/GettyImages-1281302247-scaled.jpg?resize=1536%2C1024&amp;ssl=1 1536w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/GettyImages-1281302247-scaled.jpg?resize=2048%2C1365&amp;ssl=1 2048w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/GettyImages-1281302247-scaled.jpg?resize=1200%2C800&amp;ssl=1 1200w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/GettyImages-1281302247-scaled.jpg?resize=1568%2C1045&amp;ssl=1 1568w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/GettyImages-1281302247-scaled.jpg?resize=400%2C267&amp;ssl=1 400w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/GettyImages-1281302247-scaled.jpg?resize=150%2C100&amp;ssl=1 150w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/GettyImages-1281302247-scaled.jpg?w=2340&amp;ssl=1 2340w" sizes="(max-width: 34.9rem) calc(100vw - 2rem), (max-width: 53rem) calc(8 * (100vw / 12)), (min-width: 53rem) calc(6 * (100vw / 12)), 100vw" /></figure>
<p>In 2020, ballot drop boxes were a sturdy, metallic symbol of increased voter access amid a pandemic. Absentee and mail voting surged across the country, and voters used drop boxes to return 41% of those ballots. This story also appeared in South Florida Sun Sentinel and Stateline Two years later, they’ve become a symbol of [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://publicintegrity.org/politics/elections/who-counts/campaign-to-stamp-out-ballot-drop-boxes/">‘Chaos and confusion’: The campaign to stamp out ballot drop boxes</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://publicintegrity.org">Center for Public Integrity</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure><img width="300" height="200" src="https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/GettyImages-1281302247-scaled.jpg?fit=300%2C200&amp;ssl=1" class="attachment-medium size-medium wp-post-image" alt="A voter wearing a mask puts a ballot into an election drop box." decoding="async" loading="lazy" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/GettyImages-1281302247-scaled.jpg?w=2560&amp;ssl=1 2560w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/GettyImages-1281302247-scaled.jpg?resize=300%2C200&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/GettyImages-1281302247-scaled.jpg?resize=1024%2C683&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/GettyImages-1281302247-scaled.jpg?resize=768%2C512&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/GettyImages-1281302247-scaled.jpg?resize=1536%2C1024&amp;ssl=1 1536w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/GettyImages-1281302247-scaled.jpg?resize=2048%2C1365&amp;ssl=1 2048w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/GettyImages-1281302247-scaled.jpg?resize=1200%2C800&amp;ssl=1 1200w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/GettyImages-1281302247-scaled.jpg?resize=1568%2C1045&amp;ssl=1 1568w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/GettyImages-1281302247-scaled.jpg?resize=400%2C267&amp;ssl=1 400w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/GettyImages-1281302247-scaled.jpg?resize=150%2C100&amp;ssl=1 150w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/GettyImages-1281302247-scaled.jpg?w=2340&amp;ssl=1 2340w" sizes="(max-width: 34.9rem) calc(100vw - 2rem), (max-width: 53rem) calc(8 * (100vw / 12)), (min-width: 53rem) calc(6 * (100vw / 12)), 100vw" /></figure><span class="rt-reading-time" style="display: block;"><span class="rt-label rt-prefix">Reading Time: </span> <span class="rt-time">15</span> <span class="rt-label rt-postfix">minutes</span></span>
<iframe loading="lazy" title="‘Chaos and confusion’: The campaign to stamp out ballot drop boxes" allowtransparency="true" height="150" width="100%" style="border: none; min-width: min(100%, 430px);" scrolling="no" data-name="pb-iframe-player" src="https://www.podbean.com/player-v2/?i=xd94c-12fdd51-pb&#038;from=pb6admin&#038;share=1&#038;download=1&#038;rtl=0&#038;fonts=Arial&#038;skin=f6f6f6&#038;font-color=auto&#038;logo_link=episode_page&#038;btn-skin=60a0c8"></iframe>



<figcaption>Subscribe on&nbsp;<a href="https://open.spotify.com/show/3QPPmx8PjXxSqJhlTNxtrR">Spotify</a>&nbsp;|&nbsp;<a href="https://podcasts.apple.com/us/podcast/integrity-out-loud/id1573267644">Apple Podcasts</a>&nbsp;|&nbsp;<a href="https://podcasts.google.com/feed/aHR0cHM6Ly9mZWVkLnBvZGJlYW4uY29tL2NlbnRlcmZvcnB1YmxpY2ludGVncml0eS9mZWVkLnhtbA">Google</a>&nbsp;|&nbsp;<a href="https://music.amazon.com/podcasts/550c2907-dc02-4098-a93d-603a7acf1ec7/integrity-out-loud">Amazon</a></figcaption>



<p>In 2020, ballot drop boxes were a sturdy, metallic symbol of increased voter access amid a pandemic. Absentee and mail voting surged across the country, and voters used drop boxes to return 41% of those ballots.</p>		<div class="wp-block-group alignright newspack-media-partners">
			<div class="wp-block-group__inner-container">
				<figure class="wp-block-image size-full is-resized">
					<a href="https://www.sun-sentinel.com/" target="_blank"><img width="200" height="27" src="https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/sun_sentinel_logo_white.jpg?fit=200%2C27&amp;ssl=1" class="attachment-200x999 size-200x999" alt="Website for South Florida Sun Sentinel" decoding="async" loading="lazy" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/sun_sentinel_logo_white.jpg?w=2225&amp;ssl=1 2225w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/sun_sentinel_logo_white.jpg?resize=300%2C41&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/sun_sentinel_logo_white.jpg?resize=1024%2C139&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/sun_sentinel_logo_white.jpg?resize=768%2C104&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/sun_sentinel_logo_white.jpg?resize=1536%2C208&amp;ssl=1 1536w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/sun_sentinel_logo_white.jpg?resize=2048%2C277&amp;ssl=1 2048w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/sun_sentinel_logo_white.jpg?resize=1200%2C162&amp;ssl=1 1200w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/sun_sentinel_logo_white.jpg?resize=1568%2C212&amp;ssl=1 1568w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/sun_sentinel_logo_white.jpg?resize=400%2C54&amp;ssl=1 400w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/sun_sentinel_logo_white.jpg?resize=150%2C20&amp;ssl=1 150w" sizes="(max-width: 34.9rem) calc(100vw - 2rem), (max-width: 53rem) calc(8 * (100vw / 12)), (min-width: 53rem) calc(6 * (100vw / 12)), 100vw" /></a><br/><a href="https://www.pewtrusts.org/en/research-and-analysis/blogs/stateline" target="_blank"><img width="200" height="46" src="https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/Stateline-logo1.jpg?fit=200%2C46&amp;ssl=1" class="attachment-200x999 size-200x999" alt="Website for Stateline" decoding="async" loading="lazy" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/Stateline-logo1.jpg?w=334&amp;ssl=1 334w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/Stateline-logo1.jpg?resize=300%2C68&amp;ssl=1 300w" sizes="(max-width: 34.9rem) calc(100vw - 2rem), (max-width: 53rem) calc(8 * (100vw / 12)), (min-width: 53rem) calc(6 * (100vw / 12)), 100vw" /></a>					<figcaption>
						This story also appeared in <a href="https://www.sun-sentinel.com/" target="_blank">South Florida Sun Sentinel</a> and <a href="https://www.pewtrusts.org/en/research-and-analysis/blogs/stateline" target="_blank">Stateline</a>					</figcaption>
				</figure>
			</div>
		</div>

		<p>Two years later, they’ve become a symbol of the attacks on voter access. After 2020, right-wing activists scrutinized security footage of drop boxes but failed to turn up evidence of widespread voter fraud. States across the country <a href="https://apnews.com/article/voting-rights-2022-midterm-elections-covid-health-wisconsin-c61fa93a12a1a51d6d9f4e0a21fa3b75">told the Associated Press</a> there were no cases of fraud, vandalism or theft involving drop boxes that could have affected election outcomes.</p>



<p>But the campaigns against them are increasingly succeeding. Laws, court rulings and local and state politicians in at least a dozen states have targeted drop boxes in the last two years.</p>



<p>A Texas law banned them. New Hampshire eliminated them after its governor terminated an emergency order that allowed them during the pandemic.</p>



<p>Wisconsin had more than 500 locations in 2020, but the state’s Supreme Court declared drop boxes illegal in July.</p>



<div class="is-layout-flow wp-block-group alignwide newspack-pattern subscribe__style-6 is-style-border compress-newsletter has-secondary-background-color has-background"><div class="wp-block-group__inner-container">
<div class="is-layout-flex wp-container-21 wp-block-columns are-vertically-aligned-center">
<div class="is-layout-flow wp-block-column is-vertically-aligned-center">
<p class="has-white-color has-text-color"><meta charset="utf-8"><strong>Watchdog delivered </strong></p>



<p class="has-white-color has-text-color has-small-font-size">Want our investigations in your inbox? Subscribe to our Watchdog newsletter.</p>
</div>



<div class="is-layout-flow wp-block-column is-vertically-aligned-center"><amp-layout id="n237">
	<div class="wp-block-jetpack-mailchimp" data-blog-id="201594328">
		<form
			aria-describedby="wp-block-jetpack-mailchimp_consent-text"
					>
			<p>
				<input
					aria-label="Enter your email"
					placeholder="Enter your email"
					required
					title="Enter your email"
					type="email"
					name="email"
				/>
			</p>
							<input
					name="interests[3f37dae637]"
					type="hidden"
					class="mc-submit-param"
					value="1"
				/>
									
<div class="wp-block-jetpack-button wp-block-button" style=""><button class="wp-block-button__link has-background has-primary-background-color" style="" data-id-attr="mailchimp-button-block-19" id="mailchimp-button-block-19" type="submit"><strong>Sign up</strong></button></div>
			<p id="wp-block-jetpack-mailchimp_consent-text">
							</p>

			
		</form>
		
			<div class="wp-block-jetpack-mailchimp_notification wp-block-jetpack-mailchimp_processing" role="status">
				Processing…			</div>
			<div class="wp-block-jetpack-mailchimp_notification wp-block-jetpack-mailchimp_success" role="status">
				Success! You&#039;re on the list.			</div>
			<div class="wp-block-jetpack-mailchimp_notification wp-block-jetpack-mailchimp_error" role="alert">
				Whoops! There was an error and we couldn&#039;t process your subscription. Please reload the page and try again.			</div>

			</div>
	</amp-layout></div>
</div>
</div></div>



<p>And local access is shrinking in other places:</p>



<ul><li>Battles in Pennsylvania include elected officials in one county cutting the number of drop boxes from six to one — and then to zero.</li><li>A Florida law prompted counties to ax locations and limit hours. In Palm Beach County, about 190,000 voters lived at least half a mile farther from a drop box in the 2022 primary, compared to 2020.</li><li>Populous places in Georgia reduced drop boxes to comply with a new state law, including one county that now has 80% fewer locations than it did in 2020.</li></ul>



<p>Further restrictions appear likely. Bills to ban drop boxes in Idaho, Arizona and Pennsylvania passed in one chamber of the legislature this year before falling short. With <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/interactive/2022/10/13/us/politics/republican-candidates-2020-election-misinformation.html">hundreds of GOP candidates</a> on the November ballot who question the 2020 election results, bans could become law in 2023 and beyond.</p>



<p>“There’s definitely a national push,” said Georgia Rep. Rhonda Burnough. Clayton County, in her district, offered seven drop boxes in 2020 but was restricted to three in 2022. Neighboring Fulton County dropped from 37 drop boxes to seven.</p>



<p>“Everybody benefited from drop boxes, regardless of age or occupation. It was just one of those things that was very, very convenient,” Burnough said.</p>



<p>In many areas, the curtailments will hit voters of color hard. Due to Georgia’s restrictive state law, the number of drop boxes across the diverse, vote-rich Atlanta area has dwindled. Clayton County, where Burnough lives, is 69% Black and 14% Hispanic.</p>



<p>In Florida, &#8220;restrictions on drop boxes will fall disproportionately on Black voters, voters affiliated with the Democratic party, and younger voters,&#8221; Michael C. Herron, a Dartmouth College academic <a href="https://www.brennancenter.org/sites/default/files/2022-03/Dr.%20Michael%20C.%20Herron%20-%20Expert%20Report.pdf">analyzing the impact</a> of the state’s 2021 law, found. Advocates, officials and academics also stress the changes will burden working-class voters and people who work nights or irregular schedules.</p>



<p>The campaign against drop boxes is part of the <a href="https://publicintegrity.org/politics/elections/who-counts/a-headlong-rush-by-states-to-attack-voting-access-or-expand-it/">broader push to make voting more difficult after the 2020 election</a> and former President Donald Trump’s effort to overturn and cast doubt on the results.</p>



<p>“So much of what has been standard operating procedure for election administration has been weaponized and has come under attack. And it&#8217;s a wide spectrum of functions, including ballot drop boxes,” said Tammy Patrick of Democracy Fund. She said states that have cut drop box locations without making it easy to vote by mail “are setting up voters to fail, rather than allowing the system to serve them.”</p>



<p>While drop boxes became a more common sight in 2020, they have long been popular and uncontroversial in Western states such as Washington, Utah, Oregon and Arizona. That has changed since Trump’s loss, with right-wing activist groups pledging to surveil ballot drop boxes in <a href="https://www.seattletimes.com/seattle-news/politics/republican-activists-organizing-surveillance-of-ballot-drop-boxes-in-washington/">Washington</a> and <a href="https://www.azmirror.com/2022/10/14/fringe-groups-plan-to-watch-az-ballot-drop-boxes/">Arizona</a> this year.</p>



<p>This election, voters have <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/politics/2022/10/20/arizona-ballot-drop-boxes/?utm_campaign=wp_main&amp;utm_medium=social&amp;utm_source=twitter">reported</a> they have been intimidated by vigilantes staking out drop boxes near Phoenix.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="780" height="520" src="https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/GettyImages-1410155784.jpg?resize=780%2C520&#038;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-116875" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/GettyImages-1410155784-scaled.jpg?resize=1024%2C683&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/GettyImages-1410155784-scaled.jpg?resize=300%2C200&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/GettyImages-1410155784-scaled.jpg?resize=768%2C512&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/GettyImages-1410155784-scaled.jpg?resize=1536%2C1024&amp;ssl=1 1536w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/GettyImages-1410155784-scaled.jpg?resize=2048%2C1365&amp;ssl=1 2048w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/GettyImages-1410155784-scaled.jpg?resize=1200%2C800&amp;ssl=1 1200w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/GettyImages-1410155784-scaled.jpg?resize=1568%2C1045&amp;ssl=1 1568w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/GettyImages-1410155784-scaled.jpg?resize=400%2C267&amp;ssl=1 400w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/GettyImages-1410155784-scaled.jpg?resize=150%2C100&amp;ssl=1 150w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/GettyImages-1410155784-scaled.jpg?w=2340&amp;ssl=1 2340w" sizes="(max-width: 780px) 100vw, 780px" data-recalc-dims="1" /><figcaption>Carts of vote-by-mail ballots sit in a U.S. Postal Service truck at the Miami-Dade Election Department headquarters  on July 21, 2022, in Miami. (Joe Raedle/Getty Images)</figcaption></figure>


<h2 id="h-obstacles-and-barriers-in-florida">Obstacles and barriers in Florida</h2>


<p>In April 2022, Florida Gov. Ron DeSantis declared in a press release that Florida had “stopped drop boxes.”</p>



<p>It was a misleading claim. They had been rebranded in state law as “secure ballot intake stations.&#8221;</p>



<p>Local election officials had to scramble to update references on ballot sleeves, literature for voters and flutter flags. “We had to change all of those,” said Wendy Sartory Link, the election supervisor in Palm Beach County. “So there was an expense and time commitment there.”</p>



<p>But that wasn’t the only change. <a href="https://publicintegrity.org/politics/elections/who-counts/in-florida-extreme-gerrymandering-and-people-arrested-for-voting/">Florida’s SB90, signed into law in 2021</a>, targeted drop box access following an election in which 1.5 million Floridians used one.</p>



<script src="https://unpkg.com/@newswire/frames/dist/frames.umd.js"></script>
<div data-frame-src="https://apps.publicintegrity.org/fl-dropboxes-2022/"></div>
<script type="module">
    window.newswireFrames.autoInitFrames();
</script>



<p>Now, they can be placed only in early voting sites and in elections offices, reducing location options. All drop boxes must be monitored in-person by employees of the local elections office, making round-the-clock access impractical for many Florida counties. Election officials who break the rules are subject to a $25,000 fine under the new law.</p>



<p>University of Florida political scientist Daniel A. Smith reviewed information from counties and estimated that one-fourth of Florida’s ballot drop boxes would be eliminated or limited due to the law. Boxes at early voting sites can be used only during early voting hours, for instance.</p>



<p>“It&#8217;s like having an ATM outside of a bank that is only open during banking hours. What’s the point? Except … to restrict the ability of people to use them,” Smith said.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Smith reviewed data from Florida’s Manatee County in 2020 and found that Black voters, Hispanic voters and voters with disabilities were more likely than white voters to drop off their ballots at the 24/7 locations after hours.</p>



<p>Previously, many election offices had used video surveillance to safeguard drop boxes, a common practice in other states. In Palm Beach County, four locations were monitored by video round the clock and attended to by law enforcement. Now, elections employees, and only elections employees, must monitor the boxes.</p>



<p>The hours of availability for drop boxes in Palm Beach County dropped nearly 30%, compared with the 2020 general election. Link, the election supervisor, said the new law is the reason.</p>



<p>Other changes will make the drop boxes less accessible to voters in some areas. Polk County, in Central Florida, can’t offer the James P. Austin Community Center as an early voting site and drop box location this year, due to an after-school program at the facility. “We always thought it was an ideal spot, and so I&#8217;m very disappointed,” said election supervisor Lori Edwards.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity is-style-wide"/>



<div class="wp-block-media-text is-stacked-on-mobile is-vertically-aligned-center" style="grid-template-columns:38% auto"><figure class="wp-block-media-text__media"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="780" height="829" src="https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/Who-counts-logo.jpg?resize=780%2C829&#038;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-115659 size-medium" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/Who-counts-logo.jpg?resize=963%2C1024&amp;ssl=1 963w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/Who-counts-logo.jpg?resize=282%2C300&amp;ssl=1 282w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/Who-counts-logo.jpg?resize=768%2C817&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/Who-counts-logo.jpg?resize=1444%2C1536&amp;ssl=1 1444w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/Who-counts-logo.jpg?resize=1200%2C1276&amp;ssl=1 1200w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/Who-counts-logo.jpg?resize=1568%2C1668&amp;ssl=1 1568w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/Who-counts-logo.jpg?resize=400%2C425&amp;ssl=1 400w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/Who-counts-logo.jpg?resize=150%2C160&amp;ssl=1 150w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/Who-counts-logo.jpg?w=1682&amp;ssl=1 1682w" sizes="(max-width: 780px) 100vw, 780px" data-recalc-dims="1" /></figure><div class="wp-block-media-text__content">
<h2 class="has-text-color" id="h-about-this-series" style="color:#000000;font-size:32px"><strong>About this series</strong></h2>



<p class="has-text-color" style="color:#000000;font-size:17px">This project looks at the state of voting access, voting rights and inequities in political representation in all 50 states and Washington, D.C.</p>



<div class="is-layout-flex wp-block-buttons">
<div class="wp-block-button has-custom-width wp-block-button__width-100 is-style-fill"><a class="wp-block-button__link" href="https://publicintegrity.org/politics/elections/who-counts/who-counts-in-voting/">Read more</a></div>
</div>
</div></div>



<p>The loss of the site meant more than 40,000 Polk County voters lived farther from a ballot drop box in this year’s primary, an analysis by the Center for Public Integrity found. Half of them will have to travel at least eight additional miles.</p>



<p>Changes to sites around the county left about 88,000 voters at least half a mile farther from a drop box, compared to 2020. Most live more than a mile farther from the nearest location, including the majority of the more than 13,000 Latino and 14,500 Black voters impacted.&nbsp;</p>



<p>“Location is vitally important,” said Mindy Romero of the Center for Inclusive Democracy at the University of Southern California. Romero has created a tool that draws on demographic data to help election officials place polling sites and drop boxes.</p>



<p>As in Palm Beach County, Polk County no longer has a drop box available 24/7. The number of total operating hours dropped 25%.</p>



<p>Experts say ballot drop boxes with round-the-clock video monitoring are secure and reducing their availability hurts voters.</p>



<p>“The nurse that gets off at 12 o&#8217;clock midnight, and has a ballot, she could just drop it off at one of the sites,” said LaVon Bracy of Faith in Florida, a longtime voting rights advocate in the state.</p>



<p>Bracy — who was the first Black student to graduate from Gainesville High School, in 1965 —&nbsp; sees echoes of past voter suppression efforts in the new law. “It is voter suppression 101,” she said. “It is done purposefully. And particularly it will affect people of color.”</p>



<p>Research supports the idea. Dartmouth’s Herron, who submitted an expert report as part of litigation over the law, found that “SB 90’s restrictions on drop box locations will aggravate the already existing burdens on drop box voters who reside in heavily Democratic and non-White counties in Florida.” (The University of Florida’s Smith also submitted an expert report in the suit.)</p>



<p>In Broward County, election supervisor Joe Scott campaigned on expanding the number of locations where people could drop off their ballots.</p>



<p>A West Point graduate and Iraq veteran, Scott won election to the office in 2020 — only to find after the passage of SB90 that expanding access in the county of 1.9 million would be challenging.</p>



<p>The restrictions struck him as intentional obstacles to voting. The requirement that boxes be monitored by employees is “incredibly inefficient,” he said, since it effectively requires two employees to be assigned at all times — accounting for needs like bathroom breaks.</p>



<p>Still, Scott added early voting sites in Broward County, where election supervisors also offer drop boxes. He also made plans to open up six branch offices, hoping to add drop boxes for voters that were available outside of early voting hours.</p>



<p>But the state intervened. The Florida Legislature passed a law in April 2022 that defines which branch offices qualify for drop boxes. Florida’s secretary of state said the six sites in Broward didn’t meet the new definition of a “permanent branch office.”</p>



<p>Scott wasn’t happy. “They&#8217;re moving the goalposts,” he said. “And I would say that it&#8217;s a safe bet at this point that anything that I do, they&#8217;ll go and change the law so that we can&#8217;t do it.”</p>



<figure class="wp-block-pullquote"><blockquote><p>They&#8217;re moving the goalposts. And I would say that it&#8217;s a safe bet at this point that anything that I do, they&#8217;ll go and change the law so that we can&#8217;t do it.”</p><cite> Joe Scott, BROWARD COUNTY ELECTION SUPERVISOR</cite></blockquote></figure>



<p>Scott also decided that the 24/7 drop boxes were so important that he needed to make one available in the final days of voting, despite the cost. So he’s staffing a station, which meets the state’s definition of a permanent branch office, at the Lauderhill Mall for what Scott calls “a 60-hour marathon” on the final three days of the election.</p>



<p>“That&#8217;s really where the impact will be, is working-class voters, who do tend to be disproportionately people of color,” he said. “If you look at working-class people, especially people who work maybe more than one job, people who are very busy, who are raising families, these are the people who are going to put off returning their ballot until the last minute.”</p>



<p>Putting a ballot in the mail in Florida close to Election Day is not a reliable option because it must be received by elections officials by the close of polls, regardless of when it was postmarked.</p>



<p>Scott says a single 24/7 site isn’t enough —&nbsp;but it’s all he can manage under Florida’s new laws. And he doubts many counties have the funds to staff even one.</p>


<h2 id="h-requiring-access-while-also-limiting-it">Requiring access while also limiting it</h2>


<p>Georgia’s <a href="https://publicintegrity.org/politics/elections/who-counts/voting-rights-under-attack-in-georgia-as-state-turns-purple/">sweeping election law, SB202</a>, mandated that every county offer a drop box for the first time in the state’s 234-year history.</p>



<p>It also sparked an outcry from major Georgia corporations, voting rights advocates and Major League Baseball, which pulled the 2021 All-Star Game out of the state in protest.</p>



<p>The law&#8217;s provision that makes it illegal to provide food or water to voters in line drew widespread condemnation. But so did another change, which slashed the numbers of drop boxes in populous areas. Counties are now limited to just one drop box per 100,000 voters, or one box per early voting site — whichever is less. The law also moves drop boxes inside election offices and early voting sites so they’re no longer accessible round-the-clock.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="780" height="520" src="https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/GettyImages-1229645396.jpg?resize=780%2C520&#038;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-116880" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/GettyImages-1229645396-scaled.jpg?resize=1024%2C683&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/GettyImages-1229645396-scaled.jpg?resize=300%2C200&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/GettyImages-1229645396-scaled.jpg?resize=768%2C512&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/GettyImages-1229645396-scaled.jpg?resize=1536%2C1024&amp;ssl=1 1536w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/GettyImages-1229645396-scaled.jpg?resize=2048%2C1365&amp;ssl=1 2048w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/GettyImages-1229645396-scaled.jpg?resize=1200%2C800&amp;ssl=1 1200w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/GettyImages-1229645396-scaled.jpg?resize=1568%2C1045&amp;ssl=1 1568w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/GettyImages-1229645396-scaled.jpg?resize=400%2C267&amp;ssl=1 400w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/GettyImages-1229645396-scaled.jpg?resize=150%2C100&amp;ssl=1 150w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/GettyImages-1229645396-scaled.jpg?w=2340&amp;ssl=1 2340w" sizes="(max-width: 780px) 100vw, 780px" data-recalc-dims="1" /><figcaption>Gwinnett County election workers handle ballots as part of the recount for the 2020 presidential election at the Beauty P. Baldwin Voter Registrations and Elections Building on Nov. 16, 2020, in Lawrenceville, Ga. (Megan Varner/Getty Images)</figcaption></figure>



<p>“We have 11 advance in-person voting sites, currently, and only six of them can have a drop box under the law because of the population requirement,” said Zach Manifold, Gwinnett County’s elections supervisor. The county had 23 drop boxes two years ago.</p>



<p>The law means that Taliaferro County, population 1,596, will have a per-capita rate of drop boxes that is 100 times higher than Gwinnett County’s.</p>



<p>Manifold said friends and family, and even his movers, were shocked when he told them he was accepting the job in Gwinnett County after the furor over the 2020 election results and SB202. Neighboring Fulton County, Georgia’s most populous, has <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/politics/2022/09/07/fulton-county-atlanta-elections-official/">struggled to find an election supervisor</a>.</p>



<p>The two counties are part of the Atlanta area, which was particularly affected by the drop box provision. Advocates believe it was targeted.&nbsp;</p>



<p>“They took a look at how minority communities of voters participated in the election, and they made those processes much more difficult,” said Jerry Gonzalez of the Georgia Association of Latino Elected Officials.</p>



<p>SB202 quickly drew legal challenges — including one from the U.S. Department of Justice that called provisions of the law “racially discriminatory.” In a legal filing disputing that claim, attorneys for the state argued that drop box availability has been expanded, since one is now required in each county.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-pullquote"><blockquote><p>“They took a look at how minority communities of voters participated in the election, and they made those processes much more difficult.” </p><cite><strong><em>Jerry Gonzalez of the Georgia Association of Latino Elected Officials</em></strong></cite></blockquote></figure>



<p>That ignores the situation in Atlanta. According to <a href="https://www.npr.org/2022/07/27/1112487312/georgia-voting-law-ballot-drop-box-access">an NPR analysis</a>, over half of the 550,000 Georgia voters who used drop boxes in 2020 lived in four Atlanta-area counties. Roughly half of voters in those counties are people of color. And those counties saw the number of drop boxes decline precipitously after SB202 became law — from 107 to 25.</p>



<p>Proximity matters, experts say. Research in Washington state found that most voters used the drop boxes closest to their homes, and that voters who live further from them tended to use other methods of voting.</p>



<p>The same researchers also found that adding drop boxes in Washington’s Pierce County “modestly increased voter turnout.” That effect was most prominent in primary and off-year elections.</p>



<p>“Because of the large expansion in the number of boxes [in 2020], it was treated like this was a new form of voting,” said Benjamin Gonzalez O’Brien, one of the researchers. “In fact, a number of states have had ballot drop boxes, have had no issues with them.” Oregon has used them for more than two decades.</p>



<p>The boxes are also critical in some rural areas, advocates say, including for Indigenous voters on reservations with limited mail service. “Throughout Indian Country, Native Americans are receiving insufficient services. And where ballot collection boxes can be utilized, it&#8217;s a helpful way to increase access,” said Jacqueline De León, an attorney with the Native American Rights Fund.</p>


<h2 id="h-extremely-negative-opinions-about-drop-boxes">‘Extremely negative opinions about drop boxes’</h2>


<p>In cities across Wisconsin, ballot drop boxes haven’t been restricted, they have been eliminated.</p>



<p>The state’s Supreme Court ruled in July that Wisconsin election law does not permit drop boxes. The ruling didn’t mince words: Ballot drop boxes had been used for years in parts of Wisconsin, and “thousands of votes have been cast via this unlawful method, thereby directly harming the Wisconsin voters. The illegality of these drop boxes weakens the people’s faith that the election produced an outcome reflective of their will,” wrote Justice Rebecca Bradley, part of the court’s conservative majority.</p>



<p>The ruling came as a blow to local officials like Celestine Jeffreys, Green Bay’s city clerk. In 2020, she helped map out six drop boxes across the city. The metal boxes, black with a blue stripe around the middle, were set up in a park, at city hall and near busy commercial areas. They received hundreds of ballots each day in the run-up to the election.</p>



<p>Those boxes are gone now. They’re stored in a garage on the city’s west side, and it’s unclear if they will ever be used in elections again — even though the city uses drop boxes for other business, like dropping off payments for parking ticket fines.</p>



<p>“My goal is to make voting calm, safe, secure, welcoming and predictable,” Jeffreys said. “And, you know, predictability and changing the rules all the time don&#8217;t go together.”</p>



<p>The intense scrutiny on Wisconsin elections and the outcome in 2020 has made her job challenging. “There were some of our neighbors who really had extremely negative opinions about drop boxes,” Jeffreys said.</p>



<p>Ron Heuer is one of them. Heuer lives in Kewaunee County, just east of Green Bay, and his concerns about drop boxes run so deep he put up billboards about them.</p>



<p>“2020 Green Bay Election,” says one south of the city, followed by two questions in all caps: “ILLEGAL DROP BOXES? ELECTION BRIBERY?”</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="780" height="439" src="https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/gb-billboard.jpg?resize=780%2C439&#038;ssl=1" alt="Photo of a billboard that reads &quot;2020 Green Bay Election. ILLEGAL DROP BOXES? ELECTION BRIBERY?&quot;" class="wp-image-116871" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/gb-billboard-scaled.jpg?resize=1024%2C576&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/gb-billboard-scaled.jpg?resize=300%2C169&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/gb-billboard-scaled.jpg?resize=768%2C432&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/gb-billboard-scaled.jpg?resize=1536%2C864&amp;ssl=1 1536w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/gb-billboard-scaled.jpg?resize=2048%2C1152&amp;ssl=1 2048w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/gb-billboard-scaled.jpg?resize=1200%2C675&amp;ssl=1 1200w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/gb-billboard-scaled.jpg?resize=1568%2C882&amp;ssl=1 1568w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/gb-billboard-scaled.jpg?resize=400%2C225&amp;ssl=1 400w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/gb-billboard-scaled.jpg?resize=150%2C84&amp;ssl=1 150w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/gb-billboard-scaled.jpg?w=2340&amp;ssl=1 2340w" sizes="(max-width: 780px) 100vw, 780px" data-recalc-dims="1" /><figcaption>The Wisconsin Voter Alliance billboard outside of Green Bay, Wisconsin, in 2022. (Courtesy of Wisconsin Voter Alliance)</figcaption></figure>



<p>“The purpose of the billboard was to keep that message in front of the general public,” said Heuer, whose Wisconsin Voter Alliance brought an unsuccessful lawsuit seeking to overturn Wisconsin’s election results in 2020. He formed the group in 2020 after learning about grants that the Chicago-based Center for Tech and Civic Life provided to local election officials during the pandemic.</p>



<p>Wisconsin’s five most populous cities, including Green Bay and Milwaukee, requested grant money to set up drop boxes in 2020.</p>



<p>“The Zuckerberg money came in deploying these things,” said Heuer, referring to a $350 million donation Facebook CEO Mark Zuckerberg and his wife Priscilla Chan made to the Center for Tech and Civic Life. “In these areas that were Black and brown communities, in these big cities. And they shut out everybody else. That wasn&#8217;t right.”</p>



<p>State data shows jurisdictions across Wisconsin, including Lake Nebagamon, with a population of 835 that is 98% white, offered ballot drop boxes in 2020. A map <a href="https://www.apmreports.org/story/2020/12/07/private-grant-money-chan-zuckerburg-election">published by APM Reports shows</a> that the Center for Tech and Civic Life awarded grants to both large and small jurisdictions.</p>



<p>The belief that drop boxes benefit Democrats and open the door to fraud is widely shared on the right. Dinesh D’Souza’s <a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/factcheck-usa-mules/fact-check-does-2000-mules-provide-evidence-of-voter-fraud-in-the-2020-u-s-presidential-election-idUSL2N2XJ0OQ">discredited</a> film “2000 Mules” airs unproven allegations, based on misinterpreted cell-phone location data and surveillance footage, that drop boxes were stuffed with potentially fake ballots.</p>



<p>The suspicion over outside funding has also become an animating cause nationally. While local election officials say the money was <a href="https://www.wabe.org/private-funding-saved-the-2020-election-now-some-gop-led-states-are-banning-it/">a lifeline</a> in 2020, more than a dozen GOP-controlled states have adopted bans on outside funding for elections.</p>



<p>Yet even after the 2020 election, some Republican legislators were working to establish a framework for drop boxes in Wisconsin. A statement by Trump in early 2022 <a href="https://www.jsonline.com/story/news/politics/elections/2022/01/24/donald-trump-statement-ballot-drop-boxes-snarls-wisconsin-gop-work-voting-laws-republicans/6634811001/">blew up the effort</a>.</p>



<p>“Some RINO Republicans in Wisconsin are working hand in hand with others to have drop boxes again placed in Wisconsin,” Trump said. “These fools are playing right into the Democrats’ hand. Drop boxes are only good for Democrats and cheating, not good for Republicans.”</p>



<p>The statement effectively killed support for the provision in the statehouse. The Wisconsin Supreme Court’s ruling came six months later.</p>



<p>“We&#8217;ve had so much litigation in Wisconsin since 2020,” said Barbara Beckert of Disability Rights Wisconsin. She said this year alone has been “chaos and confusion,” with the ruling in the drop box case also calling into question the right of disabled voters to have someone else return their ballot for them. (A federal court <a href="https://pbswisconsin.org/news-item/federal-judge-disabled-wisconsin-voters-can-receive-help-voting/">affirmed that right</a> in August.)</p>





<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity is-style-wide"/>



<p>For voters, Beckert said, “a drop box was a great thing — it was just one additional option to make voting more accessible and inclusive for people with disabilities.” The drop boxes were also convenient for people who provide care to those with disabilities, she added, and more secure than U.S. Postal Service mailboxes.</p>



<p>Most voters are likely unaware of the security measures election officials take around drop boxes, which typically include video or in-person surveillance, detailed chain of custody procedures for election workers handling ballots, and the security of the box itself.</p>



<p>Larry Olson’s company Laserfab has manufactured ballot drop boxes for over a decade. The Puyallup, Washington-based manufacturer currently has about 900 drop boxes in the field, he said, many ordered during the 2020 election cycle.</p>



<p>The wave of misinformation and <a href="https://www.reuters.com/investigates/section/campaign-of-fear/">harassment of election officials</a> following 2020 caught him by surprise.</p>



<p>“Our box is just a box, it obviously doesn&#8217;t have feelings,” Olson said. But he wishes people suspicious of them knew more about their design. Laserfab’s boxes are built so that water won’t drip on ballots, with tamper-proof hinges, and with ballot collection doors that automatically lock. “Literally every design feature came back to the integrity of the box and the ballots,” Olson said.</p>



<p>The boxes are sturdy and have withstood cars and buses running into them. Even the paint the company uses is designed so that white envelopes will show up clearly against it, to help election workers picking up ballots. Olson said that he’s puzzled by the controversies surrounding drop boxes. He’s used one to vote for a decade.</p>


<h2 id="fighting-over-drop-boxes-at-the-local-level">Fighting over drop boxes at the local level</h2>


<p>In areas where state laws and court rulings haven’t targeted drop boxes, they’ve become a flash point locally.</p>



<p>Some local jurisdictions have resisted efforts to remove drop boxes.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In early October, interim Secretary of State Karl Allred sent a letter to Wyoming’s 23 county clerks. “There is concern over the use of absentee ballot drop boxes,” Allred wrote. “I’m mindful of the fact that there have been no issues reported with the use of drop boxes in Wyoming, but that does not alleviate the potential for abuse or destruction of ballots through use of fire or other means.”</p>



<p>Albany County’s clerk, Jackie Gonzales, responded to Allred six days later. “Thank you for stating that you do not wish to interrupt or cause confusion to the voting process that is already in progress,” she wrote. “At this time, having to remove our absentee ballot drop box for the 2022 General Election would do both.” She added that the drop box is under constant surveillance and that a bipartisan team retrieves ballots daily and diligently logs them.</p>



<p>Other local officials have moved in the other direction.</p>



<p>In Westmoreland County, Pennsylvania, county commissioners set up six drop boxes for voters in the 2020 election after several requests for them, including a petition signed by more than 1,000 people.</p>



<p>This year, commissioners decided that access was no longer worth paying for. For the 2022 primary, commissioners voted to eliminate five of the six drop boxes.</p>



<p>And in September, the commission’s Republican majority refused to consider a plan to offer one during this year’s general election. That meant that the county would no longer have a single drop box.</p>



<p>Westmoreland County Commission chair Sean Kertes did not respond to several requests for an interview. In public statements, Kertes, a Republican, <a href="https://triblive.com/local/westmoreland/republican-commissioners-remove-ballot-drop-box-from-westmoreland-courthouse/">objected to the cost</a>.</p>



<p>Commissioner Gina Cerilli Thrasher, the lone Democrat on the commission, criticized the change. “This is a huge issue for senior citizens and those disabled that may receive their ballot late in the mail,” she told Public Integrity.</p>





<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity is-style-wide"/>



<p>She disputed the idea that cost was behind the removal of drop boxes, <a href="https://triblive.com/local/westmoreland/westmoreland-commissioners-accept-state-grant-to-pay-for-elections/">pointing to a $1.2 million grant</a> the county received from the state to assist with election costs.</p>



<p>“This has zero to do with finances and everything to do with a national political push from the far right,” she said.</p>



<p>Drop boxes are a target in other parts of Pennsylvania, a swing state Trump won in 2016 and lost in 2020.</p>



<p>America First Legal, a group headed by former Trump advisor Stephen Miller, filed suit in two other Pennsylvania counties, seeking to require 24/7 staffing of ballot drop boxes. In Lehigh County, a judge sided with the county, while Chester County agreed to add additional security measures.</p>



<p>Luzerne County’s council <a href="https://www.wnep.com/article/news/local/luzerne-county/luzerne-county-votes-on-ballot-drop-boxes-stephen-urban-beth-calpin-jim-keating-theodore-fitzgerald-cara-kreuger/523-216ae104-1380-4c75-bdaa-9fdb40d70e48">narrowly defeated</a> a measure to bar the county from paying for drop boxes. Fulton County <a href="https://www.co.fulton.pa.us/files/live-folders/commissioner-minutes-agendas/2022-09-06%20Commissioners'%20Minutes.pdf?fixcache=20220923142255">eliminated</a> availability except on Election Day. And the Pennsylvania Senate passed a bill that would have banned them throughout the state.</p>



<p>“Drop boxes were never approved by the General Assembly in the first place,” state Sen. Doug Mastriano, who co-sponsored the bill, said in a statement.</p>



<p>The measure failed to advance in the House of Representatives. Mastriano is the Republican candidate for governor in Pennsylvania, and in his platform, he pledges to “get rid of drop boxes.”</p>



<p>The attacks on this method of voting don’t sit right with Greg Guzik. The 75-year-old retired Vietnam veteran is a Westmoreland County booster, calling it “the best place in the nation.” He lives in Ligonier, at the foot of the Laurel Highlands.</p>



<p>He was among those submitting public comments to the county commission in October 2020, calling for additional drop boxes. He tried to use what was then the county’s only location but arrived with his ballot before it had been set up.</p>



<p>Guzik was not pleased about the county commission’s changes in 2022 and didn’t buy the explanation that cost was the driver. “I&#8217;m appalled, to tell you the truth,” he said.</p>



<p>Misinformation about the 2020 election is rampant in the area, Guzik said. That suspicion over elections didn’t exist when he was growing up in nearby Bradenville, but over the last two years “it seeped into every crack and town and small burg in these Southwestern PA counties.”</p>



<p>He’s watched with dismay the restrictions in the nation’s voting access. Guzik describes himself as “all about flag waving” and says he believes the government should make it easy for Americans to cast their ballots. “To have that taken away? We&#8217;re moving backwards as a country.”</p>



<p><em>Center for Public Integrity journalist Ileana Garnand also contributed to this story.</em></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://publicintegrity.org/politics/elections/who-counts/campaign-to-stamp-out-ballot-drop-boxes/">‘Chaos and confusion’: The campaign to stamp out ballot drop boxes</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://publicintegrity.org">Center for Public Integrity</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">116865</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Drilling down on water access as drought becomes the ‘new normal’&#160;&#160;</title>
		<link>https://publicintegrity.org/environment/natural-resources/drilling-down-on-water-access-as-drought-becomes-the-new-normal/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yvette Cabrera]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2022 11:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Natural Resources]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Watchdog newsletter]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://publicintegrity.org/?p=116858</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<figure><img width="300" height="200" src="https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/GettyImages-1240701723-scaled.jpg?fit=300%2C200&amp;ssl=1" class="attachment-medium size-medium wp-post-image" alt="" decoding="async" loading="lazy" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/GettyImages-1240701723-scaled.jpg?w=2560&amp;ssl=1 2560w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/GettyImages-1240701723-scaled.jpg?resize=300%2C200&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/GettyImages-1240701723-scaled.jpg?resize=1024%2C683&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/GettyImages-1240701723-scaled.jpg?resize=768%2C512&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/GettyImages-1240701723-scaled.jpg?resize=1536%2C1024&amp;ssl=1 1536w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/GettyImages-1240701723-scaled.jpg?resize=2048%2C1365&amp;ssl=1 2048w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/GettyImages-1240701723-scaled.jpg?resize=1200%2C800&amp;ssl=1 1200w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/GettyImages-1240701723-scaled.jpg?resize=1568%2C1045&amp;ssl=1 1568w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/GettyImages-1240701723-scaled.jpg?resize=400%2C267&amp;ssl=1 400w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/GettyImages-1240701723-scaled.jpg?resize=150%2C100&amp;ssl=1 150w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/GettyImages-1240701723-scaled.jpg?w=2340&amp;ssl=1 2340w" sizes="(max-width: 34.9rem) calc(100vw - 2rem), (max-width: 53rem) calc(8 * (100vw / 12)), (min-width: 53rem) calc(6 * (100vw / 12)), 100vw" /></figure>
<p>Crystal Tulley-Cordova’s job is addressing one of the most pressing needs of the Navajo Nation: access to clean water.&#160; Water is a calling that Tulley-Cordova, 39 and an enrolled member of the Navajo Nation, was drawn to from an early age. She and her family experienced the struggles of accessing safe drinking water, traveling long [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://publicintegrity.org/environment/natural-resources/drilling-down-on-water-access-as-drought-becomes-the-new-normal/">Drilling down on water access as drought becomes the ‘new normal’&nbsp;&nbsp;</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://publicintegrity.org">Center for Public Integrity</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure><img width="300" height="200" src="https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/GettyImages-1240701723-scaled.jpg?fit=300%2C200&amp;ssl=1" class="attachment-medium size-medium wp-post-image" alt="" decoding="async" loading="lazy" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/GettyImages-1240701723-scaled.jpg?w=2560&amp;ssl=1 2560w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/GettyImages-1240701723-scaled.jpg?resize=300%2C200&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/GettyImages-1240701723-scaled.jpg?resize=1024%2C683&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/GettyImages-1240701723-scaled.jpg?resize=768%2C512&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/GettyImages-1240701723-scaled.jpg?resize=1536%2C1024&amp;ssl=1 1536w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/GettyImages-1240701723-scaled.jpg?resize=2048%2C1365&amp;ssl=1 2048w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/GettyImages-1240701723-scaled.jpg?resize=1200%2C800&amp;ssl=1 1200w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/GettyImages-1240701723-scaled.jpg?resize=1568%2C1045&amp;ssl=1 1568w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/GettyImages-1240701723-scaled.jpg?resize=400%2C267&amp;ssl=1 400w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/GettyImages-1240701723-scaled.jpg?resize=150%2C100&amp;ssl=1 150w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/GettyImages-1240701723-scaled.jpg?w=2340&amp;ssl=1 2340w" sizes="(max-width: 34.9rem) calc(100vw - 2rem), (max-width: 53rem) calc(8 * (100vw / 12)), (min-width: 53rem) calc(6 * (100vw / 12)), 100vw" /></figure><span class="rt-reading-time" style="display: block;"><span class="rt-label rt-prefix">Reading Time: </span> <span class="rt-time">9</span> <span class="rt-label rt-postfix">minutes</span></span>
<p>Crystal Tulley-Cordova’s job is addressing one of the most pressing needs of the Navajo Nation: access to clean water.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Water is a calling that Tulley-Cordova, 39 and an enrolled member of the Navajo Nation, was drawn to from an early age. She and her family experienced the struggles of accessing safe drinking water, traveling long distances over dirt roads to meet their basic water needs on a daily basis.</p>



<p>Today, she is the principal hydrologist for the Navajo Nation Department of Water Resources’ water management branch. She tackles a wide array of issues across more than 27,000 square miles of reservation land: securing water rights, providing access to clean water during the COVID-19 pandemic, offering her expertise on water development projects.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<div class="is-layout-flow wp-block-group alignwide newspack-pattern subscribe__style-6 is-style-border compress-newsletter has-secondary-background-color has-background"><div class="wp-block-group__inner-container">
<div class="is-layout-flex wp-container-27 wp-block-columns are-vertically-aligned-center">
<div class="is-layout-flow wp-block-column is-vertically-aligned-center">
<p class="has-white-color has-text-color"><meta charset="utf-8"><strong>Watchdog delivered </strong></p>



<p class="has-white-color has-text-color has-small-font-size">Want our investigations in your inbox? Subscribe to our Watchdog newsletter.</p>
</div>



<div class="is-layout-flow wp-block-column is-vertically-aligned-center"><amp-layout id="nadd">
	<div class="wp-block-jetpack-mailchimp" data-blog-id="201594328">
		<form
			aria-describedby="wp-block-jetpack-mailchimp_consent-text"
					>
			<p>
				<input
					aria-label="Enter your email"
					placeholder="Enter your email"
					required
					title="Enter your email"
					type="email"
					name="email"
				/>
			</p>
							<input
					name="interests[3f37dae637]"
					type="hidden"
					class="mc-submit-param"
					value="1"
				/>
									
<div class="wp-block-jetpack-button wp-block-button" style=""><button class="wp-block-button__link has-background has-primary-background-color" style="" data-id-attr="mailchimp-button-block-25" id="mailchimp-button-block-25" type="submit"><strong>Sign up</strong></button></div>
			<p id="wp-block-jetpack-mailchimp_consent-text">
							</p>

			
		</form>
		
			<div class="wp-block-jetpack-mailchimp_notification wp-block-jetpack-mailchimp_processing" role="status">
				Processing…			</div>
			<div class="wp-block-jetpack-mailchimp_notification wp-block-jetpack-mailchimp_success" role="status">
				Success! You&#039;re on the list.			</div>
			<div class="wp-block-jetpack-mailchimp_notification wp-block-jetpack-mailchimp_error" role="alert">
				Whoops! There was an error and we couldn&#039;t process your subscription. Please reload the page and try again.			</div>

			</div>
	</amp-layout></div>
</div>
</div></div>



<p>When she joined the agency in 2018 she achieved a long-time goal: giving back to her community by working to improve water security for the Navajo people, the Diné. Last year, the American Indian Science and Engineering Society <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=M_-a7yLOznA">selected</a> Tulley-Cordova as Professional of the Year.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Tulley-Cordova sees water quality playing a critical role in people’s health. She witnessed first-hand the devastating impacts of environmental degradation on community members who lived in regions affected by uranium mining pollution, which seeped into drinking water and can trigger conditions including cancer.&nbsp;</p>



<p>She grew up in Rock Springs, New Mexico, where she now lives with her husband, their two young children and her parents. Her mother, who hails from Rock Springs, fought and survived a painful battle with breast cancer when Tulley-Cordova was a teenager. Her maternal grandmother, who was diagnosed with lung cancer, did not survive. She is the eldest daughter of Earl Tulley, a longtime environmental justice advocate who has worked to address contamination issues impacting Navajo communities.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>She has a doctoral degree in geology and an interdisciplinary graduate certificate in sustainability from the University of Utah.&nbsp;</p>



<p><em>This conversation has been edited for length and clarity.</em></p>



<p><strong>Q.</strong> <strong>You grew up within a community that had water access issues. Can you talk about how those experiences growing up inspired you to seek a career that would address those water access issues?</strong></p>



<p>My earliest water memory is hearing water getting heated up on a stove so that I could take a bath. I was probably around two or three. After that, early water memories also consist of hauling water, so [going] to a livestock well to get water. We relied on unregulated water, and I didn&#8217;t know that until I began to learn about water — like there&#8217;s a Clean Water Act, there&#8217;s regulated water from a tap; how is that different than where we used to get water?&nbsp;</p>



<p>I&#8217;ve always had an interest in water. I did a fourth-grade science project: a water filtration project, using different sediments, and filtering out water to [study] the turbidity of water.&nbsp;</p>



<p>[In college] I took geology courses, and I really enjoy being in the field, enjoy this interaction between ground water, knowing about geology and where water is stored, because in the Navajo Nation we don&#8217;t have a lot of surface water. We have a lot of groundwater. So just having this understanding that water is so powerful that it can form things like Canyon de Chelly and the Grand Canyon.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But also, water is so powerful that you can see exposed outcrops of places where we get water, like the Navajo sandstone, the coconino sandstone. That&#8217;s where we get our water from, so it&#8217;s just mind boggling as you look at the pores, using a hand lens, of those geologic formations, to think: Wow! The water that we have is coming from these formations.</p>



<p>Also, a lot of the work that my dad did with environmental justice, being an environmental justice advocate, was also related to water. There&#8217;s this nexus between uranium contamination and water contamination. I just had a greater desire to learn more about it. Going to school, it used to be weird telling people I grew up without running water. And I realized then that there&#8217;s also social justice issues associated with who I am, where I am from, where our marginalized communities were impacted by social and environmental justice.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Then going to college realizing that the <a href="https://www.usbr.gov/climate/secure/docs/2016secure/factsheet/ColoradoRiverBasinFactSheet.pdf">Seven Basin States</a> had representatives that signed a <a href="https://www.usbr.gov/lc/region/pao/pdfiles/crcompct.pdf">foundational document</a> for the Colorado River, but tribes didn&#8217;t have all of their water rights resolved. … There&#8217;s 30 tribes in the Colorado River Basin; there&#8217;s a portion that do have secured water rights. But there&#8217;s a good portion that doesn&#8217;t have secured water rights. And as climate change impacts continue to occur, our reliability on water is critical for not only Native Americans, but the human race.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Everything in our environment is reliant upon water, and having that understanding, all of the complexity of it really intrigued me, but also the desire to improve the area that I come from. So to now be back in the Navajo Nation is like living the dream.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But also, living the dream doesn&#8217;t mean that it&#8217;s always happy. It&#8217;s like a roller coaster where you experience great moments, but you also really experience sad, disheartening moments.</p>



<p><strong>Q.</strong> <strong>Can you talk about the intersection of the environmental health issues and the potential exposure of the Navajo community to pollution issues that intersect with water like uranium contamination? How big of a role did that play in your decision to pursue a career in water resources?</strong></p>



<p>My decision to be a water manager, specifically to be a hydrologist, was related to the opportunity to address the disparity of people not having water. There&#8217;s a lot of improvement of life that comes with having piped water. And not only that aspect, but also the aspect of environmental justice issues.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I feel like the greatest way to make change is working from the inside out, meaning you&#8217;re a part of an organization; you make recommendations; you&#8217;re an adviser, an expert [working] to improve the quality of life. And in this case, working as a water manager, I am improving the quality of life for Navajo residents, so that we can get out of the survival mode and go into a thriving mode.&nbsp;</p>



<p>For a long time, Indigenous people in this country, after contact, have had to learn how to survive. But the work that I&#8217;m a part of is really about the opportunity to help Indigenous people — the first Americans of this country ​​— be able to thrive. And how can we do that? We can do that through water development, because water development is a critical foundation to economic development, to improvement of reservations.</p>



<p><strong>Q.</strong> <strong>What would you say are the most pressing issues facing the Navajo Nation connected to water?&nbsp;</strong></p>



<p>The mission of what we do is to protect and manage water resources for the Navajo Nation, and there&#8217;s a large percentage of Navajo residents that don&#8217;t have piped water. So there&#8217;s this development push for improvement of water. That&#8217;s a mitigation strategy to address climate change impacts in the Navajo Nation specifically on water.&nbsp;</p>



<p>At the time that I started my job, [we were facing] 20 years of drought. The Navajo Nation is experiencing short-term, long-term drought.</p>



<p>And when you&#8217;re doing these projects like building regional water supply systems, working on securing water rights, you&#8217;re [addressing] a priority that secures water for your community and creates sustainability.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Q. The COVID-19 pandemic highlighted the needs around access to water. You came up with specific solutions in response to that. Could you talk about the work that you did in that area?</strong></p>



<p>As the pandemic happened, it put a spotlight on the disparities and on the clean water access gap that was in existence in the Navajo Nation. Not only in the Navajo Nation: for other tribes and Alaska Native villages throughout the United States, and in addition to that, rural communities.&nbsp;</p>



<p>When the COVID pandemic happened, at the start of it, the CDC [Centers for Disease Control and Prevention] asks you to wear a mask and wash your hands often. How do you do that if you&#8217;re a water hauler [who lacks running water]?&nbsp;</p>



<p>And you&#8217;ll hear variable numbers, like almost 40% [of the population doesn’t have piped water] is what the president of the Navajo Nation has described in Senate testimony. And then you&#8217;ll hear from the Indian Health Service that maybe it&#8217;s closer to 10 to 20%, depending on what report you use.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But in all honesty, no one knows the right number, because there&#8217;s never been a water census, meaning someone going to every home to ask who has piped water and who doesn&#8217;t. So that&#8217;s why there&#8217;s so much variability in the percentage of homes, the number of people impacted. No one knows those true numbers.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So what did we do to be able to address the clean water access gap? In collaboration with the Indian Health Service, the Navajo Nation COVID-19 Water Access Coordination group formed, and the first wave of money came with the <a href="https://www.kff.org/coronavirus-covid-19/issue-brief/the-coronavirus-aid-relief-and-economic-security-act-summary-of-key-health-provisions/">CARES Act</a>, $3.5 million, and that money was used to create 59 transitional water points. There&#8217;s 110 Navajo communities, and out of those 110 only a portion of them have permanent <a href="https://storymaps.arcgis.com/stories/1b4dc0d978c74d97a559e615730d4cd4">watering points</a>, and that&#8217;s why the additional 59 had to be created for residents, for communities that didn&#8217;t have a previously existing watering point.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so now we&#8217;re in the phase of <a href="https://www.congress.gov/bill/117th-congress/house-bill/1319/text">ARPA</a> , $3 million dollars from BIA [Bureau of Indian Affairs] for potable water service, potable water delivery, and then approximately $2.7 million from the Indian Health Service to also address potable water delivery.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Some of the immediate relief was stop-gap measures to help with water haulers, but where the security and sustainability really comes from is under Bipartisan Infrastructure Law funding … and then additionally being able to use the ARPA funding to be able to create long-term projects. So these long-term projects are like water transmission lines, cistern and septic projects.&nbsp; Because in the Navajo Nation we have sparse population and rural living, so not everyone can get hooked up to piped water.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Q.</strong> <strong>Given your background in geology, can you talk a little bit about the work that you&#8217;re trying to do to address that intersection of the legacy uranium contamination with the water access issues?&nbsp;</strong></p>



<p>One thing to understand is there are specific areas that are focused on addressing the legacy issues, like we have the Abandoned Mine Lands Department, we have Navajo EPA Superfund efforts that are specifically addressing those cleanup efforts, mitigation efforts, etc. How I lend my expertise to those is providing technical feedback regarding data that may need to be included.&nbsp;</p>



<p>By bringing watering points closer to residents, and by working on these bulk water supply delivery projects, it is really creating that sustainability by interconnecting public water systems of Navajo Nation communities. We create more security, more sustainability, rather than having them as standalone public water systems. …</p>



<p>I do a lot of technical support for the water rights efforts that are unresolved, as well as the ones that have been resolved and are currently going into place. Participating in those water rights efforts provides that opportunity to be able to secure water. Like diversifying our water portfolio. That&#8217;s what water rights is doing. Where we not only would have to rely upon groundwater, which historically we previously have done, but by adding surface water we&#8217;re creating that sustainability.</p>



<p><strong>Q</strong>.<strong> Can you situate us as to the overall water rights access that the Navajo Nation has?&nbsp;</strong></p>



<p>A large percentage of the Navajo Nation doesn&#8217;t have secured water rights. We haven&#8217;t resolved our water rights in Arizona, and Arizona is a large chunk of land of our nation.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We have secured water rights with the <a href="https://www.navajonationcouncil.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Navajo_Utah_Water_Rights_2022.05.27.pdf">Navajo Utah Water Rights Settlement Act</a> in Utah along the San Juan River. We have secured water rights in the San Juan River Basin in New Mexico. We&#8217;re working to resolve our water rights in the Zuni River Basin in the Rio San Jose Basin.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Water rights can be resolved in a couple of different manners, meaning through litigation or through settlement. Litigation — courts tell you what you get. [With] a settlement, you negotiate with other parties to secure what you’d like to get. It doesn&#8217;t mean everyone gets what they want.</p>



<p><strong>Q. What keeps you up at night as far as drought challenges?</strong></p>



<p>When you have a law of the river for the Colorado River Basin that&#8217;s not inclusive of tribes as sovereigns, that provides a challenge for the Colorado River Basin.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And the way in which the Colorado River Basin is managed with the upper and the lower basin, that&#8217;s what keeps me up at night. Because right now, what climatologists are encouraging us to accept is to stop calling it drought. Drought indicates that it&#8217;s a short-term situation. What they&#8217;re encouraging us to use instead is aridification. That the conditions of dry are the new normal.&nbsp;</p>





<p><strong>Q.</strong> <strong>In addition to economic development, how important of a role does water play in the lives of Navajo community members in terms of their culture?</strong></p>



<p>Every time when I share presentations, I always share that I am of the Bitter Water clan, born from the Tangle People clan; that my maternal grandfather&#8217;s clan is the Yucca Fruit Strung On A Line, and my paternal grandfather&#8217;s clan is the Water That Flows Together.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Through that identity there&#8217;s no doubt that we are water beings, meaning the Diné People of the Four Corners region of this land. And it&#8217;s important that I have that understanding of our cultural identity that comes through the clan system. And that provides a greater basis for the work that I do, being able to be a part of this vital work that is so needed for tribes, nations and pueblos throughout this country,</p>



<p>As far as the cultural identity tie, there&#8217;s a lot of acknowledgment within Navajo Nation leadership about the reverence and respect for water: to be able to carry out ceremonies that have been done for generations, to be able to continue those in reverence and respect for water. So, even though the work that I do is science-driven, there is this spiritual aspect as Indigenous people that we have a connection to with regards to the world that we&#8217;re in. And being able to understand that spirituality is also a part of the work that we do.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Q.</strong> <strong>At the end of your career, what do you hope to have accomplished when it comes to providing safe drinking water across the Navajo Nation?</strong></p>



<p>I hope to bring and provide sustainable solutions that provide a secure and sustainable water future. There&#8217;s a lot of work to be done.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The capacity that we have is not sufficient enough to be able to address these issues. There&#8217;s all this money, unprecedented money that has come available. CARES Act, ARPA, the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law. We have a decreased workforce than we started with before the pandemic, and these additional resources are out there, and the challenge is everyone&#8217;s getting that money, not just tribes. And so there is a competition for people who can do the work as well.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I know people have passed this legislation in good faith, meaning they really hope that this brings relief, aid to the places that need it. But I think even our best efforts sometimes are not good enough. And the same can be said for the work that I do.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I am giving every day over 100 percent. I haven&#8217;t even had a vacation in over two years. So it&#8217;s just one of those things: We&#8217;re holding on the best that we can. We&#8217;re doing the best that we can with the little that we have.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://publicintegrity.org/environment/natural-resources/drilling-down-on-water-access-as-drought-becomes-the-new-normal/">Drilling down on water access as drought becomes the ‘new normal’&nbsp;&nbsp;</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://publicintegrity.org">Center for Public Integrity</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">116858</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Public Integrity honors founder Charles Lewis with renaming of fellowship </title>
		<link>https://publicintegrity.org/inside-publici/public-integrity-honors-founder-charles-lewis-with-renaming-of-fellowship/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Hayden Godfrey]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Inside Public Integrity]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://publicintegrity.org/?p=116833</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<figure><img width="300" height="158" src="https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/chuck-lewis-1_5589884_1200x630-1.jpg?fit=300%2C158&amp;ssl=1" class="attachment-medium size-medium wp-post-image" alt="Charles Lewis leans agains the wall with his hands folded." decoding="async" loading="lazy" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/chuck-lewis-1_5589884_1200x630-1.jpg?w=1333&amp;ssl=1 1333w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/chuck-lewis-1_5589884_1200x630-1.jpg?resize=300%2C158&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/chuck-lewis-1_5589884_1200x630-1.jpg?resize=1024%2C538&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/chuck-lewis-1_5589884_1200x630-1.jpg?resize=768%2C403&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/chuck-lewis-1_5589884_1200x630-1.jpg?resize=1200%2C630&amp;ssl=1 1200w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/chuck-lewis-1_5589884_1200x630-1.jpg?resize=400%2C210&amp;ssl=1 400w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/chuck-lewis-1_5589884_1200x630-1.jpg?resize=150%2C79&amp;ssl=1 150w" sizes="(max-width: 34.9rem) calc(100vw - 2rem), (max-width: 53rem) calc(8 * (100vw / 12)), (min-width: 53rem) calc(6 * (100vw / 12)), 100vw" /></figure>
<p>At a ceremony honoring the career of Center for Public Integrity founder Charles “Chuck” Lewis earlier this month, CEO Paul Cheung announced that Public Integrity was renaming its graduate fellowship to the Charles Lewis American University Fellowship at the Center for Public Integrity. The joint fellowship with American University, currently held by graduate student Ileana [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://publicintegrity.org/inside-publici/public-integrity-honors-founder-charles-lewis-with-renaming-of-fellowship/">Public Integrity honors founder Charles Lewis with renaming of fellowship </a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://publicintegrity.org">Center for Public Integrity</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure><img width="300" height="158" src="https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/chuck-lewis-1_5589884_1200x630-1.jpg?fit=300%2C158&amp;ssl=1" class="attachment-medium size-medium wp-post-image" alt="Charles Lewis leans agains the wall with his hands folded." decoding="async" loading="lazy" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/chuck-lewis-1_5589884_1200x630-1.jpg?w=1333&amp;ssl=1 1333w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/chuck-lewis-1_5589884_1200x630-1.jpg?resize=300%2C158&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/chuck-lewis-1_5589884_1200x630-1.jpg?resize=1024%2C538&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/chuck-lewis-1_5589884_1200x630-1.jpg?resize=768%2C403&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/chuck-lewis-1_5589884_1200x630-1.jpg?resize=1200%2C630&amp;ssl=1 1200w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/chuck-lewis-1_5589884_1200x630-1.jpg?resize=400%2C210&amp;ssl=1 400w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/chuck-lewis-1_5589884_1200x630-1.jpg?resize=150%2C79&amp;ssl=1 150w" sizes="(max-width: 34.9rem) calc(100vw - 2rem), (max-width: 53rem) calc(8 * (100vw / 12)), (min-width: 53rem) calc(6 * (100vw / 12)), 100vw" /></figure><span class="rt-reading-time" style="display: block;"><span class="rt-label rt-prefix">Reading Time: </span> <span class="rt-time">3</span> <span class="rt-label rt-postfix">minutes</span></span>
<p>At a ceremony honoring the career of <a href="https://publicintegrity.org/">Center for Public Integrity</a> founder Charles “Chuck” Lewis earlier this month, CEO Paul Cheung announced that Public Integrity was renaming its graduate fellowship to <a href="https://www.american.edu/soc/resources/grad-fellowships-scholarships.cfm">the Charles Lewis American University Fellowship at the Center for Public Integrity</a>.</p>



<p>The joint fellowship with American University, currently held by graduate student <a href="https://publicintegrity.org/author/igarnandpublicintegrity-org/">Ileana Garnand</a>, provides an opportunity for aspiring journalists studying at AU to report for Public Integrity on a host of issues related to inequality, discrimination and democracy.</p>



<div class="is-layout-flow wp-block-group alignwide newspack-pattern subscribe__style-6 is-style-border compress-newsletter has-secondary-background-color has-background"><div class="wp-block-group__inner-container">
<div class="is-layout-flex wp-container-32 wp-block-columns are-vertically-aligned-center">
<div class="is-layout-flow wp-block-column is-vertically-aligned-center">
<p class="has-white-color has-text-color"><meta charset="utf-8"><strong>Watchdog delivered </strong></p>



<p class="has-white-color has-text-color has-small-font-size">Want our investigations in your inbox? Subscribe to our Watchdog newsletter.</p>
</div>



<div class="is-layout-flow wp-block-column is-vertically-aligned-center"><amp-layout id="n3c3">
	<div class="wp-block-jetpack-mailchimp" data-blog-id="201594328">
		<form
			aria-describedby="wp-block-jetpack-mailchimp_consent-text"
					>
			<p>
				<input
					aria-label="Enter your email"
					placeholder="Enter your email"
					required
					title="Enter your email"
					type="email"
					name="email"
				/>
			</p>
							<input
					name="interests[3f37dae637]"
					type="hidden"
					class="mc-submit-param"
					value="1"
				/>
									
<div class="wp-block-jetpack-button wp-block-button" style=""><button class="wp-block-button__link has-background has-primary-background-color" style="" data-id-attr="mailchimp-button-block-30" id="mailchimp-button-block-30" type="submit"><strong>Sign up</strong></button></div>
			<p id="wp-block-jetpack-mailchimp_consent-text">
							</p>

			
		</form>
		
			<div class="wp-block-jetpack-mailchimp_notification wp-block-jetpack-mailchimp_processing" role="status">
				Processing…			</div>
			<div class="wp-block-jetpack-mailchimp_notification wp-block-jetpack-mailchimp_success" role="status">
				Success! You&#039;re on the list.			</div>
			<div class="wp-block-jetpack-mailchimp_notification wp-block-jetpack-mailchimp_error" role="alert">
				Whoops! There was an error and we couldn&#039;t process your subscription. Please reload the page and try again.			</div>

			</div>
	</amp-layout></div>
</div>
</div></div>



<p>“When I was appointed, Chuck was really generous in reaching out and giving some great advice,” Cheung told attendees.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>That advice included the importance of innovating in journalism, Cheung said. “His tagline is ‘when they zig, we zag.’ This is something we have tried to live every single day in honor of his legacy.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>Journalists from Mother Jones, Bloomberg Industry Group, USA Today and FRONTLINE along with colleagues and supporters were among the nearly 70 people who honored Lewis’ storied career at a special event on American University’s campus.</p>



<p>“Whenever you meet a journalist and say you work at AU, they say, ‘Wait, you know Chuck Lewis?’” said Amy Eisman, the director of the journalism division at the School of Communication. “Just being in the same building with him raises us all up. The conversation invariably moves on to two things: how much Chuck has done for investigative journalism and how humble he is about it.”</p>



<p>Lewis, a native of Delaware, had an acclaimed career as a producer for ABC News and CBS News’ “60 Minutes,” which he left to found Public Integrity in 1989 and the International Consortium of Investigative Journalists, recognized in the last few years for its worldwide investigative stories including &#8220;The Panama Papers.&#8221;&nbsp;</p>





<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity is-style-wide"/>



<p>He joined American University in 2006 and created the <a href="https://investigativereportingworkshop.org/">Investigative Reporting Workshop</a> with faculty colleague Wendell Cochran in 2008, an editorially independent nonprofit newsroom It&#8217;s a model he helped to pioneer and grow nationwide.&nbsp;</p>



<p>When he retires from the faculty on Dec. 31, Lewis will be named emeritus status as a professor, and will remain with IRW as emeritus executive editor. A nationwide search for a new executive editor and full-time faculty member is underway. John Sullivan, a reporter and editor at The Washington Post and a senior editor at IRW, is interim executive editor.</p>



<p>Lewis wrote “935 Lies: The Future of Truth and the Decline of America’s Moral Integrity” and has co-authored five Public Integrity books, including the New York Times-bestselling “The Buying of the President 2004.” He was named&nbsp; a MacArthur Fellow in 1998 and has held fellowships at the University of Oxford and Harvard University.&nbsp;</p>



<p>“Chuck told me a long time ago that he thought one of his biggest strengths was introducing people to each other,” said Lynne Perri, the managing editor of IRW. “At the time, I thought perhaps he was exaggerating. But all these years later, having seen the connections up close and made many long-lasting ones myself, thanks to Chuck, I can say that yes, he’s right.”</p>



<p>Under Lewis’ stewardship, IRW has researched and reported hundreds of stories, many of which have been co-published by both legacy media and other nonprofits, including The Washington Post, NPR, PBS FRONTLINE, the National Journal, The Philadelphia Inquirer and many more local sites. IRW fellows and interns now report for NBC News, Politico, Colorado Public Radio, the Louisville Courier-Journal, the Miami Herald and many other publications.</p>



<p>“Chuck has had a huge impact on my career,” said Alexia Fernandez Campbell, a former graduate student at AU who was also a fellow at IRW. “He gave me the confidence I needed to pursue a career in investigative journalism. More than anything, he taught me that good investigative journalists aren’t born with some mysterious set of skills. All it takes is determination, curiosity and a deep commitment to holding powerful people accountable for their actions.”</p>



<p>Her career has taken her to reporting stints at Vox, the National Journal, the Atlantic —&nbsp;and now Public Integrity.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://publicintegrity.org/inside-publici/public-integrity-honors-founder-charles-lewis-with-renaming-of-fellowship/">Public Integrity honors founder Charles Lewis with renaming of fellowship </a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://publicintegrity.org">Center for Public Integrity</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">116833</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Join us: Building a diverse future for investigative news</title>
		<link>https://publicintegrity.org/inside-publici/live-events/join-us-building-a-diverse-future-for-investigative-news/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The Center for Public Integrity]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 18:09:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Live Events]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://publicintegrity.org/?p=116790</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<figure><img width="300" height="176" src="https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/mc-nelly-award2.jpg?fit=300%2C176&amp;ssl=1" class="attachment-medium size-medium wp-post-image" alt="" decoding="async" loading="lazy" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/mc-nelly-award2.jpg?w=1250&amp;ssl=1 1250w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/mc-nelly-award2.jpg?resize=300%2C176&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/mc-nelly-award2.jpg?resize=1024%2C600&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/mc-nelly-award2.jpg?resize=768%2C450&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/mc-nelly-award2.jpg?resize=1200%2C703&amp;ssl=1 1200w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/mc-nelly-award2.jpg?resize=400%2C234&amp;ssl=1 400w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/mc-nelly-award2.jpg?resize=150%2C88&amp;ssl=1 150w" sizes="(max-width: 34.9rem) calc(100vw - 2rem), (max-width: 53rem) calc(8 * (100vw / 12)), (min-width: 53rem) calc(6 * (100vw / 12)), 100vw" /></figure>
<p>Update: The recording of the discussion has been posted above. Join the Center for Public Integrity Nov. 2, 2022, at 6:30 pm EDT for a virtual fireside chat featuring Public Integrity Editor Mc Nelly Torres. Nicole Dungca, a Washington Post investigative reporter and incoming president of Asian American Journalists Association, will moderate the chat.  Dungca and [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://publicintegrity.org/inside-publici/live-events/join-us-building-a-diverse-future-for-investigative-news/">Join us: Building a diverse future for investigative news</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://publicintegrity.org">Center for Public Integrity</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure><img width="300" height="176" src="https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/mc-nelly-award2.jpg?fit=300%2C176&amp;ssl=1" class="attachment-medium size-medium wp-post-image" alt="" decoding="async" loading="lazy" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/mc-nelly-award2.jpg?w=1250&amp;ssl=1 1250w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/mc-nelly-award2.jpg?resize=300%2C176&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/mc-nelly-award2.jpg?resize=1024%2C600&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/mc-nelly-award2.jpg?resize=768%2C450&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/mc-nelly-award2.jpg?resize=1200%2C703&amp;ssl=1 1200w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/mc-nelly-award2.jpg?resize=400%2C234&amp;ssl=1 400w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/mc-nelly-award2.jpg?resize=150%2C88&amp;ssl=1 150w" sizes="(max-width: 34.9rem) calc(100vw - 2rem), (max-width: 53rem) calc(8 * (100vw / 12)), (min-width: 53rem) calc(6 * (100vw / 12)), 100vw" /></figure><span class="rt-reading-time" style="display: block;"><span class="rt-label rt-prefix">Reading Time: </span> <span class="rt-time">2</span> <span class="rt-label rt-postfix">minutes</span></span>
<iframe loading="lazy" src="https://www.facebook.com/plugins/video.php?href=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.facebook.com%2Fpublici%2Fvideos%2F3468934376764413%2F&amp;width=1280" width="1280" height="720" style="border:none;overflow:hidden" scrolling="no" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="true" allow="autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; picture-in-picture; web-share"></iframe>



<p><em><strong>Update: </strong>The recording of the discussion has been posted above. </em></p>



<p>Join the Center for Public Integrity Nov. 2, 2022, at 6:30 pm EDT for a virtual fireside chat featuring Public Integrity Editor Mc Nelly Torres. Nicole Dungca, a Washington Post investigative reporter and incoming president of Asian American Journalists Association, will moderate the chat. </p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="alignleft size-full is-resized"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/Mc-Nelly-Torres-1.jpeg?resize=300%2C340&#038;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-115387" width="300" height="340" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/Mc-Nelly-Torres-1.jpeg?w=800&amp;ssl=1 800w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/Mc-Nelly-Torres-1.jpeg?resize=265%2C300&amp;ssl=1 265w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/Mc-Nelly-Torres-1.jpeg?resize=768%2C871&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/Mc-Nelly-Torres-1.jpeg?resize=400%2C454&amp;ssl=1 400w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/Mc-Nelly-Torres-1.jpeg?resize=150%2C170&amp;ssl=1 150w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" data-recalc-dims="1" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Mc Nelly Torres (Courtesy of Mc Nelly Torres)</figcaption></figure></div>


<p>Dungca and Torres will explore an array of topics, including Torres&#8217; experience as a Latina investigative reporter, her life-long commitment to promoting diversity and inclusion in news; and her recent achievements in leadership, including building an all-Latino investigative team and championing advocacy messaging on behalf of journalists of color as one of the leaders&nbsp;at the National Association of Hispanic Journalists national board.</p>



<p>Mc Nelly Torres is the winner of this year’s distinguished <a href="https://www.iwmf.org/awards/gwen-ifill-award/">Gwen Ifill Award</a> from the International Women’s Media Foundation. In its sixth year, the IWMF’s Gwen Ifill Award honors a remarkable woman journalist of color whose work embodies Ifill’s legacy of supporting and elevating women of color in news media.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="alignleft size-full is-resized"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Nicole-Dungca.jpg?resize=301%2C288&#038;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-116829" width="301" height="288" data-recalc-dims="1" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Nicole Dungca</figcaption></figure></div>


<p>Torres has dedicated her career to elevating Latino voices in news through mentorship, training, coaching and advocacy. In her role at Public Integrity, Torres leads one of the few all-Latino investigative teams in the country. In her career, Torres has spent more than a decade producing award-winning investigative journalism for outlets including NBC6 Miami, the South Florida Sun-Sentinel and the San Antonio Express-News. She&nbsp; co-founded the Florida Center for Investigative Reporting and was the first Latina elected to the board of directors of the Investigative Reporters and Editors and the Florida Society of News Editors. Torres’ success spotlights the Center for Public Integrity’s transformation to report on inequality and our commitment to diverse voices in investigative journalism.</p>



<p>The event will be broadcast live from this webpage as well as from Public Integrity’s <a href="https://www.facebook.com/publici">Facebook page</a>. Virtual viewers will be able to ask questions during the conversation through Facebook comments.</p>



<p>This event is sponsored by the Knight Foundation. Event streaming is sponsored by American Press Institute. Investigative Reporters and Editors, the National Association of Hispanic Journalists, and Asian American Journalists Association are the diversity sponsors of the event.</p>



<figure class="is-layout-flex wp-block-gallery-34 wp-block-gallery has-nested-images columns-default is-cropped">
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="500" height="142" data-id="117039"  src="https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Knight-Foundation_logo-stacked.png?resize=500%2C142&#038;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-117039" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Knight-Foundation_logo-stacked.png?w=500&amp;ssl=1 500w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Knight-Foundation_logo-stacked.png?resize=300%2C85&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Knight-Foundation_logo-stacked.png?resize=400%2C114&amp;ssl=1 400w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Knight-Foundation_logo-stacked.png?resize=150%2C43&amp;ssl=1 150w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" data-recalc-dims="1" /></figure>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="780" height="215" data-id="117038"  src="https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/American-Press-Institute-logo_Full_BlackOrange.png?resize=780%2C215&#038;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-117038" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/American-Press-Institute-logo_Full_BlackOrange.png?w=800&amp;ssl=1 800w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/American-Press-Institute-logo_Full_BlackOrange.png?resize=300%2C83&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/American-Press-Institute-logo_Full_BlackOrange.png?resize=768%2C211&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/American-Press-Institute-logo_Full_BlackOrange.png?resize=400%2C110&amp;ssl=1 400w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/American-Press-Institute-logo_Full_BlackOrange.png?resize=150%2C41&amp;ssl=1 150w" sizes="(max-width: 780px) 100vw, 780px" data-recalc-dims="1" /></figure>
</figure>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://publicintegrity.org/inside-publici/live-events/join-us-building-a-diverse-future-for-investigative-news/">Join us: Building a diverse future for investigative news</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://publicintegrity.org">Center for Public Integrity</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">116790</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Janelle O’Dea joins Public Integrity as data reporter for local collaborations</title>
		<link>https://publicintegrity.org/inside-publici/janelle-odea-joins-public-integrity-as-data-reporter-for-local-collaborations/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The Center for Public Integrity]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 09:02:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Inside Public Integrity]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://publicintegrity.org/?p=116774</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<figure><img width="300" height="292" src="https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Janelle-ODea-2022-16-copy2-scaled.jpg?fit=300%2C292&amp;ssl=1" class="attachment-medium size-medium wp-post-image" alt="" decoding="async" loading="lazy" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Janelle-ODea-2022-16-copy2-scaled.jpg?w=2560&amp;ssl=1 2560w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Janelle-ODea-2022-16-copy2-scaled.jpg?resize=300%2C292&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Janelle-ODea-2022-16-copy2-scaled.jpg?resize=1024%2C997&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Janelle-ODea-2022-16-copy2-scaled.jpg?resize=768%2C748&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Janelle-ODea-2022-16-copy2-scaled.jpg?resize=1536%2C1496&amp;ssl=1 1536w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Janelle-ODea-2022-16-copy2-scaled.jpg?resize=2048%2C1994&amp;ssl=1 2048w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Janelle-ODea-2022-16-copy2-scaled.jpg?resize=1200%2C1169&amp;ssl=1 1200w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Janelle-ODea-2022-16-copy2-scaled.jpg?resize=1568%2C1527&amp;ssl=1 1568w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Janelle-ODea-2022-16-copy2-scaled.jpg?resize=400%2C390&amp;ssl=1 400w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Janelle-ODea-2022-16-copy2-scaled.jpg?resize=150%2C146&amp;ssl=1 150w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Janelle-ODea-2022-16-copy2-scaled.jpg?w=2340&amp;ssl=1 2340w" sizes="(max-width: 34.9rem) calc(100vw - 2rem), (max-width: 53rem) calc(8 * (100vw / 12)), (min-width: 53rem) calc(6 * (100vw / 12)), 100vw" /></figure>
<p>Janelle O’Dea is joining the Center for Public Integrity in a newly created data reporter position focused on local news collaborations and capacity-building.&#160; Strengthening the data capabilities of local news organizations, especially in underserved and underrepresented communities is a core tenet to Public Integrity’s mission to confront inequality in the U.S. She joins Public Integrity [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://publicintegrity.org/inside-publici/janelle-odea-joins-public-integrity-as-data-reporter-for-local-collaborations/">Janelle O’Dea joins Public Integrity as data reporter for local collaborations</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://publicintegrity.org">Center for Public Integrity</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure><img width="300" height="292" src="https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Janelle-ODea-2022-16-copy2-scaled.jpg?fit=300%2C292&amp;ssl=1" class="attachment-medium size-medium wp-post-image" alt="" decoding="async" loading="lazy" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Janelle-ODea-2022-16-copy2-scaled.jpg?w=2560&amp;ssl=1 2560w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Janelle-ODea-2022-16-copy2-scaled.jpg?resize=300%2C292&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Janelle-ODea-2022-16-copy2-scaled.jpg?resize=1024%2C997&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Janelle-ODea-2022-16-copy2-scaled.jpg?resize=768%2C748&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Janelle-ODea-2022-16-copy2-scaled.jpg?resize=1536%2C1496&amp;ssl=1 1536w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Janelle-ODea-2022-16-copy2-scaled.jpg?resize=2048%2C1994&amp;ssl=1 2048w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Janelle-ODea-2022-16-copy2-scaled.jpg?resize=1200%2C1169&amp;ssl=1 1200w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Janelle-ODea-2022-16-copy2-scaled.jpg?resize=1568%2C1527&amp;ssl=1 1568w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Janelle-ODea-2022-16-copy2-scaled.jpg?resize=400%2C390&amp;ssl=1 400w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Janelle-ODea-2022-16-copy2-scaled.jpg?resize=150%2C146&amp;ssl=1 150w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Janelle-ODea-2022-16-copy2-scaled.jpg?w=2340&amp;ssl=1 2340w" sizes="(max-width: 34.9rem) calc(100vw - 2rem), (max-width: 53rem) calc(8 * (100vw / 12)), (min-width: 53rem) calc(6 * (100vw / 12)), 100vw" /></figure><span class="rt-reading-time" style="display: block;"><span class="rt-label rt-prefix">Reading Time: </span> <span class="rt-time">2</span> <span class="rt-label rt-postfix">minutes</span></span>
<p>Janelle O’Dea is joining the Center for Public Integrity in a newly created data reporter position focused on local news collaborations and capacity-building.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Strengthening the data capabilities of local news organizations, especially in underserved and underrepresented communities is a core tenet to Public Integrity’s mission to confront inequality in the U.S.</p>



<p>She joins Public Integrity from the St. Louis Post-Dispatch, where she was a data reporter for five years. There, she combined the subject-matter expertise of her fellow reporters with data analysis and programming to dig deeper into stories and subjects. In 2018, she was part of the team for “<a href="http://stltoday.com/tippingpoint">Tipping Point</a>,” a series about the effects of too many vacant, dilapidated homes in St. Louis — particularly in the city&#8217;s underserved and neglected communities, where vacant housing is heavily concentrated.</p>



<p><a href="https://publicintegrity.org/wp-admin/edit.php?post_type=post"></a></p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="alignleft size-large"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="780" height="759" src="https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Janelle-ODea-2022-16-copy2.jpg?resize=780%2C759&#038;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-116752" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Janelle-ODea-2022-16-copy2-scaled.jpg?resize=1024%2C997&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Janelle-ODea-2022-16-copy2-scaled.jpg?resize=300%2C292&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Janelle-ODea-2022-16-copy2-scaled.jpg?resize=768%2C748&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Janelle-ODea-2022-16-copy2-scaled.jpg?resize=1536%2C1496&amp;ssl=1 1536w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Janelle-ODea-2022-16-copy2-scaled.jpg?resize=2048%2C1994&amp;ssl=1 2048w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Janelle-ODea-2022-16-copy2-scaled.jpg?resize=1200%2C1169&amp;ssl=1 1200w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Janelle-ODea-2022-16-copy2-scaled.jpg?resize=1568%2C1527&amp;ssl=1 1568w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Janelle-ODea-2022-16-copy2-scaled.jpg?resize=400%2C390&amp;ssl=1 400w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Janelle-ODea-2022-16-copy2-scaled.jpg?resize=150%2C146&amp;ssl=1 150w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Janelle-ODea-2022-16-copy2-scaled.jpg?w=2340&amp;ssl=1 2340w" sizes="(max-width: 780px) 100vw, 780px" data-recalc-dims="1" /><figcaption>Janelle O&#8217;Dea (Sid Hastings)</figcaption></figure></div>


<p>More recently she filed more than <a href="https://podcasts.apple.com/us/podcast/inside-the-post-dispatch/id1120246053?i=1000578842702">200 open records requests</a> to government agencies in Missouri and Illinois to compile a <a href="https://graphics.stltoday.com/apps/payrolls/salaries_2022/">database of public salaries</a> from across metro St. Louis. Not only did the project provide transparency into government spending, it allowed workers to make sure they were being paid fairly.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Over the past two years, Public Integrity has partnered with hundreds of local news organizations on topics such as <a href="https://publicintegrity.org/topics/environment/harms-way/">climate change’s impact</a> on marginalized communities, the disproportionate impact that <a href="https://publicintegrity.org/topics/education/criminalizing-kids/">police presence in schools</a> has on students of color and children with disabilities, <a href="https://publicintegrity.org/topics/politics/elections/ballotboxbarriers/">polling place closures</a> and lack of government transparency about the <a href="https://publicintegrity.org/health/coronavirus-and-inequality/analysis-trump-coronavirus-advice-secret-contradictory/">spread of COVID-19</a>.</p>



<p>O’Dea will be working on Public Integrity’s initiative to build investigative reporting capacity at local news organizations, particularly those serving Latino, Black, Asian,Indigenous and other underrepresented communities.</p>



<p>“I’m thrilled to join the Public Integrity team, and use my data skills to support the vital work done by local news outlets,” O’Dea said. “After spending nearly a decade in the newspaper industry, at papers of different sizes, I know intimately the struggles that staff and editors face each and every day.”</p>



<p>O’Dea is from Mahomet, Illinois, a small town outside Champaign-Urbana. Prior to moving to St. Louis, where she currently lives, she worked in Florida and Colorado covering business and government. She graduated from the University of Illinois with a major in journalism and a minor in informatics.</p>



<p>“Our work to help local newsrooms build capacity is key to informing communities and holding officials accountable,” said Public Integrity senior editor, Jennifer LaFleur. “I’m thrilled that O’Dea will be leading our efforts to facilitate data journalism in those newsrooms.”</p>



<p>In addition to the new data journalist focused on local collaborations, Public Integrity is <a href="https://recruiting.paylocity.com/Recruiting/Jobs/Details/1304049">hiring a data journalist</a> to support a new collaborative of local news organizations in California’s under-served Central Valley.</p>



<p>Public Integrity, which has twice won the Pulitzer Prize and been recognized with numerous other top honors in journalism, is one of the oldest nonprofit news organizations in the country. It is an independent, nonpartisan and nonprofit news organization dedicated to investigating systems and circumstances that contribute to inequality in the United States.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://publicintegrity.org/inside-publici/janelle-odea-joins-public-integrity-as-data-reporter-for-local-collaborations/">Janelle O’Dea joins Public Integrity as data reporter for local collaborations</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://publicintegrity.org">Center for Public Integrity</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">116774</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Can you tackle systemic racism without confronting race?</title>
		<link>https://publicintegrity.org/labor/can-you-tackle-systemic-racism-without-confronting-race/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[April Simpson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2022 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Inequality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Labor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Watchdog newsletter]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://publicintegrity.org/?p=116754</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<figure><img width="300" height="200" src="https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/GettyImages-1313715179-scaled.jpg?fit=300%2C200&amp;ssl=1" class="attachment-medium size-medium wp-post-image" alt="" decoding="async" loading="lazy" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/GettyImages-1313715179-scaled.jpg?w=2560&amp;ssl=1 2560w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/GettyImages-1313715179-scaled.jpg?resize=300%2C200&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/GettyImages-1313715179-scaled.jpg?resize=1024%2C683&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/GettyImages-1313715179-scaled.jpg?resize=768%2C512&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/GettyImages-1313715179-scaled.jpg?resize=1536%2C1024&amp;ssl=1 1536w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/GettyImages-1313715179-scaled.jpg?resize=2048%2C1365&amp;ssl=1 2048w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/GettyImages-1313715179-scaled.jpg?resize=1200%2C800&amp;ssl=1 1200w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/GettyImages-1313715179-scaled.jpg?resize=1568%2C1045&amp;ssl=1 1568w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/GettyImages-1313715179-scaled.jpg?resize=400%2C267&amp;ssl=1 400w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/GettyImages-1313715179-scaled.jpg?resize=150%2C100&amp;ssl=1 150w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/GettyImages-1313715179-scaled.jpg?w=2340&amp;ssl=1 2340w" sizes="(max-width: 34.9rem) calc(100vw - 2rem), (max-width: 53rem) calc(8 * (100vw / 12)), (min-width: 53rem) calc(6 * (100vw / 12)), 100vw" /></figure>
<p>It&#8217;s not a question of simple semantics. Words exercise power and consequences.&#160; In the governmental jargon that can turn rhetoric into reality, two words — “disadvantaged” and “underserved” — help to explain why one act of Congress failed to provide long sought financial assistance to Black farmers, but another may succeed. The American Rescue Plan [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://publicintegrity.org/labor/can-you-tackle-systemic-racism-without-confronting-race/">Can you tackle systemic racism without confronting race?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://publicintegrity.org">Center for Public Integrity</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure><img width="300" height="200" src="https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/GettyImages-1313715179-scaled.jpg?fit=300%2C200&amp;ssl=1" class="attachment-medium size-medium wp-post-image" alt="" decoding="async" loading="lazy" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/GettyImages-1313715179-scaled.jpg?w=2560&amp;ssl=1 2560w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/GettyImages-1313715179-scaled.jpg?resize=300%2C200&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/GettyImages-1313715179-scaled.jpg?resize=1024%2C683&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/GettyImages-1313715179-scaled.jpg?resize=768%2C512&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/GettyImages-1313715179-scaled.jpg?resize=1536%2C1024&amp;ssl=1 1536w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/GettyImages-1313715179-scaled.jpg?resize=2048%2C1365&amp;ssl=1 2048w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/GettyImages-1313715179-scaled.jpg?resize=1200%2C800&amp;ssl=1 1200w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/GettyImages-1313715179-scaled.jpg?resize=1568%2C1045&amp;ssl=1 1568w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/GettyImages-1313715179-scaled.jpg?resize=400%2C267&amp;ssl=1 400w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/GettyImages-1313715179-scaled.jpg?resize=150%2C100&amp;ssl=1 150w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/GettyImages-1313715179-scaled.jpg?w=2340&amp;ssl=1 2340w" sizes="(max-width: 34.9rem) calc(100vw - 2rem), (max-width: 53rem) calc(8 * (100vw / 12)), (min-width: 53rem) calc(6 * (100vw / 12)), 100vw" /></figure><span class="rt-reading-time" style="display: block;"><span class="rt-label rt-prefix">Reading Time: </span> <span class="rt-time">7</span> <span class="rt-label rt-postfix">minutes</span></span>
<p>It&#8217;s not a question of simple semantics. Words exercise power and consequences.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In the governmental jargon that can turn rhetoric into reality, two words — “disadvantaged” and “underserved” — help to explain why one act of Congress failed to provide long sought financial assistance to Black farmers, but another may succeed.</p>



<p>The <a href="https://www.congress.gov/bill/117th-congress/house-bill/1319/text?q=%7B%22search%22%3A%5B%22american+rescue+plan%22%2C%22american%22%2C%22rescue%22%2C%22plan%22%5D%7D&amp;r=7&amp;s=1">American Rescue Plan Act</a>, a bipartisan measure signed into law last year by President Joe Biden, set aside $4 billion for farmers considered socially disadvantaged.&nbsp;</p>



<div class="is-layout-flow wp-block-group alignwide newspack-pattern subscribe__style-6 is-style-border compress-newsletter has-secondary-background-color has-background"><div class="wp-block-group__inner-container">
<div class="is-layout-flex wp-container-39 wp-block-columns are-vertically-aligned-center">
<div class="is-layout-flow wp-block-column is-vertically-aligned-center">
<p class="has-white-color has-text-color"><meta charset="utf-8"><strong>Watchdog delivered </strong></p>



<p class="has-white-color has-text-color has-small-font-size">Want our investigations in your inbox? Subscribe to our Watchdog newsletter.</p>
</div>



<div class="is-layout-flow wp-block-column is-vertically-aligned-center"><amp-layout id="ne63">
	<div class="wp-block-jetpack-mailchimp" data-blog-id="201594328">
		<form
			aria-describedby="wp-block-jetpack-mailchimp_consent-text"
					>
			<p>
				<input
					aria-label="Enter your email"
					placeholder="Enter your email"
					required
					title="Enter your email"
					type="email"
					name="email"
				/>
			</p>
							<input
					name="interests[3f37dae637]"
					type="hidden"
					class="mc-submit-param"
					value="1"
				/>
									
<div class="wp-block-jetpack-button wp-block-button" style=""><button class="wp-block-button__link has-background has-primary-background-color" style="" data-id-attr="mailchimp-button-block-37" id="mailchimp-button-block-37" type="submit"><strong>Sign up</strong></button></div>
			<p id="wp-block-jetpack-mailchimp_consent-text">
							</p>

			
		</form>
		
			<div class="wp-block-jetpack-mailchimp_notification wp-block-jetpack-mailchimp_processing" role="status">
				Processing…			</div>
			<div class="wp-block-jetpack-mailchimp_notification wp-block-jetpack-mailchimp_success" role="status">
				Success! You&#039;re on the list.			</div>
			<div class="wp-block-jetpack-mailchimp_notification wp-block-jetpack-mailchimp_error" role="alert">
				Whoops! There was an error and we couldn&#039;t process your subscription. Please reload the page and try again.			</div>

			</div>
	</amp-layout></div>
</div>
</div></div>



<p>“A socially disadvantaged group,” according to U.S. Department of Agriculture <a href="https://uscode.house.gov/view.xhtml?req=(title:7%20section:2279%20edition:prelim)">policy guidelines</a>, “is a group whose members have been subject to racial or ethnic prejudice because of their identity as members of a group without regard to their individual qualities.” They include African Americans, American Indians, Alaskan Natives, Asians, Hispanics, Native Hawaiians and Pacific Islanders.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Within weeks, white farmers argued that it was unconstitutional for the $1.9 trillion rescue plan to authorize appropriations that excluded farmers based on their race or ethnicity. A federal judge in Florida later agreed and blocked implementation of the aid to farmers of color on grounds that it discriminated against white farmers.</p>



<p>The U.S. has long been caught in a tug of war over whether race can be used as a remedy for racial discrimination. The U.S. Supreme Court, which has historically interpreted the Constitution to prohibit many race-specific measures, will hear oral arguments this fall in cases against Harvard University and the University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill on whether colleges and universities can consider students’ race and ethnicity in admissions.</p>



<p>On his first day in office, Biden issued an executive order to advance racial equity across the federal government. The USDA program to cancel certain loan debts held by socially disadvantaged farmers was considered an important early step toward fulfilling that promise. But legal challenges prevented the program from taking effect.&nbsp;</p>



<iframe title="Rates of Direct Loan Delinquency " aria-label="Bar Chart" id="datawrapper-chart-NItoD" src="https://datawrapper.dwcdn.net/NItoD/3/" scrolling="no" frameborder="0" style="width: 0; min-width: 100% !important; border: none;" height="254"></iframe><script type="text/javascript">!function(){"use strict";window.addEventListener("message",(function(e){if(void 0!==e.data["datawrapper-height"]){var t=document.querySelectorAll("iframe");for(var a in e.data["datawrapper-height"])for(var r=0;r<t.length;r++){if(t[r].contentWindow===e.source)t[r].style.height=e.data["datawrapper-height"][a]+"px"}}}))}();</script>



<p>Then the $738 billion <a href="https://www.congress.gov/bill/117th-congress/house-bill/5376/text">Inflation Reduction Act</a>, passed on a sharply partisan vote and signed into law in August, presented a solution. It amends a section of the previous bill from benefiting “socially disadvantaged farmers” to “underserved farmers,” a broader category that can include veterans, beginning farmers and those in high poverty areas. Included in that section is $2.2 billion for farmers who can <a href="https://www.usda.gov/media/press-releases/2022/10/13/usda-seeking-public-comment-new-provision-provide-assistance">prove they experienced discrimination</a> from the USDA. </p>



<p>It separately appropriates another $3.1 billion for all borrowers who are behind on loan payments or face other financial risks. This week, USDA announced that it has distributed nearly $800 million under the program to more than 13,000 distressed borrowers, with plans to provide up to $500 million more to as many as 23,000 additional borrowers.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And it repeals the debt cancellation program in the American Rescue Plan Act.</p>



<p>"We need to be clear about this. The Inflation Reduction Act, and the work that Congress did, charts a new pathway and a new set of tools for USDA to have,” USDA Secretary Tom Vilsack said on a call with reporters this week. “These tools are available to USDA borrowers regardless of race or gender or geography or size of operation or type of operation.”</p>



<p>But the new measure has prompted legal challenge – this time, from Black farmers and other farmers of color.&nbsp;</p>



<p>A class-action lawsuit filed this month alleges that the U.S. government broke its contract with the farmers when it agreed to cancel their loan debts, while in return the farmers accepted the government’s calculation of their debt and waived their right to appeal. The farmers were harmed because they made purchases and other investments in anticipation of the financial relief, according to the <a href="https://action.bencrump.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Complaint-as-Filed_Socially-Disadvantaged-Farmers-00840987xE6B76.pdf">suit</a> brought by civil rights attorney Ben Crump and others.</p>



<p>Some Black farmers and their advocates have been skeptical, disappointed and frustrated because the Inflation Reduction Act does not directly address what they consider race-based difficulties, such as lower rates of loan approval and higher rates of delinquency.</p>



<p>Others, however, are hopeful that the overall assistance to farmers of color will be equal to or perhaps even greater than it would have been under the previous bill.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As it turned out, far fewer Black farmers were eligible to have their loans canceled under the American Rescue Plan provision than Black farmer advocates had initially estimated. About 3,100 Black farmers would have qualified, and their combined debt from those loans was less than $300 million, U.S. Rep. Alma Adams, D-N.C., vice chair of the House Agriculture Committee, noted in a July letter to Secretary Vilsack.&nbsp;</p>



<p>That meant most Black farmers would have been left out. Overlooked is that “USDA is not providing loans to Blacks,” said Lloyd Wright, a former director of the USDA’s Office of Civil Rights., Wright is among those hopeful that far more Black farmers will receive financial assistance from the two provisions in the Inflation Reduction Act than they would have through the previous bill, although he worries about whether implementation will bear this out.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In a broader context, though, the situation illustrates the difficult dilemma for efforts to address racial disparities. How can you ameliorate racial discrimination without spelling out its causes and effects?&nbsp;</p>



<p>“It's like saying you want to address gender issues, but you can't do anything that specifically focuses on women,” Ralph Richard Banks, faculty director of the Stanford Center for Racial Justice at Stanford Law School, said in a recent interview.&nbsp;</p>



<p>“In our society,” he said, “the legal norms are kind of opposed to focusing on race, per se. We want to have racial equality, equity and justice, and all this, but we don't want to single race out or treat people differently on account of race, and that does make it difficult to address race-based inequities if we don't take race into account directly.”&nbsp;</p>


<h2 id="h-a-system-that-discriminates">A system that discriminates</h2>


<p>Cash flow is critical in the business of farming, where short- and long-term income and essential operating revenues can be determined more by the whims of Mother Nature than the desires of customers and abilities of farmers. The financial difficulties of one year can easily pass into the next, and this generation’s hardships can become those of the next generation as well.</p>



<p>That makes loans essential to commercial farmers, and timely repayment of those loans more vulnerable to major disruptions in the economy, such as those related to the COVID-19 pandemic and the historic increases in the rate of inflation.</p>



<p>Black farmers and their advocates contend that over the years they have received less than their fair share of assistance through the USDA program that provides low-interest direct loans for activities such as purchasing land, crops, livestock and equipment.&nbsp;</p>



<p>That imbalance is ongoing, they say.</p>



<p>“We are in a system that’s systematically biased and racist against those farmers,” said Kara Boyd, president of the Association of American Indian Farmers and a member of the National Black Farmers Association, led by her husband, John. The Boyds and two other Virginia farmers are the named plaintiffs in the class-action lawsuit.</p>



<p>Advocates say that the current economic hardships help explain the racial differences in loan delinquency the Center for Public Integrity found in 2022 USDA data.</p>



<p>“Unfortunately, some of the farmers who were struggling before, now, they’re struggling even more because of the repeal of the act,” Boyd said.</p>



<p>But on the call with reporters Tuesday, Secretary Vilsack pointed to the $2.2 billion provision for farmers who feel that they have been unfairly treated in the past by the USDA. The department is currently seeking input on how to design and structure the program, which will be administered by one or more third parties. &nbsp;</p>


<h2 id="h-the-case-for-and-against-colorblindness">The case for (and against) colorblindness</h2>


<p>The debate over “colorblind” remedies for racial discrimination has a history of more than 120 years in U.S. constitutional law.</p>



<p>Justice John Marshall Harlan, the lone dissenter in the Supreme Court’s 1896 Plessy v. Ferguson decision that upheld “separate but equal” policies, said the Constitution prescribed color blindness in theory, but white supremacist policies were imposed in actuality.</p>



<p>“The white race deems itself to be the dominant race in this country. And so it is in prestige, in achievements, in education and in power,” he wrote in his opposition to the 7-1 decision.</p>



<p>“But in view of the Constitution, in the eye of the law, there is in this country no superior, dominant, ruling class of citizens. There is no caste here. Our Constitution is color-blind, and neither knows nor tolerates classes among citizens. In respect of civil rights, all citizens are equal before the law.”</p>





<p>In 1978, the Supreme Court upheld affirmative action plans in the case of Regents of the University of California v. Bakke. In support of that decision, Justice Harry Blackmun agreed with fellow Justice Thurgood Marshall’s assertion that race must be considered.</p>



<p>“In order to get beyond racism, we must first take account of race. There is no other way,” Blackmun wrote. “And in order to treat some persons equally, we must treat them differently. We cannot—we dare not—let the Equal Protection Clause [of the 14th Amendment] perpetuate racial superiority.”</p>



<p>But others argue that colorblindness aligns with the country’s founding principles. Peter C. Myers, a professor emeritus of political science at the University of Wisconsin-Eau Claire, said Blackmun was “sorely mistaken when he declared in defense of modern race preferences.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>Color-blindness requires that “distinctions of race or color play no proper part in the distributions of burdens and benefits in public law or policy” and “the recovery and secure establishment of the color-blindness principle in America’s public life are urgent moral and civic imperatives,” Myers wrote <a href="https://www.heritage.org/civil-society/report/the-case-color-blindness">in a 2019 article</a> for the Heritage Foundation.</p>



<p>Adia Harvey Wingfield, a sociology professor at Washington University in St. Louis, said some past efforts to remedy race-based problems in colorblind ways have widened or exacerbated racial inequality.</p>



<p>Minimum wage and Social Security laws, for example, did not adequately address the situation of the disproportionately large number of Black Americans in low-pay domestic jobs.</p>



<p>The G.I. Bill, which offered World War II veterans a range of financial benefits, including assistance for education and job training, was administered by states when segregation was the law in the South. Many state officials there steered Black veterans away from job training programs that could lead to higher-paying jobs, and to college degrees at Black schools that were underfunded rather than predominantly white institutions.</p>



<p>And while legal school segregation was technically eliminated by the Supreme Court in 1954 and by subsequent civil rights legislation, it was effectively replaced by de facto segregation in schools drawing students from neighborhoods that still show the impacts of white supremacist efforts to keep people separated by race.</p>



<p>“One of the things that’s so useful about historical research from that time period is that it shows multiple examples of race-blind public policy that still made sure racial inequality stayed in place,” Wingfield said in a recent interview.</p>



<p>“Trying to solve racial inequality by not talking about racial inequality doesn’t reduce racial inequality,” she said. “It leaves it there to continue to be perpetuated in existing forms.”</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://publicintegrity.org/labor/can-you-tackle-systemic-racism-without-confronting-race/">Can you tackle systemic racism without confronting race?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://publicintegrity.org">Center for Public Integrity</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">116754</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Stop the victim narrative, and other tips for covering working-class women</title>
		<link>https://publicintegrity.org/inside-publici/tips-covering-working-class-women/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Paul Cheung and Erika Owens]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 16:54:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Inside Public Integrity]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://publicintegrity.org/?p=116694</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<figure><img width="300" height="150" src="https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/combo-illustrations-scaled.jpg?fit=300%2C150&amp;ssl=1" class="attachment-medium size-medium wp-post-image" alt="" decoding="async" loading="lazy" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/combo-illustrations-scaled.jpg?w=2560&amp;ssl=1 2560w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/combo-illustrations-scaled.jpg?resize=300%2C150&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/combo-illustrations-scaled.jpg?resize=1024%2C512&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/combo-illustrations-scaled.jpg?resize=768%2C384&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/combo-illustrations-scaled.jpg?resize=1536%2C768&amp;ssl=1 1536w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/combo-illustrations-scaled.jpg?resize=2048%2C1024&amp;ssl=1 2048w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/combo-illustrations-scaled.jpg?resize=1200%2C600&amp;ssl=1 1200w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/combo-illustrations-scaled.jpg?resize=1568%2C784&amp;ssl=1 1568w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/combo-illustrations-scaled.jpg?resize=400%2C200&amp;ssl=1 400w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/combo-illustrations-scaled.jpg?resize=150%2C75&amp;ssl=1 150w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/combo-illustrations-scaled.jpg?w=2340&amp;ssl=1 2340w" sizes="(max-width: 34.9rem) calc(100vw - 2rem), (max-width: 53rem) calc(8 * (100vw / 12)), (min-width: 53rem) calc(6 * (100vw / 12)), 100vw" /></figure>
<p>While reporters talk with sources every day, it’s rare that conversation is about the practice of journalism itself. In September, the Center for Public Integrity and Tara Health Foundation hosted conversations about how to make news coverage of working-class women more community centered. Community leaders shared feedback on the harm they&#8217;ve seen perpetuated by journalism, [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://publicintegrity.org/inside-publici/tips-covering-working-class-women/">Stop the victim narrative, and other tips for covering working-class women</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://publicintegrity.org">Center for Public Integrity</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure><img width="300" height="150" src="https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/combo-illustrations-scaled.jpg?fit=300%2C150&amp;ssl=1" class="attachment-medium size-medium wp-post-image" alt="" decoding="async" loading="lazy" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/combo-illustrations-scaled.jpg?w=2560&amp;ssl=1 2560w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/combo-illustrations-scaled.jpg?resize=300%2C150&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/combo-illustrations-scaled.jpg?resize=1024%2C512&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/combo-illustrations-scaled.jpg?resize=768%2C384&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/combo-illustrations-scaled.jpg?resize=1536%2C768&amp;ssl=1 1536w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/combo-illustrations-scaled.jpg?resize=2048%2C1024&amp;ssl=1 2048w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/combo-illustrations-scaled.jpg?resize=1200%2C600&amp;ssl=1 1200w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/combo-illustrations-scaled.jpg?resize=1568%2C784&amp;ssl=1 1568w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/combo-illustrations-scaled.jpg?resize=400%2C200&amp;ssl=1 400w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/combo-illustrations-scaled.jpg?resize=150%2C75&amp;ssl=1 150w, https://i0.wp.com/publicintegrity.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/combo-illustrations-scaled.jpg?w=2340&amp;ssl=1 2340w" sizes="(max-width: 34.9rem) calc(100vw - 2rem), (max-width: 53rem) calc(8 * (100vw / 12)), (min-width: 53rem) calc(6 * (100vw / 12)), 100vw" /></figure><span class="rt-reading-time" style="display: block;"><span class="rt-label rt-prefix">Reading Time: </span> <span class="rt-time">3</span> <span class="rt-label rt-postfix">minutes</span></span>
<p>While reporters talk with sources every day, it’s rare that conversation is about the practice of journalism itself. In September, the Center for Public Integrity and Tara Health Foundation hosted conversations about <a href="https://www.eventbrite.com/e/making-news-coverage-of-working-class-women-more-community-centered-tickets-401476786877">how to make news coverage of working-class women more community centered</a>.</p>



<p>Community leaders shared feedback on the harm they&#8217;ve seen perpetuated by journalism, as well as suggestions about how to do better. Journalists shared their own frustrations about the challenges of trying to improve reporting practices, and with a level of honesty rarely seen in public conversations.</p>



<div class="is-layout-flow wp-block-group alignwide newspack-pattern subscribe__style-6 is-style-border compress-newsletter has-secondary-background-color has-background"><div class="wp-block-group__inner-container">
<div class="is-layout-flex wp-container-44 wp-block-columns are-vertically-aligned-center">
<div class="is-layout-flow wp-block-column is-vertically-aligned-center">
<p class="has-white-color has-text-color"><meta charset="utf-8"><strong>Watchdog delivered </strong></p>



<p class="has-white-color has-text-color has-small-font-size">Want our investigations in your inbox? Subscribe to our Watchdog newsletter.</p>
</div>



<div class="is-layout-flow wp-block-column is-vertically-aligned-center"><amp-layout id="nc6f">
	<div class="wp-block-jetpack-mailchimp" data-blog-id="201594328">
		<form
			aria-describedby="wp-block-jetpack-mailchimp_consent-text"
					>
			<p>
				<input
					aria-label="Enter your email"
					placeholder="Enter your email"
					required
					title="Enter your email"
					type="email"
					name="email"
				/>
			</p>
							<input
					name="interests[3f37dae637]"
					type="hidden"
					class="mc-submit-param"
					value="1"
				/>
									
<div class="wp-block-jetpack-button wp-block-button" style=""><button class="wp-block-button__link has-background has-primary-background-color" style="" data-id-attr="mailchimp-button-block-42" id="mailchimp-button-block-42" type="submit"><strong>Sign up</strong></button></div>
			<p id="wp-block-jetpack-mailchimp_consent-text">
							</p>

			
		</form>
		
			<div class="wp-block-jetpack-mailchimp_notification wp-block-jetpack-mailchimp_processing" role="status">
				Processing…			</div>
			<div class="wp-block-jetpack-mailchimp_notification wp-block-jetpack-mailchimp_success" role="status">
				Success! You&#039;re on the list.			</div>
			<div class="wp-block-jetpack-mailchimp_notification wp-block-jetpack-mailchimp_error" role="alert">
				Whoops! There was an error and we couldn&#039;t process your subscription. Please reload the page and try again.			</div>

			</div>
	</amp-layout></div>
</div>
</div></div>


<h2 id="h-five-takeaways-for-improving-coverage"><strong>Five takeaways for improving coverage</strong></h2>


<p>These conversations helped surface specific strategies reporters can pull into their practice, and pushed journalists to reflect on the often invisible ways reporting helps reinforce the status quo, such as by emphasizing individual heroes and villains rather than covering systemic problems.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Strategies reporters can implement include:</p>



<ol><li><strong>Stop the victim narrative. Instead, emphasize the agency and solutions of working-class women. </strong>Community leaders shared how often when a source is quoted in a story, they’re not described in the way they see themselves: as a worker with power and a plan for how to upend inequitable systems. By sharing the demands of workers and their analysis of issues, reporters can shift the narrative and honor the joy and dignity people find in their work. </li><li><strong>Invest in relationships by taking care with sources before and after the story.</strong> There is <a href="https://ethics.journalism.wisc.edu/why-should-i-tell-you-a-guide-to-less-extractive-reporting/">a duty of care to sources</a>, especially those from marginalized communities. Ongoing relationship building like reporters do with politicians and CEOs should be extended to workers and community leaders as well.</li><li><strong>Build transparency into your reporting process—it builds trust with readers and sources. </strong>Without transparency, sources don’t understand why certain quotes are chosen or how it’s possible to talk for an hour or maybe not get a quote in a piece at all. Being clear about the limitations you face as a reporter, and how you see the purpose of the story, can help set clear expectations with sources.</li><li><strong>Rethink who you consider an expert and value the expertise that comes from lived experience. </strong>Who gets listed as a potential expert, who gets media training, who is a part of institutions of power, these are all influenced by underlying systems of oppression and gatekeepers. But who knows better about the needs of working-class women than those women themselves? Treat that personal experience as an expertise as valuable as a credential or title. Prepare to speak with those workers the same way as with a CEO, think tank analyst, or academic—doing homework on the relevant landscape, asking what <em>they</em> think the problems and solutions are. Simply: treat workers as the protagonists of their own stories.</li><li><strong>Connect the dots between working women’s lived experiences and the structural causes of those experiences,</strong>” as one community leader suggested. Reporting that situates the experiences of individual workers within larger systems helps readers better understand the factors facing working women and breaks out of an oversimplified hero and villain narrative. </li></ol>


<h2 id="evolving-your-journalistic-practice"><strong>Evolving your journalistic practice</strong></h2>


<p>The depth and detail of these discussions generated so many ideas to immediately put into practice in reporting. Here’s recordings if you would like to dive into the full conversations!</p>



<p><a href="https://youtu.be/e5RFhTrOMBg"><strong>Feedback Loop</strong></a><strong>: </strong>Get feedback from community leaders in the field on how news portrays working-class women. Learn what news coverage authentically represents this community and what coverage is exhaustive and extractive.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-block-embed-youtube wp-embed-aspect-16-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<iframe loading="lazy" title="Making News Coverage of Working Class Women More Community Centered (Panel 1: Feedback Loop)" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/e5RFhTrOMBg?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</div></figure>



<p>In a few months, we’re going to follow up with journalist participants to see how or whether these conversations did influence their practice. If you’ve implemented any of these takeaways, we’d love to hear about it.</p>



<p>Thanks to all of the panelists (Ashley Clarke, Audience Engagement Editor at Public Integrity, Rhonda Vonshay Sharpe, President at the Women’s Institute for Science, Equity and Race, Nafisah Ula, Organizing Director at Jobs With Justice, Leng Leng Chancey, Executive Director at 9to5, Iris Kuo, Principal, Workplace Equity at Tara Health Foundation, Marissa Evans, Reporter at The Los Angeles Times, Sally Ho, Reporter, The Associated Press, Alexia Fernández Campbell, Senior Reporter at Public Integrity) and participants for all of these insights!</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://publicintegrity.org/inside-publici/tips-covering-working-class-women/">Stop the victim narrative, and other tips for covering working-class women</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://publicintegrity.org">Center for Public Integrity</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">116694</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>