<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<rdf:RDF
 xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
 xmlns="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/"
 xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
 xmlns:taxo="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/taxonomy/"
 xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
 xmlns:syn="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
 xmlns:admin="http://webns.net/mvcb/"
>

<channel rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/">
<title>cs.GT updates on arXiv.org</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">Computer Science -- Computer Science and Game Theory (cs.GT) updates on the arXiv.org e-print archive</description>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:date>2022-11-03T20:30:00-05:00</dc:date>
<dc:publisher>help@arxiv.org</dc:publisher>
<dc:subject>Computer Science -- Computer Science and Game Theory</dc:subject>
<syn:updateBase>1901-01-01T00:00+00:00</syn:updateBase>
<syn:updateFrequency>1</syn:updateFrequency>
<syn:updatePeriod>daily</syn:updatePeriod>
<items>
 <rdf:Seq>
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01441" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01633" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01681" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01703" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01772" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01805" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01831" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01907" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01984" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.02004" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/1912.10069" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2105.06763" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2202.06898" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2203.17232" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2208.07919" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2209.09775" />
 </rdf:Seq>
</items>
<image rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif" />
</channel>
<image rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif">
<title>arXiv.org</title>
<url>http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif</url>
<link>http://arxiv.org/</link>
</image>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01441">
<title>eXplainable AI for Quantum Machine Learning. (arXiv:2211.01441v1 [quant-ph])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01441</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Parametrized Quantum Circuits (PQCs) enable a novel method for machine
learning (ML). However, from a computational point of view they present a
challenge to existing eXplainable AI (xAI) methods. On the one hand,
measurements on quantum circuits introduce probabilistic errors which impact
the convergence of these methods. On the other hand, the phase space of a
quantum circuit expands exponentially with the number of qubits, complicating
efforts to execute xAI methods in polynomial time. In this paper we will
discuss the performance of established xAI methods, such as Baseline SHAP and
Integrated Gradients. Using the internal mechanics of PQCs we study ways to
speed up their computation.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Steinmuller_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Patrick Steinm&amp;#xfc;ller&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Schulz_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Tobias Schulz&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Graf_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ferdinand Graf&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Herr_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Daniel Herr&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01633">
<title>Cooperative Maneuvers of Highly Automated Vehicles at Urban Intersections: A Game-theoretic Approach. (arXiv:2211.01633v1 [cs.GT])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01633</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;In this paper, we propose an approach how connected and highly automated
vehicles can perform cooperative maneuvers such as lane changes and left-turns
at urban intersections where they have to deal with human-operated vehicles and
vulnerable road users such as cyclists and pedestrians in so-called mixed
traffic. In order to support cooperative maneuvers the urban intersection is
equipped with an intelligent controller which has access to different sensors
along the intersection to detect and predict the behavior of the traffic
participants involved. Since the intersection controller cannot directly
control all road users and - not least due to the legal situation - driving
decisions must always be made by the vehicle controller itself, we focus on a
decentralized control paradigm. In this context, connected and highly automated
vehicles use some carefully selected game theory concepts to make the best
possible and clear decisions about cooperative maneuvers. The aim is to improve
traffic efficiency while maintaining road safety at the same time. Our first
results obtained with a prototypical implementation of the approach in a
traffic simulation are promising.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Koopmann_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Bj&amp;#xf6;rn Koopmann&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Puch_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Stefan Puch&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Ehmen_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;G&amp;#xfc;nter Ehmen&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Franzle_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Martin Fr&amp;#xe4;nzle&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01681">
<title>Matrix Multiplicative Weights Updates in Quantum Zero-Sum Games: Conservation Laws &amp; Recurrence. (arXiv:2211.01681v1 [cs.GT])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01681</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Recent advances in quantum computing and in particular, the introduction of
quantum GANs, have led to increased interest in quantum zero-sum game theory,
extending the scope of learning algorithms for classical games into the quantum
realm. In this paper, we focus on learning in quantum zero-sum games under
Matrix Multiplicative Weights Update (a generalization of the multiplicative
weights update method) and its continuous analogue, Quantum Replicator
Dynamics. When each player selects their state according to quantum replicator
dynamics, we show that the system exhibits conservation laws in a
quantum-information theoretic sense. Moreover, we show that the system exhibits
Poincare recurrence, meaning that almost all orbits return arbitrarily close to
their initial conditions infinitely often. Our analysis generalizes previous
results in the case of classical games.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Jain_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Rahul Jain&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Piliouras_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Georgios Piliouras&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Sim_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ryann Sim&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01703">
<title>Zero-Sum Games with Noisy Observations. (arXiv:2211.01703v1 [cs.GT])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01703</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;In this paper, $2 \times 2$ zero-sum games (ZSGs) are studied under the
following assumptions: (1) One of the players (the leader) publicly and
irrevocably commits to choose its actions by sampling a given probability
measure (strategy);(2) The leader announces its action, which is observed by
its opponent (the follower) through a binary channel; and (3) the follower
chooses its strategy based on the knowledge of the leader&apos;s strategy and the
noisy observation of the leader&apos;s action. Under these conditions, the
equilibrium is shown to always exist and be often different from the Nash and
Stackelberg equilibria. Even subject to noise, observing the actions of the
leader is either beneficial or immaterial to the follower for all possible
commitments. When the commitment is observed subject to a distortion, the
equilibrium does not necessarily exist. Nonetheless, the leader might still
obtain some benefit in some specific cases subject to equilibrium refinements.
For instance, $\epsilon$-equilibria might exist in which the leader commits to
suboptimal strategies that allow unequivocally predicting the best response of
its opponent.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Sun_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ke Sun&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Perlaza_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Samir M. Perlaza&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Jean_Marie_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Alain Jean-Marie&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01772">
<title>Collaborative Honeypot Defense in UAV Networks: A Learning-Based Game Approach. (arXiv:2211.01772v1 [cs.SY])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01772</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The proliferation of unmanned aerial vehicles (UAVs) opens up new
opportunities for on-demand service provisioning anywhere and anytime, but also
exposes UAVs to a variety of cyber threats. Low/medium interaction honeypots
offer a promising lightweight defense for actively protecting mobile Internet
of things, particularly UAV networks. While previous research has primarily
focused on honeypot system design and attack pattern recognition, the incentive
issue for motivating UAV&apos;s participation (e.g., sharing trapped attack data in
honeypots) to collaboratively resist distributed and sophisticated attacks
remains unexplored. This paper proposes a novel game-theoretical collaborative
defense approach to address optimal, fair, and feasible incentive design, in
the presence of network dynamics and UAVs&apos; multi-dimensional private
information (e.g., valid defense data (VDD) volume, communication delay, and
UAV cost). Specifically, we first develop a honeypot game between UAVs and the
network operator under both partial and complete information asymmetry
scenarios. The optimal VDD-reward contract design problem with partial
information asymmetry is then solved using a contract-theoretic approach that
ensures budget feasibility, truthfulness, fairness, and computational
efficiency. In addition, under complete information asymmetry, we devise a
distributed reinforcement learning algorithm to dynamically design optimal
contracts for distinct types of UAVs in the time-varying UAV network. Extensive
simulations demonstrate that the proposed scheme can motivate UAV&apos;s cooperation
in VDD sharing and improve defensive effectiveness, compared with conventional
schemes.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Wang_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yuntao Wang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Su_Z/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Zhou Su&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Benslimane_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Abderrahim Benslimane&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Xu_Q/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Qichao Xu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Dai_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Minghui Dai&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Li_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ruidong Li&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01805">
<title>FedMint: Intelligent Bilateral Client Selection in Federated Learning with Newcomer IoT Devices. (arXiv:2211.01805v1 [cs.LG])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01805</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Federated Learning (FL) is a novel distributed privacy-preserving learning
paradigm, which enables the collaboration among several participants (e.g.,
Internet of Things devices) for the training of machine learning models.
However, selecting the participants that would contribute to this collaborative
training is highly challenging. Adopting a random selection strategy would
entail substantial problems due to the heterogeneity in terms of data quality,
and computational and communication resources across the participants. Although
several approaches have been proposed in the literature to overcome the problem
of random selection, most of these approaches follow a unilateral selection
strategy. In fact, they base their selection strategy on only the federated
server&apos;s side, while overlooking the interests of the client devices in the
process. To overcome this problem, we present in this paper FedMint, an
intelligent client selection approach for federated learning on IoT devices
using game theory and bootstrapping mechanism. Our solution involves the design
of: (1) preference functions for the client IoT devices and federated servers
to allow them to rank each other according to several factors such as accuracy
and price, (2) intelligent matching algorithms that take into account the
preferences of both parties in their design, and (3) bootstrapping technique
that capitalizes on the collaboration of multiple federated servers in order to
assign initial accuracy value for the newly connected IoT devices. Based on our
simulation findings, our strategy surpasses the VanillaFL selection approach in
terms of maximizing both the revenues of the client devices and accuracy of the
global federated learning model.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Wehbi_O/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Osama Wehbi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Arisdakessian_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Sarhad Arisdakessian&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Wahab_O/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Omar Abdel Wahab&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Otrok_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Hadi Otrok&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Otoum_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Safa Otoum&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Mourad_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Azzam Mourad&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Guizani_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Mohsen Guizani&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01831">
<title>Polynomial Life: the Structure of Adaptive Systems. (arXiv:2211.01831v1 [nlin.AO])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01831</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We extend our earlier work on the compositional structure of cybernetic
systems in order to account for the embodiment of such systems. All their
interactions proceed through their bodies&apos; boundaries: sensations impinge on
their surfaces, and actions correspond to changes in their configurations. We
formalize this morphological perspective using polynomial functors. The
&apos;internal universes&apos; of systems are shown to constitute an indexed category of
statistical games over polynomials; their dynamics form an indexed category of
behaviours. We characterize &apos;active inference doctrines&apos; as indexed functors
between such categories, resolving a number of open problems in our earlier
work, and pointing to a formalization of the &apos;free energy principle&apos; as adjoint
to such doctrines. We illustrate our framework through fundamental examples
from biology, including homeostasis, morphogenesis, and autopoiesis, and
suggest a formal connection between spatial navigation and the process of
proof.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/nlin/1/au:+Smithe_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Toby St Clere Smithe&lt;/a&gt; (Topos Institute)</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01907">
<title>The Polyhedral Geometry of Truthful Auctions. (arXiv:2211.01907v1 [cs.GT])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01907</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The difference set of an outcome in an auction is the set of types that the
auction mechanism maps to the outcome. We give a complete characterization of
the geometry of the difference sets that can appear for a dominant strategy
incentive compatible multi-unit auction showing that they correspond to regular
subdivisions of the unit cube. This observation is then used to construct
mechanisms that are robust in the sense that the set of items allocated to a
player does change only slightly when the player&apos;s reported type is changed
slightly.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Joswig_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Michael Joswig&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Klimm_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Max Klimm&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Spitz_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Sylvain Spitz&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01984">
<title>Sybil-Proof Diffusion Auction in Social Networks. (arXiv:2211.01984v1 [cs.GT])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01984</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;A diffusion auction is a market to sell commodities over a social network,
where the challenge is to incentivize existing buyers to invite their neighbors
in the network to join the market. Existing mechanisms have been designed to
solve the challenge in various settings, aiming at desirable properties such as
non-deficiency, incentive compatibility and social welfare maximization. Since
the mechanisms are employed in dynamic networks with ever-changing structures,
buyers could easily generate fake nodes in the network to manipulate the
mechanisms for their own benefits, which is commonly known as the Sybil attack.
We observe that strategic agents may gain an unfair advantage in existing
mechanisms through such attacks. To resist this potential attack, we propose
two diffusion auction mechanisms, the Sybil tax mechanism (STM) and the Sybil
cluster mechanism (SCM), to achieve both Sybil-proofness and incentive
compatibility in the single-item setting. Our proposal provides the first
mechanisms to protect the interests of buyers against Sybil attacks with a mild
sacrifice of social welfare and revenue.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Chen_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Hongyin Chen&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Deng_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xiaotie Deng&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Wang_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ying Wang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Wu_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yue Wu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zhao_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Dengji Zhao&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.02004">
<title>Truthful Matching with Online Items and Offline Agents. (arXiv:2211.02004v1 [cs.GT])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.02004</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We study truthful mechanisms for welfare maximization in online bipartite
matching. In our (multi-parameter) setting, every buyer is associated with a
(possibly private) desired set of items, and has a private value for being
assigned an item in her desired set. Unlike most online matching settings,
where agents arrive online, in our setting the items arrive online in an
adversarial order while the buyers are present for the entire duration of the
process. This poses a significant challenge to the design of truthful
mechanisms, due to the ability of buyers to strategize over future rounds. We
provide an almost full picture of the competitive ratios in different
scenarios, including myopic vs. non-myopic agents, tardy vs. prompt payments,
and private vs. public desired sets. Among other results, we identify the
frontier for which the celebrated $e/(e-1)$ competitive ratio for the
vertex-weighted online matching of Karp, Vazirani and Vazirani extends to
truthful agents and online items.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Feldman_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Michal Feldman&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Fusco_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Federico Fusco&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Leonardi_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Stefano Leonardi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Mauras_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Simon Mauras&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Reiffenhauser_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Rebecca Reiffenh&amp;#xe4;user&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/1912.10069">
<title>Learning Reserve Prices in Second-Price Auctions. (arXiv:1912.10069v3 [cs.GT] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/1912.10069</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;This paper proves the tight sample complexity of {\sf Second-Price Auction
with Anonymous Reserve}, up to a logarithmic factor, for each of all the value
distribution families studied in the literature: $[0,\, 1]$-bounded, $[1,\,
H]$-bounded, regular, and monotone hazard rate (MHR). Remarkably, the
setting-specific tight sample complexity $\mathsf{poly}(\varepsilon^{-1})$
depends on the precision $\varepsilon \in (0, 1)$, but not on the number of
bidders $n \geq 1$. Further, in the two bounded-support settings, our learning
algorithm allows {\em correlated} value distributions.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In contrast, the tight sample complexity $\tilde{\Theta}(n) \cdot
\mathsf{poly}(\varepsilon^{-1})$ of {\sf Myerson Auction} proved by Guo, Huang
and Zhang (STOC~2019) has a nearly-linear dependence on $n \geq 1$, and holds
only for {\em independent} value distributions in every setting.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We follow a similar framework as the Guo-Huang-Zhang work, but replace their
information theoretical arguments with a direct proof.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Jin_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yaonan Jin&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Lu_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Pinyan Lu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Xiao_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Tao Xiao&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2105.06763">
<title>Translating Extensive Form Games to Open Games with Agency. (arXiv:2105.06763v2 [cs.GT] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2105.06763</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We show open games cover extensive form games with both perfect and imperfect
information. Doing so forces us to address two current weaknesses in open
games: the lack of a notion of player and their agency within open games, and
the lack of choice operators. Using the former we construct the latter, and
these choice operators subsume previous proposed operators for open games,
thereby making progress towards a core, canonical and ergonomic calculus of
game operators. Collectively these innovations increase the level of
compositionality of open games, and demonstrate their expressiveness.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Capucci_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Matteo Capucci&lt;/a&gt; (University of Strathclyde), &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Ghani_N/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Neil Ghani&lt;/a&gt; (University of Strathclyde), &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Ledent_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;J&amp;#xe9;r&amp;#xe9;my Ledent&lt;/a&gt; (University of Strathclyde), &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Forsberg_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Fredrik Nordvall Forsberg&lt;/a&gt; (University of Strathclyde)</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2202.06898">
<title>The Complexity of Matching Games: A Survey. (arXiv:2202.06898v4 [cs.GT] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2202.06898</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Matching games naturally generalize assignment games, a well-known class of
cooperative games. Interest in matching games has grown recently due to some
breakthrough results and new applications. This state-of-the-art survey
provides an overview of matching games and extensions, such as $b$-matching
games and partitioned matching games; the latter originating from the emerging
area of international kidney exchange. In this survey we focus on computational
complexity aspects of various game-theoretical solution concepts, such as the
core, nucleolus and Shapley value, when the input is restricted to some
(generalized) matching game.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Benedek_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;M&amp;#xe1;rton Benedek&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Biro_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;P&amp;#xe9;ter Bir&amp;#xf3;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Johnson_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Matthew Johnson&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Paulusma_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Dani&amp;#xeb;l Paulusma&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Ye_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xin Ye&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2203.17232">
<title>Performative Power. (arXiv:2203.17232v2 [cs.LG] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2203.17232</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We introduce the notion of performative power, which measures the ability of
a firm operating an algorithmic system, such as a digital content
recommendation platform, to cause change in a population of participants. We
relate performative power to the economic study of competition in digital
economies. Traditional economic concepts struggle with identifying
anti-competitive patterns in digital platforms not least due to the complexity
of market definition. In contrast, performative power is a causal notion that
is identifiable with minimal knowledge of the market, its internals,
participants, products, or prices.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Low performative power implies that a firm can do no better than to optimize
their objective on current data. In contrast, firms of high performative power
stand to benefit from steering the population towards more profitable behavior.
We confirm in a simple theoretical model that monopolies maximize performative
power. A firm&apos;s ability to personalize increases performative power, while
competition and outside options decrease performative power. On the empirical
side, we propose an observational causal design to identify performative power
from discontinuities in how digital platforms display content. This allows to
repurpose causal effects from various studies about digital platforms as lower
bounds on performative power. Finally, we speculate about the role that
performative power might play in competition policy and antitrust enforcement
in digital marketplaces.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Hardt_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Moritz Hardt&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Jagadeesan_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Meena Jagadeesan&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Mendler_Dunner_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Celestine Mendler-D&amp;#xfc;nner&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2208.07919">
<title>Dynamic Pricing for Non-fungible Resources: Designing Multidimensional Blockchain Fee Markets. (arXiv:2208.07919v2 [math.OC] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2208.07919</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Public blockchains implement a fee mechanism to allocate scarce computational
resources across competing transactions. Most existing fee market designs
utilize a joint, fungible unit of account (e.g., gas in Ethereum) to price
otherwise non-fungible resources such as bandwidth, computation, and storage,
by hardcoding their relative prices. Fixing the relative price of each resource
in this way inhibits granular price discovery, limiting scalability and opening
up the possibility of denial-of-service attacks. As a result, many prominent
networks such as Ethereum and Solana have proposed multi-dimensional fee
markets. In this paper, we provide a principled way to design fee markets that
efficiently price multiple non-fungible resources. Starting from a loss
function specified by the network designer, we show how to compute dynamic
prices that align the network&apos;s incentives (to minimize the loss) with those of
the users and miners (to maximize their welfare), even as demand for these
resources changes. Our pricing mechanism follows from a natural decomposition
of the network designer&apos;s problem into two parts that are related to each other
via the resource prices. These results can be used to efficiently set fees in
order to improve network performance.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Diamandis_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Theo Diamandis&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Evans_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Alex Evans&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Chitra_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Tarun Chitra&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Angeris_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Guillermo Angeris&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2209.09775">
<title>FedToken: Tokenized Incentives for Data Contribution in Federated Learning. (arXiv:2209.09775v2 [cs.LG] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2209.09775</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Incentives that compensate for the involved costs in the decentralized
training of a Federated Learning (FL) model act as a key stimulus for clients&apos;
long-term participation. However, it is challenging to convince clients for
quality participation in FL due to the absence of: (i) full information on the
client&apos;s data quality and properties; (ii) the value of client&apos;s data
contributions; and (iii) the trusted mechanism for monetary incentive offers.
This often leads to poor efficiency in training and communication. While
several works focus on strategic incentive designs and client selection to
overcome this problem, there is a major knowledge gap in terms of an overall
design tailored to the foreseen digital economy, including Web 3.0, while
simultaneously meeting the learning objectives. To address this gap, we propose
a contribution-based tokenized incentive scheme, namely \texttt{FedToken},
backed by blockchain technology that ensures fair allocation of tokens amongst
the clients that corresponds to the valuation of their data during model
training. Leveraging the engineered Shapley-based scheme, we first approximate
the contribution of local models during model aggregation, then strategically
schedule clients lowering the communication rounds for convergence and anchor
ways to allocate \emph{affordable} tokens under a constrained monetary budget.
Extensive simulations demonstrate the efficacy of our proposed method.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Pandey_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Shashi Raj Pandey&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Nguyen_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Lam Duc Nguyen&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Popovski_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Petar Popovski&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
</rdf:RDF>