<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<rdf:RDF
 xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
 xmlns="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/"
 xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
 xmlns:taxo="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/taxonomy/"
 xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
 xmlns:syn="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
 xmlns:admin="http://webns.net/mvcb/"
>

<channel rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/">
<title>math.AP updates on arXiv.org</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">Mathematics -- Analysis of PDEs (math.AP) updates on the arXiv.org e-print archive</description>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:date>2022-11-03T20:30:00-05:00</dc:date>
<dc:publisher>help@arxiv.org</dc:publisher>
<dc:subject>Mathematics -- Analysis of PDEs</dc:subject>
<syn:updateBase>1901-01-01T00:00+00:00</syn:updateBase>
<syn:updateFrequency>1</syn:updateFrequency>
<syn:updatePeriod>daily</syn:updatePeriod>
<items>
 <rdf:Seq>
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01415" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01448" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01574" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01594" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01637" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01672" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01702" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01853" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01932" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01973" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01985" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2205.03095" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2206.08682" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2208.01842" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.10037" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.16757" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.00287" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.00308" />
 </rdf:Seq>
</items>
<image rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif" />
</channel>
<image rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif">
<title>arXiv.org</title>
<url>http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif</url>
<link>http://arxiv.org/</link>
</image>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01415">
<title>Asymptotic preserving schemes for nonlinear kinetic equations leading to volume-exclusion chemotaxis in the diffusive limit. (arXiv:2211.01415v1 [math.AP])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01415</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;In this work we first prove, by formal arguments, that the diffusion limit of
nonlinear kinetic equations, where both the transport term and the turning
operator are density-dependent, leads to volume-exclusion chemotactic
equations. We generalise an asymptotic preserving scheme for such nonlinear
kinetic equations based on a micro-macro decomposition. By properly
discretizing the nonlinear term implicitly-explicitly in an upwind manner, the
scheme produces accurate approximations also in the case of strong
chemosensitivity. We show, via detailed calculations, that the scheme presents
the following properties: asymptotic preserving, positivity preserving and
energy dissipation, which are essential for practical applications. We extend
this scheme to two dimensional kinetic models and we validate its efficiency by
means of 1D and 2D numerical experiments of pattern formation in biological
systems.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Estrada_Rodriguez_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Gissell Estrada-Rodriguez&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Peurichard_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Diane Peurichard&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Ruan_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xinran Ruan&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01448">
<title>Inevitable monokineticity of strongly singular alignment. (arXiv:2211.01448v1 [math.AP])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01448</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We prove that certain types of measure-valued mappings are monokinetic i.e.
the distribution of velocity is concentrated in a Dirac mass. These include
weak measure-valued solutions to the strongly singular Cucker-Smale model with
singularity of order $\alpha$ greater or equal to the dimension of the ambient
space. Consequently, we are able to answer a couple of open questions related
to the singular Cucker-Smale model. First, we prove that weak measure-valued
solutions to the strongly singular Cucker-Smale kinetic equation are
monokinetic, under very mild assumptions that they are uniformly compactly
supported and weakly continuous in time. This can be interpreted as a rigorous
derivation of the macroscopic fractional Euler-alignment system from kinetic
Cucker-Smale equation without the need to perform any hydrodynamical limit.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This suggests superior suitability of the macroscopic framework to describe
large-crowd limits of strongly singular Cucker-Smale dynamics.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Second, we perform a direct micro- to macroscopic mean-field limit from the
Cucker-Smale particle system to the fractional Euler-alignment model. This
leads to the final result -- existence of weak solutions to the fractional
Euler-alignment system with almost arbitrary initial data in $\mathbb{R}^1$,
including the possibility of vacuum. Existence can be extended to
$\mathbb{R}^2$ under the a priori assumption that the density of the mean-field
limit has no atoms.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Fabisiak_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Micha&amp;#x142; Fabisiak&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Peszek_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jan Peszek&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01574">
<title>Quasilinear P.D.Es, Interpolation spaces and H\&quot;olderian mappings. (arXiv:2211.01574v1 [math.AP])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01574</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;As in the work of Tartar ( Tartar L. Interpolation non lin\&apos;eaire et
r\&apos;egularit\&apos;e, 9, Journal of Functional Analysis, (1972), 469-489) we
developed here some new results on non linear interpolation of
$\alpha$-H\&quot;olderian mappings between normed spaces, namely, by studying the
action of the mappings on $K$-functionals and between interpolation spaces with
logarithm functors. We apply those results to obtain regularity results on the
gradient of the solution to quasilinear equations of the form $$-div(\widehat
a(\nabla u ))+V(u)=f, $$ whenever $V$ is a nonlinear potential, $f$ belongs to
non standard spaces as Lorentz-Zygmund spaces. We show among other that the
mapping $T: \ Tf=\nabla u$ is locally or globally $\alpha$-H\&quot;olderian under
suitable values of $\alpha$ and adequate hypothesis on $V$ and $\widehat a.$
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Ahmed_I/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Irshaad Ahmed&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Fiorenza_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Alberto Fiorenza&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Formica_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Maria Rosaria Formica&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Gogatishvili_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Amiran Gogatishvili&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Hamidi_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Abdallah El Hamidi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Rakotoson_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jean Michel Rakotoson&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01594">
<title>Global Solutions with Small Initial Data to Semilinear Wave Equations with Energy Supercritical Powers. (arXiv:2211.01594v1 [math.AP])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01594</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Considering $1+n$ dimensional semilinear wave equations with energy
supercritical powers $p&amp;gt; 1+4/(n-2)$, we obtain global solutions for any initial
data with small norm in $H^{s_c}\times H^{s_c-1}$, under the technical smooth
condition $p&amp;gt;s_c-s_0$, with certain $s_0\le 1$ and $s_c=n/2-2/(p-1)$. When
$p\geq 2$, we could take $s_0=1$. In particular, combined with previous works,
our results give a complete verification of the Strauss conjecture, up to space
dimension $9$. The higher dimensional case, $n\ge 10$, seems to be unreachable,
in view of the wellposed theory in $H^s$.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Shao_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Kerun Shao&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Wang_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Chengbo Wang&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01637">
<title>Sharp Lower Bound for the Blow-up Rate of Solutions to the Magnetic Zakharov System without the Skin Effect. (arXiv:2211.01637v1 [math.AP])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01637</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;In this paper, we consider the Cauchy problem of the magnetic Zakharov system
in a cold plasma without the skin effect in two-dimensional space: \[
\begin{cases} &amp;amp; i E_{1t}+\Delta E_1-n E_1+\eta E_2
(E_1\overline{E_2}-\overline{E_1} E_2)=0, \\ &amp;amp; i E_{2t}+\Delta E_2-n E_2+\eta
E_1(\overline{E_1} E_2-E_1\overline{E_2})=0, \\ &amp;amp; n_t+\nabla \cdot
\textbf{v}=0, \\ &amp;amp; \textbf{v}_t+\nabla n+\nabla (|E_1|^2+|E_2|^2)=0, \\
\end{cases} \tag{G-Z} \] with initial data
$\left(E_{10}(x),E_{20}(x),n_{0}(x),\mathbf{v}_{0}(x)\right)$, where $\eta&amp;gt;0$
is a physical constant. Compared with the classical Zakharov system, (G-Z)
contains two extra cubic coupling terms
$E_2\left(E_1\overline{E_2}-\overline{E_1}E_2\right)$ and
$E_1\left(\overline{E_1}E_2-E_1\overline{E_2}\right)$ generated by the cold
magnetic field without the skin effect, which bring another difficulty. By
making a priori estimates corresponding for these extra terms, we obtain the
sharp lower bound of blow-up rate of the finite-time blow-up solutions to the
Cauchy problem of (G-Z) in the energy space
$\mathbb{H}_1=H^1(\mathbb{R}^2)\times H^1(\mathbb{R}^2)\times
L^2(\mathbb{R}^2)\times L^2(\mathbb{R}^2)$ provided the initial data satisfy
\begin{gather*} \frac{||Q||_{L^2(\mathbb{R}^2)}^2}{1+\eta}
&amp;lt;||E_{10}||_{L^2(\mathbb{R}^2)}^2+||E_{20}||_{L^2(\mathbb{R}^2)}^2
&amp;lt;\frac{||Q||_{L^2(\mathbb{R}^2)}^2}{\eta}, \end{gather*} where $Q$ is the
unique radially positive solution of the equation \begin{gather*} -\Delta
V+V=V^3. \end{gather*} Namely, there is a constant $c&amp;gt;0$ depending on the
initial data only such that for $t$ near $T$, \begin{gather*}
\left\|\left(E_1,E_2,n,\textbf{v}\right)\right\|_{H^1(\mathbb{R}^2)\times
H^1(\mathbb{R}^2)\times L^2(\mathbb{R}^2)\times
L^2(\mathbb{R}^2)}\geqslant\frac{c}{ T-t }, \end{gather*} where $T$ is the
blow-up time.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Gan_Z/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Zaihui Gan&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Wang_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yuchen Wang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Yu_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jialing Yu&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01672">
<title>On local well-posedness of nonlinear dispersive equations with partially regular data. (arXiv:2211.01672v1 [math.AP])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01672</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We revisit the local well-posedness theory of nonlinear Schr\&quot;odinger and
wave equations in Sobolev spaces $H^s$ and $\dot{H}^s$, $0&amp;lt; s\leq 1$. The
theory has been well established over the past few decades under Sobolev
initial data regular with respect to all spatial variables. But here, we reveal
that the initial data do not need to have complete regularity like Sobolev
spaces, but only partially regularity with respect to some variables is
sufficient. To develop such a new theory, we suggest a refined Strichartz
estimate which has a different norm for each spatial variable. This makes it
possible to extract a different integrability/regularity of the data from each
variable.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Koh_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Youngwoo Koh&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Lee_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yoonjung Lee&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Seo_I/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ihyeok Seo&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01702">
<title>On diagonal canonical solutions to the Einstein field equations and their meromorphic deformations. (arXiv:2211.01702v1 [math-ph])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01702</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Explicit solutions to the non-linear field equations of gravitational
theories can be obtained, using a Riemann-Hilbert approach, from an appropriate
factorization of certain matrix functions. Here we study a class of solutions,
which we call diagonal canonical solutions, obtained via Wiener-Hopf
factorization of diagonal matrices. This class comprises, among others, the
Schwarzschild, Kasner, Einstein-Rosen and gravitational pulse wave solutions.
We show that new solutions can be obtained by a method of meromorphic
deformation of the diagonal canonical solutions and that we can define Abelian
groups of such solutions indexed by a curve in the complex plane.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math-ph/1/au:+Camara_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;M. Cristina C&amp;#xe2;mara&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math-ph/1/au:+Cardoso_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Gabriel Lopes Cardoso&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01853">
<title>On the Coupling of Well Posed Differential Models -- Detailed Version. (arXiv:2211.01853v1 [math.AP])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01853</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Consider the coupling of $2$ evolution equations, each generating a global
process. We prove that the resulting system generates a new global process.
This statement can be applied to differential equations of various kinds. In
particular, it also yields the well posedness of a predator-prey model, where
the coupling is in the differential terms, and of an epidemiological model,
which does not fit previous well posedness results.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Colombo_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Rinaldo M. Colombo&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Garavello_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Mauro Garavello&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Tandy_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Matthew Tandy&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01932">
<title>On the continuum limit of epidemiological models on graphs: convergence results, approximation and numerical simulations. (arXiv:2211.01932v1 [math.AP])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01932</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We focus on an epidemiological model (the archetypical SIR system) defined on
graphs and study the asymptotic behavior of the solutions as the number of
vertices in the graph diverges. By relying on the theory of so called graphons
we provide a characterization of the limit and establish convergence results.
We also provide approximation results for both deterministic and random
discretizations. We illustrate the analytic findings through an extensive set
of numerical simulations.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Dios_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Blanca Ayuso de Dios&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Dovetta_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Simone Dovetta&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Spinolo_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Laura V. Spinolo&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01973">
<title>On the invariant region for compressible Euler equations with a general equation of state. (arXiv:2211.01973v1 [math.AP])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01973</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The state space for solutions of the compressible Euler equations with a
general equation of state is examined. An arbitrary equation of state is
allowed, subject only to the physical requirements of thermodynamics. An
invariant region of the resulting Euler system is identified and the convexity
property of this region is justified by using only very minimal thermodynamical
assumptions. Finally, we show how an invariant-region-preserving (IRP) limiter
can be constructed for use in high order finite-volume type schemes to solve
the compressible Euler equations with a general constitutive relation.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Liu_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Hailiang Liu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Thein_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ferdinand Thein&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01985">
<title>Notes on Hardy&apos;s Uncertainty Principle for the Wigner distribution and Schr\&quot;{o}dinger evolutions. (arXiv:2211.01985v1 [math.AP])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01985</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We consider Schr\&quot;{o}dinger equations with real quadratic Hamiltonians, for
which the Wigner distribution of the solution at a given time equals, up to a
linear coordinate transformation, the Wigner distribution of the initial
condition. Based on Hardy&apos;s uncertainty principle for the joint time-frequency
representation, we prove a uniqueness result for such Schr\&quot;{o}dinger
equations, where the solution cannot have strong decay at two distinct times.
This approach reproduces known, sharp results for the free Schr\&quot;{o}dinger
equation and the harmonic oscillator, and we also present an explicit scheme
for quadratic systems based on positive definite matrices.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Knutsen_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Helge Knutsen&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2205.03095">
<title>The well-posedness of the stochastic nonlinear Schr\&quot;odinger equations in $H^2(\mathbb{R}^d)$. (arXiv:2205.03095v2 [math.AP] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2205.03095</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The Cauchy problem for the stochastic nonlinear Schr\&quot;odinger equation with a
multiplicable noise is considered where the nonlinear term is of a power type
and its coefficients are complex numbers. In particular, it is extremely
important to consider the complex coefficients in the noise which cover
non-conservative case, because they include measurement effects in quantum
physics. The main purpose of this paper is to construct classical solutions in
$H^2(\mathbb{R}^d)$ for the problem in question. The time local well-posedness
in $L^2(\mathbb{R}^d)$ and $H^1(\mathbb{R}^d)$ was investigated in the papers
[7,8]. In this paper we study the well-posedness in $H^2(\mathbb{R}^d)$ by
making use of the rescaling approach as a main tool for dealing with the
multiple noise, where we need to take advantage of a slight modification of the
deterministic Strichartz estimate to fit into requirements under the setting of
$H^2(\mathbb{R}^d)$. The other difficulty lies on the discussion on smoothness
of functions in the nonlinear term, where the proof of time local
well-posedness for the case of $H^2$-solutions does not go similarly as in the
cases of $L^2$-solutions or $H^1$-solutions, because of the complexity in the
computation of the nonlinear term with lower exponent $\alpha$. The techniques
of Kato [18,19] work well on this difficulty even for the stochastic equations.
We use the stochastic Strichartz estimate [4,16,17] as well to deal with white
noise which did not appear in the proof for $L^2$-solutions or $H^1$-solutions.
We also discuss time-global solutions in $H^2(\mathbb{R}^d)$.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Doku_I/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Isamu D&amp;#xf4;ku&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Hashimoto_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Shunya Hashimoto&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Machihara_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Shuji Machihara&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2206.08682">
<title>Spectral inequality with sensor sets of decaying density for Schr\&quot;odinger operators with power growth potentials. (arXiv:2206.08682v2 [math.AP] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2206.08682</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We prove a spectral inequality for Shubin-type operators and more general
Schr\&quot;odinger operators with confinement potentials. The sensor sets are
allowed to decay exponentially, where the precise allowed decay rate depends on
the potential. The proof uses an interpolation inequality derived by Carleman
estimates and quantitative weighted $L^2$-estimates for functions in the
spectral subspace of the operator.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Dicke_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Alexander Dicke&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Seelmann_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Albrecht Seelmann&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Veselic_I/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ivan Veselic&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2208.01842">
<title>Remarks on the determination of the Lorentzian metric by the length of geodesics. (arXiv:2208.01842v3 [math.AP] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2208.01842</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We consider a Lorentzian metric in $\R\times\R^n$. We show that if we know
the lengths of space-time geodesics starting at $(0,y,\eta)$ when $t=0$, then
we can recover the metric.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also prove the rigidity of Lorentzian metrics.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Eskin_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Gregory Eskin&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.10037">
<title>Long time asymptotics of mixed-type Kimura diffusions. (arXiv:2210.10037v2 [math.AP] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.10037</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;This paper concerns the long-time asymptotics of diffusions with degenerate
coefficients at the domain&apos;s boundary. Degenerate diffusion operators with
mixed linear and quadratic degeneracies find applications in the analysis of
asymmetric transport at edges separating topological insulators. In one space
dimension, we characterize all possible invariant measures for such a class of
operators and in all cases show exponential convergence of the Green&apos;s kernel
to such invariant measures. We generalize the results to a class of
two-dimensional operators including those used in the analysis of topological
insulators. Several numerical simulations illustrate our theoretical findings.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Bal_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Guillaume Bal&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Chen_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Binglu Chen&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Wang_Z/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Zhongjian Wang&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.16757">
<title>Nondegeneracy of the entire solution for the $N$-Laplace Liouville equation. (arXiv:2210.16757v2 [math.AP] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.16757</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;In this note, we prove the nondegenracy of the explicit finite-mass solution
to the $N$-Laplace Liouville equation on the whole space, which is recently
shown to be unique up to scaling and translation.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Takahashi_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Futoshi Takahashi&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.00287">
<title>Well-posedness and strong attractors for a beam model with degenerate nonlocal strong damping. (arXiv:2211.00287v2 [math.AP] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.00287</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;This paper is devoted to initial-boundary value problem of an extensible beam
equation with degenerate nonlocal energy damping in
$\Omega\subset\mathbb{R}^n$: $u_{tt}-\kappa\Delta u+\Delta^2u-\gamma(\Vert
\Delta u\Vert^2+\Vert u_t\Vert^2)^q\Delta u_t+f(u)=0$. We prove the global
existence and uniqueness of weak solutions, which gives a positive answer to an
open question in [24]. Moreover, we establish the existence of a strong
attractor for the corresponding weak solution semigroup, where the ``strong&quot;
means that the compactness and attractiveness of the attractor are in the
topology of a stronger space $\mathcal{H}_{\frac{1}{q}}$.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Yan_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Senlin Yan&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Zhong_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Chengkui Zhong&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.00308">
<title>On the critical exponents for a fractional diffusion-wave equation with a nonlinear memory term in a bounded domain. (arXiv:2211.00308v2 [math.AP] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.00308</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;In this paper, we prove sharp blow-up and global existence results for a time
fractional diffusion-wave equation with a nonlinear memory term in a bounded
domain, where the fractional derivative in time is taken in the sense of Caputo
type. Moreover, we also give a result for nonexistence of global solutions to a
wave equation with a nonlinear memory term in a bounded domain. The proof of
blow-up results is based on the eigenfunction method and the asymptotic
properties of solutions for an ordinary fractional differential inequality.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Zhang_Q/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Quanguo Zhang&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
</rdf:RDF>