<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>Vox -  World</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52517/voxv.png</icon>
  <updated>2022-11-05T12:24:37-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.vox.com/rss/world/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/world" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-11-05T12:24:37-04:00</published>
    <updated>2022-11-05T12:24:37-04:00</updated>
    <title>North Korean missile launches may mean new nuclear tests </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="U.S. Bombers Stage Joint Drills With South Korean Fighter Jets" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/-80G1zGgkRpKRBx_DNUwvKzTnb0=/490x0:5718x3921/1310x983/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/71588892/1439166424.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;In this handout image released by the South Korean Defense Ministry, two U.S. B-1B Lancer strategic bombers, four South Korean Air Force F-35 fighter jets and four U.S. Air Force F-16 fighter jets fly over South Korea during the “Vigilant Storm” joint air drill on November 05, 2022. | South Korean Defense Ministry via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Nuclear diplomacy is urgently needed amid rising tensions but politically untenable. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p id="YI0F9Q"&gt;US and South Korean officials believe North Korea may be gearing up for its seventh nuclear test after the country, led by dictator Kim Jong Un, launched a barrage of missiles this week, including an intercontinental ballistic missile (ICBM) in violation of repeated &lt;a href="https://www.armscontrol.org/factsheets/UN-Security-Council-Resolutions-on-North-Korea"&gt;United Nations Security Council&lt;/a&gt; efforts to stop such actions. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mKhmuT"&gt;Two US B-1B bombers, along with four F-16s and four South Korean F-35s, flew in South Korean airspace as part of the extended Vigilant Storm training exercises, as North Korea launched an &lt;a href="https://apnews.com/article/japan-united-states-south-korea-evacuations-north-5d8f0935f50d013d7e9c375cc27456e5?user_email=d0ae70922af541a4cf45e48d2575200542345a2aa90b689d43e7a2924e4e3869&amp;amp;utm_source=Sailthru&amp;amp;utm_medium=email&amp;amp;utm_campaign=Nov06_MorningWire&amp;amp;utm_term=Morning%20Wire%20Subscribers"&gt;additional four short-range ballistic missiles Saturday&lt;/a&gt;. That display capped off a week of surging tensions on the peninsula; North Korea launched 23 missiles on Wednesday — the most it has ever launched on a single day — and six on Thursday including the ICBM, according to&lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2022/11/02/world/asia/north-korea-missile-japan.html"&gt; the New York Times&lt;/a&gt;. One of Wednesday’s missiles fell so close to South Korea that Seoul &lt;a href="https://apnews.com/article/seoul-south-korea-north-joint-chiefs-of-staff-government-and-politics-7d6079c606fe796dc4771fa48b9c2bfe"&gt;launched its own air-to-surface missile tests in return&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AT2HpC"&gt;Pyongyang has said the missile launches are its response to military drills the US, Japan, and South Korea routinely conduct in the area. North Korea views such exercises as a provocation; &lt;a href="https://apnews.com/article/seoul-south-korea-nuclear-weapons-north-d3a1d9d6633e6fc910bfd8a6eadf9158"&gt;according to the Associated Press&lt;/a&gt;, Pyongyang had already obliquely threatened to use nuclear weapons should the US and South Korea launch an attack. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZU0Ddr"&gt;South Korean officials indicated that the ICBM launch had failed to reach its intended altitude and speed, and Japanese Defense Minister Yasukazu Hamada refuted early reports that one of the missiles flew over Japanese airspace; still, the launches indicate an increasingly paranoid North Korean regime that has persisted in its weapons development program despite international condemnation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RsxBXD"&gt;“The US-ROK [Republic of Korea] response in the last 24 hours — extending the US-ROK drills for a longer period, plus the report that the United States is accelerating the rotation of nuclear-capable fighter jets in the region, is only going to reinforce Kim Jong Un’s paranoia about the capabilities of the United States and the ROK to conduct decapitation strikes on his regime,” Daryl Kimball, executive director of the Arms Control Association told Vox on Friday. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="C1qmpC"&gt;At the very least, according to both US and South Korean officials, as well as experts who spoke to Vox, North Korea is likely planning a nuclear test — &lt;a href="https://www.armscontrol.org/factsheets/dprkchron"&gt;the seventh in its history&lt;/a&gt; and the fifth under current leader Kim Jong Un. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="d30h6p"&gt;The US and its allies are in an extremely tense and unsustainable standoff with North Korea, and it’s increasingly difficult to find a way to stop it. “We’re in the middle of an escalatory cycle that I think both sides need to step back from,” Kimball said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="8zQHHg"&gt;Nuclear postures are becoming more bellicose&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="qWRE8V"&gt;Since first developing its nuclear weapons program in earnest in the 1990s, North Korea, or its official title, Democratic People’s Republic of Korea (DPRK) has managed to produce some 40 to 50 nuclear warheads, although some estimates put that number as high as 116, according to &lt;a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/business/energy/what-nukes-does-north-korea-have-and-could-they-hit-the-us/2022/11/03/d69177aa-5b35-11ed-bc40-b5a130f95ee7_story.html"&gt;the Washington Post&lt;/a&gt;. This week’s missile launches demonstrate how North Korea would deliver those weapons — on short-range missiles to neighboring adversaries like Japan or South Korea, and an ICBM to the United States. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xoiGI4"&gt;“The frequency of the short-range missile tests that North Korea’s conducting, the scrambling of the aircraft in response to the US-ROK drills — in my view, this indicates that North Korea is very nervous about US-ROK combined capabilities, [and] trying to demonstrate its retaliatory capabilities,” Kimball said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Aszhu2"&gt;Nuclear development, production, and testing has accelerated significantly under Kim Jong Un, the country’s third ruler from the Kim dynasty. The DPRK’s weapons program under Kim is developing a missile capable of reaching the Pacific island of Guam, a US territory and military installation, in addition to missiles that can reach US allies in the region like South Korea and Japan. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tM7Lx0"&gt;Kim has been testing ICBMs, &lt;a href="https://www.38north.org/2022/04/revisiting-the-hwasong-17-15-controversy-what-if-north-korea-had-launched-a-hwasong-15/"&gt;the Hwasong-15 and the Hwasong-17&lt;/a&gt;, capable of reaching targets in the United States itself since 2017, although there remains some doubt about whether those weapons are consistent and sophisticated enough to actually hit their intended locations. And although Thursday’s test failed, each ICBM launch provides information for the next one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iDUGYV"&gt;In addition to technical advancements, Kim has made significant policy changes around nuclear weapons use. &lt;a href="https://www.armscontrol.org/act/2022-10/news/north-korea-passes-nuclear-law"&gt;The DPRK’s new nuclear weapons law&lt;/a&gt;, which Kim announced in September, maintains that North Korea is officially a nuclear state and will not pursue disarmament. Perhaps more alarmingly, the new policy indicates that the DPRK will launch a nuclear attack in the case of a so-called “decapitation strike” to take out North Korean leadership, or if the DPRK’s military objectives aren’t being met through conventional warfare. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1Kwu20"&gt;Kim’s increasing fear that his adversaries are planning to take him out isn’t unfounded; South Korea’s military policies in relation to the North are called the Kill Chain — a plan to take out DPRK leadership, including Kim, with conventional weapons — and Korean Massive Punishment and Retaliation (KMPR), which is the military’s retaliatory strategy in case of an attack, as &lt;a href="https://carnegieendowment.org/2022/08/15/south-korea-s-decapitation-strategy-against-north-korea-has-more-risks-than-benefits-pub-87672"&gt;the Carnegie Endowment for International Peace’s Ankit Panda wrote in August&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tjrU5g"&gt;The US’s latest &lt;a href="https://fas.org/blogs/security/2022/10/2022-nuclear-posture-review/"&gt;Nuclear Posture Review&lt;/a&gt; also contains a new specific threat against the Kim regime: “Any nuclear attack by North Korea against the United States or its Allies and partners is unacceptable and will result in the end of that regime.” Although the new threats are not pre-emptive, they still promise that, ”there is no scenario in which the Kim regime could employ nuclear weapons and survive.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0ewvp6"&gt;But part of any deterrent strategy — and a part that seems to be missing in the US and South Korea’s strategy, Panda told Vox, is reassuring an adversary. “That is traditionally a part of deterrence,” he said. “Not just making credible threats, but giving credible assurances that if the adversary doesn’t do the bad thing that you don’t want them to do, you’re not going to inflict pain on them anyway.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="maxYtw"&gt;There are also indications that the DPRK is preparing for a test, Kimball said, including construction at the DPRK’s Punngye-ri nuclear test site, as well as the fact that Kim has abandoned a unilateral nuclear weapons and long-range missile testing moratorium agreed in April 2018. Furthermore, Kim in 2021 discussed tactical nuclear weapons for the first time publicly; those capabilities had never been part of the DPRK’s military doctrine, but it’s likely that they would be testing lower yield nuclear weapons this time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dmhjkF"&gt;“They’ve been telling us that they’re going to do it for a while,” Dalton said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="zLunpJ"&gt;Negotiations have broken down — and it’s not clear how to get them back on track&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="9Ahoyl"&gt; The &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/2022/3/6/22964312/russia-putin-nuclear-disarmament-nonproliferation-interview"&gt;global status of nuclear treaties&lt;/a&gt; overall has seriously declined in recent decades — not that North Korea has considered itself subject to any since &lt;a href="https://www.cfr.org/timeline/north-korean-nuclear-negotiations"&gt;unilaterally withdrawing from the Non-Proliferation Treaty in 2003&lt;/a&gt;. Nuclear and missile tests in violation of international norms and agreements have become par for the course in the DPRK; it doesn’t mean that nuclear war is about to break out, and it’s not particularly helpful to spin out every time it happens. But it is important to pay attention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cPPJQ5"&gt;“[The escalations are] disconcerting and worrisome because there are more missiles being tested in a short period of time, but putting all of this together, this is the unsurprising and worrisome result of some four-and-a-half years of no meaningful diplomatic dialogue about risk reduction, and denuclearization and peace on the peninsula.” Kimball said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UBIn3z"&gt;Kimball pointed out that although the US has offered dialogue with North Korea to de-escalate the situation, the DPRK has refused to engage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cBWFwv"&gt;Kim likely feels wary of engaging in diplomacy with the US or South Korea because of the &lt;a href="http://ytimes.com/2019/03/02/world/asia/trump-kim-jong-un-summit.html"&gt;spectacular breakdown&lt;/a&gt; of peace talks with former President Donald Trump, Dalton said. That process ended in a humiliating failure in Hanoi, Vietnam, when Trump tried to push for full denuclearization in return for an end to the punishing sanctions regime the US has built up over the decades. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Fl9kap"&gt;“[Kim] took some risks in terms of his domestic constituency in terms of pursuing that diplomacy — and then it fell apart and I think he was embarrassed by that,” Dalton said. From North Korea’s perspective, “they’re not willing to trust South Korea or the US to engage in diplomacy,” he told Vox, and the parties involved aren’t even in agreement about what the outcome of that diplomacy would be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XDX39N"&gt;Since that breakdown, the global order has shifted, too. “China and Russia have a different view of North Korea and they both view Kim Jong Un as more of an asset than a liability,” Panda said, noting recent reports that North Korea is providing artillery to Russia in its ongoing invasion of Ukraine. “Then we might ask, reasonably, what is the quid pro quo there? &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/un-chief-urges-north-korea-resume-denuclearization-talks-2022-11-04/"&gt;Probably that Russia is going to support North Korea at the UN Security Council,&lt;/a&gt;” he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sE5wvH"&gt;Despite all of these consequential changes, the US and its allies are using the same tools to try and fix the problem of proliferation. While conventional weapons drills and sanctions may have been useful years ago, when the DPRK’s nuclear program was much smaller, Kim has made clear that the calculus has changed and he’s forging ahead with the nuclear program — perhaps with even more determination than in the past. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7ZXSzy"&gt;Increasingly harsh sanctions have helped push North Korea further away from engagement with the US and toward Russia and China, as well as driving the North Korean people further into extreme poverty. But they haven’t stopped the &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/03/24/world/asia/tankers-north-korea-china.html"&gt;illicit trade&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.cnn.com/2022/09/08/politics/fbi-north-korea-hackers-30-million-axie-infinity/index.html#:~:text=North%20Korean%20government%2Dbacked%20hackers,according%20to%20the%20United%20Nations."&gt;outright theft&lt;/a&gt;, and sheer determination on the part of the Kim regime to support the nuclear program. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jdMcS4"&gt;“Kim Jong Un has invested, over his 10-plus years in power now, in domestic talent,” Panda said. “He is ensuring that North Korea has a long-term supply of human resources and talent to sustain their missile and nuclear forces.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Lu6P51"&gt;The US could take take the temperature down by removing some sanctions to signal a desire to avoid greater conflict, although that would be “politically controversial,” Dalton said. The US could also recognize in some way North Korea’s demonstrated status as a nuclear state — also an unpopular tack, due to fears that officially recognizing that reality would send Japan and South Korea scrambling for nuclear weapons of their own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gOTcjk"&gt;But any deviation from standard practice is unlikely, Dalton said, because “nobody wants to take the blame for allowing North Korea to become a state with nuclear weapons.”&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/2022/11/5/23440456/korean-missile-launches-nuclear-tests-china-russia-japan"/>
    <id>https://www.vox.com/2022/11/5/23440456/korean-missile-launches-nuclear-tests-china-russia-japan</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ellen Ioanes</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-11-05T08:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2022-11-05T08:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Biden’s hugely consequential high-tech export ban on China, explained by an expert</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Semiconductor Wafer Manufacturing In Huai’an" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/eDw0gUpUpNygRwRPgjmexJMqDmI=/1182x0:6451x3952/1310x983/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/71588113/1428277847.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;An employee works on the production line of semiconductors at a factory in Huai’an, China, on September 27. | VCG/VCG via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;The ban on semiconductor exports to China is one of the most important policy moves of the year — and could set off a geopolitical quake. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p id="LM0lDK"&gt;One month ago, the US Commerce Department issued an exceptionally broad set of &lt;a href="https://www.bis.doc.gov/index.php/documents/about-bis/newsroom/press-releases/3158-2022-10-07-bis-press-release-advanced-computing-and-semiconductor-manufacturing-controls-final/file"&gt;prohibitions&lt;/a&gt; on exports to China of semiconductor chips and other high-tech equipment. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vAUwyE"&gt;The very technical nature of the export controls might obscure just how consequential this new policy could be — perhaps among the most important of this administration.&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gGFME1"&gt;The new rules appear to mark a major shift in the Biden administration’s China strategy, and present a substantial threat to high-tech industries in China, including military technology and artificial intelligence. Washington think tank CSIS &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/analysis/choking-chinas-access-future-ai"&gt;called&lt;/a&gt; the White House’s new approach to the Chinese tech sector “strangling with an intent to kill.” A Chinese American tech entrepreneur &lt;a href="https://mobile.twitter.com/jordanschnyc/status/1580889341265469440"&gt;tweeted&lt;/a&gt; that China’s chip businesses fear “annihilation” and “industry-wide decapitation.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IfKwqN"&gt;Dominance across cutting-edge technologies has long been a &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2022/10/27/opinion/china-america-chip-tech-war.html"&gt;centerpiece&lt;/a&gt; of Beijing’s vision for the country’s future. China can already compete with industry leaders across a &lt;a href="https://www.brookings.edu/essay/u-s-china-technology-competition/"&gt;range&lt;/a&gt; of leading-edge technologies, but global semiconductor production is still &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/analysis/choking-chinas-access-future-ai"&gt;dominated&lt;/a&gt; by a few corporations, none of them Chinese. China is dependent on foreign chips; the country spends &lt;a href="https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-war/article/3191682/chinas-semiconductor-imports-continue-contract-amid-economic"&gt;more per year&lt;/a&gt; importing chips &lt;a href="https://www.globaltimes.cn/page/202204/1259198.shtml"&gt;than oil&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pItcvB"&gt;But the new &lt;a href="https://www.bis.doc.gov/index.php/documents/about-bis/newsroom/press-releases/3158-2022-10-07-bis-press-release-advanced-computing-and-semiconductor-manufacturing-controls-final/file"&gt;export controls&lt;/a&gt; ban the export to China of cutting-edge chips, as well as chip design software, chip manufacturing equipment, and US-built components of manufacturing equipment. Not only do the prohibitions cover exports from American firms, but also apply to any company worldwide that uses US semiconductor technology — which would cover all the world’s leading chipmakers. The new rules also forbid US citizens, residents, and green-card holders from working in Chinese chip firms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Lr29Hq"&gt;In short, the Biden administration wants to prevent China from buying the world’s best chips and the machines to make them. These top chips will power not only the next generations of military and AI technologies, but also self-driving vehicles and the surveillance tech that Beijing relies on to monitor its citizens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aCkDpT"&gt;What are the stakes of the Biden administration’s move? How will China respond? Where does this geopolitical drama go next? To find out, I spoke with Jordan Schneider, a senior analyst for China and technology at the Rhodium Group, a research firm. A transcript of our conversation follows, edited for length and clarity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="8auHPz"&gt;Michael Bluhm&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p id="E7rPJ3"&gt;What is the Biden administration hoping to achieve with these export controls?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="LfEd5z"&gt;Jordan Schneider&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p id="zlxtpb"&gt;In a &lt;a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/09/16/remarks-by-national-security-advisor-jake-sullivan-at-the-special-competitive-studies-project-global-emerging-technologies-summit/"&gt;speech&lt;/a&gt; in September, National Security Adviser Jake Sullivan gave a new justification for US thinking about export controls of emerging technologies in China. He made the case that certain technologies are “&lt;a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/09/16/remarks-by-national-security-advisor-jake-sullivan-at-the-special-competitive-studies-project-global-emerging-technologies-summit/"&gt;force multipliers&lt;/a&gt;,” and so important to future economic and national security eventualities that the US needs to do whatever it can to increase the gap between American and Chinese capabilities. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qfk8ty"&gt;Because of that, you now see these path-breaking and very aggressive tech controls on semiconductors. The goal is to maintain, for certain foundational technologies, as large a lead as possible for the rest of the world ahead of China.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="4Kz76i"&gt;Michael Bluhm&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p id="HXoV6B"&gt;Observers in both the US and China have said that this is a tremendously important move by the Biden administration, for both technology and geopolitics. How big of a deal is this?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="f2GYVU"&gt;Jordan Schneider&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p id="2MKnBn"&gt;It’s a big deal for the Chinese semiconductor industry. It’s a big deal for the global semiconductor industry. When you’re weighing its importance in the entirety of US policy, it is a relatively niche thing, but it’s important because it’s an inflection point. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1wE617"&gt;It’s the first manifestation of this new doctrine that Jake Sullivan put forward, and it’s likely to play out across a number of different technologies. Alan Estevez, the undersecretary of commerce who leads the Commerce Department’s Bureau of Industry and Security, said in late October that the US is &lt;a href="https://www.nextgov.com/emerging-tech/2022/10/us-and-allies-developing-deal-export-controls-targeting-chinas-chip-access/379016/"&gt;not necessarily going to stop at semiconductors&lt;/a&gt;. They’re going to go down the list of the potential, emerging technologies that will define the next few decades of the global economic and technological landscape, and then figure out what the US can do to try to constrain domestic Chinese capabilities. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="eKF8jW"&gt;The export controls are an important fulcrum for a number of reasons. First, during these first two years of the Biden administration, it wasn’t clear that they would land where they did: taking much more aggressive steps to constrain Chinese technological development. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SfNkym"&gt;Second, it’s a milestone on a very long arc. In the early 1980s, the US was trying to boost Chinese technology, to balance against the Soviet Union. We brought China into the World Trade Organization. And now, the conclusion by a centrist Democrat president — which would be ramped up and amplified if a Republican took office — is that China can’t be trusted with frontier tech. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fgnLsq"&gt;That’s because of China’s place in the world, and in particular because of the centrality of civil-military fusion in [Chinese President Xi Jinping’s] vision — the idea that the Chinese state is hoping to use civilian companies to directly increase Chinese military capabilities. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HARJE4"&gt;The restrictions are a very dramatic decision by the Biden administration, and if US-China competition weren’t already baked in, this is really a point of no return for the relationship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="9FKNk0"&gt;Michael Bluhm&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p id="Zx8IlF"&gt;This seems like a dramatic geopolitical moment. And this relationship, at least according to some analysts, might define global politics in the 21st century. How might the export controls affect dynamics between the US and China?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="ccVhra"&gt;Jordan Schneider&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p id="udEPGr"&gt;It’s important to recognize that this is a dynamic environment. The Chinese government will have its say, too. With the Chinese Communist Party’s &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/2022/10/23/23419022/xi-jinping-third-term-communist-party-china-congress"&gt;recent Party Congress&lt;/a&gt;, we had a dramatic manifestation of just how much Xi has consolidated power and how his vision of China’s future will dominate the People’s Republic for years. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UT6znV"&gt;The Biden administration spent its first two years saying to China, “Let’s do some stuff on climate change. Maybe we can collaborate on some public-health issues&lt;em&gt;.”&lt;/em&gt; Time after time, the Chinese government has just not been interested in pursuing the positive-sum activities that the Biden administration came in thinking that it might be able to pursue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6o3TUC"&gt;The Biden administration would have liked a slightly more even balance between the competitive, collaborative, and adversarial parts of the US-China relationship, but that’s not where Xi wants to take it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="P3iNqq"&gt;The administration has come to the conclusion that the types of collaboration that Xi is particularly interested in — such as the transfer to China of foreign technologies — doesn’t play to the US advantage in the long term. There’s a completely merited lack of trust, in the Biden administration, for where Xi wants to take China.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="SA4mKY"&gt;Michael Bluhm&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p id="RqWKYl"&gt;You began your answer by making the point that China has agency here, too— and by noting Xi’s increasing political dominance. So how are China’s leaders responding to the export controls?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="tQ4FK3"&gt;Jordan Schneider&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p id="r0XbD0"&gt;We haven’t heard a lot in the past few weeks, for understandable reasons. The Party Congress is the largest political event every five years, and it definitely led to less decision-making bandwidth for senior leaders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PZr9el"&gt;Given some &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/china-holds-emergency-talks-with-chip-firms-after-us-curbs-bloomberg-news-2022-10-20/"&gt;recent reporting from Bloomberg&lt;/a&gt; about a conversation that officials from China’s Ministry of Industry and Information Technology had with senior executives in the Chinese semiconductor industry, it seems like they’re still processing what this means for the future of their industry. They will soon find, if they haven’t already, that this is a really devastating blow for the future of Chinese firms trying to develop frontier tech in the chip space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GQ6p8H"&gt;They have a number of potential paths ahead. They could double down on manufacturing lagging-edge tech, which means well-established technologies that are still widely used in countless products. They could try to punish the US by retaliating against leading electronics firms. They could retaliate directly against the semiconductor supply chain by making moves on the &lt;a href="https://www.mining-technology.com/analysis/china-rare-earths-dominance-mining/"&gt;rare earth minerals&lt;/a&gt; necessary to make chips, or on packaging — areas where China has a considerable place in the global market. They could do something as escalatory as a cyber-attack on some leading-edge American chipmaker.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ABjBGb"&gt;Given how core this vision of creating a self-reliant tech ecosystem is to China’s leaders, I don’t think they’re going to look at these export controls and say, “Okay, maybe we should give up and focus somewhere else&lt;em&gt;.”&lt;/em&gt; The long-term goal of creating leading-edge capacity in China has been such a core part of Xi’s vision that I find it hard to imagine them not taking this as a challenge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="cSAbnm"&gt;Michael Bluhm &lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p id="MmYiNZ"&gt;Building a cutting-edge tech industry is a critical part of Xi’s strategy, as you say, but the US is also working to move some chip manufacturing onshore. The pandemic made clear to many in both parties that the US was dependent on fragile supply chains for many of the most critical technologies. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pKreFK"&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/recode/2022/7/27/23277664/chips-act-solve-chip-shortage-biden-manufacturing"&gt;CHIPS Act&lt;/a&gt; passed in July with bipartisan support in the Senate, and it aims to support research and production of semiconductor chips in America. But how realistic is it to build a substantial chip manufacturing industry in the United States?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="GP9bQ4"&gt;Jordan Schneider&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p id="CER62c"&gt;It’s definitely realistic. For a long time, America manufactured most of these chips. It’s unrealistic to do what China is now going to have to do: create leading-edge chips in China by localizing thousands of different steps in the supply chain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Agut8q"&gt;The CHIPS Act and the broader push to restore semiconductor fabrication to the US has a number of different aims. The Commerce Department outlined four goals in its &lt;a href="https://www.nist.gov/document/chips-america-strategy"&gt;strategy document&lt;/a&gt;: to invest in American production of strategically important chips, particularly leading-edge chips; to make the global supply chain more sustainable, particularly for national security purposes; to support American R&amp;amp;D; and make the American semiconductor workforce more diverse and vibrant. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2yvwZI"&gt;Those aims are achievable, though it’s unclear whether the funding in the act is going to be enough. Given the worries about &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/recode/2022/9/28/23375712/chips-semiconductors-china-taiwan-conflict"&gt;potential disruption of chip manufacturing in Taiwan&lt;/a&gt;, this is a bit of an insurance policy for any eventuality there. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WgYmL7"&gt;There is also a broader justification in industrial strategy, because this is and will continue to be one of the most important industries. Without this support, it’s unlikely that much new semiconductor &lt;a href="https://www.pcmag.com/encyclopedia/term/fab"&gt;fabrication&lt;/a&gt; capacity would come online at all within the US, because it’s competing against Taiwan, Singapore, Japan, China, and South Korea, all of which subsidize domestic manufacturers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="EcZejT"&gt;Michael Bluhm&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p id="2JzSVs"&gt;In the end, how seriously do you think this could damage the Chinese high-tech industry? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="H218w6"&gt;Jordan Schneider&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p id="wzqQVm"&gt;This is essentially freezing in place the level to which these Chinese fabrication firms have advanced today. There’s a ton of fabrication capacity in lagging-edge tech in China. They’ll be able to continue business as usual, making hundreds of millions of chips that go into electronics sold all over the world. But they won’t be able to make the highest-end, highest performance, most power-efficient chips, which the US government has identified as being important — particularly for WMD, but also in the coming artificial intelligence revolution. These are the chips that are going to be running the AI models that are going to shape our lives militarily and economically. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SvBDwV"&gt;The advancement that you would expect Chinese firms to make is now largely closed off to them. The international technology and suppliers that they would need to advance to where Intel, TSMC, and Samsung currently are, is now blocked off to them, thanks to these new regulations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Sm7NgY"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Michael Bluhm is a senior editor at &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.thesgnl.com/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Signal&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;. He was previously the managing editor at the Open Markets Institute and a writer and editor for the Daily Star in Beirut.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LbOCe4"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Sqb1Bu"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/world/2022/11/5/23440525/biden-administration-semiconductor-export-ban-china"/>
    <id>https://www.vox.com/world/2022/11/5/23440525/biden-administration-semiconductor-export-ban-china</id>
    <author>
      <name>Michael Bluhm</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-11-03T18:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2022-11-03T18:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>A peace deal could end Ethiopia’s brutal civil war. Can a truce last?</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/sya1ImZ9n6bR93wT6nU83TiMFyc=/113x0:2197x1563/1310x983/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/71581921/1244430182a.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Redwan Hussein, left, representing the Ethiopian government, and Getachew Reda, right, representing the Tigray People’s Liberation Front, sign a peace agreement after peace talks in Pretoria, South Africa, on November 2. | Phill Magakoe/AFP via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;A surprise deal announced Wednesday promises peace but doesn’t offer much detail.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p id="1s7lPd"&gt;One of the world’s current deadliest conflicts and worst humanitarian crises could be moving toward a close.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rNNdBJ"&gt;On Wednesday, the Ethiopian federal government and the Tigrayan People’s Liberation Front (TPLF) came to &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/africa/african-union-parties-ethiopia-conflict-have-agreed-cease-hostilities-2022-11-02/"&gt;an agreement to permanently halt hostilities&lt;/a&gt; in a civil war that has killed tens of thousands, &lt;a href="https://www.unrefugees.org/news/ethiopia-s-tigray-refugee-crisis-explained/"&gt;displaced millions&lt;/a&gt;, pushed regions in the north to the brink of famine, and altered Ethiopia’s standing in the international community. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NYgVe2"&gt;Though the announcement was an unexpected and welcome development in the two-year conflict, &lt;a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/world-africa-63503615"&gt;questions remain&lt;/a&gt; — including whether all the involved parties will commit to the peace deal, the mechanisms for implementation, and the role of other armed actors, including the Eritrean government.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2AjpJg"&gt;“The two parties in the Ethiopian conflict have formally agreed to the cessation of hostilities as well as to systematic, orderly, smooth, and coordinated disarmament,” Olusegun Obasanjo, a former president of Nigeria who now works to mediate conflicts in Africa, announced yesterday, almost two years exactly after hostilities initially broke out in November 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IPvMhy"&gt;The deal reportedly calls for the full disarmament of Tigray’s forces within 30 days, with leaders meeting within five days to sort details. Ethiopian forces will also take control of federal facilities and major infrastructure in Tigray. (Though the official deal hasn’t yet been made public, &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2022/11/03/world/africa/ethiopia-tigray-civil-war-agreement.html"&gt;multiple&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://abcnews.go.com/International/wireStory/ethiopia-peace-deal-silence-terms-tigray-92617217"&gt;news outlets&lt;/a&gt; on Thursday obtained a copy.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gyKsjY"&gt;Thursday, Ethiopian Prime Minister&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;Abiy Ahmed &lt;a href="https://abcnews.go.com/International/wireStory/ethiopia-peace-deal-silence-terms-tigray-92617217"&gt;celebrated the deal&lt;/a&gt;, saying, “Ethiopia’s peace proposal has been accepted 100 percent.” In a &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/AbiyAhmedAli/status/1587869990006525953?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw%7Ctwcamp%5Etweetembed%7Ctwterm%5E1587869990006525953%7Ctwgr%5E%7Ctwcon%5Es1_&amp;amp;ref_url=about%3Asrcdoc"&gt;statement on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;, Abiy promised that his government’s commitment to peace “remains steadfast.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hPLcAe"&gt;The deal, the product of eight days of peace talks in &lt;a href="https://www.britannica.com/place/Pretoria"&gt;South Africa&lt;/a&gt; between the two parties and alongside&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;negotiators from the African Union like Obasanjo, surprised the world. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qCoH2E"&gt;Though an internet and media blackout, imposed by Abiy’s government at the beginning of hostilities, has made verifying information in Tigray difficult if not impossible, tens of thousands are believed to have been killed in the fighting in Tigray, while hundreds of thousands have been displaced from Tigray and the neighboring Afar and Amhara regions, &lt;a href="https://news.un.org/en/story/2022/10/1129572"&gt;according to the United Nations&lt;/a&gt;. Millions are in dire need of humanitarian assistance including food and medical care. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AAROfq"&gt;And violence in northern Ethiopia’s Tigray region had continued in the runup to the talks, which made a resolution seem increasingly unlikely. A previous humanitarian ceasefire, &lt;a href="https://www.state.gov/five-months-of-a-humanitarian-truce-in-ethiopia/"&gt;brokered in March of this year&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.aljazeera.com/news/2022/8/24/fighting-resumes-in-ethiopia-despite-truce-tigray-forces"&gt;broke down in August&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2022/10/08/world/africa/ethiopia-tigray-war-talks-us.html"&gt;American diplomatic efforts to stop the fighting&lt;/a&gt; had failed by early September, &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2022/10/08/world/africa/ethiopia-tigray-war-talks-us.html"&gt;when violence in Tigray surged again&lt;/a&gt;, with a particularly devastating impact on Tigrayan civilians. During that spate of fighting, around 500,000 people were forced from their homes; Ethiopian government forces hit a UN food truck and airstrikes hit a center for refugees near the border with Eritrea, killing at least 50 people, &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2022/10/08/world/africa/ethiopia-tigray-war-talks-us.html"&gt;the New York Times reported&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Ky6qyh"&gt;Details of the peace process are thus far scant; the TPLF has agreed to disarm and reintegrate into the federal government’s army and the government has promised to support humanitarian efforts, but other questions, such as the role of the Eritrean army, which has supported the Ethiopian forces, and other armed groups involved in the conflict haven’t yet been addressed. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XHOCQY"&gt;Parts of the deal may be difficult to implement; regional experts &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2022/11/03/world/africa/ethiopia-tigray-civil-war-agreement.html"&gt;told the New York Times&lt;/a&gt; that Tigrayan leaders might have trouble selling the disarmament portions of the reported agreement. Tigray’s lead negotiator, Getachew Reda, &lt;a href="https://abcnews.go.com/International/wireStory/ethiopia-peace-deal-silence-terms-tigray-92617217"&gt;noted that the deal contained&lt;/a&gt; “painful concessions” for the Tigrayans, including handing over control of “all federal facilities, installations, and major infrastructure ... within the Tigray region” to the federal government.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cIYInu"&gt;Obasanjo seemed to acknowledge the significant work yet to be done to ensure peace in Ethiopia. “This moment is not the end of the peace process,” he said Wednesday. “Implementation of the peace agreement signed today is critical for its success,” he added, although the mechanics of the implementation are still opaque. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="VzrAeh"&gt;The conflict has stopped, but the wounds are deep&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="qXyOz5"&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.cfr.org/global-conflict-tracker/conflict/conflict-ethiopia"&gt;conflict in Tigray&lt;/a&gt; began in November 2020, after two years of tension between Tigrayan leadership and Prime Minister Abiy Ahmed, who was elected to his office in 2018 after nearly 30 years of Tigrayan political dominance. Though Tigrayans are a minority ethnic group within Ethiopia, the TPLF consolidated power first under the autocratic regime of Meles Zenawi, to the detriment of larger ethnic groups like the Oromo, Amhara, and Somali populations; Ethiopia under Tigrayan leadership also fought a low-level, frozen conflict over the next two decades with neighboring Eritrea. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7zSZkq"&gt;In 2019, &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2019/10/11/world/africa/nobel-peace-prize.html#:~:text=Abiy%20Ahmed%2C%20the%20prime%20minister,of%20political%20and%20economic%20repression."&gt;Abiy won the Nobel Peace Prize&lt;/a&gt; for ending hostilities with Eritrea and for instituting domestic reforms like rolling back press censorship, releasing political prisoners, and allowing political opposition groups. Despite these accomplishments, though, Ethiopia’s democratic progress deteriorated quickly after Abiy’s government repeatedly delayed national elections and extended his time in power in June 2020, as the &lt;a href="https://www.cfr.org/global-conflict-tracker/conflict/conflict-ethiopia"&gt;Council on Foreign Relations&lt;/a&gt; explained. Tigrayan leadership held local elections despite the delays, solidifying the TPLF’s power in the region — and warned the federal government not to intervene or risk igniting conflict.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ERJ5GU"&gt;Abiy sent troops from the Ethiopian National Defense Force (ENDF) to Tigray on November 4, 2020, after accusing the TPLF of raiding a national military depot for weapons. Over the next few months, the low-level conflict ballooned into a civil war; Eritrean troops joined on the side of the federal government, although Abiy initially denied their presence in Tigray. &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/africa/more-than-50-killed-northern-ethiopia-air-strike-say-aid-workers-tigray-forces-2022-10-05/"&gt;They, along with ENDF troops&lt;/a&gt;, the &lt;a href="https://www.hrw.org/news/2021/12/10/ethiopia-tigray-forces-summarily-execute-civilians"&gt;Tigray Defense Forces (TDF)&lt;/a&gt;, and TDF allies the &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2022-06-21/ethiopian-military-tagets-rebels-accused-of-killing-civilians"&gt;Oromo Liberation Army&lt;/a&gt; have been accused of &lt;a href="https://apnews.com/article/africa-only-on-ap-kenya-ethiopia-eritrea-b86f4f1fbc836f132e15e1d65893b0d3"&gt;targeting civilians&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TYpMKb"&gt;Information about the humanitarian situation in Tigray and the contours of the conflict have been difficult to come by; Abiy &lt;a href="https://www.voanews.com/a/press-freedom_journalists-struggle-through-information-blackout-ethiopia/6199045.html"&gt;instituted an internet and media blackout in the region&lt;/a&gt; at the start of the war, making it difficult to verify sites of attack or numbers of casualties. A federal government blockade of the region began in June 2021, after the TPLF retook control of the region from federal forces; since then, except for a brief reprieve earlier this year, Tigrayans have suffered from a desperate lack of necessities like food, fuel, and medical supplies. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nDvjWB"&gt;Ethiopia overall and Tigray in particular have some of the most severe food insecurity outlooks in the world, according to the &lt;a href="https://reliefweb.int/report/ethiopia/ethiopia-food-security-outlook-june-2022-january-2023"&gt;Famine Early Warning System&lt;/a&gt;; that’s due to a combination of low levels of rainfall, instability limiting agricultural activity, and outside supply factors — specifically the war in Ukraine. Since the beginning of Russia’s invasion, countries including Ethiopia that rely on Ukrainian grain to feed their populations have suffered due to Russia’s Black Sea blockade. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="aXwwMN"&gt;What comes next?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="m8tvR3"&gt;In his announcement Wednesday, &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/africa/african-union-parties-ethiopia-conflict-have-agreed-cease-hostilities-2022-11-02/"&gt;Obasanjo promised&lt;/a&gt; “restoration of law and order, restoration of services, unhindered access to humanitarian supplies, protection of civilians,” a seeming acknowledgment of the dire consequences of the war for civilian populations in Tigray. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nq3a3W"&gt;United Nations head Antonio Guterres &lt;a href="https://news.un.org/en/story/2022/11/1130137"&gt;praised the announcement&lt;/a&gt; as “a critical first step” in ending the war, while noting the severe damage the war has done to the civilian population in Tigray. According to the World Health Organization, about 5.2 million people in Tigray need humanitarian assistance in Tigray, and 3.8 million need health care, &lt;a href="https://www.who.int/director-general/speeches/detail/who-director-general-s-opening-remarks-at-media-briefing---2-november-2022"&gt;with WHO chief Tedros Ghebreyesus calling the situation&lt;/a&gt; “the worst humanitarian crisis in the world.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vymAgu"&gt;Though the peace agreement promises unfettered access to humanitarian aid, Ghebreyesus expressed concerns in a media briefing Wednesday regarding the sheer scale of need.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OtTBqp"&gt;“Large numbers of displaced people are now arriving in, or moving towards, the regional capital Mekelle,” he said. “Most UN agencies and NGOs have now left towns in the region’s northeast because of security concerns. Some health partners have shut down because they cannot access the funds, fuel, and other supplies they need to serve the community,” raising concerns that the needed aid infrastructure might not become available as quickly as it’s needed. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="F34A2V"&gt;Also unclear is the role of Eritrea in the peace process; though Eritrean troops have been fighting alongside ENDF troops since nearly the beginning of the conflict and have been accused of serious crimes in the hostilities, neither they nor the regional forces like the &lt;a href="https://apnews.com/article/africa-only-on-ap-ethiopia-b280e6622d66b7e7f9b12cd1d0041ae8"&gt;Oromo Liberation Army&lt;/a&gt;, which allied with the TDF, were represented at the talks, &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/africa/african-union-parties-ethiopia-conflict-have-agreed-cease-hostilities-2022-11-02/"&gt;Reuters reported&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7Quhdr"&gt;“We still have questions on the agreement,” a Tigrayan man in Addis Ababa told Reuters. “We didn’t hear anything about Eritrea. I hope that it will be in the details.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ii7JrY"&gt;A &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/AbiyAhmedAli/status/1587869990006525953"&gt;statement Abiy posted to Twitter&lt;/a&gt; was similarly opaque; the prime minister thanked the African Union and negotiators for brokering the deal, but didn’t acknowledge the grave suffering the conflict had caused, nor did he acknowledge any of the underlying causes of the war. The only mention of fighting at all is tangential; the conclusion of Abiy’s statement thanks “the brave members of the Ethiopian National Defense Forces” and the Ethiopian people who “[with]stood a testing period.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="SwT34p"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Expression of Gratitude on the Conclusion of the Peace Talks &lt;a href="https://t.co/mB7Q0jLwsZ"&gt;pic.twitter.com/mB7Q0jLwsZ&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Abiy Ahmed Ali    (@AbiyAhmedAli) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/AbiyAhmedAli/status/1587869990006525953?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;November 2, 2022&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="pqImbk"&gt;With so few details to go on, it’s difficult to know exactly how peace can be achieved; it’s one thing to “silence the guns” and agree to disarmament, but it’s another entirely to peacefully disarm and change control of territory, let alone&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;adjudicate a truth and reconciliation process and come to a national understanding of what happened and why. Such a process, though painful, &lt;a href="https://theconversation.com/do-truth-and-reconciliation-commissions-heal-divided-nations-109925"&gt;can be critical for addressing the serious rifts in the fabric of a society&lt;/a&gt; and at least lay the groundwork for alternate forms of dispute resolution — outside of violence and armed conflict. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cXgGdN"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/world/2022/11/3/23438725/ethiopia-tigray-peace-deal-cessation-hostilities"/>
    <id>https://www.vox.com/world/2022/11/3/23438725/ethiopia-tigray-peace-deal-cessation-hostilities</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ellen Ioanes</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-11-02T18:40:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2022-11-02T18:40:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Netanyahu and the far right have triumphed. Here’s what it means for Israel.</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Benjamin Netanyahu speaking from a stage behind which is a large picture of his face and pointing finger." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/BtDRkXRhCRYvSwcrCyBE6NZo46M=/0x0:4000x3000/1310x983/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/71577217/1244329512.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Former Israeli Prime Minister and Likud party leader Benjamin Netanyahu speaks to supporters through inside a modified truck with a side bulletproof glass during a campaign event on October 29, 2022 in Bnei Brak. | Amir Levy/Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;The radical rightward shift of the Israeli body politic, explained by an expert.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p id="RtvWja"&gt;As votes are being tabulated in Israel’s fifth election since 2019, Benjamin Netanyahu’s coalition has taken the lead, meaning he is likely the country’s next leader. He’s been prime minister several times before, but there’s something different this time — and it’s not only that he’s under investigation for &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2019/11/21/20974465/benjamin-netanyahu-indicted-bribery-corruption"&gt;serious corruption charges&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ojdZ4o"&gt;Bibi Netanyahu is poised to lead a coalition that is more ideologically unified and further to the extreme right than previous coalitions he’s led. His Likud party has become more radical, and so have the parties it’s willing to build a government with. Some members of his likely parliamentary majority believe in Jewish supremacy and support racist policies that may ultimately change the way the state of Israel protects the rights of its citizens, whether Palestinians who hold citizenship or leftists, activists, and critics who seek equal rights for Palestinians in the occupied territory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZndbYi"&gt;The other big winner is Itamar Ben-Gvir of the Jewish Strength Party, who is a keystone of Netanyahu’s parliamentary coalition and a radical lawyer who espouses a &lt;a href="https://jewishcurrents.org/kahanisms-raucous-return"&gt;Kahanist worldview&lt;/a&gt; (Rabbi Meir Kahane was an American-born extremist ideologue who was an Israeli parliamentarian in the 1980s).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="H1gSoD"&gt;To understand the complexity of the Knesset — Israel’s parliamentary system — and its radical shift toward extremism, I spoke with Daniel Levy, a keen observer of Israeli politics and former negotiator for the Israeli government in its peace talks with the Palestine Liberation Organization. He’s currently the president of the &lt;a href="https://www.usmep.us/"&gt;US/Middle East Project&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2L53wK"&gt;Levy’s major takeaway: “It’s important to not fall into the trap of just seeing this as an aberration. It might be an ‘upgrade’ in extremism, but I think it’s correct to place this on a continuum of the absorption into Israeli politics of the most extreme.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fROsmZ"&gt;Netanyahu and President Joe Biden, it also might be noted, have a long history. One of my first jobs out of college, in 2009, was working as a researcher on Levy’s team at a think tank, as we thought through how then-President Barack Obama might approach Israel-Palestine. The rockiness of the Obama-Netanyahu relationship cannot be understated. Obama sought a partial freeze of Israeli settlement growth in the occupied West Bank, but when then-Vice President Biden arrived on a trip to Israel, Netanyahu &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2010/03/10/world/middleeast/10biden.html"&gt;snubbed him&lt;/a&gt; and US policy by announcing the expansion of new settlement building in East Jerusalem. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7EgKVs"&gt;I asked Levy about what another Netanyahu premiership would mean for America’s relationship with Israel, its closest Middle East partner. Though the prospects for an &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/world/2022/11/1/23434741/israel-election-palestine-under-siege-lions-den"&gt;independent and viable Palestinian state seem less likely than ever&lt;/a&gt;, Levy offered a small dose of optimism. Since Biden has already visited Israel as president, he may have the clout and the cred to offer hard truths to an Israel whose policies toward Palestinians in the occupied territories and its own citizens are increasingly beyond the pale and in contradiction of human rights, let alone American values. It remains unlikely, however, as Biden did no such thing publicly on his trip to Israel in July.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6pckTJ"&gt;Levy also discussed where the Israeli left has gone, the role of Palestinian voters and parties, and what all this might mean for the policies of the emerging Israeli government. Our conversation has been lightly edited for length and clarity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="0bwz8u"&gt;Jonathan Guyer&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p id="Gov3Sj"&gt;This is Netanyahu’s umpteenth time as prime minister. What’s going to be different this time?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="5PydG1"&gt;Daniel Levy  &lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p id="fABK0c"&gt;First, we just have to acknowledge that he’s returning to the premiership at a quite advanced stage of court cases proceeding, where he’s had to spend time in court [defending himself against corruption charges]. Those carry on. He’s not going to come in blundering on this, but it needs to be resolved. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UCatHj"&gt;He has a coalition that will be a partner in resolving it. I don’t know exactly what the resolution of it looks like. It could be as simple as — not him, but one of the coalition allies — proposing immunity for the prime minister. Quite literally, his return to the prime minister’s office is his get-out-of-jail card. Whether it’s through legislation, or whether certain personnel are changed, and the file [against him] is revisited — it could be done where the police minister insists that has to be resolved. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DyfHEm"&gt;Number two, he is likely to have a more ideologically coherent and homogenous government than has been the case for most of his time as prime minister. The nature of his coalition alliance looks different.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KaupZW"&gt;Netanyahu has tended to favor having bits of his coalition that he can dangle in front of some foreign audiences to say, “Look, you know, these guys are in my government with me.” Yair Lapid’s been there with him before, Benny Gantz has been there with him before, Labor have been there with him before. The line that “I want to do X” — X can be annexation [of occupied Palestinian territory], X can be other steps — “but I don’t have the coalition for it” no longer exists. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hVMxYn"&gt;What’s more, he has a powerful coalition ally to his right. They have two options. Either they manage to get something passed that hasn’t been passed before, whether it’s changing the status at the Temple Mount, which is very, very high risk; whether it’s laws that have not heretofore been applied in the occupied territories; whether it’s laws against Palestinian citizens of Israel that have not heretofore been applied; whether it’s rescinding of citizenship for people, which is something they’ve talked about, or things that are more directly hostile to Palestinians, perhaps annexation. That’s difficult because you can never sate the appetite, in terms of what should be annexed. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Bi7iuN"&gt;So they need one of two things, either something they can say, “We’ve delivered,” or that they can turn around and say, “Bibi stopped us.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nJh7V3"&gt;The other thing is that Netanyahu has a Likud party made much more in his own image, with very few heavyweight independent actors now, if any.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="kQWRqI"&gt;Jonathan Guyer&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p id="ebT8cy"&gt;What does this coalition look like? What is this more coherent government likely to look like?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="C6PpVs"&gt;Daniel Levy&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p id="yCwsmo"&gt;Israel has a very pure form of proportional representation where the entire country is one district of 120 seats. This is super relevant in this election. As long as you hit a 3.25 percent threshold of support, you get representation in parliament, which means the smallest number of seats a party can get in the 120-seat Knesset is four. Then you build from there. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3jbES9"&gt;This is unusually small in terms of the number of parties that constitute this coalition. It will be composed of four party “&lt;a href="https://m.knesset.gov.il/en/mk/pages/elections.aspx"&gt;lists&lt;/a&gt;.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PJuGf6"&gt;The Likud party is the traditional party of the right. As the center of gravity of Israeli politics has continually shifted rightward, so too has the Likud party. Likud have no qualms this time around. In the past it was, “Well can we really have been Ben Gvir in the government?” They’ve paved the way for that. There’s no question. No one today is saying, “Well, you know, this party is so extreme.” No one’s questioning it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aIHri6"&gt;You have two parties representing the ultra-Orthodox Haredi public, who are the other big winners, by the way. They’ve scored a phenomenal success and increased their numbers. That does tend to happen when your community is having six, seven, eight, nine children per family and everyone else isn’t. So that demography is now manifesting itself in votes. So you have the two ultra-Orthodox factions: one representing the Ashkenazi ultra-Orthodox community, the other representing the Sefardi ultra-Orthodox community. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BgRJjA"&gt;The fourth party is this amalgamation of hard-right, national-religious extremists, which is known as religious Zionism. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="AYQm9i"&gt;Jonathan Guyer&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p id="VNidqv"&gt;This fourth one&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;is the Jewish Strength Party. Tell me about that. Israel has been drifting to the right as long as I can remember. But this is pretty extreme, bigoted, Jewish supremacist, homophobic party that is normalizing the Kahanist worldview.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="wcyPJu"&gt;Daniel Levy&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p id="Fl3znM"&gt;This is now the third-largest party in the Israeli parliament. Just pause on that. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="970IEP"&gt;The third largest party in the Israeli parliament is a party that derives its ideological inspiration from the most extreme strand. Now, the leader of one element of this party is Ben Gvir, who everyone in Israel considers to be the big winner of the election. He’s a lawyer who tends to &lt;a href="https://www.france24.com/en/live-news/20221029-ben-gvir-israel-s-powerful-extreme-right-leader"&gt;represent&lt;/a&gt; Jewish murderers of Palestinians, &lt;a href="https://www.haaretz.com/israel-news/2016-01-04/ty-article/.premium/jewish-terrorisms-star-lawyer/0000017f-eda1-da6f-a77f-fdaff1f00000"&gt;who commit terror acts&lt;/a&gt;, not in uniform, as civilians. Just before [Israeli Prime Minister Yitzhak] Rabin’s assassination [at the hands of a Jewish extremist in 1995], he appeared in a famous TV clip with the emblem of Rabin’s car, and he said, “We got to his car, and we’ll get to him, too.” &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Protesters stand on and behind police barricades with signs and raised arms." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ic3uRmkDDydgJDHtIJkGMi1l-tg=/800x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/24163470/1242882982.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Eyad Tawil/Anadolu Agency via Getty Images&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;Dozens of Jewish settlers led by far-right member of Knesset Itamar Ben Gvir chanted anti-Arab slogans with Israeli flags and raided the village of Nabi Samuel in northwest Jerusalem, September 2.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="QkKrQk"&gt;He will appear in Palestinian neighborhoods where settlers are trying to move in, brandishing a pistol, using his parliamentary immunity. He has faced 50 criminal charges, of which he has been convicted of 12, including racist incitement and support of a terrorist organization. He’s also been accused of destroying evidence of Israeli attacks against Palestinians, in his role as their lawyer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iF1imz"&gt;He has, for instance, proposed that Palestinian citizens of Israel and Jewish leftists be stripped of their citizenship. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XtEwfS"&gt;He is a serial inciter. He’s the one who would lead the marches where there are chants of “Death to the Arabs.” Last night, at the gathering was “Death to the Terrorists” with a smirk. They’d replaced the Arabs with terrorists, but that’s how they define terrorists, so it’s pretty much the same there. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BprKh6"&gt;However, it’s important to not fall into the trap of just seeing this as an aberration. It might be an “upgrade” in extremism, but I think it’s correct to place this on a continuum of the absorption into Israeli politics of the most extreme. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WfvKri"&gt;It’s really important to understand that when Rabbi Meir Kahane came over from America and came into the Knesset, there was a cordon sanitaire built around him — people would literally leave the plenary, Likudnicks would stand up and leave the plenum when he spoke, and then he got banned for being racist. That was almost four decades ago. Since then, the reverse has happened. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0Q4EJJ"&gt;Since then, you have seen that serial absorption into the Israeli body politic, into Israeli government coalitions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vbi7E6"&gt;You have Avigdor Lieberman, who now people say, “Oh, he’s part of normal Israel.” No, Lieberman ran on a card of a loyalty test for citizenship, you had to be loyal to the Jewish state — as a Palestinian citizen of Israel, you had to say “I declare my loyalty not to Israel, but to the Jewish state of Israel.” He gets absorbed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7DuNeW"&gt;Naftali Bennett, who is an annexationist, and Ayelet Shaket, who came out with the most horrific racist statements, they get absorbed. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iIuKlx"&gt;Each time extremism gets absorbed, and each time what happens is the center of gravity shifts further to the right. And we move on. Then the next one gets absorbed, center of gravity shifts further to the right — reset, move on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HBppQe"&gt;The permissive environment is the key here. The enabling environment has led to this party [Jewish Strength] getting 14 seats, as things currently stand, and Ben Gvir coming forward. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bET6Nr"&gt;It’s crucial to look at what was the record, for instance, of the [outgoing] Lapid-Bennett government, and how they have also paved the way to this happening. Lapid does things that I think Bibi would have felt, “Hm, can I get away with this?” in criminalizing Palestinian civil society groups, including a famous human rights organization Al-Haq and others. They issued new regulations, more harsh regulations, on who can study, work, live, love in the West Bank (if your partner is in the West Bank or Gaza). They’ve returned to a policy of extrajudicial assassinations. This is with Labor, with the Zionist left in the government. They do all these things. And of course, what they’re doing is paving the way for more and more extremism. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="VQcIvO"&gt;Jonathan Guyer&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p id="LjXhxr"&gt;Where’s the Israeli left? Is there an Israeli left?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="41pFEZ"&gt;Daniel Levy&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p id="Bv6oRl"&gt;Let’s define our terms, because there is a left Arab party that will be the largest party on the left now, which is Hadash-Ta’al — the Communist Party and the party for renewal. This is a secular left Arab party. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1uNZej"&gt;The Zionist left, if the current results hold, will be reduced to four seats, which is the remnant of the Labor Party, which is on the threshold of extinction, once you’re at four seats. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Q3DnHo"&gt;Meretz seems to have dropped off altogether. They went into government with Bennett an avowed annexationist and hard-rightist a year ago. In that government, they did nothing to stand up for equality and human rights in practice. And unfortunately, they have earned their own certificate of extinction. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qFN2bh"&gt;We have to say another thing, because it would be remiss not to give an honorable mention to the other great enabler of this, which is the impunity accorded Israel day in, day out, year in, year out, no matter what it does, by way of violating international law, violating human rights, violating UN resolutions. Unfortunately, America takes pride of place in that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="P7XxlK"&gt;Jonathan Guyer&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p id="pRjHYe"&gt;Before we talk about that, what about the Palestinian citizens of Israel? How have they been voting in this election?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="xjN0Lh"&gt;Daniel Levy&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p id="WXADkV"&gt;This has been one of the most interesting stories in this election. You had in the last government something unprecedented, which is a party of Palestinian citizens of Israel that was a full coalition member. That party was an Islamist party, a conservative party, and they basically said — and I’m paraphrasing here — “We don’t really believe in the system, but we want to get the best for our community, and we know we’re not going to win on the Palestinian issue. And let’s set them aside.” They actually said that. They managed to deliver very little for their community. Their inclusion in the government became a rallying cry for the other side. It’s one of the reasons I think extremists did so well in this election. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PQL05Y"&gt;The other party that didn’t go in [to the government], the Joint List, split. A faction called Balad broke away and ran a fascinating, independent campaign. No one was paying any attention to Balad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vSAMz8"&gt;Everyone expected, by the way — because Palestinians rarely see the efficacy of their participation — another very low turnout. We don’t have the numbers yet, but it seems that turnout was quite high. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VAZIU8"&gt;The Palestinian citizens of Israel voted 13 seat’s worth of members of Knesset. Strange choice of language — why did I choose it? Because it seems that, according to the current statistics, both the party that was in the government, the United Arab List (Ra’am), and the remaining part of the Joint List will get five seats each, and this Balad party has three seats’ worth of votes. They won’t get in. There was an almost richly ironically comic moment during election night, when it seemed like the only way of preventing Netanyahu from forming a government was if Balad would cross the threshold. You had all these Israeli Jews who constantly pillory and spew bile against Balad praying for them to get into the Knesset. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZOYS8O"&gt;Why am I mentioning this? Balad ran &lt;em&gt;the&lt;/em&gt; campaign of this election in the Arab sector, and they ran on a platform of, “We will not lend a hand or recommend either of these potential leaders, because neither of them stands against the occupation, neither of them believes in equality, neither of them will change the structural discrimination faced by our community.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Do0z9l"&gt;They ran this really mobilizing campaign and did way better than anyone expected. Politics will become more interesting in that space in the coming period.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="TzXBw3"&gt;Jonathan Guyer&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p id="QOBSTp"&gt;Back to the question about the US. Netanyahu has this long rapport with Biden. What’s the outlook after this election for US-Israel relations?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="L6dzdD"&gt;Daniel Levy&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p id="4XMjcB"&gt;I do not think the Biden administration wants a fight. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LpgFYO"&gt;[That said,]&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;Netanyahu has a history of playing partisan politics in America. There is still a very bad taste in a lot of people’s mouths in terms of how Bibi treated Obama as a person and the Obama administration. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FCVxp5"&gt;Of course, you now have a cohort of Democrats who have made clear that they’re not comfortable with the exceptionalism with which Israel is treated in US politics. Throw into the mix how extreme this government is likely to be — no cover from any party that calls itself centrist. Not only are the coalition allies overtly racist, they also are a pretty hard group to sell if you’re in the business of pink-washing, given that they are extremely homophobic and their response to Gay Pride marches was to hold “Beast Pride” marches. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="czCuZj"&gt;But let’s see what happens in the American midterms. Let’s see how much partisan politics Bibi plays.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cQnuT0"&gt;Sadly, I do not anticipate a real change and a recognition on the American side. By failing permanently to hold Israel accountable, America has played a key role in the permanent denial of Palestinian rights and the creation of a reality which, for significant reasons, the blue-chip human rights organizations have defined as one of an apartheid reality — Human Rights Watch, Amnesty International, following in the wake of B’tselem and others inside Israel, and in the wake of Palestinian human rights groups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WFzMDS"&gt;But I would say this, and it’s important: Biden visited Israel in a trip that also took him elsewhere in the region. It was an obsequious visit, but what it did is it put a heckuva lot of credit in the bank. It is very hard to now depict Biden, as you know, “Joseph Hussein Obiden,” who’s an anti-Israel guy. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZvKXyw"&gt;He comes with a far greater ability to do so. Let’s see if that is used and if he puts that to the test if he needs to, and I’m pretty damn sure he needs to. We should have done it with the Lapid government.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/2022/11/2/23437462/israel-elections-benjamin-netanyahu-coalition-explained"/>
    <id>https://www.vox.com/2022/11/2/23437462/israel-elections-benjamin-netanyahu-coalition-explained</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jonathan Guyer</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-11-01T18:10:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2022-11-01T18:10:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Israel votes. Palestine is under siege. </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/aRrdCV-F6NcOMmhSbaxCcKf_xHY=/0x0:4403x3302/1310x983/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/71572544/1244400017.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Israeli soldiers stop a vehicle at a checkpoint south of the city of Nablus in the occupied West Bank on November 1, as Palestinian protesters demand the reopening of roads around the closed-off city, which has been under military lockdown since October 11. | Jaafar Ashtiyeh/AFP via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;The Lions’ Den, a new Palestinian resistance group, has emerged. Here’s what that says about the state of the Israel-Palestine conflict. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p id="zsxljJ"&gt;As &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2022/11/01/world/middleeast/israel-why-many-elections.html"&gt;Israel headed to the polls&lt;/a&gt; on Tuesday for its fifth election since 2019, Israeli forces have spent the last month putting Palestinian cities in the occupied West Bank under siege. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rsDfj8"&gt;Since early October, &lt;a href="https://www.972mag.com/nablus-siege-lions-den-settlers-army/"&gt;the city of Nablus&lt;/a&gt; has been choked off by Israeli settlers. Nablus and the refugee camp of &lt;a href="http://972mag.com/jenin-refugee-camp-armed-resistance/"&gt;Jenin&lt;/a&gt;, both in the West Bank, have also been the site of &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2022/04/16/world/middleeast/palestinians-israel-violence.html"&gt;Israeli security raids&lt;/a&gt;. The clampdown of Nablus comes in response to the emergence of the Lions’ Den, a Palestinian militant group that &lt;a href="https://www.aljazeera.com/news/2022/10/11/palestinian-fighters-kill-israeli-soldier-in-occupied-west-bank"&gt;shot dead an Israeli soldier&lt;/a&gt; at a checkpoint outside the city in early October. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UnxNF5"&gt;Lions’ Den has been using armed resistance against Israeli security forces in the occupied West Bank. Unlike Hamas or Islamic Jihad, they are not a religious or ideological faction, and they’re not affiliated with any party. Lions’ Den is specifically &lt;a href="https://carnegie-mec.org/diwan/88234"&gt;resisting the presence of Israeli security forces or settler violence&lt;/a&gt; to defend Palestinian cities. “The change here is that they have been using arms as a defensive mechanism when there are raids by Israelis,” Nur Arafeh, a researcher at the Carnegie Middle East Center, told me. “We’re talking about an oppressed people choosing to resist the occupation.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YtKwOe"&gt;Meanwhile, Israelis voted Tuesday for a new parliament after the collapse of a short-lived “change” government. Initial &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/middle-east/netanyahu-bids-comeback-tight-israeli-election-2022-10-31/"&gt;exit polls suggest a narrow lead&lt;/a&gt; by former Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu’s Likud Party. He’s a security-focused hawk who has only &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/us-israel-palestinians/netanyahu-renews-support-for-two-state-solution-with-palestinians-idUSKBN0O529Z20150520"&gt;reluctantly&lt;/a&gt; backed a Palestinian state and has been willing to downplay his commitment to two states to garner votes. Netanyahu has served longer as prime minister than any other Israeli, but what may be different this time is a much more unified coalition. While he has previously run the country with a bloc of many smaller parties, this right-wing coalition would have fewer parties and would be easier to hold together. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cg494I"&gt;This will be a more coherent government that can institute policy more effectively. And &lt;a href="https://www.npr.org/2022/10/31/1132246865/israel-election-netanyahu"&gt;extreme-right, pro-settler&lt;/a&gt; members of his coalition are likely to push for an even harsher crackdown on Palestinians in the occupied West Bank.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0cadA4"&gt;The violence has increased. More than 125 Palestinians have been killed in the occupied West Bank and East Jerusalem already this year. A United Nations official says that this is the most lethal year for Palestinians &lt;a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/news/world/israel-west-bank-palestinians-deadliest-year-united-nations-report-rcna54643"&gt;since 2005&lt;/a&gt;. And there is also &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2022/03/29/world/middleeast/israel-shooting-deaths.html"&gt;rising violence&lt;/a&gt; against Israelis, &lt;a href="https://news.un.org/en/story/2022/10/1129977"&gt;according to the UN&lt;/a&gt;, with two Israeli security personnel and 25 civilians killed so far this year. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5Q2PXm"&gt;Israel has responded with violent raids in Nablus and other West Bank cities, widespread &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2022/10/26/world/middleeast/israel-palestinians-insurgency-blockade-nablus-jenin.html"&gt;crackdowns&lt;/a&gt;, and what human rights groups allege to be the revival of &lt;a href="https://theintercept.com/2022/02/15/israel-assassination-west-bank-palestine/"&gt;targeted assassinations&lt;/a&gt; in the West Bank. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kZ1NYk"&gt;For two decades, Israel would conduct arrests and shootouts, or collaborate with the Palestinian Authority’s security services, but would not engage in extrajudicial killing in the West Bank. Then in February, &lt;a href="https://theintercept.com/2022/02/15/israel-assassination-west-bank-palestine/"&gt;an attack by Israeli security forces&lt;/a&gt; killed three Palestinian men who were part of a separate militant group; Israeli forces denied it was a targeted assassination at the time, but human rights groups said the tactics looked similar to that old policy. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PS7WMt"&gt;In late October, the Lions’ Den &lt;a href="https://www.aljazeera.com/news/2022/10/23/israel-kills-palestinian-top-member-of-armed-group-in-west-bank"&gt;cited two videos&lt;/a&gt; and said that Israel &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/middle-east/palestinian-militant-killed-by-israel-targeted-explosion-group-says-2022-10-23/"&gt;planted&lt;/a&gt; a bomb on the motorcycle of operative Tamer al-Kilani that killed him. (Israel and the Palestinian Authority would not comment on the attack to news organizations at the time, and the Israeli military declined to comment to Vox on whether it has revived targeted assassinations as a policy.) But both incidents show the risks Israel is willing to take. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="04yJGa"&gt;This comes as Lions’ Den, and what Al-Jazeera &lt;a href="https://www.aljazeera.com/news/2022/10/26/who-are-the-lions-den-armed-group-in-occupied-west-bank-explainer"&gt;describes&lt;/a&gt; as its “core 15-20 members,” is gaining popular support among Palestinians. Last month, Israelis put the Jerusalem refugee camp Shuafat under siege in response to its civil disobedience. Lions’ Den called for a &lt;a href="https://www.aljazeera.com/news/2022/10/12/palestinians-strike-against-israeli-siege-jerusalem-camp"&gt;one-day general strike&lt;/a&gt; in the West Bank in solidarity that showed the group’s organizing power.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Jib99j"&gt;This is a uniquely tense moment in the occupied West Bank. The lack of a Palestinian-Israeli peace process, the entrenchment of a 55-year-old military occupation of the West Bank and East Jerusalem, the blockade of Gaza, and the lack of political accountability within the Palestinian government offer few alternatives. This is not yet a widespread movement. But Lions’ Den or future groups like it could galvanize support within, and beyond, the occupied West Bank, which could ultimately lead to more political violence and changing political realities. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dgMDZk"&gt;Yara Asi, a global health researcher at the University of Central Florida, recently returned from visiting family in Nablus. She described in vivid detail the persistent hum of Israeli surveillance drones patrolling above the West Bank city and the intense security queues monitoring every vehicle and person entering and exiting it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="14LRBq"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Here in Nablus, the buzz of Israeli surveillance drones has been constant for days. Entrances to the city are still blocked. Just minutes away in Huwwara, settlers are vandalizing Palestinian property. In Jenin, a Palestinian doctor was killed this morning &amp;amp; 2 paramedics injured.&lt;/p&gt;— Yara Asi, PhD (@Yara_M_Asi) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Yara_M_Asi/status/1580889493036404736?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;October 14, 2022&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="WHL3sd"&gt;“You’re always kind of told the media narrative is ‘it’s a time of relative calm, it’s a time of relative peace.’ And then something happens, and you’ll hear ‘tensions escalated,’ ‘clashes escalated,’” Asi says. She says this framing that we so often read in the press misses the larger point. “For Palestinians, the situation is consistently intolerable.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="IN6I5r"&gt;What is driving this moment of increased violence?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="5Oc7Ik"&gt;This is the culmination of political forces of the last 30 years that have disenfranchised Palestinians. The &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/world/2019/4/15/18306224/palestinians-israel-khaled-elgindy-blind-spot"&gt;1993 Oslo Accords&lt;/a&gt;, signed on the White House lawn between Israel and the Palestine Liberation Organization (PLO), held out &lt;a href="https://merip.org/palestine-israel-primer/"&gt;the possibility&lt;/a&gt; of an independent, sovereign Palestinian state alongside Israel. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9xKDu9"&gt;But that possibility seems further away than ever. The Israeli occupation is so ingrained in the West Bank and East Jerusalem that &lt;a href="https://www.hrw.org/report/2021/04/27/threshold-crossed/israeli-authorities-and-crimes-apartheid-and-persecution"&gt;many&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/news/world/b-tselem-labels-israel-apartheid-regime-first-time-n1253863"&gt;human rights organizations&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.ohchr.org/en/press-releases/2022/03/israels-55-year-occupation-palestinian-territory-apartheid-un-human-rights"&gt;UN experts&lt;/a&gt; have started to&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;describe the situation as apartheid. There is a &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/middle-east/growing-israeli-west-bank-settlements-test-us-position-ahead-biden-visit-2022-07-11/"&gt;massive expansion of Israeli settlements&lt;/a&gt;, and Israeli settlers live under different laws and hold more rights than Palestinians living nearby. The devastating &lt;a href="https://www.aljazeera.com/news/2021/3/14/a-guide-to-the-gaza-strip"&gt;blockade of Gaza&lt;/a&gt; and Israel’s persistent &lt;a href="https://www.aljazeera.com/news/2022/8/7/timeline-israels-attacks-on-gaza-since-2005"&gt;bombing of civilian life and infrastructure&lt;/a&gt; there has made it untenable. And Palestinians who hold Israeli citizenship have far fewer opportunities than Israelis. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3zospd"&gt;Today, the Oslo generation is frustrated and has no means by which to channel it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZgjJA4"&gt;Even as the Palestinian Authority, the Biden administration, and the international community keep talking about a nonexistent two-state solution, the Israeli government often shows signs that it is not interested. Few Israeli politicians have &lt;a href="https://www.al-monitor.com/originals/2022/10/two-state-solution-shrinks-campaigning-wraps-israel"&gt;mentioned&lt;/a&gt; it on the campaign trail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xK7EWZ"&gt;Lions’ Den is emerging from a political vacuum among Palestinians. Mahmoud Abbas, the leader of the PLO, is 87 years old. He is also the president of the Palestinian Authority, which has &lt;a href="https://carnegieendowment.org/2022/09/27/procedural-guide-to-palestinian-succession-how-of-who-pub-88020"&gt;not held elections since 2009&lt;/a&gt; — he is serving the 17th year of a term that ended long ago. It’s part of why the PA has little legitimacy and has led some Palestinians to view it as a &lt;a href="https://www.972mag.com/palestinian-authority-nablus-occupation-subcontractor/"&gt;subcontractor of the Israeli occupation&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wF8Es2"&gt;“The representative body for Palestinians is the PLO, not the PA, and those elections have never taken place,” Akram Salhab, a Palestinian activist, told me. “The political process doesn’t exist, and no one even pretends it exists anymore.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="JTtIcY"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;As Israelis go vote today, remember the millions of people living under this regime that don’t choose the entity that rules them.The illusion of democracy masks a violent &amp;amp; segregationist system of apartheid.The answer isn’t just civil rights for all,but decolonisation &amp;amp; justice.&lt;/p&gt;— Salem Barahmeh (@Barahmeh) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Barahmeh/status/1587371239886110721?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;November 1, 2022&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="uLEL0D"&gt;The political system in Palestine has in practice excluded young people. “Now you have these new groups of young men in their early 20s who are so disenchanted with the Palestinian Authority, who are under intense oppression by the Israeli occupation, and who decided to take things into their own hands because there’s no political outlook,” says Arafeh. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="abRz5z"&gt;Another driver is the growing violence of Israeli settlers. Lions’ Den has mobilized in areas where &lt;a href="https://www.972mag.com/face-to-face-with-settler-violence-road-to-nablus/"&gt;settler violence&lt;/a&gt; is the highest and the &lt;a href="https://jewishcurrents.org/israeli-settler-violence-surges-as-palestinians-turn-to-armed-resistance"&gt;most extremist settlers live&lt;/a&gt;. Neither Palestinian authorities nor Israeli forces have done much to stem settler violence. In many cases, the settlers have the &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/23207299/israel-palestine-settlements-chart-two-state-biden-visit"&gt;backing of the Israeli state&lt;/a&gt;. Haaretz reported that, according to an Israeli security source, there were more than &lt;a href="https://www.haaretz.com/israel-news/2022-10-21/ty-article/.highlight/settlers-commit-100-crimes-against-west-bank-palestinians-in-last-10-days/00000183-f93d-d2c9-a3e7-f9ff40800000"&gt;100 incidents of settler violence in the West Bank&lt;/a&gt; over 10 days in October. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pzb6n0"&gt;A UN report from last month &lt;a href="https://www.ohchr.org/sites/default/files/documents/hrbodies/hrcouncil/coiopt/2022-10-19/Report-COI-OPT-14Sept2022-EN.pdf"&gt;noted&lt;/a&gt; that by “ignoring settler violence originating in outposts and not applying legal sanctions against settlers breaking the law,” Israel sends a “clear message” that such behavior is okay. A senior Biden diplomat condemned the UN report as &lt;a href="https://www.haaretz.com/us-news/2022-10-22/ty-article/.premium/u-s-decries-un-commission-of-inquirys-one-sided-report-on-israel-palestine/00000184-00b6-dd10-a7cd-d8f6a2990000"&gt;one-sided&lt;/a&gt;. Yet the US State Department has &lt;a href="https://www.jta.org/2021/12/17/united-states/in-reset-to-pre-trump-norm-state-department-terrorism-report-includes-extensive-reporting-on-west-bank-settler-violence"&gt;reported extensively on settler violence&lt;/a&gt;, including in its &lt;a href="https://www.state.gov/reports/country-reports-on-terrorism-2020/israel/"&gt;annual reporting on terrorism&lt;/a&gt;, where it noted that in 2020 the UN had “documented 771 incidents of settler violence that brought injury to 133 Palestinians and damaged 9,646 trees and 184 vehicles, mostly in the areas of Hebron, Jerusalem, Nablus, and Ramallah.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6JCQsW"&gt;That’s all set against the broader ongoing oppression. The United Nations &lt;a href="https://news.un.org/en/story/2022/10/1129977"&gt;notes&lt;/a&gt; that in the last three months, “In total, 32 Palestinians, including six children, were killed by Israeli security forces during demonstrations, clashes, search-and-arrest operations, attacks and alleged attacks against Israelis, and other incidents.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="obYgOL"&gt;It’s in this context that the Palestinians also feel abandoned by the United States, which is one of Israel’s closest international partners. President Joe Biden’s administration has changed some of its rhetoric from staunchly &lt;a href="https://prospect.org/world/dont-call-it-a-peace-plan-israel-palestine-trump/"&gt;anti-Palestinian Trump policies&lt;/a&gt;, but Biden has also quietly &lt;a href="https://www.aljazeera.com/news/2022/7/12/israel-palestine-us-policy-what-changed-under-biden-what-didnt"&gt;maintained much of Trump’s status quo&lt;/a&gt;, including keeping the US embassy in Jerusalem and focusing on deals between Israel and Arab states rather than Israeli-Palestinian talks. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="O7yYtV"&gt;There’s also a sense of abandonment from Arab governments. Countries like the United Arab Emirates, Morocco, and Bahrain have normalized relations with Israel, breaking their pledge to hold off doing so until there was an independent Palestinian state. Even Saudi Arabia, a longtime supporter of Palestinian rights, has become a &lt;a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/israeli-business-in-saudi-arabia-emerges-from-shadows-at-investment-conference-11666892535"&gt;comfortable place for Israeli business&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VGIhIV"&gt;This suggests to Israel that it can have it both ways: a clampdown on Palestinians and lucrative normalization deals with Arab states. In October, Israel announced a new law in which citizens of Arab countries it now has diplomatic ties to (Jordan, Egypt, Morocco, and Bahrain) visiting Israel are largely &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2022/oct/20/israel-imposes-strict-rules-on-travel-to-west-bank"&gt;restricted from visiting the West Bank&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WkdoWY"&gt;“Big picture: These accords have facilitated Israel’s capacity for repression in some ways, but also exacerbated the conditions where Palestinians are on the sidelines, that there isn’t really any kind of international pressure or movement to resolve some of the worsening political conditions,” Dana El Kurd, a political scientist at the University of Richmond, told me. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="ctr7Ir"&gt;Where does Palestinian resistance go from here?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="3yV3x5"&gt;The Lions’ Den’s actual membership is small, but it has proved galvanizing for many living under occupation. Though Israeli forces have put entire cities under siege, it’s not likely they’ll be able to eradicate the new group. Even as Israel targets its more prominent members, Lions’ Den is fragmented, dispersed, and essentially leaderless by design, according to the experts I interviewed. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7mxrQQ"&gt;A Palestinian Authority governor in Nablus &lt;a href="https://www.jpost.com/middle-east/article-719337"&gt;met&lt;/a&gt; last month with Lions’ Den members and urged them to give up their weapons in return for an amnesty arrangement, but they &lt;a href="https://www.middleeastmonitor.com/20221004-pa-is-negotiating-with-resistance-fighters-in-nablus-to-sell-their-weapons-israel-media/"&gt;rebuffed&lt;/a&gt; the offer. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0yphMj"&gt;Israel, meanwhile, has vowed to continue targeting the group, alleging it is “trying to carry out attacks.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qubSlf"&gt;“Our goal was and remains to strike hard and continuously at terrorists and those who dispatch them in Jenin, Nablus and wherever terrorism takes root; we will not relent even for a moment,” Prime Minister Yair Lapid &lt;a href="https://www.gov.il/en/departments/news/spoke-quality251022"&gt;said&lt;/a&gt; in October after Israeli forces conducted a raid that killed a member of Lions’ Den.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oBUbbn"&gt;Elderly neighbors that Asi, the global health scholar, spoke to in Nablus explained that this was the harshest blockade that they had experienced in 50 years. In the past, maybe Israelis would shut down the city for a couple of days, but now it has been a couple of weeks with checkpoints controlling all movement in and out of Nablus. People can’t leave to get urgent medical care, to visit family or to work, all while Israeli settlers are able to travel via an alternate network of roads that allows them to bypass Palestinian cities. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kzWrxE"&gt;“It has been really devastating to the city, especially just the uncertainty of it,” Asi says. “The tea kettle is screaming, it’s boiling, and occasionally that leads to violence.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="06qGeD"&gt;One question is whether this leads to unification among disparate Palestinians in disparate locales — across the occupied West Bank and in Gaza, in Jerusalem and in Israel’s 1948 borders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="S3zu9M"&gt;“Israel has imposed collective punishment,” says Arafeh, “so that Palestinians wouldn’t be able to go to universities or to schools. The Israeli assumption is that Palestinians would be fed up with this resistance because it’s not allowing them to go to schools, universities, or to ship products.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dqzRzl"&gt;But that assumption might not hold. &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2022/09/16/world/middleeast/ibrahim-al-nabulsi-west-bank-violence.html"&gt;Ibrahim al-Nabulsi&lt;/a&gt; was the &lt;a href="https://mondoweiss.net/2022/10/ibrahim-al-nabulsi-turns-19-in-the-grave/"&gt;18-year-old&lt;/a&gt; apparent co-founder of Lions’ Den. He was killed in a shootout with Israeli forces in September, and his final hideout has since become a shrine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="519LBR"&gt;“If you’re Palestinian today, and you look around you, what you see is an extreme, violent military occupation, which manifests in every tiny detail of your life,” says Salhab, the Jerusalem-based activist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Z0uCLo"&gt;And not all aspects of the suppression of Palestinians are so headline-grabbing. Salhab emphasizes the mundane aspects of occupation, the way he says that Israeli authorities count the number of toothbrushes there are in Palestinian homes in Jerusalem, where he lives, to confirm how many residents live in a given home. As he put it, “People don’t understand how that builds to a societal pressure that will lead to Palestinians only seeing one solution, which is resistance to Israel.”&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/world/2022/11/1/23434741/israel-election-palestine-under-siege-lions-den"/>
    <id>https://www.vox.com/world/2022/11/1/23434741/israel-election-palestine-under-siege-lions-den</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jonathan Guyer</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-11-01T17:13:05-04:00</published>
    <updated>2022-11-01T17:13:05-04:00</updated>
    <title>Bolsonaro finally speaks — but doesn’t concede the election</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/9K6z672jyK6fEFn1EAqRipCM2a0=/258x0:2277x1514/1310x983/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/71566826/1244408333.7.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;President of Brazil Jair Bolsonaro looks on during a press conference two days after being defeated by Lula da Silva in the presidential runoff at Alvorada Palace on November 1, 2022, in Brasilia, Brazil. | Andressa Anholete/Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Still, his administration confirmed that the presidential transition is beginning, as Lula prepares to take over on January 1.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p id="EHAcrm"&gt;Brazilian president Jaír Bolsonaro finally spoke to the country on Tuesday — almost 48 hours after losing the presidential runoff election to political rival and former president &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=rtAWPMLYMpQ&amp;amp;t=3s"&gt;Luiz Inácio Lula da Silva&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JeFrsx"&gt;Bolsonaro, in a very short speech, did not concede the election or recognize Lula’s victory. Instead, he said &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/g1/status/1587532186890260481?s=20&amp;amp;t=eHEMM4Rn_Z9pjI3TmyvHrg"&gt;he would follow the Constitution&lt;/a&gt;. He thanked his voters and addressed protests and pro-Bolsonaro trucker roadblocks that have sprung up across Brazil. He described demonstrations as the product of “indignation and feelings of injustice in the electoral process.” But, he said while &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/g1/status/1587530755483308032?s=20&amp;amp;t=eHEMM4Rn_Z9pjI3TmyvHrg"&gt;“peaceful protests are always welcome,”&lt;/a&gt; he condemned the blockades’ tactics, &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2022/11/01/world/americas/bolsonaro-protest-brazil-election.html"&gt;saying &lt;/a&gt;“our methods cannot be those of the left, like property invasion, destruction of goods, and restrictions on the right to come and go.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UVLBTJ"&gt;After Bolsonaro gave his statement, his chief of staff said that the president had authorized &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/DLBiller/status/1587533889492369408?s=20&amp;amp;t=zIl73EOcmlzYgFFcG2zzpw"&gt;the start of the presidential transition&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZhFqDk"&gt;Bolsonaro’s speech on Tuesday indicated that he is prepared to leave office, and to do so without a real effort to disrupt the transfer of power to Lula, despite months of agitating his supporters with unfounded claims of possible election fraud. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="B8tesp"&gt;Bolsonaro may not have had any choice. Even as the president stayed silent, Brazil’s political, &lt;a href="https://www1.folha.uol.com.br/poder/2022/10/pastores-bolsonaristas-abaixam-o-tom-e-pedem-oracao-por-lula.shtml?utm_source=twitter&amp;amp;utm_medium=social&amp;amp;utm_campaign=comptw"&gt;religious&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/americas/brazilian-court-orders-roadblocks-cleared-bolsonaro-silent-election-loss-2022-11-01/"&gt;business&lt;/a&gt; leaders — &lt;a href="https://br.noticias.yahoo.com/tarc%C3%ADsio-diz-que-buscar%C3%A1-alinhamento-011300849.html?guccounter=1&amp;amp;guce_referrer=aHR0cHM6Ly93d3cuZ29vZ2xlLmNvbS8&amp;amp;guce_referrer_sig=AQAAAFEX45UAbvlcRPTB4TsO7Rl4-k3t82TTY2GMQm8NofwJrPVPVs5L1Z4-BZ28Oybu7fDcCaah0toOfLuGmhazCPCN0nWp3YduRzzFG03ftSo4uQa6Ic7x5xlo7TT9yrscJhWyY0EurhoYfJyOycdCbcFssTBCYsvtaZ9UtL5Pm1Ai"&gt;including some of Bolsonaro’s closest allies&lt;/a&gt; — affirmed Lula’s electoral victory and promised to work with the new administration. The full-throated support for the legitimacy of Lula’s win blunted the potential threat of Bolsonaro’s silence — and the threat of the possibility the incumbent might not accept the electoral results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uHccqv"&gt;Still, Bolsonaro supporters &lt;a href="https://www.cbsnews.com/news/brazil-election-results-2022-protest-lula-bolsonaro-road-blocks/"&gt;have staged disruptive protests across the country&lt;/a&gt;, with truck drivers blocking roads and refusing to accept the results. Bolsonaro did not exactly tell these demonstrators to stand down, but he also didn’t rile them up by explicitly claiming fraud. How his supporters will react to Bolsonaro’s speech remains uncertain, &lt;a href="https://www.aljazeera.com/news/2022/11/1/brazils-supreme-court-orders-removal-of-pro-bolsonaro-roadblocks"&gt;though the Supreme Court has ordered the removal of these roadblocks.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="MFeUGy"&gt;Bolsonaro’s election denialism ends with a whimper — for now. But Bolsonarismo is likely here to stay.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="CcqEc1"&gt;Bolsonaro has long sowed doubts &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/2021/9/8/22620570/bolsonaro-brazil-september-7-democracy-supreme-court"&gt;about election integrity in Brazil&lt;/a&gt; and raised the specter of voter fraud throughout his presidency, &lt;a href="https://medium.com/dfrlab/electionwatch-claims-of-electronic-voting-fraud-circulate-in-brazil-b09cdbe6777a"&gt;including in the 2018 election he actually won&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jDDGbV"&gt;In the lead-up to the 2022 elections, &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/2021/9/8/22620570/bolsonaro-brazil-september-7-democracy-supreme-court"&gt;he amplified and intensified those claims&lt;/a&gt;, especially as Lula led in the polls and &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/2021/6/4/22456981/brazil-jair-bolsonaro-impeachment-protests-coronavirus"&gt;Bolsonaro faced political backlash for his handling of the Covid-19 pandemic and the economy&lt;/a&gt;. Specifically, Bolsonaro lied about the security of the country’s electronic voting system (which, in use since 2002, was created &lt;a href="https://www.ndi.org/e-voting-guide/examples/the-rationale-for-e-voting-in-brazil"&gt;to reduce fraud and corruption&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2020-11-12/dozens-of-fake-bolsonaros-are-running-in-brazilian-elections"&gt;to manage the logistics of a complex voting system&lt;/a&gt;). “I’ll hand over the presidential sash to whoever wins the election cleanly,” the far-right &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/americas/brazils-bolsonaro-says-he-wont-hand-over-presidency-if-there-is-vote-fraud-2021-07-01/"&gt;Bolsonaro said in July&lt;/a&gt; 2021. “Not with fraud.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Z7aAoC"&gt;But in the aftermath of the election, Bolsonaro was isolated as prominent allies and politicians affirmed they were preparing for Lula’s inauguration on January 1. And, though Bolsonaro did not say the words himself, his own administration confirmed the process is beginning. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ctZxGV"&gt;Exactly how smooth a transition that may be is still in question. Bolsonaro has previously &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/americas/bolsonaro-says-he-will-be-arrested-killed-or-declared-winner-2021-08-28/"&gt;said he saw three outcomes for the elections: death, prison, or victory&lt;/a&gt;. His reluctance to concede already chips away at the health of Brazil’s democracy, and he may still do more damage, depending on how he uses the platform of the presidency for the next two months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VoIXmA"&gt;“I don’t think he’ll be interested in working with Lula during the transition period,” said Andre Pagliarini, an assistant professor of history at Hampden-Sydney College and fellow at the Washington Brazil Office. “That said, one thing I think is fatal to any attempt by Bolsonaro to muck things up is that virtually everybody else has recognized his defeat.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XOWUAb"&gt;Still, how the post-election period has unfolded in Brazil is a reassuring sign for Brazil’s democratic institutions. Even if the future reactions of Bolsonaro and his most ardent supporters are still troublingly unpredictable, the country is withstanding &lt;a href="https://thehill.com/opinion/international/3707536-will-brazil-have-its-own-jan-6-crisis/"&gt;the type of January 6-style insurrection&lt;/a&gt; that some feared might happen in the wake of a Bolsonaro defeat. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Db3cMz"&gt;In retrospect, that’s looking like it was always going to be a bit harder to pull off. For one, Brazil gets its election results fast — the world’s fourth-largest democracy, with a population of over 210 million, including some &lt;a href="https://www.voanews.com/a/in-brazilian-amazon-a-1-000-mile-voyage-so-people-can-vote-/6773339.html"&gt;who vote from remote parts of the Amazon&lt;/a&gt;, tallies its results quickly (&lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/2018/5/8/17320758/primary-election-night-results-ohio-west-virginia-indiana-north-carolina"&gt;certainly faster than the world’s second-largest&lt;/a&gt; democracy). The country — and the world — knew Lula had won the election the day of. That, experts pointed out, has eliminated a lot of space for Bolsonaro to sow real doubts about the outcome. (There &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/americas/brazil-highway-police-blockades-fan-voter-suppression-fears-2022-10-30/"&gt;were reports of possible voter intimidation&lt;/a&gt; on the day of the election against Lula voters after police allegedly blocked roads in the northeast, Lula’s stronghold.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TxX4T1"&gt;And, again, the political establishment credited Lula with victory, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Zambelli2210/status/1586856212821336064?s=20&amp;amp;t=2AdEG2t-W-HU-e650GTm6Q"&gt;even as some of his opponents made clear they would oppose him and his agenda when in office&lt;/a&gt;. The military and police, always a potential wild card, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/malugaspar/status/1587112513388388352?s=20&amp;amp;t=kVX3FBJm7MH_V7ovy-VMag"&gt;also don’t appear to be agitating to disrupt the peaceful transfer of power&lt;/a&gt;. “At the institutional level, everyone is acting very responsibly, so Bolsonaro doesn’t have traction there,” said Paulo Barrozo, an associate law professor at Boston College.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IzPEDC"&gt;That institutional bulwark, if it holds, and Lula’s victory itself are signs that Brazil’s democracy withstood Bolsonaro’s very real threat. There are sighs of relief and celebration from many of &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/tomphillipsin/status/1587096539863842817?s=20&amp;amp;t=fZlyJwQchoPuNKXGflmO1Q"&gt;Lula’s supporters and Bolsonaro’s opponents&lt;/a&gt; who see Lula’s win as an opportunity to restore and shore up the country’s political system. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JVVxhC"&gt;But that victory is not a cure-all for the country’s sharp divisions.&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;Bolsonaro lost the election, but &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/americas/right-wing-wins-brazils-congress-show-staying-power-bolsonarismo-2022-10-03/"&gt;many of his political allies won&lt;/a&gt;, and Lula will rule over a divided government. Lula won with a coalition that &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/graphics/2022-brazil-election/"&gt;included his traditional base of support&lt;/a&gt;, but his coalition spanned from the far left to the center right, including many who voted against Bolsonaro, rather than for Lula. That may redefine the legacy of Lula, a leftist hero who went from prison back to the presidency and who, as experts said, may now govern more from the center, framing himself as a transitional leader.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5aat8C"&gt;“Starting January 1, 2023, I will govern for 215 million Brazilians and not only for those who voted for me,” Lula said in his victory speech. “There are not two Brazils. We are a single country, a single people, and a great nation.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rRdnCB"&gt;But the close results of the election — the tightest since Brazil’s transition to a democracy in 1984-1985 — make it clear that two Brazils likely do exist. Bolsonaro may have lost, but Bolsonarismo&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;and the right-wing movement he created have become a more deeply rooted political phenomenon, said Pagliarini. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="C1thqb"&gt;The election results, if anything, show the strength of the right wing in Brazil — which still had electoral success in 2022, and may see this election as a future to build on, one that transcends Bolsonaro himself. “If and when Bolsonaro leaves the stage, his presence will be felt for years to come, not just in elected office,” Pagliarini said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="g4AOvO"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update, November 1, 5 pm ET: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;This story has been updated to include information about Bolsonaro’s speech Tuesday.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/world/2022/10/31/23432788/brazil-election-lula-wins-bolsonaro-speech-no-concession"/>
    <id>https://www.vox.com/world/2022/10/31/23432788/brazil-election-lula-wins-bolsonaro-speech-no-concession</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jen Kirby</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-10-31T15:23:46-04:00</published>
    <updated>2022-10-31T15:23:46-04:00</updated>
    <title>The Pelosi attack is the culmination of longtime GOP hate-mongering </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Pelosi, in a pale blue suit, is seen in profile against a dark background, speaking into a microphone." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/vmMblYVu4pmcCJKLN_-TDQUEQD8=/0x0:5333x4000/1310x983/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/71559937/1239752783.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;House Speaker Nancy Pelosi (D-CA) speaks at a vigil at the Martin Luther King Jr. Memorial on April 4, 2022, in Washington, DC.&amp;nbsp; | Sarah Silbiger/Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;For years, Republicans made Nancy Pelosi out to be a public enemy. The attack on her home is the result.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p id="Ji46fn"&gt;Friday’s &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2022/10/28/23428394/pelosi-attack-husband-paul-nancy"&gt;brutal attack on House Speaker Nancy Pelosi’s husband&lt;/a&gt;, Paul Pelosi, at their San Francisco home was overtly political — and a logical endpoint to the decades of deeply personal villainization Speaker Pelosi has weathered from her political opponents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fCbKS9"&gt;It’s now clear the speaker was the target of Friday’s attack. The assailant broke into the home &lt;a href="https://www.cnn.com/politics/live-news/nancy-pelosi-husband-paul-attack"&gt;looking for her&lt;/a&gt;, reportedly shouting, “Where is Nancy?” — echoing what insurrectionists called out when they &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/2022/10/14/23404556/january-6-hearings"&gt;breached the US Capitol on January 6&lt;/a&gt;, 2021 — and saying that he would wait “until Nancy got home” as he confronted Paul Pelosi. The speaker’s husband suffered a skull fracture and serious injuries to his right arm and hands that required surgery after the assailant bludgeoned him with a hammer. The attacker faces &lt;a href="https://www.justice.gov/opa/pr/man-charged-assault-and-attempted-kidnapping-following-breaking-and-entering-pelosi-residence"&gt;federal assault and attempted kidnapping&lt;/a&gt; charges. (A spokesperson for the speaker said in a &lt;a href="https://www.speaker.gov/newsroom/102822-1"&gt;statement&lt;/a&gt; that Paul Pelosi is expected to make a full recovery.) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PAoiEM"&gt;Republicans have dismissed any connection between their rhetoric and the attack. Instead, they’ve blamed Democratic policies on crime and suggested that growing political violence may be the result of general anxiety around election legitimacy. Elon Musk, the billionaire Tesla CEO who was &lt;a href="https://thehill.com/policy/3709197-republicans-cheer-musks-twitter-takeover/"&gt;cheered by Republicans&lt;/a&gt; when he &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/recode/2022/10/27/23424938/elon-musk-own-twitter-deal-closes-what-will-change-superapp-layoffs-free-speech-parag-agrawal"&gt;bought Twitter&lt;/a&gt; last week, has &lt;a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2022/10/30/musk-deleted-tweet-pelosi/"&gt;advanced a right-wing anti-LGBTQ conspiracy theory&lt;/a&gt; around the circumstances of the attack. Though he deleted his post, it remained on Twitter long enough to be amplified and repeated by many on the right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bHvsjv"&gt;Even before Pelosi became speaker, Republicans in the party and those adjacent to it have demonized her regularly, featuring her in attack ads and lambasting her on Fox News. At least one of her colleagues in the House, Rep. Marjorie Taylor Greene (R-GA), has directly indicated support for violence against her. And members of right-wing militia groups such as the Oath Keepers and the Three Percenters have &lt;a href="https://www.newsweek.com/oath-keeper-who-allegedly-looked-pelosi-during-capitol-riot-sues-house-speaker-1665340"&gt;sought her assassination&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WqnyjO"&gt;Police haven’t gone into further detail about the attacker’s motivations, but his &lt;a href="https://www.cnn.com/politics/live-news/nancy-pelosi-husband-paul-attack#h_e00f25aa829a9c2c4d9fdead2cfd2eb8"&gt;Facebook posts&lt;/a&gt; on conspiracy theories around Covid-19 vaccines, the 2020 election, and the January 6 attack provide a window into his radicalization. &lt;a href="https://www.vice.com/en/article/m7gkey/david-depape-paul-pelosi-attack"&gt;Other blog posts under his name&lt;/a&gt; contained screeds against minorities, politicians, women, and global elites, and content related to &lt;a href="https://apnews.com/article/california-donald-trump-san-francisco-47c103cfe696df9faf0e57e1c7dd4f10"&gt;QAnon&lt;/a&gt; — the false pro-Trump conspiracy theory that a cabal of Satan-worshipping pedophiles, including prominent Democrats like Pelosi, are running the world. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wnUSLI"&gt;None of those posts reference Pelosi specifically, but all of them intersect with the ways she has been a familiar target of the right — and not just on the political fringes. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="BSkKjK"&gt;The long history of Republicans demonizing Nancy Pelosi&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="Iksuqp"&gt;Pelosi has been villainized by Republicans since she first ascended to Democratic leadership.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wIeGHG"&gt;In 2003, within days of her election as House minority leader, she quickly faced gendered attacks from Republicans who were, as Mark Z. Barabak wrote for the &lt;a href="https://www.latimes.com/world/la-me-pelosi012603-story.html"&gt;Los Angeles Times&lt;/a&gt; at the time, “eager to attack Pelosi as a loopy San Francisco liberal and exploit her city’s reputation as the odd-sock drawer of America. Within days, her face — garish and twisted — showed up in an attack ad slamming the Democrat in a Louisiana House race. (He won anyway.) She surfaced as Miss America, complete with tiara, in a spoof on Rush Limbaugh’s Web site.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WAaLMb"&gt;Such attacks continued throughout her tenure as minority leader, including during the 2006 election when Republicans &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2006/11/02/us/politics/02nancyads.html"&gt;ran a swath of attack ads&lt;/a&gt; featuring unflattering photos of Pelosi often looking angry, bug-eyed, or startled. And they increased in 2010, after she had become speaker. Republicans made her the face of their attacks on Democrats’ Affordable Care Act and launched a “Fire Pelosi” campaign, which involved a bus tour and images of Pelosi engulfed in flames. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rlXQs1"&gt;Under the Trump era and in the years since, the attacks have only escalated in tenor. Former President Donald Trump, who has &lt;a href="https://thehill.com/blogs/blog-briefing-room/3710580-trump-silent-on-paul-pelosi-attack/"&gt;remained silent&lt;/a&gt; about the attack on Paul Pelosi, &lt;a href="https://www.theatlantic.com/politics/archive/2019/05/trump-pelosi-video/590233/"&gt;shared doctored videos of the speaker&lt;/a&gt; designed to call into question her mental fitness, retweeted accusations that she was “&lt;a href="https://www.haaretz.com/world-news/2020-05-25/ty-article/trump-retweets-series-of-sexist-and-personal-attacks-against-top-female-democrats/0000017f-f45f-d487-abff-f7ff73320000"&gt;drinking booze on the job,&lt;/a&gt;” and had a litany of derogatory nicknames for her, among them “&lt;a href="https://www.apnews.com/ce08485cee37470db8983b8bd06c40a0"&gt;Crazy Nancy&lt;/a&gt;,” “&lt;a href="https://www.mediaite.com/tv/trump-gives-new-nickname-to-nancy-pelosi-ahead-of-d-day-ceremony-shes-a-disaster/"&gt;Nervous Nancy&lt;/a&gt;,” and “&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=s7DKYML2MRs"&gt;Nancy Antoinette&lt;/a&gt;.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Kk7rHA"&gt;Many of Trump’s followers echoed his rhetoric, online and in conservative media such as Fox News. In 2021, Fox News host Mark Levin &lt;a href="https://www.mediamatters.org/mark-levin/fox-news-host-mark-levin-launches-vulgar-sexist-attack-speaker-nancy-pelosi"&gt;called her&lt;/a&gt; “a nasty old bag — that’s what she is, a nasty, vicious, unhinged fool” who “has the hots for Trump” and “can’t get Trump out of her head.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="W89HgK"&gt;Rhetoric involving Pelosi has often taken violent turns as well. In 2018 and 2019, Taylor Greene repeatedly &lt;a href="https://www.cnn.com/2021/01/26/politics/marjorie-taylor-greene-democrats-violence/index.html"&gt;seemed to suggest support &lt;/a&gt;for Pelosi’s execution, among that of other prominent Democrats, liking a Facebook post that said “a bullet to the head” would be the most expedient way to end Pelosi’s speakership. Taylor Greene also claimed in a Facebook video that Pelosi was guilty of treason, noting “a crime punishable by death is what treason is.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="h4ynpO"&gt;One candidate in the GOP primary for Senate in Arizona this year aired a &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/jim_lamon/status/1491836062934704141?s=20&amp;amp;t=l6reae7YVDdyja7WyCH35w"&gt;Super Bowl ad&lt;/a&gt; that featured him dressed as sheriff shooting down an actor playing Pelosi, identified as “Crazy Face Pelosi,” after he says, “The good people of Arizona have had enough of you.” In the period since Labor Day, Republicans have reportedly since spent nearly &lt;a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/politics/2022/10/29/paul-pelosi-attack-republicans-target/"&gt;$40 million&lt;/a&gt; on ads that mention Pelosi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ObBTKi"&gt;Last week, National Republican Congressional Committee chair Tom Emmer (R-MN) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/tomemmer/status/1585300985999949824?s=20&amp;amp;t=OI7D_zMSciVoV87wGhAZqg"&gt;posted a video&lt;/a&gt; of himself firing a gun with the hashtag #FirePelosi. And even on Friday, just hours after the attack, Virginia’s Republican Gov. Glenn Youngkin linked the attack on Pelosi’s husband to the November elections, drawing condemnation from Democrats who &lt;a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/dc-md-va/2022/10/28/youngkin-pelosi-attack-comment-outrage/"&gt;called the comments insensitive&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VJVQZZ"&gt;“There’s no room for violence anywhere, but we’re going to send [Pelosi] back to be with him in California,” Youngkin said at a campaign rally in Stafford for GOP congressional candidate Yesli Vega.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="91I1ZS"&gt;Fox News anchors have also tried to tie the attack to Republicans’ message on crime in the midterms. “This can happen anywhere. Crime is random and that’s why it’s such a significant part of this election story,” Fox anchor Bill Hemmer &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/MattGertz/status/1585981763137904640?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw%7Ctwcamp%5Etweetembed%7Ctwterm%5E1585981763137904640%7Ctwgr%5E9a91ed128b9d4ca70a5a6a46b72479a7d53b69a6%7Ctwcon%5Es1_&amp;amp;ref_url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.vox.com%2Fpolicy-and-politics%2F2022%2F10%2F28%2F23428394%2Fpelosi-attack-husband-paul-nancy"&gt;said on air Friday&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;Republican National Committee chair Ronna McDaniel &lt;a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2022/10/30/rnc-chair-gop-rhetoric-pelosi-assault-00064129"&gt;echoed that talking point&lt;/a&gt; on Fox News Sunday, saying, “If this weren’t Paul Pelosi, this criminal would probably be out on the street tomorrow ... This is what Democrat policies are bringing.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HwQZZW"&gt;Other Republicans — including Florida Sen. Rick Scott, chair of the GOP’s Senate campaign arm — denounced the attack but argued against Republicans having a key role in fomenting the conspiracy theories of the attacker. Scott seemed to suggest the attack was rooted in a general lack of public confidence in elections.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zUZrVO"&gt;“I think what we have to do is, one, we have to condemn the violence, and then we have to do everything we can to get people — make sure people feel comfortable about these elections,” he said Sunday on &lt;a href="https://www.cnn.com/2022/10/30/politics/rick-scott-pelosi-election-conspiracies-cnntv"&gt;CNN&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dB3nTp"&gt;The vilification of Pelosi has taken an even uglier form in ultra-right-wing circles online. Conspiracy theories like the one shared by Musk abound, and even &lt;a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2022/10/31/conservatives-disinformation-paul-pelosi-assault-00064208"&gt;Republican members of Congress&lt;/a&gt; are spreading misinformation:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="Xk3Y2W"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-conversation="none"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Here is the deleted tweet from &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/CaptClayHiggins?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@CaptClayHiggins&lt;/a&gt;, a member of &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/HomelandGOP?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@HomelandGOP&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href="https://t.co/2GRdhwiOvz"&gt;pic.twitter.com/2GRdhwiOvz&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Steve Herman (@W7VOA) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/W7VOA/status/1586839478446047232?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;October 30, 2022&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="imNbpx"&gt;Some on Trump’s social media platform Truth Social have also been openly celebrating the attack, with the hashtag #PelosiCrimeFamily trending over the weekend. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bqLYkP"&gt;Arguably, the current venom aimed at Pelosi wouldn’t exist without the decades of Republican vitriol against her. President Joe Biden made that connection explicit at a fundraising dinner Friday in Philadelphia, saying that political violence is the natural outcome of the kind of rhetoric that Republicans have enabled. “What makes us think that it’s not going to corrode the political climate?” he asked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="vovv93"&gt;Misogyny, anti-elitism, and anti-democratic ideas feature heavily in attacks on Pelosi&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="0XdLwa"&gt;As the first female speaker of the House, and one serving at a time of increasing &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/22814025/democracy-trump-january-6-capitol-riot-election-violence"&gt;political polarization&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/22229753/violence-biden-inauguration-trump-right-wing-militia"&gt;anti-democratic violence&lt;/a&gt;, Pelosi has faced uniquely intense attacks that have channeled right-wing anger about her gender, wealth, and pro-democratic rhetoric. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fG3Mil"&gt;Even when she first ran for Congress, Republicans sought to portray her as unserious, a &lt;a href="https://opencommons.uconn.edu/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=1006&amp;amp;context=srhonors_theses"&gt;“liberal dilettante” and “airhead”&lt;/a&gt; — insults that ring of sexism. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vDXG9q"&gt;In 2007, conservative talk radio host Rush Limbaugh &lt;a href="https://www.politico.com/story/2009/03/gop-finds-pelosi-an-elusive-target-019630"&gt;mocked her election&lt;/a&gt; to the speakership: “This is a triumph of feminism and estrogen. ... And ladies, the long 200-year national nightmare without a woman at the top is now over.” In 2009, Democrats accused Republicans of advancing antiquated attitudes toward women when they ran an ad suggesting that Pelosi should be put “&lt;a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/BL-WB-13758"&gt;in her place&lt;/a&gt;” on the issue of Afghanistan. And in 2014, a Republican member suggested that she “might want to try” doing her research on the border, comments that her Democratic colleagues took to be &lt;a href="https://thehill.com/blogs/blog-briefing-room/news/214303-democratic-lawmaker-attack-on-pelosi-sexist/"&gt;patronizing and sexist&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="f6VmxL"&gt;Pelosi doesn’t talk about her gender much, but on occasion she has pointed out the disparate treatment and unique attacks she’s faced as a woman in congressional leadership. For instance, amid questions in 2014 about her age and whether she should hand the mantle to a successor, she &lt;a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/the-fix/wp/2014/11/13/nancy-pelosi-just-lectured-us-about-sexism-and-politics/"&gt;retorted&lt;/a&gt; that then-Senate Minority Leader Mitch McConnell, who is just two years younger than her, should be fielding similar questions. And in 2018, after being demonized by Trump and the GOP and still winning the speakership, she &lt;a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2018/11/07/republicans-declared-war-on-nancy-pelosi-and-she-won.html"&gt;told CNBC&lt;/a&gt;, “I don’t want women to think if you get attacked, you run away.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GW0Ywp"&gt;The attacks against Pelosi over the years have also focused on her wealth. On the right, there have long been harsh critiques of “elites,” often &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/videos/2019/4/3/18294392/tucker-carlson-pretends-hate-elites-populism-false-consciousness"&gt;stoked by Fox News&lt;/a&gt;; increasingly, as my &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/23373795/curtis-yarvin-neoreaction-redpill-moldbug"&gt;colleague Andrew Prokop recently explained&lt;/a&gt;, influential members of the right argue an “elite left ‘ruling class’ has captured and is ruining America, and that drastic measures are necessary to fight back against them.”   &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WPgp3U"&gt;For many — including one January 6 rioter and recruiter for &lt;a href="https://www.splcenter.org/fighting-hate/extremist-files/group/three-percenters"&gt;the Three Percenters&lt;/a&gt;, an anti-government movement — Pelosi is the face of that “&lt;a href="https://news.bloomberglaw.com/white-collar-and-criminal-law/jan-6-rioter-saw-pelosi-as-evil-incarnate-friend-tells-jury"&gt;evil&lt;/a&gt;” ruling class. And she’s often been attacked as one of that class’s most hypocritical members. She’s &lt;a href="https://www.businessinsider.com/nancy-pelosi-stock-trades-congress-investments-2022-7"&gt;faced criticism&lt;/a&gt; for initially dismissing the idea that members of Congress and their family members shouldn’t be allowed to trade stocks, despite the fact that they have access to confidential intelligence. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="D4Gd6A"&gt;It’s a critique that was particularly intense given she is one of the richest members of Congress, with an estimated net worth of &lt;a href="https://www.businessinsider.com/nancy-pelosi-stock-trades-congress-investments-2022-7"&gt;at least $46 million&lt;/a&gt;, and that fortune has grown in part thanks to lucrative trades by Paul Pelosi, a venture capitalist. She later endorsed &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2022/9/28/23377587/house-democrats-stock-trading-bill-blind-trust"&gt;legislation&lt;/a&gt; that would make it harder for members of Congress to use information they receive on the job for their own financial gain, but it currently seems unlikely to pass. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bb4gFb"&gt;Ironically, Trump attacked Pelosi for her wealth and elite status a number of times; perhaps most notably, he sought to use her wealth to portray her as out of touch in a &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/parscale/status/1252369647338319878?s=20&amp;amp;t=eO8qnFEC9l0dlfQkgjPe-w"&gt;2020 campaign ad&lt;/a&gt; ridiculing her expensive fridge filled with ice cream while Americans were going hungry during the Covid-related economic downturn. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0ycKFk"&gt;Both the sexist and anti-elite lines of attack have directly fed into the anti-democratic attacks that have recently overshadowed the rest. She was a top target during the January 6 insurrection, when the mob tore apart her office, calling out her name and searching for her. Rioters, emboldened by Trump’s lie that the 2020 election was stolen from him, left no doubt as to what they would have done to her: “We did our part. We were looking for Nancy to shoot her in the frickin’ brain. But we didn’t find her,” &lt;a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/news/us-news/jan-6-rioter-talked-shooting-nancy-pelosi-was-sentenced-60-days-rcna39484"&gt;one woman said in a selfie video&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rVJ3tN"&gt;After the insurrection was put down, Pelosi declared that “&lt;a href="https://www.speaker.gov/newsroom/1522-0"&gt;democracy won&lt;/a&gt;.” But it’s clear that pro-Trump extremists like the man who broke into her house Friday aren’t willing to give up the fight. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="S4UI4E"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update, October 31, 3:20 pm ET: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;This story, originally published on October 29, has been updated to reflect Republicans’ latest responses to the attack, the spread of conspiracy theories related to the incident, and the new charges the attacker faces. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2022/10/29/23430340/nancy-pelosi-paul-pelosi-political-violence-republican-attacks"/>
    <id>https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2022/10/29/23430340/nancy-pelosi-paul-pelosi-political-violence-republican-attacks</id>
    <author>
      <name>Nicole Narea</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-10-30T19:11:41-04:00</published>
    <updated>2022-10-30T19:11:41-04:00</updated>
    <title>What happens if Bolsonaro wins reelection in Brazil?</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Brazilian voters wave red, green, and blue flags supporting presidential candidate Luiz Inácio Lula da Silva in an upcoming runoff election." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/GezqAjyAj2lGuqrI5RbZxoDXx58=/140x0:7479x5504/1310x983/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/71558275/1244144367.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Supporters of Brazilian presidential candidate Luiz Inácio Lula da Silva wave the candidate’s flag on a street in Brasília, the Brazilian capital, on October 22. | Evaristo Sa/AFP via Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;The enormous stakes of this weekend’s presidential runoff in Brazil, explained.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p id="DaEtLA"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Editor’s note, October 30, 2022, 7:10 pm:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;This piece was published ahead of the 2022 Brazilian election. Sunday, former President Luiz Inácio Lula da Silva was declared the winner. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UmWsce"&gt;Brazilian voters on Sunday will decide which of two longtime political fixtures&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;they want to return to the country’s top elected office: incumbent&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;President Jair Bolsonaro, a far-right strongman, or former President Luiz Inácio Lula da Silva, a leftist who served for two terms from 2003 through 2010.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4rW9Rr"&gt;It will be the second round of voting this month, after neither candidate cleared &lt;a href="https://apnews.com/article/jair-bolsonaro-elections-caribbean-business-rio-de-janeiro-ab594d3793020ff830cd75636bc04281"&gt;50 percent of the vote&lt;/a&gt; in a closer-than-expected presidential contest on October 2. And it sets up a defining choice for Brazil that could have major repercussions for both the country — South America’s largest — and the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1fkrgM"&gt;At home, the fate of Brazil’s democracy may well hinge on the outcome. Bolsonaro, who was &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/2018/10/29/18037530/jair-bolsonaro-brazil-president-elections%5C"&gt;first elected president in 2018&lt;/a&gt;, has been nicknamed the “Trump of the Tropics,” and has mirrored Trump’s language about election fraud in the runup to Sunday’s race. (Trump also &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ishaantharoor/status/1567877011225337857?s=20&amp;amp;t=bR6lBl1v1D5D1TVarqeVqA"&gt;endorsed Bolsonaro&lt;/a&gt; for a second term last month.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jBHb3a"&gt;Leading up to the election campaign, Bolsonaro’s authoritarian tendencies — never exactly latent — have become even more pronounced: In 2021, &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/americas/bolsonaro-says-he-will-be-arrested-killed-or-declared-winner-2021-08-28/"&gt;he told evangelical leaders&lt;/a&gt; he foresaw “three alternatives for my future: being arrested, killed or victory,” and announced he would &lt;a href="https://apnews.com/article/lifestyle-donald-trump-courts-coronavirus-pandemic-brazil-e1545240e57ecb4d2257a7ba6bc689c9"&gt;no longer acknowledge rulings&lt;/a&gt; by one of Brazil’s Supreme Court justices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="2vwTn4"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;In unsurprising news, Trump endorses Bolsonaro, who many fear is priming Brazil for a full-blown constitutional crisis should he lose in upcoming elections (via &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/FinchelsteinF?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@FinchelsteinF&lt;/a&gt;) &lt;a href="https://t.co/ZHgUsJnBuS"&gt;pic.twitter.com/ZHgUsJnBuS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Ishaan Tharoor (@ishaantharoor) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ishaantharoor/status/1567877011225337857?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;September 8, 2022&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="oUOZpr"&gt;Such rhetoric has raised concerns that in the event of a Bolsonaro loss — which &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/americas/brazils-lula-leading-bolsonaro-by-7-points-ahead-runoff-poll-2022-10-24/"&gt;polling&lt;/a&gt; and the results of the first round of elections both indicate is the most likely outcome — he could make a desperate play to hold on to power, one that could lead to &lt;a href="https://www.wired.com/story/brazils-far-right-plots-its-own-january-6-insurrection/"&gt;mob violence along the lines of the January 6 riot&lt;/a&gt; in the United States. Even more concerning, one expert I spoke to suggested that a Bolsonaro win could be the start of a &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2018/9/13/17823488/hungary-democracy-authoritarianism-trump"&gt;Hungary-style downward spiral&lt;/a&gt; for Brazilian democracy writ large.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GS2BPK"&gt;Globally, meanwhile, the outcome of Sunday’s elections could be a critical juncture for efforts to combat climate change. Under Bolsonaro, &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/down-to-earth/2022/9/29/23373427/amazon-rainforest-brazil-jair-bolsonaro-lula-deforestation"&gt;deforestation of the Brazilian Amazon has accelerated&lt;/a&gt;; a victory by da Silva, frequently referred to as “Lula,” could see that trend reversed — good news for the world’s largest rainforest and a vital carbon sink.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aKKhI7"&gt;Pro-democracy forces are cautiously optimistic: Lula led Bolsonaro, 48.4 percent to 43.2 percent, in the first round of voting earlier this month, and &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/americas/brazils-lula-leading-bolsonaro-by-7-points-ahead-runoff-poll-2022-10-24/"&gt;polls&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/americas/brazils-lula-widen-lead-slightly-over-bolsonaro-sunday-election-poll-2022-10-24/"&gt;suggest&lt;/a&gt; that gap could widen with just two candidates in the race.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ehZ9Mo"&gt;It’s by no means a sure thing, however; Brazil’s 2022 presidential race is probably “the closest race that we have ever seen since Brazil became a democracy back in [the] 1980s,” Guilherme Casarões, a professor of political science at Brazil’s Fundação Getulio Vargas, told me this week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Ijg5hb"&gt;A &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2022/10/24/world/americas/brazil-election-polls-criminalization.html"&gt;polling miss&lt;/a&gt; — with Bolsonaro and his allies overperforming their projected support in the first round&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;— also adds some uncertainty to the final days of the race, though two experts I spoke with said that a similar degree of error isn’t as likely in the runoff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PGUV7B"&gt;Casarões told me he believes Lula will ultimately win. But, he said, “we’ve had close calls before, but not like that. So whoever wins is going to win by a very thin margin of roughly 2 to 3 percent.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="Ox5uEE"&gt;
&lt;div data-analytics-viewport="video" data-analytics-action="volume:view:article:middle" data-analytics-label="Brazil’s likely next president, explained|108932" data-volume-uuid="2356eb0bb" data-volume-id="108932" data-analytics-placement="article:middle" data-volume-placement="article" data-volume-autoplay="false" id="volume-placement-393" class="volume-video"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Vw7iRK"&gt;A Lula victory would conclude a dramatic comeback for the former president, who was &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2022/09/29/world/americas/lula-bolsonaro-brazil-election.html"&gt;sentenced to 22 years in prison&lt;/a&gt; on corruption charges and served more than a year and a half before his release in &lt;a href="https://apnews.com/article/b34fadbec5174bd080126b49ae6983d2"&gt;November 2019&lt;/a&gt; on due process grounds. Now 77, Lula remains a singular figure in Brazilian politics, one whom Barack Obama &lt;a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/the_americas/he-was-the-most-popular-politician-on-earth-now-brazils-lula-could-go-to-jail/2016/10/21/1569f2c0-897f-11e6-8cdc-4fbb1973b506_story.html"&gt;once described&lt;/a&gt; as “the most popular politician on Earth.” His election would also defy a &lt;a href="https://freedomhouse.org/report/freedom-world/2022/global-expansion-authoritarian-rule"&gt;global trend&lt;/a&gt; of democratic backsliding — and strengthen a regional one of &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2022/07/31/world/americas/latin-america-leftist-leaders.html"&gt;successful leftist candidates&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jLwcMn"&gt;If he’s elected to a third term, however, he’ll still have to contend with an incumbent apparently dead set on holding on to power, as well as a historically polarized country and a &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/americas/right-wing-wins-brazils-congress-show-staying-power-bolsonarismo-2022-10-03/"&gt;hostile Congress&lt;/a&gt; with a strong pro-Bolsonaro contingent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="IZUkD2"&gt;Bolsonaro’s threat to democracy is very real&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="enCk3N"&gt;Under Bolsonaro, Brazil has lurched rightward. But his reelection could push Brazil — the world’s fourth-largest democracy — in a far darker direction. A second Bolsonaro term could see Brazil sliding deeper into authoritarianism, experts say, in a way that has become all too familiar globally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="U7dLtl"&gt;&lt;a href="https://freedomhouse.org/report/freedom-world/2022/global-expansion-authoritarian-rule"&gt;According to Freedom House&lt;/a&gt;, which monitors the condition of global democracy, authoritarian regimes continue to press their advantage in places like Hungary, Russia, China, and beyond. In the same way that the US far right has taken to &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/2022/8/5/23292448/orban-cpac-dallas-2022-speech-trump"&gt;idolizing Hungarian President Viktor Orbán&lt;/a&gt;, Casarões said, Bolsonaro “really admires and looks up to Orbán and Putin.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KCedId"&gt;If reelected, “Bolsonaro will be able to control Congress, he will try to pack the courts, he will try to impeach some justices that have become his enemies,” Casarões told me. “The horizon really looks like Hungary.” Meanwhile, he said, “If Lula wins, this is going to energize the political system in such a way that it will probably be a little bit more resilient.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dVkUCC"&gt;But Bolsonaro isn’t poised to go quietly if he loses on Sunday. Already in the runup to the election, experts told me, political violence in Brazil has surged; according to one analysis, there have been &lt;a href="https://time.com/6218560/political-violence-brazil-election/"&gt;at least 45 politically motivated homicides&lt;/a&gt; this year in Brazil.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZBz4vb"&gt;That violence, Colin Snider, a history professor at the University of Texas at Tyler who specializes in Brazil, told me, “has been pretty much one-sided” and driven by Bolsonaro supporters; &lt;a href="https://time.com/6214070/bolsonaro-political-violence-brazil-election/"&gt;according to Guilherme Boulos&lt;/a&gt;, a left-wing Brazilian congressional candidate who won his election earlier this month, Bolsonaro’s “aggressive and irresponsible speeches have escalated a climate of violence and encouraged millions of supporters across Brazil to violently confront those who disagree with them.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RIZq3y"&gt;Bolsonaro has also spread &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2022/09/29/world/americas/election-bolsonaro-brazil-fraud.html"&gt;baseless and sweeping conspiracy theories&lt;/a&gt; about potential voter fraud in the lead-up to the election, and has made frequent proclamations about his political invincibility; in a speech on Brazil’s independence day last year, &lt;a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/world-latin-america-58479028"&gt;he told supporters&lt;/a&gt; that “only God will oust me.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WIxYGO"&gt;In doing so, according to Snider, Bolsonaro has “fanned the flames among these electorates on the possibility of any election in which he doesn’t win being an illegitimate one, which of course sounds a little familiar.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4iSLBg"&gt;It’s been enough to raise concerns in the US; last month, the US Senate &lt;a href="https://www.congress.gov/bill/117th-congress/senate-resolution/753"&gt;passed a nonbinding resolution&lt;/a&gt; “urging the Government of Brazil to ensure that the October 2022 elections are conducted in a free, fair, credible, transparent, and peaceful manner,” and calling for a review of assistance to Brazil should a government come to power “through undemocratic means, including a military coup.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Pg2Vqf"&gt;The Pentagon has also been in touch with its Brazilian counterparts ahead of the October elections, with US Defense Secretary Lloyd Austin &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/uss-austin-says-brazil-defense-minister-told-him-military-focused-transparent-2022-07-27/"&gt;remarking in July&lt;/a&gt; that it’s “especially vital for militaries to carry out their roles responsibly during elections.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YLpj41"&gt;Such concerns aren’t exactly unreasonable: Bolsonaro, a former army captain, has done plenty to align himself with Brazil’s military and bring members of the country’s armed forces &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/us-brazil-politics/brazils-bolsonaro-militarizes-his-inner-cabinet-idUSKBN2072S5"&gt;into government&lt;/a&gt;, and Brazil has previously been governed by a military dictatorship, which was in power from 1964 to 1985.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cm8KwG"&gt;In July last year, while announcing his reelection bid, Bolsonaro also &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/americas/brazils-bolsonaro-down-polls-set-officially-launch-candidacy-2022-07-24/"&gt;told supporters&lt;/a&gt;, “The army is on our side. It’s an army that doesn’t accept corruption, doesn’t accept fraud. This is an army that wants transparency.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6K65Aq"&gt;Despite those concerns, however, an outright coup might not be the biggest threat; as &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/2022/10/1/23380820/brazil-election-bolsonaro-lula-results"&gt;Vox’s Ellen Ioanes explained&lt;/a&gt; ahead of the first round of voting earlier this month, “the conditions for a military coup just aren’t there.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3TAzAl"&gt;Snider agrees, though he stipulates that you “can’t entirely” rule out the military getting involved. Instead, he said, “I think what seems most likely to me would be Bolsonaro not acknowledging the win and his supporters taking to the streets and possibly doing something rash.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="k1kI6L"&gt;If that occurs, Casarões points out, a &lt;a href="https://www.npr.org/2022/08/13/1116989125/brazil-firearm-ownership-booms-gun-laws-loosen-bolsonaro"&gt;dramatically higher rate of gun ownership&lt;/a&gt; among Bolsonaro’s most fervent supporters could make post-election violence worse, and the interval between Sunday’s election and inauguration on January 1, 2023, will pose a particular risk. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9Octww"&gt;“I want to believe that nothing more serious is going to happen,” he said, but “judging by what [Bolsonaro] has been saying and what he’s been doing, I think he’s capable of trying to push the political system to its limits.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="wmG1ly"&gt;The climate is at stake in Sunday’s runoff election&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="crbhr4"&gt;For as much as Brazilian democracy is riding on Sunday’s election and its immediate aftermath, what comes after inauguration could be just as consequential: the Brazilian Amazon is effectively on the ballot. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Of54Bz"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/down-to-earth/2022/9/29/23373427/amazon-rainforest-brazil-jair-bolsonaro-lula-deforestation"&gt;As Vox’s Benji Jones explained&lt;/a&gt; in September, “Earth’s future depends on the Amazon,” and that future looks radically different under the respective potential stewardships of Lula and Bolsonaro.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zolxEY"&gt;After nearly four years in office, Bolsonaro has already done a great deal of damage to the massive rainforest, reversing a decline in deforestation begun under Lula’s previous administration. As Jones writes, Bolsonaro as president has “&lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2019/07/28/world/americas/brazil-deforestation-amazon-bolsonaro.html"&gt;stripped enforcement measures&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/us-brazil-environment-ibama-exclusive/exclusive-as-fires-race-through-amazon-brazils-bolsonaro-weakens-environment-agency-idUSKCN1VI14I"&gt;cut spending&lt;/a&gt; for &lt;a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/d41586-022-03038-3"&gt;science&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/world-latin-america-56847958"&gt;environmental&lt;/a&gt; agencies, &lt;a href="https://news.mongabay.com/2020/05/brazil-sacks-officials-who-curbed-deforestation-on-amazon-indigenous-lands/"&gt;fired environmental experts&lt;/a&gt;, and pushed to weaken Indigenous land rights, among &lt;a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/d41586-022-03038-3"&gt;other activities&lt;/a&gt; largely in support of the agribusiness industry.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dqgLFn"&gt;For all that damage, though, another four years could be worse; as the &lt;a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/d41586-020-00508-4"&gt;journal &lt;em&gt;Nature&lt;/em&gt; has previously explained&lt;/a&gt;, the rainforest ecosystem is in danger of reaching a “tipping point” where portions spiral into an arid, savannah-like environment. Four more years of Bolsonaro could be the &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jul/14/amazon-rainforest-will-collapse-if-bolsonaro-remains-president"&gt;final push over the brink&lt;/a&gt;, further harming a crucial carbon sink, &lt;a href="https://www.eenews.net/articles/biden-talks-emissions-with-brazils-climate-denying-president/"&gt;accelerating climate change&lt;/a&gt; through continued deforestation, and laying waste to a unique ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Q193SY"&gt;Lula, by comparison, has signaled that, if elected, he will move to &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/americas/lula-no-need-fell-single-tree-boost-brazil-farm-output-2022-08-22/"&gt;reverse deforestation trends&lt;/a&gt; in the Brazilian Amazon and end illegal mining. “Brazil will look after the climate issue like never before,” he said in August. “We want to be responsible for maintaining the climate.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="X6odVH"&gt;According to Snider, protecting the Amazon is one area where Lula could be particularly influential. Though &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/americas/right-wing-wins-brazils-congress-show-staying-power-bolsonarismo-2022-10-03/"&gt;Brazil’s right-wing Congress&lt;/a&gt;, strengthened after elections earlier this month, will likely make governing a challenge for a potential Lula administration, there’s a great deal that can be done unilaterally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Uz3JSz"&gt;“The ability to roll back [deforestation] is reasonable, and this is one of the major issues at stake that’s not really voted on as much because there are instruments in place to crack down on illegal mining,” Snider said. “There are mechanisms to better monitor that, to better crack down and penalize those who do it, to those who are deforesting.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BOvbQA"&gt;Bolsonaro’s government has also &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/down-to-earth/2022/9/29/23373427/amazon-rainforest-brazil-jair-bolsonaro-lula-deforestation"&gt;declined to spend&lt;/a&gt; the environmental ministry’s full budget for enforcing deforestation protections in past years, another thing that could change under Lula. &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/down-to-earth/2022/9/29/23373427/amazon-rainforest-brazil-jair-bolsonaro-lula-deforestation"&gt;According to Christian Poirier&lt;/a&gt;, program director at the nonprofit advocacy group Amazon Watch, a Lula presidency could “undo the brutal regressions of the Bolsonaro regime.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TuByfB"&gt;First, though, Brazilian voters will go to the polls for the second time in a month, with an uncertain outcome on the other side. And whatever happens next, Snider told me, “Bolsonaro is very much a wild card.” &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/2022/10/29/23421761/brazil-runoff-election-lula-bolsonaro-democracy-climate"/>
    <id>https://www.vox.com/2022/10/29/23421761/brazil-runoff-election-lula-bolsonaro-democracy-climate</id>
    <author>
      <name>Cameron Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-10-30T19:10:54-04:00</published>
    <updated>2022-10-30T19:10:54-04:00</updated>
    <title>Who would make Bolsonaro president again?</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="A woman in a yellow shirt wears a sticker on her forehead supporting Bolsonaro in 2022. Her arms are raised and she is cheering. " src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/VwsyZnU_6Ud8LdyqP5CVMOmwzs0=/108x0:4353x3184/1310x983/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/71558399/1244278490.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;A supporter of incumbent PresidentJair Bolsonaro cheers during an October 27 rally in Sao Joao de Meriti, Brazil, ahead of a Sunday run-off election | Wagner Meier/Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;How the incumbent president might win — or lose — in Sunday’s runoff.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p id="Jtfe17"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Editor’s note, Sunday, October 30, 2022, 7:10 pm:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;This piece was published ahead of the 2022 Brazilian election. Sunday, former President Luiz Inácio Lula da Silva was declared the winner. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FR9hA3"&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/americas/brazils-lula-widens-lead-slightly-over-bolsonaro-two-polls-2022-10-26/"&gt;runoff presidential election in Brazil is close&lt;/a&gt;. Right now, the left-wing Workers’ Party (PT) candidate and former President Luiz Inácio Lula da Silva — better known as Lula — &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/americas/brazils-lula-keeps-lead-roughly-stable-race-against-bolsonaro-poll-2022-10-27/"&gt;remains ahead&lt;/a&gt; of the right-wing incumbent President Jaír Bolsonaro. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="P4yhlP"&gt;But if the polls are wrong — &lt;a href="https://www.aljazeera.com/news/2022/10/6/how-did-brazils-pollsters-underestimate-support-for-bolsonaro"&gt;and they were once already&lt;/a&gt; — the outcome of this election is still not a sure thing. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dLzuQf"&gt;One of the questions pollsters struggled with after the first round of voting earlier this month, where Bolsonaro outperformed predictions, is how to account for his supporters. Those voters may not say publicly that they are backing the current president, because they might distrust institutions and media, or may be reluctant to say they’re casting a ballot a leader who remains &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/22737145/bolsonaro-covid-19-crimes-against-humanity-icc"&gt;pretty controversial&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wtUBJs"&gt;It also raises bigger questions about who, exactly, is voting for Bolsonaro in 2022. In 2018, &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/world/2018/10/29/18025066/bolsonaro-brazil-elections-voters-q-a"&gt;some voters&lt;/a&gt; saw Bolsonaro as a break from the past, a change candidate who promised to crack down on crime and root out corruption. After a scandal-plagued and chaotic tenure of his own that included a mismanaged &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/2021/6/4/22456981/brazil-jair-bolsonaro-impeachment-protests-coronavirus"&gt;pandemic&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/03/31/world/americas/brazil-coronavirus-bolsonaro.html"&gt;economic fallout&lt;/a&gt;, that case &lt;a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/2021/07/05/brazil-bolsonaro-corruption-investigation/"&gt;may not resonate as powerfully this time around&lt;/a&gt;. Bolsonaro has always maintained a core base — evangelicals and the military among them — that is largely unshakeable. No matter what Bolsonaro does or says, they stick with him. But Bolsonaro secured &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2022/10/03/world/americas/brazil-elections-runoff-bolsonaro-lula.html"&gt;about 43 percent&lt;/a&gt; of the vote in the first round of the election, which means people outside of this base are supporting him, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="b4sWk0"&gt;Lula’s traditional base of support, in the northeast and among poor and working-class voters, has expanded to become a coalition of “everyone who are against Bolsonaro,” says Graziella Testa, a professor of public policy and government at the Fundação Getulio Vargas in Brasilía.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="m7fXtu"&gt;To get a better understanding of who backs Bolsonaro — and why — Vox spoke to Testa. She broke down some of the mechanics of voting in Brazil, and explained some of the cleavages among the voting population, a reflection of potentially more entrenched divisions within Brazil’s politics that are unlikely to disappear, no matter who wins this Sunday.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OzS4kS"&gt;This conversation has been edited and condensed for length and clarity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="5DFnsE"&gt;
&lt;h4 id="B4AtHQ"&gt;Jen Kirby&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p id="qJqxAg"&gt;Who are the Bolsonaro voters in 2022?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="n8gtVw"&gt;Graziella Testa&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p id="zl6xwB"&gt;We have some groups that are with Bolsonaro since 2018 that now are even more with Bolsonaro. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jvCBXJ"&gt;There are evangelicals. There are people that work for the army. The military is very corporatist. They received lots of good inputs from Bolsonaro — if you think &lt;a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/world-latin-america-50151327"&gt;about the reform in the pension systems&lt;/a&gt;, the militaries didn’t hurt as the regular worker in Brazil did. They have this ideological conservative agenda that is very like Bolsonaro but they also have this corporatist agenda of paycheck and pension, and Bolsonaro helped them a lot. Also, militarists in Brazil still have this ideology, as if they were this moderating power in Brazil. Most of them don’t recognize &lt;a href="https://oxfordre.com/latinamericanhistory/view/10.1093/acrefore/9780199366439.001.0001/acrefore-9780199366439-e-413"&gt;the dictatorship in Brazil&lt;/a&gt; [during which military-installed, repressive leaders ruled for 21 years starting in 1964]&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;was a dictatorship. Some of would still say it was a revolution to contain communists, and still defend that this was the best thing to do. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="eEx8qZ"&gt;We have also truck drivers and taxi drivers. Before the election of 2018, truck drivers were very unsatisfied with their conditions, and they &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2018/05/28/world/americas/brazil-truckers-strike-economy.html"&gt;made a big strike&lt;/a&gt;. In Brazil, all kinds of goods move through the country through trucks; it’s not diverse, the ways we transport our production throughout Brazil. &lt;a href="https://crisis24.garda.com/alerts/2018/05/brazil-truck-driver-strike-causing-major-disruptions-update-1"&gt;This was a very big impact in Brazil&lt;/a&gt;, to see those strikes; people would stay for hours in line to put some gasoline in the car. And Bolsonaro &lt;a href="https://www.miamiherald.com/news/nation-world/world/article267885212.html"&gt;recently directed new public policy specifically to truck drivers&lt;/a&gt;. Drivers will receive every month &lt;a href="https://www.bnamericas.com/en/analysis/brazil-secures-2022-diesel-supply"&gt;about $190&lt;/a&gt; (about 1,000 reais).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="RFyQtO"&gt;Jen Kirby&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p id="Ki4u3U"&gt;And Bolsonaro also provided support for taxi drivers, too?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="g6IkgG"&gt;Graziella Testa&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p id="7giGt3"&gt;Taxi drivers don’t get as much. [In] the most recent round of stimulus payments, there was an allowance for truck drivers; &lt;a href="https://www1.folha.uol.com.br/mercado/2022/10/governo-promete-beneficio-extra-de-ate-r-500-a-taxistas-em-meio-a-campanha-eleitoral.shtml"&gt;a gasoline allowance for taxi drivers&lt;/a&gt;; and &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/americas/brazils-economy-ministry-tries-limit-spending-fuel-related-subsidies-sources-say-2022-06-22/"&gt;a cooking gas allowance to families in poverty&lt;/a&gt;. In Brazil, we cook with gas, not with electric energy, so when gas got very expensive people started to make fires inside their houses and there were accidents because they needed to cook. Obviously [the allowance] had electoral purpose, but it was necessary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="M5jubp"&gt;Jen Kirby&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p id="otKoRY"&gt;Did it serve its electoral purpose?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="l6ybCq"&gt;Graziella Testa&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p id="US77Zt"&gt;Bolsonaro also increased &lt;a href="https://www.usnews.com/news/world/articles/2021-11-25/brazils-lower-house-approves-replacement-of-brazils-famed-bolsa-familia"&gt;Auxilio Brasil&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;,&lt;/em&gt; which used to be called Bolsa Familia, the program that started with Lula and pays money directly to people in misery or poor. It used to be &lt;a href="https://g1.globo.com/jornal-nacional/noticia/2021/10/20/governo-anuncia-auxilio-brasil-de-r-400-a-partir-de-novembro-mas-nao-revela-a-fonte-do-dinheiro.ghtml"&gt;about 400 reais a month&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.cnnbrasil.com.br/politica/bolsonaro-cita-auxilio-brasil-de-r-600-como-forma-de-atender-a-todos/"&gt;Bolsonaro increased it to $115 a month&lt;/a&gt;, so 600 reais. It was important, it was a big difference, but it didn’t impact the vote of the poor. That’s the very interesting part of this. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="b9aQQE"&gt;Bolsonaro really tried to gain the vote from poor people, but he couldn’t. Poor people go for Lula, most of them. The vote of Bolsonaro is wealthy, is evangelical, and from men, mostly. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yngFn6"&gt;Of course, those variables, they come together. Most poor people in Brazil are women, because they mostly lost their jobs during the pandemic; we have a very high [rate] of families with only one parent, and almost all the time this parent figure is a woman. If you look at the face of poverty and food insecurity, it is a face of a woman. And those women mostly vote for Lula as well. Bolsonaro didn’t get the vote he wanted with this stimulus payment specifically. He did get the support of truck drivers and taxi drivers, but they are not relevant in number of citizens when you think about a country the size of Brazil. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="LwrRej"&gt;Jen Kirby&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p id="Lhtzjg"&gt;Are there any other constituencies that support Bolsonaro?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="44W271"&gt;Graziella Testa&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p id="bmZoNo"&gt;Another important variable in the Bolsonaro vote is the size of the city. From 2018 to 2022, big cities tended to vote more for Lula, and Bolsonaro got stronger in small cities. Mostly because he has strong support from the agriculture sector, and those cities are mostly located in rural areas. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="srXf8U"&gt;You have this group of agro-related business that really supports Bolsonaro. The same way you have in the US, you have the country music, there’s a very specific culture; here in Brazil, we have this, too. We have our kind of country music and lots of those artists are with Bolsonaro because there is this support from the rural area and the agriculture sector. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="79NKQo"&gt;One thing that is interesting to note, as well, is that evangelicals are the biggest supporters of Bolsonaro, but &lt;a href="https://www.npr.org/2022/08/25/1117849457/evangelical-vote-brazil-bolsonaro-lula"&gt;Catholics are the biggest supporters of Lula&lt;/a&gt;. Until today, the difference of how educated the person is, and the region, have been important, but maybe it’s the first time you have this very strong variable that is religion in the Brazilian elections. Which is interesting because Bolsonaro has always declared that he is Catholic. His wife is the strongest tie that he has to the evangelical community. But Catholics in Brazil tend to feel that it’s not good to relate religion and state, which is the opposite of the evangelical leadership in Brazil.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="7xgIij"&gt;Jen Kirby&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p id="EYNzG2"&gt;So, as in 2018, Bolsonaro is likely to have strong support from evangelicals, the military, and the agriculture sector; Lula is likely to retain a large share of the support of working-class and poor people. Are there other notable trends?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="xiSDHw"&gt;Graziella Testa&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p id="3hp1u2"&gt;Another thing is that we also have important regional cleavages in Brazil. You have the midwest, that goes strongly for Bolsonaro. It’s the region that has most of the agriculture industry in Brazil. The south is also very supportive of Bolsonaro, and the north is also mostly Bolsonaro. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ydB5E3"&gt;Then you have the northeast, that votes — like more than 70 percent, almost 80 percent — for Lula. You have states in the northeast of Brazil, like Bahia and Pernambuco, which are big and important states. &lt;a href="https://www.americasquarterly.org/article/its-lula-forever-in-brazils-northeast/"&gt;The northeast is an important base for Lula&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aqFruN"&gt;Then you have the southeast, which is the biggest region of Brazil, with the most votes, and it’s the more divided. In this region, you have like 50-50. In the center of this dispute, you have São Paulo. São Paulo is the biggest state of Brazil, and you have a second round [of elections], as well, for governor. In the second round for governor, there is the PT candidate and the candidate that is &lt;a href="https://abcnews.go.com/International/wireStory/shooting-disrupts-bolsonaro-backed-candidates-campaign-stop-91629732"&gt;a former minister of Bolsonaro’s government&lt;/a&gt;. The same dispute that you have on the national level, &lt;a href="https://foreignpolicy.com/2022/08/31/brazil-elections-sao-paulo-haddad-lula-bolsonaro-workers-party/"&gt;you have on the state level&lt;/a&gt;. In the beginning, the candidate from PT was behind the candidate of Bolsonaro. But now &lt;a href="https://www1.folha.uol.com.br/poder/2022/10/ipec-tarcisio-tem-46-em-empate-tecnico-com-haddad-43-brancos-e-nulos-sao-7-e-indecisos-4.shtml"&gt;they are technically tied&lt;/a&gt;. This difference may impact the national-level campaign.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="uZygfn"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Brazil’s likely next president, explained","url":"https://www.vox.com/videos/2022/10/25/23422828/brazil-lula-bolsanaro-presidential-election"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;h4 id="gXAIwr"&gt;Jen Kirby&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p id="VdT7hb"&gt;In 2018, Bolsonaro attracted supporters frustrated with corruption and the state of the economy, but who maybe weren’t completely sold on the guy. What does that constituency look like in 2022?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="DP2bGK"&gt;Graziella Testa&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p id="nMibcC"&gt;You have this strong, important ideological movement in Brazil that are people who are anti-PT, who hate the Workers’ Party, which is Lula’s party, mostly because of a big corruption scandal, &lt;a href="https://www.economist.com/the-economist-explains/2021/03/09/what-did-lava-jato-brazils-anti-corruption-investigation-achieve"&gt;Lava Jato&lt;/a&gt; (Operation Car Wash). This Lava Jato scandal still hurts the PT, and you have lots of people who are not voting exactly for Bolsonaro, they’re voting because they want anything but PT. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ALHdEM"&gt;On the other hand, you also have people who vote for Lula who are not even leftists. If you ask them they will say, “I have always been ideologically right, but I cannot tolerate someone like Bolsonaro, with everything he did during the pandemic, and that’s why I’m not voting for him at all.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AadTBZ"&gt;I think the pandemic really hurt Bolsonaro, and the economic results were also a big factor. Lula [was cleared] &lt;a href="https://time.com/5946236/brazil-lula-returns/"&gt;of all the charges held against him&lt;/a&gt; [in the Lava Jato scandal] — they can open a new process now, but he’s not being prosecuted — and if there was lots of corruption during his government, it was a bigger scale involving all the coalition parties and even opposition parties. So even though this is the weakest point of Lula, for lots of people who went for Bolsonaro [in 2018], he is the option because of what Bolsonaro did with the economy and with public health during the pandemic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="R9evuB"&gt;You have a good dose of former rivals who are now supporting Lula. The vice president candidate [Geraldo Alckmin] with &lt;a href="https://en.mercopress.com/2022/09/29/lula-praises-vice-president-candidate-alckmin-the-best-thing-we-have-done"&gt;Lula used to be a rival of the PT,&lt;/a&gt; and now they compete and run together. Lula is very, very smart in a political way. He can construct those [relationships] with people who are very different from him. It’s government that has to accommodate lots of different perspectives. It’s not going to be easy to govern if Lula wins, but Lula represents everyone who is against Bolsonaro. That’s the situation now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="SZBiZS"&gt;Jen Kirby&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p id="CVM7F6"&gt;It sounds a little bit like the Democratic coalition that came together to defeat Trump in 2020. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="p43j5V"&gt;Graziella Testa&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p id="Ye8dUq"&gt;Exactly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="QZCX4w"&gt;Jen Kirby&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p id="FsdiWq"&gt;I guess we’re not quite there yet. But one of the things that has come up — similar to the US in 2020 — &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2022-09-23/lula-s-support-puts-first-round-win-back-in-play-datafolha-says#xj4y7vzkg"&gt;is the initial polling that showed Lula so far ahead&lt;/a&gt;, and potentially winning outright in the first round. In reality, the race is actually much, much closer. And so I will frame this in a very American way, which is: does this election just come down to turnout? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="ogfe1D"&gt;Graziella Testa&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p id="E614fe"&gt;Turnout is not such a big deal in Brazil as it is in the United States. But we have to point out this factor because as in the US, in Brazil, there’s a big difference between who is not going to vote and who is going to abstain from voting, and who does vote. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Y7txit"&gt;The poorer the person is, the less likely this person is going to vote. The truth is that we don’t have good measures for the likely voters as you do in the US. We are starting to have some companies who are trying to understand this in Brazil, but it’s not very calibrated yet. But because the people who are less likely to vote are the ones who mostly go for Lula, it may hurt Lula.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Mfn2sR"&gt;But you have another movement in Brazil. We all vote on the same day, on Sunday. There’s a holiday on Friday, and another holiday on Wednesday. People from the middle class and wealthy people, they can travel and they may be away from home on the day of voting. And this may hurt actually Bolsonaro, because this electorate is Bolsonaro’s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sMccRj"&gt;Another important point is that people over 70 years old are not obliged to vote anymore. But the [&lt;a href="https://www.in.gov.br/en/web/dou/-/portaria-dirben/inss-n-982-de-22-de-fevereiro-de-2022-383112438"&gt;National Institute of Social Security]&lt;/a&gt; established this year that old people could show proof of life with their vote — basically, to keep receiving your paychecks, you have to prove that you are alive. There are a few ways to do that, and now voting is included as one of those ways. So you have a percentage of old people voting, and guess who most vote for Bolsonaro? Older people.&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;[Note: &lt;a href="https://www.brasilwire.com/vote-for-bolsonaro-or-lose-your-pension/"&gt;Bolsonaro’s campaign was dinged for misleading ads&lt;/a&gt; that appeared to suggest that voting for Bolsonaro was the way to verify proof of life.] &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NbSZ7b"&gt;But this proof of life, they just needed to do that in the first round. They have the proof already. So in theory, they don’t have to go on the second round. Maybe they will vote because they were actually very ideological. But maybe they just wanted to do the proof of life, so they are not going to go on the second round.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="NZ0btP"&gt;Jen Kirby&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p id="hZBEKk"&gt;What are the legal requirements of voting in Brazil?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="Xf8Rzk"&gt;Graziella Testa&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p id="PfllcB"&gt;Up to 70 years old, we are obliged to vote. There are some people who can vote, but you don’t have to: [Those groups are] if you are more than 70 years, or if you are between 16 and 18 years. And if you cannot read and write, if you’re illiterate, voting is not mandatory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3LajkR"&gt;For everyone else, 18 to 70, voting is mandatory. There are some things that you cannot do if you don’t vote, like you can’t have a passport, you can’t be a public servant. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XEBSRc"&gt;Most of the punishments you have if you don’t vote, they are stronger for wealthier people. Who needs a passport? Someone who can go abroad. Who needs to be a public servant? Someone who can study very hard. That’s why we have the system, but it mostly obliges people who have a higher income.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="5lst5V"&gt;Jen Kirby&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p id="EaOIia"&gt;Interesting, the system is set up to encourage voting, but based on the demographics of who is voting, it favors, in some ways, Bolsonaro. For poorer people, voting may be mandatory, but they may not really feel the sting of the penalties, which also seems to make allowances for the fact that it’s probably harder for some of that group to get to the polls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="AGi5lb"&gt;Graziella Testa&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p id="YeYTiR"&gt;Another important point is that poor people, sometimes they need to use public transportation to go vote. If they have to pay for the public transportation, it’s going to be too much for them. So now you have a few cities in Brazil who have already declared that the buses and other kinds of public transportation are going to be free on the day of voting. &lt;a href="https://brazilian.report/liveblog/2022/10/24/sao-paulo-free-transportation-election-day/"&gt;One city that already did that is São Paulo, which is a very big and important city&lt;/a&gt;. You have other cities who also announced that, and there’s now a movement to make public transportation free so that poor people can also go and vote the way rich people can do with their cars. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="6DXhPs"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Brazil escaped a January 6-style insurrection — for now","url":"https://www.vox.com/2021/9/8/22620570/bolsonaro-brazil-september-7-democracy-supreme-court"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;h4 id="XTRdC0"&gt;Jen Kirby&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p id="g3Ofrm"&gt;Of course, the more people who vote, the better for democracy. But the big question now is whether, if Lula does win, which it seems he might — if a bit closer than initially thought — that Bolsonaro will accept the results. &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/2021/9/8/22620570/bolsonaro-brazil-september-7-democracy-supreme-court"&gt;We’ve already seen him sowing doubts about the integrity of the election&lt;/a&gt;. Given what we know about who is likely voting for Bolsonaro this time around, how do you think his supporters will interpret his loss — if he does lose?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="KlbYCt"&gt;Graziella Testa&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p id="667swL"&gt;Well, I think it’s very difficult to anticipate that. We cannot anticipate what the army or the military or his supporters are going to do. I have hope that we have strong enough institutions. But we are not calm. It’s not, “Okay, it’s another election.” But I think at the end, it’s going to be well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="L99xbG"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="D73uEQ"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1yZgPY"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dbDkIc"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/world/2022/10/29/23427452/bolsonaro-lula-voters-election-brazil-expert-questions"/>
    <id>https://www.vox.com/world/2022/10/29/23427452/bolsonaro-lula-voters-election-brazil-expert-questions</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jen Kirby</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2022-10-30T17:00:36-04:00</published>
    <updated>2022-10-30T17:00:36-04:00</updated>
    <title>What to expect after Russia’s latest escalatory nuclear rhetoric</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Russian President Putin At The Annual Valdai Discussion Club Event" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/OT_ADpknHc0lOL5GInMwBEmQLGw=/288x0:4896x3456/1310x983/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/71562971/1244268879.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Russian President Vladimir Putin spoke during the annual meeting of the Valdai International Discussion Club last week in Moscow. | Photo by Contributor/Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;It’s impossible to know what Putin is thinking, but there’s reason not to take it as an indication that Russia is presently planning a nuclear attack. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p id="Wz5OlL"&gt;Russian rhetoric about the use of nuclear weapons was rife with seemingly mixed signals last week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="feG6w8"&gt;First, Defense Minister Sergei Shoigu &lt;a href="https://apnews.com/article/russia-ukraine-kyiv-sergei-shoigu-climate-and-environment-government-politics-6ea801e22edee2d25c1e24d613f18e4a"&gt;called around to his Western counterparts&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;claiming that Ukraine is preparing to use a radioactive “dirty bomb” — which is not a nuclear weapon itself, but could conceivably be used in a false-flag attack as&lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/live/2022/10/26/world/russia-ukraine-war-news"&gt; a pretext for Russian nuclear escalation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;But then, President Vladimir Putin &lt;a href="https://apnews.com/article/putin-europe-government-and-politics-c541449bf88999c117b033d2de08d26d"&gt;on Thursday offered&lt;/a&gt; a&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;reassurance after tactical nuclear drills that his military is not planning a nuclear attack on Ukraine. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LZxV76"&gt;It’s impossible to know what Putin is actually thinking — and how far he’s willing to go to justify his continued attack on Ukraine — but there’s reason not to take this week’s messaging from Moscow as an indication that Russia is presently planning a nuclear attack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xj6cUo"&gt;Experts told Vox&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;the likelier explanation is that this is&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;an attempt to pressure the West into forcing Ukraine to come to a settlement for peace. The war is going poorly for Russian forces and Europe faces a long, cold winter without Russian energy supplies. It’s also an attempt to skew the information environment and sow confusion and disinformation — an integral part of Russian warfare doctrine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BkCyfS"&gt;Putin has warned throughout Russia’s seven-month-long war on Ukraine (and even before) that he would use nuclear weapons in response to perceived aggression from NATO and the West. But Wednesday’s drills aren’t necessarily a sign he is following through. The drills, in fact, occur every year; Russia’s defense apparatus &lt;a href="https://apnews.com/article/europe-government-and-politics-6c0a6d13abbdb7816694280c05618a94"&gt;followed protocol in alerting the US Department of Defense&lt;/a&gt; about them, and &lt;a href="https://fas.org/blogs/security/2022/10/steadfast-noon-exercise-and-nuclear-modernization/"&gt;NATO began conducting its own nuclear exercises October 17&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HzLaUa"&gt;The Russian narrative that Ukraine is planning to use a dirty bomb has obvious similarities to &lt;a href="https://www.armscontrol.org/act/2021-09/features/syria-russia-global-chemical-weapons-crisis#:~:text=Russia%20was%20no%20longer%20just,own%20dangerous%20chemical%20weapons%20agent."&gt;its false claims that rebel groups perpetrated&lt;/a&gt; chemical attacks in Syria. Although no Western officials or experts find the dirty bomb claims credible, Russian &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/europe/russian-uk-chiefs-staff-discuss-risk-dirty-bomb-ukraine-russian-agencies-2022-10-24/"&gt;Chief of the General Staff Valery Gerasimov &lt;/a&gt;reached out to his counterparts in both the US and the UK on Monday to express his alarm. Shoigu called defense officials in the US, UK, France, and Turkey Sunday with the same message, according to the &lt;a href="https://www.understandingwar.org/backgrounder/russian-offensive-campaign-assessment-october-24"&gt;Institute for the Study of War (ISW)&lt;/a&gt;. Monday’s call was &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/top-us-russian-generals-hold-first-talks-since-may-official-2022-10-24/"&gt;the first such between Gerasimov and Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff Gen. Mark Milley since May&lt;/a&gt;. That it happened at all is a positive development, &lt;strong&gt;i&lt;/strong&gt;ndicating that channels of communication between Russia and the West still exist, reducing the likelihood of escalation. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="236eQX"&gt;But it’s also an indicator that Moscow is likely trying to poison the information space and raise doubts in&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;the West about the risks of backing Ukraine in its continued fight for its sovereignty, Katherine Lawlor, a senior intelligence analyst at the ISW, told Vox. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HjsXSj"&gt;“The fact that we’re having these conversations means it’s working,” she said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="gaYHIG"&gt;Putin might be trying to escalate, but not the way we think&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="kHE0JU"&gt;As with a lot of nuclear posturing, the point of Russia’s latest moves about nuclear weapons might be less about actually using nukes than exerting pressure and sowing fear and confusion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YrTOrU"&gt;This week’s nuclear drills aren’t themselves unusual; they were planned, and Russian defense officials alerted the US Department of Defense that they were going on, as Moscow is required to do according to its obligations as a signatory to the New START treaty. “In this regard, Russia is complying with its arms control obligations and transparency commitments to make those notifications, and so that is something that we will continue to keep an eye on,” Pentagon spokesman &lt;a href="https://apnews.com/article/europe-government-and-politics-6c0a6d13abbdb7816694280c05618a94"&gt;Air Force Gen. Pat Ryder said Tuesday&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jKoPp0"&gt;The drills simulated a response to a potential attack and activated &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/no-indication-russian-nuclear-drills-are-cover-activity-pentagon-2022-10-27/"&gt;Russian air, land, and sea defenses&lt;/a&gt;, as Reuters reported Thursday. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uEKfjx"&gt;But it’s important to keep in mind that such drills aren’t just training maneuvers, they’re also shows of force, propaganda in a sense. That’s what kept experts watching this week’s drills, according to Natia Seskuria, an associate fellow at the Royal United Services Institute.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9U6uf3"&gt;“Now Russia is increasingly using the nuclear threats to blackmail the West,” she told Vox via email. “Last time, Russia held such drills just before launching the war in Ukraine,” so the drills could signal some form of escalation, but not necessarily in a nuclear sense.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Gv4S1A"&gt;“It seems like Putin is trying to put extra pressure on the West and overshadow the fact that Russian conventional forces are failing to achieve any success in Ukraine. The Kremlin is hoping that by scaling up the nuclear rhetoric the West would be willing to try to convince Ukraine to negotiate and accept concessions,” Seskuria said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aIgXoB"&gt;Putin had previously warned that &lt;a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/world-europe-31899680"&gt;he would be willing to use nuclear weapons during his 2014 invasion and annexation of Crimea&lt;/a&gt;, and Russian nuclear doctrine does allow for a first use in response to conventional warfare — not necessarily just as a response to a nuclear attack. According to an April report from the &lt;a href="https://sgp.fas.org/crs/nuke/R45861.pdf"&gt;Congressional Research Service,&lt;/a&gt; “This doctrine has led some U.S. analysts to conclude that Russia has adopted an ‘escalate to de-escalate’ strategy.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JYOPfz"&gt;While Ukraine is not a NATO member (it has applied for membership), it has the backing of the US and other NATO allies, which have &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/2022/6/4/23150697/how-ukraines-new-weapons-different-battlefield-russia-himars-nato"&gt;supplied weapons&lt;/a&gt; and training for Ukrainian troops &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/2022/9/11/23347304/ukraine-russian-war-kharkiv-liberation"&gt;to great effect&lt;/a&gt;. But throughout the war, &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/2022/3/13/22975269/ukraine-poland-us-mig-fighter-jets-military-aid-escalation"&gt;NATO members have been careful to avoid the possibility or appearance of direct conflict with Russia or a strike on Russian territory&lt;/a&gt; — a line that might be increasingly difficult to walk considering &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2022/10/05/world/europe/putin-annexation-ukraine-russia.html"&gt;Putin’s annexation of four southern Ukrainian regions earlier this month&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RRPv5w"&gt;The dirty bomb rhetoric, too, is an old tactic — &lt;a href="https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/The-Kremlins-Chemical-Weapons-Disinformation-Campaigns_edit.pdf"&gt;it’s similar to Russian claims in Syria that rebel groups&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.bellingcat.com/news/mena/2018/12/18/chemical-weapons-and-absurdity-the-disinformation-campaign-against-the-white-helmets/"&gt;the White Helmets rescue group&lt;/a&gt;, though those groups didn’t have access to chemical weapons and&lt;a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/world-middle-east-45586903"&gt; the Syrian regime, supported by Russia, was actually carrying out the attacks&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href="https://www.nonproliferation.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/op37-all-the-world-is-staged.pdf"&gt;Kremlin-aligned Twitter accounts&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://tass.com/world/1347015"&gt;media sources&lt;/a&gt; then repeatedly amplified Russia’s claims.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zAgbrP"&gt;Now, “Russian state media has been spreading the ‘dirty bomb’ accusations and planting fear,” Seskuria told Vox. “Russian media has a large share in mobilizing public opinion and is part of the Kremlin’s war propaganda machine, she said, adding that “the ‘dirty bomb’ accusations [are] directed at domestic consumption as well in conjunction with a high likelihood that Russia may be preparing a false-flag operation.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="smq6Qa"&gt;What is likely to happen next?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="TSQaVl"&gt;Putin &lt;a href="https://apnews.com/article/putin-europe-government-and-politics-c541449bf88999c117b033d2de08d26d"&gt;said Thursday&lt;/a&gt; that Russia would not strike Ukraine with nuclear weapons, despite his previous threatening rhetoric.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DM4o68"&gt;“There is no point in that, neither political, nor military,” Putin said, claiming statements about using all the means at his disposal to protect Russia were&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=CM8evVhzHPI"&gt; in response to Western threats&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8Q1U7J"&gt;Though Putin’s threats to use tactical nuclear weapons should be taken seriously, there are also a number of preparatory steps that would occur before such weapons were actually used on the battlefield. “I think we would see additional steps on the escalation ladder before we got [to a nuclear attack],” such as an above-ground weapons test, Lawlor said. The public would likely learn about such steps via leaks from US and allied intelligence, since there would be significant backchannel conversations. While US officials such as Secretary of State Antony Blinken have indicated that they are taking the possibility of escalation seriously, the evidence thus far doesn’t point to the imminent use of tactical nuclear weapons on the battlefield. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="M5tp9M"&gt;Furthermore, such weapons likely wouldn’t be very useful for Russia, given their fairly limited utility on the frontline and the inability of Russian conscripts to actually fight in that landscape. “Operationally, I don’t think Russian forces are prepared to do battle in a nuclear environment, because the ‘correct’ doctrinal use of nuclear weapons [...] would basically be using to punch holes in Ukrainian lines,” Lawlor said, enabling Russian mechanized units to push through and attack Ukrainian units from behind. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XNFaYE"&gt;Given what we have seen from Russian troops thus far, the likelihood them carrying out those plans successfully isn’t high. “Even the units that are trained for that are so degraded at this point,” Lawlor said. “And you’re going to tell me that a guy who was a policeman in Krasnodar Krai three weeks ago and got forcibly mobilized off the street is going to charge into an irradiated area? Absolutely not.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Whwpoa"&gt;It’s not really clear that using battlefield nuclear weapons would achieve Putin’s immediate goal of stopping Ukrainian forces from further advances and allow Russian forces to advance, given how devastating a NATO response to tactical nuclear weapons could be, Lawlor told Vox. “The operational effects of NATO retaliation in Ukraine — which would likely include targeting Russian forces, probably not troop concentrations but command posts, logistics, things like that — is going to devastate his operational capacity to continue advancing along the frontline.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5ks0zS"&gt;The nuclear weapons and false dirty bomb threats don’t make much sense from a logistical perspective, and they’re not new. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4cO8JC"&gt;That doesn’t mean the West can ignore Putin’s nuclear posturing — the risk is too great, as Ankit Panda, the Stanton Senior Fellow at the Carnegie Endowment for International Peace, told &lt;a href="https://www.newyorker.com/news/q-and-a/how-close-is-vladimir-putin-to-using-a-nuclear-bomb"&gt;The New Yorker’s&lt;/a&gt; Isaac Chotiner earlier this month. “Hopefully, this is somewhere we don’t have to actually go, but, of course, governments plan for all kinds of contingencies, and these conversations have been playing out behind closed doors in recent months, as the prospect of nuclear escalation has lingered,” he said. To that end, the US has also sent private communications to Moscow warning against the use of nuclear weapons, &lt;a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/national-security/2022/09/22/russia-nuclear-threat-us-options/"&gt;the Washington Post reported in September&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QfiJxj"&gt;But &lt;a href="https://www.usmcu.edu/Outreach/Marine-Corps-University-Press/MCU-Journal/JAMS-vol-12-no-1/Russian-Cyber-Information-Warfare/"&gt;sowing discord, confusion, and disinformation into the information space&lt;/a&gt; is a &lt;a href="https://jsis.washington.edu/news/a-russian-federation-information-warfare-primer/"&gt;known, tested part of Russian asymmetric warfare doctrine&lt;/a&gt;, which Ukraine and partner countries deliberately combatted leading up to and in the early days of the war. Don’t expect it to let up anytime soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nZDJmi"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/2022/10/30/23426491/russia-ukraine-dirty-bomb-nuclear"/>
    <id>https://www.vox.com/2022/10/30/23426491/russia-ukraine-dirty-bomb-nuclear</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ellen Ioanes</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
