<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<rdf:RDF
 xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
 xmlns="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/"
 xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
 xmlns:taxo="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/taxonomy/"
 xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
 xmlns:syn="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
 xmlns:admin="http://webns.net/mvcb/"
>

<channel rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/">
<title>cs.ET updates on arXiv.org</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">Computer Science -- Emerging Technologies (cs.ET) updates on the arXiv.org e-print archive</description>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:date>2022-11-03T20:30:00-05:00</dc:date>
<dc:publisher>help@arxiv.org</dc:publisher>
<dc:subject>Computer Science -- Emerging Technologies</dc:subject>
<syn:updateBase>1901-01-01T00:00+00:00</syn:updateBase>
<syn:updateFrequency>1</syn:updateFrequency>
<syn:updatePeriod>daily</syn:updatePeriod>
<items>
 <rdf:Seq>
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01476" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01659" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01811" />
 </rdf:Seq>
</items>
<image rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif" />
</channel>
<image rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif">
<title>arXiv.org</title>
<url>http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif</url>
<link>http://arxiv.org/</link>
</image>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01476">
<title>Integrated Photonic Tensor Processing Unit for a Matrix Multiply: a Review. (arXiv:2211.01476v1 [cs.ET])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01476</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The explosion of artificial intelligence and machine-learning algorithms,
connected to the exponential growth of the exchanged data, is driving a search
for novel application-specific hardware accelerators. Among the many, the
photonics field appears to be in the perfect spotlight for this global data
explosion, thanks to its almost infinite bandwidth capacity associated with
limited energy consumption. In this review, we will overview the major
advantages that photonics has over electronics for hardware accelerators,
followed by a comparison between the major architectures implemented on
Photonics Integrated Circuits (PIC) for both the linear and nonlinear parts of
Neural Networks. By the end, we will highlight the main driving forces for the
next generation of photonic accelerators, as well as the main limits that must
be overcome.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Peserico_N/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Nicola Peserico&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Shastri_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Bhavin J. Shastri&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Sorger_V/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Volker J. Sorger&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01659">
<title>An Open Platform for Simulating the Physical Layer of 6G Communication Systems with Multiple Intelligent Surfaces. (arXiv:2211.01659v1 [cs.ET])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01659</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Reconfigurable Intelligent Surfaces (RIS) constitute a promising technology
that could fulfill the extreme performance and capacity needs of the upcoming
6G wireless networks, by offering software-defined control over wireless
propagation phenomena. Despite the existence of many theoretical models
describing various aspects of RIS from the signal processing perspective (e.g.,
channel fading models), there is no open platform to simulate and study their
actual physical-layer behavior, especially in the multi-RIS case. In this
paper, we develop an open simulation platform, aimed at modeling the
physical-layer electromagnetic coupling and propagation between RIS pairs. We
present the platform by initially designing a basic unit cell, and then
proceeding to progressively model and simulate multiple and larger RISs. The
platform can be used for producing verifiable stochastic models for wireless
communication in multi-RIS deployments, such as vehicle-to-everything (V2X)
communications in autonomous vehicles and cybersecurity schemes, while its code
is freely available to the public.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Papadopoulos_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Alexandros Papadopoulos&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Lalas_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Antonios Lalas&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Votis_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Konstantinos Votis&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Tyrovolas_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Dimitrios Tyrovolas&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Karagiannidis_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;George K. Karagiannidis&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Ioannidis_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Sotiris Ioannidis&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Liaskos_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Christos Liaskos&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01811">
<title>Photonic Elementary Cellular Automata for Simulation of Complex Phenomena. (arXiv:2211.01811v1 [cs.ET])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01811</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Cellular automata are a class of computational models based on simple rules
and algorithms that can simulate a wide range of complex phenomena. However,
when using conventional computers, these &apos;simple&apos; rules are only encapsulated
at the level of software. This can be taken one step further by simplifying the
underlying physical hardware. Here, we propose and implement a simple photonic
hardware platform for simulating complex phenomena based on cellular automata.
Using this special-purpose computer, we experimentally demonstrate complex
phenomena including fractals, chaos, and solitons, which are typically
associated with much more complex physical systems. The flexibility and
programmability of our photonic computer presents new opportunities to simulate
and harness complexity for efficient, robust, and decentralized information
processing schemes using light.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Li_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Gordon H. Y. Li&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Leefmans_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Christian R. Leefmans&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Williams_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;James Williams&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Marandi_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Alireza Marandi&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
</rdf:RDF>