<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<rdf:RDF
 xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
 xmlns="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/"
 xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
 xmlns:taxo="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/taxonomy/"
 xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
 xmlns:syn="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
 xmlns:admin="http://webns.net/mvcb/"
>

<channel rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/">
<title>physics.acc-ph updates on arXiv.org</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">Physics -- Accelerator Physics (physics.acc-ph) updates on the arXiv.org e-print archive</description>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:date>2022-11-03T20:30:00-05:00</dc:date>
<dc:publisher>help@arxiv.org</dc:publisher>
<dc:subject>Physics -- Accelerator Physics</dc:subject>
<syn:updateBase>1901-01-01T00:00+00:00</syn:updateBase>
<syn:updateFrequency>1</syn:updateFrequency>
<syn:updatePeriod>daily</syn:updatePeriod>
<items>
 <rdf:Seq>
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01504" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01614" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01695" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01719" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.11871" />
 </rdf:Seq>
</items>
<image rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif" />
</channel>
<image rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif">
<title>arXiv.org</title>
<url>http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif</url>
<link>http://arxiv.org/</link>
</image>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01504">
<title>Redundant Field Survey Data of Cyclotron with Imperfect Median Plane. (arXiv:2211.01504v1 [physics.acc-ph])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01504</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;An accurate and detailed field map is important for cyclotron beam dynamics
studies. During the long history of cyclotron studies, many techniques have
been developed by cyclotron pioneers for the treatment of median plane field
map. In this paper, we take the TRIUMF 500 MeV cyclotron as an example to study
the asymmetric field resulting from the imperfect median plane symmetry. The
``Gordon approach&apos;&apos; and a highly accurate compact finite differentiation method
are used to investigate the historical field survey data. The redundancy in the
survey data is revealed by the expansion method, which also makes it possible
to correct the error in the measurement. Finally, both the azimuthal field
$B_\theta$ and the axial gradient of the axial field $dB_z/dz$ in the median
plane are corrected using the radial field map $B_r$. The influence of the
correction is examined by recalculating the equilibrium orbit properties of the
TRIUMF cyclotron. The result shows significantly increased vertical centering
errors of the closed orbits. Further simulation study suggests that these
centering errors can be reduced to below 1.5 cm by adjusting the trim coils&apos;
$B_r$ field within the output limits of our trim coils&apos; power supplies. The
error in the measurement field data may explain why the calculated trim coils&apos;
settings during the cyclotron commissioning in 1974 encountered difficulty.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Zhang_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Lige Zhang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Rao_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yi-Nong Rao&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01614">
<title>Lorentz Dissociation of Hydrogen Ions in a Cyclotron. (arXiv:2211.01614v1 [physics.acc-ph])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01614</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Stripping extraction of hydrogen molecular ions has gained interest in the
cyclotron industry due to its high extraction efficiency. However, the magnetic
field could result in undesired Lorentz dissociation of the hydrogen
anion/molecular ions during acceleration. Studies of dissociation under
electric fields comparable to that of a Lorentz-transformed magnetic field in a
typical cyclotron (a few MV/cm) are sparse. Hence, in order to fill in the
missing yet crucial information when designing a cyclotron, this work compiles
and summarizes the study of Lorentz dissociation of H$^-$, H$_2^+$ and H$_3^+$
for stripping extraction in a cyclotron.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Koay_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Hui Wen Koay&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01695">
<title>Characterization of Cs-free negative ion production in the ion source SPIDER by Cavity Ring-Down Spectroscopy. (arXiv:2211.01695v1 [physics.plasm-ph])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01695</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The Neutral beam Injectors of the ITER experiment will be based on negative
ion sources for the generation of beams composed by 1 MeV H/D particles. The
prototype of these sources is currently under testing in the SPIDER experiment,
part of the Neutral Beam Test Facility of Consorzio RFX, Padua. Among the
targets of the experimentation in SPIDER, it is of foremost importance to
maximize the beam current density extracted from the source acceleration
system. The SPIDER operating conditions can be optimized thanks to a Cavity
Ring-down Spectroscopy diagnostic, which is able to give line-integrated
measurements of negative ion density in proximity of the acceleration system
apertures. Regarding the diagnostic technique, this work presents a phenomenon
of drift in ring down time measurements, which develops in a time scale of few
hours. This issue may significantly affect negative ion density measurements
for plasma pulses of 1 h duration, as required by ITER. Causes and solutions
are discussed. Regarding the source performance, this paper presents how
negative ion density is influenced by the RF power used to sustain the plasma,
and by the magnetic filter field present in SPIDER to limit the amount of
co-extracted electrons. In this study, SPIDER was operated in hydrogen and
deuterium, in Cs-free conditions.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Barbisan_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;M. Barbisan&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Agnello_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;R. Agnello&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Casati_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;G. Casati&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Pasqualotto_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;R. Pasqualotto&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Sartori_E/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;E. Sartori&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Serianni_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;G. Serianni&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01719">
<title>Design and preliminary operation of a laser absorption diagnostic for the SPIDER RF source. (arXiv:2211.01719v1 [physics.plasm-ph])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01719</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The ITER Heating Neutral Beam (HNB) injector is required to deliver 16.7 MW
power into the plasma from a neutralised beam of H-/D- negative ions, produced
by an RF source and accelerated up to 1 MeV. To enhance the H-/D- production,
the surface of the acceleration system grid facing the source (the plasma grid)
will be coated with Cs because of its low work function. Cs will be routinely
evaporated in the source by means of specific ovens. Monitoring the evaporation
rate and the distribution of Cs inside the source is fundamental to get the
desired performances on the ITER HNB. In order to proper design the source of
the ITER HNB and to identify the best operation practices for it, the prototype
RF negative ion source SPIDER has been developed and built in the Neutral Beam
Test Facility at Consorzio RFX. A Laser Absorption Spectroscopy diagnostic will
be installed in SPIDER for a quantitative estimation of Cs density. By using a
wavelength tunable laser, the diagnostic will measure the absorption spectrum
of the 852 nm line along 4 lines of sight, parallel to the plasma grid surface
and close to it. From the absorption spectra the line-integrated density of Cs
at ground state will be measured. The design of this diagnostic for SPIDER is
presented, with details of the layout and of the key components. A preliminary
installation of the diagnostic on the test stand for Cs ovens is also
described, together with its first experimental results; the effect of ground
state depopulation on collected measurements is discussed and partially
corrected.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Barbisan_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;M. Barbisan&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Pasqualotto_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;R. Pasqualotto&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Rizzolo_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;A. Rizzolo&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.11871">
<title>Beam Background Simulation and Experiment at BEPCII. (arXiv:2210.11871v2 [physics.acc-ph] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.11871</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;A high-level beam background is a crucial challenge to future upgrades to the
BEPCII collider. We report here on the components of the background of a single
beam at the BEPCII collider and the BESIII detector in an experiment. Touschek
effect is the dominant source of the beam background in the inner detector,
where this is different from the previous understanding of beam background at
BEPCII. We also report a simulation of the beam background, and compare the
background count rates obtained by it with those measured in the experiment.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Shi_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;H. C . Shi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Wang_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;B. Wang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Shi_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;H. Y. Shi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Yu_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;C. H. Yu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Dong_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;M. Y. Dong&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Peng_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;H. P. Peng&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
</rdf:RDF>