<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<rdf:RDF
 xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
 xmlns="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/"
 xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
 xmlns:taxo="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/taxonomy/"
 xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
 xmlns:syn="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
 xmlns:admin="http://webns.net/mvcb/"
>

<channel rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/">
<title>math.MP updates on arXiv.org</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">Mathematics -- Mathematical Physics (math.MP) updates on the arXiv.org e-print archive</description>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:date>2022-11-03T20:30:00-05:00</dc:date>
<dc:publisher>help@arxiv.org</dc:publisher>
<dc:subject>Mathematics -- Mathematical Physics</dc:subject>
<syn:updateBase>1901-01-01T00:00+00:00</syn:updateBase>
<syn:updateFrequency>1</syn:updateFrequency>
<syn:updatePeriod>daily</syn:updatePeriod>
<items>
 <rdf:Seq>
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01397" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01403" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01439" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01525" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01541" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01632" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01637" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01683" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01685" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01702" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01710" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01755" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01769" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01838" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01899" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01940" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01947" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01974" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01989" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.02014" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.02034" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2105.06244" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2202.05652" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2202.08136" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2203.16012" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2205.05704" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2206.14277" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2207.10658" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2208.07436" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.07698" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.08342" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.17448" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.00769" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01148" />
 </rdf:Seq>
</items>
<image rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif" />
</channel>
<image rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif">
<title>arXiv.org</title>
<url>http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif</url>
<link>http://arxiv.org/</link>
</image>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01397">
<title>The fate of discrete torsion on resolved heterotic Z2xZ2 orbifolds using (0,2) GLSMs. (arXiv:2211.01397v1 [hep-th])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01397</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;This paper aims to shed light on what becomes of discrete torsion within
heterotic orbifolds when they are resolved to smooth geometries. Gauged Linear
Sigma Models (GLSMs) possessing (0,2) worldsheet supersymmetry are employed as
interpolations between them. This question is addressed for resolutions of the
non-compact C3/Z2xZ2 and the compact T6/Z2xZ2 orbifolds to keep track of local
and global aspects. The GLSMs associated with the non-compact orbifold with or
without torsion are to a large extent equivalent: only when expressed in the
same superfield basis, a field redefinition anomaly arises among them, which in
the orbifold limit reproduces the discrete torsion phases. Previously unknown,
novel resolution GLSMs for T6/Z2xZ2 are constructed. The GLSM associated with
the torsional compact orbifold suffers from mixed gauge anomalies, which need
to be cancelled by appropriate logarithmic superfield dependent FI-terms on the
worldsheet, signalling H-flux due to NS5-branes supported at the exceptional
cycles.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Faraggi_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;A.E. Faraggi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Nibbelink_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;S. Groot Nibbelink&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Heredia_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;M. Hurtado Heredia&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01403">
<title>Exact multi-instantons in topological string theory. (arXiv:2211.01403v1 [hep-th])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01403</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Topological string theory has multi-instanton sectors which lead to
non-perturbative effects in the string coupling constant and control the large
order behavior of the perturbative genus expansion. As proposed by Couso,
Edelstein, Schiappa and Vonk, these sectors can be described by a trans-series
extension of the BCOV holomorphic anomaly equations. In this paper we find
exact, closed form solutions for these multi-instanton trans-series in the case
of local Calabi-Yau manifolds. The resulting multi-instanton amplitudes turn
out to be very similar to the eigenvalue tunneling amplitudes of matrix models.
Their form suggests that the flat coordinates of the Calabi-Yau manifold are
naturally quantized in units of the string coupling constant, as postulated in
large $N$ dualities. Based on our results we obtain a general picture for the
resurgent structure of the topological string in the local case, which we
illustrate with explicit calculations in the case of local $\mathbb{P}^2$.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Gu_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jie Gu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Marino_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Marcos Marino&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01439">
<title>Inter model sets in $\mathbb R^d$ are model sets. (arXiv:2211.01439v1 [math-ph])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01439</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We show that any translate of a model set is a model set in some modified
cut-and-project scheme. Restricting to Euclidean direct space, we show that any
translate of an inter model set is a model set in some modified cut-and-project
scheme with second countable internal space. In both cases, the window in the
modified cut-and-project scheme inherits the topological and measure-theoretic
properties of the original window. Our results hold in fact for a class beyond
inter model sets, which we call almost model sets.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math-ph/1/au:+Richard_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Christoph Richard&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math-ph/1/au:+Strungaru_N/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Nicolae Strungaru&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01525">
<title>Exploring quantum geometry created by quantum matter. (arXiv:2211.01525v1 [gr-qc])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01525</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Exactly soluble models can serve as excellent tools to explore conceptual
issues in non-perturbative quantum gravity. In perturbative approaches, it is
only the two radiative modes of the linearized gravitational field that are
quantized. The goal of this investigation is to probe the `Coulombic&apos; aspects
of quantum geometry that are governed entirely by matter sources. Since there
are no gravitational waves in 3 dimensions, 3-d gravity coupled to matter
provides an ideal arena for this task. Our analysis will reveal novel aspects
of quantum gravity that bring out limitations of classical and semi-classical
theories in unforeseen regimes: non-linearities of general relativity can
magnify small quantum fluctuations in the matter sector to large effects in the
gravitational sector. Finally, this analysis leads to thought experiments that
bring out rather starkly why understanding of the nature of physical reality
depends sensitively on the theoretical lens with which it is probed. As
theories becomes richer, new scales emerge, triggering novel effects that could
not be imagined before. The model provides a concise realization of this
well-known chain.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Ashtekar_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Abhay Ashtekar&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01541">
<title>Factorization conditions for nonlinear second-order differential equations. (arXiv:2211.01541v1 [nlin.SI])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01541</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;For the case of nonlinear second-order differential equations with a constant
coefficient of the first derivative term and polynomial nonlinearities, the
factorization conditions of Rosu and Cornejo-Perez are approached in two ways:
(i) by commuting the subindices of the factorization functions in the two
factorization conditions and (ii) by leaving invariant only the first
factorization condition achieved by using monomials or polynomial sequences.
For the first case the factorization brackets commute and the generated
equations are only equations of Ermakov-Pinney type. The second modification is
non commuting, leading to nonlinear equations with different nonlinear force
terms, but the same first-order part as the initially factored equation. It is
illustrated for monomials with the examples of the generalized Fisher and
FitzHugh-Nagumo initial equations. A polynomial sequence example is also
included.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/nlin/1/au:+Gonzalez_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;G. Gonzalez&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/nlin/1/au:+Rosu_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;H.C. Rosu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/nlin/1/au:+Perez_Cornejo_O/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;O. Perez-Cornejo&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/nlin/1/au:+Mancas_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;S.C. Mancas&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01632">
<title>Equivalence of the modified Villain formulation and the dual Hamiltonian method in the duality of the XY-plaquette model. (arXiv:2211.01632v1 [hep-th])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01632</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Regarding the duality of the XY-placket model in the $2+1d$ system, We
compared and discussed the equivalence and difference between the modified
Villain formulation, recently introduced by Gorantla et al. to study duality in
exotic field theories such as fracton theory, and the standard Villain
formulation and dual Hamiltonian method we introduced in our previous paper to
study duality between Josephson junctions and quantum phase slips in the $1+1d$
system.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Yoneda_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Morishige Yoneda&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01637">
<title>Sharp Lower Bound for the Blow-up Rate of Solutions to the Magnetic Zakharov System without the Skin Effect. (arXiv:2211.01637v1 [math.AP])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01637</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;In this paper, we consider the Cauchy problem of the magnetic Zakharov system
in a cold plasma without the skin effect in two-dimensional space: \[
\begin{cases} &amp;amp; i E_{1t}+\Delta E_1-n E_1+\eta E_2
(E_1\overline{E_2}-\overline{E_1} E_2)=0, \\ &amp;amp; i E_{2t}+\Delta E_2-n E_2+\eta
E_1(\overline{E_1} E_2-E_1\overline{E_2})=0, \\ &amp;amp; n_t+\nabla \cdot
\textbf{v}=0, \\ &amp;amp; \textbf{v}_t+\nabla n+\nabla (|E_1|^2+|E_2|^2)=0, \\
\end{cases} \tag{G-Z} \] with initial data
$\left(E_{10}(x),E_{20}(x),n_{0}(x),\mathbf{v}_{0}(x)\right)$, where $\eta&amp;gt;0$
is a physical constant. Compared with the classical Zakharov system, (G-Z)
contains two extra cubic coupling terms
$E_2\left(E_1\overline{E_2}-\overline{E_1}E_2\right)$ and
$E_1\left(\overline{E_1}E_2-E_1\overline{E_2}\right)$ generated by the cold
magnetic field without the skin effect, which bring another difficulty. By
making a priori estimates corresponding for these extra terms, we obtain the
sharp lower bound of blow-up rate of the finite-time blow-up solutions to the
Cauchy problem of (G-Z) in the energy space
$\mathbb{H}_1=H^1(\mathbb{R}^2)\times H^1(\mathbb{R}^2)\times
L^2(\mathbb{R}^2)\times L^2(\mathbb{R}^2)$ provided the initial data satisfy
\begin{gather*} \frac{||Q||_{L^2(\mathbb{R}^2)}^2}{1+\eta}
&amp;lt;||E_{10}||_{L^2(\mathbb{R}^2)}^2+||E_{20}||_{L^2(\mathbb{R}^2)}^2
&amp;lt;\frac{||Q||_{L^2(\mathbb{R}^2)}^2}{\eta}, \end{gather*} where $Q$ is the
unique radially positive solution of the equation \begin{gather*} -\Delta
V+V=V^3. \end{gather*} Namely, there is a constant $c&amp;gt;0$ depending on the
initial data only such that for $t$ near $T$, \begin{gather*}
\left\|\left(E_1,E_2,n,\textbf{v}\right)\right\|_{H^1(\mathbb{R}^2)\times
H^1(\mathbb{R}^2)\times L^2(\mathbb{R}^2)\times
L^2(\mathbb{R}^2)}\geqslant\frac{c}{ T-t }, \end{gather*} where $T$ is the
blow-up time.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Gan_Z/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Zaihui Gan&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Wang_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yuchen Wang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Yu_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jialing Yu&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01683">
<title>Exact physical quantities of a competing spin chain in the thermodynamic limit. (arXiv:2211.01683v1 [math-ph])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01683</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We study the exact physical quantities of a competing spin chain which
contains many interesting and meaningful couplings including the nearest
neighbor, next nearest neighbor, chiral three spins, Dzyloshinsky-Moriya
interactions and unparallel boundary magnetic fields in the thermodynamic
limit. We obtain the density of zero roots, surface energies and elementary
excitations in different regimes of model parameters. Due to the competition of
various interactions, the surface energy and excited spectrum show many
different pictures from those of the Heisenberg spin chain.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math-ph/1/au:+Lu_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Pengcheng Lu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math-ph/1/au:+Qiao_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yi Qiao&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math-ph/1/au:+Cao_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Junpeng Cao&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math-ph/1/au:+Yang_W/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Wen-Li Yang&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01685">
<title>Generalized topological bulk-edge correspondence in continuous systems with non-Hermitian boundary conditions. (arXiv:2211.01685v1 [cond-mat.mes-hall])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01685</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The bulk-edge correspondence (BEC) is the hallmark of topological systems. In
continuous (non-lattice) Hermitian systems with unbounded wavevector it was
recently shown that the BEC is modified. How would it be further affected in
non-Hermitian systems, experiencing loss and/or gain? In this work we take the
first step in this direction, by studying a Hermitian continuous system with
non-Hermitian boundary conditions. We find in this case that edge modes emerge
at roots of the scattering matrix, as opposed to the Hermitian case, where they
emerge at poles (or, more accurately, coalescence of roots and poles). This
entails a nontrivial modification to the relative Levinson&apos;s theorem. We then
show that the topological structure remains the same as in the Hermitian case,
and the generalized BEC holds, provided one employs appropriate modified
contours in the wavevector plane, so that the scattering matrix phase winding
counts the edge modes correctly. We exemplify all this using a paradigmatic
model of waves in a shallow ocean or active systems in the presence of odd
viscosity, as well as 2D electron gas with Hall viscosity. We use this
opportunity to examine the case of large odd viscosity, where the scattering
matrix becomes $2\times2$, which has not been discussed in previous works on
the Hermitian generalized BEC.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Rapoport_O/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Orr Rapoport&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Goldstein_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Moshe Goldstein&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01702">
<title>On diagonal canonical solutions to the Einstein field equations and their meromorphic deformations. (arXiv:2211.01702v1 [math-ph])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01702</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Explicit solutions to the non-linear field equations of gravitational
theories can be obtained, using a Riemann-Hilbert approach, from an appropriate
factorization of certain matrix functions. Here we study a class of solutions,
which we call diagonal canonical solutions, obtained via Wiener-Hopf
factorization of diagonal matrices. This class comprises, among others, the
Schwarzschild, Kasner, Einstein-Rosen and gravitational pulse wave solutions.
We show that new solutions can be obtained by a method of meromorphic
deformation of the diagonal canonical solutions and that we can define Abelian
groups of such solutions indexed by a curve in the complex plane.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math-ph/1/au:+Camara_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;M. Cristina C&amp;#xe2;mara&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math-ph/1/au:+Cardoso_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Gabriel Lopes Cardoso&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01710">
<title>Bernoulli variables, classical exclusion processes and free probability. (arXiv:2211.01710v1 [math-ph])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01710</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We present a new description of the known large deviation function of the
classical symmetric simple exclusion process by exploiting its connection with
the quantum symmetric simple exclusion processes and using tools from free
probability. This may seem paradoxal as free probability usually deals with non
commutative probability while the simple exclusion process belongs to the realm
of classical probability. On the way, we give a new formula for the free energy
-- alias the logarithm of the Laplace transform of the probability distribution
-- of correlated Bernoulli variables in terms of the set of their cumulants
with non-coinciding indices. This latter result is obtained either by
developing a combinatorial approach for cumulants of products of random
variables or by borrowing techniques from Feynman graphs.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math-ph/1/au:+Bauer_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Michel Bauer&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math-ph/1/au:+Bernard_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Denis Bernard&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math-ph/1/au:+Biane_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Philippe Biane&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math-ph/1/au:+Hruza_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ludwig Hruza&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01755">
<title>KMS states and their classical limit. (arXiv:2211.01755v1 [math-ph])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01755</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;A continuous bundle of $C^*$-algebras provides a rigorous framework to study
the thermodynamic limit of quantum theories. If the bundle admits the
additional structure of a strict deformation quantization (in the sense of
Rieffel) one is allowed to study the classical limit of the quantum system,
i.e. a mathematical formalization in which convergence of algebraic quantum
states to probability measures on phase space (typically a Poisson or
symplectic manifold) is studied. In this manner we first prove the existence of
the classical limit of Gibbs states illustrated with a class of Schr\&quot;{o}dinger
operators in the regime where Planck&apos;s constant $\hbar$ appearing in front of
the Laplacian approaches zero. We additionally show that the ensuing limit
corresponds to the unique probability measure satisfying the so-called
classical or static KMS- condition. Subsequently, a similar study is conducted
for the free energy in the classical limit of mean-field quantum spin systems
in the regime of large particles, and the existence of the classical limit of
the relevant Gibbs states is discussed.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math-ph/1/au:+Ven_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Christiaan J.F. van de Ven&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01769">
<title>Beyond Schwarzschild-de Sitter spacetimes: I. A new exhaustive class of metrics inspired by Buchdahl for pure $R^2$ gravity in a compact form. (arXiv:2211.01769v1 [gr-qc])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01769</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Some sixty years ago Buchdahl pioneered a program in search of static
spherically symmetric vacua for pure $R^{2}$ gravity (Nuovo Cimento, Vol 23, No
1, pp 141-157 (1962); [https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/BF02733549]).
Surpassing several obstacles, his work culminated in a non-linear second-order
ordinary differential equation (ODE) which required being solved. However
Buchdahl deemed the ODE intractable and prematurely abandoned his pursuit for
an analytical solution. We have finally managed to break this six-decades-old
impasse and accomplish his goal. Reformulating the Buchdahl ODE, we obtain a
novel exhaustive class of metrics (which we shall call the Buchdahl-inspired
metrics hereafter) in a compact form. We are able to verify ex post, via direct
inspection, that the metric obtained herein satisfies the $R^{2}$ vacuo field
equation, hence establishing its validity. We show why the Buchdahl-inspired
metrics, which exhibit non-constant scalar curvature, defeat a
Lichnerowicz-type no-go theorem, previously proved for quadratic gravity, by
evading the overly strong restriction on the asymptotic falloff of the metric
at spatial infinity. Our novel solution thereby completes Buchdahl&apos;s
six-decades-old program. We also explore the mathematical properties of the
Buchdahl-inspired metrics in the limit of small k and in the region around the
coordinate origin.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Nguyen_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Hoang Ky Nguyen&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01838">
<title>On the Operator Origins of Classical and Quantum Wave Functions. (arXiv:2211.01838v1 [math-ph])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01838</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We investigate operator algebraic origins of the classical Koopman-von
Neumann wave function $\psi_{KvN}$ as well as the quantum mechanical one
$\psi_{QM}$. We introduce a formalism of Operator Mechanics (OM) based on a
noncommutative Poisson, symplectic and noncommutative differential structures.
OM serves as a pre-quantum algebra from which algebraic structures relevant to
real-world classical and quantum mechanics follow. In particular, $\psi_{KvN}$
and $\psi_{QM}$ are both consequences of this pre-quantum formalism. No a
priori Hilbert space is needed. OM admits an algebraic notion of operator
expectation values without invoking states. A phase space bundle ${\cal E}$
follows from this. $\psi_{KvN}$ and $\psi_{QM}$ are shown to be sections in
${\cal E}$. The difference between $\psi_{KvN}$ and $\psi_{QM}$ originates from
a quantization map interpreted as &quot;twisting&quot; of sections over ${\cal E}$. We
also show that the Schr\&quot;{o}dinger equation is obtained from the Koopman-von
Neumann equation. What this suggests is that neither the Schr\&quot;{o}dinger
equation nor the quantum wave function are fundamental structures. Rather, they
both originate from a pre-quantum operator algebra.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math-ph/1/au:+Arsiwalla_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xerxes D. Arsiwalla&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math-ph/1/au:+Chester_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;David Chester&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math-ph/1/au:+Kauffman_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Louis H. Kauffman&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01899">
<title>Formally Self-Adjoint Hamiltonian for the Hilbert-P\&apos;olya Conjecture. (arXiv:2211.01899v1 [math-ph])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01899</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We construct a formally self-adjoint Hamiltonian whose eigenvalues correspond
to the nontrivial zeros of the Riemann zeta function. We consider a
two-dimensional Hamiltonian which couples the Berry-Keating Hamiltonian to the
number operator on the half-line via a unitary transformation. We demonstrate
that the unitary operator, which is composed of squeeze (dilation) operators
and an exponential of the number operator, confines the eigenfunction of the
Hamiltonian to one dimension as the squeezing parameter tends towards infinity.
The Riemann zeta function appears at the boundary of the resulting confined
wave function and vanishes as a result of the imposed boundary condition. If
the formal argument presented here can be made more rigorous, particularly if
it can be shown rigorously that the Hamiltonian remains self-adjoint under the
imposed boundary condition, then our approach has the potential to imply that
the Riemann hypothesis is true.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math-ph/1/au:+Yakaboylu_E/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Enderalp Yakaboylu&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01940">
<title>Approximate Gibbsian structure in strongly correlated point fields and generalized Gaussian zero ensembles. (arXiv:2211.01940v1 [math.PR])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01940</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Gibbsian structure in random point fields has been a classical tool for
studying their spatial properties. However, exact Gibbs property is available
only in a relatively limited class of models, and it does not adequately
address many random fields with a strongly dependent spatial structure. In this
work, we provide a general framework for approximate Gibbsian structure for
strongly correlated random point fields. These include processes that exhibit
strong spatial rigidity, in particular, a certain one-parameter family of
analytic Gaussian zero point fields, namely the $\alpha$-GAFs. Our framework
entails conditions that may be verified via finite particle approximations to
the process, a phenomenon that we call an approximate Gibbs property. We show
that these enable one to compare the spatial conditional measures in the
infinite volume limit with Gibbs-type densities supported on appropriate
singular manifolds, a phenomenon we refer to as a generalized Gibbs property.
We demonstrate the scope of our approach by showing that a generalized Gibbs
property holds with a logarithmic pair potential for the $\alpha$-GAFs for any
value of $\alpha$. This establishes the level of rigidity of the $\alpha$-GAF
zero process to be exactly $\lfloor \frac{1}{\alpha} \rfloor$, settling in the
affirmative an open question regarding the existence of point processes with
any specified level of rigidity. For processes such as the zeros of
$\alpha$-GAFs, which involve complex, many-body interactions, our results imply
that the local behaviour of the random points still exhibits 2D Coulomb-type
repulsion in the short range. Our techniques can be leveraged to estimate the
relative energies of configurations under local perturbations, with possible
implications for dynamics and stochastic geometry on strongly correlated random
point fields.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Gangopadhyay_U/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ujan Gangopadhyay&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Ghosh_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Subhroshekhar Ghosh&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01947">
<title>Invertible bimodule categories and generalized Schur orthogonality. (arXiv:2211.01947v1 [math.QA])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01947</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The Schur orthogonality relations are a cornerstone in the representation
theory of groups. We utilize a generalization to weak Hopf algebras to provide
a new, readily verifiable condition on the skeletal data for deciding whether a
given bimodule category is invertible and therefore defines a Morita
equivalence. As a first application, we provide an algorithm for the
construction of the full skeletal data of the invertible bimodule category
associated to a given module category, which is obtained in a unitary gauge
when the underlying categories are unitary. As a second application, we show
that our condition for invertibility is equivalent to the notion of
MPO-injectivity, thereby closing an open question concerning tensor network
representations of string-net models exhibiting topological order. We discuss
applications to generalized symmetries, including a generalized Wigner-Eckart
theorem.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Bridgeman_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jacob C. Bridgeman&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Lootens_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Laurens Lootens&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Verstraete_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Frank Verstraete&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01974">
<title>Discrete approximations to Dirichlet and Neumann Laplacians on a half-space and norm resolvent convergence. (arXiv:2211.01974v1 [math.FA])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01974</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We extend recent results on discrete approximations of the Laplacian in
$\mathbf{R}^d$ with norm resolvent convergence to the corresponding results for
Dirichlet and Neumann Laplacians on a half-space. The resolvents of the
discrete Dirichlet/Neumann Laplacians are embedded into the continuum using
natural discretization and embedding operators. Norm resolvent convergence to
their continuous counterparts is proven with a quadratic rate in the mesh size.
These results generalize with a limited rate to also include operators with a
real, bounded, and H\&quot;older continuous potential, as well as certain functions
of the Dirichlet/Neumann Laplacians, including any positive real power.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Cornean_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Horia Cornean&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Garde_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Henrik Garde&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Jensen_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Arne Jensen&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01989">
<title>Bound states of weakly deformed soft waveguides. (arXiv:2211.01989v1 [math.SP])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01989</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;In this paper we consider the two-dimensional Schr\&quot;odinger operator with an
attractive potential which is a multiple of the characteristic function of an
unbounded strip-shaped region, whose thickness is varying and is determined by
the function $\mathbb{R}\ni x \mapsto d+\varepsilon f(x)$, where $d &amp;gt; 0$ is a
constant, $\varepsilon &amp;gt; 0$ is a small parameter, and $f$ is a compactly
supported continuous function. We prove that if $\int_{\mathbb{R}} f
\,\mathsf{d} x &amp;gt; 0$, then the respective Schr\&quot;odinger operator has a unique
simple eigenvalue below the threshold of the essential spectrum for all
sufficiently small $\varepsilon &amp;gt;0$ and we obtain the asymptotic expansion of
this eigenvalue in the regime $\varepsilon\rightarrow 0$. An asymptotic
expansion of the respective eigenfunction as $\varepsilon\rightarrow 0$ is also
obtained. In the case that $\int_{\mathbb{R}} f \,\mathsf{d} x &amp;lt; 0$ we prove
that the discrete spectrum is empty for all sufficiently small $\varepsilon &amp;gt;
0$. In the critical case $\int_{\mathbb{R}} f \,\mathsf{d} x = 0$, we derive a
sufficient condition for the existence of a unique bound state for all
sufficiently small $\varepsilon &amp;gt; 0$.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Exner_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Pavel Exner&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Kondej_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Sylwia Kondej&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Lotoreichik_V/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Vladimir Lotoreichik&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.02014">
<title>On the classicality of quantum dephasing processes. (arXiv:2211.02014v1 [quant-ph])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.02014</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We analyze the multitime statistics associated with pure dephasing systems
repeatedly probed with sharp measurements, and search for measurement protocols
whose statistics satisfies the Kolmogorov consistency conditions possibly up to
a finite order. We find a rich phenomenology of quantum dephasing processes
which can be interpreted in classical terms. In particular, if the underlying
dephasing process is Markovian, we find sufficient conditions under which
classicality at every order can be found: this can be reached by choosing the
dephasing and measurement basis to be fully compatible or fully incompatible,
that is, mutually unbiased bases (MUBs). For non-Markovian processes,
classicality can only be proven in the fully compatible case, thus revealing a
key difference between Markovian and non-Markovian pure dephasing processes.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Lonigro_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Davide Lonigro&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Chruscinski_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Dariusz Chru&amp;#x15b;ci&amp;#x144;ski&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.02034">
<title>Convergence of the logarithm of the characteristic polynomial of unitary Brownian motion to the Gaussian free field. (arXiv:2211.02034v1 [math.PR])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.02034</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We prove that the real and imaginary parts of the logarithm of the
characteristic polynomial of unitary Brownian motion converge to Gaussian free
fields on the cylinder, as the matrix dimension goes to infinity. This is the
natural dynamical analogue of the result for a fixed time by Hughes, Keating
and O&apos;Connell [1]. Further it complements a result by Spohn [2] on linear
statistics of unitary Brownian motion, and a recent result by Bourgade and
Falconet [3] connecting the characteristic polynomial of unitary Brownian
motion to a Gaussian multiplicative chaos measure. In the course of this
research we also proved a Wick-type identity, which we include in this paper,
as it might be of independent interest.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Forkel_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Johannes Forkel&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Sauzedde_I/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Isao Sauzedde&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2105.06244">
<title>A Graphical Calculus for Lagrangian Relations. (arXiv:2105.06244v2 [cs.LO] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2105.06244</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Symplectic vector spaces are the phase spaces of linear mechanical systems.
The symplectic form describes, for example, the relation between position and
momentum as well as current and voltage. The category of linear Lagrangian
relations between symplectic vector spaces is a symmetric monoidal subcategory
of relations which gives a semantics for the evolution -- and more generally
linear constraints on the evolution -- of various physical systems. We give a
new presentation of the category of Lagrangian relations over an arbitrary
field as a `doubled&apos; category of linear relations. More precisely, we show that
it arises as a variation of Selinger&apos;s CPM construction applied to linear
relations, where the covariant orthogonal complement functor plays the role of
conjugation. Furthermore, for linear relations over prime fields, this
corresponds exactly to the CPM construction for a suitable choice of dagger. We
can furthermore extend this construction by a single affine shift operator to
obtain a category of affine Lagrangian relations. Using this new presentation,
we prove the equivalence of the prop of affine Lagrangian relations with the
prop of qudit stabilizer theory in odd prime dimensions. We hence obtain a
unified graphical language for several disparate process theories, including
electrical circuits, Spekkens&apos; toy theory, and odd-prime-dimensional stabilizer
quantum circuits.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Comfort_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Cole Comfort&lt;/a&gt; (University of Oxford), &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Kissinger_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Aleks Kissinger&lt;/a&gt; (University of Oxford)</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2202.05652">
<title>Numerical schemes for a multi-species BGK model with velocity-dependent collision frequency. (arXiv:2202.05652v2 [math.NA] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2202.05652</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We consider a kinetic description of a multi-species gas mixture modeled with
Bhatnagar-Gross-Krook (BGK) collision operators, in which the collision
frequency varies not only in time and space but also with the microscopic
velocity. In this model, the Maxwellians typically used in standard BGK
operators are replaced by a generalization of such target functions, which are
defined by a variational procedure \cite{&lt;a href=&quot;/abs/2101.09047&quot;&gt;arXiv:2101.09047&lt;/a&gt;}. In this paper we
present a numerical method for simulating this model, which uses an
Implicit-Explicit (IMEX) scheme to minimize a certain potential function,
mimicking the Lagrange functional that appears in the theoretical derivation.
We show that theoretical properties such as conservation of mass, total
momentum and total energy as well as positivity of the distribution functions
are preserved by the numerical method, and illustrate its usefulness and
effectiveness with numerical examples.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Haack_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jeffrey Haack&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Hauck_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Cory Hauck&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Klingenberg_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Christian Klingenberg&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Pirner_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Marlies Pirner&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Warnecke_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Sandra Warnecke&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2202.08136">
<title>On BV Supermanifolds and the Super Atiyah Class. (arXiv:2202.08136v3 [math-ph] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2202.08136</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We study global and local geometry of forms on odd symplectic BV
supermanifolds, constructed from the total space of the bundle of 1-forms on a
base supermanifold. We show that globally 1-forms are an extension of vector
bundles defined on the base supermanifold. In the holomorphic category, we
prove that this extension is split if and only if the super Atiyah class of the
base supermanifold vanishes. This is equivalent to the existence of a
holomorphic superconnection: we show how this condition is related to the
characteristic non-split geometry of complex supermanifolds. From a local point
of view, we prove that the deformed de Rham double complex naturally arises as
a de-quantization of the de Rham/Spencer double complex of the base
supermanifold. Following \v{S}evera, we show that the associated spectral
sequence yields semidensities on the BV supermanifold, together with their
differential in the form of a super BV Laplacian.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math-ph/1/au:+Noja_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Simone Noja&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2203.16012">
<title>Entanglement area law for 1D gauge theories and bosonic systems. (arXiv:2203.16012v2 [quant-ph] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2203.16012</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We prove an entanglement area law for a class of 1D quantum systems involving
infinite-dimensional local Hilbert spaces. This class of quantum systems
include bosonic models such as the Hubbard-Holstein model, and both U(1) and
SU(2) lattice gauge theories in one spatial dimension. Our proof relies on new
results concerning the robustness of the ground state and spectral gap to the
truncation of Hilbert space, applied within the approximate ground state
projector (AGSP) framework from previous work. In establishing this area law,
we develop a system-size independent bound on the expectation value of local
observables for Hamiltonians without translation symmetry, which may be of
separate interest. Our result provides theoretical justification for using
tensor network methods to study the ground state properties of quantum systems
with infinite local degrees of freedom.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Abrahamsen_N/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Nilin Abrahamsen&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Tong_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yu Tong&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Bao_N/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ning Bao&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Su_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yuan Su&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Wiebe_N/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Nathan Wiebe&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2205.05704">
<title>Dynamical quantum ergodicity from energy level statistics. (arXiv:2205.05704v2 [quant-ph] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2205.05704</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Ergodic theory provides a rigorous mathematical description of classical
dynamical systems including a formal definition of the ergodic hierarchy.
Closely related to this hierarchy is a less-known notion of cyclic approximate
periodic transformations [see, e.g., I. Cornfield, S. Fomin, and Y. Sinai,
Ergodic theory (Springer-Verlag New York, 1982)], which maps any &quot;ergodic&quot;
dynamical system to a cyclic permutation on a circle and arguably represents
the most elementary notion of ergodicity. This paper shows that cyclic
ergodicity generalizes to quantum dynamical systems, and this generalization is
proposed here as the basic rigorous definition of quantum ergodicity. It
implies the ability to construct an orthonormal basis, where quantum dynamics
transports an initial basis vector to all other basis vectors one by one, while
maintaining a sufficiently large overlap between the time-evolved initial state
and a given basis state. It is proven that the basis, maximizing the overlap
over all cyclic permutations, is obtained via the discrete Fourier transform of
the energy eigenstates. This relates quantum cyclic ergodicity to level
statistics. We then show that the near-universal Wigner-Dyson level statistics
implies quantum cyclic ergodicity, but the reverse is not necessarily true. For
the latter, we study irrational flows on a 2D torus and prove that both the
classical and quantum flows are cyclic ergodic. However, the corresponding
level statistics is neither Wigner-Dyson nor Poisson. Finally, we use the
cyclic construction to motivate a quantum ergodic hierarchy of operators and
argue that under the additional assumption of Poincare recurrences, cyclic
ergodicity is a necessary condition for such operators to satisfy the
eigenstate thermalization hypothesis. This work provides a general framework
for transplanting some rigorous concepts of ergodic theory to quantum dynamical
systems.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Vikram_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Amit Vikram&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Galitski_V/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Victor Galitski&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2206.14277">
<title>Integrable Floquet systems related to logarithmic conformal field theory. (arXiv:2206.14277v2 [quant-ph] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2206.14277</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We study an integrable Floquet quantum system related to lattice statistical
systems in the universality class of dense polymers. These systems are
described by a particular non-unitary representation of the Temperley-Lieb
algebra. We find a simple Lie algebra structure for the elements of
Temperley-Lieb algebra which are invariant under shift by two lattice sites,
and show how the local Floquet conserved charges and the Floquet Hamiltonian
are expressed in terms of this algebra. The system has a phase transition
between local and non-local phases of the Floquet Hamiltonian. We provide a
strong indication that in the scaling limit this non-equilibrium system is
described by the logarithmic conformal field theory.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Yashin_V/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Vsevolod I. Yashin&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Kurlov_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Denis V. Kurlov&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Fedorov_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Aleksey K. Fedorov&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Gritsev_V/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Vladimir Gritsev&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2207.10658">
<title>Local Dirac energy decay in the 5D Myers-Perry geometry using an integral spectral representation for the Dirac propagator. (arXiv:2207.10658v3 [gr-qc] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2207.10658</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We consider the massive Dirac equation in the exterior region of the
5-dimensional Myers-Perry black hole. Using the resulting ODEs obtained from
the separation of variables of the Dirac equation, we construct an integral
spectral representation for the solution of the Cauchy problem with compactly
supported smooth initial data. We then prove that the probability of presence
of a Dirac particle to be in any compact region of space decays to zero as
$t\to\infty$, in analogy with the case of the Dirac operator in the Kerr-Newman
geometry.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Wang_Q/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Qiu Shi Wang&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2208.07436">
<title>Hamilton-Jacobi theory and integrability for autonomous and non-autonomous contact systems. (arXiv:2208.07436v2 [math-ph] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2208.07436</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;In this paper, we study the integrability of contact Hamiltonian systems,
both time-dependent and independent. In order to do so, we construct a
Hamilton--Jacobi theory for these systems following two approaches, obtaining
two different Hamilton--Jacobi equations. Compared to conservative Hamiltonian
systems, contact Hamiltonian systems depend of one additional parameter. The
fact of obtaining two equations reflects whether we are looking for solutions
depending on this additional parameter or not. In order to illustrate the
theory developed in this paper, we study three examples: the free particle with
a linear external force, the freely falling particle with linear dissipation
and the damped and forced harmonic oscillator.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math-ph/1/au:+Leon_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Manuel de Le&amp;#xf3;n&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math-ph/1/au:+Lainz_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Manuel Lainz&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math-ph/1/au:+Lopez_Gordon_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Asier L&amp;#xf3;pez-Gord&amp;#xf3;n&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math-ph/1/au:+Rivas_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xavier Rivas&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.07698">
<title>Multisymplectic Constraint Analysis of Scalar Field Theories, Chern-Simons Gravity, and Bosonic String Theory. (arXiv:2210.07698v2 [math-ph] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.07698</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The (pre)multisymplectic geometry of the De Donder--Weyl formalism for field
theories is further developed for a variety of field theories including a
scalar field theory from the canonical Klein-Gordon action, the electric and
magnetic Carrollian scalar field theories, bosonic string theory from the
Nambu-Goto action, and $2+1$ gravity as a Chern-Simons theory. The Lagrangians
for the scalar field theories and for $2+1$ Chern-Simons gravity are found to
be singular in the De Donder--Weyl sense while the Nambu-Goto Lagrangian is
found to be regular. Furthermore, the constraint structure of the
premultisymplectic phase spaces of singular field theories is explained and
applied to these theories. Finally, it is studied how symmetries are developed
on the multisymplectic phase spaces in the presence of constraints.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math-ph/1/au:+Gomis_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Joaquim Gomis&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math-ph/1/au:+Guerra_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Arnoldo Guerra IV&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math-ph/1/au:+Roman_Roy_N/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Narciso Rom&amp;#xe1;n-Roy&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.08342">
<title>Well-definedness of Physical Law Learning: The Uniqueness Problem. (arXiv:2210.08342v5 [cs.LG] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.08342</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Physical law learning is the ambiguous attempt at automating the derivation
of governing equations with the use of machine learning techniques. The current
literature focuses however solely on the development of methods to achieve this
goal, and a theoretical foundation is at present missing. This paper shall thus
serve as a first step to build a comprehensive theoretical framework for
learning physical laws, aiming to provide reliability to according algorithms.
One key problem consists in the fact that the governing equations might not be
uniquely determined by the given data. We will study this problem in the common
situation that a physical law is described by an ordinary or partial
differential equation. For various different classes of differential equations,
we provide both necessary and sufficient conditions for a function to uniquely
determine the differential equation which is governing the phenomenon. We then
use our results to devise numerical algorithms to determine whether a function
solves a differential equation uniquely. Finally, we provide extensive
numerical experiments showing that our algorithms in combination with common
approaches for learning physical laws indeed allow to guarantee that a unique
governing differential equation is learnt, without assuming any knowledge about
the function, thereby ensuring reliability.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Scholl_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Philipp Scholl&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Bacho_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Aras Bacho&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Boche_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Holger Boche&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Kutyniok_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Gitta Kutyniok&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.17448">
<title>Geometry of phase-covariant qubit channels. (arXiv:2210.17448v2 [quant-ph] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.17448</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We analyze the geometry on the space of non-unital phase-covariant qubit
maps. Using the corresponding Choi-Jamio{\l}kowski states, we derive the
Hilbert-Schmidt line and volume elements using the channel eigenvalues together
with the parameter that characterizes non-unitality. We find the shapes and
analytically compute the volumes of phase-covariant channels, in particular
entanglement breaking and obtainable with time-local generators.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Siudzinska_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Katarzyna Siudzi&amp;#x144;ska&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.00769">
<title>Instability of electroweak homogeneous vacua in strong magnetic fields. (arXiv:2211.00769v2 [math-ph] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.00769</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We consider the classical vacua of the Weinberg-Salam (WS) model of
electroweak forces. These are no-particle, static solutions to the WS equations
minimizing the WS energy locally. We study the WS vacuum solutions exhibiting a
non-vanishing average magnetic field, $\vec b$, and prove that (i) there is a
magnetic field threshold $b_*$ such that for $|\vec b|&amp;lt;b_*$, the vacua are
translationally invariant (and the magnetic field is constant), while, for
$|\vec b|&amp;gt;b_*$, they are not, (ii) for $|\vec b|&amp;gt;b_*$, there are
non-translationally invariant solutions with lower energy per unit volume and
with the discrete translational symmetry of a 2D lattice in the plane
transversal to $\vec b$, and (iii) the lattice minimizing the energy per unit
volume approaches the hexagonal one as the magnetic field strength approaches
the threshold $b_*$.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the absence of particles, the Weinberg-Salam model reduces to the
Yang-Mills-Higgs (YMH) equations for the gauge group $U(2)$. Thus our results
can be rephrased as the corresponding statements about the $U(2)$-YMH equations
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math-ph/1/au:+Gardner_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Adam Gardner&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math-ph/1/au:+Sigal_I/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Israel Michael Sigal&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01148">
<title>On Infinite Series of Bessel functions of the First Kind: $\sum_\nu J_{N\nu+p}(x), \sum_\nu (-1)^\nu J_{N\nu+p}(x)$. (arXiv:2211.01148v1 [math-ph] CROSS LISTED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01148</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Infinite series of Bessel function of the first kind, $\sum_\nu^{\pm\infty}
J_{N\nu+p}(x)$, $\sum_\nu^{\pm\infty} (-1)^\nu J_{N\nu+p}(x)$, are summed in
closed form. These expressions are evaluated by engineering a Dirac comb that
selects specific sequences within the Bessel series.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math-ph/1/au:+Sung_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Suk Hyun Sung&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math-ph/1/au:+Hovden_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Robert Hovden&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
</rdf:RDF>