<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Entrepreneurial Geekiness</title>
	<atom:link href="https://ianozsvald.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://ianozsvald.com</link>
	<description>Data Science, PyData London, Springer Spaniels, Coffee</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2022 10:35:29 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7.8</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Upcoming discussion calls for Team Structure and Buidling a Backlog for data science leads</title>
		<link>https://ianozsvald.com/2022/07/01/upcoming-discussion-calls-for-team-structure-and-buidling-a-backlog-for-data-science-leads/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ian]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2022 12:37:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Data science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pydata]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Python]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://ianozsvald.com/?p=3972</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I ran another Executives at PyData discussion session for 50+ leaders at our PyDataLondon conference a couple of weeks back. We had great conversation which dug into a lot of topics. I&#8217;ve written up notes on my NotANumber newsletter. If you&#8217;re a leader of DS and Data Eng teams, you probably want to review those [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I ran another <a href="https://london2022.pydata.org/cfp/talk/ZWPHS9/">Executives at PyData</a> discussion session for 50+ leaders at our <a href="https://pydata.org/london2022/schedule/">PyDataLondon conference</a> a couple of weeks back. We had great conversation which dug into a lot of topics. I&#8217;ve written up <a href="https://buttondown.email/NotANumber/archive/lessons-learned-from-the-executives-at-pydata/">notes on my NotANumber newsletter</a>. If you&#8217;re a leader of DS and Data Eng teams, you probably want to review those notes.</p>
<p>To follow on the conversations I&#8217;m going to run the following two (free) Zoom based discussion sessions. I&#8217;ll be recording the calls and adding notes to <a href="https://notanumber.email/">future newsletters</a>. If you&#8217;d like to join, <a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSc1XshrUEL8EF52bM5zQLV54PtX50S2rStZjngsBvKKCTHG6g/viewform">fill in this invite form</a> and I can add you to the calendar invite. You can lurk and listen or &#8211; better &#8211; join in with questions.</p>
<ul>
<li><del>Monday July 11, 4pm (UK time)</del>, <strong>Data Science Team Structure</strong> &#8211; getting a good structure for your org, hybrid vs fully remote practices, processes that support your team, how to avoid being left out</li>
<li>Monday August 8th, 4pm (UK time), <strong>Backlog &amp; Derisking &amp; Estimation</strong> &#8211; how to build a backlog, derisking quickly and estimating the value behind your project</li>
</ul>
<p>I&#8217;m expecting a healthy list of issues and good feedback and discussion for both calls. I&#8217;ll be sharing an agenda in advance to those who have contacted me. My goal is to turn these into bigger events in the future.</p>
<hr>
Ian is a Chief Interim Data Scientist via his <a href=http://morconsulting.com>Mor Consulting</a>. Sign-up for <a href=http://eepurl.com/Z44HT>Data Science tutorials in London</a> and to hear about his <a href=https://ianozsvald.com/data-science-jobs/>data science thoughts and jobs</a>. He lives in London, is walked by his high energy Springer Spaniel and is a consumer of fine coffees.]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>My first commit to Pandas</title>
		<link>https://ianozsvald.com/2021/03/10/my-first-commit-to-pandas/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ian]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 14:15:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Python]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://ianozsvald.com/?p=3955</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I&#8217;ve used the Pandas data science toolkit for over a decade and I&#8217;ve filed a couple of issues, but I&#8217;ve never contributed to the source. At the weekend I got to balance the books a little by making my first commit. With this pull request I fixed the recent request to update the pct_change docs [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;ve used the Pandas data science toolkit for over a decade and I&#8217;ve filed a couple of issues, but I&#8217;ve never contributed to the source. At the weekend I got to balance the books a little by making my first commit. With this <a href="https://github.com/pandas-dev/pandas/pull/40266">pull request</a> I fixed the <a href="https://github.com/pandas-dev/pandas/issues/39672">recent request</a> to update the pct_change docs to make the final example more readable.</p>
<p>The change was trivial &#8211; adding &#8220;periods=-1&#8221; to the argument and updating the docstring. The build process was a lot more involved &#8211; thankfully I was on a call with PyLadies London to try to help others make their first contribution to Pandas and I had organiser Marco Gorelli (a core contributor) to help when needed.</p>
<p>Ultimately it boiled down to <a href="https://pandas.pydata.org/pandas-docs/stable/development/contributing.html#creating-a-development-environment">setting up</a> a docker environment, running a new example in my shell, updating the <a href="https://github.com/pandas-dev/pandas/pull/40266/files">relevant docstring</a> on the local filesystem and then following the &#8220;<a href="https://pandas.pydata.org/pandas-docs/stable/development/contributing.html#contributing-to-the-documentation">contributing to the documentation</a>&#8221; guide. My initial commit fell foul of the docstring style rules and the automated checking tools in the docker environment point this out. Once the local filesystem checker scripts were happy I pushed to my fork, created a PR and shortly after everything was done.</p>
<p>All in it took 45 minutes to get the environment setup, another 45 minutes to make my changes and figure out how to run the right scripts, then a bit longer to push and submit a PR (followed by overnight patience before it got picked up by the team).</p>
<p>When I teach my classes I always recommend that a good way to learn new development practices (like the automated use of black &amp; flake8 in a precommit process) is to submit small fixes to open source projects &#8211; you learn so much along the way. I&#8217;ve not used docker in years and I don&#8217;t use automated docstring checking tools, so both presented nice little points for learning. I also have never used the pct_change function in Pandas&#8230;and now I have.</p>
<p>If you&#8217;ve not yet made a commit to an open source project, do have a think about it &#8211; you&#8217;ll get lots of hand holding (just be patient, positive and friendly when you leave comments) and you can stick a reference to the result on your CV for bragging rights. And you&#8217;ll have made the world a slightly better place.</p>
<hr>
Ian is a Chief Interim Data Scientist via his <a href=http://morconsulting.com>Mor Consulting</a>. Sign-up for <a href=http://eepurl.com/Z44HT>Data Science tutorials in London</a> and to hear about his <a href=https://ianozsvald.com/data-science-jobs/>data science thoughts and jobs</a>. He lives in London, is walked by his high energy Springer Spaniel and is a consumer of fine coffees.]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Skinny Pandas Riding on a Rocket at PyDataGlobal 2020</title>
		<link>https://ianozsvald.com/2020/11/30/skinny-pandas-riding-on-a-rocket-at-pydataglobal-2020/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ian]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 19:25:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Data science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pydata]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Python]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://ianozsvald.com/?p=3904</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On November 11th we saw the most ambitious ever PyData conference &#8211; PyData Global 2020 was a combination of world-wide PyData groups putting on a huge event to both build our international community and to leverage the on-line only conferences that we need to run during Covid 19. The conference brought together almost 2,000 attendees [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>On November 11th we saw the most ambitious ever PyData conference &#8211; <a href="https://global.pydata.org/">PyData Global 2020</a> was a combination of world-wide PyData groups putting on a huge event to both build our international community and to leverage the on-line only conferences that we need to run during Covid 19.</p>
<p>The conference brought together almost 2,000 attendees from <a href="https://twitter.com/John_Sandall/status/1328890209048662023">65 countries</a> with 165 speakers over 5 days on a <a href="https://global.pydata.org/pages/schedule">5-track schedule</a>. All speaker videos had to be uploaded in advance so they could be checked and then provided ahead-of-time to attendees. You can see the <a href="https://global.pydata.org/pages/program">full program</a> here, the topic list was very solid since the selection committee had the best of the international community uploading their proposals.</p>
<p>The volunteer organising committee felt that giving attendees a chance to watch all the speakers at their leisure took away constraints of time zones &#8211; but we wanted to avoid the common end result of &#8220;watching a webinar&#8221; that has plagued many other conferences this year. Our solution included timed (and repeated) &#8220;watch parties&#8221; so you could gather to watch the video simultaneously with others, and then share discussion in chat rooms. The volunteer organising committee also worked hard to build a &#8220;virtual 2D world&#8221; with <a href="https://www.gather.town/">Gather.town</a> &#8211; you walk around a virtual conference space (including the speakers&#8217; rooms, an expo hall, parks, a bar, a helpdesk and more). Volunteer Jesper Dramsch made a <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vbmqFuZLxTM&amp;t=3s">very cool virtual tour</a> of &#8220;how you can attend PyData Global&#8221; which has a great demo of how Gather works &#8211; it is worth a quick watch. Other conferences should take note.</p>
<p>Through Gather you could &#8220;attend&#8221; the keynote and speaker rooms during a watch-party and actually <em>see other attendees</em> around you, you could talk to them and you could watch the video being played. You genuinely got a sense that you were attending an event with others, that&#8217;s the first time I&#8217;ve really felt that in 2020 and I&#8217;ve presented at 7 events this year prior to PyDataGlobal (and frankly some of those other events felt pretty lonely &#8211; presenting to a blank screen and getting no feedback&#8230;that&#8217;s not very fulfilling!).</p>
<p>I spoke on &#8220;<a href="https://speakerdeck.com/ianozsvald/skinny-pandas-riding-on-a-rocket-pydataglobal-2020">Skinny Pandas Riding on a Rocket</a>&#8221; &#8211; a culmination of ideas covered in earlier talks with a focus on <em>getting more into Pandas</em> so you don&#8217;t have to learn new technologies and <em>see Vaex, Dask and SQLite in action</em> if you do need to scale up your Pythonic data science.</p>
<p>I also organised another &#8220;Executives at PyData&#8221; session aimed at getting decision makers and team leaders into a (virtual) room for an hour to discuss pressing issues. Given 6 iterations of my &#8220;Successful Data Science Projects&#8221; training course in London over the last 1.5 years I know of many issues that repeatedly come up that plague decision makers on data science teams. We got to cover a set of issues and talk on solutions that are known to work. I have a fuller write-up to follow.</p>
<p>The conference also enabled a &#8220;pay what you can&#8221; model for those attending outside of a corporate ticket, this brought in a much wider audience that could normally attend a PyData conference. The goal of the non-profit NumFOCUS (who back the PyData global events) is to fund open source so the goal is always to raise more money and to provide a high quality educational and networking experience. For this on-line global event we figured it made sense to open out the community to even more folk &#8211; the &#8220;pay what you can&#8221; model is regarded as a success (this is the first time we&#8217;ve done it!) and has given us some interesting attendee insights to think on.</p>
<p>There are definitely some lessons to learn, notably the on-boarding process was complex (3 systems had to be activated) &#8211; the volunteer crew wrote very clear instructions but nonetheless it was a more involved process than we wanted. This will be improved in the future.</p>
<p>I extend my thanks to the <a href="https://twitter.com/MSanKeys963/status/1328666692629655554">wider volunteer organising committee</a> and to NumFOCUS for making this happen!</p>
<hr>
Ian is a Chief Interim Data Scientist via his <a href=http://morconsulting.com>Mor Consulting</a>. Sign-up for <a href=http://eepurl.com/Z44HT>Data Science tutorials in London</a> and to hear about his <a href=https://ianozsvald.com/data-science-jobs/>data science thoughts and jobs</a>. He lives in London, is walked by his high energy Springer Spaniel and is a consumer of fine coffees.]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>&#8220;Making Pandas Fly&#8221; at EuroPython 2020</title>
		<link>https://ianozsvald.com/2020/07/24/making-pandas-fly-at-europython-2020/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ian]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 24 Jul 2020 14:49:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[High Performance Python Book]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pydata]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Python]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://ianozsvald.com/?p=3885</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I&#8217;ve had a chance to return to talking about High Performance Python at EuroPython 2020 after my first tutorial on this topic back in 2011 in Florence. Today I spoke on Making Pandas Fly with a focus on making Pandas run faster. This covered: Categories and RAM-saving datatypes to make 100-500x speed-ups (well, some of [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;ve had a chance to return to talking about High Performance Python at EuroPython 2020 after my first tutorial on this topic back in 2011 in Florence. Today I spoke on <a href="https://speakerdeck.com/ianozsvald/making-pandas-fly-europython-2020">Making Pandas Fly</a> with a focus on making Pandas run faster. This covered:</p>
<ul>
<li>Categories and RAM-saving datatypes to make 100-500x speed-ups (well, some of the time) including <a href="https://github.com/ianozsvald/dtype_diet/">dtype_diet</a></li>
<li>Dropping to NumPy to make things potentially 10x faster (thanks James Powell and his <a href="https://github.com/ianozsvald/callgraph_james_powell">callgraph</a> code)</li>
<li>Numba for compilation (another 10x!)</li>
<li>Dask for parallelisation (2-8x!)</li>
<li>and taking a view on Modin &amp; Vaex</li>
</ul>
<p>We might ask &#8220;why do this&#8221; and my answer is &#8220;let&#8217;s go faster using the tools we already know how to use&#8221;. Specifically &#8211; without investing time learning a new tool (e.g. Intel SDC, Vaex, Modin, Dask, Spark and more) we can extend our ability to work with larger datasets without leaving the comfort of Pandas so you can get to your answers quicker. This message went down well:<a href="https://ianozsvald.com/2020/07/24/making-pandas-fly-at-europython-2020/europython2020_feedback/" rel="attachment wp-att-3891"><img class="wp-image-3891 aligncenter" src="https://ianozsvald.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/europython2020_feedback.png" alt="Feedback from EuroPython 2020" width="628" height="234" srcset="https://ianozsvald.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/europython2020_feedback.png 1212w, https://ianozsvald.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/europython2020_feedback-300x112.png 300w, https://ianozsvald.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/europython2020_feedback-1024x382.png 1024w, https://ianozsvald.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/europython2020_feedback-768x286.png 768w, https://ianozsvald.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/europython2020_feedback-1200x448.png 1200w, https://ianozsvald.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/europython2020_feedback-512x191.png 512w" sizes="(max-width: 628px) 100vw, 628px" /></a></p>
<p>If you&#8217;re curious about this and want to go further you might want to look at my <a href="https://ianozsvald.com/training/">upcoming training courses</a> (this includes Higher Performance, Software Engineering and Successful Data Science Projects). If you want tips and you want to stay on top of what I&#8217;m working on they join my <a href="https://ianozsvald.com/data-science-jobs/">twice-a-month mailing list</a> (see the link for a recent example post).</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<hr>
Ian is a Chief Interim Data Scientist via his <a href=http://morconsulting.com>Mor Consulting</a>. Sign-up for <a href=http://eepurl.com/Z44HT>Data Science tutorials in London</a> and to hear about his <a href=https://ianozsvald.com/data-science-jobs/>data science thoughts and jobs</a>. He lives in London, is walked by his high energy Springer Spaniel and is a consumer of fine coffees.]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Weekish notes</title>
		<link>https://ianozsvald.com/2020/07/15/weekish-notes-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ian]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2020 19:20:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Data science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Python]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Week notes]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://ianozsvald.com/?p=3877</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I&#8217;ve recently switched back from Sourdough yeast to dried packet yeast mix, given a recipe by a colleague (thanks Nick!). I immediately set to work modifying his recipe (well, cutting out steps if we&#8217;re honest). The first loaf looked fine but was bland &#8211; I cut out too much salt. The next was really very [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;ve recently switched back from Sourdough yeast to dried packet yeast mix, given a recipe by a colleague (thanks Nick!). I immediately set to work modifying his recipe (well, cutting out steps if we&#8217;re honest). The first loaf looked fine but was bland &#8211; I cut out too much salt. The next was really very good (&#8220;shop quality&#8221;). For the third I used off-boil water for my autolyse and I think the water was still too hot and killed some of the yeast later giving me <a href="https://twitter.com/ianozsvald/status/1283059008144904194">this dense lump</a>. Later that evening after 2.5 hours I had a luke-warm water repeat loaf and <a href="https://twitter.com/ianozsvald/status/1283165887244140545">it was brilliant</a>. I confirmed this with toast &amp; jam this morning.</p>
<p>I&#8217;ve got quite a log of notes for my two main recipes now and will have a Sourdough on the go again this weekend.</p>
<p>Working with my &#8220;still secret&#8221; client in a safe haven locked down remote instance I lack most of my usual tools (part by design, part my ignorance during configuration). I&#8217;ve got Vi so I&#8217;m getting my hands dirty with the <a href="https://dev.to/iggredible/using-buffers-windows-and-tabs-efficiently-in-vim-56jc">underlying operations</a> (hey! :bnext and :e work fine! Ctrl P does some sort of autocomplete! :ls lists my buffers!). This is a little painful and Apache Guacamole&#8217;s remote viewer can be troublesome (stripping £ symbols, giving me 3 different keyboard configs depending on when I login, forgetting some of my windows!) but on the whole the setup is working well.</p>
<p>I&#8217;ve also had to get down and dirty with Git &#8211; no GitK or other fun tools. I&#8217;ve discovered some nice light git configs like &#8220;<a href="https://ma.ttias.be/pretty-git-log-in-one-line/">git logline</a>&#8221; which help with terminal based navigation in our small team.</p>
<p><a href="https://ianozsvald.com/training/">Training classes</a> are now listed for:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.eventbrite.co.uk/e/software-engineering-for-data-scientists-3-morning-virtual-event-tickets-111465787170">Software Engineering for Data Scientists</a> (September) &#8211; write strong, tested, reliable and defensible code from Notebooks to modules to improve collaboration and resilience</li>
<li><a href="https://www.eventbrite.co.uk/e/higher-performance-python-tickets-112262839174">Higher Performance Python</a> (October) &#8211; profile CPU &amp; memory usage, speed up your code, compile where useful and improve your Pandas &amp; Dask to enable faster iteration and faster processing on your projects with minimal effort on your part</li>
<li><a href="https://www.eventbrite.co.uk/e/successful-data-science-projects-tickets-93928096465">Successful Data Science Projects</a> (November) &#8211; discover new process &amp; tools to design data science projects that&#8217;ll run successfully, improve collaboration between your team and the wider business (this is built out of 15 years of painful lessons so you don&#8217;t have to make the same mistakes!)</li>
</ul>
<hr>
Ian is a Chief Interim Data Scientist via his <a href=http://morconsulting.com>Mor Consulting</a>. Sign-up for <a href=http://eepurl.com/Z44HT>Data Science tutorials in London</a> and to hear about his <a href=https://ianozsvald.com/data-science-jobs/>data science thoughts and jobs</a>. He lives in London, is walked by his high energy Springer Spaniel and is a consumer of fine coffees.]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Weekish notes</title>
		<link>https://ianozsvald.com/2020/07/05/weekish-notes/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ian]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 05 Jul 2020 15:42:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Data science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Python]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://ianozsvald.com/?p=3873</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I gave another iteration of my Making Pandas Fly talk sequence for PyDataAmsterdam recently and received some lovely postcards from attendees as a result. I&#8217;ve also had time to list new iterations of my training courses for Higher Performance Python (October) and Software Engineering for Data Scientists (September), both will run virtually via Zoom &#38; [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I gave <a href="https://ianozsvald.com/2020/06/23/making-pandas-fly-for-pydataamsterdam-2020/">another iteration</a> of my Making Pandas Fly talk sequence for PyDataAmsterdam recently and received some lovely postcards from attendees as a result. I&#8217;ve also had time to list new iterations of my <a href="https://ianozsvald.com/training/">training courses</a> for Higher Performance Python (October) and Software Engineering for Data Scientists (September), both will run virtually via Zoom &amp; Slack in the UK timezone.</p>
<p>I&#8217;ve been using my <a href="https://github.com/ianozsvald/dtype_diet/">dtype_diet</a> tool to time more performance improvements with Pandas and I look forward to talking more on this <a href="https://ep2020.europython.eu/schedule/24-july">at EuroPython</a> this month.</p>
<p>In baking news I&#8217;ve improved my <a href="https://twitter.com/ianozsvald/status/1278623998797021184">face-making on sourdough loaves</a> (but still have work to do) and I figure now is a good time to have a crack at <a href="https://twitter.com/ianozsvald/status/1279766985354752001">dried-yeast baking</a> again.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<hr>
Ian is a Chief Interim Data Scientist via his <a href=http://morconsulting.com>Mor Consulting</a>. Sign-up for <a href=http://eepurl.com/Z44HT>Data Science tutorials in London</a> and to hear about his <a href=https://ianozsvald.com/data-science-jobs/>data science thoughts and jobs</a>. He lives in London, is walked by his high energy Springer Spaniel and is a consumer of fine coffees.]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>&#8220;Making Pandas Fly&#8221; for PyDataAmsterdam 2020</title>
		<link>https://ianozsvald.com/2020/06/23/making-pandas-fly-for-pydataamsterdam-2020/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ian]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 23 Jun 2020 17:15:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Data science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[High Performance Python Book]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pydata]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://ianozsvald.com/?p=3863</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I thank the PyDataAmsterdam 2020 organisers for another chance to speak on Making Pandas Fly (PyDataAmsterdam 2020). This variant of the talk focuses more on: Understanding when categories beat strings and smaller floats beat larger ones What&#8217;s happening with NumPy behind the scenes How we can save 50% of our RAM (and so fit in [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I thank the <a href="https://amsterdam.pydata.org/">PyDataAmsterdam 2020</a> organisers for another chance to speak on <a href="https://speakerdeck.com/ianozsvald/making-pandas-fly-pydataamsterdam-2020">Making Pandas Fly (PyDataAmsterdam 2020)</a>. This variant of the talk focuses more on:</p>
<ul>
<li>Understanding when categories beat strings and smaller floats beat larger ones</li>
<li>What&#8217;s happening with NumPy behind the scenes</li>
<li>How we can save 50% of our RAM (and so fit in more data to the same machine) by checking dtypes with my <a href="https://ianozsvald.com/2020/06/02/weeknote-dtype-diet/">dtype_diet</a> tool</li>
<li>Considering that float16 is simulated on modern hardware and so is memory efficient but slow for calculating!</li>
<li>Tips to install <a href="https://pandas.pydata.org/pandas-docs/stable/getting_started/install.html#recommended-dependencies">bottleneck &amp; numexpr</a> to make Pandas faster</li>
<li>Digging into some Pandas internals when I filed a bug &#8211; and what I learned as a result (you can <a href="https://github.com/pandas-dev/pandas/issues/34773">learn too by reading the bug report</a>!)</li>
</ul>
<p>In a few months I&#8217;ll run another of my Higher Performance Python virtual training classes, you&#8217;re most welcome to join. You&#8217;ll find details on my very-lightly-used &#8220;<a href="https://ianozsvald.com/training/">training email list</a>&#8220;, you should join this if you&#8217;d like to hear about my upcoming training courses.</p>
<p>I make notes on some of these topics in my irregular &#8220;weekish notes&#8221; here on the blog and in my every-2-weeks &#8220;thoughts &amp; jobs&#8221; email list. You&#8217;re welcome to <a href="https://ianozsvald.com/data-science-jobs/">join the list</a> (your email is always kept private) if getting it in your inbox is more convenient.</p>
<p>At the end of my talks I always ask for a postcard &#8220;if you learned something&#8221;, I&#8217;ve just received the first for last week&#8217;s talk from the Netherlands &#8211; thanks!</p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">Thanking Henry for sending through a lovely postcard (&quot;enthusiastic talk, very valuable insights, best presentation&quot; &#8211; humbled!) from the Netherlands after my talk <a href="https://twitter.com/pydataamsterdam?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@pydataamsterdam</a> <a href="https://t.co/jPwKU880Nz">pic.twitter.com/jPwKU880Nz</a></p>
<p>&mdash; Ian Ozsvald (@ianozsvald) <a href="https://twitter.com/ianozsvald/status/1275401574437859328?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">June 23, 2020</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></p>
<hr>
Ian is a Chief Interim Data Scientist via his <a href=http://morconsulting.com>Mor Consulting</a>. Sign-up for <a href=http://eepurl.com/Z44HT>Data Science tutorials in London</a> and to hear about his <a href=https://ianozsvald.com/data-science-jobs/>data science thoughts and jobs</a>. He lives in London, is walked by his high energy Springer Spaniel and is a consumer of fine coffees.]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Weeknote (dtype-diet)</title>
		<link>https://ianozsvald.com/2020/06/02/weeknote-dtype-diet/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ian]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2020 17:16:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Data science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Week notes]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://ianozsvald.com/?p=3857</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Over the weekend I hacked on dtype_diet &#8211; a tool for Pandas users that checks their DataFrame to see if smaller datatypes might be applicable. If so they&#8217;d offer no data loss and a reduction in RAM, for Categorical data there&#8217;s also the possibility of faster calculations. This tool makes no changes, it recommends the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Over the weekend I hacked on <a href="https://github.com/ianozsvald/dtype_diet/">dtype_diet</a> &#8211; a tool for Pandas users that checks their DataFrame to see if smaller datatypes might be applicable. If so they&#8217;d offer no data loss and a reduction in RAM, for Categorical data there&#8217;s also the possibility of faster calculations. This tool makes no changes, it recommends the code you might copy into your project. I developed this as one of the ideas I didn&#8217;t get around to building whilst I was working on my book, but since that&#8217;s now published&#8230;</p>
<p>Talking of which &#8211; Micha and I have cleaned up our profiles on Amazon and Goodreads for High Performance Python 2nd ed. It is a pity we can&#8217;t do any book signings at events (seeing as we won&#8217;t have physical events for a while!). One thing I might do via my &#8220;<a href="https://ianozsvald.com/data-science-jobs/">thoughts &amp; jobs</a>&#8221; email list is to organise a Friday &#8220;coffee morning&#8221; to chat with whoever turns up about high performance Python and other subjects.</p>
<p>I&#8217;ve also learned that if I make a 1kg sourdough dough, immediately after kneading I can put 0.5kg into the fridge and 4 days later it cooks just fine. This is a nice refinement. I&#8217;m now interspersing buying fresh bread (for variety and convenience) with making my own and it feels like a more sustainable practice.</p>
<p>All going well I&#8217;ll be talking this month at PyDataAmsterdam and next month at EuroPython on higher performance Python and Pandas, I figure the dtype_diet tool will fit in nicely with a discussion about the new Pandas dtypes and their benefits over numpy dtypes.</p>
<hr>
Ian is a Chief Interim Data Scientist via his <a href=http://morconsulting.com>Mor Consulting</a>. Sign-up for <a href=http://eepurl.com/Z44HT>Data Science tutorials in London</a> and to hear about his <a href=https://ianozsvald.com/data-science-jobs/>data science thoughts and jobs</a>. He lives in London, is walked by his high energy Springer Spaniel and is a consumer of fine coffees.]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Week(ish) note</title>
		<link>https://ianozsvald.com/2020/05/20/weekish-note/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ian]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 May 2020 17:31:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Data science]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://ianozsvald.com/?p=3847</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[So &#8211; High Performance Python 2nd ed finally shipped (Amazon, Goodreads) &#8211; yay! In brief we&#8217;ve added notes on how you can be a &#8220;highly performant programmer&#8221;, added some more profiling, added Pandas onto NumPy, improved the Compiling to C chapter with more Numba and a new full section on GPUs (in the first edition [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>So &#8211; High Performance Python 2nd ed finally shipped (<a href="https://amzn.to/2zdDak9">Amazon</a>, <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/49828191-high-performance-python">Goodreads</a>) &#8211; yay! In brief we&#8217;ve added notes on how you can be a &#8220;highly performant programmer&#8221;, added some more profiling, added Pandas onto NumPy, improved the Compiling to C chapter with more Numba and a new full section on GPUs (in the first edition we said &#8211; GPUs are hard, nobody uses them, avoid them &#8211; oh, how the world moved on there!), updated async, JobLib with multiprocessing, multi-core including Dask, less RAM with Pandas and NumPy and four new &#8220;lessons from the field&#8221; from very experienced colleagues (thanks to Soledad, Linda, Vincent and Valentin). I need to write some more about this.</p>
<p>I <a href="https://twitter.com/ianozsvald/status/1263006150385176581">posted it to Twitter</a> and got a lot of lovely feedback.</p>
<p>I&#8217;ve started working on a very interesting project aimed at helping the likes of the Bank of England, the UK Government, the Civil Service and more understand the impact of the pandemic on the UK economy so fixes can be designed. My involvement is just starting, I&#8217;m hoping this will grow in interesting ways.</p>
<p>I put a simple solution into the Kaggle Covid 19 Week 5 competition and on the <a href="https://www.kaggle.com/c/covid19-global-forecasting-week-5/leaderboard">private leaderboard</a> I&#8217;m hovering around rank 10 of 90ish. My solution takes the 5 day moving average and builds wide percentile confidence bounds &#8211; it is really dumb but it turns out to be really robust too.</p>
<p>For now I&#8217;ve cancelled my upcoming courses, life with the pandemic continues to be weird so I&#8217;ve decided to simplify things a bit. They&#8217;ll restart in a few months.</p>
<p>In other news my sourdough baking continues to <a href="https://twitter.com/ianozsvald/status/1263154333518004225">improve</a>, my radishes got pretty big, my lettuce is up, the plums and pears have started to grow and generally the garden is looking awesome. I&#8217;m also working harder at training my Spaniel, we&#8217;ve got a long way to go but having her not try to flush every cat she sees in the street is a huge step forwards.</p>
<hr>
Ian is a Chief Interim Data Scientist via his <a href=http://morconsulting.com>Mor Consulting</a>. Sign-up for <a href=http://eepurl.com/Z44HT>Data Science tutorials in London</a> and to hear about his <a href=https://ianozsvald.com/data-science-jobs/>data science thoughts and jobs</a>. He lives in London, is walked by his high energy Springer Spaniel and is a consumer of fine coffees.]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Week note</title>
		<link>https://ianozsvald.com/2020/05/06/week-note/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ian]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 May 2020 12:41:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Python]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://ianozsvald.com/?p=3840</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Well, mid-next-week note I guess. I gave another variant of my higher performance Python talk last night for PyDataUK to 250 live streamers, we had some good questions, cheers all. On Friday Micha &#38; I heard that the 2nd edition of our Higher Performance Python book has gone to the printers &#8211; we&#8217;d said we&#8217;d [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Well, mid-next-week note I guess. I gave another variant of my higher performance Python talk last night for PyDataUK to 250 live streamers, we had some good questions, cheers all.</p>
<p>On Friday Micha &amp; I heard that the 2nd edition of our Higher Performance Python book has <em>gone to the printers</em> &#8211; we&#8217;d said we&#8217;d do 1 person-month each on it last summer and 9 months later (with many-person-months invested each) we&#8217;re finally there. Phew.</p>
<p>I now have an <a href="https://github.com/dabl/dabl/pull/231">open PR</a> on the dabl project to add ordinal-sorted y-axis box plot items in place of the default always-sort-by-median, which I think makes some of the exploratory process more intuitive. This also involved figuring out a new weird matplotlib rendering behaviour and writing my first unit test where I make up a dummy matplotlib figure in a test which is rendered but never displayed. There&#8217;s always a million new things to learn, right?</p>
<p>I&#8217;ve also been digging into Companies House data to look at how the <a href="https://twitter.com/ianozsvald/status/1257280918944993280">economy</a> is <a href="https://twitter.com/ianozsvald/status/1253236523568332805">responding</a> to the pandemic and this lets me play with some higher performance Pandas operations (for my talks) and to dig into pivot_table, pivot, groupby and crosstab along with stack &amp; unstack in Pandas. I&#8217;ve always been confused about how many options I have available here, I&#8217;m less confused now, but I still don&#8217;t understand some of the performance differences I see for otherwise-equivalent operations. I also discovered the Pandas <a href="https://pandas.pydata.org/pandas-docs/stable/reference/api/pandas.DataFrame.xs.html">xs</a> operation (take a cross-section of a dataframe) whilst reading a wikipedia page on crosstabs. Learning. Always learning.</p>
<p>My <a href="https://twitter.com/ianozsvald/status/1258013685907435520">kneaded sourdough</a> is improving, I&#8217;m up to 1kg now. I think I&#8217;m done with no-knead for a bit, that was fun but the really-wet dough is hard to handle. Radishes are great, pretty big now, but annoyingly the snails have found my lettuce.</p>
<hr>
Ian is a Chief Interim Data Scientist via his <a href=http://morconsulting.com>Mor Consulting</a>. Sign-up for <a href=http://eepurl.com/Z44HT>Data Science tutorials in London</a> and to hear about his <a href=https://ianozsvald.com/data-science-jobs/>data science thoughts and jobs</a>. He lives in London, is walked by his high energy Springer Spaniel and is a consumer of fine coffees.]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
