<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns:yt="http://www.youtube.com/xml/schemas/2015" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
 <link rel="self" href="http://www.youtube.com/feeds/videos.xml?channel_id=UCBn6YYmhnruGtEtlKxYbQ9A"/>
 <id>yt:channel:UCBn6YYmhnruGtEtlKxYbQ9A</id>
 <yt:channelId>UCBn6YYmhnruGtEtlKxYbQ9A</yt:channelId>
 <title>K Klein</title>
 <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCBn6YYmhnruGtEtlKxYbQ9A"/>
 <author>
  <name>K Klein</name>
  <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCBn6YYmhnruGtEtlKxYbQ9A</uri>
 </author>
 <published>2015-10-23T16:03:46+00:00</published>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:4dpRMmoDD6E</id>
  <yt:videoId>4dpRMmoDD6E</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCBn6YYmhnruGtEtlKxYbQ9A</yt:channelId>
  <title>Can Trees TALK?</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4dpRMmoDD6E"/>
  <author>
   <name>K Klein</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCBn6YYmhnruGtEtlKxYbQ9A</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-11-02T12:01:27+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-11-04T08:57:43+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Can Trees TALK?</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/4dpRMmoDD6E?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i1.ytimg.com/vi/4dpRMmoDD6E/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>Weird video for this channel but it was fun to make.
Go to https://establishedtitles.com/KKLEIN and help support the channel (and trees!). They are now running a massive early Black Friday Sale, plus 10% off on any purchase with code KKLEIN. Thanks to Established Titles for sponsoring this video!

Thanks to my patrons!!
Patreon: https://www.patreon.com/user?u=73482298


Sources:

Curwood, S. (Host). (2018). &quot;The Hidden Life of Trees&quot;. Living on Earth, 17/08/2018.

Gagliano, M., Vyazovskiy, V., Borbély, A. et al. (2016). &quot;Learning by Association in Plants&quot;. Sci Rep 6, 38427.

Grant, R. (2018). &quot;Do Trees Talk to Each Other?&quot;. Smithsonian Magazine.

Haskell, D. (2017). The Songs of Trees. Viking Penguin.

Hathaway, M. (2022). What a Mushroom Lives For. Princeton University Press.

Hinchliffe, J. (2018). &quot;Plants hate green thumbs – science backs hands-off gardening approach&quot;. The Sydney Morning Herald.

Mannix, L. (2019). &quot;Can trees learn? The plants are listening in, scientists say&quot;. The Sydney Morning Herald.

McClenaghan, B. (2019). &quot;Talking Trees: How do Trees Communicate?&quot;. Let’s Talk Science.

NOTES
[Note 1] – Note the use of the passive voice here for the tree, as opposed to active for the dog.
[Note 2] – This is specifically about the conception in scientific literature, where an “objective” and “non-sensational” view has been emphasised for a long time. In the popular culture of nations around the world, trees have often been considered “beings”, as is argued in detail in Haskell (2017).

Chapters:
0:00 - Intro
1:37 - Trees Can Talk
3:24 - Debate
4:43 - Conclusion &amp; Credits


Written and created by me
Art &amp; photography by kvd102
Music &amp; additional graphics by me.

Translations:
Leeuwe van den Heuvel - Dutch
Wand_Platte - German

#trees #language</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="2374" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="15479"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:gq5xLI77TGA</id>
  <yt:videoId>gq5xLI77TGA</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCBn6YYmhnruGtEtlKxYbQ9A</yt:channelId>
  <title>Let's Talk About Singular They.</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=gq5xLI77TGA"/>
  <author>
   <name>K Klein</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCBn6YYmhnruGtEtlKxYbQ9A</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-10-14T17:09:25+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-10-31T19:50:41+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Let's Talk About Singular They.</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/gq5xLI77TGA?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i4.ytimg.com/vi/gq5xLI77TGA/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>A sequel to the video: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=iQNdkdqoIdw

Thanks to my patrons!!
Patreon: https://www.patreon.com/user?u=73482298
Special thanks to Calvin for pestering me until I made this video.

Sources:
Baron, D. (1981-2015). The Words that Failed: A chronology of early nonbinary pronouns.
Baron, D. (1986). Grammar and Gender. New Haven.
Baron, D. (2018). A brief history of singular ‘they’. Oxford English Dictionary Blogs.
Fisher, A. (1745). A New Grammar [2nd ed. 1750]. Newcastle upon Tyne.
Gerner, J. (1998). Singular and Plural Anaphors of Indefinite Personal Pronouns in Spoken British English. Corpora Galore: Analyses and Techniques in Describing English: Papers from the Nineteenth International Conference on English Language Research on Computerised Corpora.
Graham, S. (2001). Sulawesi's fifth gender. Inside Indonesia.
McWhorter, J. (1745). The Royal They: Fighting against the tyranny of pronouns. The New Republic.
LaScotte, D. (2016). Singular they: An Empirical Study of Generic Pronoun Use. American Speech. 91 (1): 62–80.
Miller, C. &amp; Swift, K. (1980). The Handbook of Nonsexist Writing. New York. Harper &amp; Row.
Safire, W. (1985). On Language; You Not Tarzan, Me Not Jane. The New York Times.
Wagner, S. (2003). Gender in English Pronouns: Myth and Reality. University of Freiburg.
(1881). Detroit Free Press. May 13 edition.
(2018). Collins COBUILD English Dictionary.
(2022). they. The American Heritage Dictionary of the English Language.
Constitution of the United States of America. Article 1 §2.

Writings mentioned with examples of the singular “they”:
Austen, Jane. (1814). Mansfield Park.
Shakespeare, William. (p. 1623). The Comedy of Errors.
Shaw, George Bernard. (1898). Plays Pleasant and Unpleasant.
Anonymous writer. (c.1350). William and the Werewolf. Translated c. 1350-1375 to English from the original French written c. 1200.

NOTES FROM VIDEO:
[Note 1] When I say “is from”, I am arguing purely from a synchronic perspective – I mean it as a shorthand for the fact that the plural mixed gender and plural masculine are the same, and distinct from the plural feminine in French. I am not making an argument from etymology here.

[Note 2] Wagner argues that “the choice of a supposedly masculine personal pronoun (him) said nothing about the gender or sex of the referent” in Middle English. However, I would argue that the association with the masculine over the feminine still applies. Wagner herself writes that this pronoun can be used for any combination of the genders “masculine” and “neuter”, or sexes “male” and “asexual”, deliberately excluding the “feminine” or “female”. Despite being gender-neutral in some contexts, this pronoun was never epicene, not even in Middle English.

[Note 3] Note, of course, that “man” was originally the word for “human”, and only later came to mean “male adult”. In Old English, “man” was “wer”, and “woman” was “wif”.

[Note 4] Joke.

[Note 5] Note the significantly lower percentages found only three years earlier, in Erdmann (1995), with singular “they” only being used in just under 50% of cases. This study was, firstly, done on Americans, who may be more biased against the singular “they”, and was also a study of written language, reflecting how the singular “they” is often seen as too informal by publishers, and therefore either avoided by authors, or changed by the editors.

[Note 6] Actually, in the examples given from Shakespeare’s Comedy of Errors and Austen’s Mansfield Park, the gender of the referent is known (masculine in the former case, feminine in the latter), but an epicene pronoun is used regardless. Go figure.

[Note 7] I am aware that people have been identifying as non-binary for a long time, even in Europe and colonial America. The sociology and history of this is worth looking into, but I am personally less interested in it and therefore didn’t want to go into the topic in the video.

[Note 8] When it is a subject, this “sie/Sie” can be separated out into “she/feminine it” with the 3rd person singular verb ending, and “they/you” with the 3rd person plural verb ending. In the dative, the same split accords, as the former take the dative “ihr” and the latter the dative “ihnen/Ihnen”. When in the accusative or genitive, there is no difference in spoken language between the four. However, in writing, the formal “you” is distinguished from the others because it, and all its forms, are capitalised.

Chapters:
0:00 – The Epicene “They”
2:48 – The Generic “He”
5:28 – The Non-Binary “They”
7:21 – Credits

Written and Created by me
Art by kvd102
Music by me

Translations:
Ferr - Indonesian
D'ignoranza &amp; Marco Lisoni - Italian
Leeuwe van den Heuvel - Dutch
Gergő Kulman - Hungarian
Ray Karr - Spanish
Ollie - French
千雨 Chisame - Standard Mandarin, Japanese
Risto Kynkäänniemi - Finnish
Jafar - Arabic
Natália - Brazilian Portuguese
Álftanes - Cantonese
Maymun - Turkish
Eneko Andonegi - Basque

#theythem #nonbinary #historyofenglish #pronouns</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="32613" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="230151"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:iQNdkdqoIdw</id>
  <yt:videoId>iQNdkdqoIdw</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCBn6YYmhnruGtEtlKxYbQ9A</yt:channelId>
  <title>In Defence of Grammatical Gender</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=iQNdkdqoIdw"/>
  <author>
   <name>K Klein</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCBn6YYmhnruGtEtlKxYbQ9A</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-09-21T07:00:12+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-10-29T08:47:51+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>In Defence of Grammatical Gender</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/iQNdkdqoIdw?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i2.ytimg.com/vi/iQNdkdqoIdw/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>I finally talk about grammatical gender again – there was so much to say, and I didn’t even get into phonoaesthetics! Talking of aesthetics, sorry for cripplingly bad audio.

Mistakes of the video: &quot;il uomo&quot; is incorrect, it's &quot;l'uomo&quot;. *sigh*. And &quot;kiuri&quot; is a stupid typo, it's &quot;kizuri&quot;.

Contact NMorrag (composer for outro): morragtimemusic@gmail.com
Thanks to my patrons!!
Patreon: https://www.patreon.com/user?u=73482298


Sources:

Alcock, K. (2000). &quot; Grammatical noun class agreement processing in Kiswahili&quot;. Language and Speech.

Boroditsky, L. (2009). &quot;How does our language shape the way we think?&quot;. Edge. [Retrieved 8/09/2022]

Contini-Morava, E. (2000). &quot;Noun Class as Number in Swahili&quot;. Between Grammar and Lexicon. Ed. Contini-Morava, E. &amp; Tobin, Y.

Corbett, G. (2013). &quot;Number of Genders&quot;. The World Atlas of Language Structures Online. Leipzig: Max Planck Institute for Evolutionary Anthropology. [Retrieved 14/09/2022].

Roché, M. (1992). &quot;Le masculin est-il plus productif que le féminin ?&quot;. Langue française (96) 113–124.

Saussure, F. (1916). Cours De Linguistique Générale. Paris: Payot.

Textor, C. (2022). Number of Chinese Communist Party members in China 2010/2021, by gender.

Williams, A., Cotterell, R., Wolf-Sonkin, L., Blasi, D., Wallach, H. (2021). &quot;On the Relationships Between the Grammatical Genders of Inanimate Nouns and Their Co-Occurring Adjectives and Verbs&quot;. Transactions of the Association for Computational Linguistics (9) 139–159.

Office for National Statistics. (2022). Opinions and Lifestyle Survey 16/02/2022 to 13/03/2022.


Videos mentioned (in order of appearance):

https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=46ehrFk-gLk&amp;t=82s by Tom Scott

https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3B_uGsgXKdk by K Klein

https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3AnG3tbwlIw&amp;t=470s by Luke Ranieri

https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7kV_bLrfUxs by Simon Roper


NOTES FROM VIDEO (in order of appearance):

Note 1: Here, I pronounce these words with stress on the prefix rather than the first syllable of the noun stem, where it should be. This was done to emphasise where these words are different; I don’t mean to give the impression that this is how these words should be pronounced in Swahili.

Note 2: I should have said “animate” here, not “m-wa class”, because nouns of other classes are given “m-wa” concords when they are animate. Hence, the speaker can conclude from hearing these concords only that the noun is animate, which narrows the options down to 7-15% of all nouns.

Note 3: Obviously, Mandarin Chinese does have gendered language in the sense that there are words to describe differences in gender. However, it does not have any grammatical gendered language, which English does have – for instance, it would be considered incorrect to refer to a man as “she”. In modern usage, in writing, 他 (he) and 她 (she) are usually differentiated, but this separation only occurred in the 1910s with the coinage of 她.

Note 4: However, note that there are counterexamples to this. In Swahili, many nouns describing people, even when they are in a class other than m-wa (class 1/2), use m-wa concords because their animacy takes priority over their morphological class. For instance, “fundi” (“craftsman”), plural “mafundi”, is placed in the “ma” class (class 5/6) because of how its plural is formed, but still uses m-wa concords.

Note 5: I’m not saying that showing this kind of thing with emphasis is any worse inherently. It does work in English, even in writing with good use of italics. However, in speech it can definitely be confusing, with people often having to repeat themselves. Note that I am arguing from experience here.

Note 6: “iel”, sometimes spelt “ielle”, (accusative “lea”, dative “lui”, emphatic “ellui”) is a French neopronoun meant for use by non-binary people. It is a merger of “il” and “elle” (and the accusative and emphatic forms are also merged from the accusative and emphatic forms of these pronouns).


Chapters:
00:00 – Introduction
01:12 – “Grammatical Gender Carries No Meaning”
02:46 – “… and That’s a Bad Thing”
03:56 – “Grammatical Gender Changes How You Think”
05:57 – “Male”, “Female” and “Neutral”
06:36 – A Misanalysis of What Grammatical Gender Is
10:09 – Trans People and Grammatical Gender
11:50 – Credits

Written and Created by Me
Art by kvd102
Outro Music by NMorrag

Translations:
Luca Massenzio - Italian</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="9128" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="102374"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:3B_uGsgXKdk</id>
  <yt:videoId>3B_uGsgXKdk</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCBn6YYmhnruGtEtlKxYbQ9A</yt:channelId>
  <title>What People Get Wrong About Language - The Ithkuil Fallacy</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3B_uGsgXKdk"/>
  <author>
   <name>K Klein</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCBn6YYmhnruGtEtlKxYbQ9A</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-08-26T10:00:01+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-11-02T12:09:13+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>What People Get Wrong About Language - The Ithkuil Fallacy</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/3B_uGsgXKdk?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i4.ytimg.com/vi/3B_uGsgXKdk/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>Let's talk about the experimental language of Ithkuil, an experiment I carried out, and why anyone would want verb conjugations by person in German.

Sources:

Foer, J. (2012). &quot;Utopian for Beginners&quot;. The New Yorker.

Quijada, J. (2004-2019). &quot;A Grammar of the Ithkuil Language&quot;. ithkuil.net. [Retrieved 12/08/2022]

My study:
https://docs.google.com/document/d/1zluHuv02D9ChxM0BAsnUf9VeIy8aXPeXbOsZNIKm9Ds/edit?usp=sharing


Chapters:
0:00 - Ithkuil
2:03 - The Ithkuil Fallacy
4:02 - My Experiment
5:56 - My Point &amp; Credits

Written and Created by Me
Art by kvd102
Music also by Me
Thanks to everyone who took part in the experiment!

Thanks to my patrons!!
Patreon: https://www.patreon.com/user?u=73482298

JOIN DISCORD SERVER: https://discord.gg/zXfZ9AhDGJ

Translations:
Alex375 - German
@ziekteverwekker - Dutch
Алексей Автономов - Ukrainian
palpatinezw - Standard Mandarin
Rubýn - Spanish</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="9817" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="105629"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:WF9HGsZMWWc</id>
  <yt:videoId>WF9HGsZMWWc</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCBn6YYmhnruGtEtlKxYbQ9A</yt:channelId>
  <title>Duolingo Swedish Speedrun Any% in 03:14</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=WF9HGsZMWWc"/>
  <author>
   <name>K Klein</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCBn6YYmhnruGtEtlKxYbQ9A</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-08-10T23:11:20+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-08-11T06:18:53+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Duolingo Swedish Speedrun Any% in 03:14</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/WF9HGsZMWWc?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i4.ytimg.com/vi/WF9HGsZMWWc/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>A speedrun by me of the Duolingo Swedish course. The speedrun begins the moment I click &quot;Swedish&quot; and ends the moment I hit the trophy at the end of the Swedish course. This is a bad run: I just thought it was a fun video idea and I haven't seen many of them before. Please go ahead and beat this very mediocre record.

I will be uploading a normal video soon, I promise.

#duolingo #speedrun #duolingospeedrun</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="1508" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="18616"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:h3gV89ACgeg</id>
  <yt:videoId>h3gV89ACgeg</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCBn6YYmhnruGtEtlKxYbQ9A</yt:channelId>
  <title>The Diacritics That Look the Same, But Aren't</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=h3gV89ACgeg"/>
  <author>
   <name>K Klein</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCBn6YYmhnruGtEtlKxYbQ9A</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-08-03T12:52:46+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-11-05T15:56:04+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>The Diacritics That Look the Same, But Aren't</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/h3gV89ACgeg?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i1.ytimg.com/vi/h3gV89ACgeg/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>A topic I'm personally interested in. I don't know what you'll think about it, but here you go. ü and ü are different: go figure.
Sorry for the long break since the last video; I got distracted :)

You've convinced me to change the title from &quot;accent&quot; to &quot;diacritic&quot;, well done.


Thanks to my patrons!!
Patreon: https://www.patreon.com/user?u=73482298


Written and Created by Me
Art by kvd102
Music also hastily put together by me

0:00 - Intro
0:57 - Umlaut and Trema
4:12 - Credits

Translations:
Leeuwe van den Heuvel - Dutch
Alex375 - German
vlrfsg - Japanese
Constantin Iosub - Romanian
Carlo Paternoster - Italian
Hugínnn - Danish
YOAV - Hebrew</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="9364" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="114936"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:N3PT_GBL0CQ</id>
  <yt:videoId>N3PT_GBL0CQ</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCBn6YYmhnruGtEtlKxYbQ9A</yt:channelId>
  <title>&quot;Say Your Ts&quot;</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=N3PT_GBL0CQ"/>
  <author>
   <name>K Klein</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCBn6YYmhnruGtEtlKxYbQ9A</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-07-13T11:00:13+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-10-20T01:14:52+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>&quot;Say Your Ts&quot;</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/N3PT_GBL0CQ?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i3.ytimg.com/vi/N3PT_GBL0CQ/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>Low-effort video but still turned out okay. I talk about the /t/ phoneme again, weird how two of my videos are about that, huh?


Thanks to my patrons!!
Patreon: https://www.patreon.com/user?u=73482298


Written and Created by Me
Art by kvd102
Music also hastily put together by me

0:00 - Video
3:25 - Credits</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="13785" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="126482"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:dgryeM9Gfls</id>
  <yt:videoId>dgryeM9Gfls</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCBn6YYmhnruGtEtlKxYbQ9A</yt:channelId>
  <title>English, Furigana, and the Problems of Spelling Reform</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dgryeM9Gfls"/>
  <author>
   <name>K Klein</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCBn6YYmhnruGtEtlKxYbQ9A</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-06-24T11:00:34+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-10-21T15:11:05+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>English, Furigana, and the Problems of Spelling Reform</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/dgryeM9Gfls?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i1.ytimg.com/vi/dgryeM9Gfls/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>Play World of Warships here: https://wo.ws/3tTkkrM
Thank you World of Warships for sponsoring this video.
During registration use the code FIRE to get for free: 200 doubloons, 1 million credits, the Premium Battleship Tier 5 - USS Texas, and 7 Days Premium Account. Applicable to new users only.

Let's ignore the fact that I used narrow transcription for schwa (should have been broad, I know, but I'm not redoing this video AGAIN).
Also I bet you really wish I had that pop filter now after listening to that, right? So Patreon: https://www.patreon.com/user?u=73482298 innit

A sequel to the videos:
https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=lhcjFWseXIM
https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-2ppfDsmfUc
and https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=00LcdxVJahY

Videos about Japanese I referenced:
https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1eyDYbO8--s
https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=bcdYKxHT8kY
https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=s4Ec9t25yH8&amp;t=36s
https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=r7a8OjvViwE

0:00 Intro
2:18 Japanese
3:56 The Reform


Written and Created by Me
Art by kvd102
Music by Me

Thanks to my patrons!!</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="4383" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="46788"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:6Q4Rfk1fCJ4</id>
  <yt:videoId>6Q4Rfk1fCJ4</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCBn6YYmhnruGtEtlKxYbQ9A</yt:channelId>
  <title>Emojis Are Weird (Linguistically Speaking)</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6Q4Rfk1fCJ4"/>
  <author>
   <name>K Klein</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCBn6YYmhnruGtEtlKxYbQ9A</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-06-04T11:22:50+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-11-02T18:58:50+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Emojis Are Weird (Linguistically Speaking)</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/6Q4Rfk1fCJ4?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i3.ytimg.com/vi/6Q4Rfk1fCJ4/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>You know what emojis are. But what ARE emojis, like, linguistically? Well, here's a brief overview. 🤷
Grab AtlasVPN Special deal for 82% OFF at https://get.atlasvpn.com/KKlein 😎. Thanks to AtlasVPN for sponsoring this video.


Sources:

Fahlman, S. (1982). &quot;Original Bboard Thread in which :-) was proposed&quot;. School of Computer Science. Carnegie Mellon University.

Hand, C.J., Kennedy, A., Filik, R. et al. (2022). &quot;Emoji Identification and Emoji Effects on Sentence Emotionality in ASD-Diagnosed Adults and Neurotypical Controls&quot;. Journal of Autism and Developmental Disorders.

Kaye, L., Malone, S., &amp; Wall, H. (2017). &quot;Emojis: Insights, affordances, and possibilities for psychological science&quot;. Trends in Cognitive Sciences, 21(2), 66–68.

Miller, H. (2016). &quot;Investigating the Potential for Miscommunication Using Emoji&quot;. GroupLens Blogs. Available at: https://grouplens.org/blog/investigating-the-potential-for-miscommunication-using-emoji/. [accessed 27/05/2022].

Miller, H., Thebault-Spieker, J., Chang, S., Johnson, I., Terveen, L., &amp; Hecht, B. (2016). &quot;Blissfully happy or ready to fight: Varying Interpretations of Emoji&quot;. GroupLens Research. University of Minnesota.

Sproull, L. &amp; Kiesler, S. (1986). &quot;Reducing Social Context Cues: Electronic Mail in Organizational Communication&quot;. Management Science, 32, 1492-1512.



Chapters:
0:00 - Pictograms
3:01 - Ideograms
4:39 - Why Emojis?
6:14 - What are Emojis?
8:02 - Credits


Written and Created by Me
Art by kvd102
Music by Me

Thanks to my patrons!!
Patreon: https://www.patreon.com/user?u=73482298

Translations:
@ziekteverwekker - Dutch
James Morris-Wyatt - Spanish

#emojis #AtlasVPN #bestvpn</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="9379" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="90521"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:58u5Sa-UVi0</id>
  <yt:videoId>58u5Sa-UVi0</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCBn6YYmhnruGtEtlKxYbQ9A</yt:channelId>
  <title>When the Government Makes You Get a Surname</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=58u5Sa-UVi0"/>
  <author>
   <name>K Klein</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCBn6YYmhnruGtEtlKxYbQ9A</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-05-23T16:07:39+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-11-04T09:05:26+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>When the Government Makes You Get a Surname</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/58u5Sa-UVi0?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i2.ytimg.com/vi/58u5Sa-UVi0/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>A look at the development of modern surnames in Sweden. It's actually pretty interesting if you ask me.

Note this is not an unexhaustive history of surnames in Europe, or even in Sweden.


Sources:

Hedberg, J. (2021). Svenska efternamnsbyten 1920–1944. Bloggen New trends in Nordic Socio-onomastics.

Larsson, I. (2013) Namn och namnforskning. Ett levande läromedel om ortnamn, personnamn och andra namn. Ed. by Staffan Nyström (main ed.), Eva Brylla &amp; al. Version 1. Uppsala.

Noreen, Erik &amp; Adolf. (1907). Svenska familjenamn vid början av 1900-talet. Alfabetisk förteckning jämte statistiska och andra bilagor. Stockholm: Aktiebolaget Ljus.

Ryman, L. (2013) Namn och namnforskning. Ett levande läromedel om ortnamn, personnamn och andra namn. Ed. by Staffan Nyström (main ed.), Eva Brylla &amp; al. Version 1. Uppsala.

Utterström. (1985). Släktnamn. Tillkomst och spridning i norrländska städer. Kungliga skytteanska samfundets handlingar, 29. Umeå: Nyheternas tryckeri.

Willson, K. (2012). Linguistic Models and Surname Diversification Strategies in Denmark and Sweden. Onoma, 47, 299-326.

Lag om personnamn. (SFS 2016:1013) §29 Gårdsnamn.


Chapters:
0:00 - Early Swedish &quot;efternamn&quot;
1:36 - What Surnames did Commoners Have?
4:02 - The Politics of Surnames
6:16 - Made-Up Surnames
6:58 - Ending &amp; Credits


Written and Created by Me
Art by kvd102
Music by P. Almond

Thanks to my patrons!!
Patreon: https://www.patreon.com/user?u=73482298

Translations:
Mias - Portuguese
Leeuwe van den Heuvel - Dutch
pluiedev (w/ help from Anqi Chen) - Standard Mandarin</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="13859" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="259115"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:pXoaE9tZV8k</id>
  <yt:videoId>pXoaE9tZV8k</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCBn6YYmhnruGtEtlKxYbQ9A</yt:channelId>
  <title>Counting the Phonemes in a Language</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=pXoaE9tZV8k"/>
  <author>
   <name>K Klein</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCBn6YYmhnruGtEtlKxYbQ9A</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-05-08T18:54:58+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-10-21T14:48:37+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Counting the Phonemes in a Language</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/pXoaE9tZV8k?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i1.ytimg.com/vi/pXoaE9tZV8k/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>A look at what phonemes are, and how to count them in a language, with a specific look at Standard Chinese. A sequel to my video &quot;Chinese Doesn't Have Many Syllables&quot;: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=BMI6Mbx8lbw

SORRY! The stress in French goes on the second syllable. I literally speak French (ish) I don't know how I would mess that up.

This video gets very technical somewhere around the halfway mark, so don't worry if you don't get all of it.

PLEASE NOTE: there are many, MANY more ways to analyse Standard Chinese phonemes. I'm not saying that these are the only three analyses, nor that they are the three most common, nor that they are the three best. Many of the features presented can be swapped around and pieced together to make new analyses (eg. getting rid of the zero-onset phoneme but not fusing the palatal/retroflex series). This is only meant to be an exercise and some thoughts about phonemic analysis.

Sources:

Chao, Yuen Ren. 1968. A Grammar of Spoken Chinese. Berkeley: University of California Press.

Duanmu, San (2000). The Phonology of Standard Chinese. Oxford: Oxford University Press.

Lee, Wai-Sum; Zee, Eric (2003). &quot;Standard Chinese (Beijing)&quot;. Journal of the International Phonetic Association. 33 (1): 109–112.

0:00 Introduction
1:45 What is a Phoneme?
3:50 Suprasegmental Phonemes
5:05 Segmental Phonemes
5:37 Phonemic Analysis of Standard Chinese
8:21 Ending/Outro


Written and Created by Me
Art by kvd102
Thanks to my patrons!

Patreon: https://www.patreon.com/user?u=73482298</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="5448" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="77138"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:jXjvXAIwgME</id>
  <yt:videoId>jXjvXAIwgME</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCBn6YYmhnruGtEtlKxYbQ9A</yt:channelId>
  <title>Some Italian Nouns Switch Gender (And Why That's Interesting)</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=jXjvXAIwgME"/>
  <author>
   <name>K Klein</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCBn6YYmhnruGtEtlKxYbQ9A</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-04-13T15:30:33+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-11-02T21:19:06+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Some Italian Nouns Switch Gender (And Why That's Interesting)</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/jXjvXAIwgME?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i3.ytimg.com/vi/jXjvXAIwgME/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>A discussion of grammatical gender in the context of the Romance (Latin-descended) languages, with a specific focus on Italian and Romanian. I also go into the origin of some unusual (within the European context) gender features in these languages.

I'm sorry for my pronunciation, especially of Romanian. I tried with the exact amount of effort required to neither be considered lazy nor be scolded for trying too hard and still failing.


Sources:

Bateman, Nicoleta; Polinsky, Maria. &quot;Romanian as a Two-Gender Language&quot;

Petrucci, Peter R. 1993. Slavic features in the history of Romanian. Doctoral dissertation, USC.

Rosetti, Alexandru. 1965. Linguistica. The Hague: Mouton.


The film is &quot;Life of Brian&quot; by Monty Python. And yes, I'm aware that the clip I showed is technically about conjugations and I was technically talking about declensions: don't bully me, it's a funny *reference*.

Written and Created by Me
Art by kvd102
Special thanks to I.M. for all their help with the Romanian and Italian in this video :)

00:00 - L'italiano
00:20 - Grammatical Gender
03:00 - Romanian Grammatical Gender
04:59 - Heterogeneity
05:53 - Latin Grammar Time
06:49 - Conclusion

Translations:
Icaro Vega - Spanish
palpatinezw - Standard Mandarin
Leeuwe van den Heuvel - Dutch</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="5886" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="106294"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:YhSei6U9EZ8</id>
  <yt:videoId>YhSei6U9EZ8</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCBn6YYmhnruGtEtlKxYbQ9A</yt:channelId>
  <title>when you want la croissant</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=YhSei6U9EZ8"/>
  <author>
   <name>K Klein</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCBn6YYmhnruGtEtlKxYbQ9A</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-03-26T15:29:29+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-05-06T06:44:47+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>when you want la croissant</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/YhSei6U9EZ8?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i2.ytimg.com/vi/YhSei6U9EZ8/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>sorry, I'm not funny.
Bonne journée internationale de la Francophonie !
The music is Django Reinhardt: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=obOObJrhIB0

The film is &quot;The French Connection&quot; (1971) by William Friedkin.</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="1870" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="22418"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:6ZXLQNI_HEU</id>
  <yt:videoId>6ZXLQNI_HEU</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCBn6YYmhnruGtEtlKxYbQ9A</yt:channelId>
  <title>&quot;Rhythms&quot; IS Spelt With a Vowel</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6ZXLQNI_HEU"/>
  <author>
   <name>K Klein</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCBn6YYmhnruGtEtlKxYbQ9A</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-03-24T16:00:04+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-10-31T12:23:19+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>&quot;Rhythms&quot; IS Spelt With a Vowel</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/6ZXLQNI_HEU?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i3.ytimg.com/vi/6ZXLQNI_HEU/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>Low-effort video.

Written and Created by Me
Art by kvd102

Translations:
Leeuwe van den Heuvel - Dutch
Ivan - German</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="49180" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="793682"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:-mUv4cRUMdk</id>
  <yt:videoId>-mUv4cRUMdk</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCBn6YYmhnruGtEtlKxYbQ9A</yt:channelId>
  <title>Pronouns That Change By Time (And Why You Shouldn't Find Them Weird)</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-mUv4cRUMdk"/>
  <author>
   <name>K Klein</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCBn6YYmhnruGtEtlKxYbQ9A</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-03-05T18:44:05+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-11-03T22:09:52+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Pronouns That Change By Time (And Why You Shouldn't Find Them Weird)</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/-mUv4cRUMdk?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i2.ytimg.com/vi/-mUv4cRUMdk/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>A discussion of temporal pronouns, in the context of the Senegambian language of Wolof (spoken chiefly in Senegal and the Gambia).

Written and Created by Me
Art by kvd102

Interested in learning Wolof?
Check out Mor Gueye: https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCm5dJZCDO6aWM6inDHwfV9Q

Translations:
Leeuwe van den Heuvel - Dutch</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="4840" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="72045"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
</feed>
