<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" >


<channel>
      <title>Radio Free Asia</title>
      <language >en</language>
      <description></description>
      <link>https://www.rfa.org/english</link>
      <copyright>Radio Free Asia</copyright>
      <image>
            <title>Radio Free Asia</title>
            <url>https://www.rfa.org/++plone++rfa-resources/img/rfa-logo-400.jpg</url>
            <link>https://www.rfa.org/english</link>
      </image>
      
	    <atom:link href="https://www.rfa.org/english/rss2.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
      

	  


  <item>

    <title>German leader broaches human rights in China, but activists wish he went further</title>
    <description>The World Uyghur Congress and other groups say Olaf  Scholz didn’t go far enough during Beijing trip.</description>
    <link>https://www.rfa.org/english/news/uyghur/olaf-scholz-11042022173141.html</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.rfa.org/english/news/uyghur/olaf-scholz-11042022173141.html</guid>
    
        <author>By Roseanne Gerin</author>
    

    

    
            <media:content url="https://www.rfa.org/english/news/uyghur/olaf-scholz-11042022173141.html/@@images/image/social_media" type="jpeg">
              <media:description>German Chancellor Olaf Scholz meets Chinese President Xi Jinping in Beijing, China, Nov. 4, 2022.</media:description>
              <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu">Pool via Reuters</media:credit>
            </media:content>
    
    <content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
        <![CDATA[
        <p><span style="font-weight: 400;">German Chancellor Olaf Scholz briefly addressed human rights while in Beijing on Friday for a meeting with Chinese leaders, but Uyghur and other rights groups said he didn’t go far enough.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Meeting with Communist Party leader after Xi Jinping, who last month began his third five-year term in office, Scholz urged China to stand up for the international order and put pressure on Russia to end its war against Ukraine, according to a </span><a href="https://www.politico.eu/article/olaf-scholz-china-human-rights-g7-russia-ukraine/" rel="noopener" target="_blank"><span style="font-weight: 400;">report</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> by Politico Europe.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">At a joint press conference Friday with Chinese Premier Li Keqiang, Scholz told reporters that he was concerned about China closing off sectors of its international economy to foreign competition and not respecting intellectual property, the report said.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Scholz also called on China to respect human rights, saying Beijing could not escape the international ramifications of its treatment of the Uyghurs in Xinjiang by calling it an internal matter.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Human rights are interference in international affairs,” he said, according to Germany’s Suddeutsche Zeitung.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Later Friday, the Group of Seven foreign ministers, which includes Germany and the United States, issued a </span><a href="https://www.auswaertiges-amt.de/en/newsroom/news/g7-foreign-ministers-statement/2561876#:~:text=We%2C%20the%20G7%20members%2C%20strongly,was%20recklessly%20launched%20over%20Japan." rel="noopener" target="_blank"><span style="font-weight: 400;">statement</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> in Münster, Germany, that touched on China’s human rights record. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“We will continue to raise our concerns with China on its reported human rights violations and abuses, including in Xinjiang and Tibet,” the statement said. “We reiterate our concerns over the continued erosion of Hong Kong’s rights, freedoms and autonomy, and call on China to act in accordance with its international commitments and legal obligations.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Dolkun Isa, president of the World Uyghur Congress, expressed dismay that Scholz touched only briefly on the topic of human rights, and that his accompanying delegation included only business representatives and no human rights experts.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“It is extremely disappointing to state that the genocide of the Uyghurs is due to a different understanding of human rights,” Isa said in the statement. “Germany must now act together with its international partners to hold the Chinese government accountable.”  </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The World Uyghur Congress as well as Tibet Initiative Germany, Freiheit für Hongkong e.V. and the Society for Threatened Peoples criticized Scholz’s entire trip to China, saying that reporters at the news conference were not given an opportunity to ask questions.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Earlier this week, 70 human rights organizations issued an </span><a href="https://www.uyghurcongress.org/en/open-letter-70-civil-society-organisations-urge-german-chancellor-scholz-to-rethink-trip-to-beijing-amidst-human-rights-concerns%ef%bf%bc/" rel="noopener" target="_blank"><span style="font-weight: 400;">open letter</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> urging Scholz to reconsider his trip to China amid growing human rights concerns. They noted that an accompanying delegation of several top German executives implied that Berlin was increasing its economic dependence on an authoritarian government at the expense of democratic principles, including upholding human rights.  </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“The invitation of a German trade delegation to join your visit will be viewed as an indication that Germany is ready to deepen trade and economic links, at the cost of human rights and international law,” they wrote in the memo, published by Germany-based World Uyghur Congress. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In calling for Scholz to reconsider his visit, the groups said: “This would send the clearest signal that Germany, as one of the leading members of the European Union, will not offer its tacit endorsement to the ongoing oppression of Uyghurs, Hong Kongers, Tibetans, and other groups within and outside the PRC’s borders,” using the initials for the People’s Republic of China, the country’s formal name.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The United States and several Western parliaments have said China’s mistreatment of the Uyghurs, including mass arbitrary detentions, torture and forced labor, amounts to genocide and crimes against humanity. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">A damning report issued by the U.N.’s human rights chief in late August documented widespread rights abuses in Xinjiang and said the repression “may constitute international crimes, in particular crimes against humanity.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Later on Monday, when a reporter at a regular news conference asked Chinese Foreign Ministry spokesman Zhao Lijian if the two leaders discussed issues related to human rights and the rights of ethnic minorities in Xinjiang, he said</span> <span style="font-weight: 400;">China had issued a </span><a href="https://www.fmprc.gov.cn/eng/zxxx_662805/202211/t20221104_10800546.html" rel="noopener" target="_blank"><span style="font-weight: 400;">readout</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> about the meeting. But the document made no mention of the Uyghurs, Xinjiang or human rights.</span></p>
        ]]>
    </content:encoded>

    <pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2022 17:36:00 -0400</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>

    <title>Interview: “Freedom and democracy won’t come without effort”</title>
    <description>Vietnamese lawyer Ngo Anh Tuan speaks to RFA about human rights objectives</description>
    <link>https://www.rfa.org/english/news/vietnam/vietnam-lawyer-11042022172222.html</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.rfa.org/english/news/vietnam/vietnam-lawyer-11042022172222.html</guid>
    

    

    
            <media:content url="https://www.rfa.org/english/news/vietnam/vietnam-lawyer-11042022172222.html/@@images/image/social_media" type="jpeg">
              <media:description>In this Oct. 2, 2013, photo, a security officer tries to stop a photographer working close to a courtroom in Hanoi, Vietnam.</media:description>
              <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu">Source: AP</media:credit>
            </media:content>
    
    <content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
        <![CDATA[
        <p><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Vietnamese lawyer Ngo Anh Tuan spoke to RFA about a Nov. 1 meeting with U.S. officials in the run-up to the 26th U.S.-Vietnam Human Rights Dialogue. </span></i></p>
<p></p>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">On Nov. 1, Vietnamese rights lawyer Ngo Anh Tuan attended a meeting between representatives from the U.S. State Department, the U.S. Embassy in Hanoi, the U.S. Consulate in Ho Chi Minh City and family members of several jailed political dissidents at the eve of the 26th U.S.-Vietnam Human Rights Dialogue held on Nov. 2. Radio Free Asia spoke to him about the meeting on Nov. 3. The interview has been edited for brevity and clarity. </span></i></p>
<p></p>
<p><b>RFA: What were your recommendations for the U.S. government at the meeting regarding human rights in Vietnam?</b></p>
<p></p>
<p><b>Ngo Anh Tuan:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  The meeting was held on the eve of the annual U.S.-Vietnam Human Rights Dialogue. I came to the meeting at their [the U.S. government’s] invitation and was the only lawyer there. I can’t repeat what I said verbatim but here are the key things that I raised:</span></p>
<p></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Firstly, Vietnam should hold dialogues with political dissidents and utilize their knowledge and talents for the country’s development. President Ho Chi Minh did this after establishing the Democratic Republic of Vietnam, which had been seen as an appropriate policy. Unfortunately, they [the current Vietnamese government] don’t do it now.</span></p>
<p></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Secondly, [Vietnam] has to amend or remove the harsh provisions relating to freedom of speech in its current Penal Code as they contradict Vietnam’s 2013 Constitution and human rights treaties to which Vietnam is a signatory.</span></p>
<p></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Thirdly, [Vietnam] must immediately stop using its Departments of Information and Communications (DOICs) to assess people’s thoughts and ideologies and accuse them [instead of] investigation and procuracy agencies and judges. As long as these practices aren’t eliminated, DOIC assessors should be summoned to trials to clarify what they have assessed and respond to defense lawyers. Currently, DOIC assessors avoid attending hearings. While the current law stipulates that all the evidence to accuse a defendant must be clarified at the trial, I’ve never seen any judiciary assessors at any trials that I have attended.</span></p>
<p></p>
<p><b>RFA: Were there any lawyers giving similar recommendations? What are your expectations for the implementation of these recommendations?</b></p>
<p></p>
<p><b>Ngo Anh Tuan: </b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> I did not ask how many lawyers they had invited but I was the only lawyer at the meeting.</span></p>
<p></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I don’t expect all of my recommendations will be implemented right away as it would be too ambitious for a dialogue like this. It would also be challenging to realize the easiest thing in my first recommendation. Some minor issues can be done at the moment.</span></p>
<p></p>
<p><b>RFA: Suppose they could only implement one of the three recommendations, which one would you like to prioritize?</b></p>
<p></p>
<p><b>Ngo Anh Tuan:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> We want all of them to be implemented. However, what I think they can do now is the third one, i.e., the assessment of people’s thoughts and ideologies. I believe people from investigative agencies, the procuracy and the courts realize this legal flaw. If assessors are allowed to [freely] make accusations, they will be able to easily charge people for so many things. It is unacceptable that they [the assessors] examine the ideological side and then conclude the objective side of a crime. By doing so, they have made accusations before [the judicial system]. This goes against all legal principles of both Vietnam and the world.</span></p>
<p></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Lawyers have raised this issue many times with them and I think they also want a change. However, they won’t be able to do so if the current regulations are not amended.</span></p>
<p></p>
<p><b>RFA: Lawyers often encounter unpleasant or even illegal acts from authorities. Why didn’t you raise this issue in your recommendations?</b></p>
<p></p>
<p><b>Ngo Anh Tuan: </b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> I think the oppression against lawyers is not that serious but the disrespect for lawyers is a matter of fact. However, we [lawyers] put clients’ interests before ours. If we face difficulties, we still can fight against them while our clients are in much more disadvantaged situations. Our clients and ordinary people out there are much more vulnerable and disadvantaged than us. It is more appropriate for the Vietnam Bar Federation or provincial bar associations to speak up for lawyers' rights. I choose to speak up for people's rights as people's interests should outweigh lawyers'.</span></p>
<p></p>
<p><b>RFA:  You have said that freedom and democracy won’t come without effort and we have to create them and create opportunities for people around us instead of waiting for others to bring freedom and democracy to us. Could you elaborate on this?</b></p>
<p></p>
<p><b>Ngo Anh Tuan:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">  I believe most intellectuals are knowledgeable enough to realize this but they may think this is someone else’s job, not theirs. They also understand that we need to join hands to make the country a better place but they also think it’s OK if that does not include their hands. A Vietnamese saying goes: “Lead the charge if it’s a party. Follow others if it’s a march across waters.” They would think: As the pioneers have raised their hand, we can stand behind them and will raise our hand when success is almost there.</span></p>
<p></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Politics is not something super. It affects everyone, including us and our family members. For example, an inappropriate administrative decision creates difficulties for ordinary people, including us. Familiar things like land and salary issues are also politics. Society will be better if everyone speaks up against injustice and wrongdoings. Everyone can make contributions but many chose to forgo their rights. If everyone thinks we don’t need to speak up since the person next to us will do it, society, of course, will be at a standstill.</span></p>
<p></p>
<p><b>RFA:  Do you hope that human rights in Vietnam will be improved after each human rights dialogue between the U.S. and Vietnam?</b></p>
<p></p>
<p><b>Ngo Anh Tuan: </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">In this meeting, an officer asked me if they [the U.S. government] could help in any way. I bluntly asked back: Why did you ask that question? Can you really help?</span></p>
<p></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I also attended a similar meeting with the EU’s representatives before their human rights dialogue with Vietnam which seems to not have borne many fruits. Meanwhile, Ms. Erin Barclay, a senior official from the U.S. Bureau of Democracy, Human Rights and Labor, was very enthusiastic. She said that the U.S. government shared my thoughts and that she would make every effort regardless of whether the issue is small or big. She said she hoped that Vietnam would make progress and that positive changes would come.</span></p>
<p></p>
<p><b><i>RFA: </i></b><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Thank you very much.</span></i></p>
<p></p>
        ]]>
    </content:encoded>

    <pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2022 17:22:39 -0400</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>

    <title>Biden: U.S. chip subsidies are key for national security</title>
    <description>Chinese reaction to new policies may follow U.S. midterm elections and Biden-Xi meeting at G-20, experts say.</description>
    <link>https://www.rfa.org/english/news/china/biden-chips-act-11042022165531.html</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.rfa.org/english/news/china/biden-chips-act-11042022165531.html</guid>
    
        <author>Alex Willemyns for RFA</author>
    

    

    
            <media:content url="https://www.rfa.org/english/news/china/biden-chips-act-11042022165531.html/@@images/image/social_media" type="jpeg">
              <media:description>Employees make microchips at a factory of Jiejie Semiconductor Company in Nantong, in eastern China's Jiangsu province on March 17, 2021</media:description>
              <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu">AFP</media:credit>
            </media:content>
    
    <content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
        <![CDATA[
        <p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The $52 billion in recent subsidies for America’s microchip sector are necessary for U.S. national security, President Joe Biden said on Friday, recalling a visit he made to a Lockheed Martin facility that he said could not source the chips it needed to make key weapons.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The speech came as industry leaders told a trade event that American and Chinese chipmakers were both still assessing the likely impacts of the spate of recent U.S. policies impacting the chip industry, with Beijing likely weighing retaliatory measures.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Speaking in San Diego, California, Biden said the subsidies, part of the </span><a href="https://www.rfa.org/english/news/china/usa-chips-10142022154807.html"><span style="font-weight: 400;">$280-billion CHIPS Act</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> signed into law Aug. 9, were needed to restore U.S. capacity to fabricate chips that he said “power more and more of what we need,” including smartphones, cars and hospital equipment.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“America invented the computer chip, and led the industry for decades. Then something happened,” Biden said. “American companies went overseas for cheaper labor; American manufacturing got hollowed out.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The United States couldn’t afford to rely on foreign supply chains, he said, due to the risks posed by pandemics or by “political decisions made in China, Taiwan or other places.” Such a reliance was already being exposed by U.S. efforts to arm Ukraine in its fight against Russian President Vladimir Putin’s invasion of the country, Biden added.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“This is also a national security issue,” he said. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">"Earlier this year, I went down to a Lockheed factory in Alabama. They make Javelin missiles. Guess what? </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">They were having trouble supplying Javelin missiles to Ukraine, because they didn't have the chips. We didn’t have the chips to help [Ukrainians] defend themselves against Putin.”</span></p>
<p><strong>Changing industry</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The $52 billion in subsidies under the CHIPS Act have been paired with a series of export controls meant to cut China off from U.S. technologies.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Announced Oct. 13 by the Department of Commerce’s Bureau of Industry and Security, the rules require licenses to export chip-making technology to 28 listed Chinese entities. They target Beijing’s ability “to obtain advanced computing chips, develop and maintain supercomputers, and manufacture advanced semiconductors,” </span><a href="https://www.federalregister.gov/documents/2022/10/13/2022-21658/implementation-of-additional-export-controls-certain-advanced-computing-and-semiconductor"><span style="font-weight: 400;">the new rules</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> say.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The slow drip of new rules against a backdrop of massive subsidies has upended a global industry that is now worth more than $600 billion a year, according to World Semiconductor Trade Statistics.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">At an event hosted by the Washington International Trade Association earlier on Friday, Jimmy Goodrich, vice president of global policy at the Semiconductor Industry Association, said the U.S. chip industry was still taking stock of the likely impact of all the new rules and subsidies.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“It’s really been a very busy, chaotic few weeks for the private sector to try to understand the scope of the rules, but also to understand how they’re going to move forward in the short, medium and long term,” Goodrich said, noting the policies arrived amid a cyclical industry downturn.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Some private sector firms have announced forecasts next year where they might see a decline in revenue by $1 billion to $2.5 billion per company, so this is a significant set of rules in terms of commercial impact,” he said. “And of course, firms in China are struggling.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Exacerbating concerns among American chipmakers has been the unilateral nature of the export controls, with some firms worried about a vacuum forming in the Chinese market that could be filled by producers in Europe and Asia. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">A U.S. official said last month that </span><a href="https://www.rfa.org/english/news/china/china-chips-10272022151919.html"><span style="font-weight: 400;">he is confident</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> a multilateral deal will soon be struck, but Commerce Secretary Gina Raimondo told firms on Thursday that it could take <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2022-11-03/us-chipmaking-gear-makers-told-to-wait-for-relief-on-china-curbs">nine months</a></span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Melissa Duffy, a partner for trade and national security at the Silicon Valley law firm Fenwick &amp; West, said while many expect the United States to bring major chip makers like the Netherlands and Japan into an export control deal, the U.S. can act unilaterally in the meantime.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“The Commerce Department has expanded its jurisdiction with this rule to capture more things that are made outside the United States,” Duffy said at the Washington International Trade Association event, adding that many European and Asian chip firms rely on U.S. technology.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“So something that could be made in Europe – for instance, in the Netherlands – or made in Japan or South Korea that may not have any U.S. content in it … could still be subject to these rules if the products are based on U.S.-origin technology or software,” she said.</span></p>
<p><strong>Threat of blowback</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The question of China’s response also remains. So far, Beijing has slammed the U.S. export controls as being part of a “Cold War” mentality, but has otherwise refrained from introducing retaliatory measures.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Paul Trio, the director of international standards at SEMI, a global industry association representing electronics makers, told the event that Beijing was likely weighing its response until after next week, with key elections in the United States in Biden and Chinese President Xi Jinping expected to meet on the sidelines of the G-20 meeting in Bali.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“The Chinese response is going to wait until after the U.S. midterms, and then after the Biden-Xi summit, before we can see something a little more public and maybe a little stronger,” Trio said, suggesting Beijing could limit exports of rare earths, magnets or electric vehicle components. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Any action there would have a lot of downside for Chinese companies and for China, too,” he said. “They’re considering all these things, but there’s a whole host of other things they can do, like regulatory changes or investigating U.S. companies, to send a clear message on this.”</span></p>
        ]]>
    </content:encoded>

    <pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2022 16:57:00 -0400</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>

    <title>4 years on, some survivors of Laos dam collapse still waiting for promised new homes</title>
    <description>Authorities have been slow to deliver on pledges of compensation and houses after 2018 disaster.</description>
    <link>https://www.rfa.org/english/news/laos/new-homes-11042022161259.html</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.rfa.org/english/news/laos/new-homes-11042022161259.html</guid>
    
        <author>By RFA Lao</author>
    

    

    
            <media:content url="https://www.rfa.org/english/news/laos/new-homes-11042022161259.html/@@images/image/social_media" type="jpeg">
              <media:description>New permanent homes for survivors of flooding from a 2018 saddle dam collapse at the Xe Pian-Xe Namnoy hydropower plant are seen in southern Laos in 2021.</media:description>
              <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu">Citizen journalist</media:credit>
            </media:content>
    
    <content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
        <![CDATA[
        <p><span style="font-weight: 400;">More than four years after a huge dam collapsed in southern Laos, sweeping away homes and flooding villages, about 100 families are still waiting for the houses and full compensation that authorities promised them. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Instead, they’re living in small, temporary shelters that many describe as inadequate and unstable. They say officials tell them the houses, promised for September, will be ready in December, but they’re not holding their breath.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“The handover of our homes has been postponed,” said one villager who, like other sources, requested anonymity for safety reasons. “It’s now already November, and we’re still waiting for our new homes.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The July 23, 2018, collapse of the saddle dam at the Xe Pian-Xe Namnoy hydropower plant in Attapeu province killed 71 people and displaced more than 14,400.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Authorities pledged to build new homes for them, pay compensation and provide one to two hectares of arable land so farmers could make a living by growing rice and vegetables. Some 700 houses have been built, and many residents have been resettled, but about 100 families are still waiting, displaced villagers said.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Lao government, which continues to plan and build hydropower dams at blistering speed despite grappling with crushing debt, has yet to rectify the problem, villagers said.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Based on the latest relief and recovery plan, Lao authorities are scheduled to complete the construction of all new permanent homes this year. The Xe Pian-Xe Namnoy Power Co. is financing the entire project at a cost of 828 billion kip, or roughly U.S.$50 million.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Another villager recalled that authorities said they would finish building all new homes and hand them over to their owners in October, but all residents of Tamayod village and Samong-Tai village are still in limbo.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“The homes have not been completed yet,” he said. “They still live in the metal shelters as usual.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Around the </span><a href="https://www.rfa.org/english/news/laos/pnpc-4-07232022091740.html" rel="noopener" target="_blank"><span style="font-weight: 400;">fourth anniversary</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> of the disaster, Laotians affected by the flooding told RFA that while four years have been a sufficient amount of time to rebuild the saddle dam, survivors have been unable to rebuild their lives, given the lack of suitable temporary accommodations and delayed or reduced payments.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In </span><a href="https://www.rfa.org/english/news/laos/flooded-farmland-08122022174213.html" rel="noopener" target="_blank"><span style="font-weight: 400;">August</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, other survivors told RFA that they were still struggling to scratch out a living because much of the farmland that was underwater remained unusable. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Attapeu’s provincial governor told Lao media in early September that since the disaster, officials had completed “the most important work” by improving the living conditions of the survivors.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Work on building the remaining permanent houses is slow due to a lack of manpower, said another Laotian who lost a home during the disaster. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“From my observation, the construction of the permanent homes is too slow and has been delayed because only a few people are working on it,” he said. “I go looking at my [new] home often, and it’s not yet finished.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“They said that all new homes will be completed in December this year,” the source added.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The villager went on to say that government officials have not paid the sixth and final round of compensation to those affected by the dam collapse.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“They said we’ll get paid sometime in December, but I think our chances of getting it next month are very slim,” he said.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">An Attapeu province official acknowledged that the construction of the remaining permanent houses has been delayed.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“We will have to postpone the handover of the homes from October to December [because of] a shortage of workers,” he told RFA Thursday.  “The workers say they’re having trouble getting paid.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Authorities will pay the final round of compensation to affected villagers in December, he said, adding that officials are working on the matter with the Xe Pian-Xe Namnoy Power Company.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“If the company agrees with the new assessment [of the property losses], then the survivors will get compensated for the last time in the upcoming month,” the official said. “If not, we’ll have to do a new assessment. First of all, we’re speeding up the construction of the homes, then we’ll pay the compensation.”</span></p>
<p><b><i>Translated by Max Avary for RFA Lao. Written in English by Roseanne Gerin.</i></b></p>
        ]]>
    </content:encoded>

    <pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2022 16:27:13 -0400</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>

    <title>In Xinjiang, a scramble to contain COVID</title>
    <description>Satellite images and leaked videos suggest officials have struggled to contain infections.</description>
    <link>https://www.rfa.org/english/news/uyghur/xinjiang-covid-11042022154717.html</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.rfa.org/english/news/uyghur/xinjiang-covid-11042022154717.html</guid>
    
        <author>By RFA Uyghur</author>
    

    

    
            <media:content url="https://www.rfa.org/english/news/uyghur/xinjiang-covid-11042022154717.html/@@images/image/social_media" type="jpeg">
              <media:description>This quarantine facility is located on the outskirts of Xinjiang’s second-largest city, Korla. Based on satellite imagery analyzed by RFA, construction began between Sept. 15 and Sept. 20, 2022.</media:description>
              <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu">Credit: Screenshot from citizen journalist video</media:credit>
            </media:content>
    
    <content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
        <![CDATA[
        <p><span>Images taken from videos obtained by RFA Uyghur Service, show a new, prefabricated quarantine facility in Xinjiang in China’s west. <u><a href="https://wjw.xinjiang.gov.cn/hfpc/tzgg/202211/8a774377718a4eaa80d545bf4b5df3fc.shtml">Official figures</a></u> released by the government indicate only a couple of dozen new, symptomatic cases each day in the region, which has a population of nearly 26 million. </span></p>
<p><span>But the construction of the facility, along with a slew of videos from the region posted on social media, suggest a broader outbreak.</span></p>
<p><span>In the video below, for example, an animated Ma Zhijun, the Chinese Communist Party secretary in Urumqi, Xinjiang’s capital, orders officials to send people who test positive for the virus and anyone they had contact with into quarantine.</span></p>
<p><span>"Tonight the venues that have water, electricity and heat are all fine,” Ma Zhijun says in the video, which was posted to Twitter and YouTube on Oct. 20. “There’s not any limitation on the conditions.”</span></p>
<p><span>He says he was acting on behalf of Xinjiang Communist Party Secretary Ma Xingrui, who at the time was in Beijing for China’s 20<sup>th</sup> party congress, an event that was closely watched around the world. An outbreak may have embarrassed President Xi Jinping who continued to promote his zero-COVID policy as he was granted a <u><a href="https://www.rfa.org/english/news/china/china-congress-10232022161016.html">precedent-breaking third term</a></u> as party leader.</span></p>
<p><span>RFA was unable to independently verify the authenticity of the videos.  </span></p>
<p></p><div class="videoWrapper">
<iframe itemprop="video" src="https://cdnapisec.kaltura.com/p/1251832/sp/125183200/embedIframeJs/uiconf_id/33053471/partner_id/1251832?iframeembed=true&amp;playerId=kaltura_player&amp;entry_id=1_e3101fnl&amp;flashvars[streamerType]=auto"></iframe>
</div>
<p><span>Furtively shot clips have also surfaced online offering additional evidence of a rushed response to contain an outbreak.</span></p>
<p><span>The video below shows a quick scan of a dirty floor in what a woman’s voice describes as a middle school that had been turned into a makeshift quarantine facility.</span></p>
<p><span>“It has been three days already,” she says. “They have not given us any nuclei test. They bring food, shut the door and leave. Look at this filthy restroom.”</span></p>
<p><span><div class="videoWrapper">
<iframe itemprop="video" src="https://cdnapisec.kaltura.com/p/1251832/sp/125183200/embedIframeJs/uiconf_id/33053471/partner_id/1251832?iframeembed=true&amp;playerId=kaltura_player&amp;entry_id=1_fmfsq16x&amp;flashvars[streamerType]=auto"></iframe>
</div></span></p>
<p><span>The following 15-second clip — uploaded onto Chinese social media app Duoyin after the clip of the secretary leaked — suggests rough quarantine conditions weren’t isolated. It shows at least nine people lying on the floor of what appears to be a bathroom.</span></p>
<p><span>The video was harvested online by <u><a href="https://www.rfa.org/english/news/uyghur/interview-inmate-09242019174449.html">Zumret Dawut</a></u>, a Uyghur exile in the United States and activist who was imprisoned in a camp in Xinjiang, before it was removed from the app.</span></p>
<p><span></span><span><div class="videoWrapper">
<iframe itemprop="video" src="https://cdnapisec.kaltura.com/p/1251832/sp/125183200/embedIframeJs/uiconf_id/33053471/partner_id/1251832?iframeembed=true&amp;playerId=kaltura_player&amp;entry_id=1_w880rfr3&amp;flashvars[streamerType]=auto"></iframe>
</div></span></p>
<p><span>A fourth video obtained by RFA shows a man passing his camera over a large room in what he says is a local energy company’s building. He estimates there are as many as 1,000 people, which the clip shows are packed closely together on cots.</span></p>
<p><span>“No medicine is given out here,” he says.</span></p>
<p><span><div class="videoWrapper">
<iframe itemprop="video" src="https://cdnapisec.kaltura.com/p/1251832/sp/125183200/embedIframeJs/uiconf_id/33053471/partner_id/1251832?iframeembed=true&amp;playerId=kaltura_player&amp;entry_id=1_i90pqyrd&amp;flashvars[streamerType]=auto"></iframe>
</div></span><span></span></p>
<p><span>China’s strategy for containing COVID has led to complaints of harsh treatment across the country, including in Shanghai, where after weeks of being confined to their homes, residents in April shouted out of their windows and <u><a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/av/world-asia-china-61270616">banged pots in protest</a></u>.</span></p>
<p><span>Last month, <u><a href="https://www.rfa.org/english/news/tibet/lhasa-10272022165739.html">demonstrations in Tibet</a></u> of Han Chinese migrants and native Tibetans over a lockdown resulted in Chinese authorities allowing the migrants to return to their homes. RFA <u><a href="https://www.rfa.org/english/news/tibet/tibet-detentions-11032022151829.html">reported </a></u>that Chinese authorities detained around 200 Lhasa residents in the wake of the protest in the Tibetan regional capital.</span></p>
<p><span>In Xinjiang, Chinese officials imposed strict lockdowns in August and September. <u><a href="https://www.rfa.org/english/news/uyghur/hundreds-detained-09132022165944.html">RFA reported</a></u> that 600 Uyghurs from a village in Ghulja in the northern part of Xinjiang were detained after they protested a lockdown that, according to some locals, had resulted in the deaths from starvation of as many as a dozen residents.</span></p>
<p><span>Uyghurs and other Turkic minorities in the region have also been subjected to a years-long crackdown as part of a broad “anti-terrorism” campaign. <u><a href="https://www.ohchr.org/sites/default/files/documents/countries/2022-08-31/22-08-31-final-assesment.pdf">A U.N. report </a></u>in August said China’s effort to Sinicize the region has included human rights abuses and potential crimes against humanity. China denounced the report, which it said was the result of pressure from western governments.</span></p>
<p><span>Prior to the September protest, state-run Xinjiang TV had warned residents that they would be arrested for separatism, a charge often used to detain Uyghurs, if they “spread rumors” about a COVID outbreak in the area.</span><span></span></p>
        ]]>
    </content:encoded>

    <pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2022 16:16:00 -0400</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>

    <title>China moves to take control of private tech firms with 'joint venture' deals</title>
    <description>The move is a significant departure from market-oriented economic policies of the last four decades, analysts say.</description>
    <link>https://www.rfa.org/english/news/china/ventures-11042022140146.html</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.rfa.org/english/news/china/ventures-11042022140146.html</guid>
    
        <author>By Gu Ting and Hwang Chun-mei for RFA Mandarin, Cheryl Tung for RFA Cantonese</author>
    

    

    
            <media:content url="https://www.rfa.org/english/news/china/ventures-11042022140146.html/@@images/image/social_media" type="jpeg">
              <media:description>A man walks past the Tencent headquarters in Shenzhen, in China's southern Guangdong province, July 10, 2022.</media:description>
              <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu">AFP</media:credit>
            </media:content>
    
    <content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
        <![CDATA[
        <p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In a major departure from the market-oriented economic policy of the past 40 years, the Chinese Communist Party is moving to take greater control of technology and telecoms companies, with a return to the era of "joint ventures" between the state and private sector.</span></p>
<p></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">China's market regulatory body approved a new joint venture between the investment arm of state-owned telecoms giant China Unicom and tech giant Tencent, the agency said in an announcement on its official website last week.</span></p>
<p></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The joint venture was "based on the strategic needs of the company’s comprehensive advancement into the digital economy," according to statements filed by China Unicom to the Shanghai and Hong Kong stock exchanges.</span></p>
<p></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Tencent brings to the deal a massive amount of data gleaned from its WeChat super app that provides social media, payments and messaging services to 1.4 billion people in China and beyond.</span></p>
<p></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">However, Unicom Innovation Venture Capital will hold a 48% stake compared with Tencent subsidiary Shenzhen Tencent Industry Venture Capital's 42% stake, the state-run Global Times newspaper reported.</span></p>
<p></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Meanwhile, the Shanghai subsidiary of China Mobile signed a strategic cooperation agreement on Nov. 1 with e-commerce giant JD.com's subsidiary JD Technology.</span></p>
<p></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The goal of that joint venture is smart city technology, digital governance, big data and communications, Shanghai Securities News reported.</span></p>
<p></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Sources familiar with the private sector in China said further similar deals are expected by year's end, with major private tech firms assigned a state-owned "partner," meaning the state will effectively take control of at least some of their assets.</span></p>
<p></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The move follows a </span><a href="https://www.rfa.org/english/news/china/tech-crackdown-09062021151158.html"><span style="font-weight: 400;">regulatory crackdown on privately owned tech giants</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> in recent years. </span></p>
<p></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In July 2021, state-owned assets spokesman Peng Huagang said his agency would press ahead with </span><a href="https://www.rfa.org/english/news/china/tech-07192021134345.html"><span style="font-weight: 400;">"mergers" between private sector and state-owned companies</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, with takeovers implemented both by paid acquisitions and uncompensated nationalization, as well as share transfers. </span></p>
<p></p>
<figure><img alt="ENG_CHN_PlannedEconomy_11042022.2.JPG" class="image-richtext image-inline" src="https://www.rfa.org/english/news/china/eng_chn_plannedeconomy_11042022-2.jpg/@@images/890c15aa-72f4-44e4-9d8f-d4631903b064.jpeg" title="ENG_CHN_PlannedEconomy_11042022.2.JPG"/>
<figcaption>Huang Guangyu, chairman of GOME Electrical Appliances Holding Ltd., shown in this 2006 file photo, and his wife are selling off their shares in their private retail empire GOME. Credit: Reuters</figcaption>
</figure>
<p><b>Accelerating nationalization</b></p>
<p></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Hangzhou-based scholar Chang Yu said the nationalization process now appears to be accelerating in the wake of the Chinese Communist Party's 20th National Congress last month. </span></p>
<p></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">"Everyone knows that this public-private 'partnership' only works in one direction," Chang told RFA. "Even before the party congress, the government was moving against [what they termed] the disorderly expansion of capital, and stopped allowing private companies to expand."</span></p>
<p></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">"Now the party congress is over, they can speed up that process and take more drastic steps."</span></p>
<p></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Beijing-based commentator Wu Qiang said the moves are another indicator that Chinese leader Xi Jinping is taking China away from the market reforms introduced by late supreme leader Deng Xiaoping in 1979, and in the direction of a state-controlled economy similar to that of the Mao era.</span></p>
<p></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">"This heralds an era of a planned economy as mentioned in [Xi Jinping's] report to the 20th party congress," Wu told RFA. "This will place private capital, particularly Tencent and JD.com, under the control of the government in Beijing."</span></p>
<p></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">"Looking at the shareholding structure, it seems to be a hybrid kind of joint venture driven by ideology," he said.</span></p>
<p></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Wu said it was made clear during the party congress that nobody should be lobbying to protect or endorse major private companies.</span></p>
<p></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">"The last protections and lobbying [attempts] for these huge online platforms have been removed," he said.</span></p>
<p></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Current affairs commentator Ma Ju said the purpose of the joint ventures was to ensure state control of resources and technology.</span></p>
<p></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">"The aim of the cooperation agreements between China Unicom and Tencent and China Mobile and JD.com is [state] control over the flow of information and materials," Ma told RFA. "For [the Chinese Communist Party], anything relating to the internet is a matter of national security."</span></p>
<p></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">"They are controlling these companies in exactly the way they did back in 1953, through public-private 'partnerships,’" he said.</span></p>
<p></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Political commentator Jiang Feng said some private companies could eventually be eliminated.</span></p>
<p></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">"Private enterprises encourage a market economy, which goes against totalitarian rule, so they must be restricted or even eliminated," he told RFA's Asia Wants to Talk chat show.</span></p>
<p></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">"They are laying the groundwork for a command economy."</span></p>
<p></p>
<p><b>China’s wealthy looking for an out</b></p>
<p></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Reports are emerging that China's wealthiest people are getting the message, with home electronics magnate Huang Guangyu and his wife selling off their shares in their private retail empire GOME, cashing out to the tune of H.K. $960 million (U.S. $122.3 million) and reducing the size of their stake from 51.5% to 42.8% across the course of this year.</span></p>
<p></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Nanjing-based retailer Xu Jing said many wealthy business owners are highly pessimistic about their future in China, and will leave if they can.</span></p>
<p></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">"Wanting to leave and being allowed to leave aren't necessarily the same thing ... because [entrepreneurs may now be] on a government [border] control list because they have a lot of debt," Xu said. "Particularly real estate bosses."</span></p>
<p></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Changsha-based real estate insider Tian Hui gave a similar account. "Business is not good now; earnings are low, yet expenditures are ongoing," he said. "Returns are too slow, and there are bank loans [to pay back]."</span></p>
<p></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">"[The wealthy] have been selling off famous artworks and properties ever since 2019, and they are taking the money to the United States to buy land and build properties there," he said.</span></p>
<p></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Scholar Ma Hong said in a joking reference to a 1980s Chinese rock anthem by Cui Jian, "Rock and Roll on the New Long March." </span></p>
<p></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">"These rich people and bigwigs are all heading out on the new Long March, because now the government is promoting socialism in the new era," Ma said.</span></p>
<p></p>
<p><b><i>Translated and edited by Luisetta Mudie.</i></b></p>
        ]]>
    </content:encoded>

    <pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2022 14:03:04 -0400</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>

    <title>Pacific nations want compensation commitment from UN climate talks, Samoa says</title>
    <description>The islands are among the most vulnerable to rising sea levels and extreme weather.</description>
    <link>https://www.rfa.org/english/news/pacific/climate-11042022134111.html</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.rfa.org/english/news/pacific/climate-11042022134111.html</guid>
    
        <author>By Joyetter Feagaimaalii for BenarNews</author>
    

    

    
            <media:content url="https://www.rfa.org/english/news/pacific/climate-11042022134111.html/@@images/image/social_media" type="jpeg">
              <media:description>The South Pacific Ocean pounds the coastline of Funafuti Atoll, Tuvalu, 19 February 2004. Pacific Island nations are among the most vulnerable to higher sea levels.</media:description>
              <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu">AFP</media:credit>
            </media:content>
    
    <content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
        <![CDATA[
        <p><span>Samoa’s environment minister says Pacific island nations want the international climate talks in Egypt this month to establish a basis for compensating developing countries for losses caused by climate change.</span></p>
<p><span>Pacific island nations account for only a tiny fraction of the pollution that drives global warming, but are among the most vulnerable to rising sea levels and extreme weather linked to higher average global temperatures. The risks over coming decades are particularly severe for low-lying atoll nations such as Kiribati and Tuvalu.</span></p>
<p><span>“We have to stand together as a Pacific family, if this situation is not remedied, the Pacific islands will face loss and damage issues,” Samoa’s Minister of Natural Resources and Environment, Toesulusulu Cedric Schuster, told BenarNews, an RFA-affiliated online news service.</span></p>
<p><span></span></p>
<figure><img alt="" class="image-richtext image-inline" src="https://www.benarnews.org/english/news/pacific/schuster.jpg/@@images/2f168af4-4a5c-42a8-be1e-726a3a8a1c20.jpeg"/>
<figcaption>Samoa’s Minister of Natural Resources and Environment, Toeolesulusulu Cedric Schuster, speaks at the Sydney Energy Forum in Sydney, Australia, July 13, 2022. Credit: Reuters</figcaption>
</figure>
<p><br/><span>Developing nations have for decades called for financial help to address loss and damage, a term in the U.N climate negotiations that covers the consequences of planet warming that go beyond what countries can adapt to, according to the World Resources Institute, a research organization. It includes economic losses and human trauma such as flooding of burial grounds and community relocation or migration. </span></p>
<p><span>A few developed countries including Germany and New Zealand have signaled some support for such finance, but the United States, which is behind only China as a polluter, has not.</span></p>
<p><span>The 27th annual U.N climate talks start on Sunday in Sharm El-Sheikh, Egypt. The annual talks between nearly 200 nations are widely known as COP, short for Conference of the Parties. It has the overarching goal of limiting the increase in the average global temperature to 1.5 degrees Celsius, though activists and scientists say emissions reductions have not been far-reaching enough to achieve that.</span></p>
<p><span>Egypt has said that COP27 will be about moving from negotiation to implementation</span></p>
<p><span>"One of the core issues that will be addressed at the COP is loss and damage which has been a long-standing concern for Samoa let alone the Pacific,” said Schuster. “It remains one of Samoa’s priorities and it's evident in the delegation numbers that will be attending the COP this year,” he said.</span></p>
<p><span>The United States and China are both vying for influence in the Pacific and their stances at the climate talks will give an indication of the authenticity of their commitment to the region, activists say. The United States has vowed a renewed focus on the Pacific in response to China’s greater involvement in the region over the past two decades through development aid and infrastructure projects. </span></p>
<p><span>“Climate change is the single biggest security threat, the threat being our livelihoods, our wellbeing,” said Lavetanalagi Seru, regional policy officer for the Pacific Islands Climate Action Network, a non-governmental organization (NGO).</span></p>
<p><span>“If they are to work with the Pacific then they really need to consider what the Pacific island countries and leaders deem as a priority,” he said.</span></p>
<p><span>Samoa’s Prime Minister Fiame Naomi Mata'afa told the United Nations General Assembly in September that action from the climate talks is a matter of survival for Pacific island nations and other small island states.</span></p>
<p><span>"We should not put out the flame for loss and damage,” she said. “Natural disasters continue to devastate countless lives. Recent climate events are transboundary and drive home the reality that no country is immune to the impacts of climate change.”</span></p>
<p><span>Separately, Pacific island countries have created the Pacific Resilience Fund, which they hope will attract up to U.S. $1.5 billion for coping with climate change.</span></p>
<p><span>Tonga’s Prime Minister Siaosi Sovaleni said in September wealthy countries should contribute to the fund rather than only impose their own climate projects.</span></p>
<p><span>The Pacific is competing with other developing nations for assistance and so far has got less than 1.0% of the money allocated by wealthy nations for climate projects, according to Seru.</span></p>
<p><span>“The hope is that these funds will directly go to supporting grassroots communities and NGOs,” he said.</span></p>
<p><em><strong>BenarNews is an RFA-affiliated news service.</strong></em></p>
        ]]>
    </content:encoded>

    <pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2022 13:43:59 -0400</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>

    <title>China, Australia give equipment to Solomon Islands police as rivalry escalates</title>
    <description>Solomon Islands police are under equipped but their weapons have previously been stolen and used in conflicts.</description>
    <link>https://www.rfa.org/english/news/pacific/solomons-11042022133221.html</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.rfa.org/english/news/pacific/solomons-11042022133221.html</guid>
    
        <author>By Gina Maka’a and Stephen Wright for BenarNews</author>
    

    

    
            <media:content url="https://www.rfa.org/english/news/pacific/solomons-11042022133221.html/@@images/image/social_media" type="jpeg">
              <media:description>Australian Federal Police Deputy Commissioner Lesa Gale, Australian High Commissioner Lachlan Strahan, Solomon Islands Prime Minister Manasseh Sogavare, and Solomon Islands Police Commissioner Mostyn Mangau (left to right) with Daniels Defense MK18 rifles gifted by Australia to the Solomon Islands police force, on November 2, 2022 in Honiara, the Solomon Islands capital.</media:description>
              <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu">Australian High Commission handout</media:credit>
            </media:content>
    
    <content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
        <![CDATA[
        <p><span>China and U.S. ally Australia have donated weapons and vehicles to the Solomon Islands police, sparking criticism their rivalry could cause new instability in a South Pacific country that spiraled into chaos only two decades ago.</span></p>
<figure>
<figcaption></figcaption>
</figure>
<p><span>On Friday, China handed over two water cannon trucks, 30 motorbikes and 20 white utility vehicles emblazoned with the red China Aid logo. Two days earlier, Australia presented 60 MK18 rifles and 13 vehicles, some of which will be used in a new mobile protection unit for VIPs. Both countries also have been providing training in policing techniques</span>.</p>
<figure><img alt="" class="image-richtext image-inline" height="" src="https://www.benarnews.org/english/news/pacific/solomon-isands-weapons-11042022033133.html/policemanandvan.jpg/@@images/e8e804a3-8a60-4c41-ac42-6e81ff6ee6e3.jpeg" width=""/>
<figcaption>Solomon Islands Prime Minister Manasseh Sogavare looks on as a member of China’s police liaison team talks at the handover ceremony for vehicles that China donated to Solomon Islands police force, on Nov. 4, 2022 in Honiara, the Solomon Islands capital. Credit:Gina Maka’a</figcaption>
</figure>
<p><span></span></p>
<p><span>“It is clear Australia is anxious that if they do not supply guns then China will. Geopolitical interests have surpassed national interest in this country and it is a sad state of affairs,” said Solomon Islands opposition leader Matthew Wale.</span></p>
<p><span>The country of some 700,000 people has become a hot spot for the U.S.-China rivalry in the Pacific. Prime Minister Manasseh Sogavare’s government switched its diplomatic recognition to China from Taiwan in 2019 and signed a secret security pact with Beijing earlier this year. China, along with countries such as Australia and Indonesia, is also helping to bankroll the Pacific Games in the capital Honiara next year.</span></p>
<p><span>The new weapons have caused concern in the Solomon Islands and abroad. </span></p>
<p><span>Several years of instability around the turn of the century, fueled by stolen police equipment, still looms large for Solomon Islanders, who call the period The Tensions. Corruption, ethnic strife and political divides made the country seem ungovernable and culminated in an Australian-led military intervention from 2003 until 2017.</span></p>
<p></p>
<figure><img alt="" class="image-richtext image-inline" src="https://www.benarnews.org/english/news/pacific/chinaaidcars.jpg/@@images/88019cce-2826-4cd0-8dd0-bb569b5fa0b3.jpeg"/>
<figcaption>Vehicles donated by China to the Solomon Islands police force are on display at a handover ceremony in the Solomon Islands capital Honiara on November 4, 2022. Photo: Gina Maka’a</figcaption>
</figure>
<p><span></span></p>
<p><span>Sogavare, speaking at the ceremony for the handover of China’s equipment, said people who see a better equipped police force through a negative lens should consider that it has a responsibility to “protect the lives and welfare, liberty, property of all people in this country.” </span></p>
<p><span>He said riots in Honiara in November last year – which torched the city’s Chinatown and were linked to the change of diplomatic recognition – and earlier public unrest, showed the consequences of a lack of police capacity. </span></p>
<p><span>“We must have the capacity as our first line of defense and not depend on others,” Sogavare said.</span></p>
<p><span>Mihai Sora, an analyst at Australia’s Lowy Institute and former diplomat in the Solomon Islands, said community concerns about the gifts of water cannon, high-powered rifles and vehicles are well founded.</span></p>
<p><span>“There is a risk that the donated weapons and water cannons could be misused against protesters, further inflaming local tensions,” he said. </span></p>
<p><span>It appears that Australia’s hand was forced as it tries to retain its relationship with the Solomon Islands police in the face of the government’s increasingly close police and security ties with China, Sora said.</span></p>
<p></p>
<figure><img alt="" class="image-richtext image-inline" height="" src="https://www.benarnews.org/english/news/pacific/policecars.jpg/@@images/6d9c5f01-2940-4465-b3d4-c4949a94f529.jpeg" width=""/>
<figcaption>Vehicles donated by Australia to the Solomon Islands police force on display at a handover ceremony in the Solomon Islands capital Honiara on November 2, 2022. Credit: Australian High Commission handout</figcaption>
</figure>
<p></p>
<p><span>China’s ambassador to the Solomon Islands, Li Ming, said China’s donation of equipment is meant to improve the capacity of Solomon Islands police.</span></p>
<p><span>“We are fully opposed to any geopolitical games. What we are doing is to provide necessary assistance to Solomon Islands’ government and people to help maintain the safety, security and public order of the country,” he said on Friday.</span></p>
<p><span>Australia’s High Commission to the Solomon Islands said earlier in the week that there are “stringent” training and safeguards for the rifles that Australia has provided. </span></p>
<p><span>The weapons are part of a police rearming that began in 2013 and would be used by a specialized police response team as a last-resort option only, it said.</span></p>
<p><span>“In the wrong hands it will all go wrong, but the police do need equipment, and water cannons are better than bullets,” said Clive Moore, a University of Queensland professor who authored a Solomon Islands encyclopedia.</span></p>
<p><span>“But every time this happens it moves the Solomons further away from unarmed community policing. It’s part of a drift that suits Sogavare,” he said.</span></p>
<p><em><strong>BenarNews is an RFA-affiliated news service.</strong></em></p>
        ]]>
    </content:encoded>

    <pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2022 13:33:14 -0400</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>

    <title>China orders construction of state-run canteens in self-contained community hubs</title>
    <description>Local one-stop shop services will boost state control over food supply, and could be linked to war planning.</description>
    <link>https://www.rfa.org/english/news/china/canteens-11042022113231.html</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.rfa.org/english/news/china/canteens-11042022113231.html</guid>
    
        <author>By Gu Ting and Jane Tang for RFA Mandarin, Jojo Man for RFA Cantonese</author>
    

    

    
            <media:content url="https://www.rfa.org/english/news/china/canteens-11042022113231.html/@@images/image/social_media" type="jpeg">
              <media:description>State canteens have been popping up in residential compounds across Hunan, Hubei, Shandong and Yunnan provinces since July, often run and funded by neighborhood committees.</media:description>
              <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu">RFA screenshot from video</media:credit>
            </media:content>
    
    <content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
        <![CDATA[
        <p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Chinese Communist Party under Xi Jinping is accelerating a return to the state-run economics of the Mao era, with local governments and neighborhoods ordered to build self-contained community depots to serve residential compounds in time of need, experts told RFA in recent interviews.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The ministries of housing and civil affairs have ordered residential communities in pilot areas to build self-contained service depots in residential compounds offering convenience stores, vegetable stalls, state-run canteens, mail and express delivery service facilities, hair salons, laundry shops, pharmacies, maintenance points, and housekeeping services.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If rolled out nationwide, the move would effectively make it far easier to confine people to their homes, whether due to Chinese leader Xi Jinping's zero-COVID policy or other national contingencies like war, natural disaster or civil unrest.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Any grouping of 100 households must have a comprehensive service hub of at least 30 square-meters (325 square-feet) under the pilot plan, which will be implemented by local governments and district and neighborhood committees.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Efforts must be made to ensure that residential compounds all have access to community hospitals, schooling, nursing homes, and state canteens, newly built if necessary, within 15 minutes of people's homes, a Nov. 1 report on the official Chinese government website said.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">State-run "community canteens" are already starting to appear, with a social media video of one in the Fengqing residential community in the central city of Wuhan showing people lining up to buy mass-produced meals.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">"I'm here to taste the kind of fare on offer at a state-run canteen," the presenter says to camera, before tucking into a bowl of rice with various other dishes in colorful bowls on a tray.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The memory of state-run canteens and state stores under the All China Federation of Supply and Marketing Cooperatives has made many older people in China uneasy with the break with the market-reform era of Deng Xiaoping, which followed the death of Mao Zedong in 1976.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">"We suffered under the planned economy, and it's only now, under the market economy, that we finally have enough to eat," Jiangsu-based current affairs commentator Zhang Jianping told RFA. "Barely have we eaten our fill, and it's back to the planned economy again."</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">"To be honest, we all have a sense of dread ... People are also speculating whether this means there is going to be a war," he said. "War would be the only reason for a return to the planned economy, which is obviously a kind of regression."</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Hunan current affairs commentator Li Ang agreed.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">"The old planned economy and [attempts at] socialist self-sufficiency are still fresh in our memories," Li said. "We experienced all of that when we were kids."</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">"It's a clear demonstration of their determination in the face of their belief in the decoupling from Western civilization, in the wake of the 20th party congress," he said.</span></p>
<figure><img alt="ENG_CHN_StateCanteens_11042022.2.jpg" class="image-richtext image-inline" src="https://www.rfa.org/english/news/china/canteens-11042022113231.html/eng_chn_statecanteens_11042022-2.jpg/@@images/2b217538-3903-46e3-b0ec-c5d6fd5ccef1.jpeg" title="ENG_CHN_StateCanteens_11042022.2.jpg"/>
<figcaption>A newly built residential canteen in Wuhan, China. Credit: RFA screenshot from video</figcaption>
</figure>
<p><strong>Looking ahead to 'a country at war'</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">State canteens have been popping up in residential compounds across Hunan, Hubei, Shandong and Yunnan provinces since July, often run and funded by neighborhood committees, and offering more affordable meals than commercial restaurants.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">They have been particularly popular with people on a low income, such as the elderly.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">"Back then, they built canteens on a large scale to make economies of scale, and also to minimize food waste," current affairs commentator Ma Ju told RFA. "They figured that having only a few people in any place doing the cooking would free up other laborers, which could improve productivity."</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">"Today's large-scale canteen construction feels more like we're looking ahead to being a country at war."</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">However, centralizing canteens also politicizes food, and who gets to eat it, Ma said.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">"Building canteens is also about controlling people through food ... and associating the Communist Party in people's minds with getting fed," he said. "The purpose is to enable them to impose emergency measures [on the population], anywhere and at any time."</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Both state canteens and supply and marketing co-ops also </span><a href="https://www.rfa.org/english/women/li-shuxian-04272012104245.html"><span style="font-weight: 400;">evoke memories</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> from the 1970s and 1980s of being asked for food rationing tickets limiting the amount of rice, oil and other foods a family could buy in a week, with the neighborhood committees in charge of handing these over to residents.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Lai Rongwei, assistant professor at the General Education Center of Longhua University of Science and Technology, agreed that the Chinese Communist Party is looking to maintain social stability by offering a "one-stop shop" to serve people locally, and to exert collective controls over them at the same time.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">"Put simply, this is about controlling resources," Lai told RFA. "On the supply side, they will be looking to centralize all agricultural production, similar to the People's Communes before the [Deng market reforms]."</span></p>
<p><strong>'Decoupling' from the global economy</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Analysts told RFA in recent interviews that China is </span><a href="https://www.rfa.org/english/news/china/state-10312022122620.html"><span style="font-weight: 400;">quietly rebooting a Mao-era institution</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> that once functioned as a pillar of the socialist command economy to prepare for future "decoupling" from the global economy, pointing to the elevation of supply and marketing co-ops chief Liang Huiling to the ruling party's Central Committee last month. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Wu Chien-chung, associate professor at the National Taiwan Ocean University, agreed that Beijing could be planning for war.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">"It remains to be seen whether local governments ... are capable of implementing this thinking from central government, which wants to store grain to prepare for war," Wu told RFA. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Former top Communist Party aide Bao Tong </span><a href="https://www.rfa.org/english/commentaries/baotong/freedom-12202013190532.html"><span style="font-weight: 400;">warned in an essay</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> written to mark Mao Zedong's centenary in 2020: "Markets, just like history itself, can move backwards as well as forwards, and there is always a danger of regression under a great leader flying the banner of honor and right thinking." </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">"The destruction of the markets was among the most prominent of Mao's tyrannies," wrote Bao, who spent seven years in prison after the fall of his political mentor Zhao Ziyang in the wake of the 1989 Tiananmen Square protests, and remains under close surveillance in Beijing.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">While the rebooted supply and marketing cooperative stores look more like a modern supermarket than the general stores of the 1970s and 1980s, many older people in China still remember rationing -- the side-effect of a top-down, command economy.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">"I remember there was a building for the supply and marketing co-op, but they didn't let just anyone go in and buy stuff," Beijing-born economist Li Hengqing told RFA. "You had to have special ration tickets to buy oil, rice, meat and many other items."</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">"Nobody wants to go back to that," Li said.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“There wasn't any choice of products, and the attitude of the staff was generally very bad," he said. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">"I can still remember trying to buy meat and them refusing to give me any, because they were keeping it for someone they knew, or for one of the leaders. That was [typical of] state-owned enterprises."</span></p>
<p><em><strong>Translated and edited by Luisetta Mudie.</strong></em></p>
        ]]>
    </content:encoded>

    <pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2022 13:19:07 -0400</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>

    <title>U.S. offers $5 million for info on North Korean smuggling</title>
    <description>Singaporean national Kwek Kee Seng is accused of helping North Korea evade sanctions.</description>
    <link>https://www.rfa.org/english/news/korea/north-korea-reward-11042022093851.html</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.rfa.org/english/news/korea/north-korea-reward-11042022093851.html</guid>
    
        <author>Alex Willemyns for RFA</author>
    

    

    
            <media:content url="https://www.rfa.org/english/news/korea/north-korea-reward-11042022093851.html/@@images/image/social_media" type="jpeg">
              <media:description>In 2020, Cambodian authorities seized the oil tanker M/T Courageous and handed it over to the United States. The U.S. Department of Justice said satellite images showed the vessel transferring $1.5 million worth of oil to a North Korean ship.</media:description>
              <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu">AFP/U.S. Department of Justice</media:credit>
            </media:content>
    
    <content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
        <![CDATA[
        <p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The United States is offering a $5 million reward for information about a smuggling operation run by Singaporean businessman Kwek Kee Seng to ship luxury goods, money, petrol and weapon-making materials to North Korea in violation of U.N. Security Council sanctions.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Kwek is responsible for delivering oil shipments to North Korea in exchange for funds laundered through shell companies based in Panama and Singapore, and had a federal arrest warrant issued in April 2021, says a statement from the U.S. State Department on Thursday.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Kwek Kee Seng has directed the delivery of petroleum products directly to the DPRK as well as ship-to-ship transfers of fuel destined for the DPRK using one of Kwek’s oil tankers,” the State Department said, using an acronym for North Korea’s government. It added that “Kwek and his co-conspirators sought to obscure their identities.” </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Cambodian authorities in 2020 </span><a href="https://www.aljazeera.com/news/2021/7/31/us-seizes-tanker-used-to-evade-north-korea"><span style="font-weight: 400;">seized a ship</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> operated by one of Kwek’s companies and handed it over to the United States, with the U.S. Department of Justice saying at the time that satellite images showed the vessel transferring $1.5 million worth of oil to a North Korean ship.</span></p>
<figure><img alt="ENG_KOR_Smuggling_reward_11032022.2.jpg" class="image-richtext image-inline" src="https://www.rfa.org/english/news/korea/north-korea-reward-11042022093851.html/eng_kor_smuggling_reward_11032022-2.jpg/@@images/eb4813f0-ece3-4d80-8565-9066d6ec12bd.jpeg" title="ENG_KOR_Smuggling_reward_11032022.2.jpg"/>
<figcaption>The Biden administration is offering a reward of up to $5 million for information about Kwek Kee Seng, a Singapore-based businessman previously accused by the Justice Department of facilitating fuel shipments to North Korea in violation of U.N. sanctions. (FBI via Associated Press)</figcaption>
</figure>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The U.S. Treasury Department last month </span><a href="https://home.treasury.gov/news/press-releases/jy1000"><span style="font-weight: 400;">cited</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Kwek as a key player in what it called an “international evasion network” that helps to smuggle fuel into North Korea, which it said “directly supports the development of DPRK weapons programs and its military,” including missile launches.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The $5 million reward comes amid a renewed round of missile testing from North Korea, with Pyongyang </span><a href="https://www.rfa.org/english/news/korea/missiles-11022022125243.html"><span style="font-weight: 400;">firing some 26 missiles</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, as well as a possibly failed intercontinental ballistic missile, into waters near South Korea and Japan this week, also in violation of U.N. sanctions.</span></p>
        ]]>
    </content:encoded>

    <pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2022 09:40:00 -0400</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>

    <title>Junta shelling kills 2 family members and injures 2 more in Myanmar’s Sagaing region</title>
    <description>A 13-year-old boy and his grandmother died after being hit by shrapnel.</description>
    <link>https://www.rfa.org/english/news/myanmar/sagaing-shelling-kills-two-11042022051255.html</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.rfa.org/english/news/myanmar/sagaing-shelling-kills-two-11042022051255.html</guid>
    
        <author>By RFA Burmese</author>
    

    

    
            <media:content url="https://www.rfa.org/english/news/myanmar/sagaing-shelling-kills-two-11042022051255.html/@@images/image/social_media" type="jpeg">
              <media:description>Destroyed buildings in Zee Ka Nar village, which was shelled by the army on Nov. 3, 2022.</media:description>
              <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu">Kyunhla Activists Group</media:credit>
            </media:content>
    
    <content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
        <![CDATA[
        <p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Army shelling of a village in Sagaing region’s Kanbalu township killed a teenager and his grandmother and injured two other members of the same family.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">A junta shell hit a house in Zee Ka Nar village on Thursday. The boy, Paing Set Hmu, was hit in the head and died instantly. His grandmother was also hit by shell fragments and died the next morning, locals told RFA. The boy’s seven-year old sister and a female relative in her 60s suffered minor injuries to their heads, hands and legs.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Junta troops in Koe Taung Boet village fired a shell and it landed on a house in Zee Ka Nar village which is located in the west [of the township],” a local said, speaking on condition of anonymity for safety reasons.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“The whole family was injured. The 13-year-old boy, Paing Set Hmu, died immediately and his 68-year-old grandmother, Win, was hit in the abdomen and died this morning,” he said.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Junta forces shelled the nearby forest on the same day and fought skirmishes with local People’s Defense Forces, the local said.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Residents said troops stationed in Koe Taung Boet village arrested and interrogated around 10 locals after they attacked villages around the township.   </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">RFA has not been able to verify the information independently and calls to the junta spokesman for Sagaing region, Social Affairs Minister Aye Hlaing, went unanswered on Friday.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Some 1,512 civilians died in Sagaing in the 21 months since the Feb. 1, 2021 coup, the Institute for Strategy and Policy (ISP) reported at the end of last month.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Sagaing has the largest number of Internally Displaced Persons (IDPs) in Myanmar since the coup, after intense fighting forced them to flee their villages. As of Oct. 19, there were more than</span><a href="https://www.ispmyanmar.com/#images-2"> <span style="font-weight: 400;">680,629 or 41 percent of the country’s IDPs</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> in the region the independent research group said.</span></p>
        ]]>
    </content:encoded>

    <pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2022 05:46:55 -0400</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>

    <title>China buys up US technology to keep tabs on its citizens</title>
    <description>The technology helps monitor groups and censor material in places such as the Xinjiang Uyghur Autonomous Region.</description>
    <link>https://www.rfa.org/english/news/china/china-us-technology-11042022021211.html</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.rfa.org/english/news/china/china-us-technology-11042022021211.html</guid>
    
        <author>By RFA Staff</author>
    

    

    
            <media:content url="https://www.rfa.org/english/news/china/china-us-technology-11042022021211.html/@@images/image/social_media" type="jpeg">
              <media:description>Pedestrians walk on an overpass near a surveillance camera overlooking a street in Beijing, Dec. 14, 2021.</media:description>
              <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu">Reuters/Carlos Garcia Rawlins</media:credit>
            </media:content>
    
    <content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
        <![CDATA[
        <p><strong>Updated at 12:45 p.m. EDT on 11-4-2022</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Chinese public security entities have been acquiring U.S. technology with the transfers becoming increasingly regular, especially of DNA analysis equipment needed for mass surveillance, a new report has found.</span></p>
<p><a href="https://www.recordedfuture.com/the-role-of-us-technology-in-china-public-security-system"><span style="font-weight: 400;">"The Role of US Technology in China's Public Security System"</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> by the U.S. intelligence and security research group <span>Recorded Future</span> revealed the sweeping extent of technology transfers from U.S. companies to Chinese companies to be used by the public security apparatus, including in the Xinjiang Uyghur Autonomous Region.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">From DNA analysis to thermal imaging, from data storage to digital forensics and cyber security, a vast range of U.S. technology has been transferred to the Chinese public security system. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Surveillance and counter-surveillance are among the main focuses of the technology transfers, the report said.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“In some cases, public security entities in China almost certainly seek technology from U.S. companies because foreign products outperform domestic equivalents,” it said.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In other cases, the technology was acquired “to ensure compatibility” as it had already been used by Chinese organizations.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">According to the report, public security entities in the Xinjiang Uyghur Autonomous Region “appear to have purchased at least 481 hard disk drives from Seagate and Western Digital” in early-to-mid 2022, including surveillance-specialized drives and drives acquired alongside equipment from China’s leading surveillance providers. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Both Seagate Technology Holdings and Western Digital Corporation are well-known American data storage companies.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Other entities in Xinjiang, such as prisons belonging to the paramilitary Xinjiang Production and Construction Corps, have also recently carried out surveillance-oriented purchases of Seagate or Western Digital hard disk drives,” it said.</span></p>
<p><a href="https://www.top10vpn.com/assets/2021/07/Chinas-Surveillance-State.pdf"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Another report</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> released last year also said U.S. technology companies were supplying China’s surveillance state with equipment and software for monitoring populations and censoring information, including in Xinjiang.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Western governments and human rights groups have condemned Beijing for </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">surveillance and other abusive policies against the 12 million Muslim Uyghurs in the region, which they said </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">amounted to genocide and crimes against humanity. China has repeatedly denied the allegations.</span></p>
<p></p>
<figure><img alt="Xinjiang.jpg" class="image-richtext image-inline" src="https://www.rfa.org/english/news/china/xinjiang.jpg/@@images/2c78233b-10cd-4056-973b-bb47d1696799.jpeg" title="Xinjiang.jpg"/>
<figcaption>The Chinese flag behind razor wire at a housing compound in Yangisar, south of Kashgar, in China's western Xinjiang region, in a photograph taken on June 4, 2019. <br/>CREDIT: Greg Baker/AFP</figcaption>
 </figure>
<p><b>‘Extremely common transfers’</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“When I started the research, I did not expect these technology transfers to be so prevalent,” said report author Zoe Haver.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">She began the project by looking at transfers of counter-surveillance devices used by the U.S. military and U.S. law enforcement, but during the process she found that Chinese public security entities were purchasing U.S. technology for use in many other areas, such as aviation, DNA analysis, thermal imaging, optics, surveillance, cybersecurity, network infrastructure, and data storage.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“With some of the technologies that I was tracking, such as DNA analysis equipment, I observed new purchases on pretty much a day-to-day basis. These transfers are extremely common across China,” she told RFA.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Chinese public security apparatus has been seeking DNA analysis equipment, with the reliance on U.S. technology in this area “most notable,” according to the analyst.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“This equipment can potentially be used to help build population databases and carry out mass surveillance,” Haver said.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Entities belonging to the powerful Ministry of Public Security (MPS) have been acquiring U.S. technology via legal channels at industry exhibitions, third-party agents and distributors, and even from U.S. companies’ local subsidiaries in China.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Recently more and more U.S. firms have been bought by Chinese companies and this has “aided the growth of China’s domestic industries and facilitated sales of U.S. products to public security end users,” according to the report.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Another factor is the cross-border flows of talent that have become increasingly common in the era of globalization.</span></p>
<p><b>U.S. control response</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Haver compiled the report by sifting through thousands of public Chinese government procurement records and she said that she was struck by the sheer number of procurement documents.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In response to the state violence that Chinese public security entities carry out, particularly in Xinjiang, the U.S. government has taken some steps in recent years to restrict the transfer of U.S. technology to them.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Export Control Reform Act of 2018 referred to items that have law enforcement-related applications and stipulated that “the U.S. export control policy should serve to protect human rights.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In 2019 and 2020, the U.S. Department of Commerce Bureau of Industry and Security placed 21 Chinese public security entities (in addition to various Chinese companies) on an export licensing restrictions list.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">But Recorded Future report raised the question of “the efficacy of current U.S. export control measures that target Chinese public security entities and the Chinese companies that support them.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“As third-party distributors and agents play such a prominent role in the technology transfer process, the U.S. government may find it difficult to implement effective export restrictions,” Haver told RFA.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"></span></p>
<p><strong>This story has been updated to clarify the attribution of the research report. </strong></p>
        ]]>
    </content:encoded>

    <pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2022 02:21:00 -0400</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>

    <title>Vietnamese prison of conscience denied family visits after hunger strike</title>
    <description>Trinh Ba Tu's father was turned back this week after two unsuccessful trips to the prison last month.</description>
    <link>https://www.rfa.org/english/news/vietnam/tu-denied-visits-11042022010811.html</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.rfa.org/english/news/vietnam/tu-denied-visits-11042022010811.html</guid>
    
        <author>By RFA Vietnamese</author>
    

    

    
            <media:content url="https://www.rfa.org/english/news/vietnam/tu-denied-visits-11042022010811.html/@@images/image/social_media" type="jpeg">
              <media:description>Trinh Ba Tu who claims he was beaten and chained by guards at Prison Camp No. 6.</media:description>
              <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu">Facebook Trinh Ba Tu</media:credit>
            </media:content>
    
    <content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
        <![CDATA[
        <p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Jailed land rights activist Trinh Ba Tu is being denied family visits at Prison Camp No. 6 in Vietnam’s bleak Ngha An province after he started a hunger strike nearly two months ago to protest against prison guards beating him.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">He started to refuse food on Sept. 6 and told his father later that month he had been put in solitary confinement, beaten and shackled.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">At the end of September, right after Tu’s father Trinh Ba Khiem returned from prison, his family filed a petition to the Ministry of Public Security to investigate the accusations. The ministry replied that the family should send the petition to the People's Procuracy of Nghe An province. So far, his family has not received a response.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Tu was also denied two visits from his father last month and the punishments show no signs of ending, even though it’s unclear whether he is still on hunger strike.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Tu’s father went to the prison on Thursday and asked to see his son but his request was refused. He was told he couldn't make another appointment for more than two weeks.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">"I went in there for about an hour to submit the [appointment] book. Then a prison officer came out and said that Tu was still being disciplined so I couldn't send him things or see my child until November 21.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“I don't know if Tu has stopped his hunger strike yet, and I don't know what the situation is yet. The Prison Camp 6 warden said nothing more.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Khiem said the warden he spoke with was called Loc who was a captain of the local management team for political prisoners.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">RFA Vietnamese called the prison on Thursday to verify Khiem’s claims but no one answered the phone.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Prisoners normally have the right to a one-hour monthly visit from their relatives, to make a 10-minute phone call every month and to receive provisions from their families.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Khiem said he was extremely worried about his son's health, especially since two political prisoners died while serving their sentences in the prison.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In 2019, former teacher Dao Quang Thuc died in the prison while serving a 13-year sentence. This August, citizen journalist Do Cong Duong also died there. Both men were healthy before being transferred to the prison camp.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Trinh Ba Tu, 33, his brother Trinh Ba Phuong, 37, and their mother Can Thi Theu, 60, were arrested in mid-2020 on charges of "conducting propaganda against the state" for speaking out strongly on social networks about the Dong Tam land rights dispute.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><span>The dispute centered on construction of a military airport opposed by villagers south of Hanoi. The ensuing January 2020 clash left a popular local leader and three policemen dead. Twenty-nine villagers were arrested, and many were given stiff sentences.</span></span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">At the beginning of May last year, Tu and his mother were sentenced to eight years in prison and three years’ probation each. Phuong was sentenced to 10 years in prison.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Prison No. 6 is located in the region with the harshest climate in the Central region. Many former prisoners have told RFA that the guards are particularly brutal to prisoners of conscience.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"></span><span style="font-weight: 400;"></span></p>
        ]]>
    </content:encoded>

    <pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2022 01:12:00 -0400</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>

    <title>Laos rescues 11 Indian nationals trafficked to work as phone scammers</title>
    <description>Promised high-paying jobs in Singapore and Dubai, they wound up in the murky Golden Triangle economic zone.</description>
    <link>https://www.rfa.org/english/news/laos/trafficked-11032022222930.html</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.rfa.org/english/news/laos/trafficked-11032022222930.html</guid>
    
        <author>By RFA Lao</author>
    

    

    
            <media:content url="https://www.rfa.org/english/news/laos/trafficked-11032022222930.html/@@images/image/social_media" type="jpeg">
              <media:description>The Kings Romans casino is seen across the Mekong River in the Golden Triangle Special Economic Zone in northern Laos' Bokeo province, Januar, 2012.</media:description>
              <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu">Reuters</media:credit>
            </media:content>
    
    <content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
        <![CDATA[
        <p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Authorities in Laos have rescued 11 Indian nationals who were lured to the Chinese-run Golden Triangle Special Economic Zone in the north of the country and put to work as phone scammers, according to the Indian Embassy.</span></p>
<p></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The operation shines a light on the murky enclave in Bokeo province – home to the Kings Roman Casino resort – where many foreigners who were promised lucrative jobs end up held against their will by trafficking rings that exploit them under threat of violence.</span></p>
<p></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Golden Triangle economic zone is a gambling and tourism hub catering to Chinese citizens situated along the Mekong River where Laos, Myanmar and Thailand meet. In 2018, the U.S. government sanctioned the Chinese tycoon who is said to run the SEZ as head of a trafficking network.</span></p>
<p></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Last week, Lao authorities acted on a tip from the Indian Embassy to rescue 11 Indians who had been held for more than a month by traffickers in the zone. </span></p>
<p></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">They were recruited by unscrupulous middlemen to work as IT specialists in Dubai, Singapore and Thailand with offers of well-paying jobs and pre-arranged flights, visas and passports, according to Indian Embassy sources who discussed the situation off the record because they were unauthorized to speak to the press.</span></p>
<p></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Instead, they wound up in northern Laos, where they were forced to work in call centers largely unmonitored by authorities, calling people to solicit money for fraudulent investment schemes or engage in cryptocurrency scams.</span></p>
<p></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Rights groups estimate that at least 1,000 people from South and East Asia have been lured to work as scammers at the Golden Triangle zone, many of whom continue to be held against their will there.</span></p>
<p></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Extricated by Lao officials last week, the 11 workers were brought to the Lao border with Thailand and handed over to a team from the Indian Consulate in Chiang Mai, before being repatriated to India over the weekend via Bangkok, the Indian Embassy in Laos said in an announcement posted to its Facebook page.</span></p>
<p></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">RFA Lao was unable to reach Lao authorities operating in the Golden Triangle economic zone or officials in the Indian Embassy in the Lao capital Vientiane for comment on the rescue operation.</span></p>
<p></p>
<p><b>Conditions at scam centers</b></p>
<p></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">A Lao national who previously worked as a scammer in the zone told RFA on condition of anonymity that trafficking is rife there and said several foreign nationals were being held against their will at the call center where he was located.</span></p>
<p></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“There were three or four Indians and as many as 20 Thais working as scammers [when I was there],” he said, adding that most foreign nationals being held at the zone at the time were Thai, Chinese and Vietnamese, although he also met Indonesians and Malaysians.</span></p>
<p></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The former scam center worker from Laos told RFA that if they follow orders, trafficked workers could earn U.S. $450-725 per month, depending on the number of people they scammed, while those who could speak Thai, Chinese, or Vietnamese could earn even more.</span></p>
<p></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">But rules were strict and anyone who left the call center without informing members of the trafficking ring or escaped and was caught “would face a serious punishment,” he said.</span></p>
<p></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Despite the restrictions and the threat of punishment, the Lao national said that he planned to return to the zone again because “I know how to do the work and they will hire me right away.” </span></p>
<p></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In addition to luring unsuspecting foreign nationals through middlemen, scam centers also “recruit” workers through other means, the Lao national told RFA.</span></p>
<p></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">During an outbreak of COVID-19 in August and September 2021, authorities in Bokeo province temporarily closed the Golden Triangle economic zone to force employers based there to allow their workers to return home and renegotiate hiring contracts, due to the slowdown of the economy. </span></p>
<p></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Instead of allowing them to return, he said, many of the centers simply “sold” their workers to trafficking rings who forced them to do the same work stipulated in their existing contracts, threatening them with beatings and imprisonment if they refused.</span></p>
<p></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Meanwhile, the worker said, Lao authorities cannot easily enter the Chinese-run zone, which operates largely beyond the reach of the Lao government, and are often unable to arrest ring leaders because the victims of the scams rarely report their losses to police.</span></p>
<p></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Nobody takes them to court because there’s no proof,” he said. “Those who lose money dare not tell the police or take legal action.”</span></p>
<p></p>
<p><b>Foreigners targeted</b></p>
<p></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Chinese-run enclaves in Southeast Asia have come under heavy scrutiny in recent months after hundreds of </span><a href="https://www.rfa.org/english/news/china/taiwan-cambodia-scam-08232022132211.html"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Taiwanese nationals</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> were rescued after being lured into human trafficking and abusive jobs scams in Cambodia, with many victims taken to work in Chinese-owned casinos in the coastal city of Sihanoukville.</span></p>
<p></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The government has so far registered 1,267 workers in the Golden Triangle zone, only a fraction of the total, although the exact number employed there is unknown, according to Lao officials. Efforts to register workers to protect them from human trafficking and other abuses </span><a href="https://www.rfa.org/english/news/laos/worker-registrations-08242022162635.html"><span style="font-weight: 400;">have met with limited success</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> because workers balk at paying the fees and fear that signing up will get them sent home, sources have told RFA.</span></p>
<p></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In addition to the 11 Indian workers rescued last week, authorities freed 44 Pakistanis from the zone on Oct. 20 and seven Malaysians on Oct. 6. Malaysian authorities have said there are 50-100 Malaysians still being held by traffickers in the zone.</span></p>
<p></p>
<p><b><i>Translated by Sidney Khotpanya. Written in English by Joshua Lipes.</i></b></p>
        ]]>
    </content:encoded>

    <pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 22:33:33 -0400</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>

    <title>Uyghur doctor jailed for treating a ‘terrorist’ dies after release from prison</title>
    <description>Another detained Uyghur also dies shortly after his release from jail.</description>
    <link>https://www.rfa.org/english/news/uyghur/tudahun-nurehmet-11032022185154.html</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.rfa.org/english/news/uyghur/tudahun-nurehmet-11032022185154.html</guid>
    
        <author>By Shohret Hoshur for RFA Uyghur</author>
    

    

    
            <media:content url="https://www.rfa.org/english/news/uyghur/tudahun-nurehmet-11032022185154.html/@@images/image/social_media" type="jpeg">
              <media:description>Tudahun Nurehmet, former chief of the Achatagh Hospital in Uchturpan county,  Aksu prefecture, in northwestern China's Xinjiang region, in an undated photo.</media:description>
              <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu">Citizen journalist</media:credit>
            </media:content>
    
    <content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
        <![CDATA[
        <p><span style="font-weight: 400;">A Uyghur doctor sentenced to eight years in prison in China’s northwestern Xinjiang region for removing a bullet from the foot of a suspected criminal, died shortly after being released from prison in September, local police and people with knowledge of the situation said.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Tudahun Nurehmet, also known by the surname Mahmud, was the former chief of the Achatagh Hospital in Uchturpan (in Chinese, Wushi) county, Aksu (Akesu) prefecture. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In 2013, he was sentenced for treating a person Chinese authorities identified as a terrorist who was wounded during a clash in Aksu's Aykol (Ayikule) township in August of that year.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">On that day, a brawl between Muslim Uyghurs and police broke out during a security check of a mosque on the eve of the Eid al-Fitr Islamic festival marks the end of the month-long dawn-to-sunset fasting of Ramadan. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">During the altercation, police fired at unarmed people, killing three Uyghurs and wounding 20 others, RFA </span><a href="https://www.rfa.org/english/news/uyghur/clashes-08102013000244.html" rel="noopener" target="_blank"><span style="font-weight: 400;">reported</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Those who were wounded  either were taken to the hospital or left the area and sought treatment on their own, according to a policeman who was at the scene.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It was at one of these hospitals that Tudahun apparently treated one of the wounded, fulfilling his role as a doctor – which later got him arrested and sentenced to eight years in prison because the patient was identified as a terrorist. </span></p>
<p><b>Kidney disease in prison</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Tudahun was released to his family because of his deteriorating health and died of kidney complications on Sept. 18, according to a person named “Nurxenim Uyghur” who </span><a href="https://www.facebook.com/nur.uyghur.7/videos/517788666528461"><span style="font-weight: 400;">posts</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> information about the deaths of Uyghurs in Xinjiang on Facebook.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">A police officer in the town of Achatagh said Tudahun served his sentence in Urumqi’s No. 6 prison, though he did not have information about the physician’s death.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">A village policeman from Achatagh said Tudahun, the father of two children, was released one year ago and had a severe kidney problem and could not walk. He was healthy before his arrest and died due to a kidney disease that developed during his prison time, the police officer said.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">A second village police officer from the area told RFA that Tudahun was accused of protecting “a crime suspect” because he treated that person’s wound, but he could not provide the suspect’s name or the place where he received medical care.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“They did not tell us whom he treated,” he said. “It was due to an incident that took place on Eid day.“</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Tudahun “was taken away on the third day of Eid,” the village policeman said. “I don’t know if the wounded people came to the hospital or if he went to treat them. I heard he treated ‘the terrorists’ and was therefore accused of aiding them.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">A village Communist Party secretary in Achatagh said Tudahun was sentenced to eight years for removing a bullet from the foot of a wounded suspect involved in the “August 8th incident” in Aksu, referring to the deadly clashes.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“He was arrested because he hid the situation of a person who got shot, and he treated him,” he said.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">But he said Tudahun was a very skilled physician who treated patients from other towns and villages.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The party secretary said Tudahun treated the suspect on the day the incident occurred, and when the suspect was arrested on the second day, he exposed Tudahun, and police subsequently arrested the doctor. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“He was taken from his home,” the secretary said.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">As for the suspect,</span> <span style="font-weight: 400;">he left after receiving medical treatment and was later arrested at another location. </span></p>
<p><b>Another death after release</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In a similar case of an Uyghur individual dying after being released from prison, 27-year-old Alimjan Abdureshit from the town of Toqquzaq (Tuokezhake) in Kashgar (Kashi) prefecture, died on Oct. 2, about 40 days after his release from a prison or an internment camp, according to the same the Facebook page of “Nurxenim Uyghur.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">He was detained for five years for participating in “illegal religious activities.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">A staffer at a neighborhood committee in Kashgar Yengisheher (Shule) county told RFA that police took away the body of Abdurishit, who died from a combination of illness and starvation during a recent coronavirus lockdown there.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">RFA </span><a href="https://www.rfa.org/english/news/uyghur/ritual-burials-11022022133359.html" rel="noopener" target="_blank"><span style="font-weight: 400;">reported</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> earlier that authorities in Xinjiang have been collecting the bodies of deceased Uyghurs, many of whom died of starvation or lack of medical treatment during lockdowns, without informing their relatives whether their corpses would be handled according to Islamic burial rituals.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Abdureshit lived in downtown Toqquzaq when police took the former school security guard to the internment camp in 2017, said an expatriate from the county who has knowledge of the situation.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">A neighborhood committee staffer in Kashgar Yengisheher said authorities took Abdurishit away to receive so-called “education” while he was working at a middle school. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Abdureshit was healthy before his detainment, he said, though he did not know if the young man had been ill when he was released or if he died because of starvation during the lockdown.</span></p>
<p><b><i>Translated by RFA Uyghur. Reported in English by Roseanne Gerin.</i></b></p>
        ]]>
    </content:encoded>

    <pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 19:05:00 -0400</pubDate>
  </item>

</channel>


</rss>


