<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<rdf:RDF
 xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
 xmlns="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/"
 xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
 xmlns:taxo="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/taxonomy/"
 xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
 xmlns:syn="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
 xmlns:admin="http://webns.net/mvcb/"
>

<channel rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/">
<title>cs.CE updates on arXiv.org</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">Computer Science -- Computational Engineering, Finance, and Science (cs.CE) updates on the arXiv.org e-print archive</description>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:date>2022-11-03T20:30:00-05:00</dc:date>
<dc:publisher>help@arxiv.org</dc:publisher>
<dc:subject>Computer Science -- Computational Engineering, Finance, and Science</dc:subject>
<syn:updateBase>1901-01-01T00:00+00:00</syn:updateBase>
<syn:updateFrequency>1</syn:updateFrequency>
<syn:updatePeriod>daily</syn:updatePeriod>
<items>
 <rdf:Seq>
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01856" />
 </rdf:Seq>
</items>
<image rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif" />
</channel>
<image rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif">
<title>arXiv.org</title>
<url>http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif</url>
<link>http://arxiv.org/</link>
</image>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01856">
<title>Human Biophysics as Network Weights: Conditional Generative Models for Ultra-fast Simulation. (arXiv:2211.01856v1 [cs.LG])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01856</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Simulations of biophysical systems have provided a huge contribution to our
fundamental understanding of human physiology and remain a central pillar for
developments in medical devices and human machine interfaces. However, despite
their successes, such simulations usually rely on highly computationally
expensive numerical modelling, which is often inefficient to adapt to new
simulation parameters. This limits their use in dynamic models of human
behavior, for example in modelling the electric fields generated by muscles in
a moving arm. We propose the alternative approach to use conditional generative
models, which can learn complex relationships between the underlying generative
conditions whilst remaining inexpensive to sample from. As a demonstration of
this concept, we present BioMime, a hybrid architecture that combines elements
of deep latent variable models and conditional adversarial training to
construct a generative model that can both transform existing data samples to
reflect new modelling assumptions and sample new data from a conditioned
distribution. We demonstrate that BioMime can learn to accurately mimic a
complex numerical model of human muscle biophysics and then use this knowledge
to continuously sample from a dynamically changing system in real-time. We
argue that transfer learning approaches with conditional generative models are
a viable solution for dynamic simulation with any numerical model.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Ma_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Shihan Ma&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Clarke_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Alexander Kenneth Clarke&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Maksymenko_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Kostiantyn Maksymenko&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Deslauriers_Gauthier_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Samuel Deslauriers-Gauthier&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Sheng_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xinjun Sheng&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zhu_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xiangyang Zhu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Farina_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Dario Farina&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
</rdf:RDF>