<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<rdf:RDF
 xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
 xmlns="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/"
 xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
 xmlns:taxo="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/taxonomy/"
 xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
 xmlns:syn="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
 xmlns:admin="http://webns.net/mvcb/"
>

<channel rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/">
<title>physics.chem-ph updates on arXiv.org</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">Physics -- Chemical Physics (physics.chem-ph) updates on the arXiv.org e-print archive</description>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:date>2022-11-03T20:30:00-05:00</dc:date>
<dc:publisher>help@arxiv.org</dc:publisher>
<dc:subject>Physics -- Chemical Physics</dc:subject>
<syn:updateBase>1901-01-01T00:00+00:00</syn:updateBase>
<syn:updateFrequency>1</syn:updateFrequency>
<syn:updatePeriod>daily</syn:updatePeriod>
<items>
 <rdf:Seq>
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01608" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01653" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01787" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01953" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.02022" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.02042" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2201.06864" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2208.06727" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2208.13633" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.01259" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.00173" />
 </rdf:Seq>
</items>
<image rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif" />
</channel>
<image rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif">
<title>arXiv.org</title>
<url>http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif</url>
<link>http://arxiv.org/</link>
</image>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01608">
<title>Detection of complex nitrogen-bearing molecule ethyl cyanide towards the hot molecular core G10.47+0.03. (arXiv:2211.01608v1 [astro-ph.GA])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01608</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The studies of the complex molecular lines towards the hot molecular cores at
millimeter and submillimeter wavelengths provide instructive knowledge about
the chemical complexity in the interstellar medium (ISM). We presented the
detection of the rotational emission lines of the complex nitrogen-bearing
molecule ethyl cyanide (C$_{2}$H$_{5}$CN) towards the hot molecular core
G10.47+0.03 using the Atacama Large Millimeter/Submillimeter Array (ALMA) band
4 observations. The estimated column density of C$_{2}$H$_{5}$CN towards
G10.47+0.03 was (9.5$\pm$0.1)$\times$10$^{16}$ cm$^{-2}$ with the rotational
temperature of 223.8$\pm$4.3 K. The estimated fractional abundance of
C$_{2}$H$_{5}$CN with respect to H$_{2}$ towards G10.47+0.03 was
1.90$\times$10$^{-8}$. We observed that the estimated fractional abundance of
C$_{2}$H$_{5}$CN is nearly similar to the simulated abundance of
C$_{2}$H$_{5}$CN which was predicted by the three-phase warm-up model from
Garrod (2013). We also discuss the possible formation mechanism of
C$_{2}$H$_{5}$CN towards the hot molecular cores and we claimed the barrierless
and exothermic radical-radical reaction between CH$_{2}$ and CH$_{2}$CN is
responsible for the production of high abundant C$_{2}$H$_{5}$CN
($\sim$10$^{-8}$) towards G10.47+0.03 during the warm-up phases.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Manna_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Arijit Manna&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Pal_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Sabyasachi Pal&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01653">
<title>Purcell-induced suppression of superradiance for molecular overlayers on noble atom surfaces. (arXiv:2211.01653v1 [quant-ph])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01653</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We study the impact of an environment on the electromagnetic responses of a
molecule in the presence of a dielectric medium. By applying the dipole-dipole
coupling between the molecule&apos;s and the environment&apos;s degrees of freedom, we
can reduce the complex system into its components and predict excitation
lifetimes of single and few molecules attached to a dielectric surface by
knowing the entire quantum-mechanical properties of the molecules, such as
transition energies and dipole moments. The derived theory allows for the
description of superradiance between two molecules depending on the geometric
arrangement between both concerning their separation and orientation with
respect to each other. We analyse the possibility of superradiance between two
molecules bound to a dielectric sphere and determine a change of the relevant
length scale where the usually considered wavelength in free space is replaced
with the binding distance, drastically reducing the length scales at which
collective effects can take place.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Fiedler_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Johannes Fiedler&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Berland_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Kristian Berland&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Buhmann_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Stefan Yoshi Buhmann&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01787">
<title>The ice surface in premelting and freezing: transition dynamics and metastable states. (arXiv:2211.01787v1 [physics.chem-ph])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01787</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The premelting of ice is well known, but not about how the premelted and
solid surfaces convert into each other. In this work, the transition dynamics
between two phases are revealed with large-scale molecular dynamics
simulations. Supercooling and superheating states exist in the transition, and
are overcome by nucleation-like processes. The natural inhomogeneity of ice
surface enhances nuclei formation, while it only accelerates premelting but not
freezing. Furthermore, the complete freezing of ice surfaces may be hindered by
the stacking order mismatch between nuclei. This work points out the importance
of metastable states in premelting studies, and calls attention to their
potential effects on related physics.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Cui_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Shifan Cui&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Chen_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Haoxiang Chen&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01953">
<title>Epitaxial hexagonal boron nitride for hydrogen generation by radiolysis of interfacial water. (arXiv:2211.01953v1 [physics.chem-ph])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01953</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Hydrogen is an important building block in global strategies towards a future
green energy system. To make this transition possible, intense scientific
efforts are needed, also in the field of materials science. Two-dimensional
crystals, such as hexagonal boron nitride (hBN), are very promising in this
regard, as it was demonstrated that micrometer-sized exfoliated flakes are
excellent barriers to molecular hydrogen. However, it remains an open question
whether large-area layers fabricated by industrially relevant methods preserve
such promising properties. In this work we show that electron beam-induced
splitting of water creates hBN bubbles that effectively store molecular
hydrogen for weeks and under extreme mechanical deformation. We demonstrate
that epitaxial hBN allows direct visualization and monitoring of the process of
hydrogen generation by radiolysis of interfacial water. Our findings show that
hBN is not only a potential candidate for hydrogen storage, but also holds
promise for the development of unconventional hydrogen production schemes.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Binder_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Johannes Binder&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Dabrowska_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Aleksandra Krystyna D&amp;#x105;browska&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Tokarczyk_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Mateusz Tokarczyk&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Ludwiczak_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Katarzyna Ludwiczak&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Bozek_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Rafa&amp;#x142; Bo&amp;#x17c;ek&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Kowalski_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Grzegorz Kowalski&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Stepniewski_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Roman St&amp;#x119;pniewski&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Wysmolek_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Andrzej Wysmo&amp;#x142;ek&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.02022">
<title>Dynamical simulations of carotenoid photoexcited states using density matrix renormalization group techniques. (arXiv:2211.02022v1 [physics.chem-ph])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.02022</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We present a dynamical simulation scheme to model the highly correlated
excited state dynamics of linear polyenes. We apply it to investigate the
internal conversion processes of carotenoids following their photoexcitation.
We use the extended Hubbard-Peierls model, $\hat{H}_{\textrm{UVP}}$, to
describe the $\pi$-electronic system coupled to nuclear degrees of freedom
supplemented by a Hamiltonian, $\hat{H}_{\epsilon}$, that explicitly breaks
both the particle-hole and two-fold rotation symmetries of idealized
carotenoids. The electronic degrees of freedom are treated quantum mechanically
by solving the time-dependent Schr\&quot;odinger equation using the adaptive
time-dependent DMRG (tDMRG) method, while nuclear dynamics are treated via the
Ehrenfest equations of motion. By defining adiabatic excited states as the
eigenstates of the full Hamiltonian,
$\hat{H}=\hat{H}_{\textrm{UVP}}+\hat{H}_{\epsilon}$, and diabatic excited
states as eigenstates of $\hat{H}_{\textrm{UVP}}$, we present a computational
framework to monitor the internal conversion process from the initial
photoexcited state to the singlet triplet-pair states of carotenoids. We
further incorporate Lanczos-DMRG to the tDMRG-Ehrenfest method to calculate
transient absorption spectra from the evolving photoexcited state. We describe
the accuracy and convergence criteria for DMRG, and show that this method
accurately describes the dynamics of carotenoid excited states. We also discuss
the effect of $\hat{H}_{\epsilon}$ on the internal conversion process, and show
that its effect on the extent of internal conversion can be described by a
Landau-Zener-type transition. This methodological paper is a companion to our
more explanatory discussion of carotenoid excited state dynamics in,
$\textit{Photoexcited state dynamics and singlet fission in carotenoids}$, D.
Manawadu, T. N. Georges and W. Barford, $\textit{J. Phys. Chem. A}$ (2023).
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Manawadu_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Dilhan Manawadu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Valentine_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Darren J. Valentine&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Barford_W/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;William Barford&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.02042">
<title>Comparison of Matsubara dynamics with exact quantum dynamics for an oscillator coupled to a dissipative bath. (arXiv:2211.02042v1 [physics.chem-ph])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.02042</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Matsubara dynamics is the classical dynamics which results when
imaginary-time path-integrals are smoothed; it conserves the quantum Boltzmann
distribution and appears in drastically approximated form in path-integral
dynamics methods such as (thermostatted) ring-polymer molecular dynamics
(T)RPMD and centroid molecular dynamics (CMD). However, it has never been
compared directly with exact quantum dynamics for non-linear operators, because
the difficulty of treating the phase has limited the number of Matsubara modes
to fewer than ten. Here, we include up to 100 Matsubara modes in simulations of
a Morse oscillator coupled to a dissipative bath of harmonic oscillators. The
trick is to analytically continue the momentum and to make a small
approximation to the bath part of the resulting ring-polymer distribution (by
neglecting correlations between Matsubara modes of opposite sign). The
numerical stability of the resulting Matsubara dynamics simulations increases
with bath strength and decreases with system anharmonicity. The dynamics of the
Matsubara `tail&apos; (of highly oscillatory modes needed to converge the quantum
Boltzmann statistics) is found to be harmonic, and can thus be computed
efficiently. For a moderately anharmonic oscillator with a strong but
subcritical coupling to the bath, the Matsubara simulations yield non-linear
$\large\langle{\hat q^2\hat q^2(t)}\large\rangle$ time-correlation functions in
almost perfect agreement with the exact quantum results (computed using
hierarchical equations of motion). Reasonable agreement is also obtained for
weaker coupling strengths, where errors arise because of numerical instability
and real-time quantum coherence. These results give strong evidence that
Matsubara dynamics correctly explains how classical dynamics arises in quantum
systems which are in thermal equilibrium.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Prada_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Adam Prada&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Pos_E/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Eszter S. P&amp;#xf3;s&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Althorpe_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Stuart C. Althorpe&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2201.06864">
<title>Acoustic monitoring of the gelation of a colloidal suspension. (arXiv:2201.06864v2 [cond-mat.soft] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2201.06864</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Because they are sensitive to mechanical properties of materials and can
propagate even in opaque systems, acoustic waves provides us with a powerful
characterization tool in numerous fields. Common techniques mostly rely on
time-of-flight measurements and do not exploit the spectral content: however,
sound speed and attenuation spectra contain rich information. Such an acoustic
spectroscopy already exists and allows to retrieve subtle information on
systems of well-known physico-chemistry, but modeling becomes out of reach for
industrial systems. In this article, we use a simple empirical approach to
monitor the gelation of silica suspensions: we show that the gelation time
obtained from acoustic measurements is proportional to this determined with
more conventional rheological characterization. Such a results thus opens the
way for in-situ monitoring of time-evolving systems in industrial context with
acoustic methods only.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Belicard_N/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Nicolas B&amp;#xe9;licard&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Niemet_Mabiala_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Marc Junior Ni&amp;#xe9;met-Mabiala&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Tourvieille_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jean-No&amp;#xeb;l Tourvieille&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Lidon_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Pierre Lidon&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2208.06727">
<title>Reliable emulation of complex functionals by active learning with error control. (arXiv:2208.06727v2 [physics.chem-ph] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2208.06727</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;A statistical emulator can be used as a surrogate of complex physics-based
calculations to drastically reduce the computational cost. Its successful
implementation hinges on an accurate representation of the nonlinear response
surface with a high-dimensional input space. Conventional ``space-filling&apos;&apos;
designs, including random sampling and Latin hypercube sampling, become
inefficient as the dimensionality of the input variables increases, and the
predictive accuracy of the emulator can degrade substantially for a test input
distant from the training input set. To address this fundamental challenge, we
develop a reliable emulator for predicting complex functionals by active
learning with error control (ALEC). The algorithm is applicable to
infinite-dimensional mapping with high-fidelity predictions and a controlled
predictive error. The computational efficiency has been demonstrated by
emulating the classical density functional theory (cDFT) calculations, a
statistical-mechanical method widely used in modeling the equilibrium
properties of complex molecular systems. We show that ALEC is much more
accurate than conventional emulators based on the Gaussian processes with
``space-filling&apos;&apos; designs and alternative active learning methods. Besides, it
is computationally more efficient than direct cDFT calculations. ALEC can be a
reliable building block for emulating expensive functionals owing to its
minimal computational cost, controllable predictive error, and fully automatic
features.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Fang_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xinyi Fang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Gu_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Mengyang Gu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Wu_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jianzhong Wu&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2208.13633">
<title>Liquid-liquid transition in water from first principles. (arXiv:2208.13633v2 [cond-mat.stat-mech] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2208.13633</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;A longstanding question in water research is the possibility that supercooled
liquid water can undergo a liquid-liquid phase transition (LLT) into high- and
low-density liquids. We used several complementary molecular simulation
techniques to evaluate the possibility of an LLT in an ab initio neural network
model of water trained on density functional theory calculations with the SCAN
exchange correlation functional. We conclusively show the existence of a
first-order LLT and an associated critical point in the SCAN description of
water, representing the first definitive computational evidence for an LLT in
water from first principles.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Gartner_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Thomas E. Gartner III&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Piaggi_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Pablo M. Piaggi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Car_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Roberto Car&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Panagiotopoulos_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Athanassios Z. Panagiotopoulos&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Debenedetti_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Pablo G. Debenedetti&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.01259">
<title>A perspective on microscopic pressure (stress) tensor: history, current understanding, and future challenges. (arXiv:2210.01259v2 [physics.chem-ph] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.01259</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The pressure tensor (equivalent to the negative stress tensor) at both
microscopic and macroscopic levels is fundamental to many aspects of
engineering and science, including fluid dynamics, solid mechanics, biophysics,
and thermodynamics. In this perspective paper, we review methods to calculate
the microscopic pressure tensor. Connections between different pressure forms
for equilibrium and non-equilibrium systems are established. We also point out
several challenges in the field, including the historical controversies over
the definition of the microscopic pressure tensor; the difficulties with
many-body and long-range potentials; the insufficiency of software and
computational tools; and the lack of experimental routes to probe the pressure
tensor at the nanoscale. Possible future directions are suggested.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Shi_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Kaihang Shi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Smith_E/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Edward Smith&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Santiso_E/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Erik E. Santiso&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Gubbins_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Keith E. Gubbins&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.00173">
<title>Density Matrix Renormalization Group for Transcorrelated Hamiltonians: Ground and Excited States in \emph{ab initio} Systems. (arXiv:2211.00173v2 [physics.chem-ph] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.00173</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We present the theory of a density matrix renormalization group (DMRG)
algorithm which can solve for both the ground and excited states of
non-Hermitian transcorrelated Hamiltonians, and show applications in \emph{ab
initio} molecular systems. Transcorrelation (TC) accelerates the basis set
convergence rate by including known physics (such as, but not limited to, the
electron-electron cusp) in the Jastrow factor used for the similarity
transformation. It also improves the accuracy of approximate methods such as
coupled cluster singles and doubles (CCSD) as shown by some recent studies.
However, the non-Hermiticity of the TC Hamiltonians poses challenges for
variational methods like DMRG. Imaginary-time evolution on the matrix product
state (MPS) in the DMRG framework has been proposed to circumvent this problem;
but this is currently limited to treating the ground state, and has lower
efficiency than the time-independent DMRG (TI-DMRG), due to the need to
eliminate Trotter errors. In this work, we show that with minimal changes to
the existing TI-DMRG algorithm, namely replacing the original Davidson solver
with the general Davidson solver to solve the non-Hermitian effective
Hamiltonians at each site for a few low-lying right eigenstates, and following
the rest of the original DMRG recipe, one can find the ground and excited
states with improved efficiency compared to the original DMRG when
extrapolating to the infinite bond dimension limit in the same basis set.
Accelerated basis set convergence rate is also observed, as expected, within
the TC framework.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Liao_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ke Liao&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Zhai_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Huanchen Zhai&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Christlmaier_E/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Evelin Martine Christlmaier&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Schraivogel_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Thomas Schraivogel&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Rios_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Pablo L&amp;#xf3;pez R&amp;#xed;os&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Kats_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Daniel Kats&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Alavi_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ali Alavi&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
</rdf:RDF>