<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<rdf:RDF
 xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
 xmlns="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/"
 xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
 xmlns:taxo="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/taxonomy/"
 xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
 xmlns:syn="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
 xmlns:admin="http://webns.net/mvcb/"
>

<channel rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/">
<title>physics.class-ph updates on arXiv.org</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">Physics -- Classical Physics (physics.class-ph) updates on the arXiv.org e-print archive</description>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:date>2022-11-03T20:30:00-05:00</dc:date>
<dc:publisher>help@arxiv.org</dc:publisher>
<dc:subject>Physics -- Classical Physics</dc:subject>
<syn:updateBase>1901-01-01T00:00+00:00</syn:updateBase>
<syn:updateFrequency>1</syn:updateFrequency>
<syn:updatePeriod>daily</syn:updatePeriod>
<items>
 <rdf:Seq>
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01369" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01850" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01968" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01995" />
 </rdf:Seq>
</items>
<image rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif" />
</channel>
<image rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif">
<title>arXiv.org</title>
<url>http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif</url>
<link>http://arxiv.org/</link>
</image>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01369">
<title>Gravitational Dimensionality Reduction Using Newtonian Gravity and Einstein&apos;s General Relativity. (arXiv:2211.01369v1 [cs.LG])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01369</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Due to the effectiveness of using machine learning in physics, it has been
widely received increased attention in the literature. However, the notion of
applying physics in machine learning has not been given much awareness to. This
work is a hybrid of physics and machine learning where concepts of physics are
used in machine learning. We propose the supervised Gravitational
Dimensionality Reduction (GDR) algorithm where the data points of every class
are moved to each other for reduction of intra-class variances and better
separation of classes. For every data point, the other points are considered to
be gravitational particles, such as stars, where the point is attracted to the
points of its class by gravity. The data points are first projected onto a
spacetime manifold using principal component analysis. We propose two variants
of GDR -- one with the Newtonian gravity and one with the Einstein&apos;s general
relativity. The former uses Newtonian gravity in a straight line between points
but the latter moves data points along the geodesics of spacetime manifold. For
GDR with relativity gravitation, we use both Schwarzschild and Minkowski metric
tensors to cover both general relativity and special relativity. Our
simulations show the effectiveness of GDR in discrimination of classes.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Ghojogh_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Benyamin Ghojogh&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Sharma_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Smriti Sharma&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01850">
<title>Hints of the Photonic Nature of the Electromagnetic fields in Classical Electrodynamics and its connection to the electronic charge and vacuum energy density. (arXiv:2211.01850v1 [physics.class-ph])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01850</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The electromagnetic fields of a long dipole working without dispersive and
dissipative losses are analyzed in the frequency domains. The dipole produces
radiation in bursts of duration T/2 where T is the period of oscillation. The
parameter studied in this paper is the energy, U, dissipated in a single burst
of radiation of duration T/2. We have studied how U vary as a function of the
charge associated with the current in the dipole and the ratio of the length of
the dipole and its radius. We have observed a remarkable result when this ratio
is equal to the ratio of the radius of the universe to the Bohr radius. Our
results, based purely on the classical electrodynamics and general relativity,
show that, as the magnitude of the oscillating charge (as defined by the root
mean square) reduces to the electronic charge, the energy dissipated in a
single burst of radiation reduces to hv, where v is the frequency of
oscillation and h is the Planck constant. The importance of this finding is
discussed. In particular, the results show that the existence of a minimum free
charge in nature, i.e., electronic charge, is a direct consequence of the
photonic nature of the electromagnetic fields. Furthermore, the presented
findings allow to derive for the first time an expression for the vacuum energy
density of the universe in terms of the other fundamental constants in nature,
the prediction of which is consistent with experimental observations. This
equation, which combines the vacuum energy, electronic charge and mass, speed
of light, gravitational constant and Planck constant, creates a link between
classical field theories (i.e., classical electrodynamics and general
relativity) and quantum mechanics.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Cooray_V/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Vernon Cooray&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Cooray_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Gerald Cooray&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Rubinstein_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Marcos Rubinstein&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Rachidi_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Farhad Rachidi&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01968">
<title>Longitudinal waves dispersion control through the affine deformation of the interlaced wire medium. (arXiv:2211.01968v1 [physics.class-ph])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01968</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We have studied dispersion properties of interlaced wire media with geometry
deformed by affine transformation. It is revealed that the metamaterials
support eigenmodes with longitudinal polarization at low frequency range for
all deformations. The isofrequency surfaces of the matamaterial are centered at
the points at the edges of the Brillouin zone (not at Gamma-point) and have
shape of ellipsoids. The refraction indexes corresponding to the ellipsoids are
analysed both analytically and numerically.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Sakhno_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Denis Sakhno&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Koreshin_E/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Eugene Koreshin&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Belov_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Pavel A. Belov&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01995">
<title>Computing zero-group-velocity points in anisotropic elastic waveguides: globally and locally convergent methods. (arXiv:2211.01995v1 [physics.class-ph])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01995</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Dispersion curves of elastic waveguides exhibit points where the group
velocity vanishes while the wavenumber remains finite. These are the so-called
zero-group-velocity (ZGV) points. As the elastodynamic energy at these points
remains confined close to the source, they are of practical interest for
nondestructive testing and quantitative characterization of structures. These
applications rely on the correct prediction of the ZGV points. In this
contribution, we first model the ZGV resonances in anisotropic plates based on
the appearance of an exceptional mode. The resulting governing equation is
interpreted as a two-parameter eigenvalue problem. We then present three
complementary numerical procedures capable of computing ZGV points in arbitrary
nondissipative elastic waveguides. The first method is globally convergent and
guarantees to find all ZGV points but can only be used for small problems. The
second procedure is a very fast, generally-applicable, Newton-type iteration
that is locally convergent and requires initial guesses. The third method
combines both kind of approaches and yields a procedure that is applicable to
large problems, does not require initial guesses and is likely to find all ZGV
points.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Kiefer_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Daniel A. Kiefer&lt;/a&gt; (1), &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Plestenjak_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Bor Plestenjak&lt;/a&gt; (2), &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Gravenkamp_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Hauke Gravenkamp&lt;/a&gt; (3), &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Prada_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Claire Prada&lt;/a&gt; (1) ((1) Institut Langevin, ESPCI Paris, Universit&amp;#xe9; PSL, CNRS, Paris, France, (2) Faculty of Mathematics and Physics, University of Ljubljana, Ljubljana, Slovenia, (3) International Centre for Numerical Methods in Engineering (CIMNE), Barcelona, Spain)</dc:creator>
</item>
</rdf:RDF>