<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<rdf:RDF
 xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
 xmlns="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/"
 xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
 xmlns:taxo="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/taxonomy/"
 xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
 xmlns:syn="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
 xmlns:admin="http://webns.net/mvcb/"
>

<channel rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/">
<title>q-bio.QM updates on arXiv.org</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">Quantitative Biology -- Quantitative Methods (q-bio.QM) updates on the arXiv.org e-print archive</description>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:date>2022-11-03T20:30:00-05:00</dc:date>
<dc:publisher>help@arxiv.org</dc:publisher>
<dc:subject>Quantitative Biology -- Quantitative Methods</dc:subject>
<syn:updateBase>1901-01-01T00:00+00:00</syn:updateBase>
<syn:updateFrequency>1</syn:updateFrequency>
<syn:updatePeriod>daily</syn:updatePeriod>
<items>
 <rdf:Seq>
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01885" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2003.13825" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2205.02645" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.01123" />
 </rdf:Seq>
</items>
<image rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif" />
</channel>
<image rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif">
<title>arXiv.org</title>
<url>http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif</url>
<link>http://arxiv.org/</link>
</image>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01885">
<title>Using U-Net Network for Efficient Brain Tumor Segmentation in MRI Images. (arXiv:2211.01885v1 [eess.IV])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01885</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Magnetic Resonance Imaging (MRI) is the most commonly used non-intrusive
technique for medical image acquisition. Brain tumor segmentation is the
process of algorithmically identifying tumors in brain MRI scans. While many
approaches have been proposed in the literature for brain tumor segmentation,
this paper proposes a lightweight implementation of U-Net. Apart from providing
real-time segmentation of MRI scans, the proposed architecture does not need
large amount of data to train the proposed lightweight U-Net. Moreover, no
additional data augmentation step is required. The lightweight U-Net shows very
promising results on BITE dataset and it achieves a mean
intersection-over-union (IoU) of 89% while outperforming the standard benchmark
algorithms. Additionally, this work demonstrates an effective use of the three
perspective planes, instead of the original three-dimensional volumetric
images, for simplified brain tumor segmentation.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/eess/1/au:+Walsh_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jason Walsh&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/eess/1/au:+Othmani_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Alice Othmani&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/eess/1/au:+Jain_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Mayank Jain&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/eess/1/au:+Dev_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Soumyabrata Dev&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2003.13825">
<title>On the role of theory and modeling in neuroscience. (arXiv:2003.13825v5 [q-bio.NC] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2003.13825</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;In recent years, the field of neuroscience has gone through rapid
experimental advances and a significant increase in the use of quantitative and
computational methods. This growth has created a need for clearer analyses of
the theory and modeling approaches used in the field. This issue is
particularly complex in neuroscience because the field studies phenomena across
a wide range of scales and often requires consideration of these phenomena at
varying degrees of abstraction, from precise biophysical interactions to the
computations they implement. We argue that a pragmatic perspective of science,
in which descriptive, mechanistic, and normative approaches each play a
distinct role in defining and bridging levels of abstraction will facilitate
neuroscientific practice. This analysis leads to methodological suggestions,
including selecting a level of abstraction that is appropriate for a given
problem, identifying transfer functions to connect models and data, and the use
of models themselves as a form of experiment.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/q-bio/1/au:+Levenstein_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Daniel Levenstein&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/q-bio/1/au:+Alvarez_V/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Veronica A. Alvarez&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/q-bio/1/au:+Amarasingham_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Asohan Amarasingham&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/q-bio/1/au:+Azab_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Habiba Azab&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/q-bio/1/au:+Chen_Z/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Zhe Sage Chen&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/q-bio/1/au:+Gerkin_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Richard C. Gerkin&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/q-bio/1/au:+Hasenstaub_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Andrea Hasenstaub&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/q-bio/1/au:+Iyer_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ramakrishnan Iyer&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/q-bio/1/au:+Jolivet_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Renaud B. Jolivet&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/q-bio/1/au:+Marzen_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Sarah Marzen&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/q-bio/1/au:+Monaco_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Joseph D. Monaco&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/q-bio/1/au:+Prinz_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Astrid A. Prinz&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/q-bio/1/au:+Quraishi_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Salma Quraishi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/q-bio/1/au:+Santamaria_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Fidel Santamaria&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/q-bio/1/au:+Shivkumar_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Sabyasachi Shivkumar&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/q-bio/1/au:+Singh_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Matthew F. Singh&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/q-bio/1/au:+Traub_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Roger Traub&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/q-bio/1/au:+Rotstein_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Horacio G. Rotstein&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/q-bio/1/au:+Nadim_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Farzan Nadim&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/q-bio/1/au:+Redish_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;A. David Redish&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2205.02645">
<title>PyDaddy: A Python package for discovering stochastic dynamical equations from timeseries data. (arXiv:2205.02645v2 [q-bio.QM] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2205.02645</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Most real-world ecological dynamics, ranging from ecosystem dynamics to
collective animal movement, are inherently stochastic in nature. Stochastic
differential equations (SDEs) are a popular modelling framework to model
dynamics with intrinsic randomness. Here, we focus on the inverse question: If
one has empirically measured time-series data from some system of interest, is
it possible to discover the SDE model that best describes the data. Here, we
present PyDaddy (PYthon library for DAta Driven DYnamics), a toolbox to
construct and analyze interpretable SDE models based on time-series data. We
combine traditional approaches for data-driven SDE reconstruction with an
equation learning approach, to derive symbolic equations governing the
stochastic dynamics. The toolkit is presented as an open-source Python library,
and consists of tools to construct and analyze SDEs. Functionality is included
for visual examination of the stochastic structure of the data, guided
extraction of the functional form of the SDE, and diagnosis and debugging of
the underlying assumptions and the extracted model. Using simulated time-series
datasets, exhibiting a wide range of dynamics, we show that PyDaddy is able to
correctly identify underlying SDE models. We demonstrate the applicability of
the toolkit to real-world data using a previously published movement data of a
fish school. Starting from the time-series of the observed polarization of the
school, pyDaddy readily discovers the SDE model governing the dynamics of group
polarization. The model recovered by PyDaddy is consistent with the previous
study. In summary, stochastic and noise-induced effects are central to the
dynamics of many biological systems. In this context, we present an easy-to-use
package to reconstruct SDEs from timeseries data.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/q-bio/1/au:+Nabeel_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Arshed Nabeel&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/q-bio/1/au:+Karichannavar_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ashwin Karichannavar&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/q-bio/1/au:+Palathingal_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Shuaib Palathingal&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/q-bio/1/au:+Jhawar_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jitesh Jhawar&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/q-bio/1/au:+M_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Danny Raj M&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/q-bio/1/au:+Guttal_V/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Vishwesha Guttal&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.01123">
<title>Towards Learned Simulators for Cell Migration. (arXiv:2210.01123v2 [q-bio.QM] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.01123</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Simulators driven by deep learning are gaining popularity as a tool for
efficiently emulating accurate but expensive numerical simulators. Successful
applications of such neural simulators can be found in the domains of physics,
chemistry, and structural biology, amongst others. Likewise, a neural simulator
for cellular dynamics can augment lab experiments and traditional computational
methods to enhance our understanding of a cell&apos;s interaction with its physical
environment. In this work, we propose an autoregressive probabilistic model
that can reproduce spatiotemporal dynamics of single cell migration,
traditionally simulated with the Cellular Potts model. We observe that standard
single-step training methods do not only lead to inconsistent rollout
stability, but also fail to accurately capture the stochastic aspects of the
dynamics, and we propose training strategies to mitigate these issues. Our
evaluation on two proof-of-concept experimental scenarios shows that neural
methods have the potential to faithfully simulate stochastic cellular dynamics
at least an order of magnitude faster than a state-of-the-art implementation of
the Cellular Potts model.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/q-bio/1/au:+Minartz_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Koen Minartz&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/q-bio/1/au:+Poels_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yoeri Poels&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/q-bio/1/au:+Menkovski_V/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Vlado Menkovski&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
</rdf:RDF>