<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns:yt="http://www.youtube.com/xml/schemas/2015" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
 <link rel="self" href="http://www.youtube.com/feeds/videos.xml?channel_id=UCqnbDFdCpuN8CMEg0VuEBqA"/>
 <id>yt:channel:UCqnbDFdCpuN8CMEg0VuEBqA</id>
 <yt:channelId>UCqnbDFdCpuN8CMEg0VuEBqA</yt:channelId>
 <title>The New York Times</title>
 <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCqnbDFdCpuN8CMEg0VuEBqA"/>
 <author>
  <name>The New York Times</name>
  <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCqnbDFdCpuN8CMEg0VuEBqA</uri>
 </author>
 <published>2006-10-13T21:57:36+00:00</published>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:mP6u0KqyN1E</id>
  <yt:videoId>mP6u0KqyN1E</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCqnbDFdCpuN8CMEg0VuEBqA</yt:channelId>
  <title>Millions Suffered. Hundreds Died. Greg Abbott Will Probably Get Re-Elected Anyway. | NYT Opinion</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=mP6u0KqyN1E"/>
  <author>
   <name>The New York Times</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCqnbDFdCpuN8CMEg0VuEBqA</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-11-04T14:00:34+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-11-05T07:35:50+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Millions Suffered. Hundreds Died. Greg Abbott Will Probably Get Re-Elected Anyway. | NYT Opinion</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/mP6u0KqyN1E?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i2.ytimg.com/vi/mP6u0KqyN1E/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>Should politicians be held accountable for disasters which unfold under their watch? It’s a question for Texans voting for governor next week.

The incumbent, Greg Abbott, was at the helm during a storm in February 2021 in which the state — sometimes billed as the “energy capital of America” — was paralyzed by power failures. About 4.5 million homes lost electricity and at least 240 people died in freezing temperatures.

While the storm blanketed most of the United States, only Texas suffered such widespread blackouts and high death toll.

In the Opinion video above, we reveal how Mr. Abbott’s decisions before and during the storm allowed an entirely preventable humanitarian catastrophe to unfold. Among the victims was 87-year-old Connie Mae Richey, whose terrible story was brought to light in the documentary “Protecting the Greed.”

We show how fossil fuel companies made billions in unexpected profits during the storm and how some later rewarded Mr. Abbott with campaign donations.

Quick to blame others, Mr. Abbott somehow dodged full accountability — indeed, polls suggest that he is sailing toward a third term. His likely success next week shows that when Americans vote increasingly along party lines, politicians can fail with impunity.
&#13;
Subscribe: http://bit.ly/U8Ys7n&#13;
More from The New York Times Video:  http://nytimes.com/video&#13;
----------&#13;
Whether it's reporting on conflicts abroad and political divisions at home, or covering the latest style trends and scientific developments, New York Times video journalists provide a revealing and unforgettable view of the world. It's all the news that's fit to watch.</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="2115" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="44236"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:oRNk6I6zxrM</id>
  <yt:videoId>oRNk6I6zxrM</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCqnbDFdCpuN8CMEg0VuEBqA</yt:channelId>
  <title>How a Diner Talk Builds Tension in ‘The Good Nurse’ | Anatomy of a Scene</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=oRNk6I6zxrM"/>
  <author>
   <name>The New York Times</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCqnbDFdCpuN8CMEg0VuEBqA</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-10-31T15:00:39+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-11-01T07:32:15+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>How a Diner Talk Builds Tension in ‘The Good Nurse’ | Anatomy of a Scene</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/oRNk6I6zxrM?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i4.ytimg.com/vi/oRNk6I6zxrM/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>A staple in American cinema, the diner scene has been a go-to for acclaimed filmmakers like Martin Scorsese, Quentin Tarantino and David Fincher. Now, Tobias Lindholm, the Danish director making his first feature in the United States, “The Good Nurse,” hopes to add a memorable diner scene to the collection.

The movie is based on the story of Charles Cullen, the nurse who confessed to killing 29 patients at multiple hospitals in his career. Eddie Redmayne plays Charlie, and Jessica Chastain portrays Amy Loughren, a nurse who figures out his crimes after the two have become friends.

In this scene, Amy has set up a meeting with Charlie at a diner. She’s wearing a wire, and detectives are listening in. Her goal is to get Charlie to confess to the murders. The sequence mixes lunch-date mundanity with high-stakes tension in intriguing ways.

Narrating the video, Lindholm discusses how some of the elements that heighten the anxiety of the scene were executed — from tight framing to the movement outside that frame to the tools the actors use to convey a mix of emotions.

Read the New York Times review: https://nyti.ms/3sGTDoZ
Subscribe: http://bit.ly/U8Ys7n&#13;
More from The New York Times Video:  http://nytimes.com/video&#13;
----------&#13;
Whether it's reporting on conflicts abroad and political divisions at home, or covering the latest style trends and scientific developments, New York Times video journalists provide a revealing and unforgettable view of the world. It's all the news that's fit to watch.</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="241" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="10038"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:HfaWxHQ-Sng</id>
  <yt:videoId>HfaWxHQ-Sng</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCqnbDFdCpuN8CMEg0VuEBqA</yt:channelId>
  <title>Brazil's Presidential Election Will Determine the Planet's Future | NYT Opinion</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=HfaWxHQ-Sng"/>
  <author>
   <name>The New York Times</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCqnbDFdCpuN8CMEg0VuEBqA</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-10-28T14:00:09+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-10-29T08:32:01+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Brazil's Presidential Election Will Determine the Planet's Future | NYT Opinion</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/HfaWxHQ-Sng?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i1.ytimg.com/vi/HfaWxHQ-Sng/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>On Oct. 30, Brazilians go to the polls to elect their next president. But at stake is something far more important than just the leadership of one of the world’s largest economies.

Whoever wins will inherit control over more than half of the Amazon rainforest and, by extension, will determine the conditions for future life on Earth.

In the Opinion video above, Brazilian Indigenous leader Txai Suruí argues that this election is the last chance to save the Amazon.

Because of soaring deforestation rates under President Jair Bolsonaro, the Amazon ecosystem is on the brink of catastrophe. The loss of millions of trees has already caused decreased rainfall. Areas not yet turned to ranchland are projected to shift from dense forest into dry savannah as the Amazon reaches a “tipping point” — of spiraling degradation from which there is no return.

This collapse will be felt far beyond the Amazon. Rainfall across two continents, including over California’s agricultural heartlands, comes from the Amazon. Lifesaving medicines are derived from its species. Billions of tons of carbon are held in its trees. Our dependence on this ecosystem cannot be overstated.

President Bolsonaro is defiant in his desire to sacrifice the Amazon, its conservation reserves and Indigenous lands to agribusiness and “development.” His challenger, Luiz Inácio Lula da Silva, promises to stop the destruction and proved that he can be tough on environmental crime and deliver results during two previous terms in office.

For many Brazilians, this will be a painful election between two deeply flawed candidates. But for the future of human life on this planet, there is only one right choice.
&#13;
Subscribe: http://bit.ly/U8Ys7n&#13;
More from The New York Times Video:  http://nytimes.com/video&#13;
----------&#13;
Whether it's reporting on conflicts abroad and political divisions at home, or covering the latest style trends and scientific developments, New York Times video journalists provide a revealing and unforgettable view of the world. It's all the news that's fit to watch.</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="6204" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="99111"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:eR2tI7Irfdo</id>
  <yt:videoId>eR2tI7Irfdo</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCqnbDFdCpuN8CMEg0VuEBqA</yt:channelId>
  <title>This Pro-Life Pastor's Sermon on Abortion Deserves a Larger Audience  | NYT Opinion</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=eR2tI7Irfdo"/>
  <author>
   <name>The New York Times</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCqnbDFdCpuN8CMEg0VuEBqA</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-10-26T17:00:25+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-10-29T19:32:48+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>This Pro-Life Pastor's Sermon on Abortion Deserves a Larger Audience  | NYT Opinion</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/eR2tI7Irfdo?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i2.ytimg.com/vi/eR2tI7Irfdo/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>In the debate over abortion, it often seems there’s not much room for nuance: You’re either for it or against it.

But in the Opinion video above, the Rev. Clinton L. Stancil, the pastor of Wayman A.M.E. Church in St. Louis, articulates a position that is heard all too rarely, particularly among faith leaders.

He is opposed to abortion on moral grounds and counsels his parishioners against getting the procedure. But he is also vehemently supportive of a woman’s right to choose. In an interview with Opinion Video, he called the Supreme Court decision that eliminated the constitutional right to abortion “a tragedy.”

Mr. Stancil, 60, who was a sales executive for IBM before entering the ministry, anchors his pro-choice position in Scripture. But he is also deeply concerned that the new restrictions on abortion access will disproportionately harm Black communities, spurring poverty and crime. (Black women have a far higher abortion rate than white women, according to the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention.)

Mr. Stancil, who is active on civil rights issues in St. Louis and has discussed the abortion debate in his sermons this year, offered to deliver his guest essay in the form of a sermon. We recorded it as a postscript to a Sunday service this month.

As it has for many houses of worship in the United States, attendance at Wayman A.M.E. still hasn’t rebounded to prepandemic levels. So Mr. Stancil, a kinetic preacher whose partly improvised sermons often run half an hour or more, finds himself these days speaking to a congregation that is mostly tuning in via the church’s live streams. We thought his message deserved a wider audience.
&#13;
Subscribe: http://bit.ly/U8Ys7n&#13;
More from The New York Times Video:  http://nytimes.com/video&#13;
----------&#13;
Whether it's reporting on conflicts abroad and political divisions at home, or covering the latest style trends and scientific developments, New York Times video journalists provide a revealing and unforgettable view of the world. It's all the news that's fit to watch.</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="1198" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="20055"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:oAHWHHg5XWU</id>
  <yt:videoId>oAHWHHg5XWU</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCqnbDFdCpuN8CMEg0VuEBqA</yt:channelId>
  <title>How ‘Triangle of Sadness’ Turns the Tables of Status | Anatomy of a Scene</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=oAHWHHg5XWU"/>
  <author>
   <name>The New York Times</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCqnbDFdCpuN8CMEg0VuEBqA</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-10-21T15:00:37+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-10-22T09:06:38+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>How ‘Triangle of Sadness’ Turns the Tables of Status | Anatomy of a Scene</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/oAHWHHg5XWU?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i4.ytimg.com/vi/oAHWHHg5XWU/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>The wealthy get a sendup and a send-off in “Triangle of Sadness,” the latest feature from the Swedish director Ruben Ostlund, now in theaters.

The film begins in the fashion world, following an influencer-model couple (Charlbi Dean and Harris Dickinson). The two get a free cruise on a luxury yacht, where they meet an assembly of very rich passengers. But things take a turn in the third act, when a smattering of those passengers turn up shipwrecked on an island.

In this sequence, the characters, having spent an eerie first night on the island, wake up to see a lifeboat with only one person inside: Abigail (Dolly De Leon), who was a cleaning lady on the yacht.

“What was important for me,” Ostlund said, “was that I wanted to swap the power structures on the island. I wanted to turn them upside-down.” This scene begins that gradual change in the hierarchy, as Abigail, who has arrived with sustenance (as well as practical skills), begins to realize that she may have a currency on the island that she didn’t have before.

Read the New York Times review: https://nyti.ms/3SBHb4J
&#13;
Subscribe: http://bit.ly/U8Ys7n&#13;
More from The New York Times Video:  http://nytimes.com/video&#13;
----------&#13;
Whether it's reporting on conflicts abroad and political divisions at home, or covering the latest style trends and scientific developments, New York Times video journalists provide a revealing and unforgettable view of the world. It's all the news that's fit to watch.</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="437" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="29070"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:5eHWVjUAukU</id>
  <yt:videoId>5eHWVjUAukU</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCqnbDFdCpuN8CMEg0VuEBqA</yt:channelId>
  <title>Elon Musk Can't Fix Your Commute | NYT Opinion</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=5eHWVjUAukU"/>
  <author>
   <name>The New York Times</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCqnbDFdCpuN8CMEg0VuEBqA</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-10-14T14:00:05+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-10-15T00:28:13+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Elon Musk Can't Fix Your Commute | NYT Opinion</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/5eHWVjUAukU?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i2.ytimg.com/vi/5eHWVjUAukU/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>Say what you will about Elon Musk, but the man has ideas. Loads of them.

He has ideas about how to improve Twitter and colonize Mars. He has ideas about space tourism and the future of artificial intelligence. He has ideas about how to end the war in Ukraine and save children trapped in underground caves.

But in the video above, Adam Kovacs, who runs the YouTube channel Adam Something, suggests that unrelenting bravado and tremendous wealth don’t necessarily make bad ideas good.

Mr. Kovacs, who has developed a large following for his critiques of flawed urban planning and design, takes a close look at Mr. Musk’s proposals to revolutionize mass transit: the Hyperloop and the Boring Loop.

Both ideas have generated much excitement and even investment, but as Mr. Kovacs explains, they are unnecessarily complicated and not designed for real people. There’s even a word for exciting but catastrophically flawed concepts like this: “gadgetbahn.”

Mr. Musk, he says, “would rather pump millions of dollars into some made-up tech fantasy than doing something actually useful for us mortals.”
&#13;
Subscribe: http://bit.ly/U8Ys7n&#13;
More from The New York Times Video:  http://nytimes.com/video&#13;
----------&#13;
Whether it's reporting on conflicts abroad and political divisions at home, or covering the latest style trends and scientific developments, New York Times video journalists provide a revealing and unforgettable view of the world. It's all the news that's fit to watch.</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="12743" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="163018"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:bial9jhOg5s</id>
  <yt:videoId>bial9jhOg5s</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCqnbDFdCpuN8CMEg0VuEBqA</yt:channelId>
  <title>Remembering Angela Lansbury</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=bial9jhOg5s"/>
  <author>
   <name>The New York Times</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCqnbDFdCpuN8CMEg0VuEBqA</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-10-12T01:15:02+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-10-12T09:21:44+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Remembering Angela Lansbury</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/bial9jhOg5s?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i3.ytimg.com/vi/bial9jhOg5s/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>The New York Times sat down with Angela Lansbury in 2010 to discuss her life and accomplishments on the stage and screen. She spoke with us with the understanding the interview would be published only after her death.

Read the story here: https://nyti.ms/3SVHs35&#13;
Subscribe: http://bit.ly/U8Ys7n&#13;
More from The New York Times Video:  http://nytimes.com/video&#13;
----------&#13;
Whether it's reporting on conflicts abroad and political divisions at home, or covering the latest style trends and scientific developments, New York Times video journalists provide a revealing and unforgettable view of the world. It's all the news that's fit to watch.</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="11550" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="424705"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:hE76GCkx9O8</id>
  <yt:videoId>hE76GCkx9O8</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCqnbDFdCpuN8CMEg0VuEBqA</yt:channelId>
  <title>Inside the Final Days of the Doctor China Tried to Silence | Visual Investigations</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hE76GCkx9O8"/>
  <author>
   <name>The New York Times</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCqnbDFdCpuN8CMEg0VuEBqA</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-10-06T17:00:24+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-10-21T21:55:53+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Inside the Final Days of the Doctor China Tried to Silence | Visual Investigations</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/hE76GCkx9O8?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i1.ytimg.com/vi/hE76GCkx9O8/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>A New York Times video investigation reveals new details about Dr. Li Wenliang’s illness and death from Covid-19 based on medical records and an exclusive interview with a key witness.
&#13;
Subscribe: http://bit.ly/U8Ys7n&#13;
More from The New York Times Video:  http://nytimes.com/video&#13;
----------&#13;
Whether it's reporting on conflicts abroad and political divisions at home, or covering the latest style trends and scientific developments, New York Times video journalists provide a revealing and unforgettable view of the world. It's all the news that's fit to watch.</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="6575" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="165642"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:yODghavE__k</id>
  <yt:videoId>yODghavE__k</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCqnbDFdCpuN8CMEg0VuEBqA</yt:channelId>
  <title>Watch Billy Eichner and Luke Macfarlane on an Awkward Date in ‘Bros’ | Anatomy of a Scene</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=yODghavE__k"/>
  <author>
   <name>The New York Times</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCqnbDFdCpuN8CMEg0VuEBqA</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-09-30T17:00:30+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-10-21T21:51:14+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Watch Billy Eichner and Luke Macfarlane on an Awkward Date in ‘Bros’ | Anatomy of a Scene</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/yODghavE__k?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i2.ytimg.com/vi/yODghavE__k/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>Neither Bobby (Billy Eichner) nor Aaron (Luke Macfarlane) are the dating type, which only adds to the tension of their Central Park encounter in this scene from “Bros.”

Bobby has brought a large blanket to sit on, and Aaron instead chooses a spot on the grass. Aaron also seems distracted by the shirtless dudes playing football, while Bobby becomes convinced that he’s not Aaron’s type. Narrating the scene, the director Nicholas Stoller, who also co-wrote the screenplay with Eichner, said it was based on Eichner’s real experience when he brought a blanket to the park and his date refused to sit on it.

But the scene, in both a passive-aggressive, and then just plain aggressive way, shows how the two characters are beginning to fall for each other.

“It was important to me to dramatize this shift from trying to be not vulnerable in any way to slowly letting their guard down,” Stoller said. “And because it’s a comedy, we needed to do it comedically, but it also needed to play romantically.”

Because Bobby feels a little threatened by Aaron’s attraction to athletic, sports-focused “dumb guys,” as he puts it, he interrogates Aaron about that attraction, which leads to some shoving that mirrors that of the guys playing football. That transitions to an intimate moment, which acts as both a tension-breaking joke and a narrative bridge to a possible new direction for these characters.

Read the New York Times review: https://nyti.ms/3Cne8Ne
Subscribe: http://bit.ly/U8Ys7n&#13;
More from The New York Times Video:  http://nytimes.com/video&#13;
----------&#13;
Whether it's reporting on conflicts abroad and political divisions at home, or covering the latest style trends and scientific developments, New York Times video journalists provide a revealing and unforgettable view of the world. It's all the news that's fit to watch.</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="557" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="38901"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:UwVz2umG4fU</id>
  <yt:videoId>UwVz2umG4fU</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCqnbDFdCpuN8CMEg0VuEBqA</yt:channelId>
  <title>Family Caught in Immigration Battle Reaches NYC: ‘The Bus Left Us Here’ | NYT</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=UwVz2umG4fU"/>
  <author>
   <name>The New York Times</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCqnbDFdCpuN8CMEg0VuEBqA</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-09-23T23:00:20+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-09-28T18:16:50+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Family Caught in Immigration Battle Reaches NYC: ‘The Bus Left Us Here’ | NYT</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/UwVz2umG4fU?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i2.ytimg.com/vi/UwVz2umG4fU/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>Leida, Kevin and their young daughter, Victoria, fled Venezuela, crossing seven countries to reach Texas. That’s when they were pulled into a political fight between Republican governors and the White House, and dropped outside Kamala Harris’s residence. The New York Times followed them on their journey to their latest destination, New York City.

Subscribe: http://bit.ly/U8Ys7n&#13;
More from The New York Times Video:  http://nytimes.com/video&#13;
----------&#13;
Whether it's reporting on conflicts abroad and political divisions at home, or covering the latest style trends and scientific developments, New York Times video journalists provide a revealing and unforgettable view of the world. It's all the news that's fit to watch.</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="660" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="28433"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:7YjY00Cd_MI</id>
  <yt:videoId>7YjY00Cd_MI</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCqnbDFdCpuN8CMEg0VuEBqA</yt:channelId>
  <title>The Real Threat to American Democracy | NYT Opinion</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7YjY00Cd_MI"/>
  <author>
   <name>The New York Times</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCqnbDFdCpuN8CMEg0VuEBqA</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-09-21T14:00:04+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-10-16T18:08:43+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>The Real Threat to American Democracy | NYT Opinion</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/7YjY00Cd_MI?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i4.ytimg.com/vi/7YjY00Cd_MI/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>For the past two years, Americans have been overwhelmed by a deluge of headlines suggesting democracy in the United States is under threat: Voter suppression. A shortage of drop boxes. Election deniers seeking key state offices. It can be difficult to gauge what stories suggest a truly terrifying threat to democracy, and which are simply disheartening or even petty. The Opinion Video film above aims to unpack one of the most dire threats to democracy, which includes a sophisticated plot to control not only who can vote, but which votes get counted.

One thing is certain: The 2020 race was not stolen. But Mr. Trump and his Republican enablers have been working to rig future elections to their advantage. (Of course it’s the people shrieking most loudly about fraud that you really need to watch.) The former president has convinced his followers that the electoral system has been so corrupted that the only way to save America is for MAGA patriots to take over the system to ensure that the “right” candidates win going forward. His allies have been busy engineering such a legal takeover, and key pieces of the plan are already in place.

In this short film, we shine a light on those machinations, so that those who care about democracy can act to stop them.

For our Democracy to survive, we need to agree on a shared reality and for the losers — that is those who lose in honest and fair elections — to accept defeat.
&#13;
Subscribe: http://bit.ly/U8Ys7n&#13;
More from The New York Times Video:  http://nytimes.com/video&#13;
----------&#13;
Whether it's reporting on conflicts abroad and political divisions at home, or covering the latest style trends and scientific developments, New York Times video journalists provide a revealing and unforgettable view of the world. It's all the news that's fit to watch.</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="30822" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="870425"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:FJvnn0qRWb4</id>
  <yt:videoId>FJvnn0qRWb4</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCqnbDFdCpuN8CMEg0VuEBqA</yt:channelId>
  <title>Watch Warriors in Training in ‘The Woman King’ | Anatomy of a Scene</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=FJvnn0qRWb4"/>
  <author>
   <name>The New York Times</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCqnbDFdCpuN8CMEg0VuEBqA</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-09-16T17:00:07+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-09-23T10:37:18+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Watch Warriors in Training in ‘The Woman King’ | Anatomy of a Scene</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/FJvnn0qRWb4?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i3.ytimg.com/vi/FJvnn0qRWb4/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>The intensity of the action epic “The Woman King,” starring Viola Davis and now in theaters, is balanced out with moments of levity, particularly in this training montage that sets up two key characters.

Nawi (Thuso Mbedu) has been dumped by her father at the palace in the Kingdom of Dahomey in 19th-century Africa. She is taken in and trained to become a part of a group of female soldiers. The woman leading the drills is Izogie (Lashana Lynch), whom Nawi ultimately tries to emulate.

“We’ve seen training montages before and they’re always fun and exciting,” the director Gina Prince-Bythewood said, narrating the scene. “What is going to make this one different?” She said putting the focus on the story of female warriors was “the element we haven’t seen.”

Prince-Bythewood’s approach, one she employed in her previous action film, “The Old Guard,” was to have actors perform their own stunts. In this sequence, that means performers have to pull off a flip in a couple of wrestling scenes. First, it’s Lynch flipping Mbedu, which Prince-Bythewood said came with a caveat: Mbedu would only agree to being flipped six times. But apparently the sixth time was the charm.

“You see it, she gets trucked,” Prince-Bythewood said.
The segment where Nawi gets to pull the same maneuver on Ode (Adrienne Warren), a fellow trainee, came with a surprise.

“The beauty of that moment, is at the end of the wrestling, Ode shoves Nawi,” Prince-Bythewood said. “That was not scripted. That was two actors so in the moment.”

Read the New York Times review: https://nyti.ms/3dm6Dwu
Subscribe: http://bit.ly/U8Ys7n&#13;
More from The New York Times Video:  http://nytimes.com/video&#13;
----------&#13;
Whether it's reporting on conflicts abroad and political divisions at home, or covering the latest style trends and scientific developments, New York Times video journalists provide a revealing and unforgettable view of the world. It's all the news that's fit to watch.</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="1078" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="66031"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:O5d1Cclk5QA</id>
  <yt:videoId>O5d1Cclk5QA</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCqnbDFdCpuN8CMEg0VuEBqA</yt:channelId>
  <title>The Best Chef in the World | Op-Docs</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=O5d1Cclk5QA"/>
  <author>
   <name>The New York Times</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCqnbDFdCpuN8CMEg0VuEBqA</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-09-13T16:00:23+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-10-21T14:34:17+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>The Best Chef in the World | Op-Docs</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/O5d1Cclk5QA?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i4.ytimg.com/vi/O5d1Cclk5QA/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>When my father died, he held disappointment in his heart. He was 66 and had only just retired from a life of 80-hour workweeks as a successful lawyer, and this next chapter promised everything he had skimped on since deciding to go to law school: family time, creative pursuits, fun.

His liver paid no mind, however, and he died on the morning of May 1, 2020. Four days later, I interviewed Sally Schmitt, bathed in golden Californian light, via Zoom, from the damp and shadowy basement of my parents’ home in Nova Scotia.

As a filmmaker and entrepreneur, I had always admired and studied the chef Thomas Keller, a walking pinnacle of craftsmanship, refinement and success — my father’s kind of guy. I had only recently learned about Ms. Schmitt, a pioneer of the Napa Valley culinary scene and the creator of the French Laundry, the restaurant Mr. Keller made world-famous. Talking to Ms. Schmitt that morning, I learned she held a different kind of wisdom: that success may have other definitions.

Ms. Schmitt died on March 5, 2022. But in &quot;The Best Chef in the World,&quot; she shares with delightfully coy candor a message about the rewards of balance and the trap of ambition. I made this film for all of us who struggle “to stir and taste the soup” that already sits in front of us. Perhaps with time and Ms. Schmitt’s example, we will.

- by Ben Proudfoot

Credits
Director: Ben Proudfoot
Editors: Nick Garnham Wright 
Featuring: Sally Schmitt
Cinematographer: Brandon Somerhalder, David Bolen
Original Score Composition and Orchestration: Katya Richardson
Supervising Sound Editor and Re-Recording Mixer: Sean Higgins
Colorist: Stephen Derluguian
Senior Post Production Supervisor: Dillon Brown
Post Production Supervisor: Laura Carlson
Co-Producers: Beatriz Browne, Abby Lynn Kang Davis, Gabriel Berk Godoi, Rachel Greenwald, Brandon Somerhalder
Associate Producers: Elizabeth Brooke, Sarah Stewart
Archival Producer: Sarah Stewart
Online Editor: Tyler Ten Haken
Assistant Editor : Cody Wilson
Second Unit First Assistant Camera: Jordan Scott
Story Reporting: Kirstin Falk
Archival Digitization: Hannah Auslander
Sound Effects Editor: Tom Boykin
Foley Services: POSTRED
Foley Artist: Biko Gogaladze
Foley Mixer: Giorgi Lekishvili
Foley Editor: Alexander Sanikidze
Scoring Mixer: Shachar Boussani
Musicians: Dominic Flynn, Ian Gottlieb, Vasilije Katanic, Nick Kennerly, Katya Richardson, Jonathan Schlitt, Niall Taro

Read more: 

More from The New York Times Video: 
Subscribe: http://bit.ly/U8Ys7n​​
Watch all of our videos here: http://nytimes.com/video​​
Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/nytvideo​​
Twitter: https://twitter.com/nytvideo​​
----------
Op-Docs is a forum for short, opinionated documentaries by independent filmmakers. Learn more about Op-Docs and how to submit to the series. Follow The New York Times Opinion section on Facebook, Twitter and Instagram (@NYTopinion).</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="14704" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="396225"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:ccVH_1g-kCY</id>
  <yt:videoId>ccVH_1g-kCY</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCqnbDFdCpuN8CMEg0VuEBqA</yt:channelId>
  <title>OB-GYNs Confront Legal Impact of Abortion Bans | NYT News</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ccVH_1g-kCY"/>
  <author>
   <name>The New York Times</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCqnbDFdCpuN8CMEg0VuEBqA</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-09-12T17:00:15+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-09-13T23:26:04+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>OB-GYNs Confront Legal Impact of Abortion Bans | NYT News</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/ccVH_1g-kCY?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i4.ytimg.com/vi/ccVH_1g-kCY/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>As anti-abortion laws take effect across the U.S., doctors treating patients with high-risk pregnancies are facing difficult decisions — and legal risks — over their standards of care.

Subscribe: http://bit.ly/U8Ys7n&#13;
More from The New York Times Video:  http://nytimes.com/video&#13;
----------&#13;
Whether it's reporting on conflicts abroad and political divisions at home, or covering the latest style trends and scientific developments, New York Times video journalists provide a revealing and unforgettable view of the world. It's all the news that's fit to watch.</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="768" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="16169"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:0bw7rJ2eZaA</id>
  <yt:videoId>0bw7rJ2eZaA</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCqnbDFdCpuN8CMEg0VuEBqA</yt:channelId>
  <title>The Legacy of Elizabeth II: The Media Queen</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0bw7rJ2eZaA"/>
  <author>
   <name>The New York Times</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCqnbDFdCpuN8CMEg0VuEBqA</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-09-08T19:12:22+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-09-09T09:20:46+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>The Legacy of Elizabeth II: The Media Queen</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/0bw7rJ2eZaA?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i1.ytimg.com/vi/0bw7rJ2eZaA/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>Queen Elizabeth II, the world’s longest-serving monarch, whose reign of almost seven decades survived tectonic shifts in Britain’s post-imperial society, inspired broad affection for her among her subjects and weathered successive challenges posed by the romantic choices, missteps and imbroglios of her descendants, died on Thursday at Balmoral Castle in Scotland, her summer retreat. She was 96. She left behind a legacy that blended the ancient and the modern with the help of mass media.

Read the story here: https://nyti.ms/3qlcMMe&#13;
Subscribe: http://bit.ly/U8Ys7n&#13;
More from The New York Times Video:  http://nytimes.com/video&#13;
----------&#13;
Whether it's reporting on conflicts abroad and political divisions at home, or covering the latest style trends and scientific developments, New York Times video journalists provide a revealing and unforgettable view of the world. It's all the news that's fit to watch.</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="2357" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="75547"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
</feed>
