<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>THE Journal: All Current Articles</title>
    <description />
    <link>https://thejournal.com/rss-feeds/all-articles.aspx</link>
    <item>
      <title>Reading Horizons Announces Tech-Enabled Edition of Reading Horizons Discovery</title>
      <description>Literacy skills company Reading Horizons has launched a new edition of its multisensory Reading Horizons Discovery program, upgrading to a tech-enabled version that provides instant and actionable data to enable teachers to help their K–3 students become proficient readers.</description>
      <link>https://thejournal.com/articles/2022/11/03/reading-horizons-announces-tech-enabled-edition-of-reading-horizons-discovery.aspx</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 19:54:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thejournal.com/articles/2022/11/03/reading-horizons-announces-tech-enabled-edition-of-reading-horizons-discovery.aspx</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Two Nonprofits Merge in Push for More Evidence of Impact in Ed Tech Decisions</title>
      <description>Two national nonprofits, EdTech Evidence Exchange and InnovateEDU, are merging in hopes of accelerating their work to improve outcomes and efficiencies in the usage of technology K–12 education, the organizations announced.</description>
      <link>https://thejournal.com/articles/2022/11/03/two-nonprofits-merge-in-push-for-more-evidence-of-impact-in-ed-tech-decisions.aspx</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 15:29:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thejournal.com/articles/2022/11/03/two-nonprofits-merge-in-push-for-more-evidence-of-impact-in-ed-tech-decisions.aspx</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Apple Rolls Out iPad Learning App Updates, More Resources for Educators</title>
      <description>Apple recently announced a number of updates and new resources for K–12 educators, including new instructional resources emphasizing project-based learning, creativity, and collaboration, as well as professional learning opportunities.</description>
      <link>https://thejournal.com/articles/2022/11/03/apple-rolls-out-updates-more-resources-for-educators.aspx</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 14:45:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thejournal.com/articles/2022/11/03/apple-rolls-out-updates-more-resources-for-educators.aspx</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Leaders Named at Tools 4 Reading, Newsela, ParentSquare, Age of Learning, DreamBox Learning, GoGuardian, PLTW, City Fund</title>
      <description>October 2022 People on the Move for K-12 education include Judi Dodson at Tools 4 Reading, Camila Franco at Newsela, Sashangar “Sash” Sreetharan at ParentSquare, Ty West at Age of Learning, Andrew Poggio at DreamBox Learning, Dionna Smith and Ya Xu at GoGuardian, David Dimmett at Project Lead The Way, Marlon Marshall at City Fund, and dozens of leadership awards recipients at the  Association of Latino Administrators and Superintendents annual conference.</description>
      <link>https://thejournal.com/articles/2022/10/31/people-on-the-move-k12-ed-tech-october-2022.aspx</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2022 19:58:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thejournal.com/articles/2022/10/31/people-on-the-move-k12-ed-tech-october-2022.aspx</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Providing Proof of Skills Is Essential for Students' Future Success</title>
      <description>A longtime educator and expert in Competency-Based Education teaching models argues that there is a significant misalignment between the vehicles through which students communicate what they know and can do and the opportunities available in the workforce, and he says K-12 education should be implementing skills tracking, which would fix the issue for both students and employers.</description>
      <link>https://thejournal.com/articles/2022/10/31/why-providing-proof-of-skills-is-essential-for-students-future-success.aspx</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2022 14:08:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thejournal.com/articles/2022/10/31/why-providing-proof-of-skills-is-essential-for-students-future-success.aspx</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reports: Rash of Fake Active Shooter Calls Have Impacted Nearly 200 Schools This Semester</title>
      <description>Nearly 200 schools in 28 states have been targeted by hoax “active shooter” calls since the beginning of the school year, according to investigations published this week by NPR and Wired.
</description>
      <link>https://thejournal.com/articles/2022/10/26/reports-rash-of-fake-active-shooter-calls-have-impacted-nearly-200-schools-this-semester.aspx</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 08:14:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thejournal.com/articles/2022/10/26/reports-rash-of-fake-active-shooter-calls-have-impacted-nearly-200-schools-this-semester.aspx</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Digital Promise Launches New Prioritizing Racial Equity in AI Design Product Certification</title>
      <description>A new ed tech product certification, Prioritizing Racial Equity in AI Design, from nonprofit Digital Promise and the Edtech Equity Project that takes aim at racial bias in AI-powered learning software is now accepting applications from ed tech providers that intentionally promote equity in their product design.</description>
      <link>https://thejournal.com/articles/2022/10/25/digital-promise-launches-new-prioritizing-racial-equity-in-ai-design-product-certification.aspx</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 23:08:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thejournal.com/articles/2022/10/25/digital-promise-launches-new-prioritizing-racial-equity-in-ai-design-product-certification.aspx</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IBM, Hispanic Heritage Foundation Providing Free SkillsBuild Tech Courses to Latino Students</title>
      <description>The Hispanic Heritage Foundation has partnered with IBM Education to provide IBM's SkillsBuild education program to Latino high school students free of charge, giving them skills they need to meet workforce demands.</description>
      <link>https://thejournal.com/articles/2022/10/25/ibm-partners-with-hispanic-heritage-foundation-to-provide-latinos-with-free-technology-skills.aspx</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 17:59:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thejournal.com/articles/2022/10/25/ibm-partners-with-hispanic-heritage-foundation-to-provide-latinos-with-free-technology-skills.aspx</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7 Questions About PowerSchool's New Data-as-a-Service Platform, Connected Intelligence</title>
      <description>THE Journal's 7 Questions: Ed Tech Explainer series features PowerSchool Group VP Shivani Stumpf, who explains the new Data-as-a-Service solution for education called Connected Intelligence, how it works, what it will offer public schools and state education agencies that is not commonly available now, and how she envisions it helping improve K–12 education.</description>
      <link>https://thejournal.com/articles/2022/10/25/7-questions-about-powerschool-new-data-analytics-product-connected-intelligence.aspx</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 13:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thejournal.com/articles/2022/10/25/7-questions-about-powerschool-new-data-analytics-product-connected-intelligence.aspx</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is SASE a Good Solution for Securing K-12 Education This School Year?</title>
      <description>A Fortinet Field CISO and education cybersecurity expert explains when SASE can be a good solution for public school IT leaders and what they should consider first.</description>
      <link>https://thejournal.com/articles/2022/10/24/is-sase-a-good-solution-for-securing-k12-education-this-school-year.aspx</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 01:16:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thejournal.com/articles/2022/10/24/is-sase-a-good-solution-for-securing-k12-education-this-school-year.aspx</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NAEP: Remote Learning Not Solely to Blame for Decline in Reading and Math Achievement</title>
      <description>Most of the United States saw declines in reading and math achievement on standardized tests between 2019 and 2022. Those declines happened in both fourth- and eighth-grade in a large majority of states and jurisdictions.</description>
      <link>https://thejournal.com/articles/2022/10/24/naep-remote-learning-not-solely-to-blame-for-decline-in-reading-and-math-achievement.aspx</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 00:24:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thejournal.com/articles/2022/10/24/naep-remote-learning-not-solely-to-blame-for-decline-in-reading-and-math-achievement.aspx</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>K–12 Grants &amp; Upcoming Events</title>
      <description>Upcoming funding opportunities, conferences, and webinars for K–12 schools, teachers, IT practitioners, and leaders (updated semi-weekly)</description>
      <link>https://thejournal.com/articles/resources/upcoming-grants-and-events.aspx</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 20:34:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thejournal.com/articles/resources/upcoming-grants-and-events.aspx</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7 Questions About Discovery Education's Ready-To-Use Resources with SVP Lance Rougeux</title>
      <description>This installment of THE Journal’s “7 Questions: Ed Tech Explainer” series gives Discovery Education Senior Vice President Lance Rougeux an opportunity to summarize Discovery Education's new Ready-To-Use Resources for teachers, how they help in the classroom, and what's planned for these kinds of instructional materials.</description>
      <link>https://thejournal.com/articles/2022/10/24/7-questions-about-discovery-educations-ready-to-use-resources.aspx</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2022 19:44:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thejournal.com/articles/2022/10/24/7-questions-about-discovery-educations-ready-to-use-resources.aspx</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CISA Holding Virtual National Summit on School Safety, Cybersecurity for Local, State K-12 Leaders, Educators</title>
      <description>Registration is now open for the Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency’s virtual 2022 National Summit on K–12 School Safety and Security, scheduled for Nov. 1–3, 2022, and the event is specifically for public school leaders and policymakers at the state level and for local K–12 administrators, principals, educators, IT practitioners, school safety officials, mental health professionals, and school board members, CISA said.</description>
      <link>https://thejournal.com/articles/2022/10/21/cisa-holding-virtual-summit-on-school-safety-cybersecurity-for-local-state-k12-leaders-educators.aspx</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2022 19:29:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thejournal.com/articles/2022/10/21/cisa-holding-virtual-summit-on-school-safety-cybersecurity-for-local-state-k12-leaders-educators.aspx</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Object Storage for Backups Can Keep Schools' Data Safer When Ransomware Comes Calling </title>
      <description>An expert in cloud data backups explains that Instead of “adding extra fences” that hackers could potentially get around, schools are better off ensuring data is recoverable no matter the circumstance, and why object storage-based data backups are a better, safer, and more affordable solution.</description>
      <link>https://thejournal.com/articles/2022/10/21/avoid-getting-schooled-by-ransomware-protect-sensitive-student-data-with-object-storage.aspx</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2022 18:26:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thejournal.com/articles/2022/10/21/avoid-getting-schooled-by-ransomware-protect-sensitive-student-data-with-object-storage.aspx</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SchoolStatus Buys SI&amp;A, Expanding Product Line with The Achievement Initiative, Good Governance Solutions</title>
      <description>School communications and data analytics provider SchoolStatus has acquired School Innovations &amp; Achievement, a software company whose solutions aim to help K–12 school leaders track and improve student attendance and ensure local and state policy compliance, SchoolStatus said in a news release.
</description>
      <link>https://thejournal.com/articles/2022/10/20/schoolstatus-acquires-sia-adding-its-the-achievement-initiative-good-governance-solutions.aspx</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2022 22:09:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thejournal.com/articles/2022/10/20/schoolstatus-acquires-sia-adding-its-the-achievement-initiative-good-governance-solutions.aspx</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Guide 'Cybersecurity Frameworks: What K-12 Leaders Need to Know' Released by K12SIX, SETDA</title>
      <description>The national nonprofit cybersecurity advocacy group for public schools, K12 Security Information Exchange, has released a new guide for state and local K–12 education leaders, “Cybersecurity Frameworks: What K–12 Leaders Need to Know,” which urges the adoption of cybersecurity best practices at the local and state levels of public education.
</description>
      <link>https://thejournal.com/articles/2022/10/20/new-guide-cybersecurity-frameworks-what-k12-leaders-need-to-know-released-by-k12six-setda.aspx</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2022 17:38:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thejournal.com/articles/2022/10/20/new-guide-cybersecurity-frameworks-what-k12-leaders-need-to-know-released-by-k12six-setda.aspx</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>McGraw Hill Launches Social Media-Style Study App SHARPEN</title>
      <description>McGraw Hill has announced the launch of its mobile study app, SHARPEN, to help students who have been turning to social media to find studying help. In a recent Morning Consult survey McGraw Hill conducted of 500 undergraduate students, 74% said they had changed the way they study due to the pandemic, citing stress and overwhelm as factors.</description>
      <link>https://thejournal.com/articles/2022/10/19/mcgraw-hill-launches-social-media-style-study-app-sharpen.aspx</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 19:48:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thejournal.com/articles/2022/10/19/mcgraw-hill-launches-social-media-style-study-app-sharpen.aspx</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>KIRKBI Acquires BrainPOP Edtech Platform</title>
      <description>KIRKBI, the family holding and investment company of the LEGO brand, has made its first investment into digital learning by acquiring total ownership of BrainPOP, the digital education company whose key product is short animated films that help students learn with simple and clear concepts to encourage cognitive development and life skills.</description>
      <link>https://thejournal.com/articles/2022/10/19/kirkbi-acquires-brainpop-edtech-platform.aspx</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 19:42:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thejournal.com/articles/2022/10/19/kirkbi-acquires-brainpop-edtech-platform.aspx</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AWA Accepting STEM Grant Applications Through December 31</title>
      <description>The American Water Association Charitable Foundation is now accepting STEM Education grant applications from Oct. 1 through Dec. 31 as part of its Keep Communities Flowing program, which awards grants for Water and Environment, Workforce Readiness and STEM Education.</description>
      <link>https://thejournal.com/articles/2022/10/19/awa-accepting-stem-grant-applications-through-december-31.aspx</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 18:56:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thejournal.com/articles/2022/10/19/awa-accepting-stem-grant-applications-through-december-31.aspx</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Free Online Tutoring Comes to South Dakota K–12 Students Statewide</title>
      <description>South Dakota has launched a free online tutoring program for all K–12 students in the four core subjects of English/Language Arts, Math, Science, and Social Studies. The program is funded by federal dollars from the American Rescue Plan.</description>
      <link>https://thejournal.com/articles/2022/10/19/free-online-tutoring-comes-to-south-dakota-k12-students-statewide.aspx</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 16:02:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thejournal.com/articles/2022/10/19/free-online-tutoring-comes-to-south-dakota-k12-students-statewide.aspx</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Digital Citizenship Week: Five Tips for Embedding Digital Citizenship in Schools</title>
      <description>The internet has proven to be a critical tool in the classroom. Even with broad support among parents for the internet as a vital educational tool, we know the internet is a vast and varied place that can easily become a distraction or even a danger. This is where digital citizenship comes in. A former education director of technology offers five tips for embedding good digital citizenship across K–12 schools.
</description>
      <link>https://thejournal.com/articles/2022/10/18/five-tips-for-embedding-digital-citizenship-in-schools.aspx</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 21:54:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thejournal.com/articles/2022/10/18/five-tips-for-embedding-digital-citizenship-in-schools.aspx</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Teacher Burnout Top Concern Among Fellow Educators</title>
      <description>A national survey found that the majority of educators (71%) are worried about teacher burnout during the 2022-2023 school year, even though most (66%) are optimistic about the new year.</description>
      <link>https://thejournal.com/articles/2022/10/18/teacher-burnout-top-concern-among-fellow-educators.aspx</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 19:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thejournal.com/articles/2022/10/18/teacher-burnout-top-concern-among-fellow-educators.aspx</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UltiMaker Launches New MakerBot SKETCH Large 3D Printer for the Classroom</title>
      <description>3D printer manufacturer UltiMaker has introduced a larger model of its popular education-specific MakerBot 3D printer using the SKETCH platform, the company said, noting that the new MakerBot SKETCH Large 3D printer has “more 3D printing power” than the standard SKETCH printer and enables educators and students to turn their ideas and designs into reality on a larger scale.
</description>
      <link>https://thejournal.com/articles/2022/10/18/ultimaker-launches-new-makerbot-sketch-large-3d-printer-for-the-classroom.aspx</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 18:49:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thejournal.com/articles/2022/10/18/ultimaker-launches-new-makerbot-sketch-large-3d-printer-for-the-classroom.aspx</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FFL Updates E-rate Manager with New Historical Data for Tracking School Funding</title>
      <description>Funds for Learning has released an update to E-rate Manager, a free E-rate data analytics tool for schools and libraries.</description>
      <link>https://thejournal.com/articles/2022/10/18/ffl-updates-erate-manager-with-new-historical-data-for-tracking-school-funding.aspx</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 18:34:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thejournal.com/articles/2022/10/18/ffl-updates-erate-manager-with-new-historical-data-for-tracking-school-funding.aspx</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>YouScience Acquires NC3T, Expanding Its College and Career Readiness Solutions</title>
      <description>Aptitude assessment and CTE solutions provider YouScience has acquired the National Center for College and Career Transitions, or NC3T, expanding YouScience’s ability to help K–12 students find and prepare for the career and college options that best fit their interests and abilities, according to a news release.
</description>
      <link>https://thejournal.com/articles/2022/10/18/youscience-acquires-nc3t-expanding-its-college-and-career-readiness-solutions.aspx</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 18:15:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thejournal.com/articles/2022/10/18/youscience-acquires-nc3t-expanding-its-college-and-career-readiness-solutions.aspx</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Aspen SIS Integrates with Google Classroom</title>
      <description>Follett today announced its Aspen Student Information System now integrates with Google Classroom. The integration allows educators who use Google Classroom to export grades to Aspen SIS for report cards and transcripts, among other uses.</description>
      <link>https://thejournal.com/articles/2022/10/18/aspen-sis-integrates-with-google-classroom.aspx</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 17:34:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thejournal.com/articles/2022/10/18/aspen-sis-integrates-with-google-classroom.aspx</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kahoot Announces New Investment Partner General Atlantic</title>
      <description>Global learning and engagement platform Kahoot! has announced a new investor, global growth equity firm General Atlantic, to support an upcoming expansion of its offerings. With the new investor buying prior funding source SoftBank Group’s full 15% shares in the company, Kahoot! Is poised to accelerate into new customer markets, a product roadmap and new commercialization, the company said.</description>
      <link>https://thejournal.com/articles/2022/10/13/kahoot.aspx</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2022 20:09:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thejournal.com/articles/2022/10/13/kahoot.aspx</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Apple Expands Community Education Initiative to Over 600 Communities</title>
      <description>Launched in 2019, Apple’s Community Education Initiative (CEI) has been expanded to 150 partners in 600 communities in 99 countries and regions, and all 50 states, the company announced. CEI provides access to coding, creativity, and job opportunities to students of all ages and from all backgrounds, with special focus on communities that are traditionally underrepresented in technology.</description>
      <link>https://thejournal.com/articles/2022/10/13/apple.aspx</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2022 20:07:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thejournal.com/articles/2022/10/13/apple.aspx</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Research: Administrators Grapple with Morale; Teachers More Open to Student Autonomy</title>
      <description>Project Tomorrow presented findings from its latest SpeakUp Survey in a briefing to Congress today. SpeakUp is the largest research project focusing on education technology, averaging well over 300,000 participants each year since its launch. The latest research captured changes in attitudes and priorities from administrators, teachers, and students.</description>
      <link>https://thejournal.com/articles/2022/10/13/project-tomorrow.aspx</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2022 20:06:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thejournal.com/articles/2022/10/13/project-tomorrow.aspx</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mosyle Opens Public Beta of its OneK12 Six-in-One IT Solution for Schools Using Apple Devices</title>
      <description>Apple-specific MDM and security provider Mosyle has made available to all K–12 schools a “long trial” of its new Apple Unified Platform device management and security solution for educational institutions called OneK12, which integrates device management, content filtering, endpoint security, single sign-on, application management, and classroom management.
</description>
      <link>https://thejournal.com/articles/2022/10/12/mosyle-opens-public-beta-of-six-in-one-it-solution-for-schools-using-apple-devices.aspx</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2022 18:38:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thejournal.com/articles/2022/10/12/mosyle-opens-public-beta-of-six-in-one-it-solution-for-schools-using-apple-devices.aspx</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Schools to Social Media: Dedicate Verification/Reporting Processes to Distinguish Legitimate School Accounts</title>
      <description>In a survey of school communication and technology professionals, more than half reported several social media platforms have no dedicated account verification and reporting processes for accounts owned by federally recognized preK–12 or K–12 schools. This lack has burdened the schools with having to challenge fake-official and mock accounts and get their own legitimate accounts verified, wasting time and resources, and sometimes failing to prevail.</description>
      <link>https://thejournal.com/articles/2022/10/11/schools-to-social-media-dedicate-verification-reporting-processes-to-distinguish-legitimate.aspx</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2022 20:10:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thejournal.com/articles/2022/10/11/schools-to-social-media-dedicate-verification-reporting-processes-to-distinguish-legitimate.aspx</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Department of Education Opens 2 Grant Applications for Mental Health Services Providers</title>
      <description>The United States Department of Education (ED) has announced the opening of two grant applications for fiscal year 2022, one for mental health service providers (MHSPs), and one </description>
      <link>https://thejournal.com/articles/2022/10/10/department-of-education-opens-2-grant-applications-for-mental-health-services-providers.aspx</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2022 18:58:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thejournal.com/articles/2022/10/10/department-of-education-opens-2-grant-applications-for-mental-health-services-providers.aspx</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vernier Launches $1,000 Grant Program to K–12 and College Educators</title>
      <description>Vernier Science Education has announced a new grant to give 10 K–12 or college educators funds this year to promote STEM literacy. Those awarded will receive their choice of $1,000 worth of Vernier technology, an annual license for Vernier Graphical Analysis Pro, and three hours of virtual professional development.</description>
      <link>https://thejournal.com/articles/2022/10/10/vernier-launches-1000-grant-program-to-k12-and-college-educators.aspx</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2022 18:08:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thejournal.com/articles/2022/10/10/vernier-launches-1000-grant-program-to-k12-and-college-educators.aspx</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Three Strategies for Growing Student Engagement in Math Using Ed Tech Tools</title>
      <description>A virtual math teacher and math interventionist shares three ed tech tools that work for helping students overcome barriers and become more engaged and motivated in math class.</description>
      <link>https://thejournal.com/articles/2022/10/10/three-strategies-for-growing-student-engagement-in-math.aspx</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2022 16:52:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thejournal.com/articles/2022/10/10/three-strategies-for-growing-student-engagement-in-math.aspx</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Samsung Raises Prize Pool for 2023 Solve for Tomorrow Contest</title>
      <description>Samsung Electronics has announced its 13th annual Solve for Tomorrow $2 million contest to teachers of U.S. public school students in grades 6–12. The contest encourages teachers to submit ideas on how their students can help their communities by problem-solving with the help of classroom technology and other supplies. Application deadline is Nov. 2, 2022.</description>
      <link>https://thejournal.com/articles/2022/10/06/samsung-raises-prize-pool-for-2023-solve-for-tomorrow-contest.aspx</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Oct 2022 19:13:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thejournal.com/articles/2022/10/06/samsung-raises-prize-pool-for-2023-solve-for-tomorrow-contest.aspx</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Video: How YouScience's Aptitude Assessments Help Educators and Students Match Their Strengths with Course Selections and Career Paths</title>
      <description>Aptitude assessments are helpful both at the upper levels of curriculum decision-making and at the granular level with students. Educators and guidance counselors can see the gaps in so-called “career exposure” — for example where students have innate talents or aptitudes but no career interest indicates they may need more information about career possibilities — and the assessments help schools better tailor courses and programs in high school to the career paths that students show talents in and wish to explore as a possible future job.</description>
      <link>https://thejournal.com/articles/2022/10/06/podcast-how-aptitude-assessments-provide-data-direction-to-educators-help-students-brighter-futures.aspx</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Oct 2022 17:44:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thejournal.com/articles/2022/10/06/podcast-how-aptitude-assessments-provide-data-direction-to-educators-help-students-brighter-futures.aspx</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New California Law Requires Schools to Report All Cyberattacks Impacting 500 or More</title>
      <description>California Gov. Gavin Newsom has signed into a law a new requirement for K–12 schools in that state to report any cyberattack impacting more than 500 pupils or personnel, becoming the first in the nation to require disclosure even if a data breach has not occurred.
</description>
      <link>https://thejournal.com/articles/2022/10/06/new-california-law-requires-schools-to-report-all-cyber-incidents-impacting-500-pupils-or-staff.aspx</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Oct 2022 17:18:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thejournal.com/articles/2022/10/06/new-california-law-requires-schools-to-report-all-cyber-incidents-impacting-500-pupils-or-staff.aspx</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Jotform Sign Software Aims to Help Schools Digitize Paper Forms</title>
      <description>Aiming to help K–12 schools digitize their paper-based processes, online form-building provider Jotform has launched a lite version of its enterprise software called Jotform Sign with a no-cost starter plan and 50% discount offer for educational institutions that subscribe to paid plans, the company said in a news release.
</description>
      <link>https://thejournal.com/articles/2022/10/04/new-jotform-sign-aims-to-help-schools-digitize-paper-forms.aspx</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2022 02:18:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thejournal.com/articles/2022/10/04/new-jotform-sign-aims-to-help-schools-digitize-paper-forms.aspx</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3 Ways Technology Can Help Schools Address the Mental Health Crisis</title>
      <description>As schools respond to the far-reaching mental health crisis in our schools, close collaboration between students, families, schools, community organizations, and support services can be a game-changer, and technology can play a role in making the collaboration easier and automatic. An expert in digital case management systems shares three ways schools can enhance their collaboration practices to better address students' needs.</description>
      <link>https://thejournal.com/articles/2022/10/04/3-ways-technology-can-help-schools-address-the-mental-health-crisis.aspx</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2022 01:37:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thejournal.com/articles/2022/10/04/3-ways-technology-can-help-schools-address-the-mental-health-crisis.aspx</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>National Education Equity Lab Expanding No-Cost College Algebra Course to Any Title I School in Spring 2023</title>
      <description>Khan Academy and the nonprofit National Education Equity Lab today announced the expansion of its pilot program to allow high school students in historically underserved communities to take college-level Algebra I and earn college credit from Howard University at no cost, the organizations said.
</description>
      <link>https://thejournal.com/articles/2022/10/04/national-education-equity-lab-expanding-no-cost-college-algebra-to-any-title-i-school-in-spring-2023.aspx</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2022 18:09:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thejournal.com/articles/2022/10/04/national-education-equity-lab-expanding-no-cost-college-algebra-to-any-title-i-school-in-spring-2023.aspx</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MIND Research Debuts InsightMath Neuroscience-Based Program</title>
      <description>MIND Research Institute, creators 25 years ago of ST Math, a neuroscience-based preK–8 math learning program, announced this week the debut of its new program, InsightMath, a core elementary math curriculum. </description>
      <link>https://thejournal.com/articles/2022/09/30/mind-research-debuts-insightmath-neuroscience-based-program.aspx</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2022 12:25:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thejournal.com/articles/2022/09/30/mind-research-debuts-insightmath-neuroscience-based-program.aspx</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Aptitude Assessments Provide Data-Driven Direction to Educators and Help Students See Brighter Futures</title>
      <description>Aptitude assessments are helpful both at the upper levels of curriculum decision-making and at the granular level with students. Educators and guidance counselors can see the gaps in so-called “career exposure” — for example where students have innate talents or aptitudes but no career interest indicates they may need more information about career possibilities — and the assessments help schools better tailor courses and programs in high school to the career paths that students show talents in and wish to explore as a possible future job.</description>
      <link>https://thejournal.com/articles/2022/09/29/podcast-how-aptitude-assessments-provide-data-direction-to-educators-help-students-brighter-futures.aspx</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Sep 2022 21:31:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thejournal.com/articles/2022/09/29/podcast-how-aptitude-assessments-provide-data-direction-to-educators-help-students-brighter-futures.aspx</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rave Mobile Safety to Provide Anonymous Tip App to All Oklahoma Public and Charter Schools</title>
      <description>Rave Mobile Safety, which provides safety communication solutions to education and industry, announced it has partnered with all Oklahoma public and charter schools to provide its AppArmor anonymous tip program made possible by a grant from the Department of Homeland Security. The Oklahoma School Safety Institute and Oklahoma School Division made the decision to use the program for the remainder of the grant period until the end of 2023.</description>
      <link>https://thejournal.com/articles/2022/09/29/rave-mobile-safety-to-provide-anonymous-tip-app-to-all-oklahoma-public-and-charter-schools.aspx</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Sep 2022 17:55:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thejournal.com/articles/2022/09/29/rave-mobile-safety-to-provide-anonymous-tip-app-to-all-oklahoma-public-and-charter-schools.aspx</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vector Solutions Adds Cybersecurity Courses to Online Training for Schools</title>
      <description>Vector Solutions, a company that provides education and industry training courses, announced it has added eight new courses to its stable of education courses for K–12 schools. The courses address key areas of cybersecurity awareness for education leaders and employees and include topics such as creating a cybersecurity culture, preventing social engineering attacks, laws and compliance, best practices, and more. Information about the courses will be available starting Oct. 1, 2022. </description>
      <link>https://thejournal.com/articles/2022/09/29/vector-solutions-adds-cybersecurity-courses-to-online-training-for-schools.aspx</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Sep 2022 17:28:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thejournal.com/articles/2022/09/29/vector-solutions-adds-cybersecurity-courses-to-online-training-for-schools.aspx</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Data: Nearly Half of Schools Providing Home Internet Access to Students Who Need It This School Year</title>
      <description>Survey results released today by the U.S. Department of Education’s National Center for Education Statistics shows that as of the start of the 2022–23 school year, almost half of K–12 public schools reported providing internet access to students who need it at their homes, and almost three quarters are providing training on digital literacy for their students.
</description>
      <link>https://thejournal.com/articles/2022/09/27/nearly-half-of-schools-providing-home-internet-access-to-students-who-need-it-this-school-year.aspx</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2022 22:03:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thejournal.com/articles/2022/09/27/nearly-half-of-schools-providing-home-internet-access-to-students-who-need-it-this-school-year.aspx</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Federal Appeals Court Ruling Means Class-Action Suits Over Data Breaches No Longer Require Proof of Actual Harm</title>
      <description>As ransomware attacks targeting the education sector grab more headlines every week, a new ruling from a federal appeals court has further lowered the bar for people whose data is breached and leaked on the dark web to sue the organizations where the data was compromised, and educational institutions, public schools, and ed tech providers should take heed, an expert warns.</description>
      <link>https://thejournal.com/articles/2022/09/27/federal-appeals-court-ruling-means-class-action-suits-over-data-breaches-require-actual-harm.aspx</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2022 18:12:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thejournal.com/articles/2022/09/27/federal-appeals-court-ruling-means-class-action-suits-over-data-breaches-require-actual-harm.aspx</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Leadership Roles Announced for Yang, Ware, Cafiero, Beckerman, Lee, Charland, Jones, Mathews, Stimpson</title>
      <description>People on the Move in K–12 education for September are ParentSquare’s Jim Yang; Newsela’s Derrick Ware, Holly Cafiero, Igor Beckerman, and Gloria Lee; Phil Charland at SchoolStatus; Dwight D. Jones at the Institute for Education Innovation; Scholastic’s Jeffrey Mathews; and Jennifer Stimpson at T.D. Jakes Foundation.</description>
      <link>https://thejournal.com/articles/2022/09/26/new-leadership-roles-announced-for-yang-ware-cafiero-beckerman-lee-charland-jones-mathews-stimpson.aspx</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2022 15:37:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thejournal.com/articles/2022/09/26/new-leadership-roles-announced-for-yang-ware-cafiero-beckerman-lee-charland-jones-mathews-stimpson.aspx</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7 Questions about SchoolStatus with CEO Russ Davis</title>
      <description>THE Journal’s “7 Questions: Ed Tech Explainer” series gives ed tech leaders an opportunity to summarize their solution(s), explain how their product helps educators and schools, and give a quick overview for K–12 decision-makers — sort of an extended (but not too extended) elevator pitch. For this installment, SchoolStatus Founder and CEO Russ Davis explains how SchoolStatus works in a school tech ecosystem, how it helps educators and students, and how it's pivoted over the past year.</description>
      <link>https://thejournal.com/articles/2022/09/25/ed-tech-explainer-7-questions-with-schoolstatus-ceo-russ-davis.aspx</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2022 02:39:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thejournal.com/articles/2022/09/25/ed-tech-explainer-7-questions-with-schoolstatus-ceo-russ-davis.aspx</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Cybersecurity Firm Assessed a State's Entire Education System, Finding Thousands of Security Risks</title>
      <description>Cyber Security Works, an IT risk management company and partner agency of the U.S. Department of Homeland Security, recently conducted an assessment of an entire state’s public education system, analyzing the security posture across 180 school districts and charter schools, and it found 2,221 potential IT security problems, including scores of vulnerabilities known to have been weaponized by cyber criminals.</description>
      <link>https://thejournal.com/articles/2022/09/22/a-cybersecurity-firm-assessed-a-states-education-infrastructure-and-the-results-were-alarming.aspx</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2022 20:13:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thejournal.com/articles/2022/09/22/a-cybersecurity-firm-assessed-a-states-education-infrastructure-and-the-results-were-alarming.aspx</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>