<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>University of Wisconsin Data Science Degree</title>
	<atom:link href="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Jul 2022 15:27:24 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.0.3</generator>
	<item>
		<title>UW Data Science Grad Takes On Leadership Role at Microsoft, Co-Authors New Book</title>
		<link>https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/blog/uw-data-science-grad-takes-on-leadership-role-at-microsoft-co-authors-new-book/</link>
					<comments>https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/blog/uw-data-science-grad-takes-on-leadership-role-at-microsoft-co-authors-new-book/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brandon Arbuckle]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Jul 2022 21:05:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Student Stories]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Online Learning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[UW Extended Campus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[microsoft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data science degree]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[university of wisconsin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[student story]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Master's Degree]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/?p=7931</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Whether it was publishing a book on machine learning or becoming a director at one of the world’s leading tech companies, the past year has been a busy one for Austin Hagerty. He credits much of his success to what he learned in the 100 percent online University of Wisconsin Master of Science in Data [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/blog/uw-data-science-grad-takes-on-leadership-role-at-microsoft-co-authors-new-book/">UW Data Science Grad Takes On Leadership Role at Microsoft, Co-Authors New Book</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu">University of Wisconsin Data Science Degree</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Whether it was publishing a book on machine learning or becoming a director at one of the world’s leading tech companies, the past year has been a busy one for Austin Hagerty. He credits much of his success to what he learned in the 100 percent online </span><a href="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span style="font-weight: 400;">University of Wisconsin Master of Science in Data Science</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> (MSDS) program.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“I would not be in the position I am if I had not gone through that program and had that foundational knowledge and practitioner knowledge,” he said. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">But getting there wasn’t simple. Austin’s path to success resembled a winding road more than a straight line.</span></p>
<h2><b>From Programming and Art History to Project Delivery</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Before he was a published author and Director of Data and AI at </span><a href="https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Microsoft</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, Austin’s interests led him to several experiences in and outside the tech industry. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">During the 1980s, Austin&#8217;s father worked in engineering at the onset of computer-aided design and manufacturing (CAD/CAM). Influenced by his father&#8217;s career and the many computers within his childhood home, Austin began programming at an early age. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">He carried that passion for programming with him throughout high school and into college, where he pursued an undergraduate degree in physics at </span><a href="https://uwm.edu/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span style="font-weight: 400;">UW-Milwaukee</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Austin grew to love the humanities courses he was required to take for his degree and saw a new opportunity to apply his background to an entirely different field.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“I actually switched to an art history major with a focus on leveraging data and statistics,” Austin said. “Because so much of [art history] was subjective at the time, I was very interested in taking a more empirical, data-driven approach. Having been so focused on technology in my younger years, it was incredibly rewarding to focus on the humanities.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Austin graduated from UW-Milwaukee and later attended the University of California, Los Angeles (UCLA) for a </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">post-baccalaureate in art history to dive deeper into the field and explore a potential career change.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“I didn&#8217;t want to be 70 or 80 years old and say, well, I stayed in tech and never explored that other potential path in life,” he said. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Although Austin appreciated his time at UCLA, he ultimately decided</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> a career in art history wasn’t for him. With many of the art pieces he was studying being variations and copies of original work or stolen without context, the amount of data that could be analyzed in the field at the time was insufficient to drive meaningful insights. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Austin pivoted his focus back to the tech industry after college, working in project delivery as a project manager, program manager, and eventually portfolio manager</span><b>.</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> In those roles, </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">he learned how to run a business and lead engineering efforts while still keeping his technical skills intact. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">He then had an opportunity to lead a workforce analytics team at </span><a href="https://www.northwesternmutual.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Northwestern Mutual</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> in Milwaukee</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">, which allowed Austin’s background and interests to converge. Shortly after starting this new position, he enrolled in the UW Data Science program to expand his data science knowledge and grow as a leader.</span></p>
<h2><b>An Online Data Science Degree Program with Value</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">As Austin researched graduate-level data science programs, the Wisconsin native compared other universities and their tuition costs to the UW Data Science program.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Many were incredibly expensive,” he said. “And for an online program, it didn’t make sense to invest $60,000 or $70,000 just to have the university name. Instead, I prioritized quality and program value. Reputation was also important, and UW has a fantastic reputation.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The course list was another factor that stood out to Austin, as the UW program included diverse course offerings like </span><a href="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Course-Syllabus-for-DS-760.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span style="font-weight: 400;">DS 760: Ethics of Data Science</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Having a class on ethics was perfect, because that’s a constant discussion item when you’re doing any workforce analytics problem,” Austin said. “You have to continually ensure that the analysis you are doing is fair and ethical.” </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Other highlights of the program for Austin included taking courses on </span><a href="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Course-Syllabus-for-DS745.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span style="font-weight: 400;">data visualization and analysis</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, </span><a href="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Course-Syllabus-for-DS-715.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span style="font-weight: 400;">data warehousing</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, and </span><a href="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Course-Syllabus-for-DS-780.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span style="font-weight: 400;">strategic decision making</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/original_4a2f0a6c-4c4c-42fa-95d6-6f119696dee0_IMG_20211121_202943.png"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-7933 alignright" src="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/original_4a2f0a6c-4c4c-42fa-95d6-6f119696dee0_IMG_20211121_202943-225x300.png" alt="Austin with his daughter" width="416" height="554" srcset="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/original_4a2f0a6c-4c4c-42fa-95d6-6f119696dee0_IMG_20211121_202943-225x300.png 225w, https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/original_4a2f0a6c-4c4c-42fa-95d6-6f119696dee0_IMG_20211121_202943.png 720w" sizes="(max-width: 416px) 100vw, 416px" /></a>Because the UW Data Science program is 100 percent online, Austin benefited from a flexible learning environment where he could complete coursework anytime, anywhere. The online learning format was especially helpful when major life events took place, like when his family moved to a new city.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Although he graduated from the program with a 4.0 GPA, </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Austin’s experience did not come without some initial challenges. Since he had not taken a college course in many years, part of the learning curve was simply getting back into the rhythm of being a student.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Learning how to learn is in many ways more important than just rote memorization of facts and course materials,” he said.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Fortunately, faculty were engaged and eager to provide support when Austin had questions or feedback. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">He </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">also</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> received help from </span><a href="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/student-services/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Success Coach Michael Paul</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> and </span><a href="https://www.uwlax.edu/profile/jbaggett/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Dr. Jeff Baggett,</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> the assigned student advisor from his home campus of </span><a href="https://www.uwlax.edu/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span style="font-weight: 400;">UW-La Crosse</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Austin found a sense of community in the program. He enjoyed working on group projects and meeting other students through discussion sections, which resulted in interesting networking opportunities.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“I actually ran into [a former classmate] a couple of years later on the job,” he said. “And we just happened to recognize each other&#8217;s names, living in Texas, of all places. A big part of grad school is who you meet, the connections you make, and developing that passion and career support as you move forward.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Austin’s determination led him to complete the program in two years, a rapid pace for students working full-time.</span></p>
<p><em><strong>RELATED</strong>: <a href="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/blog/data-science-course-preview-foundations-of-data-science/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Take a Look at a UW Data Science Course: Foundations of Data Science</a></em></p>
<h2><b>Finding Further Success in Data Science</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">While enrolled in the UW Data Science program, Austin immediately applied the knowledge he learned in the courses to his work as Assistant Director at Northwestern Mutual. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“I wasn&#8217;t doing a lot of the coding myself, but [I learned how] I could guide the team and step in where they didn&#8217;t have skills,” he said. “It helped me be a better leader.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Austin credits the skills he acquired from the UW Data Science program for the career growth that followed. He used the knowledge and experience gained to help organizations build and grow data science functions and realize the value of data. His latest endeavor as Director of Data and AI at Microsoft opens new doors to driving impact. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“It is a great way to expand [my] knowledge, to help [Microsoft] deliver value for customers through data science, and it’s in a field that is growing and booming,” he said. “There’s a lot that I’ve learned over the years too that I’m able to apply [to this role] because of the UW program.” </span></p>
<p><em><strong>RELATED</strong>: <a href="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/blog/data-science-webinar-highlights-future-of-the-field/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Data Science Webinar Highlights the Current Job Market and Future of the Field</a></em></p>
<h2><b>Writing the Next Chapter</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The UW Data Science program has helped elevate Austin’s career in more ways than one.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Each step of the way, the program has benefited me,” he said. “I&#8217;ve been able to be an effective data science leader because I can understand the concepts and speak the language.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This includes written language as well—two months after accepting his position at Microsoft, Austin published </span><a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/3030676250?pf_rd_r=B0MZSMZSHKTZKSZA4J82&amp;pf_rd_p=5ae2c7f8-e0c6-4f35-9071-dc3240e894a8&amp;pd_rd_r=7c362973-21b6-4704-9253-fb26696e4462&amp;pd_rd_w=yQOZO&amp;pd_rd_wg=6z5s1&amp;ref_=pd_gw_unk" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Introducing HR Analytics with Machine Learning: Empowering Practitioners, Psychologists, and Organizations</span></i></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. What started as his </span><a href="https://uwex.wisconsin.edu/uwex_capstones_area_study/general-education/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span style="font-weight: 400;">capstone project</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> in the program turned into a full-fledged book when Austin formed a networking connection with Christopher Rosett at an analytics conference. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Rosett was impressed by Austin’s R programming language presentation at the conference and asked if Austin was interested in co-authoring a book with him.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“I wouldn&#8217;t have been able to write that book without the knowledge I gained in the UW program,” Austin said. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If Austin’s story is any indication, there are several ways to achieve success in the field of data science. His advice to prospective students? Focus on mastering the core elements and understand how to find and leverage new information. Students should also keep an open mind and have a desire to learn.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“There&#8217;s a lot of different paths you could take with a program like this,” he said. “And from a career perspective, stay curious. Stay intellectually hungry. Keep learning. This is not a static field.”</span></p>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Want to learn more about the </span></i><a href="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">UW Master of Science in Data Science</span></i></a><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">? </span></i><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Talk with an enrollment adviser by emailing</span></i> <a href="mailto:learn@uwex.edu"><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">learn@uwex.wisconsin.edu</span></i></a><i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> or calling 608-262-2011.</span></i></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/blog/uw-data-science-grad-takes-on-leadership-role-at-microsoft-co-authors-new-book/">UW Data Science Grad Takes On Leadership Role at Microsoft, Co-Authors New Book</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu">University of Wisconsin Data Science Degree</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/blog/uw-data-science-grad-takes-on-leadership-role-at-microsoft-co-authors-new-book/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Data Science Webinar Highlights the Current Job Market and Future of the Field</title>
		<link>https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/blog/data-science-webinar-highlights-future-of-the-field/</link>
					<comments>https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/blog/data-science-webinar-highlights-future-of-the-field/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brandon Arbuckle]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 11 Mar 2022 21:04:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Careers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[UW Data Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Master's Degree]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Online Learning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data science careers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[UW Extended Campus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data science degree]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[university of wisconsin]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/?p=7835</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The University of Wisconsin Data Science program hosted a career webinar breaking down the future of the field. The discussion, which was facilitated by UW Data Science Academic Program Manager, Jennifer Cox, and Senior Success Coach, Michael Paul, examined the current job market and career outlook for the data science industry.  The panel featured experts [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/blog/data-science-webinar-highlights-future-of-the-field/">Data Science Webinar Highlights the Current Job Market and Future of the Field</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu">University of Wisconsin Data Science Degree</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The </span><a href="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span style="font-weight: 400;">University of Wisconsin Data Science</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> program hosted a career webinar breaking down the future of the field. The discussion, which was facilitated by UW Data Science Academic Program Manager, Jennifer Cox, and Senior Success Coach, Michael Paul, examined the current job market and career outlook for the data science industry. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The panel featured experts representing different areas of data science, all of whom were either UW Data Science graduates or <a href="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/uw-data-science-advisory-board/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Advisory Board</a> members for the program:</span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><strong>Missy Wittmann, Data Solution Engineer at <a href="https://www.amfam.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">American Family Insurance</a></strong></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><strong>Brent Ferrier, Principal Data Scientist at <a href="https://www.oshkoshcorp.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Oshkosh Corporation</a></strong></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><strong>Rebecca Wells, Data and Analytics Catalyst at <a href="https://www.tranetechnologies.com/en/index.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Trane Technologies</a></strong></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><strong>Carolyn Challoner, Information Technology Instructor at <a href="https://www.fvtc.edu/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Fox Valley Technical College</a></strong></li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The four panelists shared career knowledge on a wide range of topics, including what skills you need to succeed in the field and the importance of companies cultivating an inclusive workplace. </span></p>
<h2><b>What Employers Expect From Today’s Data Science Professionals</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">To work in the data science industry, possessing business knowledge is just as important as having a strong understanding of programming languages and visualization tools. With soft skills like strong communication and collaboration, data scientists can clearly and effectively explain projects to other departments in their organization.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“As a data scientist, being able to straddle that line between business and IT is expected,”  Ferrier said. “That’s why communication is so key, because you have to live in two worlds.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Companies are searching for workers who can bring best practices to the current business through real-time analytics and personalization. In fields such as consulting and manufacturing, Ferrier said there has been a sudden rise in companies seeing the value in advanced analytics.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“There are tons of jobs out there for the jack of all trades, the generalist who can go end-to-end on a full project,” he said. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The industry is also beginning to see a specialization of roles in larger companies. Wells predicts a job market where teams consist of “unicorn” employees, or workers who are hard to find but have unique and specialized skills that can greatly improve an organization.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Instead of expecting the world out of one person, companies are starting to recognize that it does behoove them to specialize across their roles and build unicorn teams instead of that magical single unicorn,” she said. </span></p>
<h2><b>Creating An Inclusive Workplace for a Better Tomorrow</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The panel also discussed the importance of diversity and equity in the workplace. Many companies have made an effort toward inclusivity to ensure everyone has a voice. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Wittmann said American Family Insurance in particular has an </span><a href="https://www.amfam.com/making-a-difference/diversity-and-inclusion" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Inclusive Excellence</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> department, along with employee resource groups to support women in technology, different ethnicities, and veterans.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“The more diverse your teams are, the stronger the teams will be because you have different perspectives and ways of looking at things,” Wittmann said. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Companies like Trane Technologies have begun to implement anonymous hiring by removing candidates’ names from their applications. This allows hiring managers to make decisions based on an applicant’s skills while avoiding gender bias and other forms of hiring discrimination. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Remote positions have also created more job opportunities for graduates and working professionals across the country. In the case of Oshkosh Corporation, Ferrier said the company hired remote workers in Arizona who otherwise wouldn’t have been able to join the Wisconsin-based organization. The company has promoted tuition assistance as well for workers in other departments who want to acquire the core knowledge necessary for a data scientist role.</span></p>
<p><a href="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/DS_stockimage_blog_March_2022.jpg"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-7889 size-full aligncenter" src="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/DS_stockimage_blog_March_2022.jpg" alt="Group Of Businesspeople Examining Graph On Computer" width="1000" height="623" srcset="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/DS_stockimage_blog_March_2022.jpg 1000w, https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/DS_stockimage_blog_March_2022-300x187.jpg 300w, https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/DS_stockimage_blog_March_2022-768x478.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px" /></a></p>
<h2><b>Getting Your Foot in the Door</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The job market for data science has become an employee’s market in recent years, which makes the career outlook for the field a promising one.</span><b> </b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">For people looking to transition into the field or are searching for their first job after graduation, a solid résumé and proper networking can go a long way to set you apart from other applicants. The panel suggested using </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">online job boards such as </span><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span style="font-weight: 400;">LinkedIn</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, which is how Challoner found her current job at Fox Valley Technical College.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Because of my background, résumé, and data science degree, my inbox blew up,” she said.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The panel recommended broadening your search when looking for data science openings, since job titles can vary from company to company. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Organizations use many different terms,&#8221; Wittmann said. &#8220;You may not necessarily see the words ‘data science.’ They may be looking for some type of data engineer or whatnot.&#8221;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">When searching for jobs, shadowing other employees within your organization or reaching out to a company’s hiring manager for an informational interview can help you find the right fit.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“How [hiring managers] describe what they want from their employee versus what they put in a job description are often very different things,” Wells said.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Creating an online portfolio is another option to demonstrate your data science knowledge and skill set. With the UW Data Science program, students can tailor their </span><a href="https://uwex.wisconsin.edu/uwex_capstones_area_study/general-education/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span style="font-weight: 400;">final capstone project</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> to showcase a collection of work with potential employers. </span></p>
<h2><b>Furthering Your Career With a Data Science Degree</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The emergence of online degree programs has given a wider range of students more access to an education. This includes Ferrier’s wife, who went back to school online while she was raising their children as a stay-at-home mother. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“I find that a lot with our data science students,” Cox said. “They’re working a job or several jobs, have kids, and are fitting this in with their regular life.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">With the field of data science constantly evolving, the panel stressed the value of being a lifelong learner. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Getting that data literacy can help you in any career, not just one that is a traditional data science career path,” Challoner said.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">While online courses like LinkedIn Learning and Coursera are useful for supplemental learning, a master’s degree program will allow you to establish credibility and fully develop the technical skills </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">needed in data science. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">The 100% online UW Master of Science in Data Science is a suitable option for those looking to advance their careers while having the flexibility to support any lifestyle. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Want to learn more about the UW Data Science program? </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Talk with an enrollment adviser by emailing </span><a href="mailto:learn@uwex.wisconsin.edu"><span style="font-weight: 400;">learn@uwex.wisconsin.edu</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> or calling 608-262-2011.</span></p>
<p><em>The full webinar is available below:</em></p>
<p><iframe loading="lazy" title="YouTube video player" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/4P9hLbTYLyA" width="1120" height="630" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"><span data-mce-type="bookmark" style="display: inline-block; width: 0px; overflow: hidden; line-height: 0;" class="mce_SELRES_start">﻿</span></iframe></p>
<h2><b>About the Panel</b></h2>
<p><b>Missy Wittmann | Data Solution Engineer at American Family Insurance</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;" data-wp-editing="1"><a href="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/Missy-Photo.jpg"><img loading="lazy" class="alignleft wp-image-7880 size-medium" src="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/Missy-Photo-300x300.jpg" alt="Data science webinar panelist Missy Wittmann" width="300" height="300" srcset="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/Missy-Photo.jpg 300w, https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/Missy-Photo-150x150.jpg 150w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a>Over the past 36 years, Missy has worked several positions within the data space at American Family. Her passion for data led her to the Wisconsin Data Management Association (DAMA), where she was elected president and held board positions at the international level. Missy joined the UW Data Science Advisory Board to discuss the needs of the industry and ensure the program is aligned with the workforce. </span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><b>Brent Ferrier | Principal Data Scientist at Oshkosh Corporation</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/DS-graduate-headshot-ferrier.png"><img loading="lazy" class="alignleft wp-image-7768" src="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/DS-graduate-headshot-ferrier-300x300.png" alt="Data science webinar panelist Brent Ferrier" width="300" height="300" srcset="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/DS-graduate-headshot-ferrier-300x300.png 300w, https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/DS-graduate-headshot-ferrier-150x150.png 150w, https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/DS-graduate-headshot-ferrier.png 720w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a>A graduate of the UW Data Science program and an Advisory Board member, Brent is responsible for the strategy and implementation of data science initiatives at the Oshkosh Defense business unit at Oshkosh Corporation. A lifelong learner, Brent also has an MS in Cybersecurity from Georgia Tech and an MBA from UW-Parkside. His educational background in supply chain management and data regulations has further complemented his data science career.</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><b>Rebecca Wells | Data and Analytics Catalyst at Trane Technologies</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/DS-headshot-R-wells-e1641944057674.jpg"><img loading="lazy" class="alignleft wp-image-7879 size-medium" src="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/DS-headshot-R-wells-e1641944057674-300x300.jpg" alt="Data science webinar panelist Rebecca Wells" width="300" height="300" srcset="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/DS-headshot-R-wells-e1641944057674.jpg 300w, https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/DS-headshot-R-wells-e1641944057674-150x150.jpg 150w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a>Rebecca develops the data and analytics vision at Trane Technologies, where she has worked for 20 years. This includes how the organization is structured as well as the process of turning analytics into data science. A graduate of the UW Data Science program, Rebecca was drawn to the field after developing an interest in visualization storytelling. She has since been able to combine her statistics and programming skills with her pre-existing business background.</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><b>Carolyn Challoner | Information Technology Instructor at Fox Valley Technical College</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><b><a href="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/DS-graduate-headshot-challener.png"><img loading="lazy" class="alignleft wp-image-7770" src="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/DS-graduate-headshot-challener-300x300.png" alt="Data science webinar panelist Carolyn Challoner" width="300" height="300" srcset="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/DS-graduate-headshot-challener-300x300.png 300w, https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/DS-graduate-headshot-challener-150x150.png 150w, https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/DS-graduate-headshot-challener-768x769.png 768w, https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/DS-graduate-headshot-challener.png 800w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a></b>A 2018 graduate of the Data Science program, Carolyn is working to train the next generation of data scientists in Fox Valley Tech’s newly formed Data Specialist degree program. She has previously worked at IT and global marketing jobs throughout the Fox Valley region of Wisconsin, including Plexus, Miller Electric, and Kimberly-Clark. </span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><b>Michael Paul | Senior Success Coach at UW Extended Campus</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;" data-wp-editing="1"><b><a href="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/DS-success-coach-headshot-paul.jpg"><img loading="lazy" class="alignleft wp-image-7769" src="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/DS-success-coach-headshot-paul.jpg" alt="Michael Paul" width="300" height="300" srcset="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/DS-success-coach-headshot-paul.jpg 275w, https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/DS-success-coach-headshot-paul-150x150.jpg 150w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a></b>Michael has supported UW Data Science students since 2013, with a career in higher education spanning 15 years. As a success coach, Michael helps students improve their connectedness to the program, their home campus, and online resources.</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><b>Jennifer Cox | Academic Program Manager at UW Extended Campus</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><b><a href="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/DS-program-manager-headshot-cox.jpg"><img loading="lazy" class="alignleft wp-image-7772" src="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/DS-program-manager-headshot-cox-300x300.jpg" alt="Jennifer Cox" width="300" height="300" srcset="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/DS-program-manager-headshot-cox-300x300.jpg 300w, https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/DS-program-manager-headshot-cox-150x150.jpg 150w, https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/DS-program-manager-headshot-cox-768x767.jpg 768w, https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/DS-program-manager-headshot-cox.jpg 800w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a></b>Jennifer has worked in research, project management, and information science at the University of Wisconsin System since 2007. She became the Academic Program Manager for the UW Data Science program after completing the MS in Data Science degree program in 2018. Jennifer’s greatest data science interest relates to the use of data in business strategy and decision making.</span></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/blog/data-science-webinar-highlights-future-of-the-field/">Data Science Webinar Highlights the Current Job Market and Future of the Field</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu">University of Wisconsin Data Science Degree</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/blog/data-science-webinar-highlights-future-of-the-field/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Take a Look at a UW Data Science Course: Foundations of Data Science</title>
		<link>https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/blog/data-science-course-preview-foundations-of-data-science/</link>
					<comments>https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/blog/data-science-course-preview-foundations-of-data-science/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[UW Data Science Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 03 Dec 2021 18:00:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Degree Program]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://wwwtest.datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/?p=5790</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>“What are the UW Data Science master’s program courses like?” We often receive this question from prospective students. So, we created this post to give you an inside look at the first data science course in the curriculum, “DS 700: Foundations of Data Science”—and to answer some of the questions that may be on your [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/blog/data-science-course-preview-foundations-of-data-science/">Take a Look at a UW Data Science Course: Foundations of Data Science</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu">University of Wisconsin Data Science Degree</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“What are the UW Data Science master’s program courses like?” </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">We often receive this question from prospective students. So, we created this post to give you an inside look at the first data science course in the curriculum, “DS 700: Foundations of Data Science”</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">—</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">and to answer some of the questions that may be on your mind.  </span></p>
<h2><b>What do I learn in the course? </b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“DS 700: Foundations of Data Science” introduces you to data science and its importance in business decision-making. The course provides an overview of commonly used data science tools, such as R, and SQL Server, along with assignments on descriptive and predictive analytics. There is a focus on statistics, programming, ethical perspectives, and strategic deployment of analytics to lay the foundation for data science applications.</span></p>
<div style="width: 640px;" class="wp-video"><!--[if lt IE 9]><script>document.createElement('video');</script><![endif]-->
<video class="wp-video-shortcode" id="video-5790-1" width="640" height="360" preload="metadata" controls="controls"><source type="video/mp4" src="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/a-2.mp4?_=1" /><a href="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/a-2.mp4">https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/a-2.mp4</a></video></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>At the end of this course, you&#8217;ll be able to:</p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Comprehend fundamental concepts in Data Science and Analytics. </span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Understand fundamentals of SQL and apply them to Relational Databases. </span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Use R Studio for programming, using packages, debugging and knitting .Rmd files. </span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Effectively utilize packages from Tidyverse for R.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Read/Write data of various formats using R. </span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Create effective visualizations using ggformula. </span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Perform linear and logistic regression, interpret and graph the model. </span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Perform exploratory data analysis with dplyr package in R. / Perform data cleaning, management and manipulation with R. </span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Use conditional statements, loops and control flow logic in R. </span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Interpret p-values</span></li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This course features lessons that consist of lectures, readings and other media, assignments, discussion prompts, quizzes, and a final project.</span></p>
<ol>
<li><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Introduction to fundamental concepts in Data Science and Analytics</span></li>
<li><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Introduction to SQL and relational databases</span></li>
<li><span style="font-weight: 400;"> SQL Join and conditional flow statements</span></li>
<li><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Advanced SQL Server operations (Transact SQL)</span></li>
<li><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Intro to R Studio for programming, using packages, and knitting .Rmd files</span></li>
<li><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Intro to debugging in R studio, linear and logistic regression, and graphs</span></li>
<li><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Implement graphs in R, perform exploratory data analysis with dplyr</span></li>
<li><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Implement joins in R, use control flow logic, manipulate datasets, and implement imputation</span></li>
<li><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Implement functions in R, advanced debugging, good coding practice</span></li>
<li><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Write and debug code involving control flow logic</span></li>
<li><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Interpret p-values, solve complex problems using R</span></li>
<li><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Demonstrate ability to synthesize knowledge and skills</span></li>
</ol>
<h2><b>What are the lectures like? </b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">After you enroll in “Foundations of Data Science,” you can log in to the learning management system to access all course content. The lectures are hosted in Storybook+ media player and contain rich media content—slides, animations, videos, and instructor narration. You can listen and replay lectures as many times as you wish.</span></p>
<p><!-- Begin "ds700_week7" - Embedded on: July 10, 2018 4:56pm --></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Some lessons have video content featuring interviews with real-life data scientists about their work and the current industry landscape. Other videos show the professor demonstrating vital skills that data scientists use on the job, including how to perform a K-means cluster analysis or work in SQL server.</span></p>
<p><!-- Begin "ds700_lesson4_intro-to-nosql.sbproj" - Embedded on: 08-22-2021 --></p>
<div class="storybook-wrapper"><iframe loading="lazy" src="https://media.uwex.edu/content/ds/ds700_r20/ds700_lesson4_intro-to-nosql.sbproj/" width="900px" height="586px" frameborder="0" scrolling="no" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"> </iframe></div>
<p><!-- End "ds700_lesson4_intro-to-nosql.sbproj"--></p>
<h2><b>What type of assignments do I complete? </b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">There is a mini project and a final project that encourage you to practice and demonstrate the concepts you learned in the course. You might be asked to create SQL queries for various scenarios using the sample database. You will use your R</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> programming skills honed during the course to perform analytical operations and derive inferences.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Here’s an example of the mini project: </span></p>
<p><a href="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/DS-700_Lesson-Example_2021.png"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-7657 " src="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/DS-700_Lesson-Example_2021.png" alt="Data Science SQL Lesson Example" width="645" height="397" srcset="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/DS-700_Lesson-Example_2021.png 936w, https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/DS-700_Lesson-Example_2021-300x185.png 300w, https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/DS-700_Lesson-Example_2021-768x473.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 645px) 100vw, 645px" /></a></p>
<h2><b>What else do I do in the course? </b></h2>
<p><b>Learning material.</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">The professor for this course picks selections from textbooks, articles, or videos for students to watch. Sometimes, you are asked to reflect on this material in an assignment or discussion prompt.</span></p>
<p><a href="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/DS-700_Lesson-Screenshot.png"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-7658 aligncenter" src="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/DS-700_Lesson-Screenshot.png" alt="" width="673" height="434" srcset="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/DS-700_Lesson-Screenshot.png 936w, https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/DS-700_Lesson-Screenshot-300x194.png 300w, https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/DS-700_Lesson-Screenshot-768x496.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 673px) 100vw, 673px" /></a></p>
<p><b>Discussion posts.  </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">A lesson may include a graded discussion prompt, which gives you an opportunity to learn from your peers and contribute your own ideas to the group. For these, you craft an initial post and reply to other students’ posts.</span></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-5801" src="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/Screen-Shot-2018-05-02-at-4.58.36-PM.png" alt="data science course" width="600" height="486" srcset="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/Screen-Shot-2018-05-02-at-4.58.36-PM.png 748w, https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/Screen-Shot-2018-05-02-at-4.58.36-PM-300x243.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px" /></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-5800" src="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/Screen-Shot-2018-05-02-at-4.58.46-PM.png" alt="data science course" width="600" height="279" srcset="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/Screen-Shot-2018-05-02-at-4.58.46-PM.png 838w, https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/Screen-Shot-2018-05-02-at-4.58.46-PM-300x140.png 300w, https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/Screen-Shot-2018-05-02-at-4.58.46-PM-768x357.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px" /></p>
<p><b>Quizzes. </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">Most lessons include a quiz of 25 to 30 questions covering that week’s course content, readings, and videos. </span></p>
<h2><b>What technology do I use in this data science course? </b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">You use MS SQL Server, R Studio, and Microsoft Office (Access, Excel, Word, PowerPoint). </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">All of these software applications are on the virtual desktop platform, which you have access to as a student in the UW Data Science program.</span></p>
<p><a href="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/DS-MS-SQL_Server-Logo.png"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-7660 aligncenter" src="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/DS-MS-SQL_Server-Logo-300x245.png" alt="" width="139" height="114" srcset="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/DS-MS-SQL_Server-Logo-300x245.png 300w, https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/DS-MS-SQL_Server-Logo.png 400w" sizes="(max-width: 139px) 100vw, 139px" /></a><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-7661 aligncenter" src="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/DS-RStudio-Logo-300x105.png" alt="" width="183" height="64" srcset="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/DS-RStudio-Logo-300x105.png 300w, https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/DS-RStudio-Logo-1024x360.png 1024w, https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/DS-RStudio-Logo-768x270.png 768w, https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/DS-RStudio-Logo-1536x539.png 1536w, https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/DS-RStudio-Logo-2048x719.png 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 183px) 100vw, 183px" /><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-7659 aligncenter" src="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/DS-Microsoft-Office-Logo-2021-300x95.png" alt="" width="246" height="78" srcset="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/DS-Microsoft-Office-Logo-2021-300x95.png 300w, https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/DS-Microsoft-Office-Logo-2021-1024x323.png 1024w, https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/DS-Microsoft-Office-Logo-2021-768x242.png 768w, https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/DS-Microsoft-Office-Logo-2021.png 1109w" sizes="(max-width: 246px) 100vw, 246px" /></p>
<h2><b>Who developed the course? </b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/faculty/rajeev-bukralia/">Dr. Rajeev Bukralia</a>, a former instructor at UW-Green Bay, originally developed the content for “DS 700: Foundations of Data Science.” The course was revised by instructors <a href="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/faculty/praneet-tiwari/">Praneet Tiwari</a> and <a href="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/faculty/abra-brisbin/">Abra Brisbin</a>. The course is facilitated by instructor <a href="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/faculty/jae-choi/">Jae Hoon Choi</a>. Faculty work with an instructional design team and industry advisory board to ensure that the course remains cutting-edge and aligned with employer needs. </span></p>
<h2><b>Do students in the course interact? </b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Yes. Students interact and share ideas through graded discussions in the learning management system. Also, data science students can collaborate, ask questions, and have general, non-assessed discussions through Piazza, a web-based forum.</span></p>
<figure id="attachment_5833" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-5833" style="width: 600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/image002.png"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-5833" src="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/image002-1024x537.png" alt="" width="600" height="314" srcset="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/image002-1024x537.png 1024w, https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/image002-300x157.png 300w, https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/image002-768x402.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-5833" class="wp-caption-text">Click to zoom in on the conversations.</figcaption></figure>
<h2><b>How much do I do in one week?</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Generally, you need to complete one lesson per week. You have seven days to complete readings and other learning materials, lectures, assignments, and discussion posts. (If you take the course during summer term, the timeline is accelerated, and you may complete multiple lessons per week.) </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This <strong><a href="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/data-science-program/data-science-courses/">data science master’s curriculum</a></strong> is as intensive as any University of Wisconsin program—on campus or otherwise. Some students put 20 hours of work into one course each week. But that number varies widely depending on how much experience they bring to the program. Although the program requires a serious time commitment, the flexible, online format allows you to study early in the morning, late at night, or whenever works best for your schedule, making it ideal for those who work full time. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Have questions about “DS 700: Foundations of Data Science,” the rest of the curriculum, how to apply, home campuses, and more? Our enrollment advisers can help. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Call 608-262-2011 or email </span><a href="mailto:learn@uwex.wisconsin.edu"><span style="font-weight: 400;">learn@uwex.wisconsin.edu</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/blog/data-science-course-preview-foundations-of-data-science/">Take a Look at a UW Data Science Course: Foundations of Data Science</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu">University of Wisconsin Data Science Degree</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/blog/data-science-course-preview-foundations-of-data-science/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		<enclosure url="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/a-2.mp4" length="22762920" type="video/mp4" />

			</item>
		<item>
		<title>What Prerequisite Skills Are Required For Admission to the Data Science Programs?</title>
		<link>https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/blog/skills-required-for-data-science-programs/</link>
					<comments>https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/blog/skills-required-for-data-science-programs/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[UW Data Science Blog Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 17:32:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Degree Program]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data science degree]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[UW Data Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Master's Degree]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Online Learning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Master of Data Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[UW Extended Campus]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/?p=7715</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Are you interested in pursuing UW&#8217;s Data Science programs but not entirely sure whether your previous experience meets our requirements? Here are the prerequisite skills needed:</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/blog/skills-required-for-data-science-programs/">What Prerequisite Skills Are Required For Admission to the Data Science Programs?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu">University of Wisconsin Data Science Degree</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Are you interested in pursuing <a href="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/data-science-program/">UW&#8217;s Data Science programs</a> but not entirely sure whether your previous experience meets our requirements? Here are the prerequisite skills needed:</p>
<p><a href="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/MSDS-prerequisites-infographic-FINAL.png"><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone wp-image-7738 size-full" src="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/MSDS-prerequisites-infographic-FINAL.png" alt="" width="1700" height="6800" srcset="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/MSDS-prerequisites-infographic-FINAL.png 1700w, https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/MSDS-prerequisites-infographic-FINAL-75x300.png 75w, https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/MSDS-prerequisites-infographic-FINAL-256x1024.png 256w, https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/MSDS-prerequisites-infographic-FINAL-768x3072.png 768w, https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/MSDS-prerequisites-infographic-FINAL-384x1536.png 384w, https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/MSDS-prerequisites-infographic-FINAL-512x2048.png 512w" sizes="(max-width: 1700px) 100vw, 1700px" /></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/blog/skills-required-for-data-science-programs/">What Prerequisite Skills Are Required For Admission to the Data Science Programs?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu">University of Wisconsin Data Science Degree</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/blog/skills-required-for-data-science-programs/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>New Online University of Wisconsin Data Science Certificate Now Available</title>
		<link>https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/blog/new-online-data-science-certificate/</link>
					<comments>https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/blog/new-online-data-science-certificate/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Peggy Rynearson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 14:37:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/?p=7399</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>UW Extended Campus, in partnership with several University of Wisconsin System campuses, will offer an online Graduate Certificate in Data Science in September 2021. The certificate is a 5-course, 15-credit program designed for adult students interested in learning current data science skills to keep pace in today’s data-driven world.  UW System campuses participating in the [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/blog/new-online-data-science-certificate/">New Online University of Wisconsin Data Science Certificate Now Available</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu">University of Wisconsin Data Science Degree</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">UW Extended Campus, in partnership with several University of Wisconsin System campuses, will offer an </span><a href="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/data-science-program/data-science-certificate/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">online Graduate Certificate in Data Science</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> in September 2021. The certificate is a 5-course, 15-credit program designed for adult students interested in learning current data science skills to keep pace in today’s data-driven world. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">UW System campuses participating in the online data science certificate program are UW-Eau Claire, UW-Green Bay, UW-La Crosse, UW-Oshkosh, UW-Stevens Point, and UW-Superior. </span><a href="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/data-science-program/about-uw-extended-campus/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">UW Extended Campus</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, in collaboration with UW System campuses, makes advanced education possible through flexible, online programs that combine the diverse expertise and resources of UW campuses and faculty.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"></span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“We are so pleased to introduce the Graduate Certificate in Data Science,” said</span><a href="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/blog/women-in-data-science-meet-program-manager-jennifer-cox/"><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Jennifer Cox,</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Program Manager of the online UW Master of Science in Data Science. “This certificate is designed for current or potential data professionals who might not have the time or need to complete a full degree program but have a desire to enhance their data skills. A certificate can give you that edge you need to do your job better or even advance your career.”</span></p>
<h2>Data Science Certificate Offers Skills Training to Meet Demand</h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The graduate-level Data Science certificate offers students an opportunity to learn the basic principles of data science and gain proficiency in statistics, machine learning, data visualization, programming, and other techniques. It is possible to earn the data science certificate within one year; however, students may decide to take longer based on work and life commitments. Coursework completed in the data science certificate program offers an optional pathway to the online UW Data Science master&#8217;s degree offered through UW Extended Campus. Similar to other UW Extended Campus programs, students pay the same tuition whether they live in Wisconsin or out of state.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The certificate, which provides skills training for individuals seeking career advancement in data-related occupations, was created to meet the growing demand for data proficient and data literate professionals across industries. According to the U.S. Bureau of Labor Statistics, employment of </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">computer and information research scientists is projected to grow 15 percent from 2019 to 2029,</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> much faster than the average for all occupations. </span></p>
<div class="perfect-pullquote vcard pullquote-align-full pullquote-border-placement-left"><blockquote><p>&#8220;<strong>A certificate can give you that edge you need to do your job better or even advance your career.&#8221; </strong></p></blockquote></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The new certificate joins a growing catalog of </span><a href="https://uwex.wisconsin.edu/degrees-programs/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span style="font-weight: 400;">flexible, online degree and certificate programs</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> designed for adult learners offered in collaboration with UW Extended Campus and UW System campus partners. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Students with a variety of work, education, and life experience have found success in UW Extended Campus programs and are making a difference in the world today.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Prospective students seeking more information about the online UW Graduate Certificate in Data Science are encouraged to download a program guide, call 1-608-262-2011, or 608-262-2011, or email learn@uwex.wisconsin.edu.</span></p>
<h3><b>About UW Extended Campus</b></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The University of Wisconsin is one of the largest and most widely respected public higher education systems in the country. <a href="https://uwex.wisconsin.edu/">UW Extended Campus</a> partners with all UW System campuses to offer online degrees and certificates, as well as continuing education and lifelong learning opportunities. Through UW Extended Campus, people of Wisconsin and beyond can access university resources and engage in online learning, wherever they live and work—fulfilling the promise of the “Wisconsin Idea”.</span></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/blog/new-online-data-science-certificate/">New Online University of Wisconsin Data Science Certificate Now Available</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu">University of Wisconsin Data Science Degree</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/blog/new-online-data-science-certificate/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Women in Data Science: Meet UW Data Science’s Program Manager: Jennifer Cox</title>
		<link>https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/blog/women-in-data-science-meet-program-manager-jennifer-cox/</link>
					<comments>https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/blog/women-in-data-science-meet-program-manager-jennifer-cox/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kaitlynn Martin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2021 21:57:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Degree Program]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data science degree]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[UW Data Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Master's Degree]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Online Learning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[women in data science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[UW Extended Campus]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://wwwtest.datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/?p=7192</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>As part of our Women in Data Science series highlighting the importance of women in the data science industry, we’re shining the spotlight on Jennifer Cox, a M.S. graduate in data science and the program manager for the 100% online UW Master of Science in Data Science program. After graduating from UW-Platteville in 2005 with [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/blog/women-in-data-science-meet-program-manager-jennifer-cox/">Women in Data Science: Meet UW Data Science’s Program Manager: Jennifer Cox</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu">University of Wisconsin Data Science Degree</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">As part of our Women in Data Science series highlighting the importance of women in the data science industry, we’re shining the spotlight on Jennifer Cox, a M.S. graduate in data science and the program manager for the </span><a href="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span style="font-weight: 400;">100% online UW Master of Science in Data Science</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> program.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">After graduating from UW-Platteville in 2005 with a bachelor’s degree in psychology and a minor in business, Jennifer worked as a program manager at a group home for adjudicated youth. However, she missed using the technical skills she gained in her psychology degree, specifically the statistical components. </span></p>
<figure id="attachment_7200" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-7200" style="width: 350px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><a href="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/jen-family-scaled.jpg"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-7200" src="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/jen-family-225x300.jpg" alt="program manager Jen Cox with her three daughters" width="350" height="467" srcset="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/jen-family-225x300.jpg 225w, https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/jen-family-768x1024.jpg 768w, https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/jen-family-1152x1536.jpg 1152w, https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/jen-family-1536x2048.jpg 1536w, https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/jen-family-scaled.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 350px) 100vw, 350px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-7200" class="wp-caption-text"><em>Jen and her three daughters</em></figcaption></figure>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Jennifer then transitioned to working in a research project management role within the School of Medicine and Public Health at UW-Madison, which is where she discovered the data science field. She was exposed to how databases, programming, and statistics merge together to investigate issues in healthcare. Jennifer also learned how big data, artificial intelligence, and machine learning are used to advance knowledge of disease, and offer opportunities for better prevention and treatment.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">While in her role at the UW School of Medicine and Public Health, Jennifer decided to pursue a master’s degree in data science. She had been researching programs since graduating with her bachelor’s degree, but nothing seemed like the right fit. Then, she found the online UW Master of Science in Data Science program. She began her degree in 2016 while working full-time and raising her young children.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“It was not easy, but with support and encouragement from my family and the Data Science program staff, I was able to graduate in 2018,” Jennifer said. “I was thrilled to have completed another major goal in my life and in something I felt so passionate about.” </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The UW Data Science program helped Jennifer gain confidence in her ability to do her work and her employer noticed this. After she earned her degree, Jennifer joined a team of clinical informatics professionals to create a master’s degree program. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“I learned a lot about academic program development and found I enjoyed putting together the many different components required to effectively run a program,” Jennifer said.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Jennifer began her role as program manager for UW Master of Science in Data Science and </span><a href="https://appliedcomputing.wisconsin.edu/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span style="font-weight: 400;">UW Bachelor of Science in Applied Computing </span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">in August of 2020.</span><b> </b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The following Q&amp;A with Jennifer Cox spotlights her role as program manager and as a woman in the data scie</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">nce field.</span></p>
<figure id="attachment_7201" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-7201" style="width: 350px" class="wp-caption alignright"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-7201" src="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/jen-graduation-225x300.jpg" alt="" width="350" height="467" srcset="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/jen-graduation-225x300.jpg 225w, https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/jen-graduation-768x1024.jpg 768w, https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/jen-graduation-1152x1536.jpg 1152w, https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/jen-graduation-1536x2048.jpg 1536w, https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/jen-graduation-scaled.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 350px) 100vw, 350px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-7201" class="wp-caption-text"><em>Jen and her family upon graduation with her master&#8217;s degree in data science in 2018</em></figcaption></figure>
<h4><b>Q: WHAT IS YOUR ROLE AS A UW EXTENDED CAMPUS PROGRAM MANAGER?</b></h4>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">As a program manager of the MS in Data Science and BS in Applied Computing, I serve as a liaison to the programs’ partner campuses to establish systems, policies, procedures and business practices that support effective operations. I see myself as a cheerleader for the programs, encouraging and supporting our partners to communicate and make decisions together as a team to best support our students.</span> <span style="font-weight: 400;">If we have shared goals, and an understanding of one another, we can best serve our students.</span> <span style="font-weight: 400;">I also collaborate with and provide support to internal UW Extended Campus team members to satisfy goals of these programs.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It is important to me that the programs are successful because I’m very passionate about both of these fields. I believe these programs are very strong and UW Extended Campus does a great job of setting students up for success. Graduates of these programs are the future of these fields, so I want to set them up to be the best they can be.</span></p>
<h4><b>Q: WHY DID YOU CHOOSE THE UW DATA SCIENCE PROGRAM AS A STUDENT? WHAT UNIQUE PERSPECTIVES DO YOU BRING TO YOUR ROLE AS PROGRAM MANAGER?</b></h4>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">As a Wisconsin native, I knew I could trust the quality of UW programs. I chose the UW Data Science program because I liked that it was 100% online and that I could alter my school schedule based on my personal needs. I also felt the curriculum fully covered the skills needed to be successful in the field, with a good mix of technical and nontechnical coursework. The program also leverages instructors from several UW campuses. These instructors are experts in their domains and they work hard to ensure course content is continuously updated to keep us relevant in the field.</span></p>
<div class="perfect-pullquote vcard pullquote-align-full pullquote-border-placement-left"><blockquote><p>&#8220;<em><strong>Graduates of these programs are the future of these fields, so I want to set them up to be the best they can be.&#8221; &#8211; Jennifer Cox, UW Data Science Program Manager</strong></em></p></blockquote></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I am utilizing the skills I obtained as a UW Data Science student in my program manager role by using data to understand organizational needs and to guide program decisions. I’m also able to effectively communicate data-related information to all audiences so both technical and nontechnical team members can understand. I also have the advantage of experiencing the program firsthand as a student, so I am able to share a student perspective with our campus partners.</span></p>
<p><b>Q: WHY ARE WOM</b><b>EN CRUCIAL TO THE DATA SCIENCE FIELD?</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Women bring unique perspectives and experiences to all areas of work. Leveraging women’s views allows a more complete understanding of an issue and how resolution might be reached. Gathering diverse perspectives, in general, will likely lead to an outcome that is more a</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">pplicable to the masses. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Women should pursue a data science career if they have an interest, and they shouldn’t feel discouraged by the predominantly male field. There is an increasing amount of women working in technical fields and rightfully so. We need highly skilled women to use their experiences and perspectives to bring understanding to all areas of data science.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Women and men currently in the field can support women entering the data science field by encouraging involvement and providing mentorship. Women should believe in themselves and have confidence that they are a valued contributor to the field.</span></p>
<figure id="attachment_7202" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-7202" style="width: 350px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-7202" src="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/jen-family-2-225x300.jpg" alt="" width="350" height="467" srcset="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/jen-family-2-225x300.jpg 225w, https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/jen-family-2-768x1024.jpg 768w, https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/jen-family-2-1152x1536.jpg 1152w, https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/jen-family-2-1536x2048.jpg 1536w, https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/jen-family-2-scaled.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 350px) 100vw, 350px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-7202" class="wp-caption-text"><em>Jen and her family before her youngest was born</em></figcaption></figure>
<p><b>Q: WHAT ADVICE DO YOU HAVE FOR PROSPECTIVE DATA SCIENCE STUDENTS?</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Getting a master’s degree is both a financial and time commitment. You should be honest with yourself about what your interests are and what you want to get out of completing the degree. It’s also important to make sure the outcomes of the program align with your goals and that the degree makes financial sense.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Having a support system is also really important. You should discuss your coursework schedule and how long it might take you to earn the degree with your support system. It’s likely you will have to give up some time with your family and friends to be successful, but understand it’s only temporary and it will payoff in the end.</span></p>
<p><b>Q: HOW WILL DATA SCIENCE IMPACT THE FUTURE?</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In this digital age, data surrounds us and, when used and interpreted appropriately, we can improve the world around us. Organizations can use data science to improve business practices, such as making operations more efficient or improving products and services. For example, healthcare organizations can use data to improve knowledge of diseases and how to best prevent and treat them. Information gained from harnessing data can allow us to learn things that might not have been possible before.</span></p>
<h2><b>UW Data Science strives to be inclusive</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In an effort to highlight the importance of women in the data science industry, this is the second post of a blog post series from UW Data Science. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Women in Data Science series features the crucial roles women take on within the computing field. Additionally, the series highlights students, faculty, and program leaders of the UW Master of Science in Data Science program who share their experiences as women in the data science industry, and offer advice for breaking into the male-dominated profession. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The UW Master of Science in Data Science program aims to create an inclusive environment for all. If you’d like to learn about graduates of the program, read about </span><a href="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/blog/from-dentistry-to-data-science-a-uw-grads-career-journey/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Venmathi Shanmugam</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, a modeling and simulations engineer working at the Veterans Affairs office, and </span><a href="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/blog/uw-data-science-student-this-masters-degree-propelled-me-forward-in-the-data-science-field/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Halee Mason</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, a lead data scientist at Cloud9 Esports, Inc. You can also learn about our </span><a href="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/data-science-faculty/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span style="font-weight: 400;">diverse faculty members</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Have questions about the courses, tuition, or how to apply? Talk with an enrollment adviser by emailing</span></i> <a href="mailto:learn@uwex.wisconsin.edu"><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">learn@uwex.wisconsin.edu</span></i></a> <i><span style="font-weight: 400;">or calling 608-262-2011.</span></i></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/blog/women-in-data-science-meet-program-manager-jennifer-cox/">Women in Data Science: Meet UW Data Science’s Program Manager: Jennifer Cox</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu">University of Wisconsin Data Science Degree</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/blog/women-in-data-science-meet-program-manager-jennifer-cox/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Women in Data Science: Why They’re Critical to the Data Science Workforce</title>
		<link>https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/blog/women-in-data-science-why-theyre-critical-to-the-data-science-workforce/</link>
					<comments>https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/blog/women-in-data-science-why-theyre-critical-to-the-data-science-workforce/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kaitlynn Martin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 14:01:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Careers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[women in data science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data science careers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[UW Extended Campus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[UW Data Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Online Learning]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://wwwtest.datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/?p=7129</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>According to a 2020 National Center for Women and Information Technology (NCWIT) report, women make up 57 percent of the overall workforce, but only 26 percent of computing and math occupations. This is the first post in a new series from UW Master of Science in Data Science to highlight the importance and need for [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/blog/women-in-data-science-why-theyre-critical-to-the-data-science-workforce/">Women in Data Science: Why They’re Critical to the Data Science Workforce</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu">University of Wisconsin Data Science Degree</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">According to a </span><a href="https://www.ncwit.org/sites/default/files/resources/ncwit_scorecard_data_highlights_10082020.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><span style="font-weight: 400;">2020 National Center for Women and Information Technology (NCWIT) report</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, women make up 57 percent of the overall workforce, but only 26 percent of computing and math occupations. This is the first post in a new series from UW Master of Science in Data Science to highlight the importance and need for women in the data science industry. The Women in Data Science series will feature the crucial roles women take on within the computing field. Additionally, the series will highlight students, faculty, and program leaders of the UW Master of Science in Data Science program who share their experiences as women in the data science industry, and offer advice for breaking into the male-dominated profession. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Though there is a lot of work yet to be done for women’s inclusivity in data science, there are a few statistics that are worth celebrating. In this first blog post, we take a look at hiring trends, strengths women bring to data science roles, and how women can stay competitive in the industry.</span></p>
<h2><b>Positive job growth for women in data science</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">First, let’s break down the percentage of women in computing occupations. A </span><a href="https://www.burtchworks.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Burtch-Works-Study_DS-PAP-2020.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><span style="font-weight: 400;">2020 Burtch-Works</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> study found that the </span>number of women in data scientist roles is on a<b> steady, albeit slow, rise</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">. In 2018, just 15 percent of data scientists were women. However, in 2019, that number rose to 17 percent, and in 2020, it rose to 18 percent. The same study also found that the largest percentage of women in data science roles are in the entry-level individual contributor category, followed by the managerial level one category.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">These numbers indicate a possible increased presence of women in the field, along with the beginning of women-led leadership. However, there is still a great need for growth in the computing field for women and other minority groups, especially in the mid-to-senior level leadership roles historically held by men.</span></p>
<h2><b>Diversity reduces bias and improves work quality in organizations</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The 2020 NCWIT report also found that </span>women in the computing workforce are<b> more racially and ethnically diverse</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> than men in the field. As shown in the graphic below, there is a higher percentage of women with African American, Black, and Asian descent who hold computing roles than men. </span></p>
<figure id="attachment_7131" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-7131" style="width: 600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-29-at-11.57.34-AM.png"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-7131" src="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-29-at-11.57.34-AM-1024x918.png" alt="" width="600" height="538" srcset="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-29-at-11.57.34-AM-1024x918.png 1024w, https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-29-at-11.57.34-AM-300x269.png 300w, https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-29-at-11.57.34-AM-768x689.png 768w, https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-29-at-11.57.34-AM.png 1084w" sizes="(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-7131" class="wp-caption-text"><em>Graphic from the <a href="https://www.ncwit.org/sites/default/files/resources/ncwit_scorecard_data_highlights_10082020.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><span style="font-weight: 400;">2020 National Center for Women and Information Technology (NCWIT) report</span></a> showing the racial composition between women and men with computer and information sciences (CIS) bachelor degrees in 2019. At all degree levels, the women earning CIS degrees are more racially and ethnically diverse when compared to men.</em></figcaption></figure>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Workplace diversity plays a large role in reducing bias, which is especially critical in the computing field. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">According to a </span><a href="https://www.bcg.com/en-us/publications/2020/what-keeps-women-out-data-science" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><span style="font-weight: 400;">2019 Boston Consulting Group (BCG) study</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Interpreting causal relationships and correlations in large data sets requ</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">ires subtlety, and both humans and machine learning algorithms can occasionally ‘see’ patterns that lead to spurious, biased, or even downright dangerous conclusions.” A diverse team—whether by gender, race, ethnicity, sexuality, age, disability, and more—allows for various opinions and experiences to be considered when tackling projects.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Workplace diversity also</span><b> improves the quality of work</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">. A</span><a href="https://venturebeat.com/2020/12/09/columbia-researchers-find-white-men-are-the-worst-at-reducing-ai-bias/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><span style="font-weight: 400;"> study done by Columbia University</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> researchers Bo Cowgill and Fabrizio Dell’Acqua</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> found that prediction errors were correlated within demographic groups, especially by gender and ethnicity.</span> <span style="font-weight: 400;">More diverse teams will reduce the chance for compounding biases, resulting in fewer errors.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">While diversity reduces bias, it also leads to higher innovation revenue, according to </span><a href="https://www.bcg.com/en-us/publications/2018/how-diverse-leadership-teams-boost-innovation" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><span style="font-weight: 400;">an earlier study from BCG</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Innovation revenue is identified as the “share of revenues that companies have generated from enhanced or entirely new products or services in the most recent three-year period.”</span> <span style="font-weight: 400;">Because people with different backgrounds and experiences often work through problems in different ways to come up with a variety of solutions, the odds that one of the solutions will be a financial success increases.</span></p>
<h2><b>A chance to make a difference in the world</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">There are a number of ways that data science impacts the world, and according to the </span><a href="https://www.bcg.com/en-us/publications/2020/what-keeps-women-out-data-science" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><span style="font-weight: 400;">2019 BCG study</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, this is important to women. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">The study found that 73 percent of women </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">entering the data science and machine learning field</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> prioritize tangible impact in their career choice, compared to 50 percent of men.</span></p>
<figure id="attachment_7132" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-7132" style="width: 800px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-29-at-12.06.54-PM.png"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-7132" src="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-29-at-12.06.54-PM-1024x509.png" alt="" width="800" height="398" srcset="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-29-at-12.06.54-PM-1024x509.png 1024w, https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-29-at-12.06.54-PM-300x149.png 300w, https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-29-at-12.06.54-PM-768x382.png 768w, https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-29-at-12.06.54-PM-1536x764.png 1536w, https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-29-at-12.06.54-PM.png 1596w" sizes="(max-width: 800px) 100vw, 800px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-7132" class="wp-caption-text"><em>Graphic from <span style="font-weight: 400;"> the </span><a href="https://www.bcg.com/en-us/publications/2020/what-keeps-women-out-data-science" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><span style="font-weight: 400;">2019 BCG study</span></a> comparing the percentage of women and men STEM students who have a preference for working on applied problems with tangible impact. On average, the results show that women, including data science majors, place a higher emphasis on applied, impact-driven work than men do.</em></figcaption></figure>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">However, many women do not see data science roles as fulfilling their career goals. According to the same study, half of women instead see the data science field as “theoretical and abstract, focused on manipulating code and data with low impact and, by implication, low purpose.” Although there are probably many factors that contribute to this negative perception, the study cites the largest is the companies themselves. It is argued that companies are not communicating the important and meaningful role that data scientists play within their business, deterring applicants.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Data science is utilized in all industries, ranging from renewable energy, to healthcare, to public safety. Within these industries, the work of data scientists often has a tangible impact on the technology that will shape our future. In order to recruit women to data science roles, </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">companies should </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">showcase how data science is at the heart of effective decision making by highlighting the specific problems that data scientists solve in their organization. Bottom line, all i</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">ndustries </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">stand to benefit from the experiences, perspectives, and skills that women in the field have to offer, and they must work toward better communicating with women in data science.</span></p>
<h2><b>How to stand out in a competitive industry</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">you have an interest in data science and want to stay competitive, enrolling in a data science master’s degree program may be the right next move for your career. You can start by asking yourself a </span><a href="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/blog/6-questions-to-ask-before-pursuing-a-masters-degree-in-data-science/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><span style="font-weight: 400;">few important questions</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> before taking the leap, including which program is the right fit. </span><b>Diversity in faculty expertise and perspectives </b>is a critical component<span style="font-weight: 400;"> to consider before applying to a program. It’s important that you can relate to and feel supported by program faculty and staff.</span></p>
<h2><b>UW Data Science strives to be inclusive</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The gender gap within data science roles and leadership positions continues to be a pressing issue. Every organization can benefit from prioritizing diversity, equity, and inclusion initiatives within their internal culture and hiring processes. This requires conversations at all employment levels, from institutions granting degrees to CEOs discussing promotions to leadership positions. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The UW Master of Science in Data Science program aims to create an inclusive environment for all. If you’d like to learn about graduates of the program, read about </span><a href="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/blog/from-dentistry-to-data-science-a-uw-grads-career-journey/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Venmathi Shanmugam</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, a modeling and simulations engineer working at the Veterans Affairs office, and </span><a href="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/blog/uw-data-science-student-this-masters-degree-propelled-me-forward-in-the-data-science-field/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Halee Mason</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, who is a lead data scientist at Cloud9 Esports, Inc. You can also learn about our </span><a href="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/data-science-faculty/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><span style="font-weight: 400;">diverse faculty members</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Have questions about the courses, tuition, or how to apply? Talk with an enrollment adviser by emailing</span></i> <i><span style="font-weight: 400;">learn@uwex.wisconsin.edu</span></i> <i><span style="font-weight: 400;">or calling 608-262-2011.</span></i></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/blog/women-in-data-science-why-theyre-critical-to-the-data-science-workforce/">Women in Data Science: Why They’re Critical to the Data Science Workforce</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu">University of Wisconsin Data Science Degree</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/blog/women-in-data-science-why-theyre-critical-to-the-data-science-workforce/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Data Science vs. Data Analytics: The Differences Explained</title>
		<link>https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/blog/data-science-vs-data-analytics-the-differences-explained/</link>
					<comments>https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/blog/data-science-vs-data-analytics-the-differences-explained/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kaitlynn Martin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 21 Oct 2020 13:00:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Careers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data analytics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online data science degree]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[UW Data Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data science career]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data analytics career]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://wwwtest.datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/?p=6936</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>If you’ve ever scanned job websites for roles in data, you’ve probably seen listings for data scientists and data analysts accompanied by job descriptions that sound quite similar. While the two fields are interconnected, data science and data analytics vary in scope, responsibilities and goals. One overarching similarity is that professionals in both roles use [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/blog/data-science-vs-data-analytics-the-differences-explained/">Data Science vs. Data Analytics: The Differences Explained</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu">University of Wisconsin Data Science Degree</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If you’ve ever scanned job websites for roles in data, you’ve probably seen listings for data scientists and data analysts accompanied by job descriptions that sound quite similar. While the two fields are interconnected, data science and data analytics vary in scope, responsibilities and goals.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">One overarching similarity is that professionals in both roles use big data to </span><b>solve problems and create improvements in an organization. </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">The biggest difference, however, is </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">how</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> they interact with data. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Data scientists often work with vast stores of raw data, working as investigators to create ways to analyze and model that data using statistical analysis and heavy coding. The goal of their work is to uncover the questions the data can answer. Data science often lays the foundation for further investigation. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Data analysts leverage the modeling of the data scientist to create actionable and practical insights using a variety of tools. The work of data analytics involves using organized data to apply findings immediately.</span></p>
<h2><strong>Skills and Tools You’ll Need in Data Science and Data Analytics</strong></h2>
<p>There are some distinct differences between skills needed for data science and data analytics careers. However, there is also some overlap.</p>
<figure id="attachment_6950" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-6950" style="width: 1000px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><a href="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/294-ds-vs-da_Page_1.png"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-6950" src="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/294-ds-vs-da_Page_1-1024x399.png" alt="data science vs data analytics skills comparison in venn diagram" width="1000" height="390" srcset="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/294-ds-vs-da_Page_1-1024x399.png 1024w, https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/294-ds-vs-da_Page_1-300x117.png 300w, https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/294-ds-vs-da_Page_1-768x299.png 768w, https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/294-ds-vs-da_Page_1-1536x598.png 1536w, https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/294-ds-vs-da_Page_1-2048x798.png 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-6950" class="wp-caption-text"><em>A Venn diagram highlighting the similarities and differences between the skills needed for data science and data analytics careers.</em></figcaption></figure>
<h2><strong>A Deep Dive into Jobs and Responsibilities</strong></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">When looking at job opportunities, it’s important to not only look at the job title, but also the responsibilities, as the titles can overlap between data science and data analytics.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Some common job titles in the data science field are:</span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Data scientist</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Data analyst</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Data architect</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Data mining engineer</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Machine learning engineer</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Hadoop engineer</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Predictive modeler</span></li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Data science responsibilities often include: identifying opportunities for investigation, collecting data, predicting trends, cleaning and validating data, and communicating. To learn more about data science careers, </span><a href="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/data-science/data-science-careers/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><span style="font-weight: 400;">read here</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Some common job titles in the data analytics field are:</span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Data analyst</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Business analyst</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Database analyst</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Market research analyst</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Operations analyst</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Business intelligence analyst</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Tableau developer</span></li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Here are some common data analytics responsibilities: exploratory data analysis, data cleansing, statistical analysis, and developing visualizations.</span></p>
<h2><strong>Salary Expectations</strong></h2>
<p><a href="https://www.bls.gov/oes/current/oes152098.htm" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><span style="font-weight: 400;">According to the U.S. Bureau of Labor Statistics</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, the mean annual wage of a data scientist is </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">$100,560. The </span><a href="https://www.burtchworks.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Burtch-Works-Study_DS-PAP-2020.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><span style="font-weight: 400;">2020 Burtch Works Study:</span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Salaries of Data Scientists &amp; Predictive Analytics Professionals</span></i></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> found that data scientists make on average between $95,000 and $250,000 annually, depending on experience level and managerial responsibilities. According to the same report</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">, predictive analysts can make between $80,000 and $250,000 on average, also depending on experience level and managerial responsibilities. For a more in-depth look at salary information, </span><a href="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/data-science/data-scientist-salary/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><span style="font-weight: 400;">visit here.</span></a></p>
<h2><strong>Educational Advantage</strong></h2>
<figure id="attachment_6968" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-6968" style="width: 600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/Screen-Shot-2020-10-20-at-11.29.10-AM.png"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-6968" src="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/Screen-Shot-2020-10-20-at-11.29.10-AM-1024x640.png" alt="education level of data analysts and data scientists" width="600" height="375" srcset="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/Screen-Shot-2020-10-20-at-11.29.10-AM-1024x640.png 1024w, https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/Screen-Shot-2020-10-20-at-11.29.10-AM-300x187.png 300w, https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/Screen-Shot-2020-10-20-at-11.29.10-AM-768x480.png 768w, https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/Screen-Shot-2020-10-20-at-11.29.10-AM-1536x959.png 1536w, https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/Screen-Shot-2020-10-20-at-11.29.10-AM.png 1678w" sizes="(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-6968" class="wp-caption-text"><em>A graph from the<a href="https://www.burtchworks.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Burtch-Works-Study_DS-PAP-2020.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Burtch-Works study</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> </span> showing the educational levels—including bachelor&#8217;s, master&#8217;s, and Ph.D.— of predictive analytics professionals and data scientists.</em></figcaption></figure>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">One way to increase your salary is to earn an advanced degree, which is common. in both fields. The </span><a href="https://www.burtchworks.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Burtch-Works-Study_DS-PAP-2020.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Burtch-Works study</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> found that 94 percent of data scientists and 83 percent of predictive analysts hold an advanced degree. It also noted that fewer professionals are choosing an advanced degree in business, such as an MBA, and are instead choosing a quantitatively-focused degree, such as data science or mathematics.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The 100% online </span><a href="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><span style="font-weight: 400;">UW Masters in Data Science</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> prepares students for both data science and data analytics roles. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Students not only learn technical skills they need to succeed, but they also gain knowledge in effective project management, leadership, and communication. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Want to focus on data analytics? UW Extended Campus offers a virtual </span><a href="https://bootcamp.wisconsin.edu/data/landing/?s=Google-Brand_RFull_&amp;msg_cv_scta=4&amp;msg_cv_stbn=1&amp;msg_cv_fcta=1&amp;fqvar1=3&amp;pkw=%2Buw%20%2Banalytics&amp;pcrid=458621853768&amp;pmt=b&amp;utm_source=google&amp;utm_medium=cpc&amp;utm_campaign=GGL%7CUNIVERSITY-OF-WISCONSIN%7CSEM%7CDATA%7C-%7CONL%7C_RFull_%7CALL%7CBRD%7CBMM%7CSecondary%7CGeneral&amp;utm_term=%2Buw%20%2Banalytics&amp;s=google&amp;k=%2Buw%20%2Banalytics&amp;utm_adgroupid=110026184609&amp;utm_locationphysicalms=9018938&amp;utm_matchtype=b&amp;utm_network=g&amp;utm_device=c&amp;utm_content=458621853768&amp;utm_placement=&amp;gclid=EAIaIQobChMIl_Xa4ujr6wIVg4bACh0a6AGaEAAYASAAEgJ37_D_BwE&amp;gclsrc=aw.ds" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Data Analytics Bootcamp</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> that can be completed in just 24 weeks. You will graduate from the program ready to apply your knowledge in the professional world.</span></p>
<h3><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">Discover</span></em></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The University of Wisconsin offers an online, 36-credit </span><b>Master of Science in Data Science </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">degree program. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">This data science master’s program will teach you how to harness the power of big data using the latest tools and analytical methods.</span> <a href="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Start your journey.</span></a></p>
<h3><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">Explore</span></em></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Curious about what you’d learn in UW Data Science courses? </span><a href="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/data-science-program/data-science-courses/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><span style="font-weight: 400;">See the curriculum.</span></a></p>
<h3><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">Ask</span></em></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Have questions about the UW Data Science program? Contact an adviser at 608-262-2011 or learn@uwex.wisconsin.edu.</span></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/blog/data-science-vs-data-analytics-the-differences-explained/">Data Science vs. Data Analytics: The Differences Explained</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu">University of Wisconsin Data Science Degree</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/blog/data-science-vs-data-analytics-the-differences-explained/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>UW Data Science Student Works Toward Master&#8217;s Degree to Expand His Future Career</title>
		<link>https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/blog/uw-data-science-student-works-toward-masters-degree-to-expand-his-future-career/</link>
					<comments>https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/blog/uw-data-science-student-works-toward-masters-degree-to-expand-his-future-career/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kaitlynn Martin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2020 21:13:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Student Stories]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Online Learning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[university of wisconsin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[student story]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Master's Degree]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://wwwtest.datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/?p=6654</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Although he has already earned two bachelor’s degrees—one in English and the other in information science and technology (IST)—Tim Drexler isn’t done yet. As a student in the 100% online University of Wisconsin Master of Science in Data Science (UW MSDS) program, Tim hopes to gain more programming and Big Data experience in order to [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/blog/uw-data-science-student-works-toward-masters-degree-to-expand-his-future-career/">UW Data Science Student Works Toward Master&#8217;s Degree to Expand His Future Career</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu">University of Wisconsin Data Science Degree</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Although he has already earned two bachelor’s degrees—one in English and the other in information science and technology (IST)—<strong>Tim Drexler</strong> isn’t done yet. As a student in the 100% online </span><strong><a href="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">University of Wisconsin Master of Science in Data Science</a></strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> (UW MSDS) program, Tim hopes to gain more programming and Big Data experience in order to take the next step in his career.</span></p>
<p><a href="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Screen-Shot-2020-03-26-at-11.27.45-AM.png"><img loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-6660 alignleft" src="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Screen-Shot-2020-03-26-at-11.27.45-AM-214x300.png" alt="" width="253" height="355" srcset="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Screen-Shot-2020-03-26-at-11.27.45-AM-214x300.png 214w, https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Screen-Shot-2020-03-26-at-11.27.45-AM.png 417w" sizes="(max-width: 253px) 100vw, 253px" /></a></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">When he first graduated from UW-Madison with his English degree, Tim transitioned from a part-time role to a full-time one at South Central Library System, working in its delivery service. Over the past 20 years, Tim has moved up from delivery driver to delivery operations support manager.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“My job responsibilities have changed in many ways,” Tim said. “Three  times a year, we complete a data sampling of our delivery volume. I am now responsible for collecting the data and putting it together in analysis spreadsheets. Working on these projects made me seriously think about how data science is something I would be good at.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Tim’s untraditional entrance into the data science world continues to push him out of his comfort zone. On </span><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/timothy-drexler/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><span style="font-weight: 400;">LinkedIn</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, he describes himself as an “</span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Evolving Data Scientist</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In 2015, Tim began looking for a degree that would prepare him for a more technology-focused career, and he knew an online program would work best for his busy schedule. He considered Madison Area Technical College, but it offered programs with in-person class requirements that didn’t fit into his life. However, </span><strong><a href="https://flex.wisconsin.edu/degrees-programs/information-science-technology/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">University of Wisconsin Flexible Option</a></strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> caught his eye, especially its 100% online IST degree. It felt like an attainable next step that worked with Tim’s goals and around his work/life schedule.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It took Tim only 13 months to graduate from the <strong>UW Flexible Option IST program</strong> with a UW-Milwaukee bachelor’s degree—a milestone that motivated him to consider pursuing a master’s degree in data science.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“UW Flexible Option was really good preparation for online learning in general,” Tim said. “I had experience within the learning system, and I knew how to motivate myself and manage my time, which are skills I continue to use in UW MSDS.”</span></p>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400;"><strong>RELATED</strong>: </span></i><a href="https://flex.wisconsin.edu/stories-news/uw-flexible-options-first-applicant-graduates-with-information-science-and-technology-degree/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">UW Flexible Option’s First Applicant Graduates with Information Science and Technology Degree</span></i></a></p>
<h2><b>A Program Where Passion and Learning Converge</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Every course in the UW MSDS program has been a huge learning opportunity for Tim. So much so, that he finds it difficult to choose just one as his favorite. From data mining and machine learning, to data warehousing and statistical methods, the </span><strong><a href="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/data-science-program/data-science-courses/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">UW MSDS curriculum</a></strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> touches on all aspects of a data science career.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“The courses are definitely a lot of work,” Tim said. “But I feel like I’m getting so much out of them.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Tim’s favorite project in the program so far has been part of the </span><strong><a href="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/ds-740-data-mining/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">MSDS 740: Data Mining &amp; Machine Learning</a></strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> course. Students use a dataset of their choice from </span><a href="https://www.kaggle.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Kaggle</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">—an online source for datasets and programming/data analysis challenges—and analyze it by using methods covered in the course. The project allows students the freedom to find a dataset that piques their personal interests. Tim found a dataset from the </span><a href="https://www.kaggle.com/nasa/kepler-exoplanet-search-results" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Kepler Space Telescope</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> that connected to his astronomy and physics curiosities.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;I put that dataset through a machine learning analysis process and then built algorithms that identified stars with potential planetary bodies orbiting them,” Tim said. “It was really interesting to be able to use real-world, scientific data to sharpen my skills.&#8221;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In fall 2019, Tim completed the </span><strong><a href="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/ds-745-visualization-unstructured-data-analysis/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">MSDS 745: Visualization and Unstructured Data Analysis</a></strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> course, which directly related to his data collecting responsibilities at work. He said formatting the data is a continuous challenge, especially when it comes to communicating what the data represents.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“The data visualization course focused on summarizing and presenting data for non-technical people,” Tim said. “Now, I can go to my boss with a data plot or chart that illustrates how our delivery volume varies by weeks, months, and years. Then, I can work on an informative analysis that leads to meaningful action.”</span></p>
<p><strong><i>RELATED: </i></strong><a href="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/blog/uw-data-science-professor-motivates-students-to-look-at-data-through-personal-lens/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">UW Data Science Professor Motivates Students to Look at Data Through Personal Lens</span></i></a></p>
<h2><b>Supported for Success</b></h2>
<figure id="attachment_6656" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-6656" style="width: 271px" class="wp-caption alignright"><a href="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Danielle_Stertz.png"><img loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-6656" src="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Danielle_Stertz-236x300.png" alt="" width="271" height="344" srcset="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Danielle_Stertz-236x300.png 236w, https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Danielle_Stertz.png 353w" sizes="(max-width: 271px) 100vw, 271px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-6656" class="wp-caption-text">UW Flexible Option Academic Success Coach, Danielle Stertz</figcaption></figure>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Tim’s transition from earning his IST degree through UW Flexible Option to enrolling into the online UW Master of Science in Data Science program, demonstrates the high-quality and continuity of service that UW Flexible Option and UW Extended Campus coaches and advisers offer. Tim is the first to vouch for the support he has received through both programs.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“I can definitely say that I wouldn&#8217;t have made it through the UW Flexible Option without (Academic Success Coach) </span><a href="https://flex.wisconsin.edu/academic-success-coaches/danielle-stertz/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><span style="font-weight: 400;"><strong>Danielle</strong> <strong>Stertz’s</strong></span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> help,” Tim said. “She was a great advocate and was always there to answer questions. I had some tough moments in that program, and I wouldn&#8217;t have pulled through without her support.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“When I’ve contacted (Student Success Coach) </span><strong><a href="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/student-services/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Michael Paul</a></strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> for the UW MSDS program, it&#8217;s the </span>same kind of situation. He&#8217;s always answering questions and getting back to students right away. It&#8217;s pretty amazing—the work that they do, especially to support people from a distance.”</p>
<figure id="attachment_4603" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-4603" style="width: 265px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><a href="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2016/10/Michael-2015-color-headshot.jpg"><img loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-4603" src="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2016/10/Michael-2015-color-headshot-200x300.jpg" alt="" width="265" height="398" srcset="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2016/10/Michael-2015-color-headshot-200x300.jpg 200w, https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2016/10/Michael-2015-color-headshot-683x1024.jpg 683w, https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2016/10/Michael-2015-color-headshot.jpg 700w" sizes="(max-width: 265px) 100vw, 265px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-4603" class="wp-caption-text">UW Data Science Student Success Coach, Michael Paul</figcaption></figure>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Along with the support he receives, Tim also provides support to peers in his courses. A handful of students have noticed that Tim steps up to the plate within online class discussion boards and helps answer questions where and when he can.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">To Tim, he sees this as a way of putting himself in others’ shoes.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“I don’t necessarily have expertise per say, but if there&#8217;s something I can answer right away, then I don&#8217;t mind giving it a shot,” Tim said. “I try to look at it as if I had a question that I posted. I would want it answered sooner rather than later, even if it wasn&#8217;t quite right, just to spark my thinking process. It’s a way for me to help others—and myself—to get unstuck.”</span></p>
<h2></h2>
<h2><b>Ready to Take the Next Step</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">With more than half of the UW MSDS program’s courses complete, Tim is optimistic that he is becoming well prepared to move into an entry-level role as a data analyst or similar position. He views earning his master’s degree as a major step in his career and one that he is eager to see through.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“I&#8217;m coming from a field where I have no real technical background, and I’ve been fortunate to have completed a lot of classes with other students with database administration and other data science experience,” Tim said. “I&#8217;m learning a lot just from interacting with them and understanding all the ways I can specialize in different industries.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">For Tim, the flexibility, affordability, curricula, and support within the <strong>UW Flexible Option IST</strong> and <strong>UW Data Science</strong> programs made his choice to go back to school while working full time possible. Furthermore, <strong>Tim embodies the Wisconsin Idea</strong>—investing in himself to advance his skills in order to impact his future, improve processes at his work, and to connect with the greater community.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">When asked for his parting advice to prospective students, Tim is honest about his pacing throughout both programs:</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“It&#8217;s important to try to plan your class schedule so you don’t overload yourself too much in any one semester,” Tim said. “One thing I was worried about right away was having too much to do. So, I started the program with a smaller course load to get my feet wet. Do what makes the most sense for your strengths and life. And know that you have support along the way to keep you going.”</span></p>
<h2><b>What’s Next?</b></h2>
<p><a href="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/data-science-program/data-science-masters/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Start exploring</span></a> <span style="font-weight: 400;">how the </span><b>UW Master of Science in Data Science</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> online degree program can push you to new career heights. Have questions about the courses, tuition, or how to apply? Talk with an enrollment adviser by emailing</span> <a href="mailto:learn@uwex.wisconsin.edu"><span style="font-weight: 400;">learn@uwex.wisconsin.edu</span></a> <span style="font-weight: 400;">or calling 608-262-2011.</span></p>
<p><b><i>UW Master of Science in Data Science</i></b><i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> is a collaboration of several UW System campuses. Tim is earning his degree from</span></i> <a href="https://uwosh.edu/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">UW-Oshkosh</span></i></a><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></i></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/blog/uw-data-science-student-works-toward-masters-degree-to-expand-his-future-career/">UW Data Science Student Works Toward Master&#8217;s Degree to Expand His Future Career</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu">University of Wisconsin Data Science Degree</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/blog/uw-data-science-student-works-toward-masters-degree-to-expand-his-future-career/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>UW Data Science Professor Motivates Students to Look at Data Through Personal Lens</title>
		<link>https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/blog/uw-data-science-professor-motivates-students-to-look-at-data-through-personal-lens/</link>
					<comments>https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/blog/uw-data-science-professor-motivates-students-to-look-at-data-through-personal-lens/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kaitlynn Martin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2020 17:55:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Degree Program]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online degree]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[University of Wisconsin Data Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Master of Data Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Faculty Profile]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://wwwtest.datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/?p=6599</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>When Abra Brisbin was earning her undergraduate mathematics degree from Carleton College, she wanted to apply math and data to areas that made an impact in the real world. To do that, she earned her Ph.D. in applied mathematics from Cornell University, where she focused on statistical genetics—understanding how genetic variations influence people’s health. In [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/blog/uw-data-science-professor-motivates-students-to-look-at-data-through-personal-lens/">UW Data Science Professor Motivates Students to Look at Data Through Personal Lens</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu">University of Wisconsin Data Science Degree</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/Abra_Brisbin1.png"><img loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-6603 alignright" src="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/Abra_Brisbin1-265x300.png" alt="" width="301" height="341" srcset="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/Abra_Brisbin1-265x300.png 265w, https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/Abra_Brisbin1-768x868.png 768w, https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/Abra_Brisbin1.png 774w" sizes="(max-width: 301px) 100vw, 301px" /></a>When </span><strong><a href="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/faculty/abra-brisbin/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Abra Brisbin</a></strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> was earning her undergraduate mathematics degree from Carleton College, <strong>she wanted to apply math and data to areas that made an impact in the real world</strong>. To do that, she earned her Ph.D. in applied mathematics from Cornell University, where she focused on statistical genetics—understanding how genetic variations influence people’s health.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In the next two years, <strong>Abra completed a postdoc at Mayo Clinic</strong> in Rochester, Minnesota, and then moved into her current role as an <strong>associate professor in the mathematics department</strong> at the </span><a href="https://www.uwec.edu/profiles/brisbia/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><span style="font-weight: 400;">University of Wisconsin-Eau Claire</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Additionally, she co-develops and teaches courses in the 100% online </span><strong><a href="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">University of Wisconsin Master of Science in Data Science</a></strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"><strong>,</strong> including </span><a href="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/data-science-710-programming-for-data-science/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><span style="font-weight: 400;">DS 710: Programming for Data Science</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> and </span><a href="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/ds-740-data-mining/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><span style="font-weight: 400;">DS 740: Data Mining &amp; Machine Learning</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In the following Q&amp;A, Abra shares what drew her into the world of data science, <strong>what motivates her to be a teacher in the UW MSDS program</strong>, and how she helps her students gain the skills they need to be successful in the field.</span></p>
<h2><b>Q: What Drew You Into the World of Data?</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br />
</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"></span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I think one of the great things about statistics and data science is that you can analyze data from a wide variety of different fields.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">When you find an interesting data set, you can figure out what there is to learn from it. For example, I&#8217;ve worked with students on research projects involving crime rates in Eau Claire or students who have analyzed factors that influence housing prices in the city—which both have a personal importance beyond the numbers.</span></p>
<figure id="attachment_6604" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-6604" style="width: 851px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/Dataset1.png"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-6604" src="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/Dataset1.png" alt="" width="851" height="473" srcset="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/Dataset1.png 1076w, https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/Dataset1-300x167.png 300w, https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/Dataset1-768x427.png 768w, https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/Dataset1-1024x569.png 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 851px) 100vw, 851px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-6604" class="wp-caption-text">Data set from DS 740: Data Mining &amp; Machine Learning</figcaption></figure>
<h2><b>Q: Why Did You Become a Faculty Member of UW MSDS?<br />
</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"></span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It was an opportunity that came up through my connection with <a href="https://www.uwec.edu/profiles/smithaj/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Alex Smith</a>—the chair of the mathematics department at UW-Eau Claire. He was getting involved in developing the UW MSDS curriculum and it was really interesting to me. It sounded like a way where I could have some influence over designing these new courses and to really focus on the things that I think are the most important about programming for data science and machine learning.</span></p>
<h2><b>Q: What are those Important Aspects of Data Science, Machine Learning, and Programming?<br />
</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"></span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I think the problem solving aspect is really important because it’s not just simply following a series of steps. It’s thinking where you use both logic and creativity to come to a solution.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The willingness to learn is also huge. As a professor, I can&#8217;t possibly teach all of the algorithms that students might need to know when they go out to do data science in their careers. I make it a point to demonstrate how I figure things out and learn more about how various data science methods work, so that students will be prepared to teach themselves in the future when they are out of a structured learning environment.</span></p>
<h2><b>Q: What is Your Favorite Part of Teaching Your UW MSDS Courses?<br />
</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"></span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The final project in the DS 740: Data Mining &amp; Machine Learning course is really fun because the students can choose whatever topic they want to analyze. They start by choosing a data set from </span><a href="https://www.kaggle.com/datasets?utm_medium=paid&amp;utm_source=google.com+search&amp;utm_campaign=datasets&amp;gclid=EAIaIQobChMI3JjD74Ca5wIVRr7ACh3x8Ap3EAAYASAAEgKWFvD_BwE" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Kaggle</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">—an online source for data science data sets, programming challenges, and data analysis challenges.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Then, they analyze the data using two of the methods that we cover throughout the course and they come up with their assessment of how the data addresses a question that would be of interest to their target audience and which of the data analysis methods they’d recommend.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This project is when students have a chance to branch out into the data set that&#8217;s interesting to them, which can show off their personality and learning style. It&#8217;s fun to grade, because I get to read about all of these different data sets that I may not be familiar with.</span></p>
<figure id="attachment_6605" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-6605" style="width: 1066px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/Dataset2.png"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-6605 size-full" src="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/Dataset2.png" alt="" width="1066" height="600" srcset="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/Dataset2.png 1066w, https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/Dataset2-300x169.png 300w, https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/Dataset2-768x432.png 768w, https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/Dataset2-1024x576.png 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 1066px) 100vw, 1066px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-6605" class="wp-caption-text">Data set example from DS 740: Data Mining &amp; Machine Learning</figcaption></figure>
<h2><b>Q: How Would You Describe Your Teaching Style When it Comes to Online Learning?<br />
</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"></span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I’ve structured the courses I teach so that each lesson fits into one week of the semester (although the pace is faster in the summer). Most lessons have some reading and one or more short video lectures, where you can hear my voice or the voices of my co-instructors as we talk through slides or demonstrate an analysis on our computers. Additionally, lessons have some low-stakes practice problems where you can get hints and try them as many times as you want. Then, you have weekly homework, which gives you hands-on experience with implementing the methods discussed in that lesson.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The interactive part of the courses comes from our discussion board and online office hours. Our course discussion board is very active with students asking questions, helping to answer each other’s questions, and even discussing related topics, such as sharing interesting news articles they read about data science. I check the discussion board twice per day, so students get feedback quickly.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I typically have online office hours two or three times a week, once or twice during business hours, and once that&#8217;s either in the evening on a weekday or at some time on a Saturday. The goal is that as many students as possible will be able to attend at least one of those times. It can be a phone call or you have the option of sharing your webcam so we can see each other. There&#8217;s also a chat window where students can enter questions.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">When I’m answering questions in office hours, I can share my screen and demonstrate examples of code or pull up slides from the lecture to show how a question connects with the material that was covered in the class that week. Students can chime in with follow-up questions or help answer each other&#8217;s questions. We record office hours and post links to them within the discussion board, so students who can&#8217;t attend office hours can still view what was discussed.</span></p>
<h2><b>Q: What Advice Do You Have for Current and Prospective UW MSDS Students?<br />
</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"></span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Be excited about problem solving and learning about all of the aspects of data science!</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Also, be aware that master&#8217;s-level courses are challenging, even if they&#8217;re only three credits. Students who are working full-time jobs might be better served by taking just one course a semester. Some students who are very motivated can do more than that, but taking three courses in a semester while also working full-time is a very, very heavy load. It’s important to find that balance that works best for your life.</span></p>
<h2><b>Q: Why Should Prospective Students Consider UW MSDS?<br />
</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"></span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Our program offers a strong balance of the quantitative rigor that students will get from programming and</span> <span style="font-weight: 400;">data mining courses along with the business acumen that they get from courses such as </span><a href="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/ds-735-communicating-about-data/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><span style="font-weight: 400;">DS 735: Communicating About Data</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> and </span><a href="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/ds-760-ethics-data-science/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><span style="font-weight: 400;">DS 760: Ethics of Data Science</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I think the fact that this program is online makes it really good for students who are currently working in a job that uses some data science and those who want to advance their careers by getting a degree. This program can help them get to the next career step they are aiming for.</span></p>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Want to learn more about how expert faculty members, like Abra Brisbin, teach, connect, and prepare </span></i><a href="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">UW Master of Science in Data Science </span></i></a><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">students for exciting careers in the field? Check out the </span></i><a href="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/data-science-program/data-science-courses/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">program’s curriculum</span></i></a><i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> or contact an enrollment adviser at 608-262-2011 or </span></i><a href="mailto:learn@uwex.wisconsin.edu"><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">learn@uwex.wisconsin.edu</span></i></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/blog/uw-data-science-professor-motivates-students-to-look-at-data-through-personal-lens/">UW Data Science Professor Motivates Students to Look at Data Through Personal Lens</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu">University of Wisconsin Data Science Degree</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://datasciencedegree.wisconsin.edu/blog/uw-data-science-professor-motivates-students-to-look-at-data-through-personal-lens/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
