<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?> 
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
<channel>
<atom:link href="https://www.wto.org/library/rss/latest_news_e.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
<title>World Trade Organization — Latest news</title> 
<link>http://www.wto.org</link> 
<description>World Trade Organization — Latest news</description> 
<image>
	<url>http://www.wto.org/images/podcast_logo_144x144pxls.gif</url>
	<title>World Trade Organization — Latest news</title>
	<link>http://www.wto.org</link>
</image>
<ttl>15</ttl>
<itunes:author>WTO</itunes:author>
<itunes:owner>
	<itunes:name>WTO</itunes:name>
	<itunes:email>webmaster@wto.org</itunes:email>
</itunes:owner>
<itunes:image href="http://www.wto.org/images/podcast_logo_300x300pxls.gif"/>
<itunes:category text="Business" />
<itunes:explicit>clean</itunes:explicit>
<itunes:keywords>World Trade Organization, WTO,  Doha Development Agenda, DDA</itunes:keywords>
<pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2022 21:56:46 GMT</pubDate>
<lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2022 21:56:46 GMT</lastBuildDate> 
<language>en-us</language> 
<copyright>Copyright 2022 WTO</copyright>

<item>
 <title>DDG Zhang underscores importance of implementing MC12 outcomes, other trade agreements</title>
 <description><![CDATA[Speaking at a workshop on 4 November held at the Foreign Trade University (FTU) in Hanoi, a member of the WTO Chairs Programme, Deputy Director-General Xiangchen Zhang highlighted the importance of putting into practice WTO decisions and agreements, in particular those adopted at the 12th Ministerial Conference (MC12) earlier this year. ]]></description>
 <link>https://www.wto.org/english/news_e/news22_e/chair_04nov22_e.htm</link>
 <pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2022 17:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
 <guid>https://www.wto.org/english/news_e/news22_e/chair_04nov22_e.htm</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>WTO to champion importance of trade in climate action toolkit at COP27 climate summit</title>
 <description><![CDATA[The WTO is set to play an active role at the UN’s COP27 Climate Change Conference taking place in Sharm El-Sheikh, Egypt, from 6 to 18 November. A detailed agenda for the WTO’s participation and WTO resources on trade and climate change can be viewed on the new COP27 portal on the WTO website. The conference will also see the launch of the WTO’s flagship publication, the World Trade Report, entitled “Climate Change and International Trade”.]]></description>
 <link>https://www.wto.org/english/news_e/news22_e/cop27_04nov22_e.htm</link>
 <pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2022 17:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
 <guid>https://www.wto.org/english/news_e/news22_e/cop27_04nov22_e.htm</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>DDG Paugam: More collective efforts needed to address food crisis</title>
 <description><![CDATA[In a speech delivered at the Organisation for Economic Co-operation and Development meeting of Agriculture Ministers on 3  November, Deputy Director-General Jean-Marie Paugam said collective efforts by the WTO and other international organizations have helped alleviate upward pressure on food prices, but more efforts were needed to tackle the crisis ahead. He also warned that the use of export restrictions on food were spreading to products beyond oilseeds and grains and that their application beyond strict emergency situations could become a concern. His remarks are below.]]></description>
 <link>https://www.wto.org/english/news_e/news22_e/agri_04nov22_e.htm</link>
 <pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 17:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
 <guid>https://www.wto.org/english/news_e/news22_e/agri_04nov22_e.htm</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>Director-General meets with CEOs to discuss improved access to COVID-19 therapeutics</title>
 <description><![CDATA[Director-General Ngozi Okonjo-Iweala met on 3 November with CEOs from a range of companies engaged in the production of key COVID-19 therapeutics.  The purpose of the meeting was to review current challenges for expanding and diversifying production of therapeutics and explore the potential role of trade policy tools in addressing and overcoming those challenges, especially in light of ongoing discussions among WTO members on extending the TRIPS Decision at the 12th WTO Ministerial Conference (MC12) to COVID-19 diagnostics and therapeutics.]]></description>
 <link>https://www.wto.org/english/news_e/news22_e/dgno_03nov22_e.htm</link>
 <pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 17:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
 <guid>https://www.wto.org/english/news_e/news22_e/dgno_03nov22_e.htm</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>WTO marks 75th anniversary of the General Agreement on Tariffs and Trade</title>
 <description><![CDATA[On the occasion of the 75th anniversary of the General Agreement on Tariffs and Trade (GATT), WTO Deputy Director-General Anabel González and Douglas Irwin, the John French Professor of Economics of Dartmouth College, participated in a webinar to discuss the origins of the GATT, what it achieved and how it fits within the multilateral trading system. WTO Director-General Dr Ngozi Okonjo-Iweala provided introductory remarks, highlighting the key role of trade in lifting people out of poverty since the birth of the GATT. ]]></description>
 <link>https://www.wto.org/english/news_e/news22_e/hist_02nov22_e.htm</link>
 <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2022 17:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
 <guid>https://www.wto.org/english/news_e/news22_e/hist_02nov22_e.htm</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>WTO opens registration for the World Trade Congress on Gender</title>
 <description><![CDATA[Under the theme “Gender Equality for Sustainable Trade and Recovery”, the World Trade Congress on Gender will take place at the WTO from 5 to 7 December to explore how gender equality can foster sustainable trade and how trade can support women in times of crisis. The objective of the Congress is to highlight research work conducted by trade and gender experts, showcase new research initiatives and promote innovative thinking on trade and gender.]]></description>
 <link>https://www.wto.org/english/news_e/news22_e/women_01nov22_e.htm</link>
 <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2022 17:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
 <guid>https://www.wto.org/english/news_e/news22_e/women_01nov22_e.htm</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>WTO Secretariat launches Trade Remedies Data Portal </title>
 <description><![CDATA[The WTO Secretariat on 1 November launched the Trade Remedies Data Portal, an online tool that provides access to information on members’ anti-dumping and countervailing duty actions. ]]></description>
 <link>https://www.wto.org/english/news_e/news22_e/rese_01nov22_e.htm</link>
 <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2022 17:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
 <guid>https://www.wto.org/english/news_e/news22_e/rese_01nov22_e.htm</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>WTO issues information note on technical barriers to trade discussions relating to COVID-19</title>
 <description><![CDATA[The WTO Secretariat issued a new information note on 31 October providing an overview of discussions within the Committee on Technical Barriers to Trade (TBT) relating to COVID-19.]]></description>
 <link>https://www.wto.org/english/news_e/news22_e/covid_31oct22_e.htm</link>
 <pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2022 17:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
 <guid>https://www.wto.org/english/news_e/news22_e/covid_31oct22_e.htm</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>France gives EUR 50,000 to boost safe food exports from developing countries</title>
 <description><![CDATA[The Ministry of Agriculture and Food Sovereignty of France is contributing EUR 50,000 (approximately CHF 49,000) for 2022 to the Standards and Trade Development Facility (STDF) to help developing and least-developed countries (LDCs) meet international food safety, animal and plant health standards for trade and improve their access to global and regional markets. The contribution adds to the EUR 400,000 already committed to the STDF by France’s Ministry of the Economy, Finance and Industrial and Digital Sovereignty.]]></description>
 <link>https://www.wto.org/english/news_e/pres22_e/pr910_e.htm</link>
 <pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2022 17:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
 <guid>https://www.wto.org/english/news_e/pres22_e/pr910_e.htm</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>WHO, WIPO, WTO workshop looks at innovation and access to COVID-19 diagnostics and beyond</title>
 <description><![CDATA[The third in a series of technical workshops jointly hosted by the World Health Organization (WHO), the World Intellectual Property Organization (WIPO) and the WTO discussed on 29 October a wide range of health, intellectual property and trade issues regarding diagnostics, with the purpose of getting a better understanding of innovation and equitable access in this sector. The workshop, attended by 188 participants, was divided into two sessions: factual introductions by WHO, WIPO and WTO secretariats followed by a roundtable discussion by experts from various backgrounds.]]></description>
 <link>https://www.wto.org/english/news_e/news22_e/igo_02nov22_e.htm</link>
 <pubDate>Sat, 29 Oct 2022 17:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
 <guid>https://www.wto.org/english/news_e/news22_e/igo_02nov22_e.htm</guid>
</item>

</channel> 
</rss>