<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<rdf:RDF
 xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
 xmlns="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/"
 xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
 xmlns:taxo="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/taxonomy/"
 xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
 xmlns:syn="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
 xmlns:admin="http://webns.net/mvcb/"
>

<channel rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/">
<title>quant-ph updates on arXiv.org</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">Quantum Physics (quant-ph) updates on the arXiv.org e-print archive</description>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:date>2022-11-03T20:30:00-05:00</dc:date>
<dc:publisher>www-admin@arxiv.org</dc:publisher>
<dc:subject>Quantum Physics</dc:subject>
<syn:updateBase>1901-01-01T00:00+00:00</syn:updateBase>
<syn:updateFrequency>1</syn:updateFrequency>
<syn:updatePeriod>daily</syn:updatePeriod>
<items>
 <rdf:Seq>
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01376" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01380" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01381" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01383" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01392" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01428" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01433" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01441" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01444" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01477" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01485" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01489" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01497" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01514" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01525" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01552" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01620" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01650" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01653" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01657" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01665" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01668" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01681" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01684" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01687" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01735" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01773" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01803" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01815" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01819" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01838" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01857" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01870" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01884" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01895" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01899" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01923" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01925" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01934" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01942" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01947" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01989" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.02014" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.02017" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.02037" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2012.08889" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2105.06244" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2107.09984" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2109.05862" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2110.08304" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2112.09280" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2202.12615" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2203.06586" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2203.16012" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2204.06245" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2204.13684" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2204.13945" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2205.00198" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2205.05704" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2206.14277" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2207.02933" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2208.07454" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2208.13858" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.05053" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.05689" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.09457" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.16438" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.17448" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.00350" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01068" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01190" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01331" />
 </rdf:Seq>
</items>
<image rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif" />
</channel>
<image rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif">
<title>arXiv.org</title>
<url>http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif</url>
<link>http://arxiv.org/</link>
</image>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01376">
<title>Higgs Condensates are Symmetry-Protected Topological Phases: I. Discrete Symmetries. (arXiv:2211.01376v1 [cond-mat.str-el])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01376</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Where in the landscape of many-body phases of matter do we place the Higgs
condensate of a gauge theory? On the one hand, the Higgs phase is gapped, has
no local order parameter, and for fundamental Higgs fields is adiabatically
connected to the confined phase. On the other hand, Higgs phases such as
superconductors display rich phenomenology. In this work, we propose a minimal
description of the Higgs phase as a symmetry-protected topological (SPT) phase,
utilizing conventional and higher-form symmetries. In this first part, we focus
on 2+1D $\mathbb Z_2$ gauge theory and find that the Higgs phase is protected
by a higher-form magnetic symmetry and a matter symmetry, whose meaning depends
on the physical context. While this proposal captures known properties of Higgs
phases, it also predicts that the Higgs phase of the Fradkin-Shenker model has
SPT edge modes in the symmetric part of the phase diagram, which we confirm
analytically. In addition, we argue that this SPT property is remarkably robust
upon explicitly breaking the magnetic symmetry. Although the Higgs and confined
phases are then connected without a bulk transition, they are separated by a
boundary phase transition, which we confirm with tensor network simulations.
More generally, the boundary anomaly of the Higgs SPT phase coincides with the
emergent anomaly of symmetry-breaking phases, making precise the relation
between Higgs phases and symmetry breaking. The SPT nature of the Higgs phase
can also manifest in the bulk, e.g., at transitions between distinct Higgs
condensates. Finally, we extract insights which are applicable to general SPT
phases, such as a &apos;bulk-defect correspondence&apos; generalizing discrete gauge
group analogs of Superconductor-Insulator-Superconductor (SIS) junctions. The
sequel to this work will generalize &apos;Higgs=SPT&apos; to continuous symmetries,
interpreting superconductivity as an SPT property.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Verresen_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ruben Verresen&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Borla_U/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Umberto Borla&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Vishwanath_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ashvin Vishwanath&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Moroz_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Sergej Moroz&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Thorngren_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ryan Thorngren&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01380">
<title>Large-Scale $2+1$D $\mathrm{U}(1)$ Gauge Theory with Dynamical Matter in a Cold-Atom Quantum Simulator. (arXiv:2211.01380v1 [cond-mat.quant-gas])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01380</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;A major driver of quantum-simulator technology is the prospect of probing
high-energy phenomena in synthetic quantum matter setups at a high level of
control and tunability, thereby offering a venue complementary to dedicated
particle colliders. Here, we propose an experimentally feasible realization of
a large-scale $2+1$D $\mathrm{U}(1)$ gauge theory with dynamical matter and
gauge fields in a cold-atom quantum simulator with spinless bosons. We present
the full mapping of the corresponding Gauss&apos;s law onto the bosonic
computational basis. We then show that the target gauge theory can be
faithfully realized and stabilized by an emergent gauge protection term in a
two-dimensional single-species Bose--Hubbard optical Lieb superlattice with two
spatial periods along either direction, thereby requiring only moderate
experimental resources already available in current cold-atom setups. Using
infinite matrix product states, we calculate numerical benchmarks for adiabatic
sweeps and global quench dynamics that further confirm the fidelity of the
mapping. Our work brings quantum simulators of gauge theories a significant
step forward in terms of investigating particle physics in higher spatial
dimensions, and is readily implementable in existing cold-atom platforms.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Osborne_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jesse Osborne&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+McCulloch_I/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ian P. McCulloch&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Yang_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Bing Yang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Hauke_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Philipp Hauke&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Halimeh_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jad C. Halimeh&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01381">
<title>Quantum Spin Puddles and Lakes: NISQ-Era Spin Liquids from Non-Equilibrium Dynamics. (arXiv:2211.01381v1 [cond-mat.str-el])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01381</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;While many-body systems can host long-ranged entangled quantum spin liquids
(QSLs), the ingredients for realizing these as ground states can be
prohibitively difficult. In many circumstances, one requires (i) a constrained
Hilbert space and (ii) an extensive quantum superposition. The paradigmatic
example is the toric code, or $\mathbb{Z}_2$ spin liquid, which is a
superposition of closed loop states. We show how non-equilibrium Hamiltonian
dynamics can provide a streamlined route toward creating such QSLs. Rather than
cooling into the ground state of a Hamiltonian, we show how a simple parameter
sweep can dynamically project a family of initial product states into the
constrained space, giving rise to a QSL. For the toric code, this is achieved
in systems with a separation in energy scales between the $e$- and $m$-anyons,
where one can sweep in a way that is adiabatic (sudden) with respect to the
former (latter). Although this separation of scales does not extend to the
thermodynamic limit, we analytically and numerically show that this method
efficiently prepares a spin liquid in finite-sized regions, which we brand
``quantum spin lakes.&apos;&apos; This mechanism elucidates recent experimental and
numerical observations of the dynamical state preparation of the ruby lattice
spin liquid in Rydberg atom arrays. In fact, the slow dynamics of $m$-anyons
suggest that we can capture spin lake preparation by simulating the dynamics on
tree lattices, which we confirm with tensor network simulations. Finally, we
use this mechanism to propose new experiments, e.g., for preparing a
finite-sized $U(1)$ spin liquid as a honeycomb Rokhsar-Kivelson dimer model
using Rydberg atoms -- which is remarkable given its equilibrium counterpart is
unstable in $2 + 1$D. Our work opens up a new avenue in the study of
non-equilibrium physics, as well as the exploration of exotic states of finite
extent in NISQ devices.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Sahay_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Rahul Sahay&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Vishwanath_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ashvin Vishwanath&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Verresen_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ruben Verresen&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01383">
<title>Pulse-efficient quantum machine learning. (arXiv:2211.01383v1 [quant-ph])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01383</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Quantum machine learning algorithms based on parameterized quantum circuits
are promising candidates for near-term quantum advantage. Although these
algorithms are compatible with the current generation of quantum processors,
device noise limits their performance, for example by inducing an exponential
flattening of loss landscapes. Error suppression schemes such as dynamical
decoupling and Pauli twirling alleviate this issue by reducing noise at the
hardware level. A recent addition to this toolbox of techniques is
pulse-efficient transpilation, which reduces circuit schedule duration by
exploiting hardware-native cross-resonance interaction. In this work, we
investigate the impact of pulse-efficient circuits on near-term algorithms for
quantum machine learning. We report results for two standard experiments:
binary classification on a synthetic dataset with quantum neural networks and
handwritten digit recognition with quantum kernel estimation. In both cases, we
find that pulse-efficient transpilation vastly reduces average circuit
durations and, as a result, significantly improves classification accuracy. We
conclude by applying pulse-efficient transpilation to the Hamiltonian
Variational Ansatz and show that it delays the onset of noise-induced barren
plateaus.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Melo_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Andr&amp;#xe9; Melo&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Earnest_Noble_N/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Nathan Earnest-Noble&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Tacchino_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Francesco Tacchino&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01392">
<title>R\&apos;enyi Mutual Information in Quantum Field Theory. (arXiv:2211.01392v1 [hep-th])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01392</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We study a proper definition of R\&apos;enyi mutual information (RMI) in quantum
field theory as defined via the Petz R\&apos;enyi relative entropy. Unlike the
standard definition, the RMI we compute is a genuine measure of correlations
between subsystems, as evidenced by its non-negativity and monotonicity under
local operations. Furthermore, the RMI is UV finite and well-defined in the
continuum limit. We develop a replica path integral approach for the RMI in
quantum field theories and evaluate it explicitly in 1+1D conformal field
theory using twist fields. We prove that it bounds connected correlation
functions and check our results against exact numerics in the massless free
fermion theory.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Kudler_Flam_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jonah Kudler-Flam&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01428">
<title>Entanglement complexity of the Rokhsar-Kivelson-sign wavefunctions. (arXiv:2211.01428v1 [quant-ph])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01428</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;In this paper we study the transitions of entanglement complexity in an
exemplary family of states - the Rokhsar-Kivelson-sign wavefunctions - whose
degree of entanglement is controlled by a single parameter. This family of
states is known to feature a transition between a phase exhibiting volume-law
scaling of entanglement entropy and a phase with sub-extensive scaling of
entanglement, reminiscent of the many-body-localization transition of
disordered quantum Hamiltonians [Physical Review B 92, 214204 (2015)]. We study
the singularities of the RK-sign wavefunctions and their entanglement
complexity across the transition using several tools from quantum information
theory: fidelity metric; entanglement spectrum statistics; entanglement entropy
fluctuations; stabilizer R\&apos;enyi Entropy; and the performance of a
disentangling algorithm. Across the whole volume-law phase the states feature
universal entanglement spectrum statistics. Yet a &quot;super-universal&quot; regime
appears for small values of the control parameter in which all metrics become
independent of the parameter itself; the entanglement entropy as well as the
stabilizer R\&apos;enyi entropy appear to approach their theoretical maximum; the
entanglement fluctuations scale to zero as in output states of random universal
circuits, and the disentangling algorithm has essentially null efficiency. All
these indicators consistently reveal a complex pattern of entanglement. In the
sub-volume-law phase, on the other hand, the entanglement spectrum statistics
is no longer universal, entanglement fluctuations are larger and exhibiting a
non-universal scaling; and the efficiency of the disentangling algorithm
becomes finite. Our results, based on model wavefunctions, suggest that a
similar combination of entanglement scaling properties and of entanglement
complexity features may be found in high-energy Hamiltonian eigenstates.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Piemontese_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Stefano Piemontese&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Roscilde_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Tommaso Roscilde&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Hamma_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Alioscia Hamma&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01433">
<title>Testing highly nonlinear fiber for squeezed-light generation. (arXiv:2211.01433v1 [physics.optics])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01433</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Squeezed light, which is easily degraded by loss, could benefit from
generation directly in optical fiber. Furthermore, highly nonlinear fiber could
offer more efficient generation with lower pump power and shorter fiber lengths
than standard single-mode fiber. We investigate non-polarization-maintaining
highly nonlinear fiber (HNLF) for squeezed-light generation by characterizing
possible sources of excess noise, including its zero-dispersion wavelength
(ZDW) variation and polarization noise. We find significant ZDW variation and
excess polarization noise. We believe the polarization noise is from non-linear
polarization-mode dispersion. These findings are indicative of excess noise
that would reduce and potentially completely overtake any squeezing generated,
except possibly using intensity difference detection.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Chapman_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Joseph C. Chapman&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Peters_N/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Nicholas A. Peters&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01441">
<title>eXplainable AI for Quantum Machine Learning. (arXiv:2211.01441v1 [quant-ph])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01441</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Parametrized Quantum Circuits (PQCs) enable a novel method for machine
learning (ML). However, from a computational point of view they present a
challenge to existing eXplainable AI (xAI) methods. On the one hand,
measurements on quantum circuits introduce probabilistic errors which impact
the convergence of these methods. On the other hand, the phase space of a
quantum circuit expands exponentially with the number of qubits, complicating
efforts to execute xAI methods in polynomial time. In this paper we will
discuss the performance of established xAI methods, such as Baseline SHAP and
Integrated Gradients. Using the internal mechanics of PQCs we study ways to
speed up their computation.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Steinmuller_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Patrick Steinm&amp;#xfc;ller&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Schulz_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Tobias Schulz&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Graf_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ferdinand Graf&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Herr_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Daniel Herr&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01444">
<title>Pseudorandom (Function-Like) Quantum State Generators: New Definitions and Applications. (arXiv:2211.01444v1 [quant-ph])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01444</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Pseudorandom quantum states (PRS) are efficiently constructible states that
are computationally indistinguishable from being Haar-random, and have recently
found cryptographic applications. We explore new definitions, new properties
and applications of pseudorandom states, and present the following
contributions:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1. New Definitions: We study variants of pseudorandom function-like state
(PRFS) generators, introduced by Ananth, Qian, and Yuen (CRYPTO&apos;22), where the
pseudorandomness property holds even when the generator can be queried
adaptively or in superposition. We show feasibility of these variants assuming
the existence of post-quantum one-way functions.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2. Classical Communication: We show that PRS generators with logarithmic
output length imply commitment and encryption schemes with classical
communication. Previous constructions of such schemes from PRS generators
required quantum communication.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3. Simplified Proof: We give a simpler proof of the Brakerski--Shmueli
(TCC&apos;19) result that polynomially-many copies of uniform superposition states
with random binary phases are indistinguishable from Haar-random states.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4. Necessity of Computational Assumptions: We also show that a secure PRS
with output length logarithmic, or larger, in the key length necessarily
requires computational assumptions.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Ananth_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Prabhanjan Ananth&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Gulati_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Aditya Gulati&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Qian_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Lower Qian&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Yuen_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Henry Yuen&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01477">
<title>On the practical usefulness of the Hardware Efficient Ansatz. (arXiv:2211.01477v1 [quant-ph])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01477</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Variational Quantum Algorithms (VQAs) and Quantum Machine Learning (QML)
models train a parametrized quantum circuit to solve a given learning task. The
success of these algorithms greatly hinges on appropriately choosing an ansatz
for the quantum circuit. Perhaps one of the most famous ansatzes is the
one-dimensional layered Hardware Efficient Ansatz (HEA), which seeks to
minimize the effect of hardware noise by using native gates and connectives.
The use of this HEA has generated a certain ambivalence arising from the fact
that while it suffers from barren plateaus at long depths, it can also avoid
them at shallow ones. In this work, we attempt to determine whether one should,
or should not, use a HEA. We rigorously identify scenarios where shallow HEAs
should likely be avoided (e.g., VQA or QML tasks with data satisfying a volume
law of entanglement). More importantly, we identify a Goldilocks scenario where
shallow HEAs could achieve a quantum speedup: QML tasks with data satisfying an
area law of entanglement. We provide examples for such scenario (such as
Gaussian diagonal ensemble random Hamiltonian discrimination), and we show that
in these cases a shallow HEA is always trainable and that there exists an
anti-concentration of loss function values. Our work highlights the crucial
role that input states play in the trainability of a parametrized quantum
circuit, a phenomenon that is verified in our numerics.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Leone_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Lorenzo Leone&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Oliviero_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Salvatore F.E. Oliviero&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Cincio_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Lukasz Cincio&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Cerezo_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;M. Cerezo&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01485">
<title>Information compression at the turbulent-phase transition in cold atom gases. (arXiv:2211.01485v1 [cond-mat.quant-gas])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01485</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The statistical properties of physical systems in thermal equilibrium are
blatantly different from their far-from-equilibrium counterparts. In the
latter, fluctuations often dominate the dynamics and might cluster in ordered
patterns in the form of dissipative coherent structures. Here, we study the
transition of a cold atomic cloud, driven close to a sharp electronic
resonance, from a stable to a turbulent phase. From the atomic density
distribution -- measured using a spatially-resolved pump-probe technique -- we
have computed the Shannon entropy on two different basis sets. Information
compression, corresponding to a minimum in the Shannon entropy, has been
observed at criticality, where the system fluctuations organize into high-order
(low-entropy) patterns. Being independent of the representation used, this
feature is a property shared by a vast class of physical systems undergoing
phase transitions.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Giampaoli_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;R. Giampaoli&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Figueiredo_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;J. L. Figueiredo&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Rodrigues_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;J. D. Rodrigues&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Rodrigues_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;J. A. Rodrigues&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Tercas_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;H. Ter&amp;#xe7;as&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Mendonca_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;J. T. Mendon&amp;#xe7;a&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01489">
<title>Chip-scale Simulations in a Quantum-correlated Synthetic Space. (arXiv:2211.01489v1 [physics.optics])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01489</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;An efficient simulator for quantum systems is one of the original goals for
the efforts to develop a quantum computer [1]. In recent years, synthetic
dimension in photonics [2] have emerged as a potentially powerful approach for
simulation that is free from the constraint of geometric dimensionality. Here
we demonstrate a quantum-correlated synthetic crystal, based upon a
coherently-controlled broadband quantum frequency comb produced in a chip-scale
dynamically modulated lithium niobate microresonator. The time-frequency
entanglement inherent with the comb modes significantly extends the
dimensionality of the synthetic space, creating a massive nearly 400 x 400
synthetic lattice with electrically-controlled tunability. With such a system,
we are able to utilize the evolution of quantum correlations between entangled
photons to perform a series of simulations, demonstrating quantum random walks,
Bloch oscillations, and multi-level Rabi oscillations in the time and frequency
correlation space. The device combines the simplicity of monolithic
nanophotonic architecture, high dimensionality of a quantum-correlated
synthetic space, and on-chip coherent control, which opens up an avenue towards
chip-scale implementation of large-scale analog quantum simulation and
computation [1,3,4] in the time-frequency domain.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Javid_U/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Usman A. Javid&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Lopez_Rios_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Raymond Lopez-Rios&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Ling_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jingwei Ling&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Graf_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Austin Graf&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Staffa_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jeremy Staffa&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Lin_Q/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Qiang Lin&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01497">
<title>Optimizing for periodicity: a model-independent approach to flux crosstalk calibration for superconducting circuits. (arXiv:2211.01497v1 [quant-ph])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01497</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Flux tunability is an important engineering resource for superconducting
circuits. Large-scale quantum computers based on flux-tunable superconducting
circuits face the problem of flux crosstalk, which needs to be accurately
calibrated to realize high-fidelity quantum operations. Typical calibration
methods either assume that circuit elements can be effectively decoupled and
simple models can be applied, or require a large amount of data. Such methods
become ineffective as the system size increases and circuit interactions become
stronger. Here we propose a new method for calibrating flux crosstalk, which is
independent of the underlying circuit model. Using the fundamental property
that superconducting circuits respond periodically to external fluxes,
crosstalk calibration of N flux channels can be treated as N independent
optimization problems, with the objective functions being the periodicity of a
measured signal depending on the compensation parameters. We demonstrate this
method on a small-scale quantum annealing circuit based on superconducting flux
qubits, achieving comparable accuracy with previous methods. We also show that
the objective function usually has a nearly convex landscape, allowing
efficient optimization.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Dai_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;X. Dai&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Trappen_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;R. Trappen&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Yang_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;R. Yang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Disseler_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;S. M. Disseler&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Basham_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;J. I. Basham&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Gibson_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;J. Gibson&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Melville_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;A. J. Melville&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Niedzielski_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;B. M. Niedzielski&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Das_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;R. Das&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Kim_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;D. K. Kim&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Yoder_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;J. L. Yoder&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Weber_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;S. J. Weber&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Hirjibehedin_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;C. F. Hirjibehedin&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Lidar_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;D. A. Lidar&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Lupascu_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;A. Lupascu&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01514">
<title>N-photon Bound States In The Continuum For Strong Intensity Squeezing And Deterministic Stabilization Of Large Photonic Fock States. (arXiv:2211.01514v1 [quant-ph])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01514</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Large non-Gaussian states of light are a highly coveted resource in quantum
science and technology. An important example of such states are n-photon states
of light (Fock states), which, besides being the most fundamental states of the
quantized radiation field, are theoretically believed to be valuable for many
tasks including metrology, communication, simulation, quantum state generation,
and information processing. However, the deterministic creation of even
approximate large-number Fock states at optical frequencies is a long-standing
open problem. Here, we present a fundamental new effect in nonlinear photonic
systems, called n-photon bound states in the continuum, which can be applied to
deterministically create large Fock states, as well as very highly
intensity-squeezed states of light. The effect is one in which destructive
interference gives a certain quantum state of light an infinite lifetime,
despite coexisting in frequency with a radiative continuum. For Kerr nonlinear
systems, that state is an Fock state of a particular and tunable n. We develop
the theory using experimentally-realizable examples (showing examples of
producing 30-photon Fock states, and states with very large intensity squeezing
(10 dB)), and we describe schemes to pump and probe the generated quantum
states. The effect requires only Kerr nonlinearity and linear
frequency-dependent (non-Markovian) dissipation, and is in principle applicable
at any frequency. The theory and concepts are also immediately applicable to
nonlinear bosons besides photons, and should be implementable in many other
fields (e.g., superconducting circuits, magnonics, phononics). Further, we
expect the broader possibility of using engineered nonlinear photonic
structures with highly tailorable radiation loss as a basis to create many of
the other quantum photonic states that have traditionally been hard to
generate.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Rivera_N/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Nicholas Rivera&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Sloan_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jamison Sloan&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Salamin_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yannick Salamin&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Soljacic_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Marin Soljacic&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01525">
<title>Exploring quantum geometry created by quantum matter. (arXiv:2211.01525v1 [gr-qc])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01525</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Exactly soluble models can serve as excellent tools to explore conceptual
issues in non-perturbative quantum gravity. In perturbative approaches, it is
only the two radiative modes of the linearized gravitational field that are
quantized. The goal of this investigation is to probe the `Coulombic&apos; aspects
of quantum geometry that are governed entirely by matter sources. Since there
are no gravitational waves in 3 dimensions, 3-d gravity coupled to matter
provides an ideal arena for this task. Our analysis will reveal novel aspects
of quantum gravity that bring out limitations of classical and semi-classical
theories in unforeseen regimes: non-linearities of general relativity can
magnify small quantum fluctuations in the matter sector to large effects in the
gravitational sector. Finally, this analysis leads to thought experiments that
bring out rather starkly why understanding of the nature of physical reality
depends sensitively on the theoretical lens with which it is probed. As
theories becomes richer, new scales emerge, triggering novel effects that could
not be imagined before. The model provides a concise realization of this
well-known chain.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Ashtekar_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Abhay Ashtekar&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01552">
<title>Mobility edges and critical regions in periodically kicked incommensurate optical Raman lattice. (arXiv:2211.01552v1 [cond-mat.dis-nn])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01552</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Conventionally the mobility edge (ME) separating extended states from
localized ones is a central concept in understanding Anderson localization
transition. The critical state, being delocalized and non-ergodic, is a third
type of fundamental state that is different from both the extended and
localized states. Here we study the localization phenomena in a one dimensional
periodically kicked quasiperiodic optical Raman lattice by using fractal
dimensions. We show a rich phase diagram including the pure extended, critical
and localized phases in the high frequency regime, the MEs separating the
critical regions from the extended (localized) regions, and the coexisting
phase of extended, critical and localized regions with increasing the kicked
period. We also find the fragility of phase boundaries, which are more
susceptible to the dynamical kick, and the phenomenon of the reentrant
localization transition. Finally, we demonstrate how the studied model can be
realized based on current cold atom experiments and how to detect the rich
physics by the expansion dynamics. Our results provide insight into studying
and detecting the novel critical phases, MEs, coexisting quantum phases, and
some other physics phenomena in the periodically kicked systems.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Wang_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yucheng Wang&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01620">
<title>Quantum Correlation of Microwave Two-mode Squeezed State Generated by Nonlinearity of InP HEMT. (arXiv:2211.01620v1 [quant-ph])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01620</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;This study significantly concentrates on cryogenic InP HEMT high-frequency
circuit analysis using quantum theory to find how the transistor nonlinearity
can affect the quantum correlation of the modes generated in the circuit.
Firstly, the total Hamiltonian of the circuit is derived, and the dynamic
equation of the motion contributed is examined using the Heisenberg-Langevin
equation. Using the nonlinear Hamiltonian, some components are attached to the
intrinsic internal circuit of InP HEMT to fully address the circuit
characteristics. The components attached are arisen due to the nonlinearity
effects. As a result, the theoretical calculations show that the states
generated in the circuit are mixed, and no pure state is produced. Accordingly,
the modified circuit generates the two-mode squeezed thermal state, which means
one can focus on calculating the Gaussian quantum discord to evaluate quantum
correlation. It is also found that the nonlinearity factors (addressed as the
nonlinear components in the circuit) can intensely influence the squeezed
thermal state by which the quantum discord is changed. Finally, as the primary
point, it is concluded that although it is possible to enhance the quantum
correlation between modes by engineering the nonlinear components; however,
quantum discord greater than unity, entangled microwave photons, seems a
challenging task since InP HEMT operates at 4.2 K.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Salmanogli_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ahmad Salmanogli&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01650">
<title>Universality and its limits in non-Hermitian many-body quantum chaos using the Sachdev-Ye-Kitaev model. (arXiv:2211.01650v1 [hep-th])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01650</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Spectral rigidity in Hermitian quantum chaotic systems signals the presence
of dynamical universal features at time scales that can be much shorter than
the Heisenberg time. We study the analogue of this time scale in many-body
non-Hermitian quantum chaos by a detailed analysis of long-range spectral
correlators. For that purpose, we investigate the number variance and the
spectral form factor of a non-Hermitian $q$-body Sachdev-Ye-Kitaev (nHSYK)
model, which describes $N$ fermions in zero spatial dimensions. After an
analytical and numerical analysis of these spectral observables for
non-Hermitian random matrices, and a careful unfolding, we find good agreement
with the nHSYK model for $q &amp;gt; 2$ starting at a time scale that decreases
sharply with $q$. The source of deviation from universality, identified
analytically, is ensemble fluctuations not related to the quantum dynamics. For
fixed $q$ and large enough $N$, these fluctuations become dominant up until
after the Heisenberg time, so that the spectral form factor is no longer useful
for the study of quantum chaos. In all cases, our results point to a weakened
or vanishing spectral rigidity that effectively delays the observation of full
quantum ergodicity. We also show that the number variance displays
non-stationary spectral correlations for both the nHSYK model and random
matrices. This non-stationarity, also not related to the quantum dynamics,
points to intrinsic limitations of these observables to describe the quantum
chaotic motion. On the other hand, we introduce the local spectral form factor,
which is shown to be stationary and not affected by collective fluctuations,
and propose it as an effective diagnostic of non-Hermitian quantum chaos. For
$q = 2$, we find saturation to Poisson statistics at a time scale of $\log D$,
compared to a scale of $\sqrt D$ for $ q&amp;gt;2$, with $D $ the total number of
states.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Garcia_Garcia_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Antonio M. Garc&amp;#xed;a-Garc&amp;#xed;a&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Sa_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Lucas S&amp;#xe1;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Verbaarschot_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jacobus J. M. Verbaarschot&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01653">
<title>Purcell-induced suppression of superradiance for molecular overlayers on noble atom surfaces. (arXiv:2211.01653v1 [quant-ph])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01653</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We study the impact of an environment on the electromagnetic responses of a
molecule in the presence of a dielectric medium. By applying the dipole-dipole
coupling between the molecule&apos;s and the environment&apos;s degrees of freedom, we
can reduce the complex system into its components and predict excitation
lifetimes of single and few molecules attached to a dielectric surface by
knowing the entire quantum-mechanical properties of the molecules, such as
transition energies and dipole moments. The derived theory allows for the
description of superradiance between two molecules depending on the geometric
arrangement between both concerning their separation and orientation with
respect to each other. We analyse the possibility of superradiance between two
molecules bound to a dielectric sphere and determine a change of the relevant
length scale where the usually considered wavelength in free space is replaced
with the binding distance, drastically reducing the length scales at which
collective effects can take place.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Fiedler_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Johannes Fiedler&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Berland_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Kristian Berland&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Buhmann_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Stefan Yoshi Buhmann&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01657">
<title>Semiclassical spacetimes at super-Planckian scales from delocalized sources. (arXiv:2211.01657v1 [gr-qc])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01657</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We derive the gravitational field and the spacetime metric generated by
sources in quantum superposition of different locations. We start by working in
a Newtonian approximation, in which the effective gravitational potential is
computed as the expectation value of the gravitational potential operator in a
Gaussian distribution of width $R$ for the position of the source. The
effective gravitational potential is then covariantly uplifted to a fully
relativistic metric in general relativity, describing the spacetime generated
by averaging over the state of such sources. These results are then rederived
and extended by adopting an independent construction in terms of quantum
reference frames. We find three classes of quantum effective metrics which are
all asymptotically flat and reproduce the Schwarzschild metric at great
distances. The solutions differ, however, in the inner core. The quantum
uncertainty $\Delta r\sim R$ in the position of the source prevents the radius
of the transverse two-sphere to shrink to zero. Depending on the strength of
the quantum superposition effects, we have either a nonsingular black hole with
a ``quantum hair&apos;&apos; and an event horizon, a one-way wormhole with a critical
null throat or a traversable wormhole. We also provide a detailed study of the
geometric and thermodynamic properties of the spacetime structure for each of
these three families of models, as well as their phenomenology.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Akil_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ali Akil&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Cadoni_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Mariano Cadoni&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Modesto_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Leonardo Modesto&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Oi_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Mauro Oi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Sanna_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Andrea Pierfrancesco Sanna&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01665">
<title>From Auditable Quantum Authentication to Best-of-Both-Worlds Multiparty Quantum Computation with Public Verifiable Identifiable Abort. (arXiv:2211.01665v1 [quant-ph])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01665</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We construct the first secure multiparty quantum computation with public
verifiable identifiable abort (MPQC-PVIA) protocol, where PVIA security enables
outside observers with only classical computational power to agree on the
identity of a malicious party in case of an abort. Moreover, our MPQC is the
first quantum setting to provide Best-of-Both-Worlds (BoBW) security, which
attains full security with an honest majority and is secure with abort if the
majority is dishonest. At the heart of our construction is a generic
transformation called Auditable Quantum Authentication (AQA) that publicly
identifies the malicious sender with overwhelming probability. Our approach
comes with several advantages over the traditional way of building MPQC
protocols. First, instead of following the Clifford code paradigm, our protocol
can be based on a variety of authentication codes. Second, the online phase of
our MPQC requires only classical communications. Third, our construction can
achieve distributed computation via a carefully crafted protocol design, which
can be adjusted to an MPQC that conditionally guarantees output delivery.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Mi-Ying/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Mi-Ying&lt;/a&gt; (Miryam) &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Huang/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Huang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Tang_E/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Er-Cheng Tang&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01668">
<title>A Data-Driven Approach to Quantum Cross-Platform Verification. (arXiv:2211.01668v1 [quant-ph])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01668</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The task of testing whether two uncharacterized devices behave in the same
way, known as cross-platform verification, is crucial for benchmarking quantum
simulators and near-term quantum computers. Cross-platform verification becomes
increasingly challenging as the system&apos;s dimensionality increases, and has so
far remained intractable for continuous variable quantum systems. In this
Letter, we develop a data-driven approach, working with limited noisy data and
suitable for continuous variable quantum states. Our approach is based on a
convolutional neural network that assesses the similarity of quantum states
based on a lower-dimensional state representation built from measurement data.
The network can be trained offline with classically simulated data, and is
demonstrated here on non-Gaussian quantum states for which cross-platform
verification could not be achieved with previous techniques. It can also be
applied to cross-platform verification of quantum dynamics and to the problem
of experimentally testing whether two quantum states are equivalent up to
Gaussian unitary transformations.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Wu_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ya-Dong Wu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Zhu_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yan Zhu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Bai_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ge Bai&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Wang_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yuexuan Wang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Chiribella_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Giulio Chiribella&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01681">
<title>Matrix Multiplicative Weights Updates in Quantum Zero-Sum Games: Conservation Laws &amp; Recurrence. (arXiv:2211.01681v1 [cs.GT])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01681</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Recent advances in quantum computing and in particular, the introduction of
quantum GANs, have led to increased interest in quantum zero-sum game theory,
extending the scope of learning algorithms for classical games into the quantum
realm. In this paper, we focus on learning in quantum zero-sum games under
Matrix Multiplicative Weights Update (a generalization of the multiplicative
weights update method) and its continuous analogue, Quantum Replicator
Dynamics. When each player selects their state according to quantum replicator
dynamics, we show that the system exhibits conservation laws in a
quantum-information theoretic sense. Moreover, we show that the system exhibits
Poincare recurrence, meaning that almost all orbits return arbitrarily close to
their initial conditions infinitely often. Our analysis generalizes previous
results in the case of classical games.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Jain_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Rahul Jain&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Piliouras_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Georgios Piliouras&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Sim_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ryann Sim&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01684">
<title>Indefinite causal order for quantum metrology with quantum thermal noise. (arXiv:2211.01684v1 [quant-ph])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01684</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;A switched quantum channel with indefinite causal order is studied for the
fundamental metrological task of phase estimation on a qubit unitary operator
affected by quantum thermal noise. Specific capabilities are reported in the
switched channel with indefinite order, not accessible with conventional
estimation approaches with definite order. Phase estimation can be performed by
measuring the control qubit alone, although it does not actively interact with
the unitary process -- only the probe qubit doing so. Also, phase estimation
becomes possible with a fully depolarized input probe or with an input probe
aligned with the rotation axis of the unitary, while this is never possible
with conventional approaches. The present study extends to thermal noise,
investigations previously carried out with the more symmetric and isotropic
qubit depolarizing noise, and it contributes to the timely exploration of
properties of quantum channels with indefinite causal order relevant to quantum
signal and information processing.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Chapeau_Blondeau_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Francois Chapeau-Blondeau&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01687">
<title>Improving social welfare in non-cooperative games with different types of quantum resources. (arXiv:2211.01687v1 [quant-ph])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01687</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We investigate what quantum advantages can be obtained in multipartite
non-cooperative games by studying how different types of quantum resources can
improve social welfare, a measure of the quality of a Nash equilibrium. We
study how these advantages in quantum social welfare depend on the bias of the
game, and improve upon the separation that was previously obtained using
pseudo-telepathic strategies.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two different quantum settings are analysed: a first, in which players are
given direct access to an entangled quantum state, and a second, which we
introduce here, in which they are only given classical advice obtained from
quantum devices. For a given game $G$, these two settings give rise to
different equilibria characterised by the sets of equilibrium correlations
$Q_\textrm{corr}(G)$ and $Q(G)$, respectively. We show that $Q(G)\subseteq
Q_\textrm{corr}(G)$ and, by considering explicit example games and exploiting
SDP optimisation methods, provide indications of a strict separation between
the social welfare attainable in the two settings. This provides a new angle
towards understanding the limits and advantages of delegating quantum
measurements.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Abbott_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Alastair A. Abbott&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Mhalla_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Mehdi Mhalla&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Pocreau_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Pierre Pocreau&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01735">
<title>Electronic Coherent Control of an Insulator-to-Metal Mott Transition. (arXiv:2211.01735v1 [cond-mat.str-el])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01735</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Managing light-matter interaction on timescales faster than the loss of
electronic coherence is key for achieving the full quantum control of final
products in solid-solid transformations. In this work, we demonstrate coherent
electronic control of the photoinduced insulator-to-metal transition in the
prototypical Mott insulator V$_2$O$_3$. Selective excitation of a specific
interband transition with two phase-locked light pulses manipulates the orbital
occupation of the correlated bands in a way that depends on the coherent
evolution of the photoinduced superposition of states. Comparison between
experimental results and numerical solutions of the optical Bloch equations
provides an electronic coherence time on the order of 5 fs. Temperature
dependent experiments suggest that the electronic coherence time is enhanced in
the vicinity of the insulator-to-metal transition critical temperature, thus
highlighting the role of fluctuations in determining the electronic coherence.
These results open new routes to selectively switch functionalities of quantum
materials and coherently control solid-solid electronic transformations.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Franceschini_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Paolo Franceschini&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Policht_V/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Veronica R.Policht&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Milloch_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Alessandra Milloch&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Ronchi_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Andrea Ronchi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Mor_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Selene Mor&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Mellaerts_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Simon Mellaerts&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Hsu_W/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Wei-Fan Hsu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Pagliara_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Stefania Pagliara&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Ferrini_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Gabriele Ferrini&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Banfi_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Francesco Banfi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Fabrizio_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Michele Fabrizio&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Menghini_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Mariela Menghini&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Locquet_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jean-Pierre Locquet&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Conte_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Stefano Dal Conte&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Cerullo_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Giulio Cerullo&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Giannetti_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Claudio Giannetti&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01773">
<title>Universal optimization efficiency and bounds of Carnot-like heat engines and refrigerators under shortcuts to isothermality. (arXiv:2211.01773v1 [quant-ph])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01773</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Based on a quantum thermodynamic protocol for shortcut to isothermality that
smoothly modify the system-reservoir interaction can significantly speed up an
isothermal process while keeping the overall dissipation constant [Phys. Rev.
X. 10, 031015 (2020)], we extend the study of optimization performance of
Carnot-like heat engines and refrigerators in a straightforward and unified
way. We derive the universal optimization efficiency of heat engines and the
optimization coefficient of performance of refrigerators under two unified
optimization criterions, i.e., chi criterion and omega criterion. We also
derived the universal lower and upper bounds for heat engines and
refrigerators, and found that these bounds can be reached under extremely
asymmetric cases.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Zhang_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yanchao Zhang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Wang_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Shuang Wang&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01803">
<title>Control-enhanced quantum metrology under Markovian noise. (arXiv:2211.01803v1 [quant-ph])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01803</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Quantum metrology is supposed to significantly improve the precision of
parameter estimation by utilizing suitable quantum resources. However, the
predicted precision can be severely distorted by realistic noises. Here, we
propose a control-enhanced quantum metrology scheme to defend against these
noises for improving the metrology performance. Our scheme can automatically
alter the parameter encoding dynamics with adjustable controls, thus leading to
optimal resultant states that are less sensitive to the noises under
consideration. As a demonstration, we numerically apply it to the problem of
frequency estimation under several typical Markovian noise channels. Through
comparing our control-enhanced scheme with the standard scheme and the
ancilla-assisted scheme, we show that our scheme performs better and can
improve the estimation precision up to around one order of magnitude.
Furthermore, we conduct a proof-of-principle experiment in nuclear magnetic
resonance system to verify the effectiveness of the proposed scheme. The
research here is helpful for current quantum platforms to harness the power of
quantum metrology in realistic noise environments.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Zhai_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yue Zhai&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Yang_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xiaodong Yang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Tang_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Kai Tang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Long_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xinyue Long&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Nie_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xinfang Nie&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Xin_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Tao Xin&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Lu_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Dawei Lu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Li_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jun Li&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01815">
<title>High-fidelity quantum control via Autler-Townes splitting. (arXiv:2211.01815v1 [quant-ph])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01815</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We propose quantum control protocols for the high-fidelity preparation of
target states in systems with Autler-Townes splitting. We investigate an
approximated three-level system obtained from a four-level one by adiabatically
eliminating a state that does not participate in the evolution. In our work we
use linear, arctan, and Roland-Cerf functions for transferring population
between two eigenstates of the system obtaining a high fidelity for long
evolution times. Additionally, in order to overcome the restriction given by
the lifetimes of the experimental setup, we propose an accelerated adiabatic
evolution with a shortcut to adiabaticity protocol, which allows us to reach
fidelities close to one but much faster.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Delvecchio_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Michele Delvecchio&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Kirova_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Teodora Kirova&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Arimondo_E/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ennio Arimondo&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Ciampini_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Donatella Ciampini&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Wimberger_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Sandro Wimberger&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01819">
<title>Giant atom induced zero modes and localization in the nonreciprocal Su-Schrieffer-Heeger chai. (arXiv:2211.01819v1 [quant-ph])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01819</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;A notable feature of non-Hermitian systems with skin effects is the
sensitivity of their spectra and eigenstates to the boundary conditions. In the
literature, three types of boundary conditions-periodic boundary condition,open
boundary condition and a defect in the system as a boundary, are explored. In
this work we introduce the other type of boundary condition provided by a giant
atom. The giant atom couples to a nonreciprocal SuSchrieffer-Heeger chain at
two points and plays the role of defects. We study the spectrum and
localization of eigenstates of the system and find that the giant atom can
induce asymmetric zero modes. A remarkable feature is that bulk states might
localize at the left or the right chain-atom coupling sites in weak
localization regimes. This bipolar localization leads to Bloch-like states,
even though translational invariance is broken. Moreover, we find that the
localization is obviously weaker than the case with two small atoms or open
boundary conditions even in strong coupling regimes. These intriguing results
indicate that nonlocal coupling of giant atom to a nonreciprocal SSH chain
weakens localization of the eigenstates. We also show that the Lyapunov
exponent in the long-time dynamics in real space can act as a witness of the
localized bulk states.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Wang_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Junjie Wang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Li_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Fude Li&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Yi_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;X. X. Yi&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01838">
<title>On the Operator Origins of Classical and Quantum Wave Functions. (arXiv:2211.01838v1 [math-ph])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01838</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We investigate operator algebraic origins of the classical Koopman-von
Neumann wave function $\psi_{KvN}$ as well as the quantum mechanical one
$\psi_{QM}$. We introduce a formalism of Operator Mechanics (OM) based on a
noncommutative Poisson, symplectic and noncommutative differential structures.
OM serves as a pre-quantum algebra from which algebraic structures relevant to
real-world classical and quantum mechanics follow. In particular, $\psi_{KvN}$
and $\psi_{QM}$ are both consequences of this pre-quantum formalism. No a
priori Hilbert space is needed. OM admits an algebraic notion of operator
expectation values without invoking states. A phase space bundle ${\cal E}$
follows from this. $\psi_{KvN}$ and $\psi_{QM}$ are shown to be sections in
${\cal E}$. The difference between $\psi_{KvN}$ and $\psi_{QM}$ originates from
a quantization map interpreted as &quot;twisting&quot; of sections over ${\cal E}$. We
also show that the Schr\&quot;{o}dinger equation is obtained from the Koopman-von
Neumann equation. What this suggests is that neither the Schr\&quot;{o}dinger
equation nor the quantum wave function are fundamental structures. Rather, they
both originate from a pre-quantum operator algebra.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math-ph/1/au:+Arsiwalla_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xerxes D. Arsiwalla&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math-ph/1/au:+Chester_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;David Chester&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math-ph/1/au:+Kauffman_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Louis H. Kauffman&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01857">
<title>Algebra of the spinor invariants and the relativistic hydrogen atom. (arXiv:2211.01857v1 [quant-ph])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01857</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;It is shown that the Dirac equation with the Coulomb potential can be solved
using the algebra of the three spinor invariants of the Dirac equation without
the involvement of the methods of supersymmetric quantum mechanics. The Dirac
Hamiltonian is invariant with respect to the rotation transformation, which
indicates the dynamical (hidden) symmetry $ SU(2) $ of the Dirac equation. The
total symmetry of the Dirac equation is the symmetry $ SO(3) \otimes SU(2) $.
The generator of the $ SO(3) $ symmetry group is given by the total momentum
operator, and the generator of $ SU(2) $ group is given by the rotation of the
vector-states in the spinor space, determined by the Dirac, Johnson-Lippmann,
and the new spinor invariants. It is shown that using algebraic approach to the
Dirac problem allows one to calculate the eigenstates and eigenenergies of the
relativistic hydrogen atom and reveals the fundamental role of the principal
quantum number as an independent number, even though it is represented as the
combination of other quantum numbers.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Eremko_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;A.A. Eremko&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Brizhik_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;L.S. Brizhik&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Loktev_V/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;V.M. Loktev&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01870">
<title>Many-body quantum boomerang effect. (arXiv:2211.01870v1 [cond-mat.dis-nn])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01870</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We study numerically the impact of many-body interactions on the quantum
boomerang effect. We consider various cases: weakly interacting bosons, the
Tonks-Girardeau gas, and strongly interacting bosons (which may be mapped onto
weakly interacting fermions). Numerical simulations are performed using the
time-evolving block decimation algorithm, a quasi-exact method based on matrix
product states. In the case of weakly interacting bosons, we find a partial
destruction of the quantum boomerang effect, in agreement with the earlier
mean-field study [Phys. Rev. A \textbf{102}, 013303 (2020)]. For the
Tonks-Girardeau gas, we show the presence of the full quantum boomerang effect.
For strongly interacting bosons, we observe a partial boomerang effect. We show
that the destruction of the quantum boomerang effect is universal and does not
depend on the details of the interaction between particles.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Janarek_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jakub Janarek&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Zakrzewski_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jakub Zakrzewski&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Delande_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Dominique Delande&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01884">
<title>Orbital liquid in the $e_g$ orbital Hubbard model in $d=\infty$ dimensions. (arXiv:2211.01884v1 [cond-mat.str-el])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01884</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We demonstrate that the three-dimensional $e_g$ orbital Hubbard model can be
generalized to arbitrary dimension $d$, and that the form of the result is
determined uniquely by the requirements that
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(i) the two-fold degeneracy of the $e_g$ orbital be retained, and (ii) the
cubic lattice be turned into a hypercubic lattice. While the local Coulomb
interaction $U$ is invariant for each basis of orthogonal orbitals, the form of
the kinetic energy depends on the orbital basis and takes the most symmetric
form for the so-called complex-orbital basis. Characteristically, with respect
to this basis, the model has two hopping channels, one that is orbital-flavor
conserving, and a second one that is orbital-flavor non-conserving. We show
that the noninteracting electronic structure consists of two nondegenerate
bands of plane-wave real-orbital single-particle states for which the orbital
depends on the wave vector. Due to the latter feature each band is unpolarized
at any filling, and has a non-Gaussian density of states at $d=\infty$. The
\textit{orbital liquid} state is obtained by filling these two bands up to the
same Fermi energy. We investigate the $e_g$ orbital Hubbard model in the limit
$d\to\infty$, treating the on-site Coulomb interaction $U$ within the
Gutzwiller approximation, thus determining the correlation energy of the
orbital liquid and the (disordered) para-orbital states. (...) We show that the
orbital liquid is the ground state everywhere in the $(n,U)$ phase diagram
except close to half-filling at sufficiently large $U$, where ferro-orbital
order with real orbitals occupied is favored. The latter feature is shown to be
specific for $d=\infty$, being of mathematical nature due to the exponential
tails in the density of states.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Feiner_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Louis Felix Feiner&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Oles_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Andrzej M. Ole&amp;#x15b;&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01895">
<title>Quantum kinetic theory of nonlinear thermal current. (arXiv:2211.01895v1 [cond-mat.mes-hall])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01895</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We investigate the second-order nonlinear electronic thermal transport
induced by temperature gradient. We develop the quantum kinetic theory
framework to describe thermal transport in presence of a temperature gradient.
Using this, we predict an intrinsic scattering time independent nonlinear
thermal current in addition to the known extrinsic nonlinear Drude and Berry
curvature dipole contributions. We show that the intrinsic thermal current is
determined by the band geometric quantities and is non-zero only in systems
where both the space inversion and time-reversal symmetries are broken. We
employ the developed theory to study the thermal response in tilted massive
Dirac systems. We show that besides the different scattering time dependence,
the various current contributions have distinct temperature dependence in the
low temperature limit. Our systematic and comprehensive theory for nonlinear
thermal transport paves the way for future theoretical and experimental studies
on intrinsic thermal responses.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Varshney_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Harsh Varshney&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Das_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Kamal Das&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Bhalla_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Pankaj Bhalla&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Agarwal_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Amit Agarwal&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01899">
<title>Formally Self-Adjoint Hamiltonian for the Hilbert-P\&apos;olya Conjecture. (arXiv:2211.01899v1 [math-ph])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01899</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We construct a formally self-adjoint Hamiltonian whose eigenvalues correspond
to the nontrivial zeros of the Riemann zeta function. We consider a
two-dimensional Hamiltonian which couples the Berry-Keating Hamiltonian to the
number operator on the half-line via a unitary transformation. We demonstrate
that the unitary operator, which is composed of squeeze (dilation) operators
and an exponential of the number operator, confines the eigenfunction of the
Hamiltonian to one dimension as the squeezing parameter tends towards infinity.
The Riemann zeta function appears at the boundary of the resulting confined
wave function and vanishes as a result of the imposed boundary condition. If
the formal argument presented here can be made more rigorous, particularly if
it can be shown rigorously that the Hamiltonian remains self-adjoint under the
imposed boundary condition, then our approach has the potential to imply that
the Riemann hypothesis is true.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math-ph/1/au:+Yakaboylu_E/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Enderalp Yakaboylu&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01923">
<title>Stochastic Representation of the Quantum Quartic Oscillator. (arXiv:2211.01923v1 [quant-ph])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01923</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Recent experimental advances have inspired the development of theoretical
tools to describe the non-equilibrium dynamics of quantum systems. Among them
an exact representation of quantum spin systems in terms of classical
stochastic processes has been proposed. Here we provide first steps towards the
extension of this stochastic approach to bosonic systems by considering the
one-dimensional quantum quartic oscillator. We show how to exactly parameterize
the time evolution of this prototypical model via the dynamics of a set of
classical variables. We interpret these variables as stochastic processes,
which allows us to propose a novel way to numerically simulate the time
evolution of the system. We benchmark our findings by considering analytically
solvable limits and providing alternative derivations of known results.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Tucci_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Gennaro Tucci&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Nicola_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Stefano De Nicola&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Wald_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Sascha Wald&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Gambassi_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Andrea Gambassi&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01925">
<title>Exploiting Qubit Reuse through Mid-circuit Measurement and Reset. (arXiv:2211.01925v1 [quant-ph])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01925</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Quantum measurement is important to quantum computing as it extracts the
outcome of the circuit at the end of the computation. Previously, all
measurements have to be done at the end of the circuit. Otherwise, it will
incur significant errors. But it is not the case now. Recently IBM started
supporting dynamic circuits through hardware (instead of software by
simulator). With mid-circuit hardware measurement, we can improve circuit
efficacy and fidelity from three aspects: (a) reduced qubit usage, (b) reduced
swap insertion, and (c) improved fidelity. We demonstrate this using real-world
applications Bernstein Verizani on real hardware and show that circuit resource
usage can be improved by 60\%, and circuit fidelity can be improved by 15\%. We
design a compiler-assisted tool that can find and exploit the tradeoff between
qubit reuse, fidelity, gate count, and circuit duration. We also developed a
method for identifying whether qubit reuse will be beneficial for a given
application. We evaluated our method on a representative set of essential
applications. We can reduce resource usage by up to 80\% and circuit fidelity
by up to 20\%.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Hua_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Fei Hua&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Jin_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yuwei Jin&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Chen_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yanhao Chen&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Lapeyre_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;John Lapeyre&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Javadi_Abhari_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ali Javadi-Abhari&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Zhang_E/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Eddy Z. Zhang&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01934">
<title>Discovery of Optimal Thermometers with Spin Networks aided by Machine-Learning. (arXiv:2211.01934v1 [quant-ph])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01934</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The heat capacity $\mathcal{C}$ of a given probe is a fundamental quantity
that determines, among other properties, the maximum precision in temperature
estimation. In turn, $\mathcal{C}$ is limited by a quadratic scaling with the
number of constituents of the probe, which provides a fundamental limit in
quantum thermometry. Achieving this fundamental bound with realistic probes,
i.e. experimentally amenable, remains an open problem. In this work, we exploit
machine-learning techniques to discover optimal spin-network thermal probes,
restricting ourselves to two-body interactions. This leads to simple
architectures, which we show analytically to approximate the theoretical
maximal value of $\mathcal{C}$ and maintain the optimal scaling for short- and
long-range interactions. Our models can be encoded in currently available
quantum annealers, and find application in other tasks requiring Hamiltonian
engineering, ranging from quantum heat engines to adiabatic Grover&apos;s search.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Abiuso_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Paolo Abiuso&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Erdman_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Paolo Andrea Erdman&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Ronen_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Michael Ronen&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Noe_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Frank No&amp;#xe9;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Haack_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;G&amp;#xe9;raldine Haack&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Perarnau_Llobet_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Mart&amp;#xed; Perarnau-Llobet&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01942">
<title>Quantum Random Walker in Presence of a Moving Detector. (arXiv:2211.01942v1 [quant-ph])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01942</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;In this work, we study the effect of a moving detector on a discrete time one
dimensional Quantum Random Walk where the movement is realized in the form of
hopping/shifts. The occupation probability $f(x,t;n,s)$ is estimated as the
number of detection $n$ and number of shift $s$ vary. It is seen that the
occupation probability at the initial position $x_D$ of the detector is
enhanced when $n$ is small which a quantum mechanical effect but decreases when
$n$ is large. The ratio of occupation probabilities of our walk to that of an
Infinite walk shows a scaling behavior of $\frac{1}{n^2}$. It shows a definite
scaling behavior with number of shifts $s$ also. The limiting behaviours of the
walk are observed when $x_D$ is large, $n$ is large and $s$ is large and the
walker for these cases approach the Infinite Walk, The Semi Infinite Walk and
the Quenched Quantum Walk respectively.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Molla_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Md Aquib Molla&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Goswami_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Sanchari Goswami&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01947">
<title>Invertible bimodule categories and generalized Schur orthogonality. (arXiv:2211.01947v1 [math.QA])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01947</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The Schur orthogonality relations are a cornerstone in the representation
theory of groups. We utilize a generalization to weak Hopf algebras to provide
a new, readily verifiable condition on the skeletal data for deciding whether a
given bimodule category is invertible and therefore defines a Morita
equivalence. As a first application, we provide an algorithm for the
construction of the full skeletal data of the invertible bimodule category
associated to a given module category, which is obtained in a unitary gauge
when the underlying categories are unitary. As a second application, we show
that our condition for invertibility is equivalent to the notion of
MPO-injectivity, thereby closing an open question concerning tensor network
representations of string-net models exhibiting topological order. We discuss
applications to generalized symmetries, including a generalized Wigner-Eckart
theorem.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Bridgeman_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jacob C. Bridgeman&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Lootens_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Laurens Lootens&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Verstraete_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Frank Verstraete&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01989">
<title>Bound states of weakly deformed soft waveguides. (arXiv:2211.01989v1 [math.SP])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01989</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;In this paper we consider the two-dimensional Schr\&quot;odinger operator with an
attractive potential which is a multiple of the characteristic function of an
unbounded strip-shaped region, whose thickness is varying and is determined by
the function $\mathbb{R}\ni x \mapsto d+\varepsilon f(x)$, where $d &amp;gt; 0$ is a
constant, $\varepsilon &amp;gt; 0$ is a small parameter, and $f$ is a compactly
supported continuous function. We prove that if $\int_{\mathbb{R}} f
\,\mathsf{d} x &amp;gt; 0$, then the respective Schr\&quot;odinger operator has a unique
simple eigenvalue below the threshold of the essential spectrum for all
sufficiently small $\varepsilon &amp;gt;0$ and we obtain the asymptotic expansion of
this eigenvalue in the regime $\varepsilon\rightarrow 0$. An asymptotic
expansion of the respective eigenfunction as $\varepsilon\rightarrow 0$ is also
obtained. In the case that $\int_{\mathbb{R}} f \,\mathsf{d} x &amp;lt; 0$ we prove
that the discrete spectrum is empty for all sufficiently small $\varepsilon &amp;gt;
0$. In the critical case $\int_{\mathbb{R}} f \,\mathsf{d} x = 0$, we derive a
sufficient condition for the existence of a unique bound state for all
sufficiently small $\varepsilon &amp;gt; 0$.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Exner_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Pavel Exner&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Kondej_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Sylwia Kondej&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Lotoreichik_V/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Vladimir Lotoreichik&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.02014">
<title>On the classicality of quantum dephasing processes. (arXiv:2211.02014v1 [quant-ph])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.02014</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We analyze the multitime statistics associated with pure dephasing systems
repeatedly probed with sharp measurements, and search for measurement protocols
whose statistics satisfies the Kolmogorov consistency conditions possibly up to
a finite order. We find a rich phenomenology of quantum dephasing processes
which can be interpreted in classical terms. In particular, if the underlying
dephasing process is Markovian, we find sufficient conditions under which
classicality at every order can be found: this can be reached by choosing the
dephasing and measurement basis to be fully compatible or fully incompatible,
that is, mutually unbiased bases (MUBs). For non-Markovian processes,
classicality can only be proven in the fully compatible case, thus revealing a
key difference between Markovian and non-Markovian pure dephasing processes.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Lonigro_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Davide Lonigro&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Chruscinski_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Dariusz Chru&amp;#x15b;ci&amp;#x144;ski&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.02017">
<title>A cryogenic SRAM based arbitrary waveform generator in 14 nm for spin qubit control. (arXiv:2211.02017v1 [quant-ph])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.02017</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Realization of qubit gate sequences require coherent microwave control pulses
with programmable amplitude, duration, spacing and phase. We propose an SRAM
based arbitrary waveform generator for cryogenic control of spin qubits. We
demonstrate in this work, the cryogenic operation of a fully programmable radio
frequency arbitrary waveform generator in 14 nm FinFET technology. The waveform
sequence from a control processor can be stored in an SRAM memory array, which
can be programmed in real time. The waveform pattern is converted to microwave
pulses by a source-series-terminated digital to analog converter. The chip is
operational at 4 K, capable of generating an arbitrary envelope shape at the
desired carrier frequency. Total power consumption of the AWG is 40-140mW at 4
K, depending upon the baud rate. A wide signal band of 1-17 GHz is measured at
4 K, while multiple qubit control can be achieved using frequency division
multiplexing at an average spurious free dynamic range of 40 dB. This work
paves the way to optimal qubit control and closed loop feedback control, which
is necessary to achieve low latency error mitigation
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Prathapan_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Mridula Prathapan&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Mueller_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Peter Mueller&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Menolfi_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Christian Menolfi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Braendli_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Matthias Braendli&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Kossel_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Marcel Kossel&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Francese_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Pier Andrea Francese&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Heim_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;David Heim&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Oropallo_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Maria Vittoria Oropallo&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Ruffino_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Andrea Ruffino&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Zota_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Cezar Zota&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Morf_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Thomas Morf&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.02037">
<title>Average Mixing in Quantum Walks of Reversible Markov Chains. (arXiv:2211.02037v1 [quant-ph])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.02037</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The Szegedy quantum walk is a discrete time quantum walk model which defines
a quantum analogue of any Markov chain. The long-term behavior of the quantum
walk can be encoded in a matrix called the average mixing matrix, whose columns
give the limiting probability distribution of the walk given an initial state.
We define a version of the average mixing matrix of the Szegedy quantum walk
which allows us to more readily compare the limiting behavior to that of the
chain it quantizes. We prove a formula for our mixing matrix in terms of the
spectral decomposition of the Markov chain and show a relationship with the
mixing matrix of a continuous quantum walk on the chain. In particular, we
prove that average uniform mixing in the continuous walk implies average
uniform mixing in the Szegedy walk. We conclude by giving examples of Markov
chains of arbitrarily large size which admit average uniform mixing in both the
continuous and Szegedy quantum walk.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Sorci_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Julien Sorci&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2012.08889">
<title>Expressive power of complex-valued restricted Boltzmann machines for solving non-stoquastic Hamiltonians. (arXiv:2012.08889v3 [quant-ph] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2012.08889</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Variational Monte Carlo with neural network quantum states has proven to be a
promising avenue for evaluating the ground state energy of spin Hamiltonians.
However, despite continuous efforts the performance of the method on frustrated
Hamiltonians remains significantly worse than those on stoquastic Hamiltonians
that are sign-free. We present a detailed and systematic study of restricted
Boltzmann machine (RBM) based variational Monte Carlo for quantum spin chains,
resolving how relevant stoquasticity is in this setting. We show that in most
cases, when the Hamiltonian is phase connected with a stoquastic point, the
complex RBM state can faithfully represent the ground state, and local
quantities can be evaluated efficiently by sampling. On the other hand, we
identify several new phases that are challenging for the RBM Ansatz, including
non-topological robust non-stoquastic phases as well as stoquastic phases where
sampling is nevertheless inefficient. Furthermore, we find that an accurate
neural network representation of ground states in non-stoquastic phases is
hindered not only by the sign structure but also by their amplitudes.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Park_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Chae-Yeun Park&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Kastoryano_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Michael J. Kastoryano&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2105.06244">
<title>A Graphical Calculus for Lagrangian Relations. (arXiv:2105.06244v2 [cs.LO] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2105.06244</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Symplectic vector spaces are the phase spaces of linear mechanical systems.
The symplectic form describes, for example, the relation between position and
momentum as well as current and voltage. The category of linear Lagrangian
relations between symplectic vector spaces is a symmetric monoidal subcategory
of relations which gives a semantics for the evolution -- and more generally
linear constraints on the evolution -- of various physical systems. We give a
new presentation of the category of Lagrangian relations over an arbitrary
field as a `doubled&apos; category of linear relations. More precisely, we show that
it arises as a variation of Selinger&apos;s CPM construction applied to linear
relations, where the covariant orthogonal complement functor plays the role of
conjugation. Furthermore, for linear relations over prime fields, this
corresponds exactly to the CPM construction for a suitable choice of dagger. We
can furthermore extend this construction by a single affine shift operator to
obtain a category of affine Lagrangian relations. Using this new presentation,
we prove the equivalence of the prop of affine Lagrangian relations with the
prop of qudit stabilizer theory in odd prime dimensions. We hence obtain a
unified graphical language for several disparate process theories, including
electrical circuits, Spekkens&apos; toy theory, and odd-prime-dimensional stabilizer
quantum circuits.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Comfort_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Cole Comfort&lt;/a&gt; (University of Oxford), &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Kissinger_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Aleks Kissinger&lt;/a&gt; (University of Oxford)</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2107.09984">
<title>Chiral Dirac-like fermion in spin-orbit-free antiferromagnetic semimetals. (arXiv:2107.09984v3 [cond-mat.mtrl-sci] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2107.09984</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Dirac semimetal is a phase of matter, whose elementary excitation is
described by the relativistic Dirac equation. In the limit of zero mass, its
parity-time symmetry enforces the Dirac fermion in the momentum space, which is
composed of two Weyl fermions with opposite chirality, to be non-chiral.
Inspired by the flavor symmetry in particle physics, we theoretically propose a
massless Dirac-like equation yet linking two Weyl fields with the identical
chirality by assuming SU(2) isospin symmetry, independent of the space-time
rotation exchanging the two fields. Dramatically, such symmetry is hidden in
certain solid-state spin-1/2 systems with negligible spin-orbit coupling, where
the spin degree of freedom is decoupled with the lattice. Therefore, the
existence of the corresponding quasiparticle, dubbed as flavor Weyl fermion,
cannot be explained by the conventional (magnetic) space group framework. The
four-fold degenerate flavor Weyl fermion manifests linear dispersion and a
Chern number of 2, leading to a robust network of topologically protected Fermi
arcs throughout the Brillouin zone. For material realization, we show that the
transition-metal chalcogenide CoNb3S6 with experimentally confirmed collinear
antiferromagnetic order is ideal for flavor Weyl semimetal under the
approximation of vanishing spin-orbit coupling. Our work reveals a counterpart
of the flavor symmetry in magnetic electronic systems, leading to further
possibilities of emergent phenomena in quantum materials.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Liu_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Pengfei Liu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Zhang_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ao Zhang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Han_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jingzhi Han&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Liu_Q/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Qihang Liu&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2109.05862">
<title>Random-time quantum measurements. (arXiv:2109.05862v3 [quant-ph] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2109.05862</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The analysis of a continuous measurement record $z(t)$ poses a fundamental
challenge in quantum measurement theory. Different approaches have been used in
the past as records can, e.g., exhibit predominantly Gaussian noise, telegraph
noise, or clicks at random times. The last case may appear as photon clicks in
an optical spin noise measurement at very low probe laser power. Here we show
that such random-time quantum measurements can similarly to the first two cases
be analyzed in terms of higher-order temporal correlations of the detector
output $z(t)$ and be related to the Liouvillian of the measured quantum system.
Our analysis in terms of up to fourth-order spectra (quantum polyspectra) shows
that this new type of spectra reveals the same valuable information as
previously studied higher-order spectra in case of usual continuous quantum
measurements. Surprisingly, broad-band system dynamics is revealed even for
deliberately low average measurement rates. Many applications are envisioned in
high-resolution spectroscopy, single-photon microscopy, circuit quantum
electrodynamics, quantum sensing, and quantum measurements in general.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Sifft_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Markus Sifft&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Hagele_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Daniel H&amp;#xe4;gele&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2110.08304">
<title>Nonlinear Landauer formula: Nonlinear response theory of disordered and topological materials. (arXiv:2110.08304v2 [cond-mat.mes-hall] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2110.08304</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The Landauer formula provides a general scattering formulation of electrical
conduction. Despite its utility, it has been mainly applied to the
linear-response regime, and a scattering theory of nonlinear response has yet
to be fully developed. Here, we extend the Landauer formula to the
nonlinear-response regime. We show that while the linear conductance is
directly related to the transmission probability, the nonlinear conductance is
given by its derivatives with respect to energy. This sensitivity to the energy
derivatives is shown to produce unique nonlinear transport phenomena of
mesoscopic systems including disordered and topological materials. By way of
illustration, we investigate nonlinear conductance of disordered chains and
identify their universal behavior according to symmetry. In particular, we find
large singular nonlinear conductance for zero modes, including Majorana zero
modes in topological superconductors. We also show the critical behavior of
nonlinear response around the mobility edges due to the Anderson transitions.
Moreover, we study nonlinear response of graphene as a prime example of
topological materials featuring quantum anomaly. Furthermore, considering the
geometry of electronic wave functions, we develop a scattering theory of the
nonlinear Hall effect. We establish a new connection between the nonlinear Hall
response and the nonequilibrium quantum fluctuations. We also discuss the
influence of disorder and Anderson localization on the nonlinear Hall effect.
Our work opens a new avenue in quantum physics beyond the linear-response
regime.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Kawabata_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Kohei Kawabata&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Ueda_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Masahito Ueda&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2112.09280">
<title>Scaling dynamics of the ultra-cold Bose gas. (arXiv:2112.09280v2 [cond-mat.quant-gas] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2112.09280</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The large-scale expansion dynamics of quantum gases is a central tool for
ultra-cold gas experiments and poses a significant challenge for theory.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this work we provide an exact reformulation of the Gross-Pitaevskii
equation for the ultra-cold Bose gas in a coordinate frame that adaptively
scales with the system size during evolution, enabling simulations of long
evolution times during expansion or similar large-scale manipulation. Our
approach makes no hydrodynamic approximations, is not restricted to a scaling
ansatz, harmonic potentials, or energy eigenstates, and can be generalized
readily to non-contact interactions via the appropriate stress tensor of the
quantum fluid. As applications, we simulate the expansion of the ideal gas, a
cigar-shaped condensate in the Thomas-Fermi regime, and a linear superposition
of counter propagating Gaussian wavepackets. We recover known scaling for the
ideal gas and Thomas-Fermi regimes, and identify a linear regime of
aspect-ratio preserving free expansion; analysis of the scaling dynamics
equations shows that an exact, aspect-ratio invariant, free expansion does not
exist for nonlinear evolution. Our treatment enables exploration of nonlinear
effects in matter-wave dynamics over large scale-changing evolution.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Bradley_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ashton S. Bradley&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Clarke_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jordan Clarke&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Neely_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Tyler W. Neely&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Anderson_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Brian P Anderson&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2202.12615">
<title>Fall of a Particle to the Center of a Singular Potential: Classical vs. Quantum Exact Solutions. (arXiv:2202.12615v3 [quant-ph] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2202.12615</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Exact solutions describing a fall of a particle to the center of a singular
potential (collapse) in classical and quantum cases are obtained, inspected,
and compared. The quantum and classical solutions exhibit striking
similarities. In particular, at zero energy of the particle, both are
self-similar, and their characteristic spatial scales obey the same temporal
dependence. In addition to collapsing, exact expanding solutions, corresponding
to the escape of the particle from the singularity, exist for both problems.
The collapse and escape are independent and not linked to each other through
the singularity. In the quantum collapse, the wave functions of the exact
solutions have time-depended norms. This case requires reconsidering and
generalizing the continuity equations and rules for mean value calculations. It
has also been done. The analysis sheds new light on the fundamentals of quantum
mechanics.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Tribelsky_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Michael I. Tribelsky&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2203.06586">
<title>Phonon downconversion to suppress correlated errors in superconducting qubits. (arXiv:2203.06586v2 [quant-ph] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2203.06586</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Quantum error correction can preserve quantum information in the presence of
local errors, but correlated errors are fatal. For superconducting qubits,
high-energy particle impacts from background radioactivity produce energetic
phonons that travel throughout the substrate and create excitations above the
superconducting ground state, known as quasiparticles, which can poison all
qubits on the chip. We use normal metal reservoirs on the chip back side to
downconvert phonons to low energies where they can no longer poison qubits. We
introduce a pump-probe scheme involving controlled injection of pair-breaking
phonons into the qubit chips. We examine quasiparticle poisoning on chips with
and without back-side metallization and demonstrate a reduction in the flux of
pair-breaking phonons by over a factor of 20. We use a Ramsey interferometer
scheme to simultaneously monitor quasiparticle parity on three qubits for each
chip and observe a two-order of magnitude reduction in correlated poisoning due
to background radiation.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Iaia_V/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;V. Iaia&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Ku_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;J. Ku&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Ballard_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;A. Ballard&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Larson_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;C. P. Larson&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Yelton_E/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;E. Yelton&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Liu_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;C. H. Liu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Patel_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;S. Patel&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+McDermott_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;R. McDermott&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Plourde_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;B. L. T. Plourde&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2203.16012">
<title>Entanglement area law for 1D gauge theories and bosonic systems. (arXiv:2203.16012v2 [quant-ph] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2203.16012</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We prove an entanglement area law for a class of 1D quantum systems involving
infinite-dimensional local Hilbert spaces. This class of quantum systems
include bosonic models such as the Hubbard-Holstein model, and both U(1) and
SU(2) lattice gauge theories in one spatial dimension. Our proof relies on new
results concerning the robustness of the ground state and spectral gap to the
truncation of Hilbert space, applied within the approximate ground state
projector (AGSP) framework from previous work. In establishing this area law,
we develop a system-size independent bound on the expectation value of local
observables for Hamiltonians without translation symmetry, which may be of
separate interest. Our result provides theoretical justification for using
tensor network methods to study the ground state properties of quantum systems
with infinite local degrees of freedom.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Abrahamsen_N/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Nilin Abrahamsen&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Tong_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yu Tong&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Bao_N/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ning Bao&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Su_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yuan Su&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Wiebe_N/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Nathan Wiebe&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2204.06245">
<title>Entanglement of particles versus entanglement of fields: independent quantum resources. (arXiv:2204.06245v2 [quant-ph] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2204.06245</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Nature allows one to explore a manifold of remarkable quantum effects. Most
prominently, quantum entanglement can be observed in many-particle systems,
between multiple quantized fields, and hybrid combinations thereof. This
diversity, however, also leads to contradicting conclusions about what truly
constitutes entanglement in any given physical scenario. By explicitly allowing
various perspectives, we rigorously consider different notions of entanglement
in the context of first and second quantization. By providing instructive
examples, we show that particle entanglement and field entanglement are
actually distinct phenomena that can occur and be observed independently of
each other. This finding not only affects our fundamental understanding but has
direct implications on quantum technology which can harness those independent
forms of entanglement in practical scenarios.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Sperling_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jan Sperling&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Agudelo_E/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Elizabeth Agudelo&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2204.13684">
<title>Force-Gradient Sensing and Entanglement via Feedback Cooling of Interacting Nanoparticles. (arXiv:2204.13684v2 [quant-ph] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2204.13684</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We show theoretically that feedback-cooling of two levitated, interacting
nanoparticles enables differential sensing of forces and the observation of
stationary entanglement. The feedback drives the two particles into a
stationary, non-thermal state which is susceptible to inhomogeneous force
fields and which exhibits entanglement for sufficiently strong inter-particle
couplings. We predict that force-gradient sensing at the zepto-Newton per
micron range is feasible and that entanglement due to the Coulomb interaction
between charged particles can be realistically observed in state-of-the-art
setups.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Rudolph_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Henning Rudolph&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Delic_U/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Uro&amp;#x161; Deli&amp;#x107;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Aspelmeyer_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Markus Aspelmeyer&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Hornberger_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Klaus Hornberger&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Stickler_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Benjamin A. Stickler&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2204.13945">
<title>Symmetry-protected exceptional and nodal points in non-Hermitian systems. (arXiv:2204.13945v2 [quant-ph] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2204.13945</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;One of the unique features of non-Hermitian~(NH) systems is the appearance of
non-Hermitian degeneracies known as exceptional points~(EPs). The extensively
studied defective EPs occur when the Hamiltonian becomes non-diagonalizable.
Aside from this degeneracy, we show that NH systems may host two further types
of degeneracies, namely, non-defective EPs and ordinary (Hermitian) nodal
points. The non-defective EPs manifest themselves by i) the diagonalizability
of the NH Hamiltonian at these points, ii) the non-diagonalizability of the
Hamiltonian along certain intersections of these points and iii) instabilities
in the Jordan decomposition when approaching the points from certain
directions. We demonstrate that certain discrete symmetries, namely
parity-time, parity-particle-hole, and pseudo-Hermitian symmetry, guarantee the
occurrence of both defective and non-defective EPs. We extend this list of
symmetries by including the NH time-reversal symmetry in two-band systems.
Two-band and four-band models exemplify our findings. Through an example, we
further reveal that ordinary nodal points may coexist with defective EPs in NH
models when the above symmetries are relaxed.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Sayyad_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Sharareh Sayyad&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Stalhammar_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Marcus Stalhammar&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Rodland_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Lukas Rodland&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Kunst_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Flore K. Kunst&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2205.00198">
<title>Temporal witnesses of non-classicality and conservation laws. (arXiv:2205.00198v2 [quant-ph] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2205.00198</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;A general entanglement-based witness of non-classicality has recently been
proposed, which can be applied to testing quantum effects in gravity. This
witness is based on generating entanglement between two quantum probes via a
mediator. In this paper we provide a &quot;temporal&quot; variant of this witness, using
a single quantum probe to assess the non-classicality of the mediator. Within
the formalism of quantum theory, we show that if a system $M$ is capable of
inducing a coherent dynamical evolution of a quantum system $Q$, in the
presence of a conservation law, then $M$ must be non-classical. This argument
supports witnesses of non-classicality relying on a single quantum probe, which
can be applied to a number of open issues, notably in quantum gravity or
quantum biology.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Pietra_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Giuseppe Di Pietra&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Marletto_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Chiara Marletto&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2205.05704">
<title>Dynamical quantum ergodicity from energy level statistics. (arXiv:2205.05704v2 [quant-ph] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2205.05704</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Ergodic theory provides a rigorous mathematical description of classical
dynamical systems including a formal definition of the ergodic hierarchy.
Closely related to this hierarchy is a less-known notion of cyclic approximate
periodic transformations [see, e.g., I. Cornfield, S. Fomin, and Y. Sinai,
Ergodic theory (Springer-Verlag New York, 1982)], which maps any &quot;ergodic&quot;
dynamical system to a cyclic permutation on a circle and arguably represents
the most elementary notion of ergodicity. This paper shows that cyclic
ergodicity generalizes to quantum dynamical systems, and this generalization is
proposed here as the basic rigorous definition of quantum ergodicity. It
implies the ability to construct an orthonormal basis, where quantum dynamics
transports an initial basis vector to all other basis vectors one by one, while
maintaining a sufficiently large overlap between the time-evolved initial state
and a given basis state. It is proven that the basis, maximizing the overlap
over all cyclic permutations, is obtained via the discrete Fourier transform of
the energy eigenstates. This relates quantum cyclic ergodicity to level
statistics. We then show that the near-universal Wigner-Dyson level statistics
implies quantum cyclic ergodicity, but the reverse is not necessarily true. For
the latter, we study irrational flows on a 2D torus and prove that both the
classical and quantum flows are cyclic ergodic. However, the corresponding
level statistics is neither Wigner-Dyson nor Poisson. Finally, we use the
cyclic construction to motivate a quantum ergodic hierarchy of operators and
argue that under the additional assumption of Poincare recurrences, cyclic
ergodicity is a necessary condition for such operators to satisfy the
eigenstate thermalization hypothesis. This work provides a general framework
for transplanting some rigorous concepts of ergodic theory to quantum dynamical
systems.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Vikram_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Amit Vikram&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Galitski_V/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Victor Galitski&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2206.14277">
<title>Integrable Floquet systems related to logarithmic conformal field theory. (arXiv:2206.14277v2 [quant-ph] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2206.14277</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We study an integrable Floquet quantum system related to lattice statistical
systems in the universality class of dense polymers. These systems are
described by a particular non-unitary representation of the Temperley-Lieb
algebra. We find a simple Lie algebra structure for the elements of
Temperley-Lieb algebra which are invariant under shift by two lattice sites,
and show how the local Floquet conserved charges and the Floquet Hamiltonian
are expressed in terms of this algebra. The system has a phase transition
between local and non-local phases of the Floquet Hamiltonian. We provide a
strong indication that in the scaling limit this non-equilibrium system is
described by the logarithmic conformal field theory.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Yashin_V/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Vsevolod I. Yashin&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Kurlov_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Denis V. Kurlov&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Fedorov_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Aleksey K. Fedorov&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Gritsev_V/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Vladimir Gritsev&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2207.02933">
<title>On the two-dimensional time-dependent anisotropic harmonic oscillator in a magnetic field. (arXiv:2207.02933v2 [quant-ph] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2207.02933</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;A Charged harmonic oscillator in a magnetic field, Landau problems, and an
oscillator in a noncommutative space, share the same mathematical structure in
their Hamiltonians. We have considered a two-dimensional anisotropic harmonic
oscillator (AHO) with arbitrarily time-dependent parameters (effective mass and
frequencies), placed in an arbitrarily time-dependent magnetic field. A class
of quadratic invariant operators (in the sense of Lewis and Riesenfeld) have
been constructed. The invariant operators ($\hat{\mathcal{I}}$) have been
reduced to a simplified representative form by a linear canonical
transformation (the group $Sp(4, \mathbb{R})$). An orthonormal basis of the
Hilbert space consisting of the eigenvectors of $\hat{\mathcal{I}}$ is
obtained. In order to obtain the solutions of the time-dependent
Schr\&quot;{o}dinger equation corresponding to the system, both the geometric and
dynamical phase-factors are constructed. Peres-Horodecki Separability Criterion
for the bipartite coherent states corresponding to our system has been
demonstrated.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Patra_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Pinaki Patra&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2208.07454">
<title>High frequency torsional motion transduction using optomechanical coupled oscillators. (arXiv:2208.07454v2 [physics.optics] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2208.07454</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Using light to measure an object&apos;s motion is central to operating mechanical
sensors that probe forces and fields. Cavity optomechanical systems embed
mechanical resonators inside optical resonators. This enhances the sensitivity
of optomechanical measurements, but only if the mechanical resonator does not
spoil the properties of the optical cavity. For example, cavity optomechanical
detection of resonators made from optically absorbing materials, or whose
geometry does not possess suitable spatial symmetry, is challenging. Here we
demonstrate a system that overcomes challenges in measuring high-frequency
twisting motion of a nanodisk by converting them to vibrations of a photonic
crystal cavity. Optomechanical readout of the cavity then enables measurement
of the nanodisk&apos;s torsional resonances with sensitivity $5.1\times
10^{-21}-1.2\times 10^{-19}\,\text{Nm}/\sqrt{\text{Hz}}$ for a mechanical
frequency range of 5--800 MHz. The nanodisk can be outfitted with magnetic
nanostructures or metasurfaces without affecting the optical properties of the
cavity, making the system suitable for torque magnetometry and structured light
sensing.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Kaviani_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Hamidreza Kaviani&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Behera_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Bishnupada Behera&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Hajisalem_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ghazal Hajisalem&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Luiz_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Gustavo de Oliveira Luiz&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Lake_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;David P. Lake&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Barclay_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Paul E. Barclay&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2208.13858">
<title>Unitary evolution for a two-level quantum system in fractional-time scenario. (arXiv:2208.13858v2 [quant-ph] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2208.13858</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The time-evolution operator obtained from the fractional-time Schr\&quot;{o}dinger
equation (FTSE) is said to be non-unitary since it does not preserve the norm
of the vector state in time. As done in the time-dependent non-Hermitian
quantum formalism, for a traceless non-Hermitian two-level quantum system, we
demonstrate that it is possible to map the non-unitary time-evolution operator
in a unitary one. It is done by considering a dynamical Hilbert space with a
time-dependent metric operator, constructed from a Hermitian time-dependent
Dyson map, in respect to which the system evolves in a unitary way, and the
standard quantum mechanics interpretation can be made properly. To elucidate
our approach, we consider three examples of Hamiltonian operators and their
corresponding unitary dynamics obtained from the solutions of FTSE, and the
respective Dyson maps.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Cius_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;D. Cius&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Menon_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;L. Menon Jr.&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Santos_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;M. A. F. dos Santos&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Castro_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;A. S. M. de Castro&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Andrade_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;F. M. Andrade&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.05053">
<title>Strong coupling of a Gd$^{3+}$ multilevel spin system to an on-chip superconducting resonator. (arXiv:2210.05053v2 [quant-ph] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.05053</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We report the realization of a strong coupling between a Gd$^{3+}$ spin
ensemble hosted in a scheelite (CaWO$_4$) single crystal and the resonant mode
of a coplanar stripline superconducting cavity leading to a large separation of
spin-photon states of 146 MHz. The interaction is well described by the Dicke
model and the crystal-field Hamiltonian of the multilevel spin system. We
observe a change of the crystal-field parameters due to the presence of photons
in the cavity that generates a significant perturbation of the crystal ground
state. Using finite-element calculations, we numerically estimate the cavity
sensing volume as well as the average spin-photon coupling strength of
$g_0\approx$ 620 Hz. Lastly, the dynamics of the spin-cavity states are
explored via pulsed measurements by recording the cavity ring-down signal as a
function of pulse length and amplitude. The results indicate a potential method
to initialize this multilevel system in its ground state via an active cooling
process.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Franco_Rivera_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Giovanni Franco-Rivera&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Cochran_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Josiah Cochran&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Miyashita_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Seiji Miyashita&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Bertaina_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Sylvain Bertaina&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Chiorescu_I/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Irinel Chiorescu&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.05689">
<title>Mass Independent Scheme for Large Spatial Quantum Superpositions. (arXiv:2210.05689v3 [quant-ph] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.05689</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Placing a large mass in a large spatial superposition, such as a
Schr\&quot;odinger Cat state is a significant and important challenge. In
particular, testing the quantum nature of gravity in the laboratory via
entanglement will require a large spatial superposition (${\cal O}(10-100)$
$\mu$m) of a mesoscopic mass ($m\sim {\cal O}(10^{-14} -10^{-15})$ kg). To
date, the typical methods of achieving this spatial delocalization are to use
wavepacket expansions or quantum ancilla (for example spin) dependent forces,
all of whose efficacy reduces with mass. Thus achieving a spatial splitting
independent of the mass is an important open challenge. In this paper, we
present a method of achieving a mass-independent enhancement of superposition
via diamagnetic repulsion from current-carrying wires. We analyse an example
system which uses the Stern-Gerlach effect to creating a small initial
splitting, and then apply our diamagnetic repulsion method to enhance the
superposition size ${\cal O}(400-600)$ $\mu$m from an initial modest split of
the wavefunction. We provide an analytic and numeric analysis of our scheme.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Zhou_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Run Zhou&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Marshman_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ryan J. Marshman&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Bose_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Sougato Bose&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Mazumdar_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Anupam Mazumdar&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.09457">
<title>Pseudo Entropy in dS/CFT and Time-like Entanglement Entropy. (arXiv:2210.09457v2 [hep-th] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.09457</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We study holographic entanglement entropy in dS/CFT and introduce time-like
entanglement entropy in CFTs. Both of them take complex values in general and
are related with each other via an analytical continuation. We argue that they
are correctly understood as pseudo entropy. We find that the imaginary part of
pseudo entropy implies an emergence of time in dS/CFT.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Doi_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Kazuki Doi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Harper_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jonathan Harper&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Mollabashi_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ali Mollabashi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Takayanagi_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Tadashi Takayanagi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Taki_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yusuke Taki&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.16438">
<title>Quantum Variational Rewinding for Time Series Anomaly Detection. (arXiv:2210.16438v2 [quant-ph] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.16438</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Electron dynamics, financial markets and nuclear fission reactors, though
seemingly unrelated, all produce observable characteristics evolving with time.
Within this broad scope, departures from normal temporal behavior range from
academically interesting to potentially catastrophic. New algorithms for time
series anomaly detection (TAD) are therefore certainly in demand. With the
advent of newly accessible quantum processing units (QPUs), exploring a quantum
approach to TAD is now relevant and is the topic of this work. Our approach -
Quantum Variational Rewinding, or, QVR - trains a family of parameterized
unitary time-devolution operators to cluster normal time series instances
encoded within quantum states. Unseen time series are assigned an anomaly score
based upon their distance from the cluster center, which, beyond a given
threshold, classifies anomalous behavior. After a first demonstration with a
simple and didactic case, QVR is used to study the real problem of identifying
anomalous behavior in cryptocurrency market data. Finally, multivariate time
series from the cryptocurrency use case are studied using IBM&apos;s Falcon r5.11H
family of superconducting transmon QPUs, where anomaly score errors resulting
from hardware noise are shown to be reducible by as much as 20% using advanced
error mitigation techniques.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Baker_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jack S. Baker&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Horowitz_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Haim Horowitz&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Radha_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Santosh Kumar Radha&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Fernandes_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Stenio Fernandes&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Jones_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Colin Jones&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Noorani_N/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Noorain Noorani&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Skavysh_V/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Vladimir Skavysh&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Lamontangne_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Philippe Lamontangne&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Sanders_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Barry C. Sanders&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.17448">
<title>Geometry of phase-covariant qubit channels. (arXiv:2210.17448v2 [quant-ph] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.17448</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We analyze the geometry on the space of non-unital phase-covariant qubit
maps. Using the corresponding Choi-Jamio{\l}kowski states, we derive the
Hilbert-Schmidt line and volume elements using the channel eigenvalues together
with the parameter that characterizes non-unitality. We find the shapes and
analytically compute the volumes of phase-covariant channels, in particular
entanglement breaking and obtainable with time-local generators.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Siudzinska_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Katarzyna Siudzi&amp;#x144;ska&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.00350">
<title>Pulse-Level Optimization of Parameterized Quantum Circuits for Variational Quantum Algorithms. (arXiv:2211.00350v2 [quant-ph] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.00350</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Variational Quantum Algorithms (VQAs) have emerged as a powerful class of
algorithms that is highly suitable for noisy quantum devices. Therefore,
investigating their design has become key in quantum computing research.
Previous works have shown that choosing an effective parameterized quantum
circuit (PQC) or ansatz for VQAs is crucial to their overall performance,
especially on near-term devices. In this paper, we utilize pulse-level access
to quantum machines and our understanding of their two-qubit interactions to
optimize the design of two-qubit entanglers in a manner suitable for VQAs. Our
analysis results show that pulse-optimized ansatze reduce state preparation
times by more than half, maintain expressibility relative to standard PQCs, and
are more trainable through local cost function analysis. Our algorithm
performance results show that in three cases, our PQC configuration outperforms
the base implementation. Our algorithm performance results, executed on IBM
Quantum hardware, demonstrate that our pulse-optimized PQC configurations are
more capable of solving MaxCut and Chemistry problems compared to a standard
configuration.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Ibrahim_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Mohannad Ibrahim&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Mohammadbagherpoor_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Hamed Mohammadbagherpoor&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Rios_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Cynthia Rios&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Bronn_N/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Nicholas T. Bronn&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Byrd_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Gregory T. Byrd&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01068">
<title>Comment on: Bell tests explained by classical optics without quantum entanglement. (arXiv:2211.01068v2 [quant-ph] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01068</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;In a paper published in the journal Physics Essays in 2021, the author D.L.
Mamas writes &quot;A polarized photon interacts with a polarizer through the
component of the photon&apos;s electric field which is aligned with the polarizer.
This component varies as the cosine of the angle through which the polarizer is
rotated, explaining the cosine observed in Bell test data. Quantum mechanics is
unnecessary and plays no role&quot;. Mamas is right that according to this physical
model, one will observe a negative cosine. However, the amplitude of the cosine
curve is 50%, not 100%, and it consequently does not violate any Bell-CHSH
inequality. Mamas&apos; physical model is a classic local hidden variables model.
The result is illustrated with a Monte Carlo simulation.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Gill_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Richard D. Gill&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01190">
<title>Quantum City: simulation of a practical near-term metropolitan quantum network. (arXiv:2211.01190v2 [quant-ph] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01190</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We present the architecture and analyze the applications of a
metropolitan-scale quantum network that requires only limited hardware
resources for end users. Using NetSquid, a quantum network simulation tool
based on discrete events, we assess the performance of several quantum network
protocols involving two or more users in various configurations in terms of
topology, hardware and trust choices. Our analysis takes losses and errors into
account and considers realistic parameters corresponding to present or
near-term technology. Our results show that practical quantum-enhanced network
functionalities are within reach today and can prepare the ground for further
applications when more advanced technology becomes available.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Yehia_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Raja Yehia&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Neves_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Simon Neves&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Diamanti_E/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Eleni Diamanti&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Kerenidis_I/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Iordanis Kerenidis&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01331">
<title>Bell&apos;s theorem allows local theories of quantum mechanics. (arXiv:2211.01331v2 [quant-ph] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01331</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;A recent Nature Physics editorial (Nat. Phys. (2022) 18, 961) falsely claims
``any theory that uses hidden variables still requires non-local physics.&apos;&apos; We
correct this claim and explain why it is important to get this right.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Hance_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jonte R. Hance&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Hossenfelder_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Sabine Hossenfelder&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
</rdf:RDF>