<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Digital Trends</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.digitaltrends.com/feed/?key=f00edf6a58d2a8740e624dda919cab37" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.digitaltrends.com</link>
	<description>Tech News, Reviews, Deals, and How-To&#039;s</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2022 16:00:08 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/dt-site-icon.png?fit=32%2C32&#038;p=1</url>
	<title>Digital Trends</title>
	<link>https://www.digitaltrends.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<atom:link rel="hub" href="https://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com" />
					<atom:link rel="hub" href="https://pubsubhubbub.superfeedr.com" />
				<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">35334127</site>	<item>
		<title>7 Spectacular sci-fi movies that will prepare you for the rise of the metaverse</title>
		<link>https://www.digitaltrends.com/movies/best-metaverse-movies/</link>
		<pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2022 16:00:04 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Luke Dormehl]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Features]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Movies & TV]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AR]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AVATAR]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Disclosure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[free guy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Metaverse]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[minority report]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ready player one]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Matrix]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[VR]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.digitaltrends.com/?p=3186545</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[If you want a fun way to visualize the tech, virtual worlds, or ethical conundrums that the metaverse might bring about, check out these seven movies]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The metaverse: buzzword or major paradigm shift? Right now, there’s probably a bit of column A and a bit of column B. There are certainly companies out there eager to espouse their metaverse strategy (so long as you don’t ask for too many concrete details) because they don’t want to be seen as not having one. At the same time, there are other companies (including Meta, formerly Facebook) that are going full tilt when it comes to embracing this new technology.</p>
<p>According to Meta CEO Mark Zuckerberg, the metaverse will be a virtual version of the Internet in which, “you are in the experience, not just looking at it.” The company is busy working on everything from digital avatars to VR headsets that can detect and relay your facial expressions.</p>
<p>According to Matthew Ball, author of the book <a href="https://www.matthewball.vc/metaversebook" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><em>The Metaverse</em></a>, the metaverse is a “massively scaled and interoperable network of real-time rendered 3D virtual worlds that can be experienced synchronously and persistently by an effectively unlimited number of users with an individual sense of presence, and with continuity of data, such as identity, history, entitlements, objects, communications, and payments.”</p>
<p>Got that? If you haven’t – or if, like the rest of us, you’re still trying to wrap your head around what that might look like – don’t worry: Help is at hand. The term “metaverse” might have originated in Neal Stephenson’s 1992 novel <em>Snow Crash</em>, but there are plenty of movies out there that can help shed light on what we might have to look forward to with the metaverse.</p>
<p>Whether it’s depictions of the tech necessary, images of possible virtual worlds, example use cases, or just a look at some of the ethical and technical conundrums we might soon be dealing with, here are seven movies to help you out.</p>
<p>As far as preparing-for-the-metaverse homework goes, this isn’t a bad crash course …</p>
<h2>Ready Player One (2018)</h2>
<iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/cSp1dM2Vj48" width="640" height="360"></iframe>
<p>Steven Spielberg’s 2018 movie <em>Ready Player One</em> – based on Ernest Cline’s 2011 novel of the same name – is invoked in, at a rough guess, 97.3% of articles trying to explain the metaverse. With good reason, too. At the time the metaverse appeared on the radar of most people – in 2021 when Facebook renamed itself Meta – <em>Ready Player One</em> was a VR-themed movie still fresh in people’s memories.</p>
<p>In <em>Ready Player One</em>, the metaverse stand-in is called “The Oasis” and, as its name implies, represents a rare spot of technologically induced goodness in an otherwise bleak reality for the story’s protagonist. The reason for including <em>Ready Player One</em> here (other than the fact that it’s good to be aware of the reference points everyone else makes in this space) is because of the story’s focus on gaming as a primary purpose for the metaverse. Unlike the internet, which became a core part of the modern gaming experience only later, games are likely to be a big driver of metaverse technologies right from the start.</p>
<p>Today, the closest thing we have to real-world metaverses are the likes of <em>Minecraft</em>, <em>GTA Online</em>, and the spectacular <em><a href="https://www.digitaltrends.com/gaming/the-best-settings-for-microsoft-flight-simulator-2020-on-xbox-series-x/">Microsoft Flight Simulator</a></em>. Due to the size of the gaming market today, and the money it can rake in, expect games companies to be instrumental in helping push the capabilities that will enable a true real-time, synchronous virtual world to be possible. Right now it isn’t. But the opportunity for earning billions of dollars in revenue has a funny way of changing things.</p>
<h2>Minority Report (2002)</h2>
<div class="dtvideos-container" data-provider="youtube"><div style="overflow:hidden; padding-bottom:56.25%; position:relative;"><div style="width:100%; height:100%; position:absolute;"><iframe title="Minority Report - Personal Advertising in the Future" width="100%" height="100%" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/7bXJ_obaiYQ?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe></div></div><div class="dtvideos-details h-dtvideos-details-embed"><div class="dtvideos-title">Minority Report - Personal Advertising in the Future</div></div></div>
<p><em>Minority Report</em>’s inclusion on this list might seem a little surprising. After all, this isn’t a movie based on the concept of virtual worlds at all. But there’s one key moment that makes it qualify. It’s the scene in which Tom Cruise’s character, Chief John Anderton, walks through a futuristic mall, with video screens blaring out personalized adverts addressing him by name.</p>
<p>Personalized ads are, of course, nothing new in the world of 2022 when it comes to the internet. But they’ve largely not extended into the real world. That’s something the metaverse could change, though.</p>
<p>Whether it’s more immersive advertising in virtual worlds (say, as your 3D avatar wanders through virtual shopping malls) or augmented ads superimposing advertisements into the physical world, it seems clear that targeted ads are sure to ramp up in a big way in the metaverse world.</p>
<p>A fascinating <a href="https://venturebeat.com/virtual/metaverse-we-need-guaranteed-basic-immersive-rights/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">recent op-ed</a> by a VR and AR veteran entrepreneur made this case with a call for “immersive rights” for future denizens of the metaverse. Among them? The right to “experiential authenticity” to protect against just this kind of thing. All helpfully predicted back in <em>Minority Report</em>. (Which, incidentally, was directed by <em>Ready Player One</em> helmer Steven Spielberg.)</p>
<p>It’s also great at showing off mixed reality technology in action.</p>
<h2>Disclosure (1994)</h2>
<iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/dJcakDNtHDA" width="640" height="360"></iframe>
<p>When you think of Michael Crichton, author of <em>Jurassic Park</em>, chances are that <em>Disclosure</em> isn’t one of the first titles that trips off your tongue. In fact, it actually came out during a career high point for Crichton, when the aforementioned <em>Jurassic Park</em> was ruling the box office, his show <em>ER</em> dominated the TV airwaves, and <em>Disclosure</em> topped the book charts. The movie adaptation, starring Michael Douglas, followed in 1994.</p>
<p>While the metaverse isn’t a heavy theme of the book or movie, the company Douglas’ executive works for is attempting to build a collaborative, real-time virtual world that lets users walk through databases rendered as virtual worlds. The reason for its inclusion on this list is because, despite how dated much of the movie is, the overall hardware setup was pretty spot-on – including haptics, <a href="https://www.digitaltrends.com/gaming/endless-walking-vr-moon-boots-ekto/">stationary walking platforms</a>, VR goggles, <a href="https://www.digitaltrends.com/computing/meta-project-cambria-augmented-reality-laptop-replacement/">facial expression-tracking technology</a>, and more.</p>
<p>Also, it’s one of the few examples of virtual worlds in a movie being used for workplace productivity, rather than just entertainment.</p>
<h2>The Matrix (1999)</h2>
<iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/vKQi3bBA1y8" width="640" height="360"></iframe>
<p>When it comes to science fiction movies that influenced the zeitgeist, <em>The Matrix</em> is safely embedded somewhere among the top five in cinema history. But while other big hitters, like <em>2001: A Space Odyssey</em>, <em>Star Wars</em>, and <em>Le Voyage dans la Lune</em>, focused on the 20th-century dream of space travel, <em>The Matrix</em> zeroed in on cyberspace and the notion of simulated virtual worlds.</p>
<p>In <em>The Matrix</em>, what appears to be reality is actually a simulation of Earth, serving to pacify the humanity that is, in reality, serving as mass batteries for sentient machines. However, virtual worlds are also training grounds that allow Neo, Morpheus, and their vinyl-wearing comrades to practice different abilities.</p>
<p><em>The Matrix</em> helped articulate these two visions of what massive virtual worlds could mean: an opiate for the masses or a limitless world for refining and improving human potential. The metaverse could be either. We guess it depends if we take the red or blue pill.</p>
<h2>Total Recall (1990)</h2>
<iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/WFMLGEHdIjE" width="640" height="360"></iframe>
<p>1990’s <em>Total Recall</em>, loosely based on a short story by Philip K. Dick, tells the story of a construction worker who, in essence, takes a holiday from himself: visiting a neuro-tech firm that promises to implant exciting fake memories in his brain, in which the protagonist sees himself as a spy visiting Mars. For our money, the results are one of the best movies in the Arnold Schwarzenegger back catalog.</p>
<p>While the idea of false memories is different from virtual worlds, there’s no doubt that a compelling use-case for the metaverse will be to allow people to lead alternate, parallel existences in massively scaled virtual worlds populated by large numbers of other people. We already see some version of this with MMORPGs and high-grossing games like <em>GTA V</em> in the real world. But this is only going to grow further in the metaverse – especially when you start factoring in widespread VR and the ability to earn a living for yourself inside virtual realms.</p>
<p>It’s not a coincidence that some metaverse pioneers namecheck <em>Total Recall</em> as a source of inspiration in interviews.</p>
<h2>Avatar (2009)</h2>
<iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/5PSNL1qE6VY" width="640" height="360"></iframe>
<p>Two years before James Cameron’s record-breaking movie <em>Avatar</em> was released, a group called the Accelerating Studies Foundation published a way-ahead-of-the-curve report titled the <a href="https://www.academia.edu/266307/A_Metaverse_Roadmap_Pathways_to_the_3D_Web_2007" target="_blank" rel="noopener">metaverse Roadmap</a>, outlining what the 3D internet would look like in the far-future year of, err, 2016.</p>
<p>While talk of the metaverse has certainly ramped up in the last couple of years, <em>Avatar</em> arrived at an interesting time in tech history where, as the metaverse Roadmap report makes clear, ideas around this topic were beginning to swell. <em>Second Life</em> was, at the time, making waves as a metaverse of sorts, while the newly launched Google Street View showed us that recreating the world digitally – and then being able to whiz around it at will – was feasible.</p>
<p><em>Avatar</em>’s plot, in which humans remote-operate alien Na’vi bodies on a distant planet, plugged into many of these circulating ideas. It gave them a futuristic spin, of course, but the theme of virtual embodiment is only going to grow in prominence in the metaverse years to come. And, while Cameron’s movie didn’t create the term “avatar,” it certainly introduced its current usage to a much wider audience.</p>
<h2>Free Guy (2021)</h2>
<iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/X2m-08cOAbc" width="640" height="360"></iframe>
<p>As a relatively lightweight comedic movie that views the metaverse through positive, rose-tinted eyes, <a href="https://www.digitaltrends.com/movies/free-guy-visual-effects-interview-vfx/">the visually impressive <em>Free Guy</em></a> is more of a palette cleanser on this list than a serious lesson in how the metaverse will work.</p>
<p>But if Mark Zuckerberg and others like him can give us a virtual Ryan Reynolds to hang out with, we can only wish them luck in their metaverse ambitions &#8230;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
													<thumbnail>https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/best-hulu-movies-total-recall-gallery.jpg?p=1</thumbnail>
					
											<enclosure url="https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/best-hulu-movies-total-recall-gallery.jpg?p=1" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
															<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3186545</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>My Policeman review: an introspective, static drama</title>
		<link>https://www.digitaltrends.com/movies/my-policeman-review/</link>
		<pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2022 14:01:19 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Welch]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Movies & TV]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon Prime Video]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Harry Styles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Movie Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[My Policeman]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[new movies]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.digitaltrends.com/?p=3220482</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[My Policeman is an introspective drama that is undercut by Emma Corrin and Harry Styles' disappointing performances. The film is streaming now on Prime Video.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em><a href="https://www.digitaltrends.com/movies/my-policeman-new-trailer/">My Policeman</a></em> is a stately, often overly repressed adaptation of Bethan Roberts’ 2012 novel of the same name. The film has all the necessary ingredients to be another respectably dignified &#8212; if not particularly spectacular &#8212; ensemble drama from the U.K. However, despite featuring six core cast members, only one of them truly manages to leave much of a lasting impression in <em>My Policeman</em>. As for the film itself, it frequently flattens rather than deepens the emotional complexity of its story.</p>
<p>The film’s uniquely British, stiff-upper-lip attitude could have, if handled better, only further amplified the regret and desperation that is present in its tale of gay repression and multigenerational heartbreak. Instead, <em>My Policeman</em> consistently fails to dive as fully into the raw emotions of its story as it should, which robs the film’s third act of much of its intended power. While some of the film’s failings can be attributed to Michael Grandage’s relatively straightforward direction, the two disappointing performances at the center of it are also to blame for many of <em>My Policeman</em>’s problems.</p>
<figure id="attachment_3220581" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-3220581" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img  class=" size-large wp-image-3220581" src="https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Harry-Styles-and-Emma-Corrin-stand-in-a-crowd-together-in-My-Policeman.jpg?fit=720%2C480&p=1" alt="Harry Styles and Emma Corrin stand in a crowd together in My Policeman."   /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-3220581" class="wp-caption-text"><span class="credit">Amazon Studios, 2022</span></figcaption></figure>
<p><em>My Policeman</em>’s story is told through the perspectives of two of its central three characters. The film’s first act is shown through the lens of Marion, a retired schoolteacher who is played in her older years by Gina McKee. Through her recollections, we see how Marion’s younger self (played by <a href="https://www.digitaltrends.com/movies/everything-revealed-at-netflix-tudum-2022-event/"><em>The Crown</em>&#8216;s Emma Corrin</a>) first met and fell in love with her eventual husband, Tom (Linus Roache), a former policeman who is played in his younger years by Harry Styles. The memories that are shown at the start of the film also suggest that Tom and Marion’s close friendship with a museum curator named Patrick, who is played by both Rupert Everett in his older years and David Dawson as a younger man, was an entirely innocent one.</p>
<p>However, after McKee’s older Marion takes in Everett’s disabled Patrick, she begins to secretly read some of the journals he’s kept from his youth. When she does so, <em>My Policeman</em> switches to the perspective of Dawson’s younger Patrick and reveals the secret sexual relationship that he engaged in for many years with Styles’ Tom. From that point on, <em>My Policeman</em>’s multiple perspectives and timelines begin to blend together, slowly but surely revealing how Patrick, Tom, and Marion’s friendship was eventually destroyed.</p>
<p>The clever structure of <em>My Policeman</em>’s script, which was penned by Ron Nyswaner, allows the film’s story to gradually grow more layered and complex throughout the entirety of its 113-minute runtime. The film even mines a surprising amount of tension and intrigue by revealing Marion’s memories of her husband’s relationship with Patrick in the manner and pace that it does. Unfortunately, Nyswaner’s script still arrives at a conclusion that doesn’t feel nearly as messy or emotionally raw as it arguably should.</p>
<figure id="attachment_3220582" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-3220582" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img  class=" size-large wp-image-3220582" src="https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Gina-McKee-stands-on-a-beach-next-to-Rupert-Everett-in-My-Policeman.jpg?fit=720%2C480&p=1" alt="Gina McKee stands on a beach next to Rupert Everett in My Policeman."   /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-3220582" class="wp-caption-text"><span class="credit">Amazon Studios, 2022</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Styles, for his part, turns in a disappointingly one-note performance as Tom, a man who is torn between the stability of his relationship with Marion and the passion of his and Patrick’s secret romance. Styles is very clearly still growing as an actor, but he proves to be incapable of portraying the kind of vulnerability and dimensionality that <em>My Policeman</em>’s story requires of him. The same goes for Emma Corrin, who fares somewhat better than Styles, but still gives a performance as Marion that doesn’t come close to matching the elegance of McKee’s turn as her older counterpart.</p>
<p>For the most part, <em>My Policeman</em>’s present-day scenes work well precisely because of how much more nuanced and mature McKee and Roache’s performances feel as Marion and Tom. That doesn’t mean, however, that <em>My Policeman</em>’s flashbacks are all difficult to get through. Quite the opposite is true, in fact, thanks to Dawson’s genuinely revelatory performance as Patrick. Dawson has an innate ability to hold your attention whenever he’s on screen, and it’s in the scenes where <em>My Policeman</em> focuses most heavily on him that the film comes the closest to communicating the romantic tragedy of its story.</p>
<iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/xAEgWXOH1mY" width="640" height="360"></iframe>
<p>Despite the undeniable quality of Dawson’s breakout performance, though, <em>My Policeman</em>’s overall power fails to match the sum of its parts. As far as mature dramas go, the film is another competently made, occasionally stirring British romance. However, the overly clean nature of <em>My Policeman</em>’s final minutes, as well as Corrin and Styles’ lackluster performances, ultimately prevent the film from standing out much from the crowd. In the end, McKee and Dawson’s moving efforts as Marion and Patrick aren’t enough to turn <em>My Policeman</em> into the kind of provocative, emotionally searing drama that it desperately wants to be.</p>
<p>My Policeman <em>is playing in select theaters now and is currently available to stream on Amazon Prime Video.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
													<thumbnail>https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Harry-Styles-and-Emma-Corrin-stand-in-a-crowd-together-in-My-Policeman.jpg?p=1</thumbnail>
					
											<enclosure url="https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Harry-Styles-and-Emma-Corrin-stand-in-a-crowd-together-in-My-Policeman.jpg?p=1" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
															<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3220482</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Enola Holmes 2 director on Millie&#8217;s wit, Henry&#8217;s heart, and mysteries to come</title>
		<link>https://www.digitaltrends.com/movies/enola-holmes-2-director-interview-harry-bradbeer-sequel/</link>
		<pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2022 12:01:22 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rick Marshall]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Features]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Movies & TV]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best Netflix movies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enola Holmes 2]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[harry bradbeer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Henry Cavill]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Netflix]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.digitaltrends.com/?p=3219532</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Enola Holmes 2 director Harry Bradbeer shares his thoughts on stars Millie Bobby Brown and Henry Cavill, as well as his favorite moments and mysteries to come.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>After the 2020 Netflix film <em><a href="https://www.digitaltrends.com/movies/enola-holmes-review-netflix/">Enola Holmes</a></em> became a surprise hit, introducing <em>Stranger Things</em> actress Millie Bobby Brown as Sherlock Holmes&#8217; brilliant sister, the only mystery left unsolved was when we&#8217;d get a sequel. That question was answered with the November 4 premiere of <a href="https://www.digitaltrends.com/movies/enola-holmes-2-review/"><em>E</em><em>nola Holmes 2</em></a>, which delivers another exciting, fascinating, and funny chapter in Enola&#8217;s saga, complete with plenty of clever twists.</p>
<p>Along with Brown returning as the title character, <em>Enola Holmes 2</em> also brings back Henry Cavill (<em>The Witcher</em>) as Sherlock, as well as director Harry Bradbeer (<em>Fleabag</em>) behind the camera, among others. Digital Trends spoke to Bradbeer about his work on <em>Enola Holmes 2</em> and whether a third installment of the franchise could be in the works.</p>
<figure class="alignnone"><img  class=" size-large wp-image-3219944" src="https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/enola-holmes-2-bts-01.jpg?fit=720%2C480&p=1" alt="Enola Holmes 2 director Harry Bradbeer talks to stars Millie Bobby Brown and Henry Cavill on the set of the film."   /></figure>
<p><strong>Digital Trends: The first film focused on Enola learning to be independent and getting things done on her own, without help from her famous brothers. This one pivots from there quite a bit thematically. How would you describe the film’s themes this time around?</strong></p>
<p><strong>Harry Bradbeer:</strong> Well, you put your finger on it. In a sentence, it&#8217;s going from &#8220;I&#8221; to &#8220;we&#8221; &#8212; from learning to be able to stand on your own two feet to learning the power of working with others and of cooperation. [It&#8217;s about] learning you have to unite to be able to find your full strength as a human being.</p>
<p>We developed that idea into her relationship with Sherlock, into enlisting Tewkesbury&#8217;s (Louis Partridge) help, and of course, the major story that runs through it all: Her joining together with a group of working-class girls to fight corruption and further the cause of union and sisterhood.</p>
<p><strong>How did Millie Bobby Brown&#8217;s portrayal of Enola evolve over time? Was there a point where the role leaned heavier into comedy or drama or such and it took some refining to get to what we see in the films? She embodies the character so well.</strong></p>
<p>Having worked in TV, you know from your first series what you&#8217;ve learned and what you want to take forward. And so we saw what we had in the first film: this incredible actor that could teeter between the comedy and the drama and the tragedy. That balance is my stock-in-trade. It&#8217;s what I love to do, because I think that&#8217;s what life is. <a href="https://www.fastsaying.com/I-Just-Thought-Here-Is-Comedy-Here-Is-Tragedy-That-Is-The-Way-Life-Is-I-Just-Tried-To-Do-It-True-To-Life-Billy-Wilder.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Billy Wilder said comedy and tragedy is life,</a> and that&#8217;s exactly it.</p>
<p>So we were working with that, but we were listening to the way she worked and what she was bringing forward, and we realized very early on that this was a girl who was growing up in a hurry. We wanted to bring a bit of that in and grow up with her over that film, which was shot two years [after the first film] when she&#8217;s almost at her 18th birthday.</p>
<p>So we worked with what Millie had and what she was excited to do more of. We knew we wanted to do more with Sherlock. We knew the audience was desperate to see her and him solving a crime together. And of course, they wanted to see Enola and Tewkesbury develop their romance. So that was the progression.</p>
<figure class="alignnone"><img  class=" size-large wp-image-3219943" src="https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/enola-holmes-2-bts-02.jpg?fit=720%2C480&p=1" alt="Millie Bobby Brown peeks through a door while being filmed in a behind-the-scenes photo from Enola Holmes 2."   /></figure>
<p><strong>Both films have a wonderful way of working with the audience to add a bit more emotion to moments when Enola gives the camera a look for just a second that conveys how she’s feeling. How did you get the tone right for those moments when she breaks the fourth wall?</strong></p>
<p>That&#8217;s very kind of you to say. We experiment with it. Often, I would give a free take at the end of a scene, and in that case, [Brown] may throw a look in or not. We ration it, too. There are times when there is no time for levity. It&#8217;s too serious for her to give a look to the camera, or she&#8217;s doing things she&#8217;s slightly embarrassed about &#8212; like when she&#8217;s dancing with Tewkesbury.</p>
<p>He&#8217;s teaching her to dance and she&#8217;s falling in love with him, and she catches us there and she&#8217;s like, &#8220;No. Go away.&#8221; At that point, she&#8217;s saying, &#8220;Don&#8217;t look at me. Leave me alone. This is awkward.&#8221;</p>
<p>So it can be expressing awkwardness. It can be expressing complicity. It can be a wink. Or when she says, &#8220;Perhaps I should write that down,&#8221; after Sherlock gives her a piece of rather shocking advice, what else is there to say?</p>
<p><strong><a href="https://www.digitaltrends.com/movies/henry-cavill-superman-enola-holmes-2-gaming-pc-build/">Henry Cavill’s Sherlock</a> gets quite a bit more development in the sequel. What is it that Henry brings to the role that helps make it unique and special to this franchise?</strong></p>
<p>I think he&#8217;s got a real emotional connection to the character. He understands Sherlock&#8217;s loneliness, which is not just because Sherlock lives alone and his family is dysfunctional, but also because his brain works at such a rate that it&#8217;s hard for him to relate and do small talk and get on with people. That&#8217;s why sometimes he has to release his tensions and his worries by going to the bar and having a drink and getting into a fight. That&#8217;s the way he can relax.</p>
<p>His emotional difficulties are something Henry related to, connected with, and felt he could bring forward. And as a member of a very close family, [Cavill] also understands how brotherhood works. I felt right from the first time we met that he would bring something warm and interesting to the relationship with Enola.</p>
<figure class="alignnone"><img  class=" size-large wp-image-3214386" src="https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/henry-cavill-enola-holmes-2.jpg?fit=720%2C480&p=1" alt="Henry Cavill reclines as Sherlock Holmes in a scene from Enola Holmes 2."   /></figure>
<p><strong>Without revealing any spoilers, is there an element of the film you’re particularly proud of?</strong></p>
<p>The thing I really loved was the message of the film: The importance of listening to and working with others, [and] the idea of cooperation, which is something very close to my heart as a collaborative person in art and in life. I think we can be too caught up in our own egos and lost in our own <a href="https://www.digitaltrends.com/mobile/best-smartphones/">smartphones</a>, and we need to connect. It&#8217;s that element of the film &#8212; the idea of union, of setting aside our ego for the moment and our pride and being open to connection with others &#8212; that ultimately leads in the films to its actual triumph.</p>
<p>The final climax requires that cooperation [and] the setting aside of ego for the common good. That message, inside a piece of entertainment, was always my ambition. I&#8217;m proud that I think it works. I think we managed to pull that off.</p>
<p><strong>The film sets up another installment really well. Has there been discussion of where things will go in future films or how many films it would ideally take to complete Enola’s story?</strong></p>
<p>Well, we only go one film at a time, like we did with the first. But of course, we&#8217;ve talked about the future possibilities and the directions they could go in. I&#8217;m glad you can see that possibility on the horizon.</p>
<p><em>Directed by Harry Bradbeer, </em>Enola Holmes 2<em> is available now on Netflix.</em></p>

<div class="b-media h-636693a260d87">
	<div class="b-media__wrapper">
		<div class="b-media__title">
			<a id="dt-media-enola-holmes-2"></a>
			Enola Holmes 2 (2022)					</div>
		<div class="b-media__inner">
			<div class="b-media__poster">
				<img  src="https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/tegBpjM5ODoYoM1NjaiHVLEA0QM.jpg?p=1#038;p=1.jpg" alt="Enola Holmes 2">
							</div>
			<div class="b-media__info">
				<div class="b-media__header">
											<div class="b-media__rating">
							<div class="b-media__rating-item">
	<div class="b-media__rating-img">
		<img src="https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/themes/dt-stardust/assets/images/svg/icon-metacritic.svg" alt="">
	</div>
	<div class="b-media__rating-score">
		58 %	</div>
</div>
<div class="b-media__rating-item">
	<div class="b-media__rating-img">
		<img src="https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/themes/dt-stardust/assets/images/svg/icon-imdb.svg" alt="">
	</div>
	<div class="b-media__rating-score">
		6.9/10	</div>
</div>
						</div>
																							<div class="b-media__duration">
																<span>
									129m								</span>
							</div>
																				</div>

									<div class="b-media__info-item">
						<strong class="b-media__info-title">
							Genre						</strong>
						<span class="dt-clamp dt-clamp-2">
							Mystery, Adventure, Crime						</span>
					</div>
				
									
<div class="b-media__info-item">
	<strong class="b-media__info-title">
		Stars	</strong>
	<span class="dt-clamp dt-clamp-2">
		Millie Bobby Brown, Henry Cavill, Louis Partridge	</span>
</div>

<div class="b-media__info-item">
	<strong class="b-media__info-title">
		Directed by	</strong>
	<span class="dt-clamp dt-clamp-1">
		Harry Bradbeer	</span>
</div>
				
				
				<div class="b-media__buttons b-media__buttons--desktop">
											<a href="https://www.netflix.com/title/81406219" rel="nofollow" target="_blank" class="b-buy">
							<span class="b-buy__inner">watch on Netflix</span>
						</a>
									</div>
			</div>
		</div>

		<div class="b-media__buttons b-media__buttons--mobile">
							<a href="https://www.netflix.com/title/81406219" rel="nofollow" target="_blank" class="b-buy">
					<span class="b-buy__inner">watch on Netflix</span>
				</a>
					</div>

					<div class="b-media__content b-media__content--empty dt-clamp dt-clamp-6 dt-clamp-large-3">
		
					</div>

					<button class="b-media__more" data-content-expand>
				Read more			</button>
		
			</div>
</div>

]]></content:encoded>
													<thumbnail>https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/enola-holmes-2-bts-01.jpg?p=1</thumbnail>
					
											<enclosure url="https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/enola-holmes-2-bts-01.jpg?p=1" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
															<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3219532</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Don&#8217;t lock in your &#8216;game of the year&#8217; list yet. 2022 is far from over</title>
		<link>https://www.digitaltrends.com/gaming/game-of-the-year-contenders-late-2022/</link>
		<pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2022 10:45:59 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Giovanni Colantonio]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Features]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God of War: Ragnarok]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marvel's Midnight Suns]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pentiment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pokémon Scarlet and Violet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Callisto Protocol]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.digitaltrends.com/?p=3220282</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Gamers have already decided that it's Elden Ring vs. God of War Ragnarok for 2022's game of the year, but there's still a lot still to come.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Surprise, surprise: <em>God of War Ragnarok</em> is one of the <a href="https://www.digitaltrends.com/gaming/god-of-war-ragnarok-review-ps5/">best-reviewed video games of 2022</a>. Even before the game’s review embargo, you could probably have predicted that from context clues. The sequel looked like it wasn’t straying too far from the incredibly well-reviewed <em>God of War</em> (2018), so review scores would likely follow closely behind. And with those scores would surely come the inevitable “game of the year” chatter.</p>
<video src="https://content.jwplatform.com/videos/rZ69Xqfy.mp4" data-player="zpykqaab" data-embed="default" data-application-id class="video-js" controls ></video>
<p>With little time to digest the game between now and December, recency bias dictates that <em>God of War Ragnarok</em> will likely top year-end lists. That might be a deserved honor for Sony’s impressive epic, but 2022 isn’t over yet. Just as the last minutes of a basketball game can completely reverse a team’s fortune, November and December have a history of delivering bracket-busting hits that can easily get lost once the holiday season’s biggest release drops. Buzzer-beaters like <em><a href="https://www.digitaltrends.com/gaming/solar-ash-review/">Solar Ash</a> </em>and <em><a href="https://www.digitaltrends.com/gaming/shovel-knight-pocket-dungeon-impressions/">Shovel Knight: Pocket Dungeon</a></em> were some of 2021’s finest titles, but their late release dates meant they had trouble breaking into any year-end conversations.</p>
<p>Looking at the rest of 2022’s game release calendar, it seems like that could happen again. <em>God of War Ragnarok</em> might be the last behemoth launching this year, but there are still plenty of games that could wind up being some of the year’s most memorable experiences. Here are some games you should keep on your radar that show there’s still a whole quarter of the game left before you should lock in your “best of 2022” lists.</p>
<h2>Pentiment</h2>
<figure class="alignnone"><img  class=" wp-image-3165241 size-large" src="https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/Pentiment.jpg?fit=720%2C720&p=1" alt="Andreas paints in Pentiment."   /></figure>
<p>It hasn’t been a great year for Xbox (that’s putting it mildly), but that could change in a few weeks thanks to <em>Pentiment</em>. Developed by <em>Fallout: New Vegas</em> studio Obsidian Entertainment, the narrative RPG probably isn’t what you’d expect when you hear the phrase “Xbox exclusive” That’s exactly what makes it so intriguing, though. Pentiment is a 16th-century murder deduction story that chronicles the life of Andreas, a journeyman who finds himself mixed up in a series of crimes and mysteries that span decades. What’s most eye-catching about it, though, is its illustrative art style that beautifully pulls inspiration from medieval art, from woodcuts to manuscripts.</p>
<p>I got a chance to <a href="https://www.digitaltrends.com/gaming/pentiment-preview-gamescom-2022/">play <em>Pentiment</em> at Gamescom</a> this year and I found myself engrossed instantly. Its gorgeous art direction is immediately noticeable, but the RPG systems are what stuck with me the most. I was able to customize Andreas to my liking, giving him specific skills (like a background in occult studies) that would have a real impact on my story even in a short demo. If that holds true in the entire game, <em>Pentiment</em> could end up being one of 2022’s biggest surprises, giving Xbox a much-needed hit.</p>
<p><em>Pentiment</em> launches on November 15 for Xbox One, Xbox Series X/S, and PC.</p>
<h2>Somerville</h2>
<figure class="alignnone"><img  class=" wp-image-2958477 size-large" src="https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/somerville-dark-room.jpg?fit=720%2C720&p=1" alt="Characters explore a dark room, full of mysterious figures in Somerville."   /></figure>
<p><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1671410/Somerville/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><em>Somerville</em></a> is one of those indie critical darlings that seems like it came out of left field, even though it’s been right under our nose the entire time. The atmospheric adventure game is the debut title from Jumpship, a studio co-founded by former Playdead co-founder Dino Patti. Playdead was responsible for creating arguably two of the best indies of all time in both <em>Limbo</em> and <em>Inside</em>, so the expectations for Somerville are a little high.</p>
<p>Based on the little we’ve seen of it so far, though, it looks like Somerville could live up to Playdead’s greatest hits. Trailers have teased a haunting alien invasion story that seems like a small-scale version of War of the Worlds. If nothing else, Somerville looks like it’ll deliver a striking visual style that should at the very least make for an eerie 2D thriller.</p>
<p><em>Somerville</em> launches on November 15 for Xbox One, Xbox Series X/S, and PC.</p>
<h2>Pokémon Scarlet and Violet</h2>
<figure class="alignnone"><img  class=" wp-image-3205203 size-large" src="https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Pokemon-scarlet.jpg?fit=720%2C720&p=1" alt="Bellibolt standing by a pond."   /></figure>
<p>The jury’s still out on whether or not <em>Pokémon Violet</em> and <em>Scarlet</em> will be another win for the long-running monster catching franchise, but I’d be remiss not to mention it here. Nintendo’s last big release of the year is a total reinvention of the traditional Pokemon formula, adapting the game to a true open-world format. Not only that, but it brings true co-op multiplayer to the series for the first time ever. That could be enough to make it one of the freshest mainline Pokemon games in a decade.</p>
<p>I recently <a href="https://www.digitaltrends.com/gaming/pokemon-scarlet-violet-hands-on-preview/">spent a full hour with the game</a> and the change in format certainly seems to work for the series. The traditional Pokémon hooks are there, but the adventure gives players a lot more freedom to roam around and tackle objectives in any order they please. That newfound freedom already has me intrigued, so I can’t count out Nintendo’s big holiday monster just yet.</p>
<p><em>Pokémon Scarlet</em> and <em>Violet</em> launch on November 18 for Nintendo Switch.</p>
<h2>Warhammer 40,000: Darktide</h2>
<figure class="alignnone"><img  class=" wp-image-3145355 size-large" src="https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/Warhammer-40k-Darktide.jpg?fit=720%2C720&p=1" alt="A team of players stands together in Warhammer 40K: Darktide."   /></figure>
<p>If you’ve never gotten into Warhammer games, I can’t say that I blame you. The tabletop franchise pumps out several video games a year, which can make it overwhelming to keep up with. However, <em>Warhammer 40,000: Darktide</em> may be the one game to keep on your radar if you’re looking for an entry point. The co-op multiplayer game is cut from the <a href="https://www.digitaltrends.com/gaming/back-4-blood-review/"><em>Left 4 Dead</em> mold</a>, letting players squad up and blast hordes of monsters together (while collecting some precious loot, of course).</p>
<p>I jumped into a few missions during the game’s recent beta and walked out impressed. Its tense missions and tight gunplay brought me back to my <em>Destiny</em> glory days when I’d grind strikes with my clan for hours on end. Considering that <em>Darktide</em> is set to have some live service DNA, I imagine it’s the kind of game that might only get bigger, better, and more acclaimed through its lifespan. In a year where multiplayer competition is light, Daktide could stand tall as one of 2022’s best.</p>
<p><em>Warhammer 40,000: Darktide</em> launches on November 30 for PC.</p>
<h2>Marvel’s Midnight Suns</h2>
<figure class="alignnone"><img  class=" wp-image-3175739 size-large" src="https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/Marvels-Midnight-Suns.jpg?fit=720%2C720&p=1" alt="Spider-Man lands in front of other heroes in Marvel's Midnight Suns."   /></figure>
<p><em><a href="https://www.digitaltrends.com/gaming/marvel-midnight-suns-release-date/">Marvel’s Midnight Suns</a></em> is currently 2022’s biggest question mark. The upcoming game from the tactics pros at Firaxis basically looks like XCOM with superheroes, which sounds like a winning elevator pitch on paper. However, there’s a fair reason for skepticism considering that the game has been delayed several times since it was first announced, raising questions about its shape ahead of a December launch.</p>
<p>Even with those potential red flags, I find myself very optimistic about <em>Marvel’s Midnight Suns</em>. Firaxis generally has a strong track record, with hits like<em> XCOM 2</em> and <em>Civilization VI</em> to its name. Its most recent game, 2020’s<em> XCOM: Chimera Squad</em>, was an especially underrated gem that made the sometimes daunting tactics genre much more approachable. If that energy carries over into Marvel’s Midnight Suns, I imagine it could give the fantastic<em> <a href="https://www.digitaltrends.com/gaming/mario-rabbids-sparks-of-hope-review/">Mario + Rabbids: Sparks of Hope</a></em> a run for its money.</p>
<p><em>Marvel’s Midnight Suns</em> launches on December 2 for PS4, PS5, Xbox One, Xbox Series X/S, Nintendo Switch, and PC.</p>
<h2>The Callisto Protocol</h2>
<figure class="alignnone"><img  class=" wp-image-3213917 size-large" src="https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/callisto-protocol.jpeg?fit=720%2C720&p=1" alt="The Callisto Protocol monster"   /></figure>
<p>Whatever you do, don’t lock in your game of the year lists before <em>The Callisto Protocol</em> launches. The debut horror game from Striking Distance Studios is shaping up to be a worthy spiritual successor to <em>Dead Space</em> &#8212; one that might even outdo EA’s <a href="https://www.digitaltrends.com/gaming/dead-space-preview-hands-on/">upcoming remake of <em>Dead Space</em></a> itself. It seems to hit all the right beats with gruesome violence, a pitch-black atmosphere, and the brand of limb-slicing gameplay that made <em>Dead Space</em> such a hit in the first place.</p>
<p>We recently got a chance to <a href="https://www.digitaltrends.com/gaming/the-callisto-protocol-preview-ps5/">go hands-on with<em> The Callisto Protocol</em></a> and it&#8217;s certainly not holding back. “My adventure through a ruined water purification facility highlighted the strengths of the game’s visuals, sound design, and difficulty that make me fear for the protagonist&#8217;s life in the same way I did for Isaac Clarke in the original<em> Dead Space</em>,” Tomas Franzese recently wrote in a preview for the game. If that sounds like your cup of disgusting tea, don’t let it slip under the radar.</p>
<p><em>The Callisto Protocol</em> launches on December 2 for PS4, PS5, Xbox One, Xbox Series X/S, and PC.</p>
<h2><strong>More games to keep an eye on</strong></h2>
<ul>
<li><em>A Little to the Left</em> &#8212; November 8</li>
<li><em>Among Us VR</em> &#8212; November 10</li>
<li><em>Tactics Ogre: Reborn</em> &#8212; November 11</li>
<li><em>Call of Duty: Warzone 2.0</em> &#8212; November 16</li>
<li><em>The Dark Pictures Anthology: The Devil In Me</em> &#8212; November 18</li>
<li><em>Evil West</em> &#8212; November 22</li>
<li><em>Gungrave G.O.R.E.</em> &#8212; November 22</li>
<li><em>The Walking Dead: Saints &amp; Sinners 2 &#8212; Retribution</em> &#8212; December 1</li>
<li><em>Need for Speed Unbound</em> &#8212; December 2</li>
<li><em>Sunshine Shuffle</em> &#8212; December 6</li>
<li><em>Hello Neighbor 2</em> &#8212; December 6</li>
<li><em>Choo-Choo Charles</em> &#8212; December 9</li>
<li><em>Dragon Quest Treasures</em> &#8212; December 9</li>
<li><em>Crisis Core: Final Fantasy Reunion</em> &#8212; December 13</li>
<li><em>High on Life</em> &#8212; December 13</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
													<thumbnail>https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/callisto-protocol.jpeg?p=1</thumbnail>
					
											<enclosure url="https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/callisto-protocol.jpeg?p=1" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
															<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3220282</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>This is how much it costs to run a smart garden, and how much it can save</title>
		<link>https://www.digitaltrends.com/home/true-cost-smart-garden/</link>
		<pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2022 10:15:11 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Patrick Hearn]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Features]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Smart Home]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Energy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[garden]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hydroponics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[smart garden]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[smart home]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.digitaltrends.com/?p=3220022</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Smart gardens are pitched as a way to cut down on produce costs, but are they really cost-efficient? ]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;ve talked a lot about smart gardens before. They&#8217;re one of my favorite smart home devices overall, especially with the rising cost of fresh produce and with winter just around the corner. I like fresh ingredients, and it&#8217;s often less expensive to grow them at home than it is to go to the store and buy them.</p>
<p>On the other hand, it&#8217;s not always easy for someone to do that if they live in an apartment. Balconies don&#8217;t always get enough sunlight (as my failed experiment to grow potatoes this year can attest), and the available yield is small. <a href="https://www.digitaltrends.com/home/rise-garden-makes-growing-veggies-easy/">Smart gardens </a>offer an easy way to circumvent these woes by controlling the light output and watering schedule and taking the guesswork out of the process.</p>
<p>But are they really worthwhile, or do you end up spending more money in the long run? I sat down to take a look at the actual costs of a smart garden, from the initial purchase cost to the day-to-day operating costs.</p>
<p>Bear with me. Many of these numbers are rough estimates, and some are simplified to make the calculations easier to follow, but the end result should be a decent estimate of the overall cost of a smart garden.</p>
<figure class="alignnone"><img  class=" size-large wp-image-3113163" src="https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/AeroGarden-Harvest-copy.jpg?fit=720%2C479&p=1" alt="The AeroGarden Harvest with a full crop of plants."   /></figure>
<h2>Smart gardens can be expensive</h2>
<p>For this piece, I wanted to look at a garden that could produce a truly decent yield. While I adore my <a href="https://www.digitaltrends.com/home/aerogarden-smart-garden-review/">AeroGarden</a>, it&#8217;s not quite enough for more than one or two salads for my wife and me. Instead, I chose to use the Gardyn 3.0 as my starting point.</p>
<p>The Gardyn 3.0 is $999 retail. That&#8217;s a <em>lot</em> of money for a smart device, but it can grow 30 plants at once and includes 30 yCubesn(Gardyn&#8217;s version of a plant starter pod) with purchase.</p>
<p>At $4 per bagged salad, you&#8217;re looking at the equivalent of 250 meals right away. The <a href="https://www.digitaltrends.com/home/gardyn-review-easy-gardening-high-price/">Gardyn</a> might pay for itself in the long run, but you&#8217;re going to feel the expense upfront.</p>
<h2>Smart gardens have consistent yields</h2>
<p>If you&#8217;re following the growing steps, you should see anywhere from 8 to 10 pounds of produce per month from the Gardyn 3.0. It can grow a wide variety of different plants, so the value of that produce might vary wildly. Add a few extra dollars to any calculations, though; since the Gardyn grows without pesticides, it could practically be called organic.</p>
<figure class="alignnone"><img  class=" size-large wp-image-3210674" src="https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Gardyn-Kitchen.jpg?fit=647%2C720&p=1" alt="The Gardyn in someone's kitchen."   /></figure>
<p>With that in mind, let&#8217;s do a bit of math. According to FoodCoop.com, a pound of organic iceberg lettuce is roughly $3.91. At a generous estimate of 10 pounds of produce each month, the Gardyn produces $39 worth of food. At that rate, it would take just over two years to pay for itself &#8212; but wait, we can&#8217;t forget the cost of electricity and water.</p>
<h2>Utility costs contribute more than you might expect</h2>
<p>The Gardyn produces so much produce thanks to a combination of automatic watering and two powerful LED grow lights. According to Gardyn&#8217;s FAQ page, these lights use about 75 watts per second on average. Following the recommended schedule, you&#8217;re looking at about 54kWh per month of energy use.</p>
<p>The average <a href="https://www.digitaltrends.com/home/how-to-measure-home-energy-use/">rate of electricity</a> in my home state is about $0.1226 per kilowatt hour, which translates to about $6.62 per month in electrical costs just to run the Gardyn.</p>
<p>You also need to factor in water costs. The Gardyn has a 6-gallon tank, and though it does use 95% less water than similar systems, it will need to be topped off about once per week when the plants are mature. We&#8217;ll say 20 gallons of water per month.</p>
<figure id="attachment_2646097" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2646097" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img  class=" size-large wp-image-2646097" src="https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/rise-garden-personal.jpg?fit=720%2C480&p=1" alt="rise gardens: personal garden"   /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2646097" class="wp-caption-text"><span class="credit">Rise Gardens</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Water costs in the U.S are about $1.50 per 1,000 gallons. The cost of 20 gallons is minuscule and hardly worth consideration.</p>
<h2>Plants cost money, too</h2>
<p>The Gardyn 3.0 includes 30 plants out of the box, and the company says they should last about three months before they stop yielding and need to be replaced. The yCube pods cost about $5 each, so a full replacement would cost $150. However, Gardyn offers a membership that provides users with 10 free yCubes per month.</p>
<p>That membership is $34 per month for one year or $29 per month for two years. If you pay strictly monthly, it&#8217;s $39. We&#8217;ll assume a two-year membership.</p>
<p>As I established before, the Gardyn will yield around $39 of value each month. With a $29 membership fee and $6 in utilities, that&#8217;s only $4 in savings.</p>
<p>That said, it&#8217;s entirely possible to make your own yCubes and grow them in the Gardyn. There&#8217;s an entire thriving community of users that do exactly that.</p>
<h2>Does a smart garden actually save money?</h2>
<p>Truthfully, not really. The amount of time it would take to pay off the initial cost of a smart garden means you would need to use it for several years before you saw any return on investment, at which time the day-to-day maintenance costs and replacement parts would likely destroy any real savings.</p>
<figure class="alignnone"><img  class=" size-large wp-image-2969411" src="https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/lg-tiiun_product-0.jpg?fit=720%2C480&p=1" alt="LG tiiun indoor garden."   /></figure>
<p>Smart gardens shouldn&#8217;t be thought of as a way to save money, but as an alternative way to grow plants for yourself. The produce you buy in-store isn&#8217;t going to be as high quality as what you grow at home, and you&#8217;ll get better taste, color, and crunch from a smart garden yield.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s definitely a luxury item. If you&#8217;re trying to cut out all unnecessary expenses, a smart garden isn&#8217;t the way to go (although growing your own produce in a backyard garden might help cut costs). Instead, think of a smart garden as a fun way to grow plants indoors and add a few more greens to your diet, rather than a self-sustaining system for growing your own food.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
													<thumbnail>https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/smart-garden-3.jpg?p=1</thumbnail>
					
											<enclosure url="https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/smart-garden-3.jpg?p=1" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
															<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3220022</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>&#8216;Wordle&#8217; today, November 5: Answer, hints, and help for word of the day (#504)</title>
		<link>https://www.digitaltrends.com/gaming/wordle-today-answer-hint-help-november-5-504/</link>
		<pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2022 09:30:18 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sam Hill]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Gaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wordle]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wordle answer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wordle help]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wordle today]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.digitaltrends.com/?p=3216682</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Trying to solve today's Wordle? If you're stuck, we've got a few hints that will help you keep your Wordle streak alive.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Trying to solve Wordle #504 for November 5, 2022, and need some help? We have today&#8217;s Wordle answer, and some tips to help you solve it yourself. But before you take a look at the solution, check out our <a href="https://www.digitaltrends.com/gaming/best-tips-and-starting-words-for-wordle/">easy guide on playing <em>Wordle</em></a> for some tips and tricks for playing daily, including strategies and good starting words that could help you solve it by yourself.</p>
<h3>More on Wordle</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.digitaltrends.com/gaming/best-games-like-wordle/">The best games like Wordle</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.digitaltrends.com/gaming/wordle-video-game-clones/">Test your video game knowledge with these Wordle clones</a></li>
</ul>

<h2>How Wordle works</h2>
<p><em>Wordle</em> is a vocabulary game in which players get six tries to guess a five-letter word. Once you enter a guess, individual letters within the word you entered will appear in different colors. Each color has a different meaning.</p>
<ul>
<li>Green: The letter entered is 100% correct — the right letter in the right space.</li>
<li>Yellow: The entered letter is in the correct word, but you&#8217;ve placed it in the wrong space.</li>
<li>Gray: The entered letter is not used in the answer.</li>
</ul>
<p>The goal is to guess the correct word in as few attempts as possible. If you don&#8217;t get the answer in six guesses, you lose.</p>
<h2>Hints for today&#8217;s Wordle</h2>
<ul>
<li>Today’s Wordle starts with the letter D.</li>
<li>Today’s Wordle doesn&#8217;t use the same letter twice.</li>
<li>Today&#8217;s Wordle uses two vowels.</li>
</ul>
<figure id="attachment_3207273" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-3207273" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img  class=" size-full wp-image-3207273" src="https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/image_adobe_express.jpeg?fit=4500%2C3000&p=1" alt="Someone playing Wordle on a smartphone."   /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-3207273" class="wp-caption-text"><span class="credit">wachiwit - stock.adobe.com</span></figcaption></figure>
<h2>What&#8217;s the answer to Wordle #504 on November 5?</h2>
<p>Still having trouble? No worries — you can&#8217;t get them all! If you just want to see today&#8217;s Wordle answer to continue your streak, you can find it below.</p>
<p>The answer to today&#8217;s Wordle is &#8230;</p>
<h3>DREAM</h3>
]]></content:encoded>
													<thumbnail>https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/image_adobe_express.jpeg?p=1</thumbnail>
					
											<enclosure url="https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/image_adobe_express.jpeg?p=1" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
															<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3216682</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Heardle today, November 5: Answer, hints, and help for song of the day (Saturday)</title>
		<link>https://www.digitaltrends.com/movies/heardle-today-song-answer-hint-help-saturday-november-5/</link>
		<pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2022 06:30:34 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Dan Girolamo]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Movies & TV]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Heardle]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[heardle answer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[heardle hint]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[heardle today]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[today’s heardle]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.digitaltrends.com/?p=3217167</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Are you struggling to guess the Heardle for November 5? Would you like an assist? Read our clues to help guess today's song.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Are you struggling to guess the Heardle for November 5? Would you like some help?</p>
<p>The ability to guess multiple times in Heardle is a great benefit in the game. The damage is not done after one guess, so there is no reason to leave the app. Read our clues and keep guessing!</p>
<p>Remember, if you need help, we have listed some hints below to guide you in the right direction.</p>
<p>If you missed yesterday’s song of the day, then <a href="https://www.digitaltrends.com/movies/heardle-today-song-answer-hint-help-friday-november-4/">you can find the answer here</a>. Make sure to come back daily for hints and help to solve the daily Heardle.</p>
<h2><strong>How to play Heardle</strong></h2>
<p>Heardle is like <a href="https://www.digitaltrends.com/topic/wordle/">Wordle</a> or <a href="https://framed.wtf/">Framed</a>, but with a musical twist. Players listen to a clip from a popular song and try to guess the artist and song title. Players unlock a few more seconds of the song with every incorrect or skipped answer. The maximum number of guesses is six, which means users will hear 16 seconds of the song at most.</p>
<p>The goal is to name the song in as few guesses as possible.</p>
<h2><strong>Heardle song hints for </strong><strong>Saturday, November 5</strong></h2>
<ul>
<li>Today&#8217;s Heardle was released in 2002.</li>
<li>Today&#8217;s Heardle is in the genre of R&amp;B.</li>
<li>The first letter of the artist in today&#8217;s Heardle starts with the letter J.</li>
</ul>
<figure class="alignnone"><img  class=" wp-image-915672 size-large" src="https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/02/woman-listening-to-music-on-smartphone-with-earbuds.jpg?fit=720%2C720&p=1" alt="A woman wearing headphones looks at a smartphone while listening to music on a sofa."   /></figure>
<h2><strong>Heardle answer for Saturday, November 5</strong></h2>
<p>Do you give up and need some assistance? Don&#8217;t worry about it &#8212; we&#8217;re here to help! If you want to see <a href="https://www.heardle.app/">the answer to today&#8217;s Heardle</a>, <em>scroll below</em>.</p>
<p>The answer to today&#8217;s Heardle is &#8230;</p>
<h3 class="style-scope ytd-watch-metadata"><strong><b>Cry Me a River</b> by </strong>Justin Timberlake</h3>
<iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/DksSPZTZES0" width="640" height="360"></iframe>
]]></content:encoded>
													<thumbnail>https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/02/woman-listening-to-music-on-smartphone-with-earbuds.jpg?p=1</thumbnail>
					
											<enclosure url="https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/02/woman-listening-to-music-on-smartphone-with-earbuds.jpg?p=1" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
															<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3217167</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Enola Holmes 2 review: Millie Bobby Brown and Henry Cavill carry superb sequel</title>
		<link>https://www.digitaltrends.com/movies/enola-holmes-2-review/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2022 23:01:51 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rick Marshall]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Movies & TV]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best Netflix movies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enola Holmes 2]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Henry Cavill]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Millie Bobby Brown]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Movie Reviews]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.digitaltrends.com/?p=3216216</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Enola Holmes 2 stars Millie Bobby Brown and Henry Cavill make a wonderful team in a fun, funny sequel to Netflix's 2020 film.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The secret to creating a good sequel is a mystery that has stumped more than a few filmmakers and studios over the years. Hollywood&#8217;s history is peppered with follow-up films that couldn&#8217;t match their predecessors&#8217; success, but every now and then, a film finds all the right clues.</p>
<p>And occasionally &#8212; as is the case with <em>Enola Holmes 2</em> &#8212; they even make it look, well&#8230; elementary.</p>
<figure class="alignnone"><img  class=" size-large wp-image-3217119" src="https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/enola-holmes-2-millie-bobby-brown.jpg?fit=720%2C404&p=1" alt="Millie Bobby Brown sits in a carriage in a scene from Enola Holmes 2."   /></figure>
<h2>Growing up</h2>
<p>Directed by Harry Bradbeer from a script by Jack Thorne, <a href="https://www.digitaltrends.com/movies/millie-bobby-brown-enola-holmes-2-trailer/"><em>Enola Holmes</em><em> 2</em> brings back Millie Bobby Brown</a> (<a href="https://www.digitaltrends.com/topic/stranger-things/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><em>Stranger Things</em></a>) as the titular, aspiring detective who often finds herself in the shadow of her famous brother, Sherlock, played again by <em>Man of Steel</em> star <a href="https://www.digitaltrends.com/movies/henry-cavill-superman-enola-holmes-2-gaming-pc-build/">Henry Cavill.</a> The film finds Enola struggling to get her fledgling detective agency off the ground while immersed in a missing-person case with ties to the highest levels of government and industry.</p>
<p>The first <em><a href="https://www.digitaltrends.com/movies/enola-holmes-review-netflix/">Enola Holmes</a></em> did a wonderful job of introducing Brown as the title character, whose clever, perceptive nature was only matched by her social awkwardness and knack for getting into trouble. Brown made the role her own, handling both the action and the humor with ease, and showing great chemistry with not only Cavill but also the film&#8217;s audience, thanks to Enola&#8217;s affinity for breaking the fourth wall and bringing viewers into her tale.</p>
<p>All of that continues &#8212; and continues to grow &#8212; in <em>Enola Holmes 2</em>, which feels like a natural extension of the first film, from the story itself to Enola&#8217;s relationship with the surrounding characters and the audience. There&#8217;s a comfort level in the franchise now that makes Enola feel like an old friend you&#8217;re checking in on, and she has a heck of a story to tell you.</p>
<figure id="attachment_3201601" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-3201601" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img  class=" size-large wp-image-3201601" src="https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Millie-Bobby-Brown-Henry-Cavill-Enola-Holmes-2.jpg?fit=720%2C405&p=1" alt="Millie Bobby Brown, Henry Cavill, and Louis Partridge stare at a piece of paper in a scene from Enola Holmes 2."   /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-3201601" class="wp-caption-text"><span class="credit">Enola Holmes 2. Henry Cavill as Sherlock Holmes, Millie Bobby Brown as Enola Holmes, Louis Partridge as Tewkesbury. Cr. Alex Bailey/Netflix © 2022</span></figcaption></figure>
<h2>Sherlock and Enola</h2>
<p>The prevailing themes in 2020&#8217;s <em>Enola Holmes</em> centered on her desire to assert her independence, and <em>Enola Holmes 2</em> has Brown&#8217;s character now struggling to ask for and accept assistance. It&#8217;s a thematic script-flip for the character, but it&#8217;s handled smartly and manages to avoid diminishing what Enola&#8217;s accomplished as an independent woman in a frustratingly patriarchal world.</p>
<p>That&#8217;s a delicate line to walk, but Brown and the film&#8217;s creative team find the narrative balance required to do so.</p>
<p>Their efforts are supported by a nuanced performance from Cavill, whose version of Sherlock gets significantly more screen time and character development this time around, but <a href="https://www.digitaltrends.com/movies/henry-cavill-superman-enola-holmes-2-gaming-pc-build/">never overshadows Brown and her portrayal of Enola</a>. Cavill&#8217;s Sherlock is just as intellectually distant and socially awkward as Enola, but he&#8217;s smart enough to realize that by being a man, the same attributes that earn him admiration and respect work against his sister.</p>
<p>Cavill&#8217;s Sherlock isn&#8217;t an overtly emotional character, instead, his sentiments and loyalties are explored through his interaction with Enola. It&#8217;s a clever way to instill warmth and heart in a character known for being relatively cold, and it&#8217;s handled with an appropriately soft touch by Cavill and the film&#8217;s creative team.</p>
<figure class="alignnone"><img  class=" size-large wp-image-3214386" src="https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/henry-cavill-enola-holmes-2.jpg?fit=720%2C480&p=1" alt="Henry Cavill reclines as Sherlock Holmes in a scene from Enola Holmes 2."   /></figure>
<h2>The game is afoot</h2>
<p>Given the Holmes-ian foundation of the film &#8212; as filtered through author Nancy Springer&#8217;s <em>Enola Holmes</em> novels, which were adapted for the movies &#8212; it&#8217;s a little surprising that the weakest element of <em>Enola Holmes 2</em> is its central mystery.</p>
<p>Enola&#8217;s adventure sweeps her into a vast conspiracy involving a missing woman, a matchstick factory, and the British government, but the connection between all the parties involved remains somewhat opaque even after the third act&#8217;s big, revelatory scene. Although Enola pulls back the curtain and reveals the villains, the narrative never quite delivers the sort of &#8220;A-ha!&#8221; moment we&#8217;ve come to expect from tales set in and around the world of Sherlock Holmes. It&#8217;s a bit disappointing, certainly, but the film&#8217;s great performances &#8212; which also include a villainous inspector played by David Thewlis and returning characters played by Susie Wokoma and Helena Bonham Carter &#8212; lift <em>Enola Holmes 2</em> whenever the narrative gets bogged down in its own mystery.</p>
<p>Fun, funny, and impressively clever, <em>Enola Holmes 2</em> is the rare sequel that not only does well by its predecessor but expands on the franchise&#8217;s world in meaningful ways. The film&#8217;s finale sets the stage for more stories to come for Enola &#8212; and Sherlock, for that matter &#8212; and gives its fans plenty of reasons to look forward to joining them.</p>
<p><em>Directed by Harry Bradbeer, </em>Enola Holmes 2<em> premieres November 4 on Netflix. </em></p>

<div class="b-media h-636693a28003b">
	<div class="b-media__wrapper">
		<div class="b-media__title">
			<a id="dt-media-enola-holmes-2"></a>
			Enola Holmes 2 (2022)					</div>
		<div class="b-media__inner">
			<div class="b-media__poster">
				<img  src="https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/tegBpjM5ODoYoM1NjaiHVLEA0QM.jpg?p=1#038;p=1.jpg" alt="Enola Holmes 2">
							</div>
			<div class="b-media__info">
				<div class="b-media__header">
											<div class="b-media__rating">
							<div class="b-media__rating-item">
	<div class="b-media__rating-img">
		<img src="https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/themes/dt-stardust/assets/images/svg/icon-metacritic.svg" alt="">
	</div>
	<div class="b-media__rating-score">
		58 %	</div>
</div>
<div class="b-media__rating-item">
	<div class="b-media__rating-img">
		<img src="https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/themes/dt-stardust/assets/images/svg/icon-imdb.svg" alt="">
	</div>
	<div class="b-media__rating-score">
		7.8/10	</div>
</div>
						</div>
																							<div class="b-media__duration">
																<span>
									129m								</span>
							</div>
																				</div>

									<div class="b-media__info-item">
						<strong class="b-media__info-title">
							Genre						</strong>
						<span class="dt-clamp dt-clamp-2">
							Mystery, Adventure, Crime						</span>
					</div>
				
									
<div class="b-media__info-item">
	<strong class="b-media__info-title">
		Stars	</strong>
	<span class="dt-clamp dt-clamp-2">
		Millie Bobby Brown, Henry Cavill, Louis Partridge	</span>
</div>

<div class="b-media__info-item">
	<strong class="b-media__info-title">
		Directed by	</strong>
	<span class="dt-clamp dt-clamp-1">
		Harry Bradbeer	</span>
</div>
				
				
				<div class="b-media__buttons b-media__buttons--desktop">
											<a href="https://www.netflix.com/title/81406219" rel="nofollow" target="_blank" class="b-buy">
							<span class="b-buy__inner">watch on Netflix</span>
						</a>
									</div>
			</div>
		</div>

		<div class="b-media__buttons b-media__buttons--mobile">
							<a href="https://www.netflix.com/title/81406219" rel="nofollow" target="_blank" class="b-buy">
					<span class="b-buy__inner">watch on Netflix</span>
				</a>
					</div>

					<div class="b-media__content b-media__content--empty dt-clamp dt-clamp-6 dt-clamp-large-3">
		
					</div>

					<button class="b-media__more" data-content-expand>
				Read more			</button>
		
			</div>
</div>

]]></content:encoded>
													<thumbnail>https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/enola-holmes-2-millie-bobby-brown-helena-bonham-carter.jpg?p=1</thumbnail>
					
											<enclosure url="https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/enola-holmes-2-millie-bobby-brown-helena-bonham-carter.jpg?p=1" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
															<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3216216</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The best superhero deaths in movies, ranked</title>
		<link>https://www.digitaltrends.com/movies/best-superhero-deaths-in-movies-ranked/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2022 22:01:49 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anthony Orlando]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Features]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Movies & TV]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[avengers: endgame]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[avengers: infinity war]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Batman v Superman]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dc extended universe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DC Universe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[deadpool 2]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Doctor Strange]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[guardians of the galaxy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[guardians of the galaxy 2]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[marvel cinematic universe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Spider-Man]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[thanos]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Watchmen]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.digitaltrends.com/?p=3195182</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[There are many Marvel and DC superhero movies like Avengers: Infinity War, Watchmen, and Black Adam that show their heroes suffering some memorable deaths. ]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>One of the most common features in <a href="https://www.digitaltrends.com/movies/best-superhero-movies/">superhero movies</a> is someone close to the protagonist getting killed off. Gwen Stacy&#8217;s brutal death in <em>The Amazing Spider-Man 2</em> and Jonathan Kent getting killed by a tornado in <em>Man of Steel</em> are just two such tragedies that come to mind.</p>
<p>Although rare, there are times when the heroes themselves get the ax. Many movies have shown superheroes die in ways both noble and tragic, from self-sacrifice to a brutal battle with the film&#8217;s villain. The demises on this list prove that being a crime-fighter isn&#8217;t all fun and games, so be prepared to cry all over again with the best superhero deaths in movies.</p>
<p><em><strong>Warning:</strong> There are spoilers for the 2022 films Black Adam and Thor: Love and Thunder.</em></p>
<h2 class="p1">18. X-Force (Deadpool 2)</h2>
<figure id="attachment_3195278" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-3195278" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img  class=" size-large wp-image-3195278" src="https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/X-Force-Death-Scene-Deadpool-2-2018-Movie-Clip-1-24-screenshot.jpg?fit=720%2C374&p=1" alt="wade-gasping-deadpool-2"   /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-3195278" class="wp-caption-text"><span class="credit">20th Century Studios</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Halfway into this film, <a href="https://www.digitaltrends.com/movies/hugh-jackman-and-ryan-reynolds-will-reunite-for-deadpool-3/">Deadpool</a> assembles a team of mutants to break Russell out of prison and protect him from Cable. But after the movie built up Deadpool and his X-Force to save the day, things take a shocking turn when members of the team get killed off one by one as they parachute down from the sky, with Deadpool and Domino being the only survivors.</p>
<p>Such fatalities involve getting hit by a bus, shredded by a helicopter, electrocuted on a telephone, ground up in wood chipper, and burned by acidic vomit. It&#8217;s a gory and hilarious scene that defies the audience&#8217;s expectations in a way that only a Deadpool story can.</p>
<h2 class="p1">17. The Ancient One (Doctor Strange)</h2>
<figure id="attachment_3195309" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-3195309" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img  class=" size-large wp-image-3195309" src="https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Dr.-Strange-The-Ancient-One-_Its-Not-About-You_-Scene-_-Doctor-Strange-2016-Movie-Clip-HD-4K-2-41-screenshot.jpg?fit=720%2C388&p=1" alt="ancient-one-astral-form-doctor-strange"   /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-3195309" class="wp-caption-text"><span class="credit">Marvel Studios</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>After a brutal fight with Kaecilius, the Ancient One is rushed to the hospital by Doctor Strange. As her body dies, she and Strange share one last conversation in the astral plane. Discussing all the possible futures she has seen, the Ancient One expresses the great potential that Strange has in stopping Dormammu, as well as how they are both unprepared for their respective fates, just like everyone else.</p>
<p>This is beautifully emphasized in how she watches the snow as time slowly passes, showing how much she wishes to keep living even in that slowed down second, with death looming over her for eternity. In the end, she gives in to the inevitable, and her death marks the final transformation of Stephen Strange from a cold man to an empathetic superhero.</p>
<h2>16. Batman (Batman v Superman: Dawn of Justice)</h2>
<figure id="attachment_3218575" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-3218575" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img  class=" size-large wp-image-3218575" src="https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Knightmare-Injustice-Extended-_-Batman-v-Superman-4-2-screenshot.jpg?fit=720%2C298&p=1" alt="batman-unmasked-knightmare-batman-v-superman-dawn-of-justice"   /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-3218575" class="wp-caption-text"><span class="credit">Warner Bros.</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>While Bruce is asleep at his computer, he has a vision of a future in which the Earth is ruled by Darkseid and <a href="https://www.digitaltrends.com/movies/best-superman-movies-ranked/">Superman</a> is a brainwashed servant of the evil god. Batman is seen trying to acquire Kryptonite to use against the Man of Steel, but he is eventually tricked and captured by Superman&#8217;s stormtroopers before being presented to him in chains.</p>
<p>After he rips off Bruce&#8217;s mask, Superman places his hand on his old friend&#8217;s chest and drives it through his heart in a gruesome homage to Superman killing the Joker in the <em>Injustice</em> comic book. Though Bruce&#8217;s death technically hasn&#8217;t happened yet, this nightmarish depiction of the Dark Knight&#8217;s demise is a haunting glimpse of what could happen in the DC Universe.</p>
<h2>15. Loki (Avengers: Infinity War)</h2>
<figure id="attachment_1363608" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1363608" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img  class=" size-large wp-image-1363608" src="https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/avengers-infinity-war-loki.jpg?fit=720%2C405&p=1" alt="Avengers Infinity War"   /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-1363608" class="wp-caption-text"><span class="credit">Marvel Studios</span></figcaption></figure>
<p><em>Avengers: Infinity War</em> wasted no time in getting to the bloodshed, as it showed Thanos and his Black Order murder half of the Asgardian survivors, as well as the God of Mischief himself. Loki feigns loyalty to his former master after surrendering the Tesseract to him, but like the trickster he is, he tries to stab the evil Titan, declaring himself to be the son of Odin.</p>
<p>Audiences had spent years watching Loki walk a rocky path toward redemption, and just when he finds it, it is horrifying to see his life get snuffed out when Thanos snaps his neck right in front of Thor. It&#8217;s a death that haunts even Loki, who is once again alive through a series of time loops that occurred in <em>Endgame</em> and <a href="https://www.digitaltrends.com/movies/loki-review-disney-plus/">his self-titled Disney+ series</a>.</p>
<h2 class="p1">14. Deadpool (Deadpool 2)</h2>
<figure id="attachment_3195323" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-3195323" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img  class=" size-large wp-image-3195323" src="https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Deadpool-Death-Scene-_-Deadpool-2-2018-Movie-CLIP-4K-3-4-screenshot.jpg?fit=720%2C388&p=1" alt="wade-dying-deadpool-2"   /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-3195323" class="wp-caption-text"><span class="credit">20th Century Studios</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Deadpool delivered on his promise to one-up Wolverine by dying in his second film. After saving Russell from Cable&#8217;s gunshot, the depowered Wade succumbs to his wounds and dies with his friends around him. Even during his last moments alive, he can&#8217;t help but crack a few jokes as he fumbles to nail his death scene, showing how he is the Merc with a Mouth to the very end. While Cable does go back in time to save him shortly afterward, it is still nice to see Wade reunite with his true love, Vanessa, on the other side.</p>
<h2 class="p1">13. Jean Grey (X-Men: The Last Stand)</h2>
<figure id="attachment_3219600" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-3219600" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img  class=" size-large wp-image-3219600" src="https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/X-Men_-The-Last-Stand-Wolverine-vs-Jean-Grey-Scene-4k-1-57-screenshot.jpg?fit=720%2C295&p=1" alt="jean-x-men-the-last-stand"   /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-3219600" class="wp-caption-text"><span class="credit">20th Century Studios</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Though it looked like Jean had sacrificed herself to save her <a href="https://www.digitaltrends.com/movies/most-powerful-marvel-mutants-ranked/">Marvel mutant comrades</a> in <em>X2: X-Men United</em>, she returns as the evil Phoenix in the much-anticipated but divisive third film, <em>The Last Stand. </em>At the end of the movie, when the Phoenix starts destroying everything around her, Wolverine snaps Jean out of her wild state, and she begs him to save her and the world from her uncontrollable wrath.</p>
<p>There were plenty of problems with this film, but it still executed Jean&#8217;s sacrifice perfectly by having the man who loved her regretfully kill her to save the world. And though Jean was technically the villain of this film, she still went out as a hero instead of her darker half.</p>
<h2>12. Doctor Fate (Black Adam)</h2>
<figure id="attachment_3218569" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-3218569" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img  class=" size-large wp-image-3218569" src="https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Dr.-Fate-scenes-Black-Adam-trailer-0-3-screenshot.jpg?fit=720%2C290&p=1" alt="doctor-fate-beneath-jet-black-adam"   /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-3218569" class="wp-caption-text"><span class="credit">Warner Bros.</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Throughout <a href="https://www.digitaltrends.com/movies/black-adam-review/">this recent blockbuster</a>, Doctor Fate sees visions of Hawkman being killed and Kahndaq being destroyed. Though the wise sorcerer believes in destiny, he eventually decides to create a future in which Hawkman survives by facing the evil Sabbac alone. Summoning an army of clones, Fate holds off the demon while freeing Adam from his prison so he can save the day.</p>
<p>In the end, Fate exhausts all his power and gets killed by Sabbac, but he vanishes with a smile on his face, knowing that he left his friends and the world with a bright future. Since his death was in a comic book movie, there&#8217;s no guarantee he&#8217;s gone forever. After all, several people on this list have since come back to the land of the living. Nevertheless, it&#8217;s still a sad and powerful demise for such a noble hero in his very first film.</p>
<h2 class="p1">11. Groot (Guardians of the Galaxy)</h2>
<figure id="attachment_3195291" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-3195291" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img  class=" size-large wp-image-3195291" src="https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Groots-Sacrifice-⁄-We-Are-Groot-Scene-¦-Guardians-of-the-Galaxy-2014-Movie-Clip-2-0-screenshot.jpg?fit=720%2C334&p=1" alt="groot-before-dying-guardians-of-the-galaxy"   /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-3195291" class="wp-caption-text"><span class="credit">Marvel Studios</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>During the Guardians&#8217; battle against Ronan, Rocket crashes his ship into the Accuser, sending his vessel, The <em>Dark Aster</em>, plummeting toward Xandar. As Ronan&#8217;s ship falls toward the city below, Groot shields his fellow Guardians in a cocoon of vines, knowing that he&#8217;ll die protecting them.</p>
<p>Though Rocket doesn&#8217;t understand why his friend is sacrificing himself to save them, Groot wipes a tear from the former&#8217;s face and says, &#8220;We are Groot.&#8221; Though Groot wasn&#8217;t too big with words, this final line from the benevolent tree speaks volumes about how he feels about his team.</p>
<h2>10. Charles Xavier (Logan)</h2>
<figure id="attachment_3219599" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-3219599" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img  class=" size-large wp-image-3219599" src="https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/X-24-Kills-Charles-Xavier-Scene-_-Logan-2017-Movie-Clip-HD-4K-1-39-screenshot.jpg?fit=720%2C297&p=1" alt="charles-in-bed-logan"   /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-3219599" class="wp-caption-text"><span class="credit">20th Century Studios</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>When an aging Charles has a late-night visitor, thinking it&#8217;s Logan, he says he enjoyed the perfect day he shared with him and Laura. But at that moment, Charles remembers how he accidentally killed his dear X-Men with his psychic powers during a seizure, feeling he doesn&#8217;t deserve such happiness.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s painful to see Xavier look back on his life and see only the mistakes that he made to the point that he seems to wish for death. Ironically, he seems to get his wish when he finds himself stabbed by X-24, the spitting image of his best friend, Logan. This certainly isn&#8217;t the first or last time audiences saw Professor X die on the screen, but it is undoubtedly the saddest.</p>
<h2 class="p1">9. Gamora (Avengers: Infinity War)</h2>
<figure id="attachment_3219669" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-3219669" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img  class=" wp-image-3219669 size-large" src="https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Avengers-Infinity-War-2018-Thanos-Kills-Gamora-Death-Scene-HD-Bluray-1-24-screenshot-e1667504710142.jpg?fit=720%2C720&p=1" alt="gamora-on-vormir-avengers-infinity-war"   /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-3219669" class="wp-caption-text"><span class="credit">Marvel Studios</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>When Thanos and Gamora seek out the Soul Stone on the planet Vormir, the former learns he must sacrifice someone he loves in order to claim it. At first, Gamora laughs victoriously, thinking that Thanos can never get the stone because he never loved anyone. But in an ironic twist, she learns that Thanos did feel love for her and plans to kill her for the stone.</p>
<p>Gamora&#8217;s death isn&#8217;t just horrifying; Thanos choosing to sacrifice her shows that, despite his dark nature, he still has the capacity for love (or what he thinks is love), and the fact that he acquired the stone proves it.</p>
<h2 class="p1">8. Jane Foster (Thor: Love and Thunder)</h2>
<figure id="attachment_3195300" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-3195300" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img  class=" size-large wp-image-3195300" src="https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Mighty-Thor-Jane-Death-Scene-Thor_-Love-and-Thunder-2022-0-40-screenshot.jpg?fit=720%2C298&p=1" alt="thor-holding-jane-in-his-arms-thor-love-and-thunder"   /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-3195300" class="wp-caption-text"><span class="credit">Marvel Studios</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>In <a href="https://www.digitaltrends.com/movies/thor-love-and-thunder-review/">Marvel Studios&#8217; fourth Thor film</a>, Jane Foster returns just as she&#8217;s battling terminal cancer, hoping that the hammer Mjolnir can help her fight off her fatal disease. Unfortunately, she learns that she becomes too weak to live with her affliction every time she transforms out of her superpowered state. However, she still uses the last of her strength to defeat Gorr the God Butcher, and she succumbs to her cancer and dies in Thor&#8217;s arms.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s heartbreaking to see Jane leave just as she returned to the franchise in a much better way. Nevertheless, she still gets a peaceful death knowing that she got a chance to be a superhero and fight alongside her true love, Thor. She also whispers her final catchphrase into his ear in <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=lpOdAHwRnXY" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a farewell that harks back to <em>Lost in Translation</em></a><em> </em>that fans will likely ponder for years to come.</p>
<h2 class="p1">7. Yondu (Guardians of the Galaxy Vol. 2)</h2>
<figure id="attachment_3209319" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-3209319" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img  class=" size-large wp-image-3209319" src="https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Guardians-of-the-Galaxy-Vol.-2-Yondu-Death-Scene-3-22-screenshot.jpg?fit=720%2C301&p=1" alt="yondu-freezing-to-death-guardians-of-the-galaxy-vol-2"   /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-3209319" class="wp-caption-text"><span class="credit">Marvel Studios</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>After succeeding in destroying his wicked father, Ego, Peter Quill gets carried off into space by Yondu as the Celestial&#8217;s planet implodes around them. However, Yondu gives Quill his own space suit so he can survive the cold vacuum of space, and Peter is forced to watch his adoptive father die right in front of him. It&#8217;s a surprisingly dark death in such an upbeat film, but it shows that Yondu did care for Peter, despite his failings as a parent, and it is only until this moment that the latter acknowledges him as the David Hasselhoff he wanted as a dad.</p>
<h2 class="p1">6. Spider-Man (Avengers: Infinity War)</h2>
<figure id="attachment_3195288" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-3195288" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img  class=" size-large wp-image-3195288" src="https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Avengers-Disintegration-Scene-_Avengers-Turns-To-Dust_-Scene-Avengers_-Infinity-War-2018-Clip-3-14-screenshot.jpg?fit=720%2C404&p=1" alt="peter-parker-turning-to-dust-avengers-infinity-war"   /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-3195288" class="wp-caption-text"><span class="credit">Marvel Studios</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>After Thanos gains all six Infinity Stones, he snaps his fingers and turns half of all life into dust. Though many other beloved heroes vanish in an instant, Spider-Man&#8217;s body struggles to cling to life as he slowly disintegrates. When Peter falls into Tony&#8217;s arms, he breaks out in tears and goes from a proud superhero to a kid begging for his life.</p>
<p>Many audiences knew that this wasn&#8217;t the end of Spider-Man, but it still doesn&#8217;t detract from what a tearjerker his death was, and it is only made more emotional by how Tom Holland, according to his <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=kRK6fAiMQM4" target="_blank" rel="noopener">video on GQ</a>, improvised his infamous line, &#8220;I don&#8217;t wanna go.&#8221;</p>
<h2 class="p1">5. Superman (Batman v Superman: Dawn of Justice)</h2>
<figure id="attachment_3195293" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-3195293" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img  class=" size-large wp-image-3195293" src="https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Batman-v-Superman_-Dawn-of-Justice-2016-The-Death-of-Superman-Scene-10_10-_-Movieclips-2-32-screenshot.jpg?fit=720%2C296&p=1" alt="superman-lying-dead-batman-v-superman-dawn-of-justice"   /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-3195293" class="wp-caption-text"><span class="credit">Warner Bros.</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>In the final battle against Doomsday, Wonder Woman and Batman hold off the beast as Superman retrieves the latter&#8217;s Kryptonite spear. After proclaiming his love for Earth and Lois, Superman flies toward Doomsday with the spear and drives it into his chest. Unfortunately, Doomsday pierces Superman&#8217;s heart with a bone protruding from his arm.</p>
<p>But this does not stop the Man of Steel, as he drives the bone further into himself so he can force the spear through the monster&#8217;s chest, effectively killing them both. Though the film had its flaws in adapting &#8220;The Death of Superman,&#8221; his noble sacrifice is both a beautiful tribute to 1981&#8217;s<em> Excalibur</em> and an emotional juggernaut elevated by Hans Zimmer&#8217;s stirring musical score.</p>
<h2>4. Rorschach (Watchmen)</h2>
<figure id="attachment_3218566" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-3218566" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img  class=" size-large wp-image-3218566" src="https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Watchmen-Rorschachs-Death-3-5-screenshot.jpg?fit=720%2C300&p=1" alt="watchmen-rorschach-without-mask"   /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-3218566" class="wp-caption-text"><span class="credit">Warner Bros.</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>In this film, Ozymandias prevents World War III from breaking out by bombing many major cities worldwide and framing the attacks on the all-powerful Dr. Manhattan. Though the Watchmen decide to hide the truth to prevent Armageddon from starting up again, Rorschach refuses to compromise and leaves to expose Ozymandias, only to be stopped by Manhattan himself. The world around them literally freezes as the snowflakes stop falling, which leaves the focus on this emotional bout between a man and a god.</p>
<p>Jackie Earl Haley delivers a poignant final scene as Rorschach, removing his mask to show his true sadness as he goads Dr. Manhattan into killing him. And when the Doctor waves his hand and vaporizes Rorschach, Nite Owl lets out an agonizing and unforgettable cry as he watches his friend die. Though Rorschach was a morally questionable vigilante, he still firmly believed that the people should know the truth and deserve justice, which makes his death a tragic loss for the heroes&#8217; integrity.</p>
<h2 class="p1">3. Vision (Avengers: Infinity War)</h2>
<figure id="attachment_3219289" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-3219289" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img  class=" wp-image-3219289 size-large" src="https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Thanos-Kills-Vision-Scene-Avengers-Infinity-War-2018-Movie-CLIP-HD-1-1-screenshot-e1667490538965.jpg?fit=720%2C720&p=1" alt="vision-wakanda-avengers-infinity-war"   /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-3219289" class="wp-caption-text"><span class="credit">Marvel Studios</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>When Thanos arrives in Wakanda to retrieve Vision&#8217;s Mind Stone, Wanda is left with no other choice but to destroy the stone and kill the man she loves to save the universe. As the Avengers struggle to slow Thanos down, Wanda reluctantly uses her magic to shatter the Mind Stone as Vision dies a painfully slow death.</p>
<p>But this proves all for naught, as Thanos rewinds time and revives Vision so he can take the stone, which ends up killing him again. It&#8217;s not often that a film shows a character getting killed twice in a few minutes, but Vision&#8217;s dual demise stands out for how it pushed Wanda to the emotional brink as she realizes that she took her true love&#8217;s life for nothing.</p>
<h2 class="p1">2. Logan (Logan)</h2>
<figure id="attachment_3195298" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-3195298" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img  class=" size-large wp-image-3195298" src="https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Logans-Death-Scene-_-Logan-2017-_-Movie-Clip-2-10-screenshot.jpg?fit=720%2C298&p=1" alt="logan-dying"   /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-3195298" class="wp-caption-text"><span class="credit">20th Century Studios</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>In Wolverine&#8217;s last roundup, he faces off against his clone, X-24, and the Reavers to rescue Laura and her friends. Logan injects himself with a serum that enhances his powers, but he is still overpowered by X-24, who impales him on a tree branch before getting shot dead by Laura.</p>
<p>With his final breaths, Logan tells Laura not to become the killer that she was made to be, putting an end to the cycle of violence that has haunted him and his family for so long. Also, after many years of fighting and suffering, Logan is finally at peace knowing that he saved his daughter, making for a tearful end to such an iconic character.</p>
<h2 class="p1">1. Iron Man (Avengers: Endgame)</h2>
<figure id="attachment_3195286" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-3195286" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img  class=" size-large wp-image-3195286" src="https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Marvel-Universe-vs-Thanos-Army_-Iron-Man-Saves-the-Earth-and-Dies-_-Avengers_-The-Finale-part-4-1-4-screenshot.jpg?fit=720%2C298&p=1" alt="iron-man-infinity-stones-avengers-endgame"   /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-3195286" class="wp-caption-text"><span class="credit">Marvel Studios</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>In the Avengers&#8217; climactic last stand, Thanos fights his way through the heroes&#8217; army to claim the Infinity Stones for himself, and he nearly succeeds in using their power to destroy the universe. But after Thanos snaps his fingers, he is shocked to see that Tony took the Stones from his hand and merged them with his armor.</p>
<p>Uttering his now immortal catchphrase, Tony snaps his fingers and wipes out Thanos and his army, only to die from using the Stones&#8217; power. Though his death is sad, he passes peacefully knowing that he had saved the universe, and he is honored and mourned by all the friends and allies that he helped bring together as a team.</p>
<p>Sleep well, Mr. Stark. You won&#8217;t be forgotten.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
													<thumbnail>https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/best-superhero-movies-september-2021-avengers-endgame.jpg?p=1</thumbnail>
					
											<enclosure url="https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/best-superhero-movies-september-2021-avengers-endgame.jpg?p=1" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
															<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3195182</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Criminal Minds: Evolution trailer exposes a serial killer network</title>
		<link>https://www.digitaltrends.com/movies/criminal-minds-evolution-trailer-exposes-a-serial-killer-network/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2022 20:37:35 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Blair Marnell]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Movies & TV]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best thrillers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[criminal minds]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Criminal Minds: Evolution]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[paramount plus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[serial killers]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.digitaltrends.com/?p=3220588</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The Behavioral Analysis Unit team is back in Criminal Minds: Evolution, and they're facing a new generation of serial killers who have joined forces.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>If there was ever going to be a serial killer network, it would probably be CBS. For the last two decades, CBS has had, shall we say, an unhealthy fixation on serial killer-of-the-week dramas. Among the ocean of CBS procedural dramas, <a href="https://www.digitaltrends.com/movies/paget-brewster-hypochondriac-interview/"><em>Criminal Minds</em></a> had a successful 15-season run that ended in 2020. After only a two-year hiatus, a new iteration of the show is returning in just a few weeks. But in the new trailer for Paramount+&#8217;s <em>Criminal Minds: Evolution</em>, the serial killers haven&#8217;t just upped their game. They&#8217;ve banded together.</p>
<iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/dMhK_IN8oIQ" width="640" height="360"></iframe>
<p>The reunited members of the FBI&#8217;s Behavioral Analysis Unit team soon realize that the serial killers were impacted by the pandemic as well. And without their usual hunting grounds, these psychos have formed their own serial killer social network. That&#8217;s putting the team to the ultimate test since this is far from a textbook case. If anything, it&#8217;s rewriting their entire playbook.</p>
<figure class="alignnone"><img  class=" size-large wp-image-3220624" src="https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Criminal-Minds-Evolution-trailer.jpg?fit=720%2C405&p=1" alt="The cast of Criminal Minds: Evolution."   /></figure>
<p>Joe Mantegna is once again back as David Rossi, alongside Paget Brewster as Emily Prentiss, A.J. Cook as Jennifer &#8220;JJ&#8221; Jareau, Kirsten Vangsness as Penelope Garcia, Aisha Tyler as Tara Lewis, and Adam Rodriguez as Luke Alvez. Zach Gilford will also appear on a recurring basis as Elias Voit alongside Josh Stewart as Will LaMontagne Jr.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.digitaltrends.com/movies/paramount-plus-price-plans-movies-shows-sports/">Paramount+</a> is giving <em>Criminal Minds: Evolution</em> a special Thanksgiving premiere on Thursday, November 24. The first two episodes of the revival series will be released on that day, to give the holiday season an unsettling flavor. Three episodes will be released weekly through December 15, before the show goes on hiatus until January 12, 2023. At that point, the five remaining episodes of the season will once again debut weekly.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
													<thumbnail>https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Criminal-Minds-Evolution-trailer.jpg?p=1</thumbnail>
					
											<enclosure url="https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Criminal-Minds-Evolution-trailer.jpg?p=1" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
															<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3220588</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>PlayStation VR2: release date, launch games, price, and more</title>
		<link>https://www.digitaltrends.com/gaming/playstation-vr2-psvr-news-rumors-price/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2022 20:00:06 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jesse Lennox]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Gaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Guides]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PlayStation 5]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PlayStation VR2]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PSVR 2]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sony]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[virtual reaility]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.digitaltrends.com/?p=3097074</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Some major questions we have are still up in the air, but there is plenty to get excited about. Here's everything we know about the PlayStation VR2 so far.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Sony was the first of the console manufacturers to really give virtual reality a shot when it made <a href="https://www.digitaltrends.com/gaming/playstation-vr-review/">the first PlayStation VR unit</a> for the PlayStation 4. While impressive for the price, there were a lot of drawbacks: Players didn&#8217;t like having to use controllers from the PS3 generation, the camera tracking wasn&#8217;t great, and the resolution left much to be desired. Despite all of that, PS VR ended up being one of the <a href="https://www.digitaltrends.com/computing/best-vr-headsets/">bestselling headsets on the market</a>.</p>
<p>Seeming to take all the lessons learned from the PS VR, as well as looking at what advancements other headsets have made, Sony unveiled the new PlayStation VR2. Initially <a href="https://blog.playstation.com/2022/02/22/first-look-the-headset-design-for-playstation-vr2/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">just a blog post</a>, Sony has slowly been trickling out more and more information on the upcoming addition to <a href="https://www.digitaltrends.com/gaming/sony-playstation-5-review/">the PS5</a>. Some of the major questions we have are still up in the air, but there is plenty of information floating around to get excited about. Here&#8217;s everything we know about the PlayStation VR2 so far.</p>
<h3>See more</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.digitaltrends.com/gaming/psvr-2-mainstream-potential/">Sony&#8217;s next PS VR helmet is VR&#8217;s best chance at going mainstream</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.digitaltrends.com/gaming/best-psvr-games/">The best PS VR games for 2022</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.digitaltrends.com/gaming/best-ps5-games/">The best PS5 games for 2022</a></li>
</ul>

<h2>Release date</h2>
<figure id="attachment_3097389" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-3097389" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img  class=" wp-image-3097389 size-large" src="https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/playstation-vr-2-psvr2-composite.jpg?fit=720%2C720&p=1" alt="Playstation VR2 hjeadset on a PlayStation-themed wallpaper."   /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-3097389" class="wp-caption-text"><span class="credit">Sony</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>As announced on the official <a href="https://blog.playstation.com/2022/11/02/playstation-vr2-launches-in-february-at-549-99/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">PlayStation Blog</a>, PlayStation VR2 will arrive on February 22, 2023.</p>
<h2>Launch lineup</h2>
<figure class="alignnone"><img  class=" wp-image-3095170 size-large" src="https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/Horizon-Call-of-the-Mountain-playstation.jpg?fit=720%2C720&p=1" alt="Horizon Call of the Mountain game still with characters in a boat."   /></figure>
<p>Sony has stated that the PlayStation VR2 will ship with over 20 games at launch. We&#8217;ve seen a handful of VR titles teased by Sony, but there&#8217;s no definite list of which ones will be available on day one.</p>
<p>We feel that <em><a href="https://www.digitaltrends.com/gaming/horizon-call-of-the-mountain/">Horizon Call of the Mountain</a>, </em>a first-party title and the first game we saw for PS VR2, is a good bet to be one of those launch titles. Other games we know are coming to PS VR2 at launch or after include:</p>
<ul>
<li><em><a href="https://www.digitaltrends.com/gaming/among-us-vr-release-date-trailer-gameplay-news/">Among Us VR</a></em></li>
<li><em>Demeo</em></li>
<li><em>Firewall Ultra</em></li>
<li><em>Firmament</em></li>
<li><em><a href="https://www.digitaltrends.com/gaming/horizon-call-of-the-mountain/">Horizon Call of the Mountain</a></em></li>
<li>A Jurassic Park game from Coatsink</li>
<li><em>Low-Fi</em></li>
<li><em>No Man&#8217;s Sky</em></li>
<li><em><a href="https://www.digitaltrends.com/gaming/resident-evil-4-remake-release-date-trailer-gameplay-news/">Resident Evil 4 Remake</a></em></li>
<li><a href="https://www.digitaltrends.com/gaming/resident-evil-village-motion-capture/">Resident Evil Village</a></li>
<li><em>Runner</em></li>
<li><em>Samurai Slaughter House</em></li>
<li><em>Star Wars: Tales From the Galaxy&#8217;s Edge</em></li>
<li><em>The Walking Dead: Saints and Sinners &#8212; Chapter 2: Retribution</em></li>
</ul>
<p>Unfortunately, it was confirmed on the <a href="https://blog.playstation.com/2022/09/16/official-playstation-podcast-episode-439-virtual-impressions/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">official PlayStation Podcast</a> in episode 439 that PS VR2 will not be backward compatible with the original PS VR. This is a major blow to the potential launch lineup for the headset, as well as the potential for those great older games to get a second life.</p>
<h2>Specs</h2>
<figure class="alignnone"><img  class="size-large wp-image-3143006 " src="https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/playstation-v2-2-boundary.jpg?fit=720%2C405&p=1" alt="The PlayStation VR 2's boundary feature as seen through the headset."   /></figure>
<p>Even for the time, the first PS VR was quite underpowered, as well as cumbersome. The resolution, tracking, and makeshift motion controls with the camera, plus the thick cords and extra box, made it a chore to use. PS VR2 flips the script by appearing to be, at least for the time, one of the most powerful headsets on the market.</p>
<p>The first major question is always going to be about cords. While we can&#8217;t untether the PS VR2 from the PS5, which is doing the heavy lifting, we at least are down to a single, slim USB Type-C wire running from the headset into your console. It isn&#8217;t ideal, obviously, but it&#8217;s still a big step up from the last iteration.</p>
<p>PS VR2 will have two OLED eye displays that each display at a 2000 x 2040 resolution, combined equaling 4000 x 2040 at a 110-degree field of view, which is higher than <a href="https://www.digitaltrends.com/computing/quest-2-vr-headset-is-dominating-steam/">the Meta Quest 2</a>. It will also be able to handle foveated rendering and frame rates of 90Hz or 120Hz. What that all means is this headset can do 4K HDR and potentially hit up to 120 frames per second. This will all vary from game to game, however.</p>
<p>Not only is the PS VR2 impressive in what your eye will see but also in how it will see your eye. PS VR2 will feature eye-tracking technology, which can allow for more immersive experiences but potentially also ease motion sickness. There&#8217;s a lot of potential with eye-tracking and how it can be implemented, but it&#8217;s still so new that we don&#8217;t really know what to expect from it.</p>
<p>Another great lesson PS VR2 learned was to ditch the external camera and use inside-out tracking. This means the headset itself has four cameras built in that make it track your movements far more accurately, without any blind spots or lighting interference that the PS VR camera had trouble with. It will also have built-in 3D audio, which is essential for VR.</p>
<p>We also learned that <a href="https://www.digitaltrends.com/gaming/playstation-vr2-features-see-through/">PS VR2 will have a see-through view</a> option that allows users to activate the exterior cameras to see their real surroundings without having to remove the headset. Much like other modern VR units, you will also be able to create your own play boundaries with the controllers and be warned if you&#8217;re approaching them to help keep you safe.</p>
<p>PS VR 2 will come with two modes: one for VR-specific content and the other for non-VR content. VR Mode gives a full 360-degree view at the previously mentioned resolution of 4000 x 2040 HDR at 90Hz/120Hz frame rates. Cinematic Mode, on the other hand, is for using the headset as a screen for normal games or media. This will run at 1920 x 1080 HRD and 24Hz/60Hz or 120Hz frame rates.</p>
<p>Finally, let&#8217;s talk about the new controllers. Called the PS VR2 Sense controllers, these look very similar to other top VR controllers in design. Each controller has a thumbstick, two face buttons, a trigger, and a button where your thumb will rest. It has the same adaptive triggers as the PS5&#8217;s DualSense controller, haptic feedback, and full-finger touch detection. This lets the game know whether or not your fingers are resting on the controller or lifted to more accurately represent gestures in-game.</p>
<p>We even got a full trailer showing how all this technology comes together to create the most immersive VR experience yet.</p>
<iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/u5L9Mvh7tAk" width="640" height="360"></iframe>
<p>While nothing new was shown, it did highlight how the display, eye tracking, rendering, FOV, and haptic feedback in the controller and headset itself will combine to fully immerse you in the game.</p>
<h2>Price</h2>
<figure id="attachment_3097405" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-3097405" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img  class=" wp-image-3097405 size-large" src="https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/playstation-vr-2-psvr2-behind-composite.jpg?fit=720%2C720&p=1" alt="PlayStation VR2 headset from behind with controllers."   /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-3097405" class="wp-caption-text"><span class="credit">Sony</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Also confirmed with the release date was the starting price for the headset. For just the unit itself, which includes the two controllers and headphones, it will cost you $550. There is also a bundle that packs in a voucher code for <em>Horizon Callo of the Mountain </em>that brings the price up to an even $600, which would be a slight discount on the game assuming it will cost $70 like a traditional PS5 game.</p>
<h2>Pre-order</h2>
<p>Much like the PS5, or any new gaming hardware, really, expect the PS VR2 to sell out very fast upon launch. Sony will begin issuing pre-orders on November 15, however you can <a href="https://www.playstation.com/en-us/ps-vr2/register-to-pre-order/?smcid=psvr2-psd:landingpagebanner:register" target="_blank" rel="noopener">register for your pre-order right now</a> to order directly from PlayStation.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
													<thumbnail>https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/playstation-vr-2-psvr2-composite.jpg?p=1</thumbnail>
					
											<enclosure url="https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/playstation-vr-2-psvr2-composite.jpg?p=1" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
															<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3097074</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Great, now even the RTX 4090 power connectors are starting to melt</title>
		<link>https://www.digitaltrends.com/computing/now-the-geforce-rtx-4090-power-connectors-are-starting-to-melt/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2022 19:55:03 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Nathan Drescher]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GeForce RTX 4090]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GPU]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[graphics cards]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nvidia]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.digitaltrends.com/?p=3220608</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The Nvidia drama just got worse as Tom's Hardware has reported on a GeForce RTX 4090 power connector meltdown.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Nvidia drama just got worse as <a href="https://www.tomshardware.com/news/rtx-4090-native-16-pin-melting" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Tom&#8217;s Hardware</a> has reported on an Nvidia RTX 4090 power connector meltdown. This comes hot on the heels of stories of the <a href="https://www.digitaltrends.com/computing/why-nvidia-rtx-4090s-are-melting/">GPU&#8217;s 16-pin power adapter overheating and melting</a>.</p>
<p>&#8220;Maybe the first burnt connector with native ATX3.0 cable,&#8221; redditor <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/nvidia/comments/yltzbt/maybe_the_first_burnt_connector_with_native_atx30/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">u/nk950357 posted</a>, along with a photo of a melted connector. The photo shows a 12VHPWR power connector from the RTX 4090&#8217;s own native power supply. This doesn&#8217;t appear to be a case of using a cheap third-party power supply.</p>
<figure id="attachment_3220614" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-3220614" class="wp-caption alignnone is-caption-text"><img  class="size-large wp-image-3220614" src="https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/rtx4090powermeltdown.jpeg?fit=720%2C549&p=1" alt="the rtx 4090 power adaptor melted "   /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-3220614" class="wp-caption-text"><span class="text">image: Ricky TO / Facebook</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>It&#8217;s been a bad week for Nvidia, with nearly two dozen reports of melting 16-pin power adapters hitting the headlines. One 4090 even <a href="https://www.digitaltrends.com/computing/nvidia-geforce-rtx-4090-connector-burns-up/">burst into flames</a>. While the 4090 is a powerful graphics card, there&#8217;s clearly a problem here. AMD latched onto it and <a href="https://www.digitaltrends.com/computing/amd-makes-fun-of-nvidia-rtx-4090-power-adapters/">dunked on Nvidia</a> during its RDNA 3 launch.</p>
<p>&#8220;There&#8217;s no need to for a new power adapter,&#8221; head of graphics at AMD, Scott Herkelman, said during the event.</p>
<p>Nvidia said it <a href="https://www.digitaltrends.com/computing/nvidia-takes-action-rtx-4090-melting-issue/">will replace any unit with a 16-pin power adapter that has melted</a>, but now it seems there are new components melting.</p>
<p>The Reddit post follows the same post on Facebook from a user called Ricky TO. Although written in Chinese, the post explains he used an MSI GeForce RTX 4090 Gaming X Trio 24G card. He chose to go with the native ATX3.0 power supply rather than risk trouble with the 16-pin power adapter.</p>
<p>If you are using a GeForce RTX 4090 graphics card, you are probably feeling nervous right now. You can <a href="https://www.digitaltrends.com/computing/cablemod-reveals-nvidia-rtx-409-power-adapter/">use an adapter</a> and potentially void your warranty. Likewise, you may want to stick to your CPU&#8217;s integrated graphics for the time being until we hear more about this issue, and any potential fixes.</p>
<p>The problem could be much bigger than issues with the power supply. It could be an issue with the RTX 4090 itself, or at least something with the quality of the components that make up the 12VHPWR power connector. Nvidia hasn&#8217;t said anything yet as it continued to investigate. This latest melting component doesn&#8217;t make us feel any more confident.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
													<thumbnail>https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/rtx4090powermeltdown.jpeg?p=1</thumbnail>
					
											<enclosure url="https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/rtx4090powermeltdown.jpeg?p=1" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
															<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3220608</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Twitter is reportedly working on paid DMs to celebrities</title>
		<link>https://www.digitaltrends.com/social-media/twitter-is-reportedly-working-on-paid-dms-to-celebrities-feature/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2022 19:50:57 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anita George]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social Media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[direct messaging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Elon Musk]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media section]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Twitter]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.digitaltrends.com/?p=3220308</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Twitter is reportedly working on another feature to help generate revenue. This time it involves paid DMs to celebrities.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In what appears to be another effort to help Twitter generate revenue <a href="https://www.digitaltrends.com/social-media/elon-musk-finally-in-charge-of-twitter-reports-say/">at the start of its Elon Musk era</a>, the social media platform is reportedly working on paid Direct Messaging (DM), with a particular emphasis on those paid messages being sent to celebrities.</p>
<p>On Thursday, <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2022/11/03/technology/elon-musk-twitter-money-finances.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">The New York Times published a report</a> in which it mentioned that &#8212; according to internal documents it saw and &#8220;two people with knowledge of the work&#8221; &#8212; that Twitter was working on a paid DM feature that would allow users to send messages to celebrities for a fee. The fee structure for this feature apparently hasn&#8217;t been officially finalized yet, but The Times did note that it could be &#8220;as little as a few dollars per direct message.&#8221;</p>
<p>A few more details regarding the in-progress feature were also shared in the report:</p>
<ul>
<li>Twitter would likely receive a portion of the fees.</li>
<li>It&#8217;s possible that these paid messages would &#8220;appear in a special area of the direct message inbox.&#8221; Celebrities would have to elect to receive such messages.</li>
</ul>
<p>And as with other in-progress features, the report also noted that &#8220;there is no guarantee that the product will launch.&#8221; Whether it launches or not, the attempt to create a paid DMs feature is a clear bid to quickly generate revenue after Musk&#8217;s costly deal to buy the platform.</p>
<p>And it&#8217;s not the only feature geared toward creating new revenue streams: The Musk era of Twitter, which began just last week, has already seen a number of proposed/in-progress changes to the popular microblogging platform, including <a href="https://www.digitaltrends.com/social-media/twitter-blue-is-losing-ad-free-articles-and-musks-latest-tweets-indicate-further-changes/">a revamped Twitter Blue with a new (higher) subscription price</a>, paid verification badges, and even paywalled videos. None of these changes are live yet, but Twitter is working on them.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
													<thumbnail>https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/sony-xperia-5-ii-twitter-app.jpg?p=1</thumbnail>
					
											<enclosure url="https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/sony-xperia-5-ii-twitter-app.jpg?p=1" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
															<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3220308</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Casting Harry Styles and capturing England in the late 20th century in My Policeman</title>
		<link>https://www.digitaltrends.com/movies/my-policeman-interviews/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2022 19:30:53 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jason Struss]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Features]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Movies & TV]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon Prime Video]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dramas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Entertainment interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Harry Styles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LGBTQ movies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[My Policeman]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.digitaltrends.com/?p=3220358</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[In an interview with Digital Trends, director Michael Grandage and actress Gina McKee talk about working with Harry Styles in their new film, My Policeman.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It&#8217;s only been a little over 50 years since <a href="https://theconversation.com/buggery-bribery-and-a-committee-the-story-of-how-gay-sex-was-decriminalised-in-britain-79597" target="_blank" rel="noopener">homosexuality was decriminalized in England</a>, but the stories of those who were impacted by the law remain just as relevant and vital now as they did in the past. <em>My Policeman</em>, a new film based on the novel by Bethan Roberts, tells such a story and focuses on three people: Tom, the titular policeman, who is closeted; Patrick, an out gay man forced to live in the shadows; and Marion, a schoolteacher who loves Tom and wants him to be something he&#8217;s not.</p>
<p>Now streaming on <a href="https://www.digitaltrends.com/movies/new-on-amazon-prime/">Prime Video</a>, the film has attracted attention due primarily to the casting of <a href="https://www.digitaltrends.com/movies/my-policeman-new-trailer/">popular singer Harry Styles as Tom</a>. In a conversation with Digital Trends, director Michael Grandage and actress Gina McKee discuss casting Styles as Tom, how the film captures a vital moment in <a href="https://www.digitaltrends.com/movies/queer-icons-hollywood-golden-age/">LGBTQ history</a>, and why it&#8217;s important to confront past mistakes before it&#8217;s too late.</p>
<p><em>Note: this interview has been condensed for length and clarity.</em></p>
<p><strong>Digital Trends: What drew you both to this project?</strong></p>
<p><strong>Gina McKee (actress, older Marion): </strong>For me, it was the dynamic of three people who are brought together in youth by love and divided by prejudice. Then, they are reunited four decades later by a catalyst. I&#8217;m being deliberately vague so I don&#8217;t give the story away. [Laughs]</p>
<p>I liked that there was this love triangle where you&#8217;ve got three people who are victims of their time, and what they do to one another and for one another indelibly marks their lives. I think that is a really rich territory to explore, and that&#8217;s what originally drew me to it.</p>
<figure class="alignnone"><img  class=" size-large wp-image-3220394" src="https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/my-policeman-swimming-pool.jpg?fit=720%2C388&p=1" alt="A man and a woman in a swimming pool in My Policeman."   /></figure>
<p><strong>Michael Grandage (director): </strong>I wanted to bring my own voice to it. I was born in England in the early &#8217;60s. The law that criminalized homosexuality was still the same as it was in 1957, when Patrick and Tom were around.</p>
<p>I&#8217;m thrilled, obviously, that <a href="https://www.digitaltrends.com/movies/best-lgbt-movies-on-paramount-plus/">the whole LGBTQ community</a> has made such advances. It&#8217;s been an amazing 40 years since that time. But I am very aware that right now it&#8217;s a bit fragile again. I think part of why I was drawn to this film was I believe it&#8217;s great to make a film where you can look at something cinematically.</p>
<p>How wonderful if you can make a film that could hopefully, fingers crossed, be seen by many young people, because it&#8217;s going to be that group that will help keep us moving forward and never allow us to move back to that time when gay people were persecuted.</p>
<p>If they can see a film that helps them understand what the law in this country was like and what it did to people and how it destroyed lives. Then I hope they will become advocates for making sure that doesn&#8217;t happen again.</p>
<figure class="alignnone"><img  class=" size-large wp-image-3220397" src="https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/my-policeman-gina-mckee.jpg?fit=720%2C377&p=1" alt="An older Marion looks at the horizon in My Policeman."   /></figure>
<p><strong>Gina, I found out that during filming, Michael showed you dailies of Emma Corrin, who plays the younger version of your character in the &#8217;50s. How did that shape your performance when we see Marion as an older woman in the 1990s?</strong></p>
<p><strong>McKee: </strong>It was really interesting. I think I saw about four of her scenes. It&#8217;s sort of like osmosis. It&#8217;s not like you can say, “Oh, it was one thing.” There&#8217;s something about the spirit of Emma, which I&#8217;ve seen in her past work and I also saw it in <strong>My Policeman</strong>, in how she observes, how she watches, and how she listens to others.</p>
<p>Those elements of her character and her portrayal were certainly useful. And they kind of affirm an instinct that I already had, but just needed the courage of the affirmation to go with it. So, it was useful in that respect. She has a very interesting way of listening and observing.</p>
<figure class="alignnone"><img  class=" size-large wp-image-3220395" src="https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/my-policeman-emma-harry.jpg?fit=720%2C457&p=1" alt="A man looks at a woman in My Policeman."   /></figure>
<p><strong><em>My Policeman</em>’s cast boasts a terrific array of veteran and up-and-coming actors. For Tom, the central character, you cast a novice thespian, pop singer Harry Styles, and a veteran character actor, Linus Roache, to embody the character. What was it about both Harry and Linus that made them ideal for them to embody that role in different time periods?</strong></p>
<p><strong>Michael Grandage: </strong>Well, it&#8217;s a difficult role, Tom, because he&#8217;s a policeman and is gay, but the law is against him and so he has to break the law to be his own true self. The result of those two factors mean that he gives absolutely nothing away and that he effectively closes down.</p>
<p>As a result, he’s difficult to read. He&#8217;s shy. He’s beautiful, but his personality is hardly giving anything out at all. And that&#8217;s a very difficult acting challenge. I needed somebody as the young Tom to be able to want to take that on, where most of his performance is placed on him by others. Because it&#8217;s about what he isn&#8217;t giving out. When I met with Harry, he understood the very shy, insular nature of this man.</p>
<p>When I was looking for somebody to play Tom 40 years later, I cast Linus partly because they share similar physical features. But it was more important for me to find an older actor who also understood that even after 40 years, Tom didn&#8217;t ever really come out of his shell. Linus understood that and that&#8217;s where the casting of those two came from.</p>
<p><strong>It isn&#8217;t easy to categorize <em>My Policeman</em>. You can categorize it as a gay love story or a movie about marriage or a portrait of England in two time periods: the 1950s and the 1990s. Gina, how would you define the movie?</strong></p>
<p><strong>McKee: </strong>That&#8217;s a brilliant question. I think <em>My Policeman</em> touches on a number of elements, but I think ultimately it&#8217;s a movie with a message that if you can find the courage to address your past, you need to do it before it&#8217;s too late.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.amazon.com/My-Policeman-Harry-Styles/dp/B09Y8GB9R3?ref=DVM_US_DL_SL_GO_AST_MYPLCMN_mkw_sWl8iyY8w-dc&amp;mrntrk=pcrid_632698891330_slid__pgrid_148806095451_pgeo_9067609_x__ptid_kwd-1670679631850&amp;gclid=CjwKCAjw8JKbBhBYEiwAs3sxN4gnmKu_XpooIPLY_pqbbkQThl6db3zMuBAyWQcsuJqza284K1NLMxoCbY0QAvD_BwE" target="_blank" rel="sponsored noopener">My Policeman</a> <em>is currently streaming on Prime Video and playing in select theaters.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
													<thumbnail>https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/my-policeman-swimming-pool.jpg?p=1</thumbnail>
					
											<enclosure url="https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/my-policeman-swimming-pool.jpg?p=1" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
															<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3220358</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Watch someone use MagSafe to save their iPhone from a floorboard disaster</title>
		<link>https://www.digitaltrends.com/mobile/watch-someone-use-magsafe-to-save-their-iphone-floorboard-disaster/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2022 19:02:02 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Cristina Alexander]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple MagSafe Duo Charger]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iPhone 14 Plus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[magsafe]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.digitaltrends.com/?p=3220330</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[An iPhone slipping through the cracks of a floorboard can be anyone's worst nightmare. But if you have a MagSafe charger, all hope may not be lost.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Dropping an iPhone through the cracks of the floor sounds like a nightmare for anybody who owns one. David Cogen, founder of <a href="https://theunlockr.com/author/dcogen/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">TheUnlockr.com</a>, lived this particular nightmare when he dropped his <a href="https://www.digitaltrends.com/mobile/apple-iphone-14-plus-review/">iPhone 14 Plus</a> and it slipped beneath the floorboards during a night out at a bar. Luckily, <a href="https://www.digitaltrends.com/mobile/my-favorite-apple-iphone-14-feature-magsafe-why/">MagSafe</a> came to the rescue.</p>
<p>Cogen shared a video on Twitter on Thursday showing the exact moment he dropped his iPhone 14 Plus through the floorboard at a local bar the night before — and everyone who attempted to help him fish it out from underneath, including the bar manager, using various tools to no avail. The next day, he returned to the bar, slipped a MagSafe Duo charger through the crack of the floorboard, and successfully fished his phone back to the surface and his hand.</p>
<blockquote class="h-lazy-embed" data-width="500" data-dnt="true" data-initial-classes="twitter-tweet" data-embed-name="twitter" data-sdk-src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">My brand new <a href="https://twitter.com/Apple?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@apple</a> iPhone 14 Plus fell through the floorboards of a bar &#129318;&zwj;&#9794;&#65039;&#8288;<br />&#8288;<br />Huge thanks to <a href="https://twitter.com/dunnadidit?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@dunnadidit</a> for filming the endeavor and <a href="https://twitter.com/ryan_kao?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@ryan_kao</a> for trying so hard to help me &#128591; <a href="https://t.co/5QlkOov3gD">pic.twitter.com/5QlkOov3gD</a></p>
<p>&amp;mdash; David Cogen (@theunlockr) <a href="https://twitter.com/theunlockr/status/1588195186315780097?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 3, 2022</a></p></blockquote>
<p>For the uninitiated, MagSafe was initially created as a magnetic charger for MacBooks that would slip out of the charging port instead of dragging the device down to the ground if someone accidentally trips over it. Today, Apple uses MagSafe as a ring of magnets embedded into the iPhone to hold MagSafe accessories — like the aforementioned MagSafe Duo charger, phone cases, and even card holders. Apple introduced MagSafe with the iPhone 12 series, continued it with the iPhone 13, and brought it back once more with the iPhone 14 family.</p>
<p>MagSafe chargers are designed to allow iPhone users to charge their phones wirelessly without the need to plug a Lightning cable into the charging port. Now, after Cogen&#8217;s dilemma, we know that they also serve as magnetic fishing hooks to help retrieve iPhones that have fallen between a rock and a hard place. Or, in his case, under the floorboard of a bar.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
													<thumbnail>https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/iphone-12-pro-max-with-magsafe-scaled.jpg?p=1</thumbnail>
					
											<enclosure url="https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/iphone-12-pro-max-with-magsafe-scaled.jpg?p=1" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
															<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3220330</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>This app put a kitten on my iPhone 14 Pro and I adore it so much</title>
		<link>https://www.digitaltrends.com/mobile/pixel-pals-app-iphone-14-pro-dynamic-island-pet-cute/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2022 18:30:35 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Joe Maring]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Features]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iPhone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iPhone 14 Pro]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iPhone 14 Pro Max]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.digitaltrends.com/?p=3219739</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The Dynamic Island opens a new door of possibilities for the iPhone 14 Pro. One app uses it to showcase virtual pets — and I simply adore it.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Dynamic Island — Apple&#8217;s re-envisioning of the notch — is one of the hallmark features of the <a href="https://www.digitaltrends.com/mobile/apple-iphone-14-pro-review/">iPhone 14 Pro</a> and <a href="https://www.digitaltrends.com/mobile/apple-iphone-14-pro-max-review/">iPhone 14 Pro Max</a>. The morphing black bar is now a tiny home for your music, timers, incoming calls, and other system notifications. <a href="https://www.digitaltrends.com/mobile/apple-ipados-16-ios-16-1-launch-release-news/">And since iOS 16.1 dropped in October</a>, the Dynamic Island is now open for developers to do with it as they please.</p>
<p>It&#8217;ll take some time for all of your favorite apps to tap into the Island, but I&#8217;ve already found my favorite use for it. Thanks to an app called Pixel Pals, I now have a tiny, virtual cat that&#8217;s always hanging out in the Dynamic Island when I&#8217;m using my iPhone. It adds zero functionality and offers zero utility — and I adore it so, so much.</p>
<h2>How Pixel Pals works</h2>
<figure id="attachment_3219688" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-3219688" class="wp-caption alignnone is-caption-text"><img  class="wp-image-3219688 size-large" src="https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/pixel-pals-iphone-14-pro-dynamic-island-4.jpg?fit=720%2C720&p=1" alt="The Pixel Pals app on an iPhone 14 Pro Max. A digital cat is chasing a red ball on top of the Dynamic Island."   /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-3219688" class="wp-caption-text"><span class="text">Look at my little guy chasing his ball</span> <span class="credit">Joe Maring/Digital Trends</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Getting started with Pixel Pals is actually quite simple. Open the App Store on your iPhone, <a href="https://apps.apple.com/us/app/pixel-pals-widget-activity/id6443919232?uo=4" target="_blank" rel="sponsored noopener">download the Pixel Pals app</a>, and that&#8217;s all there is to it. When you open Pixel Pals, you&#8217;ll see a small cat (named Hugo) hanging out on top of your Dynamic Island. You can also change it to Rupert the dog, and you can pay for the premium version ($1.49/month or $10/year) to unlock six other critters.</p>
<p>Tapping your Pixel Pal shows its age, weight, and six hearts you can fill up as you grow your relationship with it — something you do by feeding or playing games together. I like giving Hugo fish (because he deserves it), followed by a short game of beacon ball. Hugo usually takes a nap after such a big day, and I can&#8217;t blame him one bit.</p>
<figure id="attachment_3219687" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-3219687" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img  class=" size-large wp-image-3219687" src="https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/pixel-pals-iphone-14-pro-dynamic-island-3.jpg?fit=720%2C479&p=1" alt="Pixel Pals app on the iPhone 14 Pro Max."   /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-3219687" class="wp-caption-text"><span class="credit">Joe Maring/Digital Trends</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>These are features <a href="https://twitter.com/ChristianSelig/status/1570863225234923520?s=20&amp;t=rWR_aIp1BK6hoavXdC-YEA" target="_blank" rel="noopener">developer Christian Selig also added to his Reddit client, Apollo</a>. All of it works just as well here, and it&#8217;s a smart way to use the Dynamic Island without actually using the <a href="https://developer.apple.com/documentation/activitykit/displaying-live-data-with-live-activities" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Live Activities API</a>. But where Apollo keeps your virtual floofs exclusive to the app, Pixel Pals <em>does </em>use the API — letting you bring Pixel Pals with you wherever you go on your iPhone.</p>
<p>From the Pixel Pals app, tap the toggle next to <em>Always Show Pixel Pal</em>. When you swipe up to go home, your Pixel Pal flies inside the Dynamic Island and keeps hanging out with you on your home screen or in any other apps you use. You can change what your Pixel Pal does in the Island — including running, sleeping, or just chillin&#8217; like a villain. And if you pay for Pixel Pals Premium, you can have <em>two </em>Pixel Pals in the Dynamic Island at once.</p>
<h2>What it&#8217;s like living with a cat on my iPhone</h2>
<figure id="attachment_3219685" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-3219685" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img  class=" size-large wp-image-3219685" src="https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/pixel-pals-iphone-14-pro-dynamic-island-1.jpg?fit=720%2C479&p=1" alt="Pixel Pals app running in the Dynamic Island on the iPhone 14 Pro Max."   /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-3219685" class="wp-caption-text"><span class="credit">Joe Maring/Digital Trends</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>So, what&#8217;s all of this actually like in daily use? Just as adorable as you&#8217;d expect. Whether you&#8217;re scrolling through Twitter, looking at pictures on Reddit, or managing emails in Outlook, your Pixel Pal stays in the Dynamic Island throughout all of it.</p>
<p>It doesn&#8217;t <em>do </em>anything outside of the animation you choose, but I&#8217;m perfectly fine with that. Simply having a pixelated kitten to come along with me on my phone is both relaxing and calming in ways I didn&#8217;t expect. Responding to Microsoft Teams messages throughout the day isn&#8217;t particularly exciting, but when I have Hugo to accompany me, it&#8217;s a significantly more pleasant experience.</p>

<a class=" size-large-wrap h-lightbox is-zoomable"  href='https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/pixel-pals-iphone-14-pro-dynamic-island-2.jpg?fit=2000%2C1333&p=1' rel="wp-att-3219686"><img    src="https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/pixel-pals-iphone-14-pro-dynamic-island-2.jpg?fit=720%2C720&p=1" class="attachment-large size-large wp-image-3219686" alt="Pixel Pals app in the iPhone 14 Pro Max&#039;s Dynamic Island." /></a>
<a class=" size-large-wrap h-lightbox is-zoomable"  href='https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/pixel-pals-iphone-14-pro-dynamic-island-5.jpg?fit=2000%2C1333&p=1' rel="wp-att-3219689"><img    src="https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/pixel-pals-iphone-14-pro-dynamic-island-5.jpg?fit=720%2C720&p=1" class="attachment-large size-large wp-image-3219689" alt="Pixel Pals Live Activity on an iPhone 14 Pro Max Lock Screen." /></a>

<p>Like other apps that use the Dynamic Island, you have a couple of ways to interact with your Pixel Pal when it&#8217;s hanging out in the Island. Tapping your pet takes you back to the Pixel Pals app, while pressing and holding shows a larger view of your Pixel Pal, its name, and shortcuts to feed and play with it. I wish you could interact with your Pixel Pal directly in the Dynamic Island rather than these shortcuts always redirecting you to the app, but that&#8217;s a limitation with Apple&#8217;s API rather than the app itself.</p>
<p>There are a couple of other quirks to take note of. Since Pixel Pals uses the Live Activities API, you&#8217;ll see a small widget for your pet on the lock screen whenever the <em>Always Show Pixel Pal </em>setting is enabled. Furthermore, whenever your Pixel Pal is hanging out in the Dynamic Island, it makes the Island a bit larger than it normally is. They&#8217;re easy things to adjust to, and a small price to pay for such a cute companion.</p>
<h2>More of these Dynamic Island apps, please</h2>
<figure id="attachment_3219690" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-3219690" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img  class=" size-large wp-image-3219690" src="https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/pixel-pals-iphone-14-pro-dynamic-island-6.jpg?fit=720%2C479&p=1" alt="An iPhone 14 Pro Max with the display turned on. We see the Home Screen and Pixel Pals running in the Dynamic Island."   /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-3219690" class="wp-caption-text"><span class="credit">Joe Maring/Digital Trends</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>There&#8217;s not much more to say about Pixel Pals. It hasn&#8217;t radically changed my iPhone 14 Pro Max or added any extra functionality to it. But what Pixel Pals lacks in practicality, it makes up for in strides with cuteness and whimsy. The Dynamic Island is a whimsical feature by design, and Pixel Pals fully embraces that in the best way possible.</p>
<p>So many of the examples we’ve seen for Live Activities/Dynamic Island have been very information-focused — trip data for an Uber ride, updates on your Starbucks order, live scores for a football game, etc. Those are objectively more useful implementations of the Dynamic Island, and things I’m very much looking forward to using as more devs/apps support the feature.</p>
<p>But Pixel Pals also shows the fun side of the Dynamic Island, and it’s one I hope to see more of in the future. Phones are supposed to be fun, and Pixel Pals with the Dynamic Island is a prime example of how that’s still possible in 2022.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
													<thumbnail>https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/pixel-pals-iphone-14-pro-dynamic-island-1.jpg?p=1</thumbnail>
					
											<enclosure url="https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/pixel-pals-iphone-14-pro-dynamic-island-1.jpg?p=1" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
															<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3219739</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Apple TV 4K (2022) review: overpowered in all the right ways</title>
		<link>https://www.digitaltrends.com/home-theater/apple-tv-4k-2022-review/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2022 18:25:50 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Caleb Denison]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Home Theater]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[apple tv]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple TV 4K]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple TV 4K 2022]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TV]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.digitaltrends.com/?p=3217042</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Apple has released two new Apple TV 4K boxes for 2022, and while they may not look radically different on paper, they are made for the future. ]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The latest generation of Apple TV 4K is here. There are two versions, separated by several features and a mere $20, with a few key upgrades here and there. It would be easy to kind of glaze over what’s new and different, but I have a different take for this Apple TV 4K 2022 review.</p>
<p>I think the fact that not a lot has changed is among some of the best news I can deliver, but some new features, including a super-powerful processor, push the new Apple TV 4K 2022 over the top.</p>
<p>Still, if you&#8217;re considering saving even more money by buying the older 2nd-Generation version, you can learn more about the differences between the two in our <a href="https://www.digitaltrends.com/home-theater/apple-tv-4k-2021-vs-apple-tv-4k-2022/">Apple TV 4K (2021) vs. Apple TV 4K (2022) comparison</a>.</p>
<h2><b>Video review</b></h2>
<video src="https://content.jwplatform.com/videos/OLSpBqT9.mp4" data-player="zpykqaab" data-embed="default" data-application-id class="video-js" controls ></video>
<h2>What&#8217;s new</h2>
<p>To begin, let’s run down the two new Apple TV 4K products we have. First off, prices are down a bit, which I think we can all agree is a big step in the right direction. There’s now a $130 version and a $150 version &#8212; about $50 less expensive than what the last refresh cost at launch. Both have the same Siri remote, now with a <a href="https://www.digitaltrends.com/mobile/iphone-usb-c-legislation-passed-2024-european-union/">USB-C connector.</a> Both get an A15 Bionic chip, and both now support HDR 10+ in addition to Dolby Vision HDR and several other HDR formats.</p>
<p>Stepping up to the premium version gets you double the onboard storage, 128GB up from 64GB in the lesser model. It also keeps Gigabit Ethernet support (the lesser model loses it), and it has Thread networking support, which we will discuss more below.</p>
<p>I’m going to focus on the premium version in this review, because that’s the one I received for evaluation, but also because I think that if you’re going to buy a new Apple TV 4K, this is the one you should buy.</p>
<p>First off, it’s only $20 more than the lesser model. Second, as I’ll discuss shortly, there’s a good chance you might need the extra storage in the future, even if you don’t need the Ethernet port and Thread support.</p>
<h2>Powerful potential</h2>
<p>As pleased as I am that there’s a USB-C Siri remote (even though it&#8217;s <a href="https://www.digitaltrends.com/home-theater/apple-tv-4k-2022-least-interesting-features/">a bit of a boring upgrade</a>) and that Gigabit Ethernet has been added along with the <a href="https://www.digitaltrends.com/home/guide-to-thread-in-the-smart-home/">support for Thread</a>, the most notable improvement to the new Apple TV 4K is the upgrade to Apple&#8217;s A15 Bionic chip.</p>
<p>One of the chief reasons I recommend folks get an Apple TV is that the device has always offered a significant amount of processing headroom, and the A15 bionic &#8212; up from the A12 in the second-generation model &#8212; continues that trend. Unlike so many other tech devices that suffer from planned obsolescence, the Apple TV 4K is built to last. For many years to come, it’s going to be able to handle the latest apps, as well asoffer quick load times and fast scrolling. It’s going to be able to handle increasingly fancy on-screen graphics. It’s going to be able to handle updates Apple may have on its roadmap or even stuff Apple hasn’t even conceived of yet.</p>
<p>Or, to look at it another way, a first-generation Apple TV 4K released in 2017 likely still works just fine, and it&#8217;s still supported by Apple.</p>
<figure id="attachment_3217980" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-3217980" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img  class=" size-large wp-image-3217980" src="https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Apple-TV-4K-2022-Gen-3-10.jpg?fit=720%2C404&p=1" alt="Controlling Apple TV 4K using an Apple Watch."   /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-3217980" class="wp-caption-text"><span class="credit">Zeke Jones/Digital Trends</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>I have a smart TV at home that’s only a couple of years old, and it is now slow as molasses just opening apps, nevermind delays in getting a stream started. It routinely stalls on me, which I find very frustrating. You’re not going to run into that kind of issue with Apple TV 4K, because the processor is kind of a monster. I love how quick the experience of using this device is. Apps seem to launch a bit faster than the 2021 model, and they clearly launch far faster than they did with the old HD version.</p>
<h3><b>Apple&#8217;s gaming future? </b></h3>
<p>I suspect that horsepower is there for at least one more reason beyond future-proofing. Apple sent me a PlayStation 5 controller along with the review unit without really saying anything more about it. Apple hasn’t announced anything specific about any developments in its gaming aspirations, but it stands to reason the more powerful chip could deliver smoother and more responsive gameplay for games available now, as well as more graphics-intensive games in the future.</p>
<p>I don’t know what’s in store for the future of Apple Arcade or if Apple&#8217;s gaming ambitions range beyond Apple Arcade, or at least Apple Arcade as we know it today. But something tells me gaming isn&#8217;t going to be an add-on feature that just sort of disappears into the background like it did on, say, Roku (or <a href="https://www.digitaltrends.com/gaming/google-stadia-shutting-down-in-january-2023/">killed off entirely like Google Stadia</a>.)</p>
<p>It’s entirely possible the new Apple TV 4K is a gateway into Apple&#8217;s bigger, better gaming plans &#8212; or maybe even <a href="https://www.digitaltrends.com/gaming/everything-we-know-about-netflix-gaming/">Netflix’s gaming</a> plans. I can see the Apple TV 4K making it to Netflix’s list of supported devices soon, and if it does, the Apple TV 4K will be ready to take on those games.</p>

<a class=" size-large-wrap h-lightbox is-zoomable"  href='https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Apple-TV-4K-2022-Gen-3-4.jpg?fit=3840%2C2160&p=1' rel="wp-att-3217972"><img    src="https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Apple-TV-4K-2022-Gen-3-4.jpg?fit=720%2C720&p=1" class="attachment-large size-large wp-image-3217972" alt="Playing a mobile car racing game on Apple TV 4K using a Sony PlayStation 5 controller." /></a>
<a class=" size-large-wrap h-lightbox is-zoomable"  href='https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Apple-TV-4K-2022-Gen-3-5.jpg?fit=3840%2C2160&p=1' rel="wp-att-3217973"><img    src="https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Apple-TV-4K-2022-Gen-3-5.jpg?fit=720%2C720&p=1" class="attachment-large size-large wp-image-3217973" alt="The PlayStation 5 Controller being used to play mobile games on an Apple TV 4K." /></a>
<a class=" size-large-wrap h-lightbox is-zoomable"  href='https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Apple-TV-4K-2022-Gen-3-12.jpg?fit=3840%2C2160&p=1' rel="wp-att-3217982"><img    src="https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Apple-TV-4K-2022-Gen-3-12.jpg?fit=720%2C720&p=1" class="attachment-large size-large wp-image-3217982" alt="Apple Arcade splash screen on a Samsung S95B OLED TV." /></a>

<p>That’s where I think the need for more onboard storage comes in. If Apple gets more aggressive with making the Apple TV 4K a real gaming device, having enough storage to handle bigger games is going to be absolutely necessary.</p>
<p>Of course, I’m also hopeful &#8212; perhaps foolishly so &#8212; that Apple TV 4K could one day support cloud-based gaming, even if the biggest cloud-gaming players right now are big Apple competitors.</p>
<h2><b>Stitching up the smart home</b></h2>
<p>Beyond gaming, I also think this new Apple TV 4K is a sort of Trojan horse or gateway to a better smart home experience. I know that the second-gen Apple TV 4K already has a Thread radio in it, but something feels different with this new version.</p>
<p>Thread, if you’re not familiar, is part of a standard that aims to make smart home device use far easier than it’s been for the past several years. Think of it as a low-power wireless communications system that’s independent of your home wireless network. Let’s say you get a new <a href="https://www.digitaltrends.com/home/best-video-doorbells/">video doorbell</a> that’s Thread-enabled. Instead of having to connect it to your network using an app, it would just connect to the local Thread network. It’s the “thread” that stitches all your smart home stuff together. Only one Thread device needs to be connected to the internet, and then they all have access.</p>
<p>I think the new Apple TV 4K here is going to end up being a big part of that transition as it takes place. Again, this is tech that&#8217;s been built into the second-gen Apple TV 4K for a while now, but something about Apple highlighting its inclusion in the $150 Apple TV Wi-Fi/Ethernet model makes it feel like it&#8217;s poised to take off. The Apple TV 4K as a home hub is looking more and more promising.</p>
<p>Again, to repeat, you have to buy the $150 Apple TV 4K for all this Thread stuff. The less-expensive model doesn&#8217;t have it.</p>
<h2>For the AV enthusiasts</h2>
<p>And, finally, there’s the addition of <a href="https://www.digitaltrends.com/home-theater/what-is-hdr10-plus-hdr-formats/">HDR 10+</a> support, which is interesting because this basically just helps out Samsung TV owners. Samsung is the last hold-out on <a href="https://www.digitaltrends.com/home-theater/what-is-dolby-vision-hdr-for-tvs/">Dolby Vision</a>, refusing to pay the licensing fees to add it to their TVs and, instead, pushing forward the open and free standard of HDR 10+. Considering Samsung is the number-one TV brand in terms of sales, it makes sense Apple would want to serve that audience.</p>
<p>That means that shows and movies on, say, Amazon Prime Video and Apple TV + that would have been in plain-jane HDR on a Samsung TV while everyone else was getting Dolby Vision will now be in HDR 10+, offering a better overall HDR experience that&#8217;s much closer to that experience by Dolby Vision users.</p>

<a class=" size-large-wrap h-lightbox is-zoomable"  href='https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Apple-TV-4K-2022-Gen-3-13.jpg?fit=3840%2C2160&p=1' rel="wp-att-3217983"><img    src="https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Apple-TV-4K-2022-Gen-3-13.jpg?fit=720%2C720&p=1" class="attachment-large size-large wp-image-3217983" alt="The HDR 10+ logo appears on the Samsung S95B OLED" /></a>
<a class=" size-large-wrap h-lightbox is-zoomable"  href='https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Apple-TV-4K-2022-Gen-3-11.jpg?fit=3840%2C2160&p=1' rel="wp-att-3217981"><img    src="https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Apple-TV-4K-2022-Gen-3-11.jpg?fit=720%2C720&p=1" class="attachment-large size-large wp-image-3217981" alt="A viewer uses AirPods Max headphones to experience Spatial Audio on the new Apple TV 4K" /></a>

<p>So long as I&#8217;m on the topic of A/V features that appeal to enthusiasts, I feel like I need to revisit Spatial Audio on the Apple TV 4K. This is one thing the Apple TV 4K does that no other streaming box is doing nearly as well right now. The <a href="https://www.digitaltrends.com/home-theater/apple-airpods-pro-2-review/">AirPods Pro 2</a> or the <a href="https://www.digitaltrends.com/home-theater/apple-airpods-max-review/">AirPods Max</a> connected to the Apple TV 4K, with head tracking turned on, is, in my opinion, the best personal audio experience there is for watching movies. And I say this having heard some incredibly convincing DTS Headphone:X demos. Spatial Audio on Apple products, though, is an end-to-end solution that just works and is so much fun. This is the closest I’ve heard to big-theater Dolby Atmos in the home, and I say this as someone who has tested numerous <a href="https://www.digitaltrends.com/home-theater/best-dolby-atmos-soundbars/">Dolby Atmos Soundbars</a> and Dolby Atmos surround speaker systems.</p>
<h2>An end to that annoying black screen</h2>
<p>Folks who have experienced an annoying picture dropout when switching from one type of media to another will be pleased to know that a future TVOS update will allow the new Apple TV 4K (2022) to support quick media switching, better known in A/V circles as QMS. As one of many promised <a href="https://www.digitaltrends.com/home-theater/hdmi-explained-everything-you-need-to-know-news-specs/">HDMI 2.1 features</a>, QMS will work in coordination with <a href="https://www.digitaltrends.com/computing/what-is-variable-refresh-rate-vrr/">variable refresh rate (VRR)</a> to ensure there&#8217;s no &#8220;adjustment period&#8221; &#8212; manifesting as a black screen &#8212; when switching from, say, a 24 FPS movie to a 60 FPS video. Presently, no TVs support QMS, but they soon will, and when they do, the forward-looking Apple TV 4K (2022) will be ready.</p>
<h2>A powerhouse streamer, not just for Apple fans</h2>
<p>To recap what&#8217;s new: The A15 Bionic Chip keeps the Apple TV 4K seriously overpowered, and that’s a very good thing. It looks like Gaming is about to get even bigger on the Apple TV 4K, though, admittedly, that remains to be proven. HDR 10+ support brings a better experience to Samsung TV owners. The built-in Thread radio keeps the box ready to be at the heart of a smart home, and we’re one step closer to not needing Lightning cables anymore as Apple continues its transition toward USB-C.</p>
<p>That’s the case for the new Apple TV 4K, but a lot about what has endeared me to this streaming set-top box hasn’t changed and isn&#8217;t new. So, do I still love it?</p>

<a class=" size-large-wrap h-lightbox is-zoomable"  href='https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Apple-TV-4K-2022-Gen-3-8.jpg?fit=3840%2C2160&p=1' rel="wp-att-3217976"><img    src="https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Apple-TV-4K-2022-Gen-3-8.jpg?fit=720%2C720&p=1" class="attachment-large size-large wp-image-3217976" alt="The Apple TV 4K standing vertically with the Apple logo showing from the front" /></a>
<a class=" size-large-wrap h-lightbox is-zoomable"  href='https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Apple-TV-4K-2022-Gen-3-6.jpg?fit=3840%2C2160&p=1' rel="wp-att-3217974"><img    src="https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Apple-TV-4K-2022-Gen-3-6.jpg?fit=720%2C720&p=1" class="attachment-large size-large wp-image-3217974" alt="The new Apple TV 4K Siri remote featuring a USB-C connector" /></a>
<a class=" size-large-wrap h-lightbox is-zoomable"  href='https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Apple-TV-4K-2022-Gen-3-9.jpg?fit=3840%2C2160&p=1' rel="wp-att-3217978"><img    src="https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Apple-TV-4K-2022-Gen-3-9.jpg?fit=720%2C720&p=1" class="attachment-large size-large wp-image-3217978" alt="The rear view of an Apple TV 4K showing gigabit ethernet port, HDMI port, and power port, with the Siri remote alongside in the background" /></a>

<p>I do. It wasn&#8217;t always that way, though. For many years, I was <i>not </i>in love with the Apple TV 4K. It seemed overpriced, comically overpowered, and too much of an Apple fan device. But over time, <a href="https://www.digitaltrends.com/home-theater/why-the-apple-tv-is-the-best-streaming-box-you-can-buy-right-now/">I’ve changed my tune</a>.</p>
<p>I’ve come to appreciate the Apple TV, because it is reliably fast, it has the least ad-riddled interface available, it’s got top-notch cross-platform search to help you find and start watching whatever it is you want to watch, and it consistently supports the best video and audio quality available across a broad variety of apps.</p>
<p>And, yes, there is also a long list of reasons that Apple device users will especially like it, like SharePlay, Siri control with AirPods, Audio Sharing, Picture Calibration, and the ability to use your iPhone, iPad, or Apple Watch as a remote. AirPlay, <a href="https://www.digitaltrends.com/home/best-apple-homekit-enabled-devices/">HomeKit</a>, Apple Photos, <a href="https://www.digitaltrends.com/home-theater/what-is-apple-music/">Apple Music</a>, and Apple Fitness are integrated with the <a href="https://www.digitaltrends.com/mobile/apple-watch-series-8-review/">Apple Watch </a>so you can see your rings progress on-screen as you work out. The list goes on.</p>
<p>Is it the most versatile streamer out there? Well, <a href="https://www.digitaltrends.com/home-theater/nvidia-shield-update-android-11/">Nvidia Shield</a> can do a few things the Apple TV 4K can’t. And for portability, I’m way more likely to toss a new <a href="https://www.digitaltrends.com/home-theater/chromecast-google-tv-update-android-12/">Chromecast</a> into my bag than an Apple TV 4K. But on the whole, the Apple TV 4K is probably the smartest, most advanced, most future-proof streamer available that will suit most people’s needs. It doesn’t try to be all things to all people, but what it does, it does better than anything else.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
													<thumbnail>https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Apple-TV-4K-2022-Gen-3-10.jpg?p=1</thumbnail>
					
											<enclosure url="https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Apple-TV-4K-2022-Gen-3-10.jpg?p=1" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
															<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3217042</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Litter Robot 4 review: a smart, automated pooper-scooper</title>
		<link>https://www.digitaltrends.com/home/litter-robot-4-review/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2022 18:00:48 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Patrick Hearn]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Smart Home]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[litter box]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[litter robot]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[smart home]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[smart pet device]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.digitaltrends.com/?p=3219259</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The Litter Robot 4 is a fantastic, self-cleaning litter box that can help keep an eye on your cat's health. ]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Have you ever considered the potential utility of a Wi-Fi-enabled, <a href="https://www.digitaltrends.com/home/pet-tech-products-at-ces-2022/">smart litter box</a>? I hadn&#8217;t, but now that I&#8217;ve used the Litter Robot 4, I can&#8217;t imagine another way. You don&#8217;t realize how much time is spent scooping out a litter box until you don&#8217;t have to do it anymore.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s not a pleasant job. It stinks, dust flies everywhere, and your cat is utterly unappreciative of all the effort you put into giving her a good life. The Litter Robot 4 not only automatically scoops itself out, but it also bags up the remains in an odor-proof drawer for easy disposal later.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s a fantastic device, albeit a bit on the pricey side. Whisker sent the latest model to me to try out, and it&#8217;s been great &#8212; in theory. In practice, my cat used it twice, noticed the rotating of the drum, and then refused to go anywhere near the Litter Robot again. There&#8217;s nothing in any reviewer guide about how to get a cat to cooperate, although Whisker does include instructions for introducing your cat to the litter box.</p>
<h2>A luxury cat bathroom</h2>
<p>The Litter Robot 4 has an interesting design. There&#8217;s a small step in the front that your cat will need to use to climb into the litter box, and that might be off-putting to some animals. It serves a purpose, though: the step is actually a scale.</p>
<figure class="alignnone"><img  class=" size-large wp-image-3220004" src="https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Litter-Robot-4-1.jpg?fit=720%2C540&p=1" alt="The Litter Robot 4 in the corner of a room."   /></figure>
<p>The litter box itself is more of a dome, and it can look a bit smaller than some litter boxes. My cat is a larger girl, and she had to get accustomed to the smaller size. There&#8217;s a plastic tarp-like material at the bottom that the litter goes on top of, too.</p>
<p>The Litter Robot 4 isn&#8217;t small, so make sure you leave enough room for it in your home. With dimensions of 22 inches by 27 inches, it can&#8217;t be tucked away under a table or hidden. The good news is that it does a great job of blocking out odor, so you don&#8217;t have to worry about stinking up your house.</p>
<p>The litter box definitely has a premium feel to it that matches its $700 price tag.</p>
<h2>A litter of features</h2>
<p>It&#8217;s hard to nail down any specific features I could ask for in a smart litter box. It&#8217;s just not something you often think about. The main appeal, obviously, is that it&#8217;s self-cleaning; it does this by rotating the main drum and filtering the clean litter through a mesh. Any clumps and other matter are left on top of the mesh and then dumped through a hole into a bagged container in the bottom of the Litter Robot.</p>
<p>It works well, and it only takes a few seconds to clean the litter box. Sensors embedded within the waste container send alerts through the Whisker app, letting me know when it&#8217;s time to empty it out or when the litter is low.</p>
<p>There&#8217;s also a light just under the rim that lets you see at a glance whether your cat is in the box or not. As I mentioned earlier, the step also has a scale in it, and that has <a href="https://www.digitaltrends.com/home/pet-tech-buying-guide/">been a useful tool</a>.</p>
<p>I started my cat on a diet food just before the Litter Robot 4 arrived, but I couldn&#8217;t tell whether it worked. Over the first few days, each time she stepped up into the box, it recorded her weight in the app. Little by little, I watched as she dropped a 10th of a pound at a time.</p>
<p>Sensors in the drum detect the presence of your cat and prevent the Litter Robot from activating, so there&#8217;s no worry that it will empty the litter while your cat is inside. This sensor is actually quite sensitive; you can tell when it&#8217;s active because the light atop the Litter Robot turns red.</p>
<p>There&#8217;s a control panel on top of the drum that can be used to manually cycle the litter, but the app also gives easy controls. Most of the work is done automatically, and you only need to intervene when it&#8217;s time to refill the litter or empty the waste tray. There&#8217;s also an internal filter that should be swapped out every two to three weeks.</p>
<p>The app tells you how often your cat is detected, and how often the box has cycled. If you&#8217;re trying to keep an eye on how often your cat uses the bathroom, this is a particularly useful trait. After all, cats are notoriously good at hiding symptoms of illness.</p>
<p>You can download the device history from the app and bring it with you to the vet to help identify any patterns. Paired with a diagnostic cat litter, the Litter Robot can be a phenomenal tool for spotting health problems before they worsen.</p>
<h2>Day-to-day use</h2>
<p>It&#8217;s a well-known fact that cats are divas. They know they&#8217;re fabulous, and they expect everyone else to treat them as such &#8212; even when we know they&#8217;re derps at heart.</p>
<p>The lack of a clean litter box is one of the main causes of feline misbehavior, but the Litter Robot 4 nicely handles that issue. In fact, if your cats get along, multiple cats can use the same Litter Robot without issue.</p>
<p>With a single cat, most people will need to empty out the waste drawer about once a week. That frequency will increase with the number of cats using the Litter Robot.</p>
<figure class="alignnone"><img  class=" size-large wp-image-3219273" src="https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Litter-Robot-4.jpg?fit=720%2C470&p=1" alt="A cat sits in the Litter Robot 4 and watches his owner."   /></figure>
<p>I love the concept of the Litter Robot, and I think it&#8217;s a fantastic device that works great. I just haven&#8217;t figured out how to convince my cat that she won&#8217;t be eaten if she steps into it. Once I do, I will relish the lack of litter box odor and that I won&#8217;t have to scoop litter every single night before bed. It kind of kills the whole relaxation vibe I have going.</p>
<p>The major downside to the Litter Robot 4 is the price. At $699, it&#8217;s definitely not an impulse purchase, but Whisker does help offset the cost by offering a 90-day in-home trial. It also includes a one-year warranty for free, with a three-year warranty for an extra $100.</p>
<p>If you&#8217;re a cat lover, then I would wholly recommend the Litter Robot 4. It will save you a lot of time and help keep your home a bit cleaner, especially since cats typically face outwards when using it &#8212; and as such, they don&#8217;t fling litter out of the box like it&#8217;s confetti on New Years&#8217; Eve, 1999.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
													<thumbnail>https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Litter-Robot-4.jpg?p=1</thumbnail>
					
											<enclosure url="https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Litter-Robot-4.jpg?p=1" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
															<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3219259</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Apple TV+ drops the first teaser for comedy thriller Sharper</title>
		<link>https://www.digitaltrends.com/movies/apple-tv-drops-the-first-teaser-for-comedy-thriller-sharper/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2022 17:49:35 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Blair Marnell]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Movies & TV]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[apple tv plus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[john lithgow]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Julianne Moore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sebastian Stan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sharper]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.digitaltrends.com/?p=3219936</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Sebastian Stan, Julianne Moore, John Lithgow, Justice Smith, and Briana Middleton headline Sharper, an upcoming comedy thriller from Apple TV+.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It&#8217;s never too early to begin promoting next year&#8217;s movies. And <a href="https://www.digitaltrends.com/movies/how-to-cancel-your-apple-tv-plus-subscription/">Apple TV+</a> is getting a head start with its new comedy thriller, <em>Sharper</em>. The first teaser for the film doesn&#8217;t really tell us much of anything about it. Instead, it relies on the star power of its five leading cast members, only three of whom actually speak in the video. This is more about setting the mood than anything else, even though plot information is withheld as if it was a state secret.</p>
<iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/qrekjZP3n4g" width="640" height="360"></iframe>
<p>Julianne Moore&#8217;s character is the one who says &#8220;if they&#8217;re not looking for you, they don&#8217;t see you,&#8221; while Sebastian Stan&#8217;s character adds that &#8220;you can&#8217;t cheat an honest man.&#8221;  Justice Smith and Briana Middleton are only briefly shown, but they don&#8217;t get a chance to offer any lines. Instead, it&#8217;s John Lithgow&#8217;s voice that closes the teaser with some sage advice: &#8220;If you&#8217;re gonna steal, steal a lot.&#8221;</p>
<p>That doesn&#8217;t exactly tell us what to expect, although the &#8220;bad boy&#8221; expression that Stan strikes at the end says a lot about who he&#8217;s playing. Perhaps he&#8217;s the one listening to the words of Lithgow&#8217;s character.</p>
<figure class="alignnone"><img  class=" size-large wp-image-3220028" src="https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Sebastian-Stan-Sharper.jpg?fit=720%2C405&p=1" alt="Sebastian Stan in Sharper."   /></figure>
<p>Apple TV+&#8217;s synopsis for the film is not very descriptive at all, but it is all we have to go on at the moment.</p>
<p>“<em>Sharper</em> unfolds within the secrets of New York City, from the penthouses of Fifth Avenue to the shadowy corners of Queens. Motivations are suspect and expectations are turned upside down when nothing is as it seems.&#8221;</p>
<p>Brian Gatewood and Alessandro Tanaka wrote the script for <em>Sharper</em>, which landed a place on The Black List in 2020. Benjamin Caron directed the film, which will premiere on Apple TV+ on February 17, 2023.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
													<thumbnail>https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Sebastian-Stan-Sharper.jpg?p=1</thumbnail>
					
											<enclosure url="https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Sebastian-Stan-Sharper.jpg?p=1" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
															<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3219936</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>One Piece Film Red review: A colorful action-musical anime</title>
		<link>https://www.digitaltrends.com/movies/one-piece-film-red-anime-movie-review/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2022 17:01:08 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Guillermo Kurten]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Movies & TV]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Anime]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Movie Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[One Piece Film: Red]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.digitaltrends.com/?p=3219489</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[One Piece Film: Red's by-the-numbers formula doesn't quite make it stand out, but it's a visual show-stopper and loving expansion of Oda's world.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Not many longtime genre fans could&#8217;ve accurately predicted how big of a global and <a href="https://www.digitaltrends.com/movies/best-anime-on-netflix/">mainstream juggernaut anime would become</a>, and the impending success of director Gorō Taniguchi and Toei Company&#8217;s <em>One Piece Film: Red </em>is another colorful example of why that is. It&#8217;s one of the <a href="https://www.digitaltrends.com/movies/anime-we-cant-wait-to-see-in-2022/">most highly anticipated remaining anime of 2022</a>, and for the franchise creator and mangaka Eiichiro Oda, this is just one more notch in his and the expansive pirate-odyssey world of <em>One Piece </em>overall.</p>
<p>This is the 15th anime movie adaptation in the series, and while all of the entries prior to <em>Red </em>fall under the blanket term of non-canon, certain elements of this latest endeavors make continuity a little more of gray area and, in some places, allows its story to make some refreshing additions to the formula. Putting some focus on one fan-favorite character, Red-Haired Shanks, and the original Uta &#8212; along with the musical numbers she injects into the movie &#8212; are some instances of this. It does ultimately cater to an all-too-familiar &#8220;anime movie&#8221; formula in the end that won&#8217;t exactly grip initiated fans, but it&#8217;s a generally loving expansion of Oda&#8217;s pirate universe.</p>
<h2>A vibrant feast for the eyes</h2>
<figure class="alignnone"><img  class=" size-large wp-image-3219717" src="https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/One-Piece-Film-Red_12-setting.jpg?fit=720%2C404&p=1" alt="The music island in One Piece Film: Red where Uta is set to perform."   /></figure>
<p>Longtime anime and <em>One Piece </em>fans have been waiting for this film for several reasons, one of which &#8212; unsurprisingly &#8212; is what the animation studio at the helm would do in the movie&#8217;s visual department. And, expectedly, Toei Animation does not disappoint here.</p>
<p>While some of the high-octane action sequences can feel colorfully overwhelming, the film is an unfiltered and vibrant dose of eye candy that should appeal to longtime fans and newcomers alike. This shouldn&#8217;t come as a surprise for an IP as massive as <em>One Piece</em>, especially since the studios on the TV side of these properties often tend to take the reigns of the cinematic adaptations as well.</p>
<p>Other anime movies released this year, namely <em>Dragon Ball Super: Super Hero </em>and <a href="https://www.digitaltrends.com/movies/jujutsu-kaisen-0-anime-movie-review/"><em>Jujutsu Kaisen 0</em></a>, have upped their respective games in flexing the potential of animation as a medium, but <em>One Piece Film: Red </em>can comfortably and proudly stand alongside them with the studio&#8217;s achievements.</p>
<figure class="alignnone"><img  class=" size-large wp-image-3219737" src="https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/One-Piece-Film-Red-Uta.jpg?fit=720%2C404&p=1" alt="Uta wearing a flashy costume for her on-stage performance."   /></figure>
<p>The whole of this franchise&#8217;s universe can be succinctly described as &#8220;colorful&#8221; and &#8220;vibrant,&#8221; but the expanded scope in <em>Red </em>certainly shows, including in the art direction and character designs. Elegia &#8212; the Island of Music where the story predominantly takes place &#8212; feels about as unique as any of the settings found within the manga source material or the TV anime adaptation, which is as high a compliment as any for a semi-out-of-continuity original story.</p>
<p>Oda was credited as being very closely involved in the production of the movie compared to past entries, and that certainly also shows in the character designs. This goes for the various flashy wardrobes the main and supporting cast sport throughout the movie but, more importantly, goes for the movie&#8217;s new star attraction in the form of Uta.</p>
<p>Nonetheless, nothing and no one goes unnoticed no matter how long (or briefly) they appear.</p>
<h2>Welcome new character spotlights</h2>
<figure class="alignnone"><img  class=" size-large wp-image-3219889" src="https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/One-Piece-Film-Red_2.jpg?fit=720%2C404&p=1" alt="Red-Haired Shanks in One Piece Film: Red."   /></figure>
<p>Eiichiro Oda has assured fans since <em>One Piece</em>&#8216;s inception that the Straw Hat Pirates would be universally beloved, but the biggest selling points of <em>Red </em>are Red-Haired Shanks and the aforementioned Uta. The former has been generally elusive in the source material&#8217;s world, so his getting any kind of focused attention in a feature film was always going to be a plus.</p>
<p>Uta is mostly the star of the show in this movie, though, and the Grand Line&#8217;s resident J-Pop idol is as suitably larger-than-life as longtime fans would want to see in a fresh face within the <em>One Piece </em>world.</p>
<figure class="alignnone"><img  class=" size-large wp-image-3219890" src="https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/One-Piece-Film-Red_14.jpg?fit=720%2C404&p=1" alt="Uta on stage in One Piece Film: Red."   /></figure>
<p>And, in a somewhat refreshing change of pace as far as the movies go, the story does a decent job of showcasing a plot that has a little more emotional resonance with the main cast than normal. That&#8217;s what partly paves the way for the movie&#8217;s most inventive aspect: the musical numbers.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s a fun way to work in an otherwise atypical subgenre <a href="https://www.digitaltrends.com/movies/best-shounen-action-anime-tv-film-2022/">for action-shounen anime</a>, and Uta&#8217;s voice for the singing segments &#8212; Ado &#8212; does an excellent job performing the various upbeat songs in the movie.</p>
<p>Though, for some, this could give mixed results. As endlessly and wonderfully bizarre as this universe is, these musical numbers slightly hold back the pacing of the plot. It isn&#8217;t a dealbreaker, but as much as anime fans take to the music used in anime openings and endings, the frequency and length of the numbers give the story a stop-and-go pace in places.</p>
<h2>An admittedly formulaic structure</h2>
<figure class="alignnone"><img  class=" size-large wp-image-3219896" src="https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/One-Piece-Film-Red_8.jpg?fit=720%2C404&p=1" alt="Uta with Luffy on stage in One Piece Film: Red."   /></figure>
<p>Even with crowd-pleasers like Shanks and Uta, though, <em>Red </em>doesn&#8217;t exactly have too much that makes it stand out in an already packed crowd of big-budget anime movies.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s great to see anime movies, in addition to the primary TV medium, get more international box office recognition, but it&#8217;s hard not to admit that cinematic adaptations of big-time anime IPs (like <em>Dragon Ball</em>) follow fairly by-the-numbers plot structure.</p>
<p>The emotional investment between the main cast makes things a little more interesting than normal, but it still doesn&#8217;t escape the template of the almost nonsensically high-stakes climax that&#8217;s tough to get too invested in, knowing that the conflicts in these movies are almost always standalone. Similarly, the biggest spectacles in these kinds of movies always cram in more characters than the screen can handle just to sell everyone&#8217;s favorite side characters five seconds of fame.</p>
<p>Nonetheless, <em>Red </em>is an overall good and <a href="https://www.digitaltrends.com/movies/best-anime-on-amazon-prime-video/">entertaining anime romp</a> that&#8217;ll satisfy longtime fans even if it&#8217;s nothing groundbreaking and is also fairly safe for prospective fans curious to see what this sprawling pirate fantasy is all about.</p>
<p><em>Toei Company&#8217;s </em>One Piece Film: Red <em>is now playing in theaters.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
													<thumbnail>https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/One-Piece-Film-Red.jpg?p=1</thumbnail>
					
											<enclosure url="https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/One-Piece-Film-Red.jpg?p=1" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
															<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3219489</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Legend of Zelda: Tears of the Kingdom release date, trailers, gameplay, and more</title>
		<link>https://www.digitaltrends.com/gaming/breath-of-the-wild-2-release-date-trailer-story-news/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2022 17:00:37 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jon Bitner]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Gaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Breath of the wild 2]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nintendo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Legend of Zelda: Breath of the Wild]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Legend of Zelda: Tears of the Kingdom]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[upcoming games]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.digitaltrends.com/?p=2499244</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[From playable characters and returning enemies to the release date and storyline, here is everything we know — and don't know — about Tears of the Kingdom.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>When Nintendo released the teaser trailer for <em>Breath of the Wild 2</em> several years ago, it unleashed a whirlwind of rumors and speculation about a sequel to one of the <a href="https://www.digitaltrends.com/gaming/best-zelda-games/">best Zelda games</a>. As the dust started to settle, a few things were made clear &#8212; but much remained up in the air. Nintendo is notoriously scarce with information regarding first-party titles, and that holds true for this much-anticipated sequel.</p>
<p>Thankfully, Nintendo has given us a few new glimpses into what we now know will be called <em>The Legend of Zelda: Tears of the Kingdom</em>. Eagle-eyed viewers have been able to piece together a lot of the clues seen in the announcement trailer, and the latest gameplay reveal has plenty of other hidden secrets for us to decode. Plus, we&#8217;ve heard a few things directly from the legendary game designer Eiji Aonuma, which has only added fuel to the fire.</p>
<p>From playable characters and returning enemies to the release date and storyline, here&#8217;s everything we know &#8212; and don&#8217;t know &#8212; about <em>The Legend of Zelda: Tears of the Kingdom</em>.</p>
<p><strong>Further reading</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.digitaltrends.com/gaming/upcoming-switch-games/">The best upcoming Nintendo Switch games</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.digitaltrends.com/gaming/things-we-want-in-legend-of-zelda-breath-of-the-wild-2/">10 things we want in Breath of the Wild 2</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.digitaltrends.com/gaming/botw-2-shouldnt-release-switch/">Zelda: Breath of the Wild 2 should wait for a Switch Pro</a></li>
</ul>
<h2>Release date</h2>
<figure class="alignnone"><img  class=" wp-image-3178118 size-large" src="https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/tok.jpg?fit=720%2C720&p=1" alt="Link flying through air in The Legend of Zelda: Tears of the Kingdom."   /></figure>
<p><em>The Legend of Zelda: Tears of the Kingdom </em>is set to launch on May 12, 2023.</p>
<p><em>The Legend of Zelda: Tears of the Kingdom</em> was set for a 2022 release during Nintendo&#8217;s E3 2021 keynote, but as of March 2022, series producer Eiji Aonuma announced that the game would be delayed until 2023. His statement on the matter was, &#8220;For those of you who have been looking forward to a release this year, we apologize. As previously announced, the adventure in this sequel will take place not just on the ground as in the previous game, but also in the skies above. However, the expanded world goes beyond that, and there will be an even wider variety of features you can enjoy, including new encounters and gameplay elements. In order to make this game’s experience something special, the entire development team is continuing to work diligently on this game, so please wait a while longer.”</p>
<h2>Platforms</h2>
<figure class="alignnone"><img  class=" wp-image-3029536 size-large" src="https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/the-legend-of-zelda-breath-of-the-wild-2-link-master-sword-wood.jpg?fit=720%2C404&p=1" alt="Link holds a corrupted version of the Master Sword in the sequel to The Legend of Zelda: Breath of the Wild."   /></figure>
<p><em>The Legend of Zelda: Tears of the Kingdom</em> will only be available on Nintendo Switch. Nintendo isn&#8217;t keen on porting its high-performing first-party titles to other consoles, and we don&#8217;t expect that trend to change when <em>Tears </em>is eventually released.</p>
<p>And despite the launch of the <a href="https://www.digitaltrends.com/gaming/nintendo-switch-oled-review/">Switch OLED model,</a> rumors continue to swirl about<a href="https://www.digitaltrends.com/gaming/botw-2-shouldnt-release-switch/"> a potential Switch Pro Console</a> &#8212; and it&#8217;ll be interesting to see if <em>The Legend of Zelda: Tears of the Kingdom</em> coincides with the launch of a &#8220;next-gen&#8221; Switch. With <em>Hyrule Warriors</em> pushing the system to its limits, there&#8217;s no doubt <em>The Legend of Zelda: Tears of the Kingdom</em> could benefit from some upgraded hardware.</p>
<h2>Trailers</h2>
<p>Nintendo has released three trailers for <em>The Legend of Zelda: Tears of the Kingdom</em> &#8212; a brief reveal trailer, a short gameplay trailer announced during E3, and the latest during a Nintendo Direct in 2022.</p>
<iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/3fr1Z07AV00" width="640" height="360"></iframe>
<p>The gameplay trailer is particularly interesting, as it shows a variety of new mechanics, including some that look to be borrowed from <em>Skyward Sword</em>.</p>
<iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Pi-MRZBP91I" width="640" height="360"></iframe>
<iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/2SNF4M_v7wc" width="640" height="360"></iframe>
<p>This latest trailer was still very brief but starts off showing some ancient carvings before revealing Link opening a massive door, rushing out onto a floating platform, and fearlessly diving off. He lands on some sort of flying device before the title is revealed. Originally, Nintendo withheld revealing the official title for <em>The Legend of Zelda: Tears of the Kingdom</em> due to it spoiling aspects of the story. This has led to tons of fan speculation and theory-crafting, such as Ganon&#8217;s corpse rising from Hyrule Castle, the return of Malice, and even connections to <em>The Legend of Zelda: Twilight Princess. </em></p>
<p>While there&#8217;s no consensus on hard details, most agree this will be a much darker game than the first.</p>
<h2>Gameplay</h2>
<figure class="alignnone"><img  class="size-large wp-image-2721152 " src="https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/breath-of-the-wild-2.jpg?fit=720%2C397&p=1" alt="Link is surrounded by magic in The Legend of Zelda: Breath of the Wild 2."   /></figure>
<p>While there&#8217;s a lot we don&#8217;t know about <em>The Legend of Zelda: Tears of the Kingdom</em>&#8216;s gameplay, we&#8217;re pretty confident that players will be returning to the Hyrule seen in the original <em>Breath of the Wild</em>. Eiji Aonuma said that he would love to visit the world again and introduce new gameplay concepts alongside a new story. He later went on to say that <em>The Legend of Zelda: Tears of the Kingdom</em> will indeed be a <a href="https://www.gameinformer.com/e3-2019/2019/06/11/breath-of-the-wilds-director-is-returning-for-the-sequel">&#8220;continuation&#8221; of the original</a>, meaning we should expect to see more of the Hyrule we&#8217;ve come to know and love over the past few years.</p>
<p>The latest E3 trailer confirmed much of that statement &#8212; although we now have a bunch of floating islands in the sky we&#8217;ll be able to explore. It&#8217;s unclear if these locations will be easily accessible while roaming around on the ground or if they&#8217;ll be set in a completely different timeline &#8212; similar to the young and adult Link variants seen in <em>Ocarina of Time</em>.</p>
<p>One thing everyone picked up from the reveal trailer is the fact that this entry is looking to be a much darker adventure than its predecessor. Aonuma went on to confirm this, saying the entry will be similar to <em>The Legend of Zelda: </em><em>Majora&#8217;s Mask</em> in tone &#8212; easily the darkest and most disturbing game in the series. How exactly that will play out is unknown. However, it&#8217;s been confirmed that <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/2019/06/11/zelda-breath-of-the-wild-sequel-is-not-related-to-majoras-mask">it will <em>not</em> tie into <em>Majora&#8217;s Mask</em></a> in any way. It might be going for a similar aesthetic, but that doesn&#8217;t mean any story elements from the hit Nintendo 64 title will make an appearance.</p>
<p>Apparently, the driving factor for making a <em>Breath of the Wild</em> sequel came from the development team conjuring up too many DLC ideas. While DLC works to add small changes to a game &#8212; it essentially functions as an expansion &#8212; you&#8217;re often limited to the existing structure of the title. Aonuma said that the team had some big changes they wanted to implement, but they <a href="https://www.gameinformer.com/e3-2019/2019/06/11/breath-of-the-wilds-director-is-returning-for-the-sequel">couldn&#8217;t do this using DLC</a>. As time went on and more ideas began percolating, it became clear that a new game was the only way to make these a reality.</p>
<figure class="alignnone"><img  class=" wp-image-2620504 size-large" src="https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/breath-of-the-wild-2-zelda-and-link.jpg?fit=720%2C720&p=1" alt="Zelda and Link exploring a cave."   /></figure>
<p>As soon as the trailer was revealed at E3 2019, the internet exploded with rumors and speculation. Not all of it is reliable, but we&#8217;ve compiled a list of the most realistic rumblings. Nintendo hasn&#8217;t commented either way about the following claims, so it&#8217;s possible that some of these great ideas might make it into the final product:</p>
<ul>
<li>The reveal trailer shows Link and Zelda exploring some sort of underground chamber, but Zelda looks markedly different than we remember. Her hair has been cut short into a type of bob, and fans are speculating that&#8217;s because she will be a playable character. Shorter hair has less of a chance of clipping into other objects and makes it easier to pull off a clean look without any janky animation. We&#8217;re not sure how likely this is &#8212; but we can&#8217;t deny it would be great to run around Hyrule as someone other than Link.</li>
<li>Watching Link and Zelda together in the reveal trailer gave some fans the impression that this might be a co-op title. Aonuma was asked about this possibility and didn&#8217;t give a direct answer. While it probably won&#8217;t be the driving force of the game, we&#8217;re hopeful that you&#8217;ll be able to partner up with a friend this time around.</li>
<li>Several cave paintings seem to reference a time before the Calamity occurred. Does this mean the title could be a prequel to the original?</li>
<li>Traditional dungeons might make a return. Since players are already familiar with the map of Hyrule, it makes sense that new locations will have to be underground or indoors.</li>
<li>Ganondorf is the most likely villain, as he fits the appearance of the slumped-over corpse seen in the trailer. Some are also speculating that Zant, one of the antagonists of <em>The Legend of Zelda: Twilight Princess</em>, might also make a return, but there isn&#8217;t much evidence to back up this claim.</li>
</ul>
<p>As for the E3 2021 gameplay trailer, we saw Link with a few new tricks &#8212; such as the ability to teleport through solid objects and a deadly new gauntlet &#8212; and it confirmed that much of <em>The Legend of Zelda: Tears of the Kingdom</em> won&#8217;t stray too far from the original title. Speculation is already swirling about how Link, Zelda, and Ganon all fit into the picture, but for now, it&#8217;s just a bunch of fan theories, regardless of how intriguing they may be. Until Nintendo gives us some more concrete details, we&#8217;ll leave the guesswork up to internet sleuths.</p>
<p>The newest 2022 trailer shows off new ways to interact with objects to raise directly up into the sky environments by rewinding time.</p>
<h2>Multiplayer</h2>
<figure class="alignnone"><img  class="size-large wp-image-2619751 " src="https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/pull-out-sword.jpg?fit=720%2C405&p=1" alt="Link with the Master Sword in The Legend of Zelda: Breath of the Wild."   /></figure>
<p>The game is rumored to include co-op &#8212; but that&#8217;s only because fans saw Link and Zelda exploring together in the reveal trailer. Nothing is official yet, although offering co-op would be a massive change when compared to <em>Breath of the Wild</em>.</p>
<h2>Preorder</h2>
<p>It&#8217;s still a long way off, but you can preorder <em>The Legend of Zelda: Tears of the Kingdom</em> on <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Legend-Zelda-Breath-Wild-Nintendo-Switch/dp/B097B2YWFX/ref=sr_1_2?keywords=zelda+breath+of+the+wild+2+nintendo+switch&amp;qid=1645012500&amp;sprefix=zelda+breth+of+the+wild+2%2Caps%2C220&amp;sr=8-2&amp;tag=nlife-20" target="_blank" rel="sponsored noopener">Amazon</a> and <a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/the-legend-of-zelda-tears-of-the-kingdom-nintendo-switch/6464080.p?acampID=0&amp;cmp=RMX&amp;irclickid=y4yyXHwMOxyNRmTzS82UByWnUkDXyhSFzW3FV00&amp;irgwc=1&amp;loc=Narrativ+Campaign&amp;mpid=3139288&amp;ref=198&amp;skuId=6464080" target="_blank" rel="sponsored noopener">Best Buy</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
													<thumbnail>https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/zelborg-new.jpg?p=1</thumbnail>
					
											<enclosure url="https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/zelborg-new.jpg?p=1" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
															<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2499244</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>More Ratchet and Clank games are joining PlayStation Plus Premium</title>
		<link>https://www.digitaltrends.com/gaming/ratchet-and-clank-20th-anniversary/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2022 16:05:44 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[George Yang]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Gaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Insomniac Games]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Playstation 3]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ratchet and Clank: Rift Apart]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.digitaltrends.com/?p=3220273</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[To celebrate the 20th anniversary of the Ratchet and Clank franchise, Sony is adding more games from its PS3 era to the PlayStation Plus Premium service.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>To celebrate the 20th anniversary of Insomniac&#8217;s Ratchet &amp; Clank franchise, Sony <a href="https://blog.playstation.com/2022/11/04/celebrating-20-years-of-ratchet-clank/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">announced</a> that it is adding five new games from its PlayStation 3 era to the PlayStation Plus Premium subscription service on November 15.</p>
<p>A few Ratchet &amp; Clank games were already available on Sony&#8217;s revamped PS Plus service, but the update expands that list out significantly. Here&#8217;s the full list of games coming to the service.</p>
<ul>
<li><em>Ratchet &amp; Clank </em>(PS3)</li>
<li><em>Ratchet &amp; Clank: Going Commando</em></li>
<li><em>Ratchet &amp; Clank: Up Your Arsenal</em></li>
<li><em>Ratchet &amp; Clank: Deadlocked</em></li>
<li><em>Ratchet &amp; Clank Future: Tools of Destruction</em></li>
</ul>
<p>It&#8217;s worth noting that PlayStation 3 games can only be <a href="https://www.digitaltrends.com/gaming/best-games-on-playstation-plus-ps-extra-premium/">streamed from the PlayStation Plus Premium</a> service, not downloaded directly like how Xbox Game Pass games can operate.</p>
<p>Additionally, the PlayStation 5 game <em>Ratchet &amp; Clank: Rift Apart</em> will receive a free 20th-anniversary armor pack today. It contains five armors that are inspired by different games in the franchise. The Commando Armor is inspired by <em>Going Commando</em>, Holoflux Armor inspired by <em>Ratchet &amp; Clank Future: A Crack in Time</em>, Quest Armor inspired by <em>Ratchet &amp; Clank: Quest for Booty</em>, Marauder Armor inspired by <em>Deadlocked</em>, and a Clank armor inspired by Ratchet&#8217;s robot companion.</p>
<blockquote class="h-lazy-embed" data-width="500" data-dnt="true" data-initial-classes="twitter-tweet" data-embed-name="twitter" data-sdk-src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">Today, we&rsquo;re celebrating 20 years of travel across space, time and dimensions with Ratchet &amp;amp; Clank!</p>
<p>Details on the anniversary Armor Pack for Rift Apart, and classic games from the series coming to PlayStation Plus Premium: <a href="https://t.co/1BVEaFbdk5">https://t.co/1BVEaFbdk5</a> <a href="https://t.co/cMCQRGsWmk">pic.twitter.com/cMCQRGsWmk</a></p>
<p>&amp;mdash; PlayStation (@PlayStation) <a href="https://twitter.com/PlayStation/status/1588546848976797697?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 4, 2022</a></p></blockquote>
<p>The first <em>Ratchet &amp; Clank</em> game launched in 2002 for the PlayStation 2 when Insomniac was still an independent developer. The studio is best known for working on the Ratchet &amp; Clank and Spyro franchises. It also developed the PlayStation-exclusive first-person shooter series, Resistance. Insomniac created one Microsoft exclusive, <em>Sunset Overdrive</em>, for Xbox One and PC. Nowadays, Insomniac is most well-known for <em>Marvel&#8217;s Spider-Man</em> and <em>Marvel&#8217;s Spider-Man: Miles Morales</em> for PS4 and PS5.</p>
<p>Currently, Insomniac is working on <em>Marvel&#8217;s Spider-Man 2</em> and a <a href="https://www.digitaltrends.com/gaming/marvels-wolverine-release-date-trailer-gameplay-news/">new <em>Wolverine</em> game</a>. The former is slated to release <a href="https://www.digitaltrends.com/gaming/spider-man-2-reveal/">sometime in 2023</a> while the latter hasn&#8217;t received a definitive release window yet.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
													<thumbnail>https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/ratchet-and-clank.jpg?p=1</thumbnail>
					
											<enclosure url="https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/ratchet-and-clank.jpg?p=1" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
															<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3220273</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The dream isn&#8217;t over &#8212; AMD&#8217;s RX 7900 XTX may still hit 3GHz</title>
		<link>https://www.digitaltrends.com/computing/amd-radeon-rx-7900-xtx-clock-speed-may-go-up/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2022 15:23:15 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Monica J. White]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AMD Radeon RX 7900 XTX]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[RDNA 3]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[RX 7000-series]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[RX 7900 XT]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.digitaltrends.com/?p=3220163</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The upcoming AMD Radeon RX 7900 XTX was initially said to have a higher clock speed. Rumors say it might still get there.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Prior to AMD&#8217;s <a href="https://www.digitaltrends.com/computing/how-to-watch-amd-rx-7000-launch/">launch of its new RDNA 3 GPUs</a>, the rumor mill has been running wild with speculation about clock speeds on the new flagships. Some sources said that the cards would be able to hit 3GHz; 4GHz has also been floated around as a highly unbelievable, but enticing theory. Now that we know more about the <a href="https://www.digitaltrends.com/computing/amd-rx-7900-xtx-vs-rx-7900-xt/">Radeon RX 7900 XTX and RX 7900 XT</a>, it&#8217;s safe to say they won&#8217;t be hitting 3GHz, let alone 4GHz.</p>
<p>With that said, it seems that 3GHz for RDNA 3 is not entirely out of the question &#8212; it just seems very unlikely to happen on AMD&#8217;s own reference models. Here&#8217;s what we know.</p>
<iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/mUXp4Hqr_lM" width="640" height="360"></iframe>
<p>In this generation of graphics cards, AMD appears to be all about the performance per watt. It managed to keep the TDP on the RX 7900 XTX and the RX 7900 XT reasonable, at 355 and 335 watts respectively. Comparing the <a href="https://www.digitaltrends.com/computing/amd-rx-7900-xtx-vs-nvidia-rtx-4090/">RX 7900 XTX to Nvidia&#8217;s RTX 4090</a> reveals a 95W gap between the two, to AMD&#8217;s advantage. The AMD flagship is also much, much cheaper. With all that said, it will likely fall behind Nvidia&#8217;s behemoth GPU in terms of raw performance.</p>
<p>The 7900 XTX has a 2.3GHz game clock and a 2.5GHz boost clock. While the RTX 4090 has a similar boost clock (2.52GHz), it can also handle a fair bit of overclocking. However, when it comes to the overclocking capabilities of the 7900 XTX, we&#8217;re getting some conflicting information.</p>
<p>According to what AMD has shared at the event (as can be seen in the above PCWorld video), the Navi 31 GPU has been designed to support as much as 3GHz. This implies that AMD, in its pursuit of performance-per-watt superiority, may have limited the power of its reference models, but that doesn&#8217;t mean that its board partners won&#8217;t be able to unlock higher clock speeds. Mind you, this information comes from Jarred Walton of Tom&#8217;s Hardware, and not directly from AMD.</p>
<blockquote class="h-lazy-embed" data-width="500" data-dnt="true" data-initial-classes="twitter-tweet" data-embed-name="twitter" data-sdk-src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">Some people asked during the stream so I asked AIBs and they are saying about only 3% OC over the XTX with preliminary drivers (that have been used mostly for thermal testing, to be fair). If true then it looks like the XTX is already close to maxed out &#128546; <a href="https://t.co/X9E7EbSwIQ">pic.twitter.com/X9E7EbSwIQ</a></p>
<p>&amp;mdash; coreteks (@coreteks) <a href="https://twitter.com/coreteks/status/1588329053530251265?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 4, 2022</a></p></blockquote>
<p>On the other hand, Coreteks, a YouTuber, claims that AMD&#8217;s board partners are only seeing an overclocking potential of around 3%. This can still go up with the final version of the new drivers, though. We also know that there will be different versions of the card with a 3&#215;8-pin connector. This will drive up the power consumption, and consequently, allow higher clock speeds.</p>
<p>In all likelihood, custom versions of the RX 7900 XTX and RX 7900 XT will be capable of hitting higher clock speeds. It&#8217;s hard to say whether 3GHz will be attainable, but we&#8217;re unlikely to be stuck at the 2.5GHz provided by the reference model.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
													<thumbnail>https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/AMD-Radeon-RX-7900-XTX_10.jpg?p=1</thumbnail>
					
											<enclosure url="https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/AMD-Radeon-RX-7900-XTX_10.jpg?p=1" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
															<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3220163</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Matter Launch Day Event brought big news about future updates, compatible products</title>
		<link>https://www.digitaltrends.com/home/matter-launch-day-news/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2022 14:58:37 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jon Bitner]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Smart Home]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[matter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nanoleaf]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[smart home]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SmartThings]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.digitaltrends.com/?p=3219633</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The Matter Launch Event gave us a closer look at which products are implementing the technology, when they'll be available, and what to expect in the future.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Matter and its accompanying certification program were <a href="https://www.digitaltrends.com/home/matter-officially-available/">announced last month</a>, and now we’re getting our first official look at how companies will be using the new connectivity standard in their smart home lineup.</p>
<p>The <a href="https://csa-iot.org/newsroom/smart-home-innovation-set-to-accelerate-with-matter%ef%bf%bc/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">Matter Launch Event</a> kicked off today in Amsterdam &#8212; and it sounds like manufacturers are eager to get the tech integrated with their products. Over 190 devices are already Matter-certified or in line to get certified. The organization has also expanded to eight authorized locations for testing, which should speed up the process and get Matter into your home at an accelerated pace.</p>
<figure class="alignnone"><img  class=" size-large wp-image-3219643" src="https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Matter-CSA.jpg?fit=720%2C405&p=1" alt="The Matter logo on a colorful background."   /></figure>
<p>Matter’s initial launch will support lighting, electrical products, HVAC controls, window coverings, security sensors, door locks, video players, and protocol bridges. During today’s Launch Event, the Connectivity Standards Alliance (CSA) revealed several new smart home categories are being worked on, including door closures, environmental sensors, smoke and carbon monoxide detectors, and motion sensors.</p>
<p>Teams are also working on Matter support for cameras and home appliances, although these are not yet available to manufacturers.</p>
<p>Aside from support for new smart home categories and a general rush of excitement from manufacturers, the CSA event brought us some actual dates and specific products that will be getting Matter support. This includes <a href="https://developer.amazon.com/en-US/blogs/alexa/device-makers/2022/11/matter-works-with-alexa-introduction-november-2022.html" target="_blank" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener">17 Echo devices</a> in December with more to follow next year, the Nanoleaf Essentials Bulbs and Lightstrip in 2023, and three sensors from Eve Systems (Eve Energy, Eve Door and Window, Eve Motion) on December 12. Amazon also confirmed that it is collaborating with Samsung SmartThings to improve compatibility between the two ecosystems. Philips Hue Bridge is also receiving an update to Matter early in the next year.</p>
<p>Matter is expected to play a big role in the smart home industry, so expect to hear even more announcements as we inch closer to 2023.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
													<thumbnail>https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Matter-CSA.jpg?p=1</thumbnail>
					
											<enclosure url="https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Matter-CSA.jpg?p=1" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
															<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3219633</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Marvel Snap gets some big quality of life changes in new update</title>
		<link>https://www.digitaltrends.com/gaming/marvel-snap-gets-some-big-quality-of-life-changes-in-new-update/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2022 14:26:51 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Joseph Yaden]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Gaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marvel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[marvel snap]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobile gaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nuverse]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.digitaltrends.com/?p=3220161</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Marvel Snap got a major update, which brings a new customization option to the hit card game.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Nuverse released a sizable <em><a href="https://www.digitaltrends.com/gaming/marvel-snap-casual-game/">Marvel Snap</a></em> <a href="https://www.marvelsnap.com/newsdetail?id=7159460754754771718" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">update</a> on November 3 that brings numerous quality of life <a href="https://www.digitaltrends.com/gaming/marvel-snap-progression-op-ed/">improvements across the board</a>. Most notably, a new Titles feature has been added, along with improvements to the Wolfsbane and Dagger cards, among many other visual and audio changes.</p>
<p>Titles are new items added to the reward pool that are similar to avatars and card backs. These will appear on the Matchmaking screen as you load into a game, offering a bit more customization.</p>
<blockquote class="h-lazy-embed" data-width="500" data-dnt="true" data-initial-classes="twitter-tweet" data-embed-name="twitter" data-sdk-src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">The latest MARVEL SNAP patch is now live!</p>
<p>What&amp;#39;s new in this patch? &#128064;<br />&#128313;New feature &mdash; Titles <br />&#128313;Art, Visual, &amp;amp; Audio Upgrades<br />&#128313;Lots of Bug Fixes!</p>
<p>In-depth patch notes here<br />&#128073;<a href="https://t.co/1sZtiAp9mO">https://t.co/1sZtiAp9mO</a> <a href="https://t.co/kRyvyLbfNM">pic.twitter.com/kRyvyLbfNM</a></p>
<p>&amp;mdash; MARVEL SNAP (@MARVELSNAP) <a href="https://twitter.com/MARVELSNAP/status/1588321935053594624?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 4, 2022</a></p></blockquote>
<p>Both Wolfsbane and Dagger have been updated and will now count unrevealed cards toward their Power buffs, making them slightly more effective. The Daredevil card is now featured as part of Card Series 3, and Nick Fury is included as part of the Random Pool, meaning you can pull it from sources like X-Mansion and Agent 13.</p>
<p><em>Marvel Snap</em> has also received art, visual, and audio improvements across the board. Nuverse has updated the Foil and Prism Mods to be more clearly visible, and has added general polish to the UI, game board, and buttons. There are also new location sounds for Attilan, Muir Island, Nidavellir, Sewer System, and many others.</p>
<p>Numerous bug fixes have also been implemented, including fixes for avatars not showing up and a major error that caused some purchases to occur twice. Nuverse has also fixed an issue that would cause art to display as the wrong location prior to being revealed (this only occurred on the PC version of <em>Marvel Snap</em>).</p>
<p>The free update is available to download across all versions of <em>Marvel Snap</em> now.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
													<thumbnail>https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/marvel_snap_trailer_screenshot-jpg.jpg?p=1</thumbnail>
					
											<enclosure url="https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/marvel_snap_trailer_screenshot-jpg.jpg?p=1" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
															<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3220161</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>A shocking true crime story is revealed in A Friend of the Family: True Evil</title>
		<link>https://www.digitaltrends.com/movies/jan-broberg-faces-the-past-in-a-friend-of-the-family-true-evil/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2022 14:15:20 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Blair Marnell]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Movies & TV]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[A Friend of the Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[A Friend of the Family: True Evil]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[peacock]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Streaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TV]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.digitaltrends.com/?p=3219898</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Kidnapping victim Jan Broberg opens up about her past and discovers another victim in Peacock's trailer for A Friend of the Family: True Evil.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Peacock&#8217;s <a href="https://www.digitaltrends.com/movies/a-friend-of-the-family-trailer/"><em>A Friend of the Family</em></a> miniseries is currently dramatizing the story of Jan Broberg, a woman who was abducted twice: Once when she was 12, and again when she was 14 years old. The man who took Jan was not a stranger to her or her parents. His name was Robert Berchtold, and he was the titular &#8220;friend of the family.&#8221; While the miniseries still has a few episodes left before the finale on November 10, the real Jan Broberg is confronting that dark period in her life in Peacock&#8217;s upcoming companion documentary, <em>A Friend of the Family: True Evil</em>.</p>
<iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/jQ2n3A3mwVg" width="640" height="360"></iframe>
<p>In the trailer above, Broberg touches upon one of the most shocking aspects of her story: Berchtold was sexually intimate with both of Broberg&#8217;s parents. But this sexual predator also set his sights on Broberg when she was just a child, and he attempted to brainwash her while abusing her and taking her away from her family twice. It&#8217;s a horrific experience to relive even decades later; yet, perhaps the cruelest twist is that Broberg wasn&#8217;t Berchold&#8217;s only victim.</p>
<figure class="alignnone"><img  class=" size-large wp-image-3219902" src="https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/A-Friend-of-the-Family-True-Evil-Trailer.jpg?fit=720%2C405&p=1" alt="Jan Broberg in A Friend of the Family True Evil."   /></figure>
<p>The name of Berchtold&#8217;s other victim isn&#8217;t mentioned in the trailer, but she is seen speaking with Broberg as they attempt to come to terms with what happened to them when they were children. It&#8217;s not a happy story by any stretch of the imagination, yet through this tragedy, Broberg and her family have endured and found a purpose by exposing the evil things that were done to her.</p>
<p><em>A Friend of the Family: True Evil</em> will premiere on Peacock on November 15.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
													<thumbnail>https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/A-Friend-of-the-Family-True-Evil-Trailer.jpg?p=1</thumbnail>
					
											<enclosure url="https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/A-Friend-of-the-Family-True-Evil-Trailer.jpg?p=1" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
															<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3219898</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Where to watch the League of Legends 2022 World Championship</title>
		<link>https://www.digitaltrends.com/movies/league-of-legends-lol-worlds-2022-championship-where-to-watch/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2022 14:01:52 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jason Struss]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Features]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Movies & TV]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eSports]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[league of legends]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[League of Legends World Championship 2022]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[moba]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Where to stream]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.digitaltrends.com/?p=3218305</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Want to see who wins the 2022 League of Legends World Tournament Final? Digital Trends will let you know where to watch the event and when it happens.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>You may not have known it, but the year&#8217;s biggest sports tournament is about to hold its final. No, it&#8217;s not <a href="https://www.digitaltrends.com/home-theater/watch-world-series-in-4k/">baseball and the World Series</a>; it&#8217;s the 2022 League of Legends World Championship. The popular e-sports contest, which sees players from around the world compete to become the champion of the popular <a href="https://www.digitaltrends.com/gaming/league-of-legends-fighting-game-project-l-free-to-play/">Riot Games video game <em>League of Legends</em></a>, has been running for just over a decade, and shows no signs of waning.</p>
<p>Players and fans alike may not know that they too can participate in the championship by streaming it on a number of platforms. But where is it streaming? And do you need to pay to see it? Digital Trends has all the answers for you below.</p>
<h2>Where is it streaming?</h2>
<p>Fortunately for fans and casual viewers alike, there are a number of options to view the final. Your best bet is to go to the home source: Riot Games. Their <a href="https://www.twitch.tv/riotgames" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Twitch channel</a> will carry the final match live in addition to <a href="https://lolesports.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">their official website</a>. You can also view the match on the <a href="https://www.youtube.com/c/lolesports" target="_blank" rel="noopener">LoL esports YouTube channel</a>. Finally, you can view the tournament&#8217;s ultimate battle on Riot&#8217;s <a href="https://trovo.live/s/RiotGames" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Trovo page</a>.</p>
<h2>What time does it start?</h2>
<p>The final starts at 8 p.m. Eastern Standard Time.</p>
<h2>Where is it taking place?</h2>
<figure class="alignnone"><img  class=" size-large wp-image-3220007" src="https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/lol-worlds-championship.jpg?fit=720%2C468&p=1" alt="An image of the Summoner's Cup trophy from the League of Legends World Championships."   /></figure>
<p>The final is set to take place at the Chase Center in San Francisco. For the occasion, the final will showcase &#8220;the most ambitious stage build ever,&#8221; according to Carrie Dunn, the global head of creative for Riot Games Esports. There will be an elaborate opening ceremony with musical acts Lil Nas X and Jackson Wang set to perform.</p>
<h2>Who is competing?</h2>
<p>In the final, two teams from Korea, T1 and DRX, will face off in a winner-take-all final that is guaranteed to make history. Why? Both teams have players that are 26 years old (T1&#8217;s Lee &#8220;Faker&#8221; Sang-hyeok and DRX&#8217;s Kim &#8220;Deft&#8221; Hyuk-kyu). No matter who wins, they will break the record set in 2017 when Kang &#8220;Ambition&#8221; Chan-yong, then 25, became the oldest champion in the tournament&#8217;s history.</p>
<p>There have been 11 champions in the tournament&#8217;s short history with one team, SK Telecom T1, winding the Summoner&#8217;s Cup three times (but with different team members). For a handy list of past winners, click <a href="https://www.dexerto.com/league-of-legends/all-league-of-legends-worlds-winners-1975038/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">here</a>.</p>
<h2>What is League of Legends?</h2>
<p>Oh boy, if you&#8217;re here seeking the answer to that question, you have a lot of catching up to do. Just in case, here&#8217;s a brief primer: <a href="https://www.digitaltrends.com/gaming/best-free-to-play-games/"><em>League of Legends</em> is a multiplayer online battle arena (or MOBA) game</a>. It was first released in 2009 and has become the most popular e-sport ever. We can go on about the game&#8217;s origins, the game&#8217;s storylines and characters, but all you need to know is in <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/video-games/2019/10/27/league-legends-is-now-years-old-this-is-story-its-birth/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">this excellent article</a> from <em>The Washington Post</em>.</p>
<h2>What does Lil Nas X have to do with this?</h2>
<div class="dtvideos-container" data-provider="youtube"><div style="overflow:hidden; padding-bottom:56.25%; position:relative;"><div style="width:100%; height:100%; position:absolute;"><iframe title="Lil Nas X - STAR WALKIN&#039; (League of Legends Worlds Anthem)" width="100%" height="100%" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/HYsz1hP0BFo?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe></div></div><div class="dtvideos-details h-dtvideos-details-embed"><div class="dtvideos-title">Lil Nas X - STAR WALKIN' (League of Legends Worlds Anthem)</div></div></div>
<p>First, that&#8217;s a rude question to ask! But we&#8217;ll answer it anyway: He wrote and performed the theme song to this year&#8217;s tournament, &#8220;Star Walkin.&#8221; A <a href="https://comicbook.com/gaming/news/lil-nas-x-league-of-legends-song-skin-worlds/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">noted video game fan, Lil Nas X</a> is by far the biggest musical act in the tournament&#8217;s history. If you haven&#8217;t listened to the song, you should check it out. It&#8217;s good for playing video games or just cleaning around the house.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
													<thumbnail>https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/lol-worlds-championship.jpg?p=1</thumbnail>
					
											<enclosure url="https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/lol-worlds-championship.jpg?p=1" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
															<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3218305</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>How to watch The Weather Channel without cable</title>
		<link>https://www.digitaltrends.com/home-theater/how-to-stream-weather-channel-online/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2022 13:33:01 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Phil Nickinson]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Features]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Home Theater]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[directv stream]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[frndly tv]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[FuboTV]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hulu + live]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hulu with Live TV]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Streaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Weather Channel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[weather]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[YouTube TV]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.digitaltrends.com/?p=3188459</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The Weather Channel is available on a surprisingly few streaming services. Here's how to watch it if you don't have cable.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>There are a million ways to get information on the weather these days. Windows, for one. Computers for another. But for a lot of folks, it&#8217;s still all about The Weather Channel — the ubiquitous channel that, appropriately enough, is all about The Weather. On a Channel.</p>
<p>And even though Hurricane Ian has made its way through Florida, the fun and destruction isn&#8217;t quite over yet, with the storm setting its sights on Savannah, Ga., and the rest of the East Coast. That&#8217;s how hurricanes work, boys and girls. So it&#8217;s not quite time to turn off The Weather Channel just yet.</p>
<p>But for those who no longer have cable television, watching The Weather Channel can be surprisingly difficult. We&#8217;ll take the work out of it, though, and show you how to stream The Weather Channel online.</p>
<figure class="alignnone"><img  class=" size-large wp-image-3188476" src="https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/the-weather-channel-yttv.jpg?fit=720%2C540&p=1" alt="The Weather Channel on YouTube TV."   /></figure>
<h2>How to stream The Weather Channel</h2>
<p>If you&#8217;re no longer a cable subscriber and are looking to stream The Weather Channel through one of the traditional streaming services in the U.S. (these also are known as MVPDs, for multichannel video programming distributors), you&#8217;ll find you have surprisingly few options.</p>

<p>That&#8217;s the bad news. The good news is that The Weather Channel is available on the most popular streaming service, <a href="https://www.digitaltrends.com/home-theater/what-is-youtube-tv/">YouTube TV</a>. That means <a href="https://www.digitaltrends.com/home-theater/youtube-tv-5-million-subscribers/">more than 5 million accounts</a> already can stream The Weather Channel as part of the single YouTube TV streaming plan (which as of this writing costs $65 a month).</p>
<p>The next biggest streaming service on which you&#8217;re also able to stream The Weather Channel is <a href="https://www.digitaltrends.com/home-theater/fubotv-channels-pricing-features/">FuboTV</a>, which sports just shy of 1 million subscribers at last count. The Weather Channel is included there on its base &#8220;Pro&#8221; plan, which runs $70 a month for 139 channels. Also available is The Weather Channel en Español.</p>
<p>Worth noting is that YouTube TV and Fubo TV also are the only streaming services that offer any sort of 4K option, though it&#8217;s mostly limited to live sports (or in the case of YouTube TV, also to a good bit of on-demand content).</p>
<p>The Weather Channel also is now available on <a href="https://www.digitaltrends.com/home-theater/what-is-hulu-plus-live-tv/">Hulu With Live TV</a>. That&#8217;s notable because Hulu With Live TV, in addition to being the second-largest live streaming platform in the U.S., also includes subscriptions to the Hulu on-demand library, ESPN+, and Disney+. It&#8217;ll cost you $75 a month to get on board.</p>
<p>The least-expensive way to get The Weather Channel actually is from a streaming service called <a href="https://try.frndlytv.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Frndly TV</a>. (As in &#8220;friendly.&#8221;) Its basic plan costs $7 a month and gives you more than 40 channels at SD video quality, and the ability to watch on one device at a time. You get get more options and better quality for $2 more, and the full smash for $11 a month.</p>
<p>And finally, you can stream The Weather Channel on <a href="https://www.digitaltrends.com/home-theater/what-is-directv-now/">DirecTV Stream</a>. But you won&#8217;t find it on the least expensive plan. Instead, you&#8217;ll have to start with at least the &#8220;Choice&#8221; plan, which gets you 105 channels for $70 a month.</p>
<figure class="alignnone"><img  class=" size-large wp-image-3188482" src="https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/twc-roku.jpg?fit=720%2C540&p=1" alt="The Weather Channel on Roku."   /></figure>
<h2>The Weather Channel TV app</h2>
<p>If for whatever reason streaming The Weather Channel just isn&#8217;t your thing, there&#8217;s another option. &#8220;The Weather Channel TV App&#8221; is &#8230; a dedicated app to watch The Weather Channel on your TV. It&#8217;s not quite the same as the live, linear channel, but it&#8217;s better than nothing. With it, you&#8217;ll get weather alerts and updates, local forecasts, radar, maps, and on-demand shows.</p>
<p>And it&#8217;s available most everywhere such apps are found, including Roku and Amazon Fire TV, which takes care of the two biggest streaming platforms. You also can find it on Android TV, Apple TV, on Samsung smart TVs, and on Xfinity Flex.</p>
<p>The Weather Channel TV App costs $3 a month or $30 a year. And as an added bonus, if you already get The Weather Channel by some other means &#8212; be it cable TV or one of the streaming services we listed above &#8212; you can sign in to The Weather Channel TV App and get all of this, too.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
													<thumbnail>https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/twc-roku.jpg?p=1</thumbnail>
					
											<enclosure url="https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/twc-roku.jpg?p=1" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
															<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3188459</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Meta Quest Pro review: the future right on your face</title>
		<link>https://www.digitaltrends.com/gaming/meta-quest-pro-review/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2022 13:30:22 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alan Truly]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Meta]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[meta quest pro]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Metaverse]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[VR]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[VR headsets]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.digitaltrends.com/?p=3218960</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Meta's Quest Pro is a high-end VR headset that's meant for work, so I spent a week putting it through its paces to share what works and what doesn't.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Meta Quest Pro is not your standard VR headset. In many way, it&#8217;s a new category of product, meant as a device to replace your laptop for work.</p>
<p>Despite all the skepticism around the headset due to the company that makes it, I was fascinated by its claims to replicate the daily work experience on a headset. There&#8217;s much more the Quest Pro can do, but entering into my intensive days of testing the core features of the Meta Quest Pro, productivity was my focus.</p>
<p>While it still feels like the early days of headsets like these, I was surprised by just how many things it did well. If you can set aside your biases, you&#8217;ll find a fascinating piece of technology that impressed me time and time again.</p>
<h2>The Quest Pro display</h2>
<figure class="alignnone"><img  class=" size-large wp-image-3218736" src="https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Three-browser-windows-are-open-in-a-Quest-Pro.jpg?fit=720%2C479&p=1" alt="Three browser windows are open in a Quest Pro."   /></figure>
<p>When I start my day, I usually check my email, see what&#8217;s happening on Twitter, and browse the news. I currently use three different devices at my desk to handle this task. A desktop computer with three monitors would work also. <a href="https://www.digitaltrends.com/computing/quest-pros-virtual-screens-versus-real-monitors/">With the Quest Pro, I can handle all of that from the Meta browser with three windows open</a> side-by-side with a better and more flexible view than physical monitors.</p>
<p>The size and aspect ratio can be adjusted by dragging a corner, just like a window on your traditional computer, but in my view within the headset, they appear enormous. The size of a window on a traditional monitor is limited by its physical dimensions. On the Quest Pro, you can fill your entire readable view with a single window, and you can have two more browser windows like this on either side.</p>
<figure class="alignnone"><img  class=" size-large wp-image-3218737" src="https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/A-huge-browser-window-is-down-filling-the-entire-view.jpg?fit=720%2C479&p=1" alt="A huge browser window is filling the entire view."   /></figure>
<p>You can either turn your head, twist your body, or drag the window control to see the others if you have them this large. Text is sharp and easy to read once the Quest Pro has been adjusted correctly, which is a very important detail that I&#8217;ll discuss in more detail below.</p>
<h2>Perfecting the Quest Pro&#8217;s fit</h2>
<figure id="attachment_3218610" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-3218610" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img  class=" size-large wp-image-3218610" src="https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/From-a-side-view-you-can-see-how-glasses-can-be-worn-along-with-a-Quest-Pro.jpg?fit=720%2C479&p=1" alt="From a side view, you can see how glasses can be worn along with a Quest Pro."   /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-3218610" class="wp-caption-text"><span class="credit">Tracey Truly</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>After you set up a desktop computer, monitor, and keyboard, it’s ready to go the moment you wake it up. That’s hard to beat, but the Quest Pro only takes a moment longer once you’re accustomed to wearing it and know where controls and apps are located. It&#8217;s similar to using a tablet for the first time. You have to accept that it takes a few days and possibly weeks to become fully acclimated, as well as build new habits and muscle memory.</p>
<p>When I first put on the Quest Pro, I was impressed with the bright, colorful display but disappointed to find that the screen didn&#8217;t immediately appear to be sharp. To be fair, I’m a bit nearsighted and expected that a screen that’s less than two inches from my eyes wouldn’t present a challenge.</p>
<p>My close-up vision is very good. As unintuitive as it was, I put on my glasses, which are shaped to bend light and help me see distant objects better. I was pleasantly surprised to find that the display was much sharper in the Quest Pro headset as soon as I put on my corrective lenses.</p>
<p>It’s probably a side effect of the pancake lenses that bounce light around internally to allow a tight focus in a very narrow space, making the photons travel further. I’m not certain if that’s the reason for the apparent distance of the headset&#8217;s screen, but I&#8217;ve seen others agree that the Quest Pro might require you to wear your prescription lenses even if you don’t with other VR headsets.</p>
<p>In addition to that, I didn’t receive the notification to do a fit adjustment at first, and I was wearing the headset a bit too low on my forehead. I pushed it up, then it was too high, according to the fit adjustment app. That&#8217;s when I started making micro-adjustments to the vertical placement. The Quest Pro uses eye-tracking in its adjustment app to check for perfect alignment. I also had the lenses separated too far. An interpupillary distance (IPD) of 67 was best for my eyes.</p>
<figure id="attachment_3218598" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-3218598" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img  class=" size-large wp-image-3218598" src="https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/This-photo-shows-the-three-places-to-adjust-the-Quest-Pro-for-the-best-display-clarity.jpg?fit=720%2C479&p=1" alt="This photo shows the three places to adjust the Quest Pro for the best display clarity."   /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-3218598" class="wp-caption-text"><span class="credit">Alan Truly</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>With these refinements, the screen became incredibly sharp to my eyes. With attention to the headset placement, it’s fine for watching videos, exercising, and even light browsing without glasses. It takes a few tries to get the hang of the ideal position for the Quest Pro, but now it has become second nature. I put on the headset, push it up slightly, tighten the head strap, and it&#8217;s good to go.</p>
<p>If I&#8217;m working and need to read and edit text, I put on my glasses first. There&#8217;s an adjustment wheel at the front that provides extra room for glasses so they won&#8217;t bump into the Quest Pro&#8217;s lenses. The brightness, contrast, and color are wonderful to my eyes, and I have no complaints about the display quality. I actually lowered the screen brightness for more comfort and the side benefit is enjoying a longer battery life.</p>
<h2>The battery life isn&#8217;t a problem</h2>
<figure id="attachment_3218632" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-3218632" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img  class=" size-large wp-image-3218632" src="https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Alan-Truly-tries-to-power-a-Quest-Pro-with-an-ancient-battery-pack.jpg?fit=720%2C479&p=1" alt="Alan Truly tries to power a Quest Pro with an ancient battery pack."   /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-3218632" class="wp-caption-text"><span class="credit">Tracey Truly</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>I&#8217;ve only been using the Quest Pro for about a week but I haven&#8217;t had any problems with the battery life. I can work for two or three hours, and when I take a break, I put the headset on the included dock to top it up while I have lunch or stretch my legs.</p>
<p>If I need to push through for several hours to meet a deadline and the battery gets low, <a href="https://www.digitaltrends.com/computing/how-long-does-quest-pro-battery-last-metas-answer/">I can plug the Quest Pro into a charger and keep working</a>. The headset can also be charged by an external battery pack. Depending on the capacity, a good external battery can power the headset for many hours, even when working away from a wall outlet.</p>
<p>My old 10,000mAh battery pack with a USB-A plug doesn&#8217;t put out enough power to keep the Quest Pro going, but more modern versions that can output at least 18W should work to keep the headset running, and I have a newer battery pack on the way to test this idea. 18W is the lowest power output of the charger Meta includes with the Quest Pro, so I think it should work.</p>
<p>It seems like Meta missed an opportunity to sell a Quest Pro battery accessory on launch day. Perhaps Meta wanted to avoid drawing attention to the short two-hour battery life. The news broke about this anyway, and it probably would have been better to have the solution available in store in advance.</p>
<p>The bottom line is that the Quest Pro can run for a few hours depending on your usage, but it won&#8217;t last as long as most modern laptops. <a href="https://www.digitaltrends.com/gaming/best-meta-quest-2-accessories/">Battery life is, however, about the same as the Quest 2</a>, Pico 3, and other standalone VR headsets. The good news is that extending battery life is easy if you need to do so.</p>
<h2>Performance improvements</h2>
<figure class="alignnone"><img  class=" size-large wp-image-3202256" src="https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Meta-Quest-Pro-uses-a-Qualcomm-Snapdragon-XR2-chip.jpg?fit=720%2C479&p=1" alt="Meta Quest Pro uses a Qualcomm Snapdragon XR2+ chip"   /></figure>
<p>Meta upgraded the processor and memory in its Quest Pro, so it should outperform its previous best, the Quest 2. The Qualcomm Snapdragon XR2+ is based on the same design as the XR2 chip, but Meta claims the Quest Pro has a 50% improvement in performance.</p>
<p>The speed of a device is affected by more than the raw power of its CPU, of course. Thermal limitations can cause a device to purposely slow down to prevent overheating. Known as throttling, this issue shows up after several minutes or even hours of use. The Meta Quest 2, for example, is known to have a reduced clock speed and never reaches the full potential of the XR2 chip, a permanent throttling. Also, graphics and neural processors have a huge impact on modern computer use, particularly VR headsets.</p>
<figure class="alignnone"><img  class=" size-large wp-image-3219564" src="https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Heres-the-Meta-Quest-Pros-score-on-BrowserBenchs-Speedometer-2.0.jpg?fit=720%2C479&p=1" alt="Here's the Meta Quest Pro's score on BrowserBench's Speedometer 2.0."   /></figure>
<p>It&#8217;s hard to quantify VR headset performance, since there aren&#8217;t any benchmarking apps available in the Quest app store. A browser benchmark isn&#8217;t the best way to check performance, since it is also dependent on browser optimization. The tests at BrowserMark.org work on the Quest Pro, making it easy to compare to a Quest 2 headset. In my tests, my Quest Pro scored 33.13 on Speedometer 2.0, compared to 29.5 on a Quest 2. That&#8217;s a 12% improvement. The Quest Pro&#8217;s MotionMark graphics score was 133.32 versus 121.67 for the Quest 2 a 9% improvement.</p>
<p>These results are very slow compared to the same tests performed on a modern laptop with the latest browsers; however, that might not be relevant to actual usage. After several hours of working with the Quest Pro, I never noticed any slowdown or sluggishness.</p>
<p>Productivity work usually isn&#8217;t as challenging as gaming, but a VR headset is constantly tracking head movement and recalculating the display, monitoring controller input as well as any external devices. Since the Quest Pro has eye, face, and hand-tracking, those tasks must be handled rapidly as well. Everything felt responsive throughout several days and many hours of use.</p>
<h2>Killer apps and app gaps</h2>
<figure class="alignnone"><img  class=" size-large wp-image-3218739" src="https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Gravity-Sketch-on-the-Quest-Pro-makes-it-easy-to-create-flowing-organic-shapes.jpg?fit=720%2C479&p=1" alt="Gravity Sketch on the Quest Pro makes it easy to create flowing organic shapes."   /></figure>
<p>I like comparing the Quest Pro to an iPad, because it feels the same in terms of both its lack and its potential. There are obviously huge gaps in native productivity apps for the Quest Pro. The first “killer apps” for the iPad took advantage of its unique features, a huge touchscreen before laptops had touchscreens, and a nice pressure-sensitive stylus. <a href="https://www.digitaltrends.com/mobile/best-ipad-pro-drawing-apps/">Paint apps exploded in popularity on the iPad and made it a serious art tool</a>.</p>
<p>The Quest Pro already has several great tools that take advantage of its unique virtual reality power by placing you directly in the three-dimensional design world of your creation. Gravity Sketch, a powerful 3D modeling app, was available on the Quest and Quest 2 long before the Quest Pro was even hinted at, and it&#8217;s even better now.</p>
<p>Gravity Sketch provides a designer’s dream experience, making it <a href="https://www.digitaltrends.com/mobile/luma-ai-iphone-app-create-3d-models-hands-on-review/">easy to create detailed 3D models and even flowing organic shapes</a> with a swipe of the controller along a curve of your imagination. An optional mixed-reality view places your 3D product design or artwork into reality while you work. There are several other great examples of 3D design tools in the Quest App Store. Adobe is even joining in with its new Substance3D app.</p>
<figure class="alignnone"><img  class=" size-large wp-image-3218669" src="https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Figmin-XR-brings-animation-to-your-living-room-or-office.jpg?fit=720%2C479&p=1" alt="Figmin XR brings animation to your living room or office."   /></figure>
<p>Figmin XR lets you create mixed-reality artwork within that environment instead of trying to develop it on a computer that lacks such abilities. This speeds up workflow tremendously. It’s like learning to swim; that’s best done in the water.</p>
<p>There are plenty of gaps in productivity apps, however. There are no major photo editors or 2D graphic design tools in the Quest App Store. If you have a favorite image or graphic editor that’s available on Android, you should write the developer to request a Quest Pro version. There’s room for several vector design and image editors on the Quest Pro. The first few photo editors to arrive are sure to be rewarded with orders from Quest Pro owners that are hungry for this capability.</p>
<p>In the meantime, you have to rely on web apps. The good news is that web apps have rapidly advanced in quality. Canva and Pixlr are excellent graphic design and photo editing apps that can run in the Quest Pro browser. Microsoft 365 allows browser access to Word, Excel, PowerPoint, and OneNote. Google Workspace is usable with a paired keyboard but isn’t an ideal solution yet. Meta’s browser isn’t as powerful and doesn’t work with every web app.</p>
<figure class="alignnone"><img  class=" size-large wp-image-3218740" src="https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Word-Excel-and-Pixlr-are-open-in-windows-on-a-Quest-Pro.jpg?fit=720%2C479&p=1" alt="Word, Excel, and Pixlr are open in windows on a Quest Pro."   /></figure>
<p>I’m used to writing in a Markdown text editor and I found a nice one on the web called <a href="https://lex.page/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Lex</a> that I’ve been using with the Quest Pro. It lets me quickly add subheadings, italicize, and bold text. There’s also a word count which is a very useful feature for writers. If you use WordPress, that also works with the Meta browser. Most websites and web apps work well but some don’t.</p>
<p>If a web app doesn’t suffice or there isn’t one that fits your needs, you can connect your Quest Pro to a real computer and still take care of whatever you need to do while enjoying the giant screen space available in the headset.</p>
<h2>Remote desktop apps</h2>
<figure class="alignnone"><img  class=" size-large wp-image-3218741" src="https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Immersed-is-a-good-remote-desktop-alternative-for-the-Quest-Pro.jpg?fit=720%2C479&p=1" alt="Immersed is a good remote desktop alternative for the Quest Pro."   /></figure>
<p>The Quest Pro has a native remote desktop app called Horizon Workrooms. It’s very nice and makes it easy to connect to a Mac or Windows PC. On the Mac, you can open three virtual screens, even if you only have one physical display or are using a MacBook without an external monitor. On Windows, there is just a single virtual screen but Meta says the three-screen option is coming soon. Horizon Workrooms works but is a bit restrictive once you get used to manipulating three Quest Pro browser windows.</p>
<p>To regain that freedom of controlling multiple screens, their sizes, and aspect ratios, the Immersed app is a better solution. You can create vertical displays and use screens at different resolutions. There are many more options, and if you think you’ll be relying on the computer for long periods, it might be worth checking it out. Immersed already supports multiple virtual displays on both Mac and Windows computers.</p>
<h2>My traditional computer setup</h2>
<figure id="attachment_3218644" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-3218644" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img  class=" size-large wp-image-3218644" src="https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Alan-Trulys-standing-desk-has-a-MacBook-Air-Surface-Book-2-and-iPhone-13-Pro-Max.jpg?fit=720%2C479&p=1" alt="Alan Truly's standing desk has a MacBook Air, Surface Book 2, and iPhone 13 Pro Max."   /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-3218644" class="wp-caption-text"><span class="credit">Alan Truly</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>I have a fairly traditional computer setup with a few quirks that come from being a tech writer and having a good understanding of ergonomics. I don&#8217;t use a tower with a multi-monitor setup on a wide desk with a chair, but I do have two computers at my small desk, along with my phone, providing three screens to check. It&#8217;s a standing desk with a laptop mount for my MacBook Air so it sits at eye level. My Surface Book 2 is mounted on an adjustable arm, and I keep my iPhone 13 Pro Max on a tray on the laptop shelf.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s often easiest to view Twitter on my phone. Some apps are designed for a vertical screen, and if you have extra space at the sides, it’s often used for advertising. For apps and websites that work better on the big screen, I use my MacBook or Surface Book.</p>
<figure id="attachment_3218662" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-3218662" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img  class=" size-large wp-image-3218662" src="https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/A-Logitech-MX-Keys-and-Rapoo-M500-mouse-make-it-easy-to-switch-between-devices.jpg?fit=720%2C479&p=1" alt="A Logitech MX Keys and Rapoo M500 mouse make it easy to switch between devices."   /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-3218662" class="wp-caption-text"><span class="credit">Alan Truly</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>The <a href="https://www.digitaltrends.com/computing/why-the-m2-macbook-air-is-worth-upgrade/">MacBook Air is newer and serves as my primary computer</a>. The Surface Book allows me to test things on Windows and serves as another display when I’m writing while referencing other material. I have a Logitech MX Keys Bluetooth keyboard at a comfortable typing height that can switch between three devices with a tap. I have a Rapoo M500 mouse with similar three-way switching.</p>
<p>That means I can cycle between the MacBook, Surface Book, and Quest Pro without the need to change the input tools my hands are used to using. That muscle memory follows me from device to device.</p>
<h2>Quest Pro input choices</h2>
<p>When I’m very busy, I’ll choose the most familiar tools to get the job done. With my keyboard and mouse, I’m truly comfortable working on the Quest Pro despite the newness of the experience. It doesn&#8217;t feel awkward and unfamiliar &#8212; it feels right, at least most of the time.</p>
<figure id="attachment_3218626" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-3218626" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img  class=" size-large wp-image-3218626" src="https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/The-Quest-Pro-has-great-hand-tracking-capabilities.jpg?fit=720%2C479&p=1" alt="The Quest Pro has great hand-tracking capabilities."   /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-3218626" class="wp-caption-text"><span class="credit">Tracey Truly</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>What’s cool is the ability to take care of the same work, albeit at a slower pace with only the headset itself. With the Quest Pro’s excellent hand-tracking and dictation, you can get by without using a mouse, a keyboard, or even the included Quest Pro Touch Controllers. It would be very difficult to carry my two computers upstairs and set them up in an ergonomically correct position for work. By comparison, <a href="https://www.digitaltrends.com/computing/ready-to-work-in-vr-and-embrace-metaverse/">I can grab my Quest Pro and go anywhere in the house and be back at work in seconds</a>.</p>
<p>As good as the hand-tracking is, it’s awkward to type using the on-screen keyboard with the pinch gestures needed to select a key. The Touch Controllers make typing much easier. This method can’t compare to the speed and accuracy of a physical keyboard; however, with two hands working at once, it’s relatively easy to do web searches, fill out forms, and handle light-duty typing.</p>
<figure class="alignnone"><img  class=" size-large wp-image-3218617" src="https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Metas-new-Quest-Pro-Touch-Controllers-are-fast-and-accurate..jpg?fit=720%2C479&p=1" alt="Meta's new Quest Pro Touch Controllers are fast and accurate."   /></figure>
<p>The Touch Controllers also have haptics to provide feedback as you type. The joystick allows scrolling in any direction and you can use the lower trigger to quickly grab and rearrange windows.</p>
<p>Dictation is usually quite accurate but is a bit slow to fill in what is spoken and you can&#8217;t edit with your voice. Speaking to type is a skill I haven’t spent much time on, but it would probably become easier and more natural with practice. I like a physical keyboard, and I don’t anticipate that changing until a computer learns to read my thoughts.</p>
<p>It’s very nice to have so many options, and that’s another unique feature of the Quest Pro. With new ways to interact, see more, and make adjustments without the limitations of physical monitors, this is <a href="https://www.digitaltrends.com/computing/nexpad-portable-touchscreen-perches-on-laptops/">an opportunity to explore new ways of connecting to a computer</a>, where you can work, and how you can become more productive.</p>
<h2>Is the Quest Pro right for you?</h2>
<p>The Quest Pro isn’t the perfect VR headset or an ideal productivity device yet. There are bugs, glitches, and missing productivity apps, all of which should improve over time. <a href="https://www.digitaltrends.com/computing/quest-pro-will-not-replace-your-laptop/">You shouldn&#8217;t get rid of your computer, laptop, or phone</a>, even though the Quest Pro or something like it will probably replace some or all of those devices in the future. The Quest Pro isn&#8217;t the solution to every work need, but it’s a very compelling start to a new way of computing.</p>
<p>If you’re intrigued and can afford the $1,500 price without selling your computer, you should give it a thorough test, going beyond the very limited demo available at Best Buy or the Meta retail store. Take it home or to the office and connect it to a keyboard and mouse. You might be surprised to find how comfortable and familiar it feels. I certainly was.</p>
<p>I can easily recommend the Quest Pro to anyone that already uses VR for work or is interested in the prospect. It&#8217;s certainly your best option at this point. If you&#8217;re a content creator or developer interested in exploring this new marketplace, there&#8217;s obviously much more to dive into with this headset. This type of technology will never truly take off until it&#8217;s more accessible, but as a vision of the future, the Quest Pro has me captivated.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
													<thumbnail>https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Alan-Truly-is-writing-using-a-Quest-Pro-with-a-paiered-keyboard-and-mouse.jpg?p=1</thumbnail>
					
											<enclosure url="https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Alan-Truly-is-writing-using-a-Quest-Pro-with-a-paiered-keyboard-and-mouse.jpg?p=1" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
															<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3218960</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Hulu Live and the Disney Bundle are getting more expensive</title>
		<link>https://www.digitaltrends.com/home-theater/hulu-live-disney-bundle-price-increase/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2022 13:23:03 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Phil Nickinson]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Home Theater]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Disney]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Disney+ Bundle]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hulu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hulu + live]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hulu with Live TV]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.digitaltrends.com/?p=3219990</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[If you pay for Hulu Live or the Disney Bundle, you'll likely have to pay more starting December 8, 2022.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It&#8217;s officially price increase season. Hulu has announced via emails and on its website that <a href="https://www.digitaltrends.com/home-theater/what-is-hulu-plus-live-tv/">Hulu with Live TV</a> — which also includes Disney+ and ESPN+ to become the full &#8220;Disney Bundle&#8221; — will increase in price from $70 a month to $75 a month beginning December 8, 2022.</p>
<p>And if you have the Disney Bundle without live TV, you can expect that price to increase from $14 a month to $15 on that same date.</p>
<figure id="attachment_3103089" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-3103089" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img  class=" size-large wp-image-3103089" src="https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/hulu-live-tv-guide-0622-13.jpg?fit=720%2C479&p=1" alt="The live guide on Hulu With Live TV."   /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-3103089" class="wp-caption-text"><span class="credit">Phil Nickinson/Digital Trends</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>News of the Hulu price increases comes just a day after <a href="https://www.digitaltrends.com/home-theater/sling-tv-price-increase-december-2022/">Sling TV announced it was increasing the cost</a> of its basic plans by $5 a month.</p>
<p>If any of this sounds familiar and/or a bit confusing, it&#8217;s because <a href="https://www.digitaltrends.com/home-theater/disney-plus-ads-prices/">December 8 also is the date</a> on which Disney+ launches a plan that includes advertising with the on-demand content. That plan costs $8 a month, or $3 a month less than a &#8220;Premium&#8221; Disney+ subscription. That plan was announced in August and came with its own set of price tweaks across the Disney Bundle spectrum.</p>
<p>Come December 8, this is how everything will shake down:</p>
<ul>
<li>Disney+ with ads: $8 a month</li>
<li>Disney+ Premium (no ads): $11 a month</li>
<li>Hulu with ads: $8 a month</li>
<li>ESPN+ with ads: $10 a month</li>
<li>Disney+ and Hulu, with ads: $10 a month</li>
<li>Disney+ (no ads), Hulu, ESPN+, with ads: $15 a month (note that this plan will no longer be available to purchase or switch to on Disney+ after December 7, but existing subscribers can keep it at the new price)</li>
<li>Disney+ (no ads), Hulu (no ads), ESPN+ (with ads): $20 a month</li>
<li>Disney+ (with ads), Hulu (with ads) + Live TV, ESPN+ (with ads): $70 a month</li>
<li>Hulu (with ads) + Live TV, ESPN+ (with ads), and Disney+ (no ads): $75 a month (note that this plan will no longer be available to purchase or switch to after December 8, but existing subscribers can keep it at the new price)</li>
<li>Hulu With Live TV, Hulu on-demand (without ads), Disney+ (no ads), and ESPN+ (with ads): $83 a month</li>
</ul>
<p>That&#8217;s &#8230; a lot of options. And if you&#8217;re doing your billing through a T-Mobile account, some of it might not be available. But the bottom line is this: You&#8217;re just going to have to pick what you want, pay attention to the price, and get ready to pay a bit more come early December.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
													<thumbnail>https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/hulu-live-22-11.jpg?p=1</thumbnail>
					
											<enclosure url="https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/hulu-live-22-11.jpg?p=1" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
															<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3219990</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
