<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<rdf:RDF
 xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
 xmlns="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/"
 xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
 xmlns:taxo="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/taxonomy/"
 xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
 xmlns:syn="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
 xmlns:admin="http://webns.net/mvcb/"
>

<channel rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/">
<title>physics.flu-dyn updates on arXiv.org</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">Physics -- Fluid Dynamics (physics.flu-dyn) updates on the arXiv.org e-print archive</description>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:date>2022-11-03T20:30:00-05:00</dc:date>
<dc:publisher>help@arxiv.org</dc:publisher>
<dc:subject>Physics -- Fluid Dynamics</dc:subject>
<syn:updateBase>1901-01-01T00:00+00:00</syn:updateBase>
<syn:updateFrequency>1</syn:updateFrequency>
<syn:updatePeriod>daily</syn:updatePeriod>
<items>
 <rdf:Seq>
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01414" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01440" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01560" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01649" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01685" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01754" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2203.09514" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.13426" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.16358" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.16762" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.00771" />
 </rdf:Seq>
</items>
<image rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif" />
</channel>
<image rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif">
<title>arXiv.org</title>
<url>http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif</url>
<link>http://arxiv.org/</link>
</image>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01414">
<title>Inertial migration of a sphere in plane Couette flow. (arXiv:2211.01414v1 [physics.flu-dyn])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01414</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We study the inertial migration of a torque-free neutrally buoyant sphere in
wall-bounded plane Couette flow over a wide range of channel Reynolds numbers,
$Re_c$, in the limit of small particle Reynolds number\,($Re_p\ll1$) and
confinement ratio\,($\lambda\ll1$). Here, $Re_c = V_\text{wall}H/\nu$ where $H$
denotes the separation between the channel walls, $V_\text{wall}$ denotes the
speed of the moving wall, and $\nu$ is the kinematic viscosity of the Newtonian
suspending fluid; $\lambda = a/H$, $a$ being the sphere radius, with
$Re_p=\lambda^2 Re_c$. The channel centerline is found to be the only
(stable)\,equilibrium below a critical $Re_c\,(\approx 148)$, consistent with
the predictions of earlier small-$Re_c$ analyses. A supercritical pitchfork
bifurcation at the critical $Re_c$ creates a pair of stable off-center
equilibria, symmetrically located with respect to the centerline, with the
original centerline equilibrium simultaneously becoming unstable. The new
equilibria migrate wallward with increasing $Re_c$. In contrast to the
inference based on recent computations, the aforementioned bifurcation occurs
for arbitrarily small $Re_p$ provided $\lambda$ is sufficiently small. An
analogous bifurcation occurs in the two-dimensional scenario, that is, for a
circular cylinder suspended freely in plane Couette flow, with the critical
$Re_c$ being approximately $110$.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Anand_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Prateek Anand&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Subramanian_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ganesh Subramanian&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01440">
<title>On the development and analysis of coupled surface-subsurface models of catchments. Part 2. A three-dimensional benchmark model and its properties. (arXiv:2211.01440v1 [physics.flu-dyn])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01440</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The objective of this three-part work is the formulation and rigorous
analysis of a number of reduced mathematical models that are nevertheless
capable of describing the hydrology at the scale of a river basin (i.e.
catchment). Coupled effects of surface and subsurface flows are considered.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this second part, we construct a benchmark catchment scenario and
investigate the effects of parameters within their typical ranges. Previous
research on coupled surface-subsurface models have focused on numerical
simulations of site-specific catchments; here our focus is broader and
emphasises the study of general solutions to the mathematical models, and their
dependencies on dimensionless parameters. This study provides a foundation
based on the examination of a geometrically simple three-dimensional benchmark
scenario. We develop a nondimensional coupled surface-subsurface model, and
extract the key dimensionless parameters. We then apply asymptotic methods in
order to discuss some potential simplifications, including the reduction of the
geometry to a two-dimensional form, where the principal groundwater and
overland flows occur in the hillslope direction. Numerical solutions
demonstrate the effects of model parameters and provide guidance on the
validity of the dimensional reductions.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Morawiecki_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Piotr Morawiecki&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Trinh_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Philippe H. Trinh&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01560">
<title>Imaging the decay of quantized vortex rings to decipher quantum dissipation. (arXiv:2211.01560v1 [cond-mat.quant-gas])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01560</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Like many quantum fluids, superfluid helium-4 (He II) can be considered as a
mixture of two miscible fluid components: an inviscid superfluid and a viscous
normal fluid consisting of thermal quasiparticles [1]. A mutual friction
between the two fluids can emerge due to quasiparticles scattering off
quantized vortex lines in the superfluid [2]. This quantum dissipation
mechanism is the key for understanding various fascinating behaviors of the
two-fluid system [3,4]. However, due to the lack of experimental data for
guidance, modeling the mutual friction between individual vortices and the
normal fluid remains an unsettled topic despite decades of research [5-10].
Here we report an experiment where we visualize the motion of quantized vortex
rings in He II by decorating them with solidified deuterium tracer particles.
By examining how the rings spontaneously shrink and accelerate, we provide
unequivocal evidences showing that only a recent theory [9] which accounts for
the coupled motion of the two fluids with a self-consistent local friction can
reproduce the observed ring dynamics. Our work eliminates long-standing
ambiguities in our theoretical description of the vortex dynamics in He II,
which will have a far-reaching impact since similar mutual friction concept has
been adopted for a wide variety of quantum two-fluid systems, including atomic
Bose-Einstein condensates (BECs) [11,12], superfluid neutron stars [13-15], and
gravity-mapped holographic superfluid [16,17].
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Tang_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yuan Tang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Guo_W/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Wei Guo&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Kobayashi_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Hiromichi Kobayashi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Yui_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Satoshi Yui&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Tsubota_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Makoto Tsubota&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Kanai_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Toshiaki Kanai&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01649">
<title>Inverse Magnus effect in a rarefied gas. (arXiv:2211.01649v1 [physics.flu-dyn])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01649</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The transverse force exerted on a rotating sphere immersed in an otherwise
uniform flow of a rarefied gas is investigated based on the
Bhatnagar-Gross-Krook (BGK) model of the Boltzmann equation assuming the
Maxwell boundary condition on the sphere. In several existing studies, it has
been shown that the transverse force acting on the sphere, also known as the
Magnus force, has opposite signs in the free molecular and continuum flows. The
present study intends to clarify the force&apos;s transition in terms of the Knudsen
number (i.e., the reciprocal ratio of the sphere radius to the molecular mean
free path) with a particular interest in the impact of the sphere&apos;s surface
accommodation. It is found that the threshold of the Knudsen number, at which
the transverse force changes the sign, depends only weakly on the accommodation
coefficient, suggesting certain robustness in the threshold. The present study
is an extension of the previous work [S. Taguchi and T. Tsuji, J. Fluid. Mech.
933, A37 (2022)], in which the case of complete accommodation (diffuse
reflection) is exclusively considered.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Taguchi_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Satoshi Taguchi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Tsuji_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Tetsuro Tsuji&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01685">
<title>Generalized topological bulk-edge correspondence in continuous systems with non-Hermitian boundary conditions. (arXiv:2211.01685v1 [cond-mat.mes-hall])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01685</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The bulk-edge correspondence (BEC) is the hallmark of topological systems. In
continuous (non-lattice) Hermitian systems with unbounded wavevector it was
recently shown that the BEC is modified. How would it be further affected in
non-Hermitian systems, experiencing loss and/or gain? In this work we take the
first step in this direction, by studying a Hermitian continuous system with
non-Hermitian boundary conditions. We find in this case that edge modes emerge
at roots of the scattering matrix, as opposed to the Hermitian case, where they
emerge at poles (or, more accurately, coalescence of roots and poles). This
entails a nontrivial modification to the relative Levinson&apos;s theorem. We then
show that the topological structure remains the same as in the Hermitian case,
and the generalized BEC holds, provided one employs appropriate modified
contours in the wavevector plane, so that the scattering matrix phase winding
counts the edge modes correctly. We exemplify all this using a paradigmatic
model of waves in a shallow ocean or active systems in the presence of odd
viscosity, as well as 2D electron gas with Hall viscosity. We use this
opportunity to examine the case of large odd viscosity, where the scattering
matrix becomes $2\times2$, which has not been discussed in previous works on
the Hermitian generalized BEC.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Rapoport_O/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Orr Rapoport&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Goldstein_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Moshe Goldstein&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01754">
<title>Laminar mixed convection in an eccentric annular horizontal duct for a thermodependent non-Newtonian fluid. (arXiv:2211.01754v1 [physics.flu-dyn])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01754</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The present work focuses on the study of mixed convection of a purely viscous
shear-thinning fluid in a horizontal annular eccentric duct. The inner and
outer cylinders are heated with constant and uniform heat flux densities. The
objective of this work is to study the effect of the variation of eccentricity,
rheological behavior of the fluid as well as the thermodependency of the
rheological parameters on the reorganization of the flow and thermal
stratification caused by the buoyancy forces. At the entrance of the heating
zone, the dynamic regime is assumed to be established and the temperature
profile uniform. The conservation equations are solved numerically using a
finite difference method with implicit schemes. A secondary azimuthal flow,
induced by natural convection, develops downstream of the inlet section. This
flow creates a stratification of the thermal field on a given section of the
duct, which intensifies downstream from the entrance. On the other hand, the
decrease in consistency with increasing temperature near the heated walls
produces a centrifugal radial flow towards the walls. The presence of an
eccentricity induces in turn a significant effect on the main dynamic field and
the stratification of the thermal field. Two cases of upward and downward
eccentricity are treated. These show that an upward shift increases the
stratification of the thermal field, while the stratification begins to weaken
from a certain amount of eccentricity in the case of downward shift. This
represents an important result in terms of possible industrial applications. We
may indeed conclude that an appropriate choice of downward eccentricity can
reduce the thermal stratification, observed experimentally in the case of a
concentric heated annular duct [1], when this stratification is undesirable.
The choice of this eccentricity depends on rheological and thermal properties
of the fluid.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Messaoudene_N/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;N Ait Messaoudene&lt;/a&gt; (UB1), &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Horimek_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;A Horimek&lt;/a&gt; (UB1), &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Nouar_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;C Nouar&lt;/a&gt; (LEMTA), &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Benaouda_Zouaoui_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;B Benaouda-Zouaoui&lt;/a&gt; (UB1)</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2203.09514">
<title>Emergence of isotropy and dynamic scaling in 2D wave turbulence in a homogeneous Bose gas. (arXiv:2203.09514v3 [cond-mat.quant-gas] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2203.09514</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We realise a turbulent cascade of wave excitations in a homogeneous 2D Bose
gas, and probe on all relevant time and length scales how it builds up from
small to large momenta, until the system reaches a steady state with matching
energy injection and dissipation. This all-scales view directly reveals the two
theoretically expected cornerstones of turbulence formation -- the emergence of
statistical momentum-space isotropy under anisotropic forcing, and the
spatiotemporal scaling of the momentum distribution at times before any energy
is dissipated.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Galka_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Maciej Ga&amp;#x142;ka&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Christodoulou_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Panagiotis Christodoulou&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Gazo_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Martin Gazo&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Karailiev_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Andrey Karailiev&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Dogra_N/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Nishant Dogra&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Schmitt_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Julian Schmitt&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Hadzibabic_Z/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Zoran Hadzibabic&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.13426">
<title>A revision on Rayleigh capillary jet breakup. (arXiv:2210.13426v2 [physics.flu-dyn] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.13426</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The average Rayleigh capillary breakup length of a cylindrical Newtonian
viscous liquid jet moving with homogeneous velocity $\hat{U}$ (negligible
external forces) must be determined by the selection of normal modes with
time-independent amplitude and wavelength (invariant modes, IMs). Both positive
and negative group velocity IMs exist in ample ranges of the parameter domain
(Weber and Ohnesorge numbers), which explains (i) the average breakup length
independence on ambient conditions (long-term resonance), and (ii) its
proportionality to the inverse of the spatial growth rate of the dominant
positive group velocity IM. Published experimental results since Grace (1965,
PhD Thesis) confirm our proposal.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Ganan_Calvo_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Alfonso M. Ganan-Calvo&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.16358">
<title>Applicability of machine learning in uncertainty quantification of turbulence models. (arXiv:2210.16358v2 [physics.flu-dyn] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.16358</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;White paper: The aim of this work is to apply and analyze machine learning
methods for uncertainty quantification of turbulence models. In this work we
investigate the classical and data-driven variants of the eigenspace
perturbation method. This methodology is designed to estimate the uncertainties
related to the shape of the modeled Reynolds stress tensor in the Navier-Stokes
equations for Computational Fluid Dynamics (CFD). The underlying methodology is
extended by adding a data-driven, physics-constrained machine learning approach
in order to predict local perturbations of the Reynolds stress tensor. Using
separated two-dimensional flows, we investigate the generalization properties
of the machine learning models and shed a light on impacts of applying a
data-driven extension.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Matha_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Marcel Matha&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Kucharczyk_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Karsten Kucharczyk&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.16762">
<title>Spin hydrodynamic generation in unsteady flows. (arXiv:2210.16762v2 [physics.flu-dyn] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.16762</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We theoretically investigate a spin-mediated conversion from fluid dynamics
to voltage, known as spin hydrodynamic generation (SHDG), in oscillatory and
transient unsteady flows. We consider unsteady flows of liquid metal between
two parallel infinite planes and then calculate its vorticity fields based on
the Navier--Stokes equation for an incompressible viscous fluid. The spin
accumulation and spin current generated by unsteady flows are derived using a
spin-diffusion equation, including spin-vorticity coupling, which is a couple
of angular momentum between electron spin and vorticity field in unsteady
flows. The estimation of SHDG in liquid mercury flow suggests that an
observable magnitude of voltage can be induced in unsteady flows. Our results
are expected to enable the realization of high-speed spin devices with unsteady
flows and broaden the range of fluid spintronics applicability.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Funato_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Takumi Funato&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Matsuo_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Mamoru Matsuo&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.00771">
<title>Creation of an isolated turbulent blob fed by vortex rings. (arXiv:2211.00771v2 [physics.flu-dyn] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.00771</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Turbulence is hard to control. A plethora of experimental methods have been
developed to generate this ephemeral state of matter, leading to fundamental
insights into its statistical and structural features as well as its onset at
ever higher Reynolds numbers. In all cases however, the central role played by
the material boundaries of the apparatus poses a challenge on understanding
what the turbulence has been fed, and how it would freely evolve. Here, we
build and control a confined state of turbulence using only elemental building
blocks: vortex rings. We create a stationary and isolated blob of turbulence
($Re_\lambda$=50-300) in a quiescent environment, initiated and sustained
solely by vortex rings. We assemble a full picture of its three-dimensional
structure, onset, energy budget and tunability. Crucially, the incoming vortex
rings can be endowed with conserved quantities, such as helicity, which can
then be controllably transferred to the turbulent state. Our `one eddy at a
time&apos; approach paves the way for sculpting turbulent flows much as a state of
matter, `printing&apos; it at a targeted position, localizing it, and ultimately
harnessing it. Our work paves the way to gaining a complete picture of this
ephemeral state of flow.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Matsuzawa_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Takumi Matsuzawa&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Mitchell_N/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Noah P. Mitchell&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Perrard_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Stephane Perrard&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Irvine_W/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;William T.M. Irvine&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
</rdf:RDF>