<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"><channel><title>IEEE Spectrum</title><link>https://spectrum.ieee.org/</link><description>IEEE Spectrum</description><atom:link href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/feeds/topic/energy.rss" rel="self"></atom:link><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2022 16:00:14 -0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/eyJ0eXAiOiJKV1QiLCJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJpbWFnZSI6Imh0dHBzOi8vYXNzZXRzLnJibC5tcy8yNjg4NDUyMC9vcmlnaW4ucG5nIiwiZXhwaXJlc19hdCI6MTY5OTk5OTQzOX0.aimbeagNFKGtififsLPFvztNYGr1_NMvLOOT1mPOjEU/image.png?width=210</url><link>https://spectrum.ieee.org/</link><title>IEEE Spectrum</title></image><item><title>Egg-Crate Nanostructured PV Crosses Solar Threshold</title><link>https://spectrum.ieee.org/perovskite</link><description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/different-colored-layers-and-textures.jpg?id=32046017&width=1200&height=800&coordinates=0%2C52%2C0%2C52"/><br/><br/><p>By adding periodic nanostructures that look like egg-crate foam to <a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/power-from-commercial-perovskite-solar-cells-is-coming-soon" target="_self">tandem solar cells</a> made of silicon and perovskites, researchers at the Helmholtz-Zentrum Berlin in Germany have achieved a certified efficiency of 29.8 percent. </p><p>This was the world record for tandem solar-cell efficiency until July of this year, when researchers at the Swiss Federal Institute of Technology Lausanne (EPFL) surpassed it slightly, setting a new record of 31 percent. The German team, however, has presented details of how they achieved their milestone efficiency—and insights about how to further the <a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/power-from-commercial-perovskite-solar-cells-is-coming-soon" target="_blank">promise of perovskite solar tech</a>—in a recent paper in <em><a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41565-022-01228-8" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Nature Nanotechnology</a></em>. </p><p>Silicon solar cells have a theoretical efficiency limit of around 29 percent, with the best cells today reaching efficiencies of just under 27 percent. Solar cells made of III-V semiconductors can achieve efficiencies higher than 30 percent, but those materials are expensive and difficult to process. </p><p><a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/perovskites-for-tandem-solar-cells-" target="_self">Tandem cells</a>, in which silicon is coated with easy-to-make <a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/stable-perovskite-cell-boosts-solar-power" target="_self">photovoltaic perovskites</a>, offer a way to achieve efficiencies over 40 percent, in theory at least, at low cost and without needing drastically different manufacturing facilities. </p><p>Teams working on such tandem devices have so far tried to eke out every little efficiency gain by tweaking the chemical composition of the perovskites, making nicer more uniform layers, and improving the contact between the two material layers, among other tricks.</p><p>The German team, and the Swiss team after them, boosted efficiency by creating a texture on the silicon surface. Texturing solar cells reduces reflection losses, which increases the current that the device generates, says Philipp Tockhorn, a researcher at Helmholtz-Zentrum and first author of the new paper. “Textures are essential to tap the full optical potential of perovskite–silicon tandem solar cell and to reduce optical losses to a minimum.”</p><p>The standard way to texture silicon-only cells is to create random pyramidal structures that are several micrometers in size. But that doesn’t work for tandem cells because the height of standard pyramidal textures surpasses the thickness of the perovskite layer, Tockhorn says. To overcome that, researchers have tried to either alter the perovskite deposition method while keeping the pyramid texture the same, or tried tweaking the pyramidal textures to more easily deposit perovskite solution on them. “There is a challenge to fully cover the texture without pinholes, which would deteriorate the performance,” he says.</p><p>The Swiss EPFL team’s solution was to use a <a href="https://actu.epfl.ch/news/new-world-records-perovskite-on-silicon-tandem-sol/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">hybrid vapor/solution</a> processing technique that is compatible with <a href="https://www.pv-magazine.com/2022/04/29/epfl-achieves-29-2-efficiency-for-tandem-solar-cell-with-fully-textured-silicon/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">pyramidal textured</a> silicon surfaces. They made a 1-square-centimeter<sup> </sup>solar cell with a power conversion efficiency of 31.25 percent.</p><p>But Tockhorn and his colleagues decided to investigate shallower nanotextures. Based on previous experimental work and backed up by optical simulations, the team decided on a sinusoidal design with a hexagonal arrangement. These nanotextures can be easily coated with perovskite without compromising the quality of the perovskite, he says.</p><p>Not only did the nanotexturing improve efficiency, it also increased the yield of high-quality tandem solar cells. That’s because the textured surface retained the perovskite solution better than a flat silicon surface, resulting in a better-quality perovskite film. Out of 45 nanotextured tandem solar cells, only two had visible holes after perovskite coating, making for about 95 percent yield. The planar devices had a 50 percent yield: 15 out of 30 devices showed macroscopic holes.</p><p>The German group used ultraviolet nanoimprint lithography and etching to make the nanostructured silicon surface. The final perovskite–silicon cell was 1 cm<sup>2</sup> in size. The nanoimprint techniques they used are relatively easy to scale up to large area, Tockhorn says. “Many researchers from academia regard nanoimprint lithography as a very promising tool for solar cells due to its sheer simplicity and versality in terms of structure type.”</p><p>Now that they have a proof-of-concept demonstration for making solution-based perovskite layers on textured silicon wafers, he says they are working on improving the devices to boost efficiency even further. “We need to aim for a fully textured perovskite top cell, that is textured at the front and at the interface between perovskite and silicon.” </p>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2022 16:06:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spectrum.ieee.org/perovskite</guid><category>Perovskite</category><category>Perovskite-silicon tandems</category><category>Nanostructured silicon</category><category>Tandem solar cell</category><category>Solar power</category><category>Photovoltaics</category><dc:creator>Prachi Patel</dc:creator><media:content medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/different-colored-layers-and-textures.jpg?id=32046017&amp;width=980"></media:content></item><item><title>Ukraine’s Grid Needs Parts—Will Western Firms Step Up?</title><link>https://spectrum.ieee.org/russia-targets-ukraine-grid</link><description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/a-truck-with-a-ukrainian-license-plate-and-a-vehicle-with-a-cherry-picker-multiple-workers-fix-electric-wires-on-poles.jpg?id=32034055&width=1200&height=800&coordinates=0%2C188%2C0%2C0"/><br/><br/><p>“Soldiers on the power front.” That’s what grid operator <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/company/ukrenergo/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Ukrenergo</a> calls the workers who’ve kept Ukraine’s high-voltage trunk lines buzzing since Russia invaded in February, risking live fire, mines, and missiles to restore war-damaged power lines and substations. Their sometimes deadly job intensified suddenly last month when Russian forces launched a focused assault on Ukraine’s power system that’s still underway. </p><p>“It has been the largest attack on energy infrastructure in history,” said Ukrenergo chairman Volodymyr Kudrytskyi in an email to <em>IEEE Spectrum</em>. “The scale of damage is now very large, the shelling continues, and no one can tell when it stops.” </p><p><a href="https://www.cnn.com/2022/10/28/europe/ukraine-russia-war-winter-intl-cmd/index.html" target="_blank">Russia has destroyed several coal-fired power plants</a>, including a cogeneration plant that heats large areas of Kyiv. But most of the barrage has targeted <a href="https://news.yahoo.com/as-temperatures-begin-to-fall-russia-steps-up-attacks-on-ukraines-vulnerable-power-grid-190531785.html" target="_blank">outdoor equipment</a>: the switchyards that link power stations to the grid, and over one-third of Ukrenergo’s substations.</p><p>The intensity can be fearsome. On Monday, Russia launched <a href="https://meduza.io/en/feature/2022/10/31/we-ll-tough-it-out-but-their-disgrace-will-cost-them-dearly?utm_source=email&utm_medium=briefly&utm_campaign=2022-11-01" target="_blank">50 cruise missiles as well as explosive drones during just one 2-hour span</a>. As a result, a majority of Kyiv’s population, along with much of central Ukraine, again lost power, water, and heat.</p><p>Ukraine, for obvious reasons, is disseminating only a blurry picture of the grid damage. Ukrenergo and <a href="https://dtek.com/en/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">DTEK</a>, which operates most of Ukraine’s coal-fired power stations plus power distribution in eastern Ukraine, restrict location-specific damage details fearing such intel will improve Russia’s targeting.</p><p class="pull-quote">DTEK and Ukrenergo say they need access to parts stockpiles held by grid operators and generators abroad. The reason comes down to the number, rarity, and manufacturing time for the parts that Russia is destroying.</p><p>The invader is already disturbingly precise. Kudrytskyi and DTEK executive director Dmytro Sakharuk say Russia hits the grid nodes most crucial to delivering power over large areas. That insight, they suggest, implies involvement of experts at Russian firms such as Moscow-based grid operator <a href="http://www.fsk-ees.ru" target="_blank">Rosseti</a> and electricity conglomerate <a href="https://www.fsk-ees.ru/eng/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">InterRAO</a>.</p><p>“There are several very important substations through which big parts of Ukraine are connected. Those look very similar to many others, some of which are closer to the border and easier to hit. They could also hit even bigger substations. But they mainly target those important substations,” Sakharuk told <em>IEEE </em><em>Spectrum</em> last week from a bunker in Kyiv during an air-raid warning. (Rosseti and InterRAO did not respond to requests for comment by our deadline.)</p><p>Damage now exceeds what Ukraine’s line worker/soldiers can repair, says Sakharuk, because they have run out of crucial components.</p><p>Governments are pledging to act. For example USAID’s Kyiv-based <a href="https://energysecurityua.org/" target="_blank">Energy Security Project</a> told <em>Spectrum</em> it is already acquiring “repair material” for power distribution in Sumy and Kharkiv and plans to help Ukrenergo with critical components and a backup control center in western Ukraine.</p><p>DTEK, however, had no offers from fellow power firms that it believes are most capable of supplying <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/feed/update/urn:li:activity:6985936295122341888?utm_source=share&utm_medium=member_desktop" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">critical equipment</a> that it needs as soon as possible. </p><p>Most European, U.S., and U.K. utilities contacted for comment did not respond, or referred questions to trade associations that did not respond. </p><h3>Missing in Action</h3><p>For Ukraine’s grid operators, the impact of Russia’s antigrid campaign is poignant and permanent. Within DTEK, 11 workers were injured on the job since 10 October, and one was killed. That brings DTEK’s occupational death toll since February to four. Ukrenergo lost four on the job since the invasion, including two killed in the northeast on 10 October and one in the north on 17 October when missiles struck substations.</p><p>Losses would be greater if Ukraine’s forces didn’t shoot down so many missiles. Western countries have promised to send more and better antimissile systems, spurred by the grid attacks. Also helping is <a href="https://mediacenter.org.ua/strong-some-nato-representatives-shown-interest-in-the-ukrainian-made-eppo-app-strong/" target="_blank">an app enabling citizens to report incoming missiles</a> hugging the ground to avoid radar detection.</p><p>Russia’s antigrid campaign has been deadly for Ukraine’s population, and it’s caused more blackouts followed by more and longer rolling blackouts. Losing power for hours or days adds one more burden to life under siege, but it is a necessary evil to prevent a nationwide grid collapse that could take days to unravel.</p><p>Also helping keep the grid from collapsing is <a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/ukraine-europe-electricity-grid" target="_self">Ukraine’s snap synchronization with Europe’s grid</a> in March. When attacks suddenly knock lines and plants out of operation in Ukraine, generators and batteries across the world’s largest interconnected power system ramp up to buffer the shock and maintain Ukraine’s 50-hertz AC frequency. </p><p>Until last month the same grid links enabled Ukraine to export power to Europe, earning crucial cash, but now they deliver European power <a href="https://uacrisis.org/en/day-246" target="_blank">to shore up domestic supplies</a>. Last week, amidst fears of energy shortages, <a href="https://www.upstreamonline.com/production/ukraine-braced-for-difficult-winter-after-missile-attacks/2-1-1341493" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Kyiv advised refugees wanting to return to wait until the spring</a>. </p><p>But to keep power on through the winter, DTEK and Ukrenergo say they need access to parts stockpiles held by grid operators and generators abroad. The reason comes down to the number, rarity, and manufacturing time for the parts that Russia is destroying.</p><p>Switchgear and circuit breakers are needed in great number, but easiest to replace. In some cases DTEK engineers can use two or three damaged units to assemble one working part, and a broad range of suppliers inside and outside Ukraine make equipment with the required specifications. </p><p>Harder components to find are digital control systems, which may require custom design, and transformers delivering the required Soviet-standard voltage conversions, which are rarely produced now outside Ukraine and Russia and take months to produce. </p><p class="pull-quote">Western utilities could be heeding Ukraine’s reticence to provide details that could help Russia. Or they could fear that supporting Ukraine’s power engineers could hang a bulls’-eye for Russian cyberattackers on their own operations.</p><p>DTEK has raised the possibility of retrieving some transformers from retired coal-fired power plants or substations in the former Soviet-block states of Eastern Europe. Sakharuk says international firms could also help by letting Ukraine jump ahead in  manufacturing queues.<br/></p><p>European companies have delivered supplies worth over €10 million to Ukraine during the war, according to the European Commission. Most have gone to Ukrenergo, which says it has received “substantial assistance from European system operators.”</p><p>More equipment is likely, but as yet there is little tangible to point to since 10 October. </p><p>Sakharuk said he knew of only one company, Warsaw-based grid operator <a href="https://www.pse.pl/web/pse-eng" target="_blank">Polskie Sieci Elektroenergetyczne</a> (PSE), that had committed new equipment, and it was for Ukrenergo. A spokesperson for PSE said it is also restoring a 400-kilovolt transmission link with Ukraine this year that will enable Europe’s grid to provide more support.</p><p>Germany’s <a href="https://www.amprion.net/index-2.html" target="_blank">Amprion</a> is also likely to provide more equipment according to Vitaliy Krusch, a Ukrainian-born operations planner for the Dortmund-based grid operator. </p><p class="shortcode-media shortcode-media-rebelmouse-image">
<img alt="3 men hold a Ukrainian flag in front of electrical equipment" class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="32a538563893431d2c3df5efea570c64" data-rm-shortcode-name="rebelmouse-image" id="03be4" loading="lazy" src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/3-men-hold-a-ukrainian-flag-in-front-of-electrical-equipment.jpg?id=32034064&width=980"/>
<small class="image-media media-caption" placeholder="Add Photo Caption...">Vitaliy Krusch of Amprion [left], Oleg Lysak of Ukrenergo [center], and Frank Lamberty of Amprion display the Ukrainian flag.</small><small class="image-media media-photo-credit" placeholder="Add Photo Credit...">Amprion</small></p><p>With Amprion’s backing, Krusch has spearheaded five aid convoys delivering over €2 million worth of supplies, including two large emergency generators, 160 tonnes of humanitarian and medical aid, and 15 ambulances. On return trips he has brought 78 refugees to Germany.</p><p>The scale of the work was visible during a video call last week with <em>Spectrum</em>, as Krusch’s 3-year-old daughter clamored for his attention. Krusch explained that she’s had less time with him since the war, between the aid work and night shifts in Amprion’s control room.</p><h3>Confronting War Crimes</h3><p>Krusch is gearing up for a sixth convoy to roll in mid-November. But when asked if it would carry grid components needed immediately in Ukraine, an Amprion spokesperson redirected that question to the Brussels-based <a href="https://www.entsoe.eu/" target="_blank">European Network of Transmission System Operators</a> (ENTSO-E), saying, “They are coordinating all aid.” </p><p>ENTSO-E, however, responded with a statement denying it was coordinating aid. “ENTSO-E is not involved in coordinating this activity on behalf of the member [transmission system operators],” wrote the organization’s spokesperson.</p><p>Other inquiries led to similar dead ends. <a href="https://www.nationalgrid.com/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">National Grid</a>, which operates in the United States and the United Kingdom, referred <em>Spectrum</em> to the London-based <a href="https://www.energynetworks.org/" target="_blank">Energy Networks Association</a>, which sent a press release from March about donated generators. U.S. transmission heavyweight <a href="https://aep.com/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">American Electric Power</a> suggested contacting the <a href="https://www.eei.org/" target="_blank">Edison Electric Institute</a>, a Washington, D.C.–based utility trade group. It didn’t respond. </p><p>Some of the nonresponse may be strategic. Western utilities could be heeding Ukraine’s reticence to provide details that could help Russia. Or they could fear that supporting Ukraine’s power engineers could hang a bulls’-eye for Russian cyberattackers on their own operations. </p><p>Russian power engineers may be fearing negative consequences as well, if they have provided expertise to maximize damage to Ukraine’s power system. </p><p>Experts on crimes against humanity conclude that <a href="http://unlawful,%20and%20many%20undoubtedly%20are,%20but%20are%20not%20necessarily%20so." rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">at least some of Russia’s attacks on the grid are war crimes</a>. And a recent investigation shows that those targeting Russia’s missiles and drones deserve serious scrutiny.</p><p>On 24 October, Amsterdam-based investigative organization <a href="https://www.bellingcat.com/news/uk-and-europe/2022/10/24/the-remote-control-killers-behind-russias-cruise-missile-strikes-on-ukraine/" target="_blank">Bellingcat uncloaked the “remote control killers” in the Russian Armed Forces</a> involved in missile targeting. </p><p>The secretive group includes dozens of mostly young military engineers with experience in missile programming, IT, and computer gaming, some of whom also worked at Russia’s Damascus command center while Russian cruise missiles struck anti-Assad forces in Syria. </p><p>Among other investigative tools, Bellingcat obtained phone records showing that calls between the group members and their officers “spiked shortly before many of the high-precision Russian cruise missile strikes that have killed hundreds and deprived millions in Ukraine of access to electricity and heating.” </p>]]></description><pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2022 15:15:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spectrum.ieee.org/russia-targets-ukraine-grid</guid><category>Russia-ukraine war</category><category>Power grid</category><category>Ukraine</category><category>Russia</category><category>Drones</category><category>Ukraine conflict</category><dc:creator>Peter Fairley</dc:creator><media:content medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/a-truck-with-a-ukrainian-license-plate-and-a-vehicle-with-a-cherry-picker-multiple-workers-fix-electric-wires-on-poles.jpg?id=32034055&amp;width=980"></media:content></item><item><title>Researchers Tap Infrared Light to Produce Hydrogen</title><link>https://spectrum.ieee.org/infrared-solar-panels</link><description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/sun-rays-coming-up-over-the-earth-s-horizon.jpg?id=32022079&width=1200&height=800&coordinates=0%2C167%2C0%2C167"/><br/><br/><p>A little more than half of the sun’s energy that reaches Earth does so as infrared rays. The longer wavelength of infrared light makes it less energetic, which makes it hard to capture with existing solar cells.</p><p>Researchers have made semiconductor nanocrystals that can convert infrared light to higher-energy visible light with an efficiency of over 5 percent, much higher than methods reported so far. The team could use the converted light to drive a chemical reaction that produces hydrogen fuel from methanol.</p><p>“Solar light in the infrared region has been a vast source of untapped energy,” says <a href="http://www.kuchem.kyoto-u.ac.jp/organization/member/bk_200710/sakamoto_e_preview.html" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Masanori Sakamoto</a>, a professor of chemistry at <a href="https://www.kyoto-u.ac.jp/en" target="_blank">Kyoto University</a>. Developing an artificial infrared light-to-fuel conversion system is key for the complete utilization of sustainable solar energy, he says.</p><hr/><p>Generating high-energy light from multiple low-energy photons, a process called infrared upconversion, has caught researchers’ attention recently as a way to utilize the full solar-energy spectrum. There are two prominent ways researchers are exploring upconversion, explains <a href="http://naik.rice.edu/gururaj-naik/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Gururaj Naik</a>, an electrical and computer engineering professor at <a href="https://www.rice.edu/" target="_blank">Rice University</a>, who was not involved in the research. One is to use organic molecules in which infrared light creates unpaired electrons; those electrons can then come together to emit higher-energy photons with about 5 percent efficiency. </p><p>The practical choice of materials for solar cells are lanthanides like ytterbium or erbium, which have multiple energy levels for electrons to occupy. When the material absorbs low-energy infrared photons, excited electrons jump up and around multiple times to reach higher energy levels before falling and emitting high-energy photons. Lanthanides have an upconversion efficiency of 0.5 to 2 percent.</p><p>In 2015, Naik and <a href="http://dionne.stanford.edu/" target="_blank">Jennifer Dionne</a> of Stanford University proposed a <a href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/1501.04159.pdf" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">new route</a> to infrared upconversion that relied on plasmon resonance, one that could in theory give an efficiency of 25 percent. <a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/plasmonics-takes-a-step-closer-to-realworld-applications" target="_self">Surface plasmons</a> are waves of electrons formed when light hits a metal surface. The excitation of plasmonic materials also creates high-energy “hot electrons” and “hot holes.”</p><p>Naik found a way to channel those hot electrons and holes into structures made of thin alternating layers of indium gallium nitride and gallium nitride. These structures act as quantum wells and trap the hot carriers, where they can recombine and release a high-energy photon. The efficiency was only 0.1 percent, far from the theoretical maximum.</p><p>This is where the Japanese researchers’ work comes in. By cleverly designing nanocrystals of cadmium sulfide and copper sulfide, they have made quantum wells into which the hot carriers flow more easily and get trapped better. The result is an infrared-to-visible upconversion efficiency of over 5 percent.</p><p>Their nanocrystals are hexagonal, platelike crystals of copper sulfide, with a border of cadmium sulfide. Infrared excitation in the copper sulfide creates hot electrons and holes, which are injected into the cadmium sulfide and recombine to emit high-energy light in the visible region.</p><p>Naik says the Japanese team chose the right material and nanoparticle size to achieve this feat. “As you shrink the particles, hot-carrier injection gets very efficient,” Naik says. “The metal-semiconductor interface also makes a very big difference. These researchers did both—created a better interface and smaller size.”</p><p>As a demonstration, the researchers placed the nanoparticles in a methanol-water solution and shone infrared light on it. Without the nanoparticles, the low-energy light would do nothing. But the nanoparticles soaked up the infrared light and produced higher-energy light, which was absorbed by platinum catalysts to trigger a chemical reaction that produces hydrogen.</p><p>Applying this system in solar cells to produce electricity from infrared light could be tricky, Sakamoto admits. So for now, the team is planning to pursue infrared-driven solar fuels. “We are planning to apply the current system to other IR-driven photocatalytic reactions,” he says.</p>]]></description><pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2022 14:19:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spectrum.ieee.org/infrared-solar-panels</guid><category>Hydrogen</category><category>Upconversion nanoparticles</category><category>Quantum well</category><category>Infrared light</category><category>Solar power</category><dc:creator>Prachi Patel</dc:creator><media:content medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/sun-rays-coming-up-over-the-earth-s-horizon.jpg?id=32022079&amp;width=980"></media:content></item><item><title>High Voltage Aerial Covered Conductor</title><link>https://engineeringresources.spectrum.ieee.org/free/w_defa3382/prgm.cgi</link><description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/high-voltage-aerial-covered-conductor.gif?id=32010135&width=1200&height=800&coordinates=79%2C0%2C79%2C0"/><br/><br/><p>Hendrix Aerial Covered Conductor systems have been in use worldwide for almost 72 years. Starting in 1951 at 5 kV and 15 kV classes, usage grew rapidly to include 25 kV, 35 kV, and 46 kV. It was not until 1995 that 69 kV spacer cable was introduced and shortly thereafter, 69 kV Tree Wire systems. The march towards high voltage didn't stop there, however, and 115 kV Spacer Cable Systems were introduced in 2019.</p> <p>This paper will describe the basic concept, history, and advantages of covered conductor systems compared to other design options, review individual component features including design considerations, and how and why the concept of aerial covered conductor systems migrated to transmission voltage classes. Also discussed will be motivation for compact line design at transmission voltages, and why this is important not only for reliability and economics, but also from a standpoint of minimization of ecosystem disruption and promotion of carbon capture.</p>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2022 18:56:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://engineeringresources.spectrum.ieee.org/free/w_defa3382/prgm.cgi</guid><category>Type:whitepaper</category><dc:creator>Hendrix</dc:creator><media:content medium="image" type="image/gif" url="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/high-voltage-aerial-covered-conductor.gif?id=32010135&amp;width=980"></media:content></item><item><title>Why Is Hydroelectricity So Green, and Yet Unfashionable?</title><link>https://spectrum.ieee.org/hydroelectric-power</link><description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/an-aerial-view-of-a-long-concrete-dam-the-farther-end-of-yangtze-river-which-rests-on-the-bank-of-a-river-at-which-point-the.jpg?id=31978226&width=1200&height=800&coordinates=0%2C131%2C0%2C131"/><br/><br/><p>
<strong>I live in Manitoba</strong>, a province of Canada where all but a tiny fraction of electricity is generated from the potential energy of water. Unlike in British Columbia and Quebec, where generation relies on huge dams, our dams on the Nelson River are low, with hydraulic heads of no more than 30 meters, which creates only small reservoirs. Of course, the potential is the product of mass, the gravitational constant, and height, but the dams’ modest height is readily compensated for by a large mass, as the mighty river flowing out of Lake Winnipeg continues its course to Hudson Bay.
</p>
<p>
	You would think this is about as “green” as it can get, but in 2022 that would be a mistake. There is no end of gushing about China’s cheap solar panels—but when was the last time you saw a paean to hydroelectricity?
</p>
<hr/>
<p>
	Construction of large dams began before World War II. The United States got the Grand Coulee on the Columbia River, the Hoover Dam on the Colorado, and the dams of the Tennessee Valley Authority. After the war, construction of large dams moved to the Soviet Union, Africa, South America (Brazil’s Itaipu, at its completion in 1984 the world’s largest dam, with 14 gigawatts capacity), and Asia, where it culminated in China’s unprecedented effort. China now has three of the world’s six largest hydroelectric stations: Three Gorges, 22.5 GW (the largest in the world); Xiluodu, 13.86 GW; and Wudongde, 10.2 GW. Baihetan on the Jinsha River should soon begin full-scale operation and become the world’s second-largest station (16 GW).
</p>
<p>
	But China’s outsize drive for hydroelectricity is unique. By the 1990s, large hydro stations had lost their green halo in the West and come to be seen as environmentally undesirable. They are blamed for displacing populations, disrupting the flow of sediments and the migration of fish, destroying natural habitat and biodiversity, degrading water quality, and for the decay of submerged vegetation and the consequent release of methane, a greenhouse gas. There is thus no longer a place for Big Hydro in the pantheon of electric greenery. Instead, that pure status is now reserved above all for wind and solar. This ennoblement is strange, given that wind projects require enormous quantities of embodied energy in the form of steel for towers, plastics for blades, and concrete for foundations. The manufacture of solar panels involves the environmental costs from mining, waste disposal, and carbon emissions.
</p>
<p class="pull-quote">
	In 2020 the world’s hydro stations produced 75 percent more electricity than wind and solar combined and accounted for 16 percent of all global generation
</p>
<p>
	And hydro still matters more than any other form of renewable generation. In 2020, the world’s hydro stations produced 75 percent more electricity than wind and solar combined (4,297 versus 2,447 terawatt-hours) and accounted for 16 percent of all global generation (compared with nuclear electricity’s 10 percent). The share rises to about 60 percent in Canada and 97 percent in Manitoba. And some less affluent countries in Africa and Asia are still determined to build more such stations. The largest projects now under construction outside China are the 
	<a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/squabbling-over-the-waters-of-the-river-nile" target="_self">Grand Ethiopian Renaissance Dam</a> on the White Nile (6.55 GW) and Pakistan’s Diamer-Bhasha (4.5 GW) and Dasu (4.3 GW) on the Indus.
</p>
<p>
	I never understood why dams have suffered such a reversal of fortune. There is no need to build megastructures, with their inevitable undesirable effects. And everywhere in the world there are still plenty of opportunities to develop modest projects whose combined capacities could provide not only excellent sources of clean electricity but also serve as long-term 
	<a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/4-new-ways-to-store-renewable-energy-with-water" target="_self">stores of energy</a>, as reservoirs for drinking water and irrigation, and for recreation and aquaculture.
</p>
<p>
	I am glad to live in a place that is reliably supplied by electricity generated by low-head turbines powered by flowing water. Manitoba’s six stations on the Nelson River have a combined capacity slightly above 4 GW. Just try to get the equivalent here from solar in January, when the snow is falling and the sun barely rises above the horizon!
</p>
<div class="flourish-embed flourish-chart" data-src="visualisation/11327493?672664"><script src="https://public.flourish.studio/resources/embed.js"></script></div>
<p>
<em>This article appears in the November 2022 print issue as “Hydropower, the Forgotten Renewable.”</em>
</p>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2022 15:00:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spectrum.ieee.org/hydroelectric-power</guid><category>Renewable energy</category><category>Hydroelectric power</category><category>Hydroelectric dam</category><dc:creator>Vaclav Smil</dc:creator><media:content medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/an-aerial-view-of-a-long-concrete-dam-the-farther-end-of-yangtze-river-which-rests-on-the-bank-of-a-river-at-which-point-the.jpg?id=31978226&amp;width=980"></media:content></item><item><title>Can Alt-Fuel Credits Accelerate EV Adoption?</title><link>https://spectrum.ieee.org/evs-boost-renewables-program</link><description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/car-sitting-in-a-parking-lot.jpg?id=31999276&width=1200&height=800&coordinates=0%2C104%2C0%2C105"/><br/><br/><p>The United States is home to the world’s largest biofuel program. For the past decade and a half, the U.S. government has mandated that the country’s government-operated planes, trains, and automobiles run on a fuel blend partly made from corn- and soybean-based biofuels.<br/></p><p>It’s a program with decidedly mixed results. Now, it might get a breath of new life. </p><p>Earlier this month, Reuters <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/autos-transportation/exclusive-us-epa-expected-propose-electric-cars-be-eligible-renewable-fuel-2022-10-05/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">reported</a> that the program could be expanded to provide power for charging electric vehicles. It would be the biggest change in the history of a program that has, in part, failed to live up to its designers’ ambitious dreams.</p><p>In one way, the program in question—the Renewable Fuel Standard (RFS)—is a relic from a bygone era. U.S. lawmakers established the RFS in 2005 and expanded it in 2007, well before solar panels, wind turbines, and electric vehicles became the stalwarts of decarbonization they are today.</p><p>The RFS, in essence, mandated that the blend powering engines in the nation’s official service vehicles run on a certain amount of renewable fuel. Petroleum refiners have to put a certain amount of renewable fuel—such as ethanol derived from corn or cellulose—into the U.S. supply. If a refiner couldn’t manage it, it could buy credits, called Renewable Identification Numbers (RINs), from a supplier that did.</p><p>From 2006, the RFS set a schedule of yearly obligations through 2022, with annually rising RIN targets. The long-term targets were more ambitious than the actual amount of biofuel the U.S. ever actually produced. (It didn’t help that fossil fuel producers <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/commodities/what-is-stake-us-biofuel-blending-law-2022-beyond-2022-01-11/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">fought</a> tooth and nail to reduce their obligations. Meanwhile, agriculture-industry lobbyists <a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/us-usa-biofuels/trump-epa-finalizes-2020-biofuel-rule-corn-lobby-objects-idUSKBN1YN20M" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">fought</a> just as hard against those reductions.) </p><p>By the mid-2010s, the U.S. Environmental Protection Agency, which stewards the RFS, had repeatedly downsized the targets by nearly 25 percent. In 2016, a U.S. government report <a href="https://www.gao.gov/assets/gao-17-94.pdf" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">stated</a>, quite bluntly, that “it is unlikely that the goals of the RFS will be met as envisioned.” A more recent study <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC8892349/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">found</a> that, since the program coaxed farmers into using more land for corn cultivation, RFS biofuel wasn’t actually any less carbon-intensive than gasoline.</p><p>Now, it is 2022. Amidst a backdrop of rising fuel prices, the Biden administration might bring the RFS its greatest shakeup yet.</p><p>The proposed changes aren’t set in stone. The EPA is under orders to propose a 2023 mandate by 16 November. Any electric vehicle add-on would likely debut by then. Reuters <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/environment/biden-administration-leans-tesla-guidance-renewable-fuel-policy-reform-2022-06-23/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">previously reported</a> that the Biden administration has reached out to electric vehicle maker Tesla to collaborate on crafting the mandates.</p><p>The changes might bolster the RFS with a new type of credit, an “e-RIN,” which would mark an amount of energy used for charging electric vehicles. The changes might nudge the RFS away from corn and oil: Car-charging companies and power-plant biogas suppliers might become eligible, too.</p><p>It wouldn’t be this administration’s first attempt at boosting electric vehicles. While California <a href="https://www.automotiveworld.com/articles/what-does-californias-ice-ban-mean-for-the-us/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">leads</a> state governments in slating a 2035 target for ending most internal combustion vehicle sales, the federal government’s ambitious Inflation Reduction Act allocated funds for tax credits on electric vehicles. That plan, however, has proven contentious due to an asterisk: A $7,500-per-vehicle credit would apply only to cars for which most battery material and components come from North America.</p><p>Many analysts <a href="https://www.csis.org/analysis/ira-and-ev-tax-credits%E2%80%94can-we-kill-multiple-birds-one-stone-0" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">believe</a> that the plan could actually slow electric vehicle take-up rather than accelerate it. And although the plan seeks to reduce U.S. electric-vehicle supply chains’ reliance on Chinese rare earths and battery components, U.S.-friendly governments in Europe, Japan, and South Korea <a href="https://www.csis.org/analysis/ira-and-ev-tax-credits%E2%80%94can-we-kill-multiple-birds-one-stone-0" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">have criticized</a> the plan for purportedly discriminating against non-U.S. vehicles, potentially breaching World Trade Organisation rules.</p><p>Nunes says it’s currently unclear whether federal government action via a fuel standard would be more effective than direct investment. It’s not the only question with an answer that is still in flux. </p><p>“How much cleaner are electric vehicles relative to internal combustion engines that are powered by fuels that fall under the RFS?” says Nunes. “Because that’s really the comparison that you care about.”</p><p>What that means is that any electric vehicle standard will only be as carbon-free as the supply chains that go into making the vehicles and the electrical grid from which they draw power; and that puts the pressure on governments, electricity providers, and consumers alike to decarbonize the grid.</p><p>Meanwhile, in a future U.S. where electric vehicles come to dominate the roads, sidelining internal combustion engines and liquefied fuels for good, do biofuels and the RFS’s original purpose still have a place?</p><p>Nunes believes so. “There are certainly areas of the economy where electrification does not make a lot of sense,” he says.</p><p>In the world of aviation, for instance, battery tech hasn’t quite advanced to a point that would make electric flights feasible. “That’s where, I think, using things like sustainable aviation fuels and biofuels, et cetera, makes a lot more sense,” Nunes says.</p>]]></description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spectrum.ieee.org/evs-boost-renewables-program</guid><category>Electric vehicles</category><category>Alternative fuels</category><category>Alternative energy</category><category>Biofuels</category><category>Renewable energy</category><dc:creator>Rahul Rao</dc:creator><media:content medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/car-sitting-in-a-parking-lot.jpg?id=31999276&amp;width=980"></media:content></item><item><title>Tiny Ultrasound Sensors Could Monitor EV Batteries</title><link>https://spectrum.ieee.org/ev-battery</link><description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/a-man-in-protective-goggles-sits-at-a-bench-adjusting-a-knob-on-the-bench-is-a-silver-pouch-in-a-stand-with-wires-attached-to-i.jpg?id=31994641&width=1200&height=800&coordinates=0%2C0%2C0%2C127"/><br/><br/><p>Ultrasound sensors as small as a thumbnail can scan lithium-ion batteries to check their charge, health, and safety, a new study finds.</p><p>The findings suggest that ultrasound—that is, sound waves at frequencies higher than human hearing can detect—might one day help <a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/ev-battery-fast-charging" target="_self">electric vehicles</a> better estimate how much charge remains in their batteries. This approach might also help detect unstable batteries on the verge of disaster, quickly test battery quality during manufacturing, and identify which used batteries are healthy enough to be resold to reduce waste, says study lead author <a href="https://www.ornl.gov/staff-profile/hongbin-sun" target="_blank">Hongbin Sun</a>, an ultrasonic engineer at the <a href="https://www.ornl.gov/" target="_blank">Oak Ridge National Laboratory</a>, in Tennessee.</p><p>Estimating how much charge is left in a commercial lithium-ion battery is currently a challenging task. For instance, <a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/electric-vehicles" target="_self">electric vehicles</a> typically experience an uncertainty of about <a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/quantum-sensor-range-anxiety" target="_self">10 percent</a> when estimating battery charge. This in turn reduces their driving range by about 10 percent, to ensure that they stay within their batteries’ safety margins.</p><hr/><p>In order to find a simple, inexpensive, and nondestructive way to estimate lithium-ion battery charge, scientists investigated ultrasound. As lithium-ion batteries discharge and recharge, the underlying electrochemical reactions lead to mechanical changes in the properties and structure of their components, which ultrasound scans can detect, in principle.</p><p>Previous work on ultrasonic scans of lithium-ion batteries each typically experimented with just one ultrasonic frequency. In the new study, researchers examined multiple ultrasonic frequencies to see what advantages and disadvantages each might have in estimating battery charge.</p><p>In experiments, scientists used commercial off-the-shelf ultrasound sensors about 1.25 centimeters wide to monitor 2.4 ampere-hour lithium-ion battery cells during charging and discharging. They tested relatively low-frequency 750-kilohertz, 1-megahertz, and 1.5-MHz ultrasound waves, since battery materials largely absorb frequencies higher than that. (For reference, humans can hear frequencies between roughly 20 hertz and 20 kHz.)</p><p class="shortcode-media shortcode-media-rebelmouse-image rm-resized-container rm-resized-container-25 rm-float-left" data-rm-resized-container="25%" style="float: left;">
<img alt="Diagram of a grey rectangle labelled pouch cell, with an ultrasonic transmitter on top and an ultrasonic receiver below." class="rm-shortcode rm-resized-image" data-rm-shortcode-id="f46a7a6e7fd70ffb865f2bb2aa6cb696" data-rm-shortcode-name="rebelmouse-image" id="24795" loading="lazy" src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/diagram-of-a-grey-rectangle-labelled-pouch-cell-with-an-ultrasonic-transmitter-on-top-and-an-ultrasonic-receiver-below.jpg?id=31994690&width=980" style="max-width: 100%"/>
<small class="image-media media-caption" placeholder="Add Photo Caption..." style="max-width: 100%;">An ultrasonic transmitter can send ultrasonic waves through a lithium-ion battery to an ultrasonic receiver, conveying data on the battery’s state.</small><small class="image-media media-photo-credit" placeholder="Add Photo Credit..." style="max-width: 100%;">ORNL/U.S. Department of Energy/Elsevier</small></p><p>The researchers observed that the wave velocities of all three frequencies were linked with the state of charge. The way the waves weakened also helped reveal how materials in the battery changed in terms of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Phase_(matter)" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">phase</a> during charging and discharging.</p><p>“The method we proposed provides a fast and low-cost solution for battery performance assessment and understanding material phase changes during battery charge and discharge,” Sun says. “For industrial-scale applications, it could potentially be used for the prediction of the battery state of charge and assessment of whether the battery is losing the ability to hold its charge.”</p><p>Sun notes that a potential application of this method would embed low-cost piezoelectric ultrasound sensors in electric-vehicle batteries to continuously monitor them. He says the technique currently has an uncertainty of about 5 percent when estimating battery charge, roughly twice as good as current techniques. By improving sensor calibration and accounting for temperature effects during measurements, “we expect the error can be decreased to about 2 percent,” Sun says. “We expect this reduction in uncertainty to translate into improved EV range.”</p><p>Moreover, using ultrasound scans, “flawed batteries can be easily detected,” Sun says. Ultrasound scanning “may also have the potential to provide an early warning for battery fires, since ultrasound is very sensitive to temperature changes and material changes inside a battery.”</p><p>Future research needs to test this technique on multiple kinds of lithium-ion batteries, as well as a range of charging rates and a larger number of charging cycles; the method “still needs a lot of additional work and validation of the technique before commercialization,” Sun says.</p><p>The scientists detailed <a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/abs/pii/S0378775322010680?via=ihub" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">their findings</a> in the 30 November issue of the <em>Journal of Power Sources</em>.</p>]]></description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 15:39:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spectrum.ieee.org/ev-battery</guid><category>Ultrasound</category><category>Batteries</category><category>Lithium-ion batteries</category><category>Electric vehicles</category><dc:creator>Charles Q. Choi</dc:creator><media:content medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/a-man-in-protective-goggles-sits-at-a-bench-adjusting-a-knob-on-the-bench-is-a-silver-pouch-in-a-stand-with-wires-attached-to-i.jpg?id=31994641&amp;width=980"></media:content></item><item><title>A Rich Harvest in the Desert</title><link>https://spectrum.ieee.org/lithium-mining</link><description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/image.jpg?id=31994788&width=980"/><br/><br/><p>The Big Picture features technology through the lens of photographers.</p><p>Every month, <em>IEEE Spectrum</em> selects the most stunning technology images recently captured by photographers around the world. We choose images that reflect an important advance, or a trend, or that are just mesmerizing to look at. We feature all images on our site, and one also appears on our monthly print edition.</p><p>Enjoy the latest images, and if you have suggestions, leave a comment below.</p><h3>Lithium Mining: A Harvest in the Desert</h3><br/><img alt="Giant evaporation pools in the Atacama Desert yield lithium and salt." class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="b1f26c7fc61483bcf25e3c4b201b429c" data-rm-shortcode-name="rebelmouse-image" id="f47d9" loading="lazy" src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/giant-evaporation-pools-in-the-atacama-desert-yield-lithium-and-salt.jpg?id=31959150&width=980"/><p>
	The rise in global demand for lithium—spurred mainly by the manufacturing of lithium-ion batteries for electric vehicles—has triggered expanded mining of the world’s known major caches of lithium. One of the richest deposits of lithium ore is in Chile’s Atacama Desert. The area, said to be the driest region on earth, has long been a premier source of sodium nitrate, or saltpeter. To extract lithium, miners pump a naturally occurring brine from beneath Atacama’s salt flats into giant evaporation pools on the surface. Initially, the liquid is a dark blue color. But over the course of 18 months, the sun and the arid desert air strip away a great deal of the brine’s moisture. Left behind are pools of a bright yellow slurry that has a roughly 6-percent lithium content. A nearby chemical plant processes the slurry into lithium carbonate powder suitable for making batteries for automotive propulsion.
</p><p class="caption">
John Moore/Getty Images
</p><h3>James Webb's Far-Fetched Scenerey</h3><br/><img alt="James Webb\u2019s view into deep space has yielded a view of a distant constellation that is reminiscent of a mountain range under a starry night sky." class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="3749d32dc9f8904f48d90ab87856371e" data-rm-shortcode-name="rebelmouse-image" id="c282b" loading="lazy" src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/james-webb-u2019s-view-into-deep-space-has-yielded-a-view-of-a-distant-constellation-that-is-reminiscent-of-a-mountain-range-und.jpg?id=31959187&width=980"/><p>
	Objects in the James Webb Space Telescope’s imager are farther away than they appear. The level of detail in this image is startling, considering that it would take 9,100 years of travel at the speed of light to reach this gas cloud from Earth. That’s a long commute. Captured in the picture are the so-called Cosmic Cliffs. What appears at first glance to be a mountain range is actually a sprawling pocket of gas inside a star cluster known as NGC 3324. The Hubble Telescope has already captured images of the constellation, so it was only natural to produce an updated set of glamour shots using James Webb’s more sensitive imaging equipment.
</p><p class="caption">
	ESA/CSA/STSCI/NASA
</p><h3>Alternative Fuel From Artificial Leaf</h3><br/><img alt="A green-and-blue device laminated in clear plastic floats on a river, with Cambridge University\u2019s Kings College in the background." class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="68a00ac546c8a6048416ad6c2324f6c2" data-rm-shortcode-name="rebelmouse-image" id="ff495" loading="lazy" src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/a-green-and-blue-device-laminated-in-clear-plastic-floats-on-a-river-with-cambridge-university-u2019s-kings-college-in-the-back.jpg?id=31959214&width=980"/><p>For eons, leaves have been creating the fuel that plants run on virtually out of thin air. A little sun, plus some oxygen and water, is enough to keep a plant going strong. Now, scientists are making strides in the ongoing effort to reverse engineer the leaf. The aim is to pull the carbon dioxide from the air and, using a catalyst, generate a cleaner alternative to the fossil fuels on which we so greatly depend. Researchers will continue trying to improve the yield and efficiency of photovoltaic devices designed to produce hydrogen fuel by splitting the water covering about three-fourths of the Earth’s surface. But a team at the University of Cambridge has demonstrated an artificial leaf that sits on the surface of a body of water and does a fairly good job of producing syngas from carbon dioxide and water. The version shown here (floating on the River Cam near the Cambridge campus) has a surface area of only 100 square centimeters. The Cambridge team already has its sights set on bigger models that would each be capable of powering dozens of homes in carbon-neutral fashion.<br/></p><p class="caption">
	VIRGIL ANDREI
</p><h3>Better Bot Battles</h3><br><img alt="Sparks fly in the BattleBots arena as a green robot attempts to saw open its red-and-black opponent like a can of tuna." class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="245dcffa7b23c43b5901f4b684719188" data-rm-shortcode-name="rebelmouse-image" id="32d71" loading="lazy" src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/sparks-fly-in-the-battlebots-arena-as-a-green-robot-attempts-to-saw-open-its-red-and-black-opponent-like-a-can-of-tuna.jpg?id=31959216&width=980"/><p>For 22 years, roboticists have been dreaming up automaton warriors and sending their mechanical creations into battle. Sparks fly when these mean machines try to smash, saw, or burn their opponents into submission. The BattleBots competition is so thrilling that it continues to be televised despite a surfeit of viewing options competing for eyeballs. The latest season of the show began filming this month. When it airs, expect to see bots that have better batteries, more-refined control systems, and real-time telemetry that lets the human operators know when to, say, power down a weapon to keep it from being destroyed by overheating.<br/></p><p class="caption">
	DISCOVERY CHANNEL
</p></br>]]></description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spectrum.ieee.org/lithium-mining</guid><category>The big picture</category><category>James webb space telescope</category><category>Photosynthesis</category><category>Battlebots</category><category>Automatons</category><category>Renewable energy</category><category>Astronomy</category><dc:creator>Willie Jones</dc:creator><media:content medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://assets.rbl.ms/31994788/origin.jpg"></media:content></item><item><title>Fast-Charging EV Batteries With Nickel Foil</title><link>https://spectrum.ieee.org/ev-battery-fast-charging</link><description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/a-grey-box-labeled-ec-power-with-a-minus-and-plus-sticker-on-the-side-and-equipment-on-top.jpg?id=31967086&width=1200&height=800&coordinates=0%2C53%2C0%2C54"/><br/><br/><p>Standard electric-vehicle batteries can recharge much of their range in just 10 minutes with the addition of a thin sheet of nickel inside them, a new study finds. This could provide a welcome and economically attractive alternative to expensive EVs that carry massive and massively expensive battery packs. </p><p>If faster-charging options were available, enabling the EV’s sticker price to drop substantially, some researchers suspect consumers’ EV phobia and industry dogma against “<a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/quantum-sensor-range-anxiety" target="_self">range anxiety</a>“ could be overcome. </p><p>For instance, a conventional long-range EV with a 120-kilowatt-hour pack that requires an hour to recharge could be replaced with an EV with a 60-kWh pack capable of 10-minute fast charging while preserving a very similar travel time during long-distance trips.<br/></p><p class="pull-quote">“Lithium-ion batteries can be very stable and safe at elevated temperatures with a simple adjustment of battery materials—[and] elevated temperatures give us fast-charging capability.”<br/>—Chao-Yang Wang, Penn State</p><p>In the new study, researchers experimented with a lithium-ion battery with a roughly 560-kilometer range when fully charged. (The battery’s energy density was 265 watt-hours-per-kilogram.) By adding an ultrathin nickel foil to its interior, they could recharge it to 70 percent in 11 minutes for a roughly 400-km range, and 75 percent in 12 minutes for a roughly 440-km range.<br/></p><p>“Our technology enables smaller, faster-charging batteries to be deployed for mass adoption of affordable electric cars,” says study senior author Chao-Yang Wang, a battery engineer at Pennsylvania State University. “When we use up 200 miles per charge, we can stop and go to the restroom, and 10 minutes later the vehicle is recharged and ready for another 200 miles of travel. So there is no range anxiety this way.”</p><p>In <a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/lithiumion-battery-warms-up-operates-in-subzero-temperatures" target="_self">2016</a>, Wang and his colleagues added nickel foil to lithium-ion battery interiors to heat them and help them perform better in the freezing cold. In the new study, they similarly used nickel foil to warm EV batteries and boost their performance, a strategy they also pursued in 2021 for <a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/evtol-battery" target="_self">batteries for electric flying cars</a>.</p><p>“Conventional lithium-ion batteries are developed for man-portable electronics—as such, scientists and developers are very afraid of heat,” Wang says. “We went against this traditional mind-set.”</p><p>Batteries operate best when they are hot, but not too hot. Keeping batteries consistently at precisely the right temperature has been a major challenge for battery engineers. In the past, they relied on external, bulky heating and cooling systems to regulate battery temperature, which respond slowly and waste a lot of energy, Wang says.</p><p class="pull-quote">“Our work improves the current state of art by three times.”<br/>—Chao-Yang Wang, Penn State</p><p>In the new study, the scientists regulated battery temperatures from inside the batteries using nickel foil. “We needed a simple way to get the battery to an elevated temperature very quickly—within a minute, since fast charging only lasts for 10 minutes,” Wang says. “We happened to have invented an internal heating foil in our earlier work on self-heating batteries.”</p><p>All in all, they found “lithium-ion batteries can be very stable and safe at elevated temperatures with a simple adjustment of battery materials,” Wang says. This let them “enjoy the side benefit that elevated temperatures give us fast-charging capability.”</p><p>The battery lasted for more than 900 cycles when charged to 75 percent, for a range of about 402,000 km, and roughly 2,000 cycles when charged to 70 percent, for a range of about 804,000 km—or 500,000 miles. All in all, then, this performance is equivalent to a half-million mile range in which every charge is a fast charge, they say.</p><p>The scientists note their work “is quite different from current electric cars claiming 100 or 150 miles after 10 minutes of charging because these cars usually have a 600-mile cruise range, so filling energy for 150 miles is essentially equal to charging to 25 percent,” Wang says. “Our work improves the current state of art by three times.”</p><p>These findings come as California, the largest auto market in the United States, aims to effectively retire the internal combustion engine by 2035. The new fast-charging technology works for most energy-dense batteries, and permits the use of electric vehicles with relatively small, cheap batteries that can nevertheless avoid range anxiety due to fast charging, Wang says.</p><p>Wang’s lab partnered with startup <a href="https://ecpowergroup.com/" target="_blank">EC Power</a> to develop the technology. The company is now working to manufacture and commercialize the fast-charging battery.</p><p>In the future, “we would like to achieve charging ultrahigh energy density batteries to 80 percent in 5 minutes. This will give consumers a similar experience to filling gas,” Wang says. “We believe that we have laid the scientific foundation for this ultimate goal, and what is left is to fine-tune more stable materials and our thermal modulation strategy.”</p><p>The scientists detailed <a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-022-05281-0" target="_blank">their findings</a> online 12 October in the journal <em>Nature</em>.</p>]]></description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 15:02:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spectrum.ieee.org/ev-battery-fast-charging</guid><category>Lithium-ion batteries</category><category>Range anxiety</category><category>Rechargeable batteries</category><category>Fast charging</category><category>Nickel</category><category>Electric vehicles</category><dc:creator>Charles Q. Choi</dc:creator><media:content medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/a-grey-box-labeled-ec-power-with-a-minus-and-plus-sticker-on-the-side-and-equipment-on-top.jpg?id=31967086&amp;width=980"></media:content></item><item><title>The Inflation Reduction Act vs. China’s PV Dominance</title><link>https://spectrum.ieee.org/senate-bill-inflation-reduction-act-solar</link><description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/many-sheep-below-blue-solar-panels.jpg?id=31948365&width=1200&height=800&coordinates=0%2C142%2C0%2C142"/><br/><br/><p>The falling costs of solar photovoltaics have been crucial for the clean-energy technology’s rise. And China has been <a href="https://www.iea.org/news/the-world-needs-more-diverse-solar-panel-supply-chains-to-ensure-a-secure-transition-to-net-zero-emissions" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">instrumental</a> in making <a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/us-imposes-much-stiffer-tariffs-on-chinese-solar-manufacturers" target="_self">solar power affordable</a> in many parts of the world, thanks in part to the country’s low energy and labor costs. </p><p>On the flip side, over the past decade, the global manufacturing capacity for solar panels has shifted out of Europe, Japan, and the United States almost entirely to China. According to a <a href="https://www.iea.org/reports/solar-pv-global-supply-chains" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">recent report</a> by the International Energy Agency, the country manufactures over 80 percent of all the main elements needed for solar panels: <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Polycrystalline_silicon" target="_blank">polysilicon</a>, ingots, wafers, cells, and modules. This heavy concentration of the PV supply chain in one region of the world does not bode well for a secure, risk-free transition. </p><p>Many hopes are on the <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/08/15/by-the-numbers-the-inflation-reduction-act/" target="_blank">Inflation Reduction Act</a> (IRA), signed by President Biden into law in August, to spur the U.S. solar industry. The IRA will provide financial incentives that encourage domestic manufacturing and deployment of solar technologies. </p><p>But a limited domestic supply chain of solar PV components in the United States has analysts being cautiously optimistic. “The IRA is definitely going to have an impact, but a lot hinges on the details,” says Sylvia Leyva Martinez, an analyst at research and consultancy firm <a href="https://www.woodmac.com/" target="_blank">Wood Mackenzie</a> and author of a <a href="https://www.woodmac.com/press-releases/u.s.-solar-market-ready-for-rebound-after-tumultuous-first-half-of-2022/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">new Solar Market Insight report</a> together with the <a href="https://www.seia.org/" target="_blank">Solar Energy Industries Association</a> (SEIA).</p><p>The IRA will give <a href="https://www.pv-magazine.com/2022/08/15/whats-in-the-inflation-reduction-act-for-the-solar-industry/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">tax credits</a> to solar power projects that purchase domestically produced hardware. It will provide direct tax credits for manufacturing polysilicon and other components in the solar supply chain, and it will give loan guarantees to new factories that make any component.</p><p>According to the Wood Mackenzie report, the IRA should help the solar market grow by 40 percent, or about 62 gigawatts of additional solar capacity, between 2023 and 2027. But, says Martinez, “I don’t think it would remove China’s position as the market leader because they already dominate.”</p><p>It’s simply too hard for any other country to compete with the low costs of solar PV manufacturing in China right now. If U.S. solar-module manufacturing capacity does indeed increase enough, she says, and “if they’re competitive enough with those produced in China or Southeast Asia, that would help other countries have an alternative source for modules.” </p><p>In the meantime, what could more immediately help the U.S. market, and in turn those in Europe and Japan, is the creation of a demand-supply ecosystem, she says. Case in point: the June <a href="https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/leading-us-solar-companies-announce-consortium-to-spend-over-6-billion-on-solar-modules-and-support-expansion-of-domestic-supply-chain-301571646.html" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">announcement</a> of the US Solar Buyer Consortium formed by four major solar project developers in the United States. These companies—led by <a href="https://www.aes.com/" target="_blank">AES Corp</a>., which provides clean energy to the likes of Amazon, Google, and Microsoft—have committed to buying 7 GW of domestic solar panels each year starting in 2024. </p><p>“That could match U.S. demand with U.S. supply,” she says. “But it could also set an example for how supply-demand partnerships are helping to create a self-sufficient domestic market.”</p><p>The big hurdle for the U.S. solar industry to overcome is its supply constraint, says Martinez. The United States has a small number of solar-module manufacturers with limited production capacity. The same applies to polysilicon: a small amount of polysilicon is produced in the country today, but most of it is for electronics, not for solar applications. And while a few U.S. polysilicon companies, such as <a href="https://www.recsilicon.com/" target="_blank">REC Silicon</a>, are increasing production, in response to the IRA, China currently makes more than three-quarters of the world’s polysilicon. </p><p>Polysilicon and module capacity aside, there is no production of silicon ingot, wafer, or solar cells in the United States at all. “In order to have a fully domestic supply, there needs to be increased production capacity across the supply chain,” she says.</p><p>Given these supply-chain issues, Wood Mackenzie and the SEIA don’t expect the full benefits of the IRA to kick in until at least 2024. The SEIA expects the IRA to create new investments in domestic solar module, tracker, inverter, and racking production capacity within the next three years, and investments in solar ingot, wafer, and cell capacity within the next five years. </p><p>Time will tell whether the IRA will boost U.S. solar, says Martinez, but for now it’s still a welcome measure. As Martinez’s colleague Michelle Davis, lead author of the report, put it in a press release: “The Inflation Reduction Act has given the solar industry the most long-term certainty it has ever had.”</p>]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 15 Oct 2022 14:34:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spectrum.ieee.org/senate-bill-inflation-reduction-act-solar</guid><category>Solar manufacturing</category><category>Inflation reduction act</category><category>China</category><category>Solar panels</category><dc:creator>Prachi Patel</dc:creator><media:content medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/many-sheep-below-blue-solar-panels.jpg?id=31948365&amp;width=980"></media:content></item><item><title>Supporting Renewable Energy Technology Development with Modeling and Simulation</title><link>https://engineeringresources.spectrum.ieee.org/free/w_math07/prgm.cgi</link><description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/supporting-renewable-energy-technology-development-with-modeling-and-simulation.gif?id=31942139&width=1200&height=800&coordinates=82%2C0%2C82%2C0"/><br/><br/><p>In this webinar, MathWorks will discuss how to align modeling and simulation techniques with different stages in the technology development cycle for renewable energy systems. Through worked examples of both solar power and wind power systems, we will consider early-stage design - where the primary focus is on aspects such as system architecture, longer-term power production, and trade-studies, through to more detailed design - where the primary focus is on specific technology characteristics, energy management, and control. These considerations support design exploration and design rigor, meaning you can navigate the technology development cycle rapidly and with confidence.</p> <p><strong>Speakers</strong>:</p> <p><strong>Graham Dudgeon, MEng, PhD</strong>, <em>Principal Technologist </em>– <em>Electrical Systems, MathWorks</em></p> <ul> <li>Graham Dudgeon is principal technologist for electrical technology at MathWorks. Over the last two decades Graham has supported several industries in the electrical technology area, including aerospace, marine, automotive, industrial automation, medical devices, and power and utilities, with an emphasis on system modeling and simulation, control design, real-time simulation, machine learning, and data analytics. Prior to joining MathWorks, Graham was Senior Research Fellow at the Rolls-Royce University Technology Centre in Electrical Power Systems at the University of Strathclyde in Scotland, UK.</li> </ul>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2022 16:18:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://engineeringresources.spectrum.ieee.org/free/w_math07/prgm.cgi</guid><category>Type:webinar</category><dc:creator>MathWorks</dc:creator><media:content medium="image" type="image/gif" url="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/supporting-renewable-energy-technology-development-with-modeling-and-simulation.gif?id=31942139&amp;width=980"></media:content></item><item><title>Robots and AI Could Optimize Lithium-Ion Batteries</title><link>https://spectrum.ieee.org/lithium-ion-battery</link><description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/battery-icon-with-lightning-bolts-on-sides.jpg?id=31888618&width=1200&height=800&coordinates=0%2C80%2C0%2C80"/><br/><br/><p>Cutting-edge electronics, including electric vehicles and the latest smartphones, all depend on batteries whose chemistries are still largely developed manually by trial and error. Now, a new study reveals that artificial intelligence can direct robots in rapidly finding advanced new battery formulations. A team of scientists detailed <a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-022-32938-1" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">their findings</a> online 27 September in the journal <em>Nature</em><em> Communications</em>.</p><p>The conventional techniques for developing new batteries can take years because researchers have to experiment with many possible components. This is complicated by the need to achieve multiple competing goals, such as longer life, greater capacity, faster charging, and improved safety.</p><p>“The kind of lithium-ion battery you might find in a Tesla EV may have one primary salt—typically lithium hexafluorophosphate—as well as two or three liquid solvents in which the salt is dissolved and one or two additives that are secret,” says  Jay Whitacre, an energy technologist at Carnegie Mellon University who was co-senior author of the <em>Nature <em>Communications</em></em> paper. “There are many compelling potential combinations of all these components, potentially with multiple salts, five or six or more solvents, multiple additives, which can be incredibly complicated to rifle through.”</p><p>In the new study, researchers sought to accelerate battery development by coupling a robotics platform named Clio with an AI called Dragonfly in order to find the best combination of battery components in an autonomous manner.</p><p>“It’s like putting peanut butter and chocolate together,” Whitacre says. “I’m the experimentalist who has always wanted to find a way to mix up chemicals for batteries in an automated way,” whereas study co-senior author Venkat Viswanathan “is the computer-modeling machine-learning person who wanted to take people out of the loop.”</p><p>In the new study, the system autonomously experimented with lithium hexafluorophosphate salt and the solvents ethylene carbonate, ethyl-methyl carbonate, and dimethyl carbonate. (In a lithium-ion battery, a salt dissolves in one or more solvents to form a liquid electrolyte. Lithium ions move from one electrolyte to another to carry electric charge.)</p><p>The robotic system used pumps to inject various combinations of solvents into pouches with a lithium nickel manganese cobalt oxide cathode and a graphite anode. “There wasn’t a person telling the system what to do; the system decided what to do,” Whitacre says.</p><p>In 42 experiments over two working days, the system autonomously identified six electrolytes that enable faster charging than a conventional electrolyte composition. This approach hit upon the new chemistry six times as fast as it would likely have taken to discover it via a random search.</p><p>The researchers note their system likely performs more experimental measurements per day than an average human operator and uses about 30 percent as many lab materials. In the future, they suggest their system may prove 20 to 1,000 times as efficient as people doing this work.</p><p>The sole goal of these experiments was a faster-charging battery. However, the scientists note this system can also pursue multiple objectives simultaneously.</p><p>“As we dive more and more into this project, we’re aiming at true exploration and discovery with more complicated possible combinations of electrolytes placed into many test cells to see what does and does not work,” Whitacre says.</p>]]></description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2022 13:00:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spectrum.ieee.org/lithium-ion-battery</guid><category>Robotics</category><category>Artificial intelligence</category><category>Electric vehicles</category><category>Smartphones</category><category>Mobile devices</category><category>Electrolytes</category><category>Tesla</category><category>Lithium-ion batteries</category><dc:creator>Charles Q. Choi</dc:creator><media:content medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/battery-icon-with-lightning-bolts-on-sides.jpg?id=31888618&amp;width=980"></media:content></item><item><title>Geothermal May Beat Batteries for Energy Storage</title><link>https://spectrum.ieee.org/geothermal-energy</link><description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/illustration-of-a-mountain-scene-with-different-types-of-energy-sources.jpg?id=31887415&width=1200&height=800&coordinates=13%2C0%2C13%2C0"/><br/><br/><p>Geothermal systems carry warmth from Earth’s interior up to the surface for heating or electricity. But geothermal power plants are expensive to build, and will get even less economically viable as wind and solar power get cheaper and more plentiful. However, even as wind and solar grow, so does the need to store electricity from those temperamental sources.</p><p>A new proposal could solve those issues and bolster all three renewable technologies. The idea is simple—use advanced geothermal reservoirs to store excess wind and solar power in the form of hot water or steam, and <a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/oil-wells-as-solar-thermal-wellsprings" target="_self">bring up that heat</a> when wind and solar aren’t available, to turn turbines for electricity.</p><hr/><p>“It would allow next-generation geothermal plants to break from the traditional baseload operating paradigm and earn much greater value as suppliers of wind and solar,” says <a href="https://mae.princeton.edu/about-mae/spotlight/wilson-ricks-sustaining-energy-our-future" target="_blank">Wilson Ricks</a>, a graduate student in mechanical and aerospace engineering at Princeton University. </p><p>Ricks, his Ph.D. advisor <a href="https://mae.princeton.edu/people/faculty/jenkins" target="_blank">Jesse Jenkins</a>, and <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/jack-norbeck" target="_blank">Jack Norbeck</a>, cofounder and chief technology officer of Houston-based advanced geothermal developer <a href="https://www.fervoenergy.com/" target="_blank">Fervo Energy</a>, ran extensive simulations of such geothermal reservoir energy storage to see if the technical components of the system as well as the economics actually work out. They found that the systems could indeed store <a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/long-term-energy-storage-molten-salt" target="_blank">electricity over a range of time scales</a>, from a few hours up to many days, as efficiently as lithium-ion batteries. Plus, says Ricks, “the storage capacity effectively comes free of charge with construction of a geothermal reservoir.” </p><p>Their results apply only to enhanced geothermal plants, like the ones Fervo and other companies such as Cambridge, Mass.–based <a href="https://www.quaise.energy/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Quaise Energy</a> and Seattle-based <a href="http://altarockenergy.com/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">AltaRock Energy</a> are developing.</p><p>Conventional geothermal systems drill wells into naturally occurring hydrothermal reservoirs. But these pockets of hot water deep underground do not exist everywhere. In the United States, for instance, they are mostly located in the west.</p><p>Enhanced geothermal systems (EGS) get around this geographical limitation by creating artificial reservoirs. Developers create fractures in hot, dry rock formations by drilling into or <a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/altarock-energy-melts-rock-with-millimeter-waves-for-geothermal-wells" target="_self">melting the rock</a>, and then injecting water into the fissures. Production wells bring the heated water up for producing electricity. “For scales necessary to contribute to national or global electricity decarbonization, we need to be able to extract geothermal heat outside of conventional formations,” Ricks says.</p><p>Fervo Energy raised <a href="https://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20220822005182/en/Fervo-Energy-Raises-138-Million-for-247-Carbon-Free-Next-Generation-Geothermal-Energy" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">US $138 million</a> in venture capital funding in August to advance its technology. The company uses innovations from the oil and gas industry, such as horizontal drilling and distributed fiber-optic sensing, to create underground reservoirs. The company plans to use the new funds to complete two pilot projects, including <a href="https://cloud.google.com/blog/products/infrastructure/google-fervo-geothermal-project-creates-carbon-free-energy" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">one with Google</a> in Nevada.</p><p>Once these EGS systems are in place, they would be ideal for storing energy as well as producing electricity. Excess wind or solar energy could be used to inject water into the artificial reservoirs, where it would accumulate and build up pressure. The production wells could then be opened up when electricity is needed. </p><p>“EGS reservoirs are created in rock formations that are naturally impermeable; everything outside the artificial reservoir is sealed off,” says Ricks. “It’s very similar to a hydropower reservoir, where you choose when to have water go through the dam and generate electricity.”</p><p>Depending on the geology and traits of the rocks, Ricks and his colleagues’ simulations found that the systems could store energy with up to 90 percent efficiency over one cycle. That’s comparable with lithium-ion and pumped hydro storage, he says. The cost, meanwhile, would be minimal compared to other energy storage technologies. It would require larger facilities on the surface, but the storage space would be effectively free, since the EGS reservoirs are being built for electricity anyway. </p><p>In January, the team received $4.5 million in funding from the <a href="https://arpa-e.energy.gov/" target="_blank">Advanced Research Projects Agency–Energy</a> (ARPA-E) to demonstrate a full-scale test of geothermal reservoir energy storage in the field. The detailed findings of their modeling study appear in a paper published recently in the journal <em><a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/abs/pii/S0306261922002537#!" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Applied Energy</a></em>.</p>]]></description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2022 18:14:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spectrum.ieee.org/geothermal-energy</guid><category>Geothermal energy</category><category>Energy storage</category><category>Enhanced geothermal system</category><category>Grid-scale energy storage</category><dc:creator>Prachi Patel</dc:creator><media:content medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/illustration-of-a-mountain-scene-with-different-types-of-energy-sources.jpg?id=31887415&amp;width=980"></media:content></item><item><title>Russia Annexes Nuclear Station, Invites Sanctions</title><link>https://spectrum.ieee.org/zaporizhzhia-nuclear-power-plant-putin</link><description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/a-person-holding-a-gun-in-foreground-with-a-building-in-the-background.jpg?id=31886862&width=1200&height=800&coordinates=188%2C0%2C189%2C0"/><br/><br/><p>A few hours after polls closed for “referenda” in Ukraine’s occupied oblasts last month, Russia-installed officials in Ukraine’s Zaporizhzhia <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Oblasts_of_Ukraine" target="_blank">oblast</a> reported that <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20220927194634/https://www.pbs.org/newshour/world/pro-moscow-officials-say-one-occupied-area-of-ukraine-has-voted-to-join-russia" target="_blank">93.11 percent of votes cast there favored annexation</a>. Within days Moscow had officially absorbed Zaporizhzhia into the Russian Federation and Russian president Vladimir Putin had declared the region’s embattled nuclear power plant—Europe’s largest—to be Russian property.<br/></p><p>Never mind that a recent telephone survey of adults in Energodar, the city built to house Zaporizhzhia’s nuclear power staff, found only 6 percent support for joining Russia, <a href="http://xn--ukrainian%20nuclear%20power%20firm%20energoatoms%20claim%20that%20only%206%25%20of-3d26c/" target="_blank">according to Ukrainian nuclear power firm Energoatom</a>. Or that Ukrainian forces control over a quarter of the region, including its capital. Or the referendum’s hasty organization, and reports of voter intimidation and other elections irregularities. </p><p class="pull-quote">Ukrainian president Volodymyr Zelenskyy insists that both Ukraine and Europe need the huge plant’s 6-gigawatt generating capacity to stay warm this winter. </p><p>In the three other oblasts that held referenda last month, subsequent gains by Ukrainian forces contradict Russia’s claims to tighter control. Not so in Zaporizhzhia. Battle lines there are static, thanks to the vulnerable nuclear reactors and spent nuclear fuel standing in the way of any Ukrainian counteroffensive. And actions implementing Putin’s orders have intensified the quandaries facing the several thousand employees still there working to prevent a catastrophic accident:</p><hr/><ul><li>Immediately after last month’s vote, Russian forces detained plant director Ihor Murashov, released video of him saying he worked for Ukraine’s state security service, and then <a href="https://ua.interfax.com.ua/news/general/862921.html" target="_blank">expelled him from Russian-held territory</a>.</li><li>Rosatom, Russia’s state-owned nuclear energy conglomerate, created a subsidiary to absorb the plant and named its own plant director—even as Energoatom CEO Petro Kotin declared himself the new director and said workers should continue following orders from Kyiv.</li><li>Reports emerged of Rosatom officials <a href="https://infoatom.news/2022/10/01/011020221101" target="_blank">pressuring plant personnel</a>, hitherto paid by Energoatom, to sign on as Rosatom employees or face military conscription. </li></ul><p>Energoatom, meanwhile, complicated the situation last week by ordering the plant to restart power generation, three-and-a-half weeks after Energoatom put Zaporizhzhia’s last operating reactors into cold shutdown <a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/nuclear-energy-brinkmanship-in-ukraine" target="_self">at the insistence of Ukrainian nuclear safety experts</a>. Missile strikes had repeatedly knocked out transmission lines powering safety systems until the plant shut down.</p><p class="pull-quote">“Rosatom [Russia’s state-owned nuclear energy conglomerate] has basically been exempt from the sanctions because Rosatom has cornered the market. They’re one of the few companies worldwide that control the entire nuclear fuel cycle.”<br/>—Sonja Schmid, Virginia Tech</p><p>“Ambiguity about the command-and-control chain” makes the embattled facility’s security even more precarious according to <a href="https://www.iaea.org/newscenter/pressreleases/iaea-director-general-grossi-and-ukrainian-president-zelensky-meet-in-kyiv-discuss-situation-at-znpp" target="_blank">a statement last week by Rafael Grossi</a>, director general of the International Atomic Energy Agency (IAEA). Grossi noted the “enormous pressure” on staff, who face “extremely difficult” decisions for themselves and their families in the face of Rosatom’s and Energoatom’s conflicting demands. </p><p>In a highly unusual move, Grossi also took a side in the conflict for the first time since Russian forces seized Zaporizhzhia in March. Grossi <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/europe/iaea-chief-zaporizhzhia-nuclear-power-plant-is-ukrainian-facility-2022-10-06/" target="_blank">told reporters in Kyiv</a> that “the position of the IAEA is that this facility is a Ukrainian facility.”</p><p>Putin’s land and facility grabs may also force the United States, the European Union, and other nations to do something new: extend their regime of sanctions against Russian citizens and businesses to include Rosatom. Russia’s nuclear giant dominates the global uranium supply chain and is building more than a dozen nuclear power plants, including reactors in Turkey, Hungary, India, and Bangladesh. </p><p>Olga Kosharna, a nuclear-safety expert and former advisor to Ukraine’s nuclear regulator, said Rosatom’s international projects are a crucial pressure point to force Russia to demilitarize Europe’s largest nuclear power plant. As she put it during a public briefing last week, “only sanctions and only the collapse of Rosatom’s projects to build nuclear power plants abroad can somehow stop this madness.”</p><h2>Who’s in Command in Zaporizhzhia? </h2><p>The heightened tensions at Zaporizhzhia shattered a month of relative calm there. While detonation of Russian landmines <a href="http://by%20wild%20boars,%20dogs%20or%20foxes." target="_blank">attributed to wild boars, dogs, and foxes</a> still rattled the plant, missile and mortar attacks ceased when the last reactors were turned off on 11 September. Nuclear threats to Ukraine did not stop, but shifted elsewhere. On 19 September missiles <a href="https://www.cbc.ca/news/world/ukraine-russia-missile-nuclear-plant-1.6587546" target="_blank">exploded 300 meters from Energoatom’s South Ukraine Nuclear Power Plant</a>. And Russian officials ratcheted up talk of using nuclear weapons in Ukraine.</p><p>Ukrainian experts have argued that restarting fission reactions and power generation at Zaporizhzhia would once again inspire Russian forces to use it for blackmail and intimidation. That prediction was affirmed early Saturday when a missile strike knocked the entire plant off the grid, forcing it to rely yet again on diesel generators to cool its reactors and spent fuel for almost 48 hours.</p><p>Still, Ukrainian president Volodymyr Zelenskyy insists that both Ukraine and Europe need the huge plant’s 6-gigawatt generating capacity to stay warm this winter. Energoatom’s Kotin added further justification last week, <a href="https://apnews.com/article/russia-ukraine-kyiv-science-climate-and-environment-cb13338afce133cd9fc39f78200393a6" target="_blank">telling the Associated Press</a> that Zaporizhzhia needed to restart to keep safety-critical equipment from freezing. </p><p class="pull-quote">France’s opposition to sanctions may be the hardest to overcome, according to one source <em>Spectrum </em>consulted, since its nuclear industry is most tightly entwined with Rosatom.</p><p>A Ukrainian nuclear-safety expert, speaking anonymously because they are not authorized to discuss the topic on the record, told <em>IEEE Spectrum </em>that weather predictions did not support Kotin’s argument, and said operating reactors in a war zone was a far greater risk. Reactors in “cold” shutdown are roughly 70 °C, versus 320 °C in operation.</p><p><em>IEEE Spectrum</em> asked Rosatom whether restarting the plant was safe, but did not receive a reply by press time. Calls to a number attributed to the plant’s Rosatom-appointed director, Oleg Romanenko, did not go through. </p><p>Romanenko was previously the chief engineer at <a href="https://www.rosenergoatom.ru/en/npp/balakovo-npp/" target="_blank">Rosatom’s Balakovo power station</a>, roughly 900 kilometers southeast of Moscow. It has four Soviet-designed VVER-1000 nuclear-power units similar to the six at Zaporizhzhia. He was one of 11 Rosatom employees sent to Zaporizhzhia in March. </p><p>The <a href="https://myrotvorets.center/" target="_blank">Myrotvorets Center</a>, a civil-society group based in Langley, Va., and Warsaw that tracks alleged Russian militants, war criminals and collaborators in Ukraine, <a href="https://myrotvorets.center/criminal/romanenko-oleg-evgenevich/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">lists Romanenko</a> as a “Russian war criminal” and a “nuclear terrorist.”</p><h2>Nuclear Sanctions</h2><p>Russian officials show no sign of concern about accusations of war crimes committed in Ukraine. However, they have shown sensitivity about accusations that Rosatom—one of the Kremlin’s corporate crown jewels—is directly involved in the war in Ukraine, according to Mykhailo Gonchar, president of the Kyiv-based Centre for Global Studies Strategy XXI. The Ukrainian national-security expert argues that Russia fears imposition of Western sanctions on Rosatom. </p><p>In a brief to <em>IEEE Spectrum</em> last week, Gonchar notes repeated denials in past months that Rosatom was involved in running the Zaporizhzhia power plant, such as <a href="https://euobserver.com/opinion/155819" target="_blank">a 19 August 2022 statement</a>: “We categorically deny any involvement of Rosatom or any of its employees in the management or operations of the plant at any level.” </p><p>So far Western sanctions have broadly hit Russia’s economy, and they have ratcheted up eight times since February, as seen in <a href="https://www.consilium.europa.eu/en/policies/sanctions/restrictive-measures-against-russia-over-ukraine/history-restrictive-measures-against-russia-over-ukraine/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">this timeline of European sanctions since 2014</a>. But they’ve spared Rosatom. “Rosatom has basically been exempt from the sanctions because Rosatom has cornered the market. They’re one of the few companies worldwide that controls the entire nuclear fuel cycle,” says Sonja Schmid, an associate professor in Virginia Tech’s department of science, technology, and society and author of a <a href="https://direct.mit.edu/books/book/3404/Producing-PowerThe-Pre-Chernobyl-History-of-the" target="_blank">2015 book on the Soviet nuclear-energy industry</a>. </p><p>Gonchar, however, says Putin’s moves last week implicating Rosatom in Zaporizhzhia increase pressure on Western governments to override concerns from nuclear-energy-industry lobbyists.</p><p>France may be the hardest to win over, says Gonchar, since its nuclear industry is most tightly entwined with Rosatom. All of the country’s major nuclear equipment and services firms—including EDF, Framatome, Alstom, and Orano—have partnerships with Rosatom. And just before Russia’s February 2022 invasion, EDF agreed to buy General Electric’s French turbine business (known by the French acronym GEAST) in collaboration with Rosatom, which is the operation’s biggest customer.</p><p>Gonchar says blocking Rosatom’s access to GEAST would hit Russia hard, since only GEAST and Ukrainian state-owned Turboatom manufacture the steam turbines Rosatom needs for its international nuclear projects.</p><p>U.S. nuclear lobbyists such as <a href="https://www.eenews.net/articles/how-russias-invasion-is-affecting-u-s-nuclear/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">the Washington, D.C.-based Nuclear Energy Institute</a> have opposed sanctions on the grounds that they would boost nuclear fuel costs and thus raise power rates. In the United States alone, Rosatom subsidiaries have contracts to supply US $6.5 billion of uranium and its derivatives through 2028. </p><p>However, Gonchar says the impact on consumers is easily overstated. Nuclear power plants refuel only every 18 or 24 months, and then only to replace one-third of their reactors’ fuel. He notes that projections by independent experts in the United States suggest that even a doubling of fuel prices would increase nuclear power costs less than 3 percent.</p><p>And the industry is making moves to shift away from Russian fuel supplies. Industry news source <a href="https://www.spglobal.com/commodityinsights/en/market-insights/blogs/electric-power/070722-global-nuclear-fuel-supply-chain-uranium-russia-ukraine-war" target="_blank">Platts</a> reported that by nuclear industry standards, change was already “exceedingly fast” by July.</p>]]></description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2022 16:36:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spectrum.ieee.org/zaporizhzhia-nuclear-power-plant-putin</guid><category>Ukraine conflict</category><category>Ukraine</category><category>Russia</category><category>Nuclear power</category><category>Nuclear energy</category><dc:creator>Peter Fairley</dc:creator><media:content medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/a-person-holding-a-gun-in-foreground-with-a-building-in-the-background.jpg?id=31886862&amp;width=980"></media:content></item><item><title>Nighttime Charging of EVs May Overburden the Grid</title><link>https://spectrum.ieee.org/electric-vehicles</link><description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/a-man-with-a-phone-looks-at-the-charger-of-his-electric-vehicle.jpg?id=31865556&width=1200&height=800&coordinates=0%2C0%2C0%2C209"/><br/><br/><p>The vast majority of electric vehicle owners currently charge their cars at home at night. However, a new study finds this might gravely burden the grid as more EVs hit the road. Instead, a much better strategy in the future is a greater emphasis on daytime charging, scientists say.<br/></p><p>The number of electric passenger cars, delivery vans and other light-duty vehicles may reach more than 300 million worldwide by 2035, an order of magnitude increase when compared to 2021, <a href="https://about.bnef.com/electric-vehicle-outlook/" target="_blank">according to energy market analyst firm Bloomberg New Energy Finance</a>. In California alone, cumulative sales of EVs reached 1 million in <a href="https://www.gov.ca.gov/2022/02/25/california-leads-the-nations-zev-market-surpassing-1-million-electric-vehicles-sold/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">February</a>, accounting for about 6 percent of the state’s cars and light trucks.</p><p>The drive toward EVs and renewable energy is ultimately designed to lower fossil fuel use and reduce greenhouse gas emissions. However, the campaigns pushing both these shifts are largely uncoordinated. In the new study, researchers examined what effects of growing EV ownership might have in the long term on power grids based more and more on renewable energy.</p><p>California plans for 50 percent or 24 million of its light-duty vehicles to be electric by 2035. The scientists investigated the effects this might have on the whole U.S. portion of the Western Interconnection grid, which covers 11 states with more than 75 million people, because California depends heavily on electricity imports from the other western states. Their models included an increase in solar and wind generation 3.5 times and 3 times 2019 levels, respectively.</p><p>Currently, more than 80 percent of electric vehicle charging, and as much as 93 percent, takes place at home, mostly in the evening, <a href="https://www.osti.gov/biblio/1503821" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">according to the National Renewable Energy Lab in Golden, Colo</a>. The researchers found this strategy could increase peak electricity demand by up to 25 percent if half of all cars are electric by 2035, and by 50 percent if all vehicles go electric.</p><p>In contrast, shifting to daytime charging would minimize the impact of EVs on the grid. “Right now, we have a lot of power available in the evening,” says study senior author Ram Rajagopal, an electrical engineer at Stanford University. “However, when we look at 2035, the grid is predominantly solar.”</p><p>By changing the emphasis of charging toward the daytime, “we don’t really have to add any resources to the grid,” Rajagopal says. “We’re not saying that everyone should move to daytime charging. We think the emphasis should be a more balanced approach, more tilted toward daytime charging.”</p><p>However, a number of barriers currently hamper such a shift. Rajagopal points out, “If you’re working at home and you have a charger at home, then it’s not a big deal, but if you drive to work, you will need to have a charger there and there will be a cost for that charging, and people usually don’t really have an awareness of the costs of charging at home.”</p><p>Policymakers will likely want more widespread deployment of shared charging infrastructure, likely with a focus on low- and middle-income populations as well as small and medium-size businesses. “We’re already seeing a lot of investment going that way in the <a href="https://www.electrificationcoalition.org/work/federal-ev-policy/inflation-reduction-act/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Inflation Reduction Act</a>,” Rajagopal says.</p><p>Moreover, across the United States, states will likely want to rethink electricity pricing structures as their EV charging needs increase and their grids change, the researchers say.</p><p>“Right now electricity rates reflect the current very mild penetration of EVs,” Rajagopal says. “Once we see a deep penetration, a discount during the daytime would go a really long way toward people changing their habits.”</p><p>Future research can explore what happens when trucking fleets also go electric, Rajagopal says.</p><p>The scientists detailed <u><a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41560-022-01105-7" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">their findings</a></u> online 22 September in the journal <em>Nature Energy</em>.</p>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Oct 2022 14:25:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spectrum.ieee.org/electric-vehicles</guid><category>Grid</category><category>Renewable energy</category><category>Electric vehicles</category><category>Ev charging</category><dc:creator>Charles Q. Choi</dc:creator><media:content medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/a-man-with-a-phone-looks-at-the-charger-of-his-electric-vehicle.jpg?id=31865556&amp;width=980"></media:content></item><item><title>Home Heating With Hydrogen: Ill-Advised as It Sounds</title><link>https://spectrum.ieee.org/home-heating-with-hydrogen-is-ill-advised</link><description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/two-white-boilers-mounted-on-a-wood-wall-with-pipes-and-tubes.jpg?id=31859785&width=1200&height=800&coordinates=0%2C184%2C0%2C184"/><br/><br/><p>Hydrogen, if it comes from splitting water with renewable electricity, has its role as a climate-friendly energy source. It could help decarbonize challenging sectors like heavy industry, shipping, and aviation.</p><p>But hydrogen makes absolutely no sense for heating homes and buildings, according to a new review of several international studies. It is simply much too expensive and inefficient for that purpose, says Jan Rosenow, Europe director at the Regulatory Assistance Project, an energy think tank in Brussels, who authored the commentary published in the journal <em><a href="https://www.cell.com/joule/fulltext/S2542-4351%2822%2900416-0" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Joule</a></em>.</p><p>Space heating today mostly relies on burning natural gas or other fossil fuels. The gas and heating industry are promoting hydrogen as a clean substitute for fossils. Using hydrogen in current infrastructure, they say, would be much easier than switching to electric heat pumps, the biggest competitor today for low-carbon heating. Several countries are considering hydrogen heating strategies. But they do not seem to be based on scientific evidence, Rosenow’s analysis shows. </p><p>“Hydrogen home heating is attractive to gas grid companies because it allows them to continue using their assets,” Rosenow says. “The heating industry is supportive [because] they manufacture systems that currently use gas, and now have products that can run on hydrogen. So they also have an interest in retaining molecules that they can use.”</p><p>Meanwhile, policymakers seem to have gotten behind the idea “because it sounds easy,” he says. “You just replace gas in the pipes. And there’s no disruption to the consumer.”</p><p>Cost and efficiency numbers belie the hydrogen heating hype, though, Rosenow says. He looked at 32 independent studies from Brazil, California, the E.U., and the United Kingdom. They include energy-system modeling, customer-cost modeling, and environmental-impact studies, done at scales spanning from city level to international. He chose studies that were not carried out by or on behalf of any industry, whether gas, electricity, or heat pump or boiler manufacturers. </p><p>The studies show that using renewable electricity to first make hydrogen with electrolysis, and then using the hydrogen to heat spaces is less efficient than using the electricity to directly power a heat pump. Electrolyzers are around 80 percent efficient, and boilers have average efficiencies of 85 percent, resulting in an overall efficiency of hydrogen heating of 70 percent. Meanwhile, a heat pump produces three to four units of heat for each unit of electricity. “You need five to six times more electricity to generate the same amount of heat with hydrogen than with an efficient heat pump,” Rosenow says. “That’s the Achilles’ heel for hydrogen. It’s basic thermodynamics.”</p><p>Besides being less efficient, hydrogen is also significantly more expensive per unit of heat delivered when compared to heat pumps, his review found. Switching to hydrogen isn’t as easy as the industry makes it sound. It will require changing distribution pipelines, pipe work in buildings, and furnaces, all of which will add to consumers’ heating cost.</p><p>Others have come to the same conclusion. At a recent Financial Times Hydrogen Summit in London, one U.K. utility representative likened hydrogen home heating to <a href="https://www.rechargenews.com/energy-transition/astonishingly-expensive-using-hydrogen-to-heat-homes-will-be-like-spaffing-money-up-the-wall-utility/2-1-1246366" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">burning cash</a>. A report by energy analysis firm Cornwall Insight released days before Rosenow’s review showed that using hydrogen to heat a home would cost <a href="https://hydrogen-central.com/hydrogen-could-nearly-double-cost-heating-home-compared-gas-about-70-increase-home-energy-bills-according-report-renewable-energy-charity/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">twice as much as using natural gas</a>. </p><p>But the hydrogen lobby, backed by large players in the gas industry, is strong, as David Cebon, professor of mechanical engineering at the University of Cambridge, outlined in a recent <a href="https://www.rechargenews.com/energy-transition/wrong-side-of-history-wake-up-to-the-hype-around-green-hydrogen-for-heating/2-1-1282365" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">opinion piece</a>. The U.K. government is carrying out a number of small, private trials for hydrogen heating, and is expected to decide on the role that hydrogen will play when it makes a strategic decision on the future of the gas grid in 2026. By 2030, there could be whole towns being heated by hydrogen in the U.K. Similar hydrogen heating trials are underway in Spain and the Netherlands. In the United States, where the <a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/hydrogen-economy-inflation-reduction-act" target="_self">hydrogen economy is also picking up speed</a> thanks to the Inflation Reduction Act, gas monopolies are also <a href="https://www.latimes.com/business/story/2022-03-21/los-angeles-needs-clean-energy-hydrogen-could-be-the-answer" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">starting to push for the switch to hydrogen</a>.</p><p>There are many applications where hydrogen could be essential. But for buildings, writes Cebon, “heat pumps are a clear winning technology. Decarbonising heat will be hard enough. And when speed is everything, there is no time for the hydrogen distraction.”</p>]]></description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2022 15:22:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spectrum.ieee.org/home-heating-with-hydrogen-is-ill-advised</guid><category>Home heating</category><category>Hydrogen</category><dc:creator>Prachi Patel</dc:creator><media:content medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/two-white-boilers-mounted-on-a-wood-wall-with-pipes-and-tubes.jpg?id=31859785&amp;width=980"></media:content></item><item><title>Taming the Climate Is Far Harder Than Getting People to the Moon</title><link>https://spectrum.ieee.org/decarbonization</link><description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/chimneys-and-cooling-towers-from-a-coal-fired-power-station-releasing-smoke-and-steam-into-the-atmosphere.jpg?id=31803087&width=1200&height=800&coordinates=0%2C81%2C0%2C81"/><br/><br/><p>
<strong>In his 1949</strong> book <em>The Concept of Mind</em>, Gilbert Ryle, an English philosopher, introduced the term “category mistake.” He gave the example of a visitor to the University of Oxford who sees colleges and a splendid library and then asks, “But where is the university?” The category mistake is obvious: A university is an institution, not a collection of buildings.
</p><p>
	Today, no category mistake is perhaps more consequential than the all-too-common view of the global energy transition. The error is to think of the transition as the discrete, well-bounded task of replacing carbon fuels by noncarbon alternatives. The apparent urgency of the transition leads to calls for confronting the challenge just as the United States dealt with two earlier ones: winning the nuclear-arms race against Nazi Germany and the space race against the Soviet Union. The Manhattan Project produced an atomic bomb in three years, and Project Apollo put two U.S. citizens on the moon in July 1969, eight years after President Kennedy had announced the goal.
</p><hr/><p>
	But difficult and costly as those two endeavors were, they affected only small parts of the economy, their costs were relatively modest, and the lives of average citizens were hardly affected. It is just the opposite for the decarbonization of the energy supply.
</p><p>
	Ours is an overwhelmingly fossil-fueled civilization, and the size and complexity of our extensive supersystem of fuel extraction, processing, distribution, storage, and conversion means that a complete displacement of it will directly affect every person and every industry, not least the growing of food and the long-distance transport of goods and people. The costs will be stupendous.
</p><p class="pull-quote">
	Affluent nations would have to devote on the order of 15 to 20 percent of their annual economic product to the task of decarbonizing the economy.
</p><p>
	By the time the <a href="https://www.ctbto.org/nuclear-testing/history-of-nuclear-testing/manhattan-project/manhattan-project/" target="_blank">Manhattan Project</a> ended in 1946, it had cost the country nearly US $2 billion, about $33 billion in today’s money, the total equal to only about 0.3 percent of the 1943-45 gross domestic product. When Project Apollo ended in 1972, it had cost about $26 billion, or $207 billion in today’s money; over 12 years it worked out annually to about 0.2 percent of the country’s 1961-72 GDP.
</p><p>
	Of course, nobody can provide a reliable account of the eventual cost of global energy transition because we do not know the ultimate composition of the new primary energy supply. Nor do we know what shares will come from converting natural renewable flows, whether we will use them to produce hydrogen or synthetic fuels, and the extent to which we will rely on nuclear fission (and, as some hope, on fusion) or from other, still unknown options.</p><p class="shortcode-media shortcode-media-rebelmouse-image">
<img alt="A series of cubes made of red blocks where each block is worth 1 billion dollars." class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="f92cd39478fc49dcab74edc3fac8c89e" data-rm-shortcode-name="rebelmouse-image" id="e3193" loading="lazy" src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/a-series-of-cubes-made-of-red-blocks-where-each-block-is-worth-1-billion-dollars.png?id=31812355&width=980"/>
<small class="image-media media-photo-credit" placeholder="Add Photo Credit...">Chris Philpot; Sources: CTBTO Preparatory Commission; ScienceDirect; McKinsey Global Institute</small>
</p><p>
	But a recent attempt to estimate such costs confirms the magnitude of the category mistake. The <a href="https://www.mckinsey.com/business-functions/sustainability/our-insights/the-economic-transformation-what-would-change-in-the-net-zero-transition" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">McKinsey Global Institute</a>, in a highly conservative estimate, puts the cost at $275 trillion between 2021 and 2050. That is roughly $9.2 trillion a year, compared with the 2021 <a href="https://www.visualcapitalist.com/visualizing-the-94-trillion-world-economy-in-one-chart/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">global economic produc</a>t of $94 trillion. Such numbers imply an annual expenditure of about 10 percent of today’s world economic product. And because the world’s low-income countries could not carry such burdens, affluent nations would have to devote on the order of 15 to 20 percent of their annual economic product to the task. Such shares are comparable only to the spending that was required to win World War II.
</p><p><em>This article appears in the October 2022 print issue as “Decarbonization Is Our Greatest Challenge.”</em></p>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 29 Sep 2022 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spectrum.ieee.org/decarbonization</guid><category>Energy</category><category>Decarbonization</category><category>Reducing carbon emissions</category><dc:creator>Vaclav Smil</dc:creator><media:content medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/chimneys-and-cooling-towers-from-a-coal-fired-power-station-releasing-smoke-and-steam-into-the-atmosphere.jpg?id=31803087&amp;width=980"></media:content></item><item><title>Converting Coal Power Plants to Nuclear Gains Steam</title><link>https://spectrum.ieee.org/nuclear-power-plant</link><description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/illustration-of-a-building-concept.jpg?id=31822097&width=1200&height=800&coordinates=0%2C60%2C0%2C60"/><br/><br/><p>On a planet aspiring to become carbon neutral, the once-stalwart coal power plant is an emerging anachronism. </p><p>It is true that, in much of the developing world, coal-fired capacity <a href="https://www.carbonbrief.org/mapped-worlds-coal-power-plants/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">continues to grow</a>. But in every corner of the globe, political and financial pressures <a href="https://www.power-technology.com/news/g20-overseas-coal-financing/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">are mounting</a> to bury coal in the past. In the United States, coal’s share of electricity generation <a href="https://www.eia.gov/energyexplained/electricity/electricity-in-the-us-generation-capacity-and-sales.php" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">has plummeted</a> since its early 2000s peak; 28 percent of U.S. coal plants <a href="https://www.power-eng.com/coal/nearly-60-gw-of-coal-fired-capacity-to-retire-by-2035-eia-says/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">are planned</a> to shutter by 2035. </p><p>As coal plants close, they leave behind empty building shells and scores of lost jobs. Some analysts have proposed a solution that, on the surface, seems almost too elegant: turning old coal plants into nuclear power plants. </p><p>On 13 September, the <a href="https://www.energy.gov/" target="_blank">U.S. Department of Energy</a> (DOE) released a report suggesting that, in theory, over 300 former and present coal power plants <a href="https://fuelcycleoptions.inl.gov/SiteAssets/SitePages/Home/C2N2022Report.pdf" target="_blank">could be converted to nuclear</a>. Such a conversion has never been done, but the report is another sign that the idea is gaining momentum—if with the slow steps of a baby needing decades to learn to walk.</p><p>“A lot of communities that may have not traditionally been looking at advanced nuclear, or nuclear energy in general, are now being incentivized to look at it,” says <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/victoribarrajr" target="_blank">Victor Ibarra Jr.</a>, an analyst at the <a href="https://nuclearinnovationalliance.org/about-us" target="_blank">Nuclear Innovation Alliance</a> think tank, who wasn’t involved with the DOE study.</p><p>Conversion backers say the process has benefits for everybody involved. Plant operators might save on costs, with transmission lines, cooling towers, office buildings, and roads already in place. Once-coal-dependent communities might gain jobs and far better air quality.</p><p>“I think it’s something that people have been talking about for a while,” says <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/patrick-white-2a903166?trk=public_profile_browsemap" target="_blank">Patrick White</a>, project manager at the Nuclear Innovation Alliance.</p><p>DOE analysts screened 349 retired and 273 still-operating coal-plant sites across the United States. They filtered out sites that were retired earlier than 2012, sites that weren’t operated by utilities, and sites deemed unsuitable for nuclear reactors (such as plants in disaster-prone or high-population-density areas). That left 157 recently retired and 237 operating sites that could—in theory—house nuclear reactors.</p><p>Not all of these remaining coal plants are perfect fits, however. Most nuclear plants around the world today are large light-water reactors, with capacities well over a gigawatt—quite a bit more than typical coal plants. Large reactors need consistent and prolific water sources to cool themselves, something not every old coal plant can provide. DOE analysts flagged only 35 recently retired and 96 operating coal sites that could house a large light-water reactor within half a mile. </p><p>But in the future, not all reactors might be so large. Many still-speculative <a href="https://www.energy.gov/ne/advanced-small-modular-reactors-smrs" target="_blank">small modular reactor designs</a> might deliver just a few hundred megawatts. (In Hainan, China, <a href="https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/Articles/Linglong-One-reactor-pit-installed-at-Changjiang" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Linglong One</a>—the world’s first small modular reactor plant—is now under construction.) Depending on the design, these could be cooled with less water or even air, making them far more feasible fits for coal sites. DOE analysts found 125 recently retired and 190 operating sites that could house such small reactors.</p><p>Either option will be an uphill battle. In the United States, any new reactor must gain the blessing of the federal <a href="https://www.nrc.gov/about-nrc.html" target="_blank">Nuclear Regulatory Commission</a> (NRC), a process that can take up to five years and drive up costs in a sector <a href="https://ourworldindata.org/cheap-renewables-growth" target="_blank">already facing rising prices</a>. Only <a href="https://www.wabe.org/30b-georgia-power-nuclear-plant-delayed-up-to-6-more-months/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">one nuclear power plant</a> is currently under construction in the United States, in eastern Georgia.</p><p>A specific challenge would-be-conversions must face is that the NRC’s standards—both for atmospheric pollution and for the amount of radiological material a reactor can release—are much tighter than federal standards for coal plants.</p><p>On the state level, no fewer than <a href="https://www.ncsl.org/research/environment-and-natural-resources/states-restrictions-on-new-nuclear-power-facility.aspx" target="_blank">12</a>—California, Connecticut, Hawaii, Illinois, Maine, Massachusetts, Minnesota, New Jersey, New York, Oregon, Rhode Island, and Vermont—all have their own conditions restricting new nuclear construction.</p><p>Even if regulations didn’t stand in the way, coal-to-nuclear conversion has never been done. However, there is one project that has made some headway. </p><p>In Kemmerer, Wyo., nestled in the foothills of the Rocky Mountains, the nuclear energy firm <a href="https://www.terrapower.com/" target="_blank">TerraPower</a> plans to <a href="https://natriumpower.com/wyoming/" target="_blank">retrofit an existing coal plant</a> with a <a href="https://www.terrapower.com/our-work/natriumpower/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">sodium fast reactor</a>. The firm is planning to start building its reactor around 2026, hoping to deliver power by decade’s end. Even so, it hasn’t attained regulatory approval just yet.</p><p>If Wyoming will be the first, there are signs that it won’t be the last. In neighboring Montana, state legislators <a href="https://www.spglobal.com/commodityinsights/en/market-insights/latest-news/electric-power/021221-montana-senate-panel-oks-study-to-convert-colstrip-coal-plant-to-nuclear" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">recently approved</a> a study for converting one coal plant to nuclear. That plant, situated in the coal mining town of Colstrip, currently faces its imminent end as nearby Oregon and Washington plan to <a href="https://www.tricitiesbusinessnews.com/2021/01/clean-energy-ban-coal/" target="_blank">ban coal power</a> by 2025.</p><p>In West Virginia, once coal’s citadel, the state government <a href="https://www.npr.org/2022/02/08/1079339405/west-virginia-ban-nuclear-power-coal" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">eliminated</a> its old ban on nuclear power plants. Nationally, the recently enacted Inflation Reduction Act <a href="https://www.ans.org/news/article-4292/the-ira-crediting-nuclear-energy/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">offers</a> tax credits for nuclear projects in communities with retiring coal plants—something that will certainly increase interest in conversions.</p><p>“Are all of these sites going to get nuclear power plants? Probably not,” says White. “But is this a really good way for people to start the conversation on what are potential next steps, and where are potential sites to look at it? I think that’s a really cool opportunity.”</p>]]></description><pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2022 17:00:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spectrum.ieee.org/nuclear-power-plant</guid><category>Coal</category><category>Nuclear</category><category>Climate change</category><category>Energy</category><category>Nuclear power</category><dc:creator>Rahul Rao</dc:creator><media:content medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/illustration-of-a-building-concept.jpg?id=31822097&amp;width=980"></media:content></item><item><title>Zero-Energy Tech Heats When Cold and Cools When Hot</title><link>https://spectrum.ieee.org/passive-radiative-cooling-device</link><description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/a-blue-gloved-hand-holds-a-grey-square-in-front-of-a-green-plant.jpg?id=31787347&width=1200&height=800&coordinates=0%2C176%2C0%2C176"/><br/><br/><p>A new heat-management device senses temperature and in response changes its shape to heat up or cool down, all without using any external energy. By supplementing commercial heating and cooling technologies, the zero-energy device could cut down the year-round energy demand of building temperature control, its developers say.</p><p>Heating and cooling accounts for <a href="https://www.un.org/en/actnow/facts-and-figures" target="_blank">nearly half of global energy consumption</a>. To bring down the greenhouse gas emissions from temperature management, researchers have recently sped up the hunt for high-performance technologies that can adjust temperatures without consuming much energy, if any. </p><p>One way to do this is to tap into the sun and outer space, respectively, as hot and cold sources. Smart windows, for instance, can be triggered by heat or electricity to switch between absorbing the sun’s infrared heat on cold days or reflecting it in the summer. For a zero-energy option, some teams have made <a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/efficient-airconditioning-by-beaming-heat-into-space" target="_self">passive radiative cooling</a> systems that beam heat directly into outer space at infrared wavelengths that pass straight through Earth’s atmosphere. </p><p>Rujun Ma and colleagues at <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nankai_University" target="_blank">Nankai University</a>, in Tianjin, China, wanted to make a dual-mode device that switches between heating and cooling modes by perceiving temperature change. “The ultimate goal of thermal management is temperature control,” Ma says, so having a temperature-responsive system makes most sense. And while color-changing windows and infrared modulators that respond to temperature changes have been produced, they can do either heating or cooling, but not both.</p><p>What makes the new device unique is its ability to work across wavelengths ranging from the visible band to the infrared band, “covering the entire region that contributes to radiative thermal management, including solar heating and radiative cooling,” Ma says. </p><p>The team looked for inspiration to the Himalayan rabbit’s fur—which is white when the weather is warm but darkens when it is cold—and the opening and folding of the leaves of the <a href="https://www.gardenlively.com/touch-me-not-plant/" target="_blank">touch-me-not (<em>Mimosa pudica</em>) plant</a>.</p><p>The device consists of two main layers. The top layer is a temperature-sensitive actuator sheet that emits infrared radiation. This sheet is made of specially designed polymers that respond unevenly to temperature changes, making it roll up when cold and unfurl when it is hot. The bottom layer is a thermochromic substrate that changes color in response to temperature and also absorbs visible light. </p><p>In heating mode, when the ambient temperature is low, the actuator sheet curls up and the thermochromic substrate turns gray, absorbs sunlight, and warms up. Conversely, in cooling mode, the actuator lays flat and covers the substrate, reflecting sunlight and emitting infrared radiation to siphon away any heat in the substrate. The trigger temperature for switching between modes can be adjusted by tweaking the polymers in the actuator and the thermochromic powders that go in the substrate.</p><p>In the lab, the 4-by-4-centimeter device lasted through 500 rolling and unfolding cycles. Ma and his colleagues also tested the device outdoors, as they detail in their paper published in <em><a href="https://www.pnas.org/doi/abs/10.1073/pnas.2207353119" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences</a></em>. Based on the field experiments, they calculated that the device had a solar heating power of around 252.2 watts per square meter and a cooling power of around 59.7 W/m<sup>2</sup>. </p><p>The researchers translated these numbers to energy savings based on heating in January temperatures and cooling in July. Calculations showed that this device saved the most energy per area for temperature control, compared with other temperature-responsive thermal-management devices reported so far.</p><p>“It will significantly improve thermal energy utilization efficiency,” says Ma, “although there is still a lot of room for improvement in solar heating power and radiative cooling power.”</p>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2022 17:51:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spectrum.ieee.org/passive-radiative-cooling-device</guid><category>Radiative cooling</category><category>Solar thermal</category><category>Infrared</category><category>Passive cooling</category><category>Heat management</category><dc:creator>Prachi Patel</dc:creator><media:content medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/a-blue-gloved-hand-holds-a-grey-square-in-front-of-a-green-plant.jpg?id=31787347&amp;width=980"></media:content></item><item><title>Exploring the Value of Power Modules</title><link>https://ad.doubleclick.net/ddm/trackclk/N5744.125581.6383549968321/B28005468.338910302;dc_trk_aid=537092994;dc_trk_cid=177580565;dc_lat=;dc_rdid=;tag_for_child_directed_treatment=;tfua=;ltd=</link><description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/image.png?id=31699487&width=980"/><br/><br/><p>In this training series, we will discuss the high level of integration of DC/DC power modules and the significant implications that this has on power supply design. </p><p><a href="https://ad.doubleclick.net/ddm/trackclk/N5744.125581.6383549968321/B28005468.338910302;dc_trk_aid=537092994;dc_trk_cid=177580565;dc_lat=;dc_rdid=;tag_for_child_directed_treatment=;tfua=;ltd=" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow" target="_blank">Watch this free webinar now!</a></p><p>In addition to high power density and small solution size, modules can also simplify EMI mitigation and reduce power supply design time. And thanks to improved process and packaging technology, a power module may even provide all of these benefits with a lower overall solution cost as well.</p><hr/><p>In addition to these core topics, this training series also touches on some of the lesser-known aspects of power module design like inductor withstand voltage and high-temperature storage testing.</p>]]></description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2022 12:15:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ad.doubleclick.net/ddm/trackclk/N5744.125581.6383549968321/B28005468.338910302;dc_trk_aid=537092994;dc_trk_cid=177580565;dc_lat=;dc_rdid=;tag_for_child_directed_treatment=;tfua=;ltd=</guid><category>Texas instruments</category><category>Power electronics</category><category>Power supplies</category><category>Type:webinar</category><dc:creator>Texas Instruments</dc:creator><media:content medium="image" type="image/png" url="https://assets.rbl.ms/31699487/origin.png"></media:content></item><item><title>Engineers Make Green Hydrogen From Air</title><link>https://spectrum.ieee.org/engineers-make-green-hydrogen-from-air</link><description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/numerous-floating-pairs-of-connected-spheres.jpg?id=31658114&width=1200&height=800&coordinates=0%2C104%2C0%2C105"/><br/><br/><p><strong>The most sustainable</strong> way to make hydrogen fuel is to split water using renewable electricity—but that requires access to freshwater. Now, researchers have reported a way to make hydrogen fuel from just humidity in the air. </p><p>Their electrolyzer extracts moisture from air and splits it via renewably powered electrolysis to create hydrogen. It is the first such electrolyzer to produce high purity (99 percent) hydrogen from air that has as little as 4 percent humidity, says <a href="https://twitter.com/kevinli06613844?lang=en" target="_blank">Gang Kevin Li</a>, a professor of chemical engineering at the <a href="https://www.unimelb.edu.au/" target="_blank">University of Melbourne</a>, in Australia. The success could open up the possibility of producing hydrogen in semi-arid regions, which also have some of the highest solar- and wind-power potential. </p><p>Tests of the prototype direct-air electrolyzer over 12 consecutive days showed that it could produce almost 750 liters of hydrogen a day on average per square meter of electrolyzer. Li and his colleagues reported the details in the journal <em><a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-022-32652-y" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Nature Communications</a></em>. </p><p>Hydrogen offers the prospect of clean, emission-free energy, and the hydrogen economy has gathered steam in the past few years due to <a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/hydrogen-economy-inflation-reduction-act" target="_blank">increases in funding and improvements in technology</a>. But most of the hydrogen around the world today is still produced from natural gas or coal. Green hydrogen from electrolysis is still a nascent technology because of the need for electrolyzers on a large scale. </p><p>Many teams are working on alternative ways to make green hydrogen. <a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/artificial-leaf-hydrogen-syngas" target="_self">Solar-powered water-splitting</a> devices, for example, use photocatalysts, which absorb sunlight to split water into hydrogen and oxygen but have a low <a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/solar-hydrogen-converter-outlasts-next-best-by-14x" target="_self">solar-to-hydrogen efficiency</a> of only 1 percent. To overcome the need for freshwater, there have been attempts to produce hydrogen from saline and brackish waters, but the devices have to deal with contamination and chlorine as a by-product.</p><p>Li and his colleagues decided to use moisture in the air as the water source. Globally, there are nearly 13 trillion tonnes of water in the air at any moment, they say, and even dry environments such as the expansive <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sahel" target="_blank">Sahel region</a> in Africa have an average relative humidity of 20 percent.</p><p>To tap into that humidity, the researchers soaked a sponge or foam with a water-absorbing electrolyte liquid, and sandwich it between two electrodes. “Water extracted by the electrolyte is spontaneously transported to the electrodes by capillary force and electrolyzed into hydrogen at the cathode and oxygen at the anode,” Li explains. “The whole process is passive, and no moving parts or mechanics are involved.”</p><p>The researchers demonstrated the use of both solar panels or a small wind turbine to power the module. They tested the prototype both indoors and outdoors in the hot, dry Melbourne summer. The solar-to-hydrogen efficiency of the device is over 15 percent, Li says.</p><p><br/></p><div class="rm-embed embed-media"><script src="https://cdn.jwplayer.com/players/8q1bDOsY-5Zdv3OJ1.js"></script></div><p><br/></p><p>For the outdoor tests, they connected five electrolyzers in parallel, which, powered by the sun, produced 745 L of hydrogen per square meter a day, enough to heat a home. They also let the prototype run by itself for eight months to showcase durability.</p><p>The prototype is only a few square centimeters in area right now. But over the next year, with funding from investors, the team plans to make larger electrolyzers, with electrode areas of 10 square meters, Li says. They are also improving the electrolyte recipe to further increase the energy efficiency and output, he says. </p><p>Both efficiency and output should not be affected when the device is scaled up. But the main challenge the team faces is to find the right materials for the electrolyzer, he says. “How can we make it cheaper and better?”</p><p><em>This article appears in the November 2022 print issue as “Pulling Fuel Out of Thin Air.”</em></p>]]></description><pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2022 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spectrum.ieee.org/engineers-make-green-hydrogen-from-air</guid><category>Green hydrogen</category><category>Power</category><category>Solar power</category><category>Wind power</category><dc:creator>Prachi Patel</dc:creator><media:content medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/numerous-floating-pairs-of-connected-spheres.jpg?id=31658114&amp;width=980"></media:content></item><item><title>Get the Rohde &amp; Schwarz EMI White Paper</title><link>https://www.rohde-schwarz.com/solutions/test-and-measurement/emc-testing/emi-debugging/white-paper-how-to-measure-and-reduce-common-mode-emi-registration_254960.html?cid=010_de_eml-nl_130_ieee_22-09_int__how-to-measure-and-reduce_eblast_text-ad____MM-1080685</link><description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/image.png?id=26851523&width=980"/><br/><br/><p>Nowadays, electric machines are often driven by power electronic converters. Even though the use of converters brings with it a variety of advantages, common mode (CM) signals are a frequent problem in many installations. Common mode voltages induced by the converter drive common mode currents damage the motor bearings over time and significantly reduce the lifetime of the drive. </p><p><a href="https://www.rohde-schwarz.com/solutions/test-and-measurement/emc-testing/emi-debugging/white-paper-how-to-measure-and-reduce-common-mode-emi-registration_254960.html?cid=010_de_eml-nl_130_ieee_22-09_int__how-to-measure-and-reduce_eblast_text-ad____MM-1080685" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Download this free whitepaper now!</a></p><hr/><p>Hence, it’s essential to measure these common mode quantities in order to take suitable countermeasures. Handheld oscilloscopes in combination with Rogowski probes offer a simple and reliable way to accurately determine the required quantities and the effectiveness of different countermeasures.<u></u><u></u></p>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Sep 2022 12:22:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.rohde-schwarz.com/solutions/test-and-measurement/emc-testing/emi-debugging/white-paper-how-to-measure-and-reduce-common-mode-emi-registration_254960.html?cid=010_de_eml-nl_130_ieee_22-09_int__how-to-measure-and-reduce_eblast_text-ad____MM-1080685</guid><category>Rohde schwarz</category><category>Electromagnetic interference</category><category>Oscilloscopes</category><category>Power electronic converters</category><category>Power electronics</category><category>Type:whitepaper</category><dc:creator>Rohde &amp; Schwarz</dc:creator><media:content medium="image" type="image/png" url="https://assets.rbl.ms/26851523/origin.png"></media:content></item><item><title>Aluminum Sulfur—Is This How the Future Spells Lithium Ion?</title><link>https://spectrum.ieee.org/aluminum-sulfur-batteries-li-ion-s-new-competitor</link><description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/the-three-primary-constituents-of-the-battery-are-aluminum-left-sulfur-center-and-rock-salt.jpg?id=31529084&width=1200&height=800&coordinates=0%2C0%2C0%2C1"/><br/><br/><p>In a leap toward low-cost batteries for large-scale grid storage, an international team of researchers led by MIT material chemist Donald Sadoway have invented a battery made of aluminum and sulfur, two of the most abundant and low-cost materials in the world. </p><p>The nascent battery already has an energy density comparable to that of today’s lithium-ion batteries at cell level, and should come in at less than a sixth of the cost, the team reported in <em><a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-022-04983-9" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Nature</a> </em>on 24 August. The battery also charges in minutes and is nonflammable thanks to its molten salt electrolyte that does not burn. “You can put a blowtorch to this thing and it won’t catch fire,” says Sadoway.</p><p>Other than storing solar and wind power for the grid, the new battery would be ideal for small-scale residential backup systems and EV charging stations, where they could quickly charge several cars at once. </p><p class="pull-quote">“Lithium as we can see increasingly is the wrong choice. It doesn’t belong in cars and certainly not in grid-level storage. I wanted to make a battery without lithium.”<br/>—Donald Sadoway, MIT</p><p>The need for long-term storage technologies is increasing as the adoption of renewables accelerates around the world. Lithium-ion batteries are much too expensive for that. That’s partly because behind every lithium-ion battery is a convoluted global supply chain fraught with environmental and <a href="https://www.business-humanrights.org/en/from-us/briefings/transition-minerals-sector-case-studies/human-rights-in-the-mineral-supply-chains-of-electric-vehicles/" target="_blank">human rights</a> issues, which has led many to look for the cobalt, lithium, manganese, and nickel needed for lithium batteries on the <a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/the-seabed-solution" target="_self">ocean floor</a>, which creates its own ecological <a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/mine-ocean-battery-metal-shortage" target="_self">dilemma</a>.</p><p>“Batteries we use in America should be invented in America, sourced in America, and made in America,” Sadoway says. “Until then you’re going to be beholden to China, the Democratic Republic of Congo, Chile, and others. Lithium as we can see increasingly is the wrong choice. It doesn’t belong in cars and certainly not in grid-level storage. I wanted to make a battery without lithium.”<br/> </p><p>He and his team chose aluminum, the most abundant metal on Earth, as one electrode. As a bookend electrode, they picked sulfur, the cheapest nonmetal. Then came time to search for the right electrolyte. They avoided the flammable organic liquid electrolytes used in lithium-ion batteries and chose a <a href="https://link.springer.com/chapter/10.1007/978-94-009-3863-2_16" target="_blank">chloro-aluminate molten salt</a>, which needs to be a liquid to be activated. In the paper, the researchers report a battery that operates at the salt’s melting point of 110 °C for operation. But he says they have already brought that melting point down to 65 °C and can see ways to get to room-temperature operation. </p><p class="pull-quote">“Lithium ion has had 30 years of industrial optimization. This is brand new. I’m confident that what we have coming out of the starting gate is competitive.”<br/>—Donald Sadoway, MIT</p><p>Besides being nonflammable, the electrolytes prevent the buildup of metal dendrites on the electrode that can cause shorting, and allows for rapid charging. In the laboratory, the battery cells underwent hundreds of charging cycles at very high rates without aluminum dendrite formation.</p><p>The battery already shows an energy density of almost 530 watt-hours per liter, on par with common lithium-ion chemistry. And it’s still early stages, Sadoway says, so improvements are very likely. “I would remind you, when you compare aluminum sulfur today with lithium ion, a fair comparison would be to compare with lithium ion in 1993,” he says. “Lithium ion has had 30 years of industrial optimization. This is brand new. I’m confident that what we have coming out of the starting gate is competitive.”</p><p>For the “opening act,” he says, small-scale storage systems with capacities of tens of kilowatt-hours seems like a perfect fit for the aluminum-sulfur battery. Competitors like <a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/a-liquid-metal-battery-for-grid-storage-nears-production" target="_self">liquid metal batteries</a> such as the ones <a href="https://www.cbsnews.com/boston/news/donald-sadoway-ambri-liquid-metal-battery-mit/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">soon to be delivered</a> by Ambri, a startup Sadoway cofounded in 2010, require much higher temperatures of 500 °C and make sense for large systems with power capacities of tens of megawatt-hours, he says. “Aluminum sulfur is a scale-down problem, not a scale-up problem. It would be ideal for a single-family home. You’d be able to have a 50- to 100-kilowatt-hour pack to get you through the night and a couple days of cloudy skies.”</p><p>Sadoway and Luis Ortiz, a cofounder of Ambri, have already created a new spinoff company called Avanti, which has licensed the patents for the new battery system. They now plan to scale up the technology. </p><p>For now, he says this research paper is a reminder that there are better, cheaper, safer technologies to work on than lithium ion if people are willing to invest the time and money. Big car companies are putting millions into building gigafactories for lithium batteries, but Sadoway compares lithium-ion technology today to vacuum tubes back in the mid-1950s—a technology whose time will soon be over. </p><p>“Imagine you’re in 1954, and you’re about to build a gigafactory for vacuum tubes, and someone lifts a curtain and there’s the transistor,” he says. “Well, you’re going to have an ‘Oh, shit!’ moment.”</p>]]></description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2022 15:13:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spectrum.ieee.org/aluminum-sulfur-batteries-li-ion-s-new-competitor</guid><category>Batteries</category><category>Lithium-ion batteries</category><category>Sulfur battery</category><category>Energy storage</category><category>Grid storage</category><category>Aluminum-ion</category><dc:creator>Prachi Patel</dc:creator><media:content medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/the-three-primary-constituents-of-the-battery-are-aluminum-left-sulfur-center-and-rock-salt.jpg?id=31529084&amp;width=980"></media:content></item><item><title>Will an EV-Filled World Pass the Sulfuric-Acid Test?</title><link>https://spectrum.ieee.org/sulfuric-acid-shortage</link><description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/overhead-view-of-mounds-of-yellow-pelletized-sulfur.jpg?id=31464451&width=1200&height=800&coordinates=0%2C104%2C0%2C105"/><br/><br/><p>Look at the periodic table, and think of the elements needed for a prosperous planet powered by renewable energy. Sulfur likely won’t be the first to come to mind.</p><p>It probably doesn’t help the yellow element’s noxious reputation to learn that most of the world’s sulfur comes as a by-product of refining fossil fuels. In a net-zero future, a future where petroleum and natural-gas production enter terminal decline and never return to their past carbon-spewing heights, sulfur production will fall away, too.</p><p>Therein lies the problem. Sulfur—easily turned into sulfuric acid—is a necessary tool for <a href="https://www.essentialchemicalindustry.org/chemicals/sulfuric-acid.html#:~:text=By%20far%20the%20largest%20amount,important%20fertilizer%20in%20sulfur%2Ddeficient." target="_blank">creating fertilizer</a> and <a href="https://www.researchgate.net/post/Why_do_we_use_acids_for_heavy_metal_extraction" target="_blank">extracting heavy metals from their ores</a> before they can go into batteries, wind turbines, and electric-vehicle components. Even as sulfur production is set to fall, sulfuric-acid demand is set to rise. </p><p>That’s a recipe for an impending crisis, researchers <a href="https://doi.org/10.1111/geoj.12475" target="_blank">warn in a paper published 21 August</a> in <em>The Geographical Journal</em>.</p><p>Today, the world uses 246 million tonnes of sulfuric acid in a year. The researchers project that number might increase to 400 million tonnes by 2040.</p><p class="pull-quote">Sulfuric acid is necessary for extracting heavy metals such as nickel, cobalt, and rare earths for batteries, magnets, and other renewable-energy technologies. The world’s needs are going up—from 246 million tonnes today to 400 million tonnes by 2040—but the supply could be drying out. Sulfur is most cheaply obtained as a by-product of petroleum refineries. </p><p>That’s because, when it comes to renewable energy, sulfuric acid has a very critical use. Extracting heavy metals, such as nickel, cobalt, and rare earths, relies on chemical processes that use sulfuric acid to separate the metals from their ores. Those heavy metals are key elements in lithium-ion batteries, electric motors, and other technologies crucial for the renewable transition.</p><p>(Sulfur has other roles, too. Perhaps even more significantly than renewables, sulfuric acid is a <a href="https://www.sulphurinstitute.org/about-sulphur/sulphur-the-fourth-major-plant-nutrient/" target="_blank">key element in manufacturing fertilizers</a>. Sulfuric acid <a href="http://www.utahbiodieselsupply.com/blog/how-using-sulfuric-acid-works-when-making-biodiesel/" target="_blank">goes into biofuels</a>, and sulfur is used <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sulfur_vulcanization" target="_blank">to vulcanize and harden rubber</a>.)</p><p>Where does that sulfur come from, then? Decades ago, most of it came from mining. In 1894, a German chemist named <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Herman_Frasch" target="_blank">Herman Frasch</a> plotted a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Frasch_process" target="_blank">process</a> of tapping a sulfur-containing mineral deposit by pumping it with superheated water. The sulfur will melt and bubble up to the surface. Sulfur miners have used the same process ever since.</p><p>The Frasch process can be tremendously damaging to the surrounding environment and mineworkers’ health. The minerals that contain sulfur often also tend to contain toxic metals like mercury, arsenic, and thallium. The process also spews out wastewater that contains <a href="https://www.osha.gov/hydrogen-sulfide" target="_blank">hydrogen sulfide</a>, which causes poisoning symptoms similar to those of carbon monoxide. (Although hydrogen sulfide is in fact some ten times more toxic than CO.) </p><p>By the 1950s, the world had exhausted the most easily available sulfur deposits. Mining costs skyrocketed, rapidly inflating the element’s market price. Analysts warned of an impending <a href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/40392456" target="_blank">“sulphur famine.”</a></p><p class="pull-quote">“A lot of people, they take sulfur for granted.”<br/>—Jean-Michel Lavoie, University of Sherbrooke, Québec</p><p>In swept the fossil-fuel industry’s waste to save the day. By coincidence, sulfur’s presence in petroleum makes it harder to refine into diesel, jet fuel, and other assorted products. To sort it out, refineries have to filter out the sulfur—thereby making it available to the rest of the world. Today, more than 80 percent of the world’s sulfur comes from these acts of waste management. As dirty as it sounds, it’s actually cleaner than mining.</p><p>However, naturally, if carbon-emitting fossil fuels go, refineries like this will likely go too. It’s hard to know how quickly that will happen, but in a scenario where the world reaches net-zero carbon dioxide emissions by 2050, the researchers estimate that sulfur production would drop by one-half or even more. </p><p>“It’s an eye-opener,” <a href="https://www.usherbrooke.ca/genie-chimique-biotech//departement/professeurs/jean-michel-lavoie/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Jean-Michel Lavoie</a>, a chemist at the <a href="https://www.ltb-btl.ca/en/home/" target="_blank">Laboratoire des Technologies de la Biomasse</a>, on the campus of the University of Sherbrooke, in Québec, who was not an author of the paper. “We never really focus on trying to solve these problems, but I think we’re going to start looking into solutions.”</p><p>The world could swing back to sourcing sulfur directly from mines. That may happen if the economics favor it. But it’s costlier than getting it from petroleum, and the Frasch process carries an unacceptable ecological burden (not to mention unpleasant <a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-020-18661-9" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">social impacts</a> that disproportionately affect people in developing countries).</p><p>“Research is urgently needed to develop low-cost, low environmental impact methods of extracting large quantities of elemental sulfur,” said <a href="https://www.geog.ucl.ac.uk/people/academic-staff/mark-maslin" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Mark Maslin</a>, a geographer at University College London and one of the paper's authors, in a <a href="https://phys.org/news/2022-08-sulfur-shortage-potential-resource-crisis.html" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">press release</a>. </p><p>Maslin and his colleagues believe, however, that there won’t be a single solution to a sulfur shortage. In some fields, like biofuel production, recycling sulfuric acid is quite common. A few scientists have begun tinkering with sulfuric-acid substitutes—nitric acid, for example—though that’s still quite speculative.</p><p>Reducing the future need for sulfuric-acid certainly wouldn’t hurt. Already, there are batteries (such as lithium iron phosphate batteries) that have lower energy-capacity-to-weight ratios but take in less nickel, cobalt, and heavy metals, and thus need less sulfuric acid. Future research could shape batteries that deliver the best of both worlds.</p><p>What is clear is that weaning off fossil fuels may have quite a number of intended side effects—bad or good—and a sulfur shortage is just one of them.</p><p>“A lot of people, they take sulfur for granted,” says Lavoie.</p><p><br/></p><p><em><strong>Update 7 September:</strong> The previous version of this story compared toxicities of carbon monoxide and hydrogen sulfide but did not specify that the latter is in fact 10 times more toxic than CO. That ambiguity has now been corrected. </em><br/></p>]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Sep 2022 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spectrum.ieee.org/sulfuric-acid-shortage</guid><category>Sulfur</category><category>Petroleum</category><category>Renewable energy</category><dc:creator>Rahul Rao</dc:creator><media:content medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/overhead-view-of-mounds-of-yellow-pelletized-sulfur.jpg?id=31464451&amp;width=980"></media:content></item><item><title>The War in Ukraine Disrupts Trade in Both Food and Fuel</title><link>https://spectrum.ieee.org/russian-exports</link><description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/a-man-in-a-hard-hat-reaches-down-into-the-cargo-hold-of-a-ship-and-puts-his-hand-into-a-big-pile-of-yellowish-grain-two-other-m.jpg?id=31170659&width=1200&height=800&coordinates=0%2C0%2C0%2C176"/><br/><br/><p><strong>The Russian invasion</strong> of Ukraine has brought a stream of reports about the country’s energy exports. Here are the basic facts.  </p><p>Russia ranks second in the extraction of both crude oil (behind the United States and ahead of Saudi Arabia) and natural gas (behind the United States and ahead of Iran), and it is the sixth-largest producer of coal (behind Australia and ahead of South Africa). Before the war, Russia exported about 55 percent of its fossil-fuel output, mostly to the European Union. The EU bought about 85 percent of the natural gas that Russia shipped out (via pipelines from Western Siberia) and nearly 55 percent of the crude oil and refined oil products that Russia exported (via pipelines and tankers). </p><hr/><p>This means that in 2021 the EU got more than 40 percent of its natural gas, 27 percent of its oil, and 46 percent of its coal imports from Russia, for which it paid €99 billion, or nearly US $10 billion a month. Since the start of the war, soaring energy prices have lifted this import bill to about $23 billion a month, making the EU a significant de facto financier of the Russian invasion: three-quarters of a billion a day! Belatedly, in May, the EU produced its <a href="https://ec.europa.eu/commission/presscorner/detail/en/IP_22_3131" target="_blank">REPowerEU plan</a>, which is intended to drastically reduce this dependence.  </p><p>But Russian exports go far beyond fossil fuels; there is also food. It is one thing for the EU to reduce its dependence on Russian hydrocarbons, quite another for many low-income countries to do without Russian (and Ukrainian) grain. This is because Russia has changed from a proverbial agricultural basket case to a food basket. Any attempt to reduce imports of its foodstuffs would impose higher prices on precisely those nations that can least afford them. </p><p class="pull-quote">It is one thing for the EU to reduce its dependence on Russian hydrocarbons, quite another for many low-income countries to do without Russian (and Ukrainian) grain.</p><p>The Soviet Union long struggled to produce wheat, and beginning in the 1970s the country indeed began to import the grain en masse from the United States. After the Soviet Union unraveled in the early 1990s, its wheatlands were divided between Russia and Ukraine. Russian agriculture at first shrank, then staged a comeback in the early years of the new century: By 2015 it had begun to export about as much wheat as the United States, and in 2018 it sold nearly twice as much (almost 44 million tonnes), most of it going to the Middle East and Africa. Some of the countries in those regions have also been buying Ukrainian wheat (the country is the fifth-largest exporter of wheat) and sunflower oil, for which Ukraine provides half and Russia a fifth of global exports. </p><p>Moreover, thanks to its large natural-gas production, Russia is also the world’s second-largest producer of ammonia (after China, ahead of India), a key ingredient for artificial nitrogenous fertilizers, of which it is the second-largest exporter. Its reserves of potash and phosphates make it, respectively, the world’s second-largest producer (and exporter) of potassium (after Canada) and the fourth-largest producer (after China, Morocco, and the United States) of phosphates. No other country controls a similarly large share of each of the three plant macronutrients that are needed to sustain high crop yields.  </p><p>No wonder the war raised concerns about the near-complete disruption of Ukrainian food exports (Odesa’s port was blockaded) and about the reduction of Russia’s grain and fertilizer shipments. Global food prices had begun to rise already during the pandemic, and their further expected war-induced increase will have the greatest impact in Asia and Africa, where people typically spend 30 to 40 percent of their disposable income on food; the U.S. share in 2020, by contrast, was about 9 percent.  </p><p>Worst of all, the <a href="https://www.wfp.org/" target="_blank">World Food Programme</a> and the <a href="https://www.fao.org/home/en" target="_blank">Food and Agriculture Organization</a> of the United Nations now expect that rising food prices, widespread supply problems, and worsening drought in parts of Africa will raise the number of malnourished and hungry people. That is why it was encouraging to hear in late July that Russia and Ukraine had agreed to restart Ukrainian food shipments: The first grain-carrying ship left Odesa, Ukraine’s largest port, for Lebanon on 1 August 2022. </p><p><em>This article appears in the September 2022 print issue as “Fuel, Food, and War.”</em></p><div class="rm-embed embed-media"><div class="flourish-embed flourish-map" data-src="visualisation/10779144?602891"><script src="https://public.flourish.studio/resources/embed.js"></script></div></div>]]></description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Aug 2022 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spectrum.ieee.org/russian-exports</guid><category>Energy</category><category>Food</category><category>Food insecurity</category><category>War</category><dc:creator>Vaclav Smil</dc:creator><media:content medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/a-man-in-a-hard-hat-reaches-down-into-the-cargo-hold-of-a-ship-and-puts-his-hand-into-a-big-pile-of-yellowish-grain-two-other-m.jpg?id=31170659&amp;width=980"></media:content></item><item><title>Fitful Ukrainian Nuclear Plant Stokes Powerful Fears</title><link>https://spectrum.ieee.org/ukraine-nuclear-power-plant-fears</link><description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/a-power-plant-seen-in-the-distance-with-road-signs-in-the-foreground.jpg?id=31252865&width=1200&height=800&coordinates=0%2C162%2C0%2C162"/><br/><br/><p>For several weeks now shelling from, on, and around the Zaporizhzhia nuclear power station has emboldened nuclear safety experts in Ukraine to openly advocate for a controlled shutdown of the beleaguered plant. <a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/nuclear-energy-brinkmanship-in-ukraine" target="_self">As <em>IEEE Spectrum</em> reported last week</a>, they argue that proactively stopping power generation at the two units still operating, and cooling their reactors, would reduce the likelihood of a nuclear disaster—one that Ukrainian state experts say could be more devastating than the Chernobyl and Fukushima accidents.</p><p>Yesterday disruption of a crucial transmission line forced a total shutdown in a dangerous series of events that once again spotlighted Zaporizhzhia’s precarious situation.</p><p>For the second time this month, backup diesel generators and other automatic emergency systems had to kick in. This time they completely disconnected Europe’s largest nuclear power plant from Ukraine’s grid for the first time since it began operating in 1985.</p><p class="pull-quote">Radioactive coal ash piles near the nuclear power plant were shelled on Tuesday. Monitors picked up rising radiation levels as the ash spread. By Thursday morning, the ash piles were also on fire.  </p><p>In <a href="https://apnews.com/article/russia-ukraine-kyiv-united-nations-climate-and-environment-c4b57d9b04e43d35747148b230eed187" target="_blank">his nightly address yesterday</a> Ukrainian president Volodymir Zelenskyy credited Zaporizhzhia’s diesel generators and its Ukrainian staff for avoiding a “radiation” incident. “Russia has put Ukraine and all Europeans one step away from a radiation disaster,” said Zelenskyy.</p><p>International Atomic Energy Agency director general Rafael Grossi pressed for an IAEA mission to Zaporizhzhia “in the next few days” to bring stability to the situation. “Almost every day there is a new incident at or near the Zaporizhzhia Nuclear Power Plant. We can’t afford to lose any more time,” said Grossi in <a href="https://www.iaea.org/newscenter/pressreleases/update-94-iaea-director-general-statement-on-situation-in-ukraine" target="_blank">an IAEA statement issued yesterday</a>.</p><p>Today, rather than leave the plant off-line, however, Ukrainian staff at the Russian-occupied plant <a href="https://t.me/energoatom_ua/9208" target="_blank">restarted one of the plant’s six units</a> after transmission repairs strengthened the plant’s external power supply.</p><p>Energoatom, Ukraine’s nuclear power utility, celebrated the restart in patriotic terms: “Zaporizhzhia NPP nuclear power professionals are real heroes! They tirelessly and tightly hold the nuclear and radiation safety of Ukraine and the whole of Europe on their shoulders, and they’re working selflessly to get their home country to have life-giving electricity.”</p><p>The roots of yesterday’s near-miss go back to the shelling on Tuesday of coal ash piles near the Zaporizhzhia nuclear plant, which Russia seized in March and sits just across the Dnipro River from Ukrainian-held territory. Ukrainian military intelligence reported that <a href="https://gordonua.com/news/war/okkupanty-obstrelivayut-sklady-s-zoloy-zaporozhskoy-tes-chtoby-podnyat-oblaka-radioaktivnoy-pyli-gur-1622832.html" target="_blank">Russia was shelling the piles to incite fear</a> because the ash is “at least 2.5 times” more radioactive than background levels, and laced with heavy metals and other toxins.</p><p>Russian occupation authorities <a href="https://apnews.com/article/russia-ukraine-kyiv-united-nations-climate-and-environment-c4b57d9b04e43d35747148b230eed187" target="_blank">blamed Ukraine</a> for the shelling.</p><p>Regardless, monitors picked up rising radiation levels in the area on Tuesday as the ash spread. By Thursday morning the ash piles were also on fire, including underneath the giant transmission line to Dniprovska that was delivering Zaporizhzhia’s generation to Ukraine’s grid—the last of four such 750-kilovolt lines from the station still operating after six months of war.</p><p>A forest fire was also burning nearby in Energodar, the city where most Zaporizhzhia plant workers live.</p><blockquote class="rm-embed twitter-tweet" data-partner="rebelmouse" data-twitter-tweet-id="1560370933566771201">
<div style="margin:1em 0">\u201cthis is how a map of radiation spread will look like if there is an accident on Zaporizhzhia Nuclear Power Plant. \n\nsource: Ukrainian Hydrometeorological Institute\n\nPS Zaporizzhia NPP is the biggest in Europe. Now occupied by Russians who are using it as a military facility\u201d</div> — UkraineWorld (@UkraineWorld)
        <a href="https://twitter.com/ukraine_world/statuses/1560370933566771201">1660856395</a>
</blockquote>
<script async="" charset="utf-8" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js"></script><p>At 12:12 pm Kyiv time yesterday, <a href="https://t.me/snriugovua/486" target="_blank">according to Ukraine’s nuclear regulator</a>, the 750-kV transmission line went offline due to the fire below. An emergency protection scheme, triggered by a sudden voltage drop at Zaporizhzhia’s unit 5, prompted its backup generators and coolant pumps to start up. Unit 6, in contrast, revved down to a reduced generating mode that enabled it to power its own safety systems.</p><p>But both units—and the rest of the plant—still had a backup source of grid power on standby via a 330-kV transmission line to an adjacent 330-kV substation. That means diesel generators were not the plant’s only means of cooling Zaporizhzhia’s reactor cores and spent fuel pools.</p><p>After the 750-kV line to Dniprovska returned to operation at 12:29 pm, unit 6 returned to generating power for Ukraine’s grid for almost 2 hours until fire once again shut off the line. This time the diesel generators activated at unit 6.</p><p>The 750-kV line was restored later in the day. But the plant continued to draw power from its 330-kV grid connection overnight.</p><p><br/></p><div class="rm-embed embed-media"><script async="" data-telegram-post="energoatom_ua/9204" data-width="100%" src="https://telegram.org/js/telegram-widget.js?19"></script></div><p class="caption"><strong>The above Telegram post from the Ukrainian Energoatom agency shows fires that prompted a complete shutdown of the Zaporizhzhia nuclear plant.</strong> </p><p>When one reactor restarted at 2:04 pm Kyiv time today, it did so via two power lines according to <a href="https://t.me/Ukrenergo/1383" target="_blank">a Telegram post by Ukrainian grid operator Ukrenergo</a>: “The operation of two trunk lines damaged by [Russian forces] was restored….Thanks to this, stable energy supply and safe functioning of spent nuclear fuel storage facilities and other important facilities located at the ZNPP site are currently ensured.”</p><p>Later in the day Energoatom <a href="https://t.me/energoatom_ua/9214" target="_blank">announced</a> the restart of the second unit that had been shut down the day before. </p><p>Experts in the United States continue to back a total shutdown. “I would put a priority on reducing the temperature of the fuel rods [to reduce risk],” said Thomas Cochran, the longtime former nuclear energy safety and nuclear proliferation expert for the Natural Resources Defense Council. “There is more safety margin against power failures after the reactors have cooled down for a while,” agreed Ed Lyman, director of nuclear power safety at the Union of Concerned Scientists.</p><p>Nuclear experts in Ukraine advocating shutdown, such as Viktor Shenderovych, formerly chief of nuclear plant design at Ukraine’s National Research and Development Center for Nuclear Power and Energy, did score one win for their position recently. On August 19, Ukraine’s nuclear regulator amended Zaporizhzhia’s license to operate, ordering Energoatom to <a href="https://ua.interfax.com.ua/news/general/853200.html" target="_blank">maintain the ‘cold stop’ status of Zaporizhzhia units 1 and 2</a>, where Russian military vehicles <a href="https://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-11126467/Russia-tells-staff-Zaporizhzhia-nuclear-power-plant-not-come-work.html" target="_blank">appear to be parked in the turbine halls</a>.</p><p>Zelenskyy stated yesterday that the IAEA and “other international organizations” need to act faster. However, hurdles still complicate Grossi’s plans to lead a mission to Zaporizhzhia. One is Ukraine’s concern about the many Russian experts within the IAEA. In <a href="https://www.ft.com/content/a99752be-c959-47a5-9b35-b10f576094f4" target="_blank">an interview with the <em>Financial Times</em> published on Wednesday</a>, Ukrainian energy minister and former Energoatom vice president German Galushchenko expressed his hope that IAEA nuclear experts “from any country [but] not Russians” could soon be dispatched to the embattled plant. </p>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2022 18:34:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spectrum.ieee.org/ukraine-nuclear-power-plant-fears</guid><category>Ukraine conflict</category><category>Ukraine</category><category>Russia</category><category>Nuclear power</category><category>Nuclear safety</category><dc:creator>Peter Fairley</dc:creator><media:content medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/a-power-plant-seen-in-the-distance-with-road-signs-in-the-foreground.jpg?id=31252865&amp;width=980"></media:content></item><item><title>Floating Artificial Leaf Turns CO2 Into Fuel</title><link>https://spectrum.ieee.org/artificial-leaf-hydrogen-syngas</link><description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/a-green-square-floats-on-the-water-in-front-of-buildings-and-blue-sky.jpg?id=31173420&width=1200&height=800&coordinates=0%2C136%2C0%2C137"/><br/><br/><p>A new artificial leaf is light enough to float on water, where it can soak up sunlight and carbon dioxide from air, and use the water below to produce fuels.</p><p>Researchers at Cambridge University tested their 100-square-centimeter artificial-leaf device outdoors on a river. Depending on the catalyst used, the device either splits water to <a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/researchers-tweak-artificial-photosynthesis-for-more-efficient-hydrogen-production" target="_self">produce hydrogen</a> fuel, or <a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/artificial-photosynthesis-moves-on-from-water-splitting-to-co2-reduction" target="_self">converts carbon dioxide </a>into syngas, a mix of carbon monoxide and hydrogen that is used to make other fuels like methanol. Fleets of such devices could be deployed on brackish water ponds, canals, and on seas, so as not to compete with land use, they say.</p><p>“We are trying to mimic nature with an integrated, simple device that can utilize water,” says Virgil Andrei, a chemistry research fellow at the University of Cambridge who led the work, which was reported in the journal <em><a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-022-04978-6" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Nature</a></em>. “We have a device that not only works like a natural leaf, it also has the flexible, lightweight properties of a leaf.”</p><p>Scientists have been trying to copy the photosynthetic energy-producing ability of plants for years. The ultimate goal is an artificial leaf: a passive device that uses a photovoltaic material to harvest sunlight and then with the help of catalysts turns carbon dioxide into fuel. Since Harvard researchers reported the <a href="https://www.science.org/doi/pdf/10.1126/science.1209816" target="_blank">first water-splitting artificial leaf</a> in 2011, many teams have been working on similar technologies to also <a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/maximum-potential-for-turning-co2-into-fuel-using-solar-energy" target="_blank">reduce carbon dioxide to make fuels</a>, fertilizers, and other chemicals. Carbon dioxide reduction is much more complicated than splitting water, and it requires the right combination of catalysts and reaction parameters. </p><p>In 2019 Andrei, chemistry professor Erwin Reisner, and their colleagues reported the <a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41563-019-0501-6" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">first artificial leaf</a> that could make syngas. They used perovskite light absorbers and either platinum or cobalt catalysts for the reaction. The platinum catalyst splits water into oxygen and hydrogen in the presence of sunlight, while cobalt triggers the reduction of carbon dioxide and water into syngas. But their devices, and most others reported so far, tend to be small-scale prototypes tested only in laboratory settings.</p><p>The Cambridge team had upscaling and commercialization in mind for their new work. “We thought if we want to push this technology towards commercialization, we really need to redesign the device structure,” Andrei says. “One idea would be to shrink the device.”</p><p>So the team replaced the thick glass substrates they had used before with thin conductive plastic substrates. They coated these with layers, each a few micrometers thick, of perovskites, conductive metal-oxide and polymer, and cobalt or platinum catalyst. They used a mixture of standard epoxy glue and graphite powder to coat the layers to protect them from moisture.</p><p>The lightweight device floated in water, and under sunlight it quickly produced syngas bubbles, which further helped keep the device afloat. The artificial leaf worked well for a 24-hour test period. It produced hydrogen and carbon monoxide with efficiencies of about 0.6 percent and 0.05 percent, respectively, for each gram. That is low but comparable to natural photosynthesis, which has a typical efficiency of 0.5 to 1 percent, Andrei says. </p><p>The upside, he adds, is that you can make this device much cheaper in principle compared with other solar fuel technologies, which rely on separate photovoltaic cells and electrochemical cells to conduct the reactions and take up space on land. “You can have something very simple and light that can be deployed on water anywhere.”</p><p>Andrei says the team has not done a techno-economic analysis yet, but that they plan to do that soon. They are also working on making the device even lighter, and figuring out the best way to deploy it—be it a large plastic dome or simply a sealed plastic bag—and continuously collect the syngas or hydrogen for use.</p>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2022 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spectrum.ieee.org/artificial-leaf-hydrogen-syngas</guid><category>Syngas</category><category>Hydrogen economy</category><category>Artificial photosynthesis</category><category>Solar power</category><category>Artificial leaf</category><dc:creator>Prachi Patel</dc:creator><media:content medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/a-green-square-floats-on-the-water-in-front-of-buildings-and-blue-sky.jpg?id=31173420&amp;width=980"></media:content></item><item><title>Software Turns Promise Up for Offshore Wind</title><link>https://spectrum.ieee.org/vertical-axis-wind-turbine</link><description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/illustration-shows-two-versions-of-a-turbine-design-in-sun-and-in-stormy-weather.jpg?id=31179195&width=1200&height=800&coordinates=0%2C89%2C0%2C90"/><br/><br/><p><span style="background-color: initial;">A radical new idea for offshore wind turbines would replace tall unwieldy towers that had blades on top with lightweight, towerless machines whose blades resemble the loops of a whisk. Now new software can help optimize these unusual designs to help make them a reality, researchers say.</span><br/></p><p>This new work comes as the U.S. government plans to boost <a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/more-stagger-more-wind-power" target="_self">offshore wind energy</a>. In March, the White House announced <a href="https://www.energy.gov/articles/energy-secretary-granholm-announces-ambitious-new-30gw-offshore-wind-deployment-target" target="_blank">a national goal</a> to deploy 30 gigawatts of new offshore wind power by 2030. The federal government suggested this initiative could help power more than 10 million homes, support roughly 77,000 jobs, cut 78 million tonnes in carbon emissions, and spur US $12 billion in private investment per year. As part of this new plan, in <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/23/fact-sheet-biden-administration-launches-new-federal-state-offshore-wind-partnership-to-grow-american-made-clean-energy/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">June</a>, the White House and eleven governors from along the East Coast launched a Federal-State Offshore Wind Implementation Partnership to further develop the offshore wind supply chain, including manufacturing facilities and port capabilities.</p><p>One reason offshore wind is attractive is the high demand for electricity on the coasts. People often live far away from where onshore wind is the strongest, and there is not enough space in cities for enough solar panels to power them, says <a href="https://energy.sandia.gov/programs/renewable-energy/water-power/water-power-personnel/ryan-coe/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Ryan Coe</a>, a mechanical engineer in Sandia National Laboratories’ water-power group in Albuquerque.</p><p class="pull-quote">The guy wires can be shortened or lengthened to adjust the height of the blades in response to wind conditions, much as modifying the amount of tension in a bowstring can help change the curve of a bow.</p><p>However, nearly 60 percent of the accessible offshore wind in the United States blows across water more than 60 meters deep. At such depths, it would prove very expensive to build a foundation for wind turbines on the seafloor. However, this deeper offshore wind energy remains attractive, as it roughly equals the entire annual electricity consumption in the United States.<br/></p><p>Wind turbines that can float above the seafloor could help play a key role in renewable energy. However, floating offshore wind turbines face their own challenges, such as their cost.</p><p>“Floating offshore wind is currently estimated to be three to five times more expensive than land-based wind in the United States,” says mechanical engineer <a href="https://energy.sandia.gov/programs/renewable-energy/wind-power/wind-energy-staff/brandon-ennis" target="_blank">Brandon Ennis</a>, Sandia’s offshore wind technical lead in Albuquerque.</p><p>The aim of the U.S. Department of Energy’s <a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/underwater-manta-kites-tidal-power-harvesting" target="_self">Advanced Research Project Agency–Energy</a>’s <a href="https://arpa-e.energy.gov/technologies/programs/atlantis" target="_blank">ATLANTIS</a> project is to optimize the design of floating offshore wind turbines to maximize their power while minimizing their expense. The new, towerless design might help reduce both their mass and cost, Ennis says.</p><p>When it comes to land-based wind power, the turbines themselves represent about 65 percent of their levelized cost of energy—that is, their lifetime costs divided by energy production. In comparison, when it comes to floating offshore wind power, the turbines represent only about 20 percent of their levelized costs, Ennis says. Instead, their floating platforms are the biggest factors behind these costs.</p><p>“Given this difference in contribution to the levelized cost of energy of the turbine itself, it makes sense that the turbine design for floating offshore wind could be radically different than what is optimal on land,” Ennis says.</p><p>Most land-based wind turbines nowadays are <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wind_turbine#Types" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">horizontal-axis machines</a>. They each possess a tower with blades that spin on a horizontal shaft, which cranks a generator behind the blades in the turbine’s nacelle, the box at the top of the turbine.</p><p>In contrast, the new design is a <a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/are-vertical-axis-turbines-the-future-of-offshore-wind-power" target="_self">vertical-axis wind turbine</a> (VAWT). These can resemble <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Revolving_door" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">revolving doors</a>—they each possess blades that spin on a vertical shaft, with a generator below the blades. Placing a wind turbine’s massive generator at the base of the machine instead of high up on a tower makes it much less top heavy, which reduces the size and cost of the floating platform needed to keep it afloat.</p><p>One challenge when it comes to VAWTs is protecting them from extreme winds. Traditional horizontal-axis wind turbines (HAWTs) can rotate away from intense, damaging winds, but previous VAWTs catch wind from every direction.</p><p>The new design replaces the central vertical tower often used in previous VAWTs with a set of taut wires. These wires can be shortened or lengthened to adjust the height of the blades in response to wind conditions, much as modifying the amount of tension in a bowstring can help change the curve of a bow.</p><p>This new design can help maximize each wind turbine’s energy capture while controlling strain. In addition, replacing the shaft with wires further reduces the weight of the turbine, allowing the floating platform to be significantly smaller and less expensive.</p><p>Previous VAWTs with towers often weighed more than HAWTs. In contrast, the new towerless design may weigh less than traditional HAWT designs, Ennis says.</p><p class="shortcode-media shortcode-media-rebelmouse-image">
<img alt="A photograph looking skyward at a white tower with a large loop around it." class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="13c97d001d3cb427c6607ae4f8c50082" data-rm-shortcode-name="rebelmouse-image" id="b681c" loading="lazy" src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/a-photograph-looking-skyward-at-a-white-tower-with-a-large-loop-around-it.jpg?id=31179342&width=980"/>
<small class="image-media media-caption" placeholder="Add Photo Caption...">A historical photo shows Sandia’s experimental 34-meter-diameter vertical-axis wind turbine, built in Texas in the 1980s.</small><small class="image-media media-photo-credit" placeholder="Add Photo Credit...">Randy Montoya/Sandia National Laboratories</small></p><p>Less mass above the water level requires less mass below the water level, leading to a lighter, cheaper platform, Ennis notes. “The optimal wind energy system would remove all mass and cost that is not directly capturing energy from the wind, and the towerless VAWT design concept moves toward that goal by reducing the turbine mass and the associated platform mass,” Ennis says. Sandia filed a patent application for the new design in 2020.</p><p>However, a key challenge with all VAWTs is how they were not the focus of research as the wind industry steadily grew for the past 30 years, Ennis says. As such, where HAWTs possess software to help in their design, VAWTS did not.</p><p>Now Sandia researchers have developed a new tool to model the way in which VAWTs and their floating platforms might respond to different wind and sea conditions. This new Offshore Wind Energy Simulator (<a href="https://arc.aiaa.org/doi/pdf/10.2514/1.J060476" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">OWENS</a>) can help optimize the design and control of these machines.</p><p>“Without a tool like ours, there cannot be a floating offshore VAWT industry, and it has been exciting to see our team advance that capability in such a short time compared to the historical development of design tools in the wind industry,” Ennis says.</p><p>The OWENS tool can also simulate land-based VAWTs. Moreover, with some modifications, it can model unconventional HAWTs, such as <a href="https://newsroom.ucla.edu/releases/innovative-biplane-design-next-generation-wind-turbines" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">bi-wing blades</a> or <a href="https://iopscience.iop.org/article/10.1088/1757-899X/1034/1/012042/meta" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">shrouded concepts</a>, as well as cross-flow marine hydrokinetic turbines, which are essentially VAWTs submerged in water instead of air, Ennis says.</p><p>Popular misinformation does exist concerning VAWTs, Ennis says. “People claim that VAWTs have lower aerodynamic performance,” he says. “That’s wrong. Lift-based VAWTs are predicted to have the ability to slightly exceed the maximum efficiency of a horizontal-axis wind turbine.”</p><p>Ennis does note that “VAWTs that were commercialized in the ’90s had fatigue issues. They also used aluminum blades with bolted joints, which is almost the worst material decision you could make for fatigue, and the design standards weren’t sufficient to characterize the operational life of a wind turbine.” However, modern designs can overcome these concerns, he says.</p><p>The researchers are validating OWENS with a land-based 34-meter-diameter VAWT built at Sandia in the ’80s. This research can eventually help certify VAWT models against pertinent design standards. They plan to submit their findings to the journal <em>Wind Energy Science</em>.</p><p>The scientists hope to have an optimized floating VAWT design by the end of the year, Ennis says. They next aim to have a small physical demo machine to verify its performance.</p><p>“Vertical-axis wind turbines offer some meaningful advantages over traditional horizontal-axis wind turbines, particularly for floating offshore wind energy,” Ennis says. “With our new design software, we are in a good position to evaluate just how significant these advantages might be for our towerless VAWT system.”</p>]]></description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2022 19:25:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spectrum.ieee.org/vertical-axis-wind-turbine</guid><category>Offshore wind</category><category>Wind turbines</category><category>Wind energy</category><category>Arpa-e</category><category>Sandia national laboratories</category><category>Wind power</category><dc:creator>Charles Q. Choi</dc:creator><media:content medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/illustration-shows-two-versions-of-a-turbine-design-in-sun-and-in-stormy-weather.jpg?id=31179195&amp;width=980"></media:content></item><item><title>Modeling Thermal Runaway in Battery Cells and Packs</title><link>https://event.on24.com/wcc/r/3860127/EB6AC3A7FDE6ADC9CD9EB634FADE8F51</link><description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/image.png?id=26851526&width=980"/><br/><br/><p>Lithium-ion (Li-ion) batteries are the preferred choice for electric and hybrid vehicles, energy storage systems, and consumer electronics. One of the top safety concerns with Li-ion batteries is thermal runaway and its cascading effect through the whole pack. To predict thermal runaway, it is necessary to account for several different physical phenomena, including chemical reactions within the cell, heat transfer at the cell and pack level, the structural design of the pack, and fluid flow in the battery pack's cooling system.</p><p><span></span>Join us for this live webinar to see how multiphysics simulation can help you accurately model battery cells and packs, predict thermal runaway, and optimize the design of thermal management for battery packs. The webinar will include demonstrations in the COMSOL software and conclude with a Q&A session. </p><p><a href="https://event.on24.com/wcc/r/3860127/EB6AC3A7FDE6ADC9CD9EB634FADE8F51" target="_blank">Register today!</a></p>]]></description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2022 18:57:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://event.on24.com/wcc/r/3860127/EB6AC3A7FDE6ADC9CD9EB634FADE8F51</guid><category>Batteries</category><category>Type:webinar</category><category>Comsol</category><category>Lithium-ion batteries</category><category>Multiphysics simulation</category><dc:creator>COMSOL</dc:creator><media:content medium="image" type="image/png" url="https://assets.rbl.ms/26851526/origin.png"></media:content></item><item><title>Revamping an Art Deco Masterpiece</title><link>https://spectrum.ieee.org/restore-power</link><description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/image.jpg?id=31198373&width=980"/><br/><br/><p>The Big Picture features technology through the lens of photographers.</p><p>Every month, <em>IEEE Spectrum</em> selects the most stunning technology images recently captured by photographers around the world. We choose images that reflect an important advance, or a trend, or that are just mesmerizing to look at. We feature all images on our site, and one also appears on our monthly print edition.</p><p>Enjoy the latest images, and if you have suggestions, leave a comment below.</p><h3>Power Station Restoration</h3><br/><img alt="Image of a newly restored control room in a power station in London." class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="32c442f3e1cdfe199aeec07099b1d72a" data-rm-shortcode-name="rebelmouse-image" id="9fef1" loading="lazy" src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/image-of-a-newly-restored-control-room-in-a-power-station-in-london.jpg?id=31147265&width=980"/><p>
	This beautifully outfitted room is the newly restored Control Room A at the Battersea Power Station in London. For half a century, the electric power hub controlled the flow of current that met one-fifth of London’s electricity demand. The hub was decommissioned in 1983. Now it has been returned to its original 1930s Art Deco glory. The painstaking restoration, complete with period details—including the gauges engineers relied on when the station was fully functional and a glass elevator that will give visitors a panoramic view of the London skyline–took decades to complete.
</p><p class="caption">
	James Parsons
</p><h3></h3><br/><img alt="Photo zooming in on the eye of a person wearing an electronic contact lens" class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="3baa7fca72642d0103b759fa82669522" data-rm-shortcode-name="rebelmouse-image" id="1a661" loading="lazy" src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/photo-zooming-in-on-the-eye-of-a-person-wearing-an-electronic-contact-lens.jpg?id=30978650&width=980"/><h3>
<a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/looking-through-mojo-visions-newest-ar-contact-lens" target="_blank">Augmented-Reality Contacts</a>
</h3><p>
	In March 2022, IEEE Spectrum Senior Editor Tekla S. Perry took a glimpse at the world through the latest iteration of Mojo Vision’s AR contact lens. She didn’t put the lens in her eye because the company had not yet completed the prototype’s safety testing. Still, she saw enough to confirm that Mojo Vision’s engineers had pulled off a few exciting advances. Among them were a 14,000-pixel-per-inch monochrome microLED display, eye tracking using an accelerometer, a gyroscope, and a magnetometer, and onboard power using medical-grade microbatteries. By June, the team was confident that it had hurdled any remaining safety concerns—so much so that Mojo Vision CEO Drew Perkins [shown here] put a pair of Mojo’s high-tech lenses to the test in his own eyes.
</p><p class="caption">
	MOJO VISION
</p><h3></h3><br/><img alt="Image of a cochlear implant that uses pulses of electricity to hear" class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="a12a646e82fd7b7481a3edc1eacd50e7" data-rm-shortcode-name="rebelmouse-image" id="31736" loading="lazy" src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/image-of-a-cochlear-implant-that-uses-pulses-of-electricity-to-hear.jpg?id=30978772&width=980"/><h3>
<a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/cochlear-implant" target="_blank">Hearing With Light</a>
</h3><p>
	The cochlear implant is an impressive feat of engineering. Figuring out how to use pulses of electric current to stimulate the cochlear nerve that feeds auditory information to the brain was a big achievement. But according to users, the implants still leave quite a bit to be desired. That’s why a group of researchers from institutions across Europe have been trying to give the implants a whole new ring. Instead of manipulating electrons to stimulate the cochlear nerve, they’ve invented a new version that does it with photons. The beams of light can be controlled with a level of specificity that helps solve cochlear implant wearers’ major complaints, including voices that sound flat and robotic, stripped of the subtle inflections that help communicate things like sarcasm. The implant captures some of the dynamics of music that had been lost in transmission. And it promises to solve the cocktail-party problem—where  background noise, including other conversations, overwhelms the signal representing a speaker’s voice.
</p><p class="caption">
	Lakshay Khurana and Daniel Keppeler 
</p><h3></h3><br/><img alt="Image of a battery and wires connected to the battery in the snow" class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="dddcc0e1df4a7401788ab8cabeac6d5b" data-rm-shortcode-name="rebelmouse-image" id="01880" loading="lazy" src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/image-of-a-battery-and-wires-connected-to-the-battery-in-the-snow.jpg?id=30979058&width=980"/><h3>
<a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/too-hot-too-cold-not-for-these-lithium-batteries" target="_blank">Weather-beating Battery</a>
</h3><p>
	Even before the introduction of the General Motors EV1 in 1996, it was clear that if we’re ever going to replace cars powered by fossil fuels with electric vehicles, we’ll need batteries that take and deliver charge reliably in both hot and cold climates. For EV propulsion, we’ve come a long way since the lead-acid chemistry still used to power electric starters and cabin electronics. Now a team of researchers at the University of California, San Diego, says it has hit upon a new electrolyte chemistry for lithium batteries that doesn’t freeze at temperatures down to  –100 °C. And because the dibutyl ether solvent in the new electrolyte binds weakly with the lithium ions in solution, those ions are free to move easily and create a strong current, even on the most frigid of winter mornings. What’s more, the dibutyl ether resists evaporation and side reactions that would irreversibly decompose the electrolyte when the battery is exposed to high temperatures on hot summer days.
</p><p class="caption">
	David Baillot/UC San Diego Jacobs School of Engineering 
</p>]]></description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2022 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spectrum.ieee.org/restore-power</guid><category>Ar contact lens</category><category>Art deco</category><category>Battersea power station</category><category>Big picture</category><category>Cochlear implant</category><category>Cocktail party problem</category><category>Control room a</category><category>Electric vehicles</category><category>Lithium battery</category><category>Mojo vision</category><dc:creator>Willie Jones</dc:creator><media:content medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://assets.rbl.ms/31198373/origin.jpg"></media:content></item></channel></rss>