<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0"><channel><description>Official Plotly Tumblr Blog</description><title>Plotly Blog</title><generator>Tumblr (3.0; @plotlyblog)</generator><link>https://blog.plotly.com/</link><item><title>How to Create Interactive Climate Model Maps in Python</title><description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;El Niño is likely this winter,&amp;rdquo; the forecaster said. &amp;ldquo;El Niño typically brings above normal winter cloudiness and rainfall across the southern U.S. and milder conditions to Canada…&amp;rdquo;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
You may have heard something like this spoken on your TV, radio, or written on the internet recently. Have you ever wondered how a meteorologist or climatologist comes to such conclusions?
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
In this post, we&amp;rsquo;ll show you how to create interactive climate maps using the &lt;a href="https://climate.copernicus.eu/climate-data-store" target="_blank"&gt;Copernicus Data Store&lt;/a&gt;, where you can visualize, examine, and explore the same data that your local forecaster sees.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Copernicus is a game-changing project that &amp;ldquo;makes information about the past, present, and future climate freely available, and functions as a one-stop shop for users to explore climate data.&amp;rdquo; Access to data is open, free and unrestricted.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;!-- more --&gt;
&lt;figure class="tmblr-full" data-orig-height="1496" data-orig-width="3508" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/a155NQa.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://64.media.tumblr.com/a42c506b4fcaafba4fff222b55585806/tumblr_inline_pmsz9rRNoy1srua81_540.png" data-orig-height="1496" data-orig-width="3508" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/a155NQa.png"/&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
We have entered a golden age of freely available weather and climate data on the web - spanning time horizons from the next few hours or days and even into the coming weeks or months. NOAA&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href="https://nomads.ncep.noaa.gov/" target="_blank"&gt;NCEP NOMADS&lt;/a&gt; is a treasure trove of such information and now ECMWF&amp;rsquo;s [&lt;a href="https://www.ecmwf.int/" target="_blank"&gt;European Centre for Medium Range Weather Forecasts&lt;/a&gt;] &lt;a href="https://climate.copernicus.eu/climate-data-store" target="_blank"&gt;Copernicus Climate Data Store&lt;/a&gt; has burst onto the scene.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Before we start mapping, let&amp;rsquo;s get set up with Copernicus. We&amp;rsquo;ll use their API to get the climate data for our visualizations.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;Getting started is easy:&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
1. Make an account &lt;a href="https://climate.copernicus.eu/climate-data-store" target="_blank"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;br/&gt;
2. Navigate to the &amp;rsquo;&lt;a href="https://cds.climate.copernicus.eu/cdsapp#!/search?type=dataset" target="_blank"&gt;data store&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo; portion of the site.
&lt;br/&gt;
3. In this post, &amp;lsquo;seasonal forecast&amp;rsquo; datasets will be considered (access &lt;a href="https://cds.climate.copernicus.eu/cdsapp#!/search?type=dataset&amp;amp;keywords=((%20%22Product%20type:%20Seasonal%20forecasts%22%20))" target="_blank"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;).
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
For further weather and climate map inspiration, check out our post &amp;rsquo;&lt;a href="https://medium.com/@plotlygraphs/how-to-create-2d-and-3d-interactive-weather-maps-in-python-and-r-77ddd53cca8" target="_blank"&gt;How to Create 2D and 3D Interactive Weather Maps in Python and R&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;1. Download your first dataset&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
In the climate forecasting space, &lt;i&gt;anomalies&lt;/i&gt; (difference from average) are often the most frequently examined data. While looking at raw outputs can be useful in some circumstances, understanding how much warmer, cooler, drier, or wetter than normal an area may be is the end goal. For the purposes of this post, we&amp;rsquo;ll be looking at forecast &lt;i&gt;anomalies&lt;/i&gt;.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
In order to download the data in NetCDF format (the file type you&amp;rsquo;ll need to work with the climate data in Plotly, you will have to install the &lt;a href="https://cds.climate.copernicus.eu/api-how-to" target="_blank"&gt;Climate Data Store Application Program Interface&lt;/a&gt; (CDS API). For Python users, this step should be pretty straightforward:
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
1. Install the CDS API key and store it in your home directory.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;figure class="tmblr-full" data-orig-height="192" data-orig-width="935" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/tmEYvlh.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://64.media.tumblr.com/e8ced322b79e4324f35ac72d9e89f2c5/tumblr_inline_pmsz9r1GIj1srua81_540.png" data-orig-height="192" data-orig-width="935" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/tmEYvlh.png"/&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
2. Install the CDS API client &amp;ldquo;pip install cdsapi.&amp;rdquo;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;figure class="tmblr-full" data-orig-height="173" data-orig-width="934" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/3aweK2H.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://64.media.tumblr.com/7cb8fffae516c9280a1838215199c78d/tumblr_inline_pmsz9r5Ri51srua81_540.png" data-orig-height="173" data-orig-width="934" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/3aweK2H.png"/&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Now let&amp;rsquo;s download some data 👌
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
We&amp;rsquo;ll start off with a sea surface temperature dataset from the &lt;a href="https://www.ecmwf.int/" target="_blank"&gt;ECMWF model&lt;/a&gt;, often considered the gold standard when it comes to weather and climate prediction. Follow &lt;a href="https://cds.climate.copernicus.eu/cdsapp#!/dataset/seasonal-postprocessed-single-levels?tab=overview" target="_blank"&gt;this link&lt;/a&gt; to the data and navigate to the &amp;ldquo;Download Data&amp;rdquo; tab in the page.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Under the &amp;ldquo;Download Data&amp;rdquo; tab, you&amp;rsquo;ll find a form where you can specify the data you&amp;rsquo;d like to download through the API. Selections in this form will create an API request for the desired data. To view this request, fill out the form and click the red &amp;ldquo;Show API request&amp;rdquo; button at the bottom-left beneath the form.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Fill out your form like this:
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;figure class="tmblr-full" data-orig-height="797" data-orig-width="1033" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/jeH7YUx.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://64.media.tumblr.com/21fd0e4deed6b7d3f840bef07970ba3e/tumblr_inline_pmsz9sviX11srua81_540.png" data-orig-height="797" data-orig-width="1033" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/jeH7YUx.png"/&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;figure class="tmblr-full" data-orig-height="663" data-orig-width="1029" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/aMxu6XI.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://64.media.tumblr.com/4b68f0f39ccb59bbf6548007a622fd88/tumblr_inline_pmsz9s12KF1srua81_540.png" data-orig-height="663" data-orig-width="1029" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/aMxu6XI.png"/&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;figure class="tmblr-full" data-orig-height="702" data-orig-width="1047" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/v968hIA.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://64.media.tumblr.com/52b569ea191354a7036184afa99b29f2/tumblr_inline_pmsz9tw7N11srua81_540.png" data-orig-height="702" data-orig-width="1047" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/v968hIA.png"/&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Then, click the &amp;ldquo;Show API request&amp;rdquo; to reveal your request. (&amp;ldquo;Hide API request&amp;rdquo; tucks it away again.)
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Next, copy the API request and paste it into a Jupyter notebook. Remember when we mentioned that it needs to be in NetCDF format? This is where we&amp;rsquo;ll take change the requested file format from &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/GRIB" target="_blank"&gt;GRIB&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/NetCDF" target="_blank"&gt;NetCDF&lt;/a&gt;:
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;figure class="tmblr-full" data-orig-height="374" data-orig-width="823" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/V32wH7C.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://64.media.tumblr.com/cddc99e7f2524c1b04634f170e035c7f/tumblr_inline_pmsz9tQu7V1srua81_540.png" data-orig-height="374" data-orig-width="823" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/V32wH7C.png"/&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Click &lt;a href="https://plot.ly/~Dreamshot/9351/import-xarray-as-xr-import-plotlyplotly/#/" target="_blank"&gt;HERE&lt;/a&gt; for an example Jupyter Notebook to download and process the climate data.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;2. Your first plot: Sea Surface Temperature Anomaly&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Now you should have your dataset in your home directory! Next, we leverage the power of Python with Plotly to view and inspect climate data in a new, interactive format that enables you to zoom to low levels for greater detail.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Gone are the days of worrying about whether data for your country will show, in this case we&amp;rsquo;ll produce a world map with data that covers the Earth 👌 🗺
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
The first plot shows sea surface temperature anomalies, or a difference from the average sea surface temperature at a given location (or grid box).
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Sea surface temperature anomalies are particularly important in the tropical oceans, as anomalies help to modify the &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Walker_circulation" target="_blank"&gt;Walker Circulation&lt;/a&gt;, whose behavior play a major role in precipitation (and temperature) patterns across the global tropics (and to a lesser extent the middle latitudes).
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Early in 2019, we have an El Niño signature in the tropical Pacific Ocean. The warmest sea surface temperatures (and anomalies) are located across the west-central equatorial Pacific, which has been an area of consistent atmospheric lift, increased cloud cover, and precipitation.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
You can download the Jupyter Notebook &lt;a href="https://plot.ly/~Dreamshot/9351/import-xarray-as-xr-import-plotlyplotly/#/" target="_blank"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and use it to make all the plots below.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe width="640" height="500" frameborder="0" seamless="seamless" scrolling="no" src="https://plot.ly/~Dreamshot/9345.embed?width=640&amp;amp;height=500"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;3. Air Temperature Anomaly&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
This plot looks at the forecast temperature anomaly, in Celsius, for the month of March 2019. The model data again comes from the ECMWF, although the Copernicus data store hosts four additional models from institutions across Europe: UK Met Office (UKMO), Météo France, Deutscher Wetterdienst (DWD), and Centro Euro-Mediterraneo sui Cambiamenti Climatici (CMCC).
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Red colors show warmer-than-average temperatures while blue indicates below-average temperatures.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe width="640" height="500" frameborder="0" seamless="seamless" scrolling="no" src="https://plot.ly/~Dreamshot/9349.embed?width=640&amp;amp;height=500"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;4. Precipitation Anomaly&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
This plot examines precipitation rate anomaly in mm/second for the month of March 2019.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Precipitation is often considered one of the most challenging parameters to forecast. Generally speaking, precipitation outlooks have lower confidence than temperature outlooks.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
This is because precipitation (rain, snow) can be irregular in coverage and intensity. There may be sharp differences in amounts over short distances, depending on the lay of the land (e.g. more in the mountain ranges, less in the valleys). Compared to temperature, it is generally much less uniform and therefore a more frequent forecast challenge.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
In the chart below, negative values (blues) indicate below-normal monthly precipitation while positive values (yellows, oranges) indicate above-normal monthly precipitation.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe width="640" height="500" frameborder="0" seamless="seamless" scrolling="no" src="https://plot.ly/~Dreamshot/9347.embed?width=640&amp;amp;height=500"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
So, with this wealth of climate data at your fingertips, get graphing with Plotly and start exploring your world in a new way!</description><link>https://blog.plotly.com/post/182754641327</link><guid>https://blog.plotly.com/post/182754641327</guid><pubDate>Tue, 12 Feb 2019 02:53:19 -0500</pubDate><category>weather</category><category>climate</category><category>ecmwf</category><category>python</category><category>plotly</category><category>data science</category><category>big data</category></item><item><title>I Spy with my Graphing Eye 📊 👁️</title><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&amp;ldquo;No one is dumb who is curious. The people who don&amp;rsquo;t ask questions remain clueless throughout their lives.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
-Neil deGrasse Tyson
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;figure class="tmblr-full" data-orig-height="423" data-orig-width="750" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/CKM6fqP.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://64.media.tumblr.com/45b72bbd944d64a552149fa53344f4ac/tumblr_inline_pjmculmRzm1srua81_540.png" data-orig-height="423" data-orig-width="750" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/CKM6fqP.png"/&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.insightsintoimpact.com/evaluative-thinking-the-heart-of-meaningful-useful-evaluation/thinking-and-awareness/" target="_blank"&gt;Image Source&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Nowadays, plots, graphs, stats, and facts are everywhere - as you scroll through your Twitter feed, down your Facebook wall, and in the news article you are reading.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Being able to &lt;b&gt;read&lt;/b&gt;, &lt;b&gt;interpret&lt;/b&gt;, and &lt;b&gt;question&lt;/b&gt; these diagrams is a key 21st century skill that is easy to overlook in our fast-paced digital world.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;!-- more --&gt;
Recently, the New York Times partnered with the American Statistical Association for a new monthly feature, &amp;ldquo;What&amp;rsquo;s Going On in This Graph?&amp;rdquo; (WGOITG)
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Once a month, The Times publishes a graph, map, or chart that is stripped of some key information. Students are invited to visit the site and and discuss what they see, answering these three questions from a mathematical standpoint:
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
1.What do you notice?
&lt;br/&gt;
2. What do you wonder?
&lt;br/&gt;
3. What&amp;rsquo;s going on in this graph?
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;i&gt;The process of sense-making truly begins when we create questioning, curious classrooms full of students&amp;rsquo; own thoughts and ideas. By asking: &lt;b&gt;What do you notice? What do you wonder?&lt;/b&gt; we give students opportunities to see problems in big-picture ways and discover multiple strategies for tackling a problem.&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
We&amp;rsquo;re big fans of WGOITG, so we decided to try it ourselves - with the Plotly team.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Designers, engineers, and data scientists chimed in on their thoughts about the three original charts below.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
As you read through the post, challenge yourself to answer the three questions listed above.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
For more thought-provoking plots, check out the &lt;a href="https://plot.ly/feed/" target="_blank"&gt;Plotly feed&lt;/a&gt; or our recent blog post on &lt;a href="https://medium.com/@plotlygraphs/leading-the-charge-10-charts-on-electric-vehicles-in-plotly-d951acdc49c1" target="_blank"&gt;going electric&lt;/a&gt; ⚡
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;1. College majors, post-graduate employment, and earnings&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;iframe width="1200" height="600" frameborder="0" scrolling="no" src="//plot.ly/~Dreamshot/9342.embed"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;i&gt;&amp;ldquo;I notice a strong correlation. It looks like the total number of graduates/popularity of a major is strongly correlated with employment rate and not the median annual salary. I wonder how the shaded area (most/least popular majors) was determined. Is it sized to represent the data?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
-Chelsea D.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;i&gt;&amp;ldquo;I wonder about what we can infer about supply and demand for these jobs based on the color. Hard to tease apart: are blue jobs overpaid due to lack of supply? Or are red ones underpaid due to oversupply? School student counseling is at the low end of both, so the low pay is likely not due to oversupply.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
-Nicolas K.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;i&gt;&amp;ldquo;I notice that the line is fairly straight, which means that all of the majors have a roughly proportionate amount of graduates who are employed. I wonder why there aren&amp;rsquo;t more green and blue (higher incomes, I think?) for popular majors.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
-Shammamah H.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;2. Labor-Force Participation Rate&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;iframe width="900" height="800" frameborder="0" scrolling="no" src="//plot.ly/~Dreamshot/9324.embed"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;i&gt;&amp;ldquo; I wonder why Germany is gaining ground so fast? And why is the U.S. losing ground? And who else is in the OECD that&amp;rsquo;s dragging down the average? Are we seeing only the OECD countries above the average at the end of the period? How are the other countries doing?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
-Nicolas K.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;i&gt;&amp;ldquo;I notice that Germany experienced two dramatic increases in labour force participation over short periods of time. I wonder why in Japan and Germany, labour force participation increased during the Great Recession while in all the other countries, participation was generally declining.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
-Ashley P.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;3. Sea Surface Temperature Anomaly&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;iframe width="900" height="800" frameborder="0" scrolling="no" src="//plot.ly/~Dreamshot/9335.embed"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;i&gt;&amp;ldquo;I notice this chart doesn&amp;rsquo;t have an indicator of time. The meaning it communicates will be vastly different if these changes in sea surface temperature have happened over a day, a year, or several years. I wonder how variable these temperatures are generally. Do they ever rise or fall by more than three degrees?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
-Ashley P.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;i&gt;&amp;ldquo;I notice that the lines at the top become more rare. I wonder if the projection that was chosen is not optimal.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
-Dmitry S.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;i&gt;&amp;ldquo;I wonder when the data were collected, and what the graph might look like around hurricane season. I notice that the Pacific ocean tends to have warmer water than the Atlantic.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
-Shammamah H.</description><link>https://blog.plotly.com/post/181043057242</link><guid>https://blog.plotly.com/post/181043057242</guid><pubDate>Wed, 12 Dec 2018 05:09:19 -0500</pubDate><category>datascience</category><category>datavisualization</category><category>data</category><category>python</category></item><item><title>Leading the Charge 🔌 🚘: 10 Charts on Electric Vehicles in Plotly</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Nissan, Tesla, BMW, and many other car companies use Dash or are customers of &lt;a href="https://dash.plot.ly/dash-deployment-server" target="_blank"&gt;Dash Deployment Server&lt;/a&gt; (DDS). To see what Dash is all about, check out Plotly&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href="https://dash.plot.ly/gallery" target="_blank"&gt;Dash Gallery&lt;/a&gt;, or check out our recent post on &lt;a href="https://medium.com/@plotlygraphs/7-of-the-dash-communitys-latest-creations-ed4f53e0b1fa" target="_blank"&gt;Dash apps&lt;/a&gt;. Interested? &lt;a href="https://plotly.typeform.com/to/rkO85m" target="_blank"&gt;Get in touch&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
This post is the first in a two-part series. We&amp;rsquo;ll share some fresh visualizations on the world of electric cars: who&amp;rsquo;s leading the way, the costs of going electric, which manufacturers are most represented out on the road, and more.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
🚗 🚗 🚗
&lt;!-- more --&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;1. Who drives the most?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Following the low-population Republic of San Marino on the Italian Peninsula, the United States has the dubious distinction of having the most motor vehicles per 1,000 people. The number sits at 910.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Of countries with more than a million inhabitants, New Zealand is next on the list. This country in the southwest Pacific, whose tagline is &amp;ldquo;clean and green,&amp;rdquo; has 774 cars per 1,000 folks. Italy (679), Canada (662), and Finland (612) follow closely.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
On the other side of the spectrum, West African Togo (2), Bangladesh (3), Liberia (3), and the Solomon Islands (3) have the fewest cars per 1,000 individuals.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;figure class="tmblr-full" data-orig-height="800" data-orig-width="1200" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/kBVQLuE.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://64.media.tumblr.com/3e85b691a5b5f75ad1149185e31f8018/tumblr_inline_pgbu2rJyPy1srua81_540.png" data-orig-height="800" data-orig-width="1200" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/kBVQLuE.png"/&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_countries_by_vehicles_per_capita" target="_blank"&gt;Data Source&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;2. Which country boasts the largest proportion of electric vehicles?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Norway. Nearly 40 percent of total new car sales between 2013–2017 were electric, meaning this Scandinavian nation has the most plug-in electric vehicles (EV) per capita in the world.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
In fact, Oslo, Norway, is recognized as the EV capital of the world.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
What&amp;rsquo;s the secret? Ninety-eight percent of Norway&amp;rsquo;s electricity comes by way of hydropower, making the country&amp;rsquo;s fleet of electric cars one of the cleanest on the globe. All electric cars and vans in Norway are exempt from on-purchase  taxes.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
In second place is Iceland at 14 percent electric, and in third place, Andorra at 5.6 percent. Although the United States has the most motor vehicles per 1,000 people, only 1.1 percent of them are electric.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;figure class="tmblr-full" data-orig-height="600" data-orig-width="1000" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/Xi73Tc2.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://64.media.tumblr.com/a4e69bddc181ea97969474648d211edc/tumblr_inline_pgbu2rxfV81srua81_540.png" data-orig-height="600" data-orig-width="1000" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/Xi73Tc2.png"/&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Electric_car_use_by_country" target="_blank"&gt;Data Source&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;3. Which U.S. states are winning the EV race? 🏎️&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
California, Hawaii, Washington, Oregon, Vermont, and Georgia - in that order. Those states are the ones with more than two EVs registered per 1,000 people.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
On the flip side of the coin, Mississippi is dead last with one EV for every 6,667 people. Arkansas, West Virginia, and Louisiana aren&amp;rsquo;t far behind.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
EV registrations within a state are influenced by a variety of factors, including state and local incentive programs, charging infrastructure, and fuel pricing.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;figure class="tmblr-full" data-orig-height="800" data-orig-width="1200" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/WKi5JRC.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://64.media.tumblr.com/b916b1a8bf3d89ee2d3292052ee6e69f/tumblr_inline_pgbu2s19vi1srua81_540.png" data-orig-height="800" data-orig-width="1200" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/WKi5JRC.png"/&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.energy.gov/eere/vehicles/articles/fotw-1004-november-20-2017-california-had-highest-concentration-plug-vehicles" target="_blank"&gt;Data Source&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;4. Who&amp;rsquo;s who in the EV biz?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Perhaps it doesn&amp;rsquo;t come as a surprise, but over 90 percent of Tesla&amp;rsquo;s manufactured vehicles are electric. This number dwarfs the second place company, China&amp;rsquo;s Zhidou (31 percent), and third place BYD Auto (12 percent) also of China.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Other notable electric producers include BMW (0.7 percent), Nissan (0.6 percent), and General Motors (0.3 percent).
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;figure class="tmblr-full" data-orig-height="1000" data-orig-width="800" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/cF21ztr.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://64.media.tumblr.com/ee9c0bb64229e6d5e75e44c469da02fc/tumblr_inline_pgbu2tWuGb1srua81_540.png" data-orig-height="1000" data-orig-width="800" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/cF21ztr.png"/&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://qz.com/1102552/ladies-and-gentlemen-the-winners-and-losers-of-the-electric-car-race-so-far/" target="_blank"&gt;Data Source&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;5. Tesla&amp;rsquo;s slide in European markets&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Tesla&amp;rsquo;s sales fell in several European countries in early 2018.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;figure class="tmblr-full" data-orig-height="800" data-orig-width="850" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/afTJpnY.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://64.media.tumblr.com/523a1613f5be21ccdab1a40cde475032/tumblr_inline_pgbu2t0rYN1srua81_540.png" data-orig-height="800" data-orig-width="850" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/afTJpnY.png"/&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2018-08-11/jaguar-i-pace-and-other-rivals-a-headache-for-tesla-s-elon-musk" target="_blank"&gt;Data Source&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
A blend of stiffer competition, like Porsche&amp;rsquo;s all-electric Taycan (pictured below), and a lack of significant rebates, contributed to the downturn.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;figure class="tmblr-full" data-orig-height="1333" data-orig-width="2000" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/eJDsY8y.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://64.media.tumblr.com/54ad7681cff9686820096f2c9e6080ce/tumblr_inline_pgbu2u0C3G1srua81_540.jpg" data-orig-height="1333" data-orig-width="2000" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/eJDsY8y.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;i&gt;Porsche&amp;rsquo;s all-electric Taycan, the first battery-powered car from the iconic German sports car maker.&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Jaguar is also delivering its new and (relatively) affordable I-Pace, an all-electric sport-utility vehicle, seen as direct competition to Tesla.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&amp;ldquo;The data from both IHS and regional transportation departments is not reflective of actual sales data,&amp;rdquo; Tesla countered (&lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2018-08-11/jaguar-i-pace-and-other-rivals-a-headache-for-tesla-s-elon-musk" target="_blank"&gt;Behrmann and Kehnscherper, Bloomberg, 2018&lt;/a&gt;).
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;6. What does it cost to charge an EV? 💰&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Average retail electricity prices have gradually ticked upward over the past several decades. During 2017, the average price for one kilowatt hour of electricity was about 11 cents - although there is significant regional variability and it even changes depending on the time of day.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Every EV has a kWh/100 mile figure. Take the Nissan Leaf for instance: 29. Simple math tells us that it would cost $3.19 to travel 100 miles (29*11).
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
However, the cost of electricity is based on the rates set by utility companies, and the more you use, the more you pay, typically. Therefore, you might find yourself paying much more than the national average to charge your EV.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
You&amp;rsquo;d be better off juicing up the battery at the mall during your lunch break!
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;figure class="tmblr-full" data-orig-height="600" data-orig-width="1000" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/cIDh0LO.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://64.media.tumblr.com/97f64d95e1e4475da999fb32bdfc9fe1/tumblr_inline_pgbu2uipEy1srua81_540.png" data-orig-height="600" data-orig-width="1000" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/cIDh0LO.png"/&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.statista.com/statistics/183700/us-average-retail-electricity-price-since-1990/" target="_blank"&gt;Data Source&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;7. EV batteries have become much less expensive&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Despite how pricey it is to charge them, lithium-ion batteries used in EVs have been dramatically cheaper. From 2009 to 2017, the average price had decreased from $1000 kWh to $209 kWh. For EVs to become cost-competitive with internal combustion engine vehicles, the price needs to reach approximately $100 kWh, which isn&amp;rsquo;t far off.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;figure class="tmblr-full" data-orig-height="750" data-orig-width="1000" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/zZyaL1D.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://64.media.tumblr.com/cf649d50775c542b7bfd0d67aecfbda0/tumblr_inline_pgbu2ukjq31srua81_540.png" data-orig-height="750" data-orig-width="1000" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/zZyaL1D.png"/&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.ben-evans.com/benedictevans/2018/8/29/tesla-software-and-disruption" target="_blank"&gt;Data Source&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;8. China is the lithium ion battery powerhouse&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
The Tesla Gigafactory 1, based in Sparks, Nevada, USA, will not only be the world&amp;rsquo;s biggest lithium ion battery plant when construction finishes &amp;ndash; but possibly the &lt;a href="https://www.tesla.com/en_NZ/Gigafactory" target="_blank"&gt;biggest building in the world&lt;/a&gt;, full stop.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;figure class="tmblr-full" data-orig-height="675" data-orig-width="1440" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/eirCR9f.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://64.media.tumblr.com/5a3edb75332d1c67d33663b8db5cbf6a/tumblr_inline_pgbu2u1if11srua81_540.jpg" data-orig-height="675" data-orig-width="1440" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/eirCR9f.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Tesla&amp;rsquo;s Gigafactory 1, Sparks, Nevada, USA [&lt;a href="https://www.tesla.com/en_NZ/Gigafactory" target="_blank"&gt;image source&lt;/a&gt;]
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Despite that impressive feat, China is still expected to dominate EV battery production over the next decade.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;figure class="tmblr-full" data-orig-height="500" data-orig-width="700" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/hNxFNvl.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://64.media.tumblr.com/fff5a43df6a4427bfc56ecff4f3b9d1b/tumblr_inline_pgbu2wbyl61srua81_540.png" data-orig-height="500" data-orig-width="700" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/hNxFNvl.png"/&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.benchmarkminerals.com/teslas-gigafactory-to-be-worlds-biggest-battery-plant-but-china-will-dominate-electric-vehicle-lithium-ion-production-for-next-decade/" target="_blank"&gt;Data Source&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;9. and 10. Which countries offer the most charging ports?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
During 2017, France was the king of EV charge points 🥇
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
A whopping 11,987 additional charge points were installed in the country, which was 4,050 more than Germany, which came in second.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
The remainder of the top 10 included many European countries: U.K., Switzerland, Austria, Norway, Italy, Belgium, and Sweden, in that order.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Canada  followed in 10th place with 1,070 charge points installed during 2017.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
By 2020, The City of Montreal, where Plotly is based, will have &lt;a href="https://montrealgazette.com/news/local-news/montreals-electric-car-sharing-project-will-favour-several-players" target="_blank"&gt;a network of 1,000 charging stations&lt;/a&gt; of its own, with a price tag of $10 million. In our next post, we&amp;rsquo;ll explore how Montreal and the province of Quebec are promoting EV use.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;figure class="tmblr-full" data-orig-height="450" data-orig-width="700" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/9h8fdoZ.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://64.media.tumblr.com/52604985a1c1f1ea030104bac8697a53/tumblr_inline_pgbu2wuHx71srua81_540.png" data-orig-height="450" data-orig-width="700" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/9h8fdoZ.png"/&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://greenerideal.com/infographics/electric-car-charging-points/" target="_blank"&gt;Data Source&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Tesla&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Supercharger network&amp;rdquo;  accounts for 1,317 chargers globally. This particular charger gives the Tesla Model S 170 miles of range in just 30 minutes and a full charge in 75 minutes.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;figure class="tmblr-full" data-orig-height="500" data-orig-width="700" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/CicrgeB.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://64.media.tumblr.com/12cab0b5b911a2bce73c4e3e89a624e8/tumblr_inline_pgbu2xyGPH1srua81_540.png" data-orig-height="500" data-orig-width="700" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/CicrgeB.png"/&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;figure class="tmblr-full" data-orig-height="2117" data-orig-width="2822" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/X5dteLo.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://64.media.tumblr.com/d4d22206c806708b10f27f9069394e3b/tumblr_inline_pgbu2xDe6T1srua81_540.jpg" data-orig-height="2117" data-orig-width="2822" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/X5dteLo.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;i&gt;Tesla vehicle charging station, Mt Ruapehu, New Zealand&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
In our next post, we&amp;rsquo;ll look at how Plotly&amp;rsquo;s home base of Quebec, Canada, is trying to make it easier for drivers to go electric ⚡️</description><link>https://blog.plotly.com/post/178882545787</link><guid>https://blog.plotly.com/post/178882545787</guid><pubDate>Tue, 09 Oct 2018 06:20:32 -0400</pubDate><category>electric vehicles</category><category>climate change</category><category>renewable energy</category><category>data</category><category>data science</category><category>data analytics</category></item><item><title>Streamtubes in Plotly with Python</title><description>&lt;p&gt;🌟 Before we introduce this seriously cool visualization, we’d like to announce that plotly.py has surpassed 5 million downloads! Thank you for helping us reach this milestone! 🙌
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Once Upon a Time 🕰
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
It was the year 2008. If you wanted to create 3-D plots for interactive scientific data visualization, the Mayavi Python library was your go-to.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
The charts may have looked slick for their time, but it doesn&amp;rsquo;t take a rocket scientist to tell you that we&amp;rsquo;ve come a long way.
See for yourself:
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Mayavi Streamtube Example, circa 2008&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;figure class="tmblr-full" data-orig-height="696" data-orig-width="928" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/MDPKZOL.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://64.media.tumblr.com/7e882d5d079504fec2055b97a053517f/tumblr_inline_pf4dawQWT01srua81_540.png" data-orig-height="696" data-orig-width="928" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/MDPKZOL.png"/&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Plotly Streamtube Example, 2018&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;figure class="tmblr-full" data-orig-height="622" data-orig-width="1253" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/BgxJzkx.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://64.media.tumblr.com/4aac1fb53f7e8c43f1b23d57e98a17e4/tumblr_inline_pf4dawzpx11srua81_540.png" data-orig-height="622" data-orig-width="1253" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/BgxJzkx.png"/&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;!-- more --&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;So What&amp;rsquo;s a Streamtube?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
• A streamtube is a tubular region surrounded by streamlines that form a closed loop.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
• It&amp;rsquo;s a continuous version of a cone plot (3-D quiver plot).
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
• A streamtube is impermeable since the walls of the tube are made up of streamlines, and there can be no flow normal to a streamline.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
• Since streamlines don&amp;rsquo;t intersect, the same streamlines pass through a streamtube at all points along its length.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Streamtubes in Plotly ⤵️&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;a href="https://plot.ly/python/streamtube-plot/" target="_blank"&gt;https://plot.ly/python/streamtube-plot/&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
• In streamtube plots, attributes include &lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;y&lt;/i&gt;, and &lt;i&gt;z&lt;/i&gt;, which set the coordindates of the vector field, and &lt;i&gt;u&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;v&lt;/i&gt;, and &lt;i&gt;w&lt;/i&gt;, which sets the &lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;y&lt;/i&gt;, and &lt;i&gt;z&lt;/i&gt; components of the vector field.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
• You can use &lt;i&gt;starts&lt;/i&gt; to determine the streamtube&amp;rsquo;s starting position.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
• The maximum number of segments displayed can be determined by calling &lt;i&gt;maxdisplayed&lt;/i&gt; in your chart code.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;1. Basic Streamtube&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Our first example is a simple one. It satisfies the definition of a streamtube wholly: a tubular region surrounded by streamlines that form a closed loop.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
This particular tubular region is made up of 27 streamlines.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;figure class="tmblr-full" data-orig-height="594" data-orig-width="977" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/7szxr0N.gif"&gt;&lt;img src="https://64.media.tumblr.com/f3f3c65cc1a389bbaa8d97b151391042/tumblr_inline_pf4daxIBlg1srua81_540.gif" data-orig-height="594" data-orig-width="977" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/7szxr0N.gif"/&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://plot.ly/~Dreamshot/9281/import-plotly-plotly-version-/#/" target="_blank"&gt;Python code&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://plot.ly/r/streamtube-plot/" target="_blank"&gt;R code&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://plot.ly/~Dreamshot/9279/#/" target="_blank"&gt;Link to plot&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/plotly/datasets/master/streamtube-basic.csv" target="_blank"&gt;Link to data&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;2. Starting Position and Segments&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
This plot shows how you can display wind speed and direction as a streamtube. It uses two functions that are unique to this particular chart type: &lt;i&gt;starts&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;maxdisplayed&lt;/i&gt;, which are described above.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
When dealing with wind data, be sure to use a colorscale that highlights the peak values!
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;figure class="tmblr-full" data-orig-height="733" data-orig-width="1352" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/J3KZljc.gif"&gt;&lt;img src="https://64.media.tumblr.com/e82efc8a50d5b61d6b0b85f5b01032aa/tumblr_inline_pf4daxJcwz1srua81_540.gif" data-orig-height="733" data-orig-width="1352" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/J3KZljc.gif"/&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://plot.ly/~Dreamshot/9284/import-plotly-plotly-version-/#/" target="_blank"&gt;Python code&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://plot.ly/r/streamtube-plot/" target="_blank"&gt;R code&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://plot.ly/~Dreamshot/9282/#/" target="_blank"&gt;Link to plot&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/plotly/datasets/master/streamtube-wind.csv" target="_blank"&gt;Link to data&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Onto more complicated &lt;a href="https://plot.ly/~empet/14972/vector-field-visualization-with/#/" target="_blank"&gt;examples&lt;/a&gt; of streamtubes in Plotly…
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;3. Streamtubes Displaying the Arnold-Beltrami-Childress (ABC) Flow&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
• The &lt;a href="https://arxiv.org/ftp/arxiv/papers/1512/1512.04367.pdf" target="_blank"&gt;ABC flow&lt;/a&gt; is a three-parameter incompressible velocity field that provides an exact solution of Euler&amp;rsquo;s equation for inviscid Newtonian fluids in three dimensions.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
• Euler&amp;rsquo;s equation is a special case of the Navier-Stokes equation, which expresses Newton&amp;rsquo;s 2nd law of motion for fluid flow. Newton&amp;rsquo;s 2nd law of motion states that the sum of the forces acting on the volume of fluid V is equal to the rate of change of its momentum.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
• Inviscid flow is the flow of an inviscid fluid, in which the &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Viscosity" target="_blank"&gt;viscosity&lt;/a&gt;, or thickness, of the fluid is equal to zero.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
• It is the prototype for the study of turbulence, providing a simple example of dynamic chaos.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
• Why is that important? Chaotic behavior exists in many natural systems and is not limited to turbulence. Other examples include: weather and climate, road traffic, and biology.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
• By charting the chaotic behavior, we can gain better insights into it.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
• In Cartesian coordinates, it is represented as:
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;i&gt;x = A sin z + C cos y&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;i&gt;y = B sin x + A cos z&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;i&gt;z = C sin y + B cos x&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
The cone plot representation of the ABC-vector field defined on a volumetric region:
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;figure class="tmblr-full" data-orig-height="600" data-orig-width="650" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/SzawQqu.gif"&gt;&lt;img src="https://64.media.tumblr.com/4d36c10b6615fd10f967a94da7ec2aab/tumblr_inline_pf4daxazq21srua81_540.gif" data-orig-height="600" data-orig-width="650" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/SzawQqu.gif"/&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://plot.ly/~empet/14971/vector-field-visualization-wit/#/" target="_blank"&gt;Python code&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://plot.ly/~empet/14950/the-cone-plot-of-the-abc-flow/#/" target="_blank"&gt;Link to plot&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
The second example below shows streamtubes displaying the ABC-flow starting from a z-plane. The ABC-vectors have a fast change of the direction and magnitude in each slice perpendicular to one of the axes. In this case, we gain better insights into the flow structure, plotting the streamtubes that start from different volume slices.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
We think it looks like a cool haircut 💇
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;figure class="tmblr-full" data-orig-height="600" data-orig-width="650" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/NkvDEUJ.gif"&gt;&lt;img src="https://64.media.tumblr.com/f449dfd167c67ca5c3dff6eb25c4ddee/tumblr_inline_pf4dayH7bg1srua81_540.gif" data-orig-height="600" data-orig-width="650" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/NkvDEUJ.gif"/&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://plot.ly/~empet/14972/vector-field-visualization-with/#/" target="_blank"&gt;Python code&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://plot.ly/~empet/14961/streamtubes-in-the-abc-flow/#/" target="_blank"&gt;Link to plot&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Streamtubes of the ABC Flow: Flowing from X-Plane&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Here we illustrate streamtubes of the ABC flow that start from a plane perpendicular to the x-axis.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
The previous example showed streamtubes that are flowing from a plane perpendicular to the z-axis.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;figure class="tmblr-full" data-orig-height="600" data-orig-width="650" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/EjGmHlK.gif"&gt;&lt;img src="https://64.media.tumblr.com/1bdaad4e77d18262fcef0908000308cf/tumblr_inline_pf4dayw1w11srua81_540.gif" data-orig-height="600" data-orig-width="650" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/EjGmHlK.gif"/&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://plot.ly/~empet/14973/vector-field-visualization-with/#/" target="_blank"&gt;Python code&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://plot.ly/~empet/14954/streamtubes-in-the-abc-flow/#/" target="_blank"&gt;Link to plot&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Streamtubes of the ABC Flow: Flowing from Y-Plane&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
This plot shows streamtubes of the ABC flow that start from a plane perpendicular to the y-axis.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
The previous example showed streamtubes that are flowing from a plane perpendicular to the x-axis.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;figure class="tmblr-full" data-orig-height="600" data-orig-width="650" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/DShB2Oc.gif"&gt;&lt;img src="https://64.media.tumblr.com/314ed431e1fcc4fe06057bffeab309a4/tumblr_inline_pf4dayv16n1srua81_540.gif" data-orig-height="600" data-orig-width="650" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/DShB2Oc.gif"/&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://plot.ly/~empet/14974/vector-field-visualization-with/#/" target="_blank"&gt;Python code&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://plot.ly/~empet/14952/streamtubes-in-the-abc-flow/#/" target="_blank"&gt;Link to plot&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Although streamtubes represent a plot type that borders on the esoteric, some intriguing applications can be made with a bit of thought and creativity. For inspiration, check out the &lt;a href="https://plot.ly/feed/?q=streamtubes" target="_blank"&gt;Plotly feed&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Special thanks to &lt;a href="https://plot.ly/~empet#/" target="_blank"&gt;Emilia Petrisor&lt;/a&gt; for her ABC-flow plot contributions.</description><link>https://blog.plotly.com/post/178123311802</link><guid>https://blog.plotly.com/post/178123311802</guid><pubDate>Sat, 15 Sep 2018 18:44:40 -0400</pubDate><category>streamtube</category><category>plotly</category><category>python</category><category>r</category><category>science</category><category>math</category><category>data</category><category>data science</category></item><item><title>Cone Plots in Plotly with Python</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Cone plots (also known as 3-D quiver plots) represent vector fields defined in some region of the 3-D space.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
A vector field associates to each point of coordinates (x, y, z) a vector of components (u, v, w).
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
In this post, we&amp;rsquo;ll explore how &lt;a href="https://plot.ly/feed/#/" target="_blank"&gt;Plotly&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt; cone plots can be used to visualize atmospheric wind 💨, magnetic fields, a trajectory of the Rössler System, and tangent vector fields to a surface.
&lt;!-- more --&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;So what&amp;rsquo;s a 3-D vector?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
∙ A vector is a geometric object that has magnitude and direction.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
∙ A 3-D vector is useful in any physical space where both magnitude and direction matter.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
∙ In 3-D space, vectors are identified with triples of scalar components. In the case of the example image below: &lt;i&gt;a = (ax, ay, az)&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;figure class="tmblr-full" data-orig-height="1024" data-orig-width="1083" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/RaploxH.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://64.media.tumblr.com/7e97f1f790f2b75dc32fb3e77032d149/tumblr_inline_pbnbdq5Lst1srua81_540.png" data-orig-height="1024" data-orig-width="1083" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/RaploxH.png"/&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
The direction of the vector field at a point is illustrated by a geometric cone, colored according to the vector norm (magnitude) at that point.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Cone plots can be used in a variety of abstract ways: to model a vortex (such as a tornado), illustrate an explicitly defined vector field, chart a hyperboloid, plot a system of non-linear ordinary differential equations, and show winds at various atmospheric levels.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
For extra insights, check out our &lt;a href="https://plot.ly/python/3d-cone/" target="_blank"&gt;tutorial&lt;/a&gt; about making 3-D cone plots in Python with Plotly.
&lt;!-- more --&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Cone Plot Showing Atmospheric Wind&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
This plot uses an explicitly defined vector field. A vector field refers to an assignment of a vector to each point in a subset of space.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
In this plot, we visualize a collection of arrows that simply model the wind speed and direction at various levels of the atmosphere.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
3-D weather plots can be useful to research scientists to gain a better understanding of the atmospheric profile, such as during the prediction of severe weather events like tornadoes and hurricanes.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;figure class="tmblr-full" data-orig-height="1296" data-orig-width="1826" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/7We9Ado.gif"&gt;&lt;img src="https://64.media.tumblr.com/743313d366717b67138b47159cd28a15/tumblr_inline_pbnbdqIQPy1srua81_540.gif" data-orig-height="1296" data-orig-width="1826" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/7We9Ado.gif"/&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://plot.ly/~Dreamshot/9260/this-example-looks-at-hypothetical-wind/#/" target="_blank"&gt;Python code&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://plot.ly/~Dreamshot/9258/#/" target="_blank"&gt;Link to plot&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Speaking of tornado-like rotations, here is an example of a cone plot of a vortex. The size of the cones are driven by wind speed.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;figure class="tmblr-full" data-orig-height="750" data-orig-width="900" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/NoTTeYR.gif"&gt;&lt;img src="https://64.media.tumblr.com/2262e0b98cfc1d4ee723c07a3f7b49d4/tumblr_inline_pbnbdroU4C1srua81_540.gif" data-orig-height="750" data-orig-width="900" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/NoTTeYR.gif"/&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://plot.ly/~Dreamshot/9270/this-example-looks-at-a-vortex-represen/#/" target="_blank"&gt;Python code&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/plotly/datasets/master/vortex.csv" target="_blank"&gt;Data&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://plot.ly/~Dreamshot/9262/#/" target="_blank"&gt;Link to plot&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Cone Plot of a Magnetic Field&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
The Biot-Savart Law is an equation that describes the magnetic field created by a current-carrying wire.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
It was named after Jean-Baptiste Biot and Felix Savart in 1820 when the pair derived the mathematical expression for magnetic flux density.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
In this example, we leverage the law to create a hypothetical magnetic field created by an electric current moving through three circular loops.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;figure class="tmblr-full" data-orig-height="800" data-orig-width="900" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/oH0Z96h.gif"&gt;&lt;img src="https://64.media.tumblr.com/e03c7cffbb8d9c36dfe41c227e9b1dfe/tumblr_inline_pbnbds7kqa1srua81_540.gif" data-orig-height="800" data-orig-width="900" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/oH0Z96h.gif"/&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://plot.ly/~empet/14904/magnetic-field-created-by-electric-curr/#/" target="_blank"&gt;Python code&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://plot.ly/~empet/14888/magnetic-field-created-by-electric-current-through-three-circular-loops/#/" target="_blank"&gt;Link to plot&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Cone Plot Showing a Trajectory of the Rössler System&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
The Rössler system is a system of three ordinary differential equations, whose dynamics exhibits an attractor, &lt;a href="http://mathworld.wolfram.com/Attractor.html" target="_blank"&gt;or a set of states, invariant under the dynamics, towards which neighboring states in a given basin of attraction asymptotically approach in the course of dynamic evolution&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Originally studied by Otto Rössler, these differential equations &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/R%C3%B6ssler_attractor" target="_blank"&gt;define a continuous-time dynamical system that exhibits chaotic dynamics associated with the fractal properties of the attractor&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;rdquo;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
The equations have been found to be useful in modeling equilibrium in chemical reactions.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;figure class="tmblr-full" data-orig-height="750" data-orig-width="900" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/f55JSkC.gif"&gt;&lt;img src="https://64.media.tumblr.com/332bcce6b8f4711153f3760d469ba547/tumblr_inline_pbnbdtlHpg1srua81_540.gif" data-orig-height="750" data-orig-width="900" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/f55JSkC.gif"/&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://plot.ly/~Dreamshot/9266/this-example-looks-at-the-rossler-system/#/" target="_blank"&gt;Python code&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://plot.ly/~empet/14880/cone-plot-along-a-trajectory-within-the-rossler-attractor/" target="_blank"&gt;Link to plot&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Cone Plot of a Tangent Vector Field&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
In mathematics, a tangent vector is a vector that is tangent to (or just touches) a curve or surface at a given point.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Tangent vector fields are an &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href="https://graphics.stanford.edu/~mdfisher/vectorFieldDesign.html" target="_blank"&gt;essential ingredient in controlling appearance for applications ranging from anisotropic shading to texture synthesis and non-photorealistic rendering&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;rdquo;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Below, we examine the tangent vector field along the coordinate lines of a parameterized hyperboloid.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;figure class="tmblr-full" data-orig-height="650" data-orig-width="800" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/0fnduOe.gif"&gt;&lt;img src="https://64.media.tumblr.com/c8fe0403087fac4a449a5a2ba9d24df6/tumblr_inline_pbnbdtl9Qr1srua81_540.gif" data-orig-height="650" data-orig-width="800" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/0fnduOe.gif"/&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://plot.ly/~Dreamshot/9269/examine-the-tangent-vector-field-along-t/" target="_blank"&gt;Python code&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/plotly/datasets/master/vortex.csv" target="_blank"&gt;Data&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://plot.ly/~Dreamshot/9267/#/" target="_blank"&gt;Link to plot&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;

With &lt;a href="https://plot.ly/python/3d-cone/" target="_blank"&gt;3-D cone plots&lt;/a&gt; in Plotly, you can allow the user to visualize vector fields across a variety of disciplines: meteorology, engineering, mathematics, and more. Bring your vectors to life with cone plots in &lt;a href="https://plot.ly/feed/#/" target="_blank"&gt;Plotly&lt;/a&gt;!</description><link>https://blog.plotly.com/post/175740325442</link><guid>https://blog.plotly.com/post/175740325442</guid><pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2018 06:14:32 -0400</pubDate><category>coneplot</category><category>vortex</category><category>python</category><category>r</category><category>data</category><category>science</category><category>math</category><category>vector</category><category>3d</category><category>plotly</category><category>quiver</category><category>quiverplot</category></item><item><title>What is a SPLOM chart? Making scatterplot matrices in Python</title><description>&lt;p&gt;The scatterplot matrix, known acronymically as SPLOM, is a relatively uncommon graphical tool that uses multiple scatterplots to determine the correlation (if any) between a series of variables.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
These scatterplots are then organized into a matrix, making it easy to look at all the potential correlations in one place.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
SPLOMs, invented by &lt;a href="https://statistics.yale.edu/people/john-hartigan" target="_blank"&gt;John Hartigan&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;a href="http://people.inf.elte.hu/fekete/algoritmusok_msc/klaszterezes/John%20A.%20Hartigan-Clustering%20Algorithms-John%20Wiley%20&amp;amp;%20Sons%20(1975).pdf" target="_blank"&gt;1975&lt;/a&gt;, allow data aficionados to quickly realize any interesting correlations between parameters in the data set.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
In this post, we&amp;rsquo;ll go over how to make SPLOMs in Plotly with Python. For extra insights, check out our SPLOM tutorial in &lt;a href="https://plot.ly/python/splom/" target="_blank"&gt;Python&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://plot.ly/r/splom/" target="_blank"&gt;R&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;!-- more --&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Scatterplot Matrix for Diabetes Dataset&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
This &lt;a href="https://www.kaggle.com/uciml/pima-indians-diabetes-database" target="_blank"&gt;dataset&lt;/a&gt;, originally from the National Institute of Diabetes and Digestive and Kidney Diseases, can be used to attempt to predict whether or not a patient has diabetes based on diagnostic measurements.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
The dataset includes several medical predictor variables, such as glucose, blood pressure, and BMI.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
In this case, a SPLOM is a effective way of examining any correlations between the variables.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
• The existence of high blood pressure and high glucose is correlated well with diabetes.
&lt;br/&gt;
• BMI above 30 especially for those over the age of 40 appears to be an indicator for diabetes.
&lt;br/&gt;
• Have high glucose while being pregnant appears to typically be associated with diabetes.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;figure class="tmblr-full" data-orig-height="1000" data-orig-width="1000" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/asRJnUR.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://64.media.tumblr.com/6cf61ff5cd3b6412d1be0c426c290f49/tumblr_inline_p9y6fuxmKS1srua81_540.png" data-orig-height="1000" data-orig-width="1000" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/asRJnUR.png"/&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.kaggle.com/uciml/pima-indians-diabetes-database" target="_blank"&gt;Source&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/plotly/datasets/master/diabetes.csv" target="_blank"&gt;Data&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://plot.ly/~Dreamshot/9242/import-plotly-plotly-version-/" target="_blank"&gt;Python code&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Scatterplot Matrix for Heart Disease Dataset&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
This &lt;a href="http://archive.ics.uci.edu/ml/datasets/heart+disease" target="_blank"&gt;database&lt;/a&gt; contains 76 medical attributes where the goal is to identify the presence of heart disease in the patient.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Published experiments refer to a subset of the attributes, in which researchers concentrated on attempting to distinguish heart disease positive (values 1, 2, 3, 4) from heart disease negative (value 0) patients.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
The dataset was included in the University of &lt;a href="https://www.kaggle.com/c/heart-disease" target="_blank"&gt;Toronto Deep Health Hackathon&lt;/a&gt; in 2017.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
• Having a lower maximum heart rate and a higher cholesterol value seems to be a heart disease indicator.
&lt;br/&gt;
• A larger ST depression as determined by an electrocardiogram appears to be a good indicator of heart disease.
&lt;br/&gt;
• The finding of a reversible defect during a thallium stress test appears to be a reasonable indicator for heart disease, particularly in older patients and those with a higher resting blood pressure.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;figure class="tmblr-full" data-orig-height="1000" data-orig-width="1000" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/pFGfGzt.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://64.media.tumblr.com/33b59913694a91314bf7d8340d27f9c3/tumblr_inline_p9y6fwvT6L1srua81_540.png" data-orig-height="1000" data-orig-width="1000" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/pFGfGzt.png"/&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://archive.ics.uci.edu/ml/datasets/heart+disease" target="_blank"&gt;Source&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Dreamsh0t/SPLOM/master/heart_disease.csv" target="_blank"&gt;Data&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://plot.ly/~Dreamshot/9243/import-plotly-plotly-version-/" target="_blank"&gt;Python code&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Scatterplot Matrix for Predicting Rain&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Precipitation is typically considered to be the most impactful weather parameter.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
While sophisticated computer models are used to forecast rain (or the lack thereof) on a daily basis, a meteorologist might glean useful climatological information from a SPLOM.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
In this plot, we examine the relationship between various weather parameters in an attempt to understand when rainfall may be more likely.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;Blue&lt;/b&gt; dots indicate days on which &lt;b&gt;rain&lt;/b&gt; fell and &lt;b&gt;brown&lt;/b&gt; dots indicate days on which &lt;b&gt;no rain&lt;/b&gt; fell.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
The city used in this example is Auckland, New Zealand.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
• Lower amounts of sun hours and higher humidity are typical of days that have rain.
&lt;br/&gt;
• When the minimum temperature is 5.0ºC (41ºF) or lower, rain is unlikely.
&lt;br/&gt;
• When the maximum temperature is 23.0ºC (73ºF) or higher, rain is unlikely.
&lt;br/&gt;
• Two particular wind directions, in conjunction with higher wind speeds, are more associated with rain than others: 220–300º on the compass (southwest to northwest) and 010–070º (north to northeast).
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;figure class="tmblr-full" data-orig-height="1000" data-orig-width="1000" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/PelHGTa.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://64.media.tumblr.com/771db110a2ee98434629b06c827f00b1/tumblr_inline_p9y6fxmj751srua81_540.png" data-orig-height="1000" data-orig-width="1000" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/PelHGTa.png"/&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://cliflo.niwa.co.nz/" target="_blank"&gt;Source&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Dreamsh0t/SPLOM/master/SPLOM_weather.csv" target="_blank"&gt;Data&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://plot.ly/~Dreamshot/9248/import-plotly-plotly-version-/" target="_blank"&gt;Python code&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Scatterplot Matrix for Identifying Iris Flower Species&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Through the analysis of flower traits, a scatterplot matrix can help to distinguish between different Iris flower species.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
This &lt;a href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/plotly/datasets/master/iris-data.csv" target="_blank"&gt;dataset&lt;/a&gt; examines sepal length, sepal width, petal length, and petal width and then classifies the species.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Light blue indicates Iris setosa, pink Iris versicolor, and purple Iris virginica.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
• Iris setosa has a large sepal width but small petal width.
&lt;br/&gt;
• Iris virginica has a large sepal length and petal length.
&lt;br/&gt;
• Iris versicolor sits between setosa and virginica much of the time.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;figure class="tmblr-full" data-orig-height="600" data-orig-width="600" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/G9fpEjw.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://64.media.tumblr.com/07fa39c28cf501759d2d8ea1ec88a84d/tumblr_inline_p9y6fy5Uz01srua81_540.png" data-orig-height="600" data-orig-width="600" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/G9fpEjw.png"/&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://archive.ics.uci.edu/ml/datasets/iris" target="_blank"&gt;Source&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/plotly/datasets/master/iris-data.csv" target="_blank"&gt;Data&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://plot.ly/~Dreamshot/9255/import-plotly-plotly-version-/" target="_blank"&gt;Python code&lt;/a&gt;</description><link>https://blog.plotly.com/post/174657459542</link><guid>https://blog.plotly.com/post/174657459542</guid><pubDate>Thu, 07 Jun 2018 05:56:50 -0400</pubDate><category>python</category><category>datascience</category><category>graph</category><category>plot</category><category>chart</category><category>r</category><category>splom</category><category>data analytics</category></item><item><title>What is a FIPS code? County-level charts in Python</title><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.nws.noaa.gov/mirs/public/prods/maps/cnty_fips_def.htm" target="_blank"&gt;FIPS codes&lt;/a&gt; are five-digit codes that are assigned to each U.S. county.The first two digits identify the state and the last three identify the county.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Think of it like a fancy version of a ZIP Code or postal code that distinguishes a county.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
FIPS codes are easier to utilize in data and information systems than state and county names. This makes datasets that come packaged with FIPS codes a portal into national, state, and county-level graphical and/or statistical analyses for a variety of topics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- more --&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;figure class="tmblr-full" data-orig-height="816" data-orig-width="1056" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/nlFZKjV.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://64.media.tumblr.com/93250351765002cf0242ecce81a9b440/tumblr_inline_p96edrQU8w1srua81_540.jpg" data-orig-height="816" data-orig-width="1056" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/nlFZKjV.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Curious about your FIPS code? Find out &lt;a href="https://www.nrcs.usda.gov/wps/portal/nrcs/detail/?cid=nrcs143_013697" target="_blank"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
In this post, we’ll investigate some data from the &lt;a href="http://www.healthdata.org/" target="_blank"&gt;Institute for Health Metrics and Evaluation&lt;/a&gt; from its &lt;a href="http://ghdx.healthdata.org/us-data" target="_blank"&gt;Global Health Data Exchange&lt;/a&gt; resource. This data is easy to read into Plotly, as we’ll demonstrate, since FIPS codes are included in the files.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
If health-related data is your thing, check out our recent post “&lt;a href="https://medium.com/@plotlygraphs/assessing-global-health-one-at-a-time-d061a144a421" target="_blank"&gt;Assessing Global Health, One 📈 at a Time&lt;/a&gt;.”
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
County-level maps in Plotly can reveal spatial patterns, trends, and local tendencies within the dataset you are examining. Hover-over your home county and engage with the data instead of looking at a legend and guessing a value.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
For more on USA county-level choropleth maps in Python, &lt;a href="https://plot.ly/python/county-choropleth/" target="_blank"&gt;head here&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Alcohol Use Disorders&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
This map investigates the percent change in alcohol use disorders between 1980 and 2014. At a full-U.S. scale it is a busy map, but several areas stand out:
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
•Alcohol use disorders have decreased, in some cases significantly, across the Carolinas.
&lt;br/&gt;
•The largest increases are spread far and wide, although the Ohio Valley and Pennsylvania are particularly noticeable, as well as the Four Corners region.
&lt;br/&gt;
•The decrease over the years across South Dakota and Nebraska sticks out amidst a sea of red.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;figure class="tmblr-full" data-orig-height="450" data-orig-width="900" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/Dit2xrB.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://64.media.tumblr.com/b4c4e5cba5e67ee1979e1a7410e672b7/tumblr_inline_p96edsITlF1srua81_540.png" data-orig-height="450" data-orig-width="900" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/Dit2xrB.png"/&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://ghdx.healthdata.org/us-data" target="_blank"&gt;Source&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Dreamsh0t/FIPS/master/alcohol_disorders_change.csv" target="_blank"&gt;Data&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://plot.ly/~Dreamshot/9199/import-plotly-plotly-version-/" target="_blank"&gt;Python code&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Zooming In&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
By using Plotly’s “scope” function, we can zoom down to a low level and obtain more detail: &lt;script src="https://gist.github.com/Dreamsh0t/f241948a980c0c2b0cd589f1839cd117.js"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
We can now closely examine the three states that had the largest decrease in alcohol use disorders during 1980 to 2014. Central North Carolina is the epicenter, with Durham County posting a massive 82.5% decrease in the 34 year period, second to only Miami-Dade County in south Florida for the biggest drop in the United States.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;figure class="tmblr-full" data-orig-height="450" data-orig-width="900" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/EK2Vken.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://64.media.tumblr.com/4ee67a760d6b760d105fd211c7626cde/tumblr_inline_p96edsUuJV1srua81_540.png" data-orig-height="450" data-orig-width="900" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/EK2Vken.png"/&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://ghdx.healthdata.org/us-data" target="_blank"&gt;Source&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Dreamsh0t/FIPS/master/alcohol_state_level.csv" target="_blank"&gt;Data&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://plot.ly/~Dreamshot/9208/import-plotly-plotly-version-/" target="_blank"&gt;Python code&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Diabetes Prevalence&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
In the October 31, 2008 issue of Morbidity and Mortality Weekly Report, Centers for Diseases and Prevention reported that the incidence of new onset diagnosed diabetes in U.S. adults had increased by 90% over the previous decade.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
The map below, which examines the percent change in diabetes prevalence between 1999 and 2012, certainly supports that statistic.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
The states with the largest burden increases include Kansas, Oklahoma, Arkansas, and Missouri, as well as western Tennessee and Kentucky.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
This region sits just west and north of the so-called “&lt;a href="https://www.diabeteswellbeing.com/diabetes-belt/" target="_blank"&gt;diabetes belt&lt;/a&gt;,” so it is a potential indicator that the region is expanding.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;figure class="tmblr-full" data-orig-height="450" data-orig-width="900" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/29AiDdg.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://64.media.tumblr.com/06ce3b8ec87a0431b74d1fcfb3f2961d/tumblr_inline_p96edtDBEI1srua81_540.png" data-orig-height="450" data-orig-width="900" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/29AiDdg.png"/&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://ghdx.healthdata.org/us-data" target="_blank"&gt;Source&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Dreamsh0t/FIPS/master/diabetes_prevalence_change.csv" target="_blank"&gt;Data&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://plot.ly/~Dreamshot/9200/import-plotly-plotly-version-/" target="_blank"&gt;Python code&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;A Closer Look&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Here, we hone in on four central U.S. states that have seen a large increase in diabetes prevalence recently.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Benton County in northwest Arkansas saw an increase of 62.4% and Seward County in southwest Kansas observed an increase of 68.8%, which are not only chart topping locally but on the national level as well.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
The keen geographer would be able to differentiate between the states without borders, but for the rest of us, dark gray state borders can only help.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Notice below we use white county borders to make them pop and black state borders so that those stand out clearly: &lt;script src="https://gist.github.com/Dreamsh0t/4e7f5f976ceaa2ab648785f7daa060c5.js"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;figure class="tmblr-full" data-orig-height="450" data-orig-width="900" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/80Aci5b.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://64.media.tumblr.com/ba3c8845f063c478c15da804f2ebee79/tumblr_inline_p96edtPTsG1srua81_540.png" data-orig-height="450" data-orig-width="900" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/80Aci5b.png"/&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://ghdx.healthdata.org/us-data" target="_blank"&gt;Source&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Dreamsh0t/FIPS/master/diabetes_state_level.csv" target="_blank"&gt;Data&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://plot.ly/~Dreamshot/9209/import-plotly-plotly-version-/" target="_blank"&gt;Python code&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Interpersonal Violence&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Between 1980 and 2014, the percentage of counties in which mortality rates decreased from interpersonal violence was 93.4%.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
The green colors indicate counties where interpersonal violence has trended downward. This was especially clear in Texas and across the Deep South; chiefly Florida and Georgia, as well as into Appalachia.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
California also featured significant decreases.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
On the other hand, red shades show where interpersonal violence increased. This occurred in patches across the Midwest and Ohio Valley, but was most prominent in eastern Pennsylvania and upstate New York.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;figure class="tmblr-full" data-orig-height="450" data-orig-width="900" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/iamdUIX.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://64.media.tumblr.com/c91d886f077f3a2e8bb65d1ada543593/tumblr_inline_p96edtaTgX1srua81_540.png" data-orig-height="450" data-orig-width="900" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/iamdUIX.png"/&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://ghdx.healthdata.org/us-data" target="_blank"&gt;Source&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Dreamsh0t/FIPS/master/interpersonal_violence_change.csv" target="_blank"&gt;Data&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://plot.ly/~Dreamshot/9203/import-plotly-plotly-version-/" target="_blank"&gt;Python code&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Ohio Stands Out&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Many states, particularly across the south and west, observed a reduction in interpersonal violence between 1980 and 2014. However, there is a pocket of states in the northeastern corner of the U.S. that had some increases.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Central and eastern Ohio contains one of those pockets, where Franklin County tallied a 67% increase in interpersonal violence during the 24-year period.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Between 1980 and 2014, the percentage of counties in which mortality rates increased from interpersonal violence was just 6.6% — a number propelled forward by states like Ohio, Pennsylvania, and New York.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Notice below we use a gray plot background color to make our state pop out a little more: &lt;script src="https://gist.github.com/Dreamsh0t/17323cd04a02a4f1bfa7b394f2d0098a.js"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;figure class="tmblr-full" data-orig-height="450" data-orig-width="900" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/UxgAiOT.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://64.media.tumblr.com/5f1537022dd75372ec61cfccbc16f339/tumblr_inline_p96edugxYR1srua81_540.png" data-orig-height="450" data-orig-width="900" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/UxgAiOT.png"/&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://ghdx.healthdata.org/us-data" target="_blank"&gt;Source&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Dreamsh0t/FIPS/master/interpersonal_state_level.csv" target="_blank"&gt;Data&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://plot.ly/~Dreamshot/9210/import-plotly-plotly-version-/" target="_blank"&gt;Python code&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Where do your Avocados come from? 🥑&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
U.S. avocados are commercially grown in California, Texas, and Florida across the Lower 48. In terms of total avocado-producing acreage, The Golden State accounts for over 81%.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Outside of California, Miami-Dade County in South Florida has almost 11,700 avocado bearing acres, good for third highest north of the (Mexican) border.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Unsurprisingly, the avocado tree does not tolerate freezing temperatures and can only be grown in subtropical or tropical climates like Florida, California, Texas, Mexico, and New Zealand.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;figure class="tmblr-full" data-orig-height="450" data-orig-width="900" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/10EfGoW.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://64.media.tumblr.com/fd0f097aee65d21d506e592fabc2a6a5/tumblr_inline_p96eduQZJm1srua81_540.png" data-orig-height="450" data-orig-width="900" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/10EfGoW.png"/&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://quickstats.nass.usda.gov/#E93CFBD6-6E60-3C6B-90A6-FF24070F146C" target="_blank"&gt;Source&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Dreamsh0t/FIPS/master/avocados.csv" target="_blank"&gt;Data&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://plot.ly/~Dreamshot/9215/import-plotly-plotly-version-/" target="_blank"&gt;Python code&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;California-cado&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
According to the California Avocado Commission, California is the top producer of avocados in the United States and home to 95% of the country’s crop. There are approximately 6,000 growers in the state, a majority of which are located in San Diego County.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
In fact, San Diego County alone produces about 40% of California’s avocados and has nearly 18,000 avocado-bearing acres of land. Ventura County has the second most avocado-bearing acres in the state with over 15,500.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;figure class="tmblr-full" data-orig-height="450" data-orig-width="900" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/nlaUioc.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://64.media.tumblr.com/bfcab44073dd637a996778daf25cc0f0/tumblr_inline_p96edubG8o1srua81_540.png" data-orig-height="450" data-orig-width="900" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/nlaUioc.png"/&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://quickstats.nass.usda.gov/#E93CFBD6-6E60-3C6B-90A6-FF24070F146C" target="_blank"&gt;Source&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Dreamsh0t/FIPS/master/avocados_cali.csv" target="_blank"&gt;Data&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://plot.ly/~Dreamshot/9218/import-plotly-plotly-version-/" target="_blank"&gt;Python code&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;California’s Central Valley the Almond Epicenter&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Kern County, in California’s Mediterranean Central Valley, is home to the most almond-bearing acres in the United States — nearly 144,000 as of 2012.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
In fact, California almonds comprise 99.99% of production in the lower 48 AND approximately 62% of the world stock.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Almonds are also cultivated in Spain, Iran, Morocco, Italy, and Australia.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;figure class="tmblr-full" data-orig-height="450" data-orig-width="900" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/55JGDJR.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://64.media.tumblr.com/0a601ef8ac15c7cab1f4c96a67b475f8/tumblr_inline_p96edviwgG1srua81_540.png" data-orig-height="450" data-orig-width="900" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/55JGDJR.png"/&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://quickstats.nass.usda.gov/#E93CFBD6-6E60-3C6B-90A6-FF24070F146C" target="_blank"&gt;Source&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Dreamsh0t/FIPS/master/avocados_cali.csv" target="_blank"&gt;Data&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://plot.ly/~Dreamshot/9223/import-plotly-plotly-version-/" target="_blank"&gt;Python code&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Where you’re Most Likely to see a U-Haul&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Between 2016 and 2017, the independent city of Falls Church, Virginia, very close to Washington D.C. had the largest migration (or number of new residents) per 1,000 population for a locality that has more than 10,000 residents.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;5 biggest migrant increases, by county [location | migrants per 1,000 population]&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
1. Falls Church, Virginia | 49.02
&lt;br/&gt;
2. Comal County, Texas | 48.69
&lt;br/&gt;
3. Wasatch County, Utah | 47.81
&lt;br/&gt;
4. Hays County, Texas | 47.27
&lt;br/&gt;
5. Kendall County, Texas | 46.84
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;5 biggest migrant decreases, by county [location | migrants per 1,000 population]&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
1. Campbell County, Wyoming | -55.31
&lt;br/&gt;
2. Martin County, Kentucky | -43.22
&lt;br/&gt;
3. Cheyenne County, Nebraska | -40.31
&lt;br/&gt;
4. Geary County, Kansas | -39.96
&lt;br/&gt;
5. McDowell County, West Virginia | -37.01
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;figure class="tmblr-full" data-orig-height="450" data-orig-width="900" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/hjd8mL8.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://64.media.tumblr.com/f381fcdc0ae0a37893d8086d0e8ab71a/tumblr_inline_p96edvxmh11srua81_540.png" data-orig-height="450" data-orig-width="900" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/hjd8mL8.png"/&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.census.gov/newsroom/press-releases/2018/popest-metro-county.html" target="_blank"&gt;Source&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Dreamsh0t/FIPS/master/net_migration.csv" target="_blank"&gt;Data&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://plot.ly/~Dreamshot/9230/import-plotly-plotly-version-/" target="_blank"&gt;Python code&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Migration, Normalized&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
For another perspective, here is the same data as above but standardized. The growth across the western U.S. is evident, along with the sliding population across the northern Plains and northeastern Rockies (fossil fuel slump).
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;For a refresher on normal distributions, recall the &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/68%E2%80%9395%E2%80%9399.7_rule" target="_blank"&gt;68–95–99.7 rule&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;figure class="tmblr-full" data-orig-height="450" data-orig-width="900" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/h4j6PUI.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://64.media.tumblr.com/591f40ab0b7ae6e533eed791a9cb3b72/tumblr_inline_p96edwQlAB1srua81_540.png" data-orig-height="450" data-orig-width="900" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/h4j6PUI.png"/&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.census.gov/newsroom/press-releases/2018/popest-metro-county.html" target="_blank"&gt;Source&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Dreamsh0t/FIPS/master/migration_sigma.csv" target="_blank"&gt;Data&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://plot.ly/~Dreamshot/9233/import-plotly-plotly-version-/" target="_blank"&gt;Python code&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Colorscales&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Looking for the right colorscale to complement your choropleth map? Look no further: &lt;a href="https://react-colorscales.getforge.io/." target="_blank"&gt;https://react-colorscales.getforge.io/.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
County-level maps in Plotly can reveal spatial patterns, trends, and local tendencies within the dataset you are examining. Hover-over your home county and engage with the data instead of looking at a legend and guessing a value.</description><link>https://blog.plotly.com/post/174174340512</link><guid>https://blog.plotly.com/post/174174340512</guid><pubDate>Wed, 23 May 2018 05:57:07 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>How to Create 2D and 3D Interactive Weather Maps in Python and R</title><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure class="tmblr-full" data-orig-height="480" data-orig-width="615" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/svQ3UP1.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://64.media.tumblr.com/da02f15b5b7815bd0236d83e906615c4/tumblr_inline_p7fx49ydqA1srua81_540.jpg" data-orig-height="480" data-orig-width="615" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/svQ3UP1.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;i&gt;Robert FitzRoy. Source: nzhistory.govt.nz.&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
It was the year 1860. Robert FitzRoy, of England and New Zealand, was using the new telegraph system to gather daily weather observations and produce the first synoptic weather map. He coined the term “weather forecast” and his were the first ever to be published daily.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Fitzroy probably would have never imagined in his wildest dreams what the weather map scene would be like 160 years into the future…
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
⏩ ⏩ ⏩
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;!-- more --&gt;
In 2018, weather maps are commonly produced in the &lt;a href="http://cola.gmu.edu/grads/" target="_blank"&gt;Grid Analysis and Display System (GrADS)&lt;/a&gt;, R, and &lt;a href="https://moderndata.plot.ly/weather-and-geography-charts-made-in-python-or-r/" target="_blank"&gt;Python&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;figure class="tmblr-full" data-orig-height="800" data-orig-width="1200" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/d23teP8.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://64.media.tumblr.com/27f5b63f7af71b7ec44f9fcf4744e6a4/tumblr_inline_p7fx49wND51srua81_540.png" data-orig-height="800" data-orig-width="1200" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/d23teP8.png"/&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;i&gt;Kazakhstan, parts of Russia and China, and Japan had a colder than normal start to winter in 2017–18.&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Weather and climate maps in Plotly add a new layer to the interrogation of our atmosphere. When it comes to these maps, Plotly’s point of difference comes in its ability to hover-over and interact with specific data points on the fly, instead of looking at a legend and ‘ballparking’ a value.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Below, you’ll find several new examples of weather and climate maps created from freely available data on the web. If you’d like to create similar maps, you’ll have to get familiar with the &lt;a href="https://www.esrl.noaa.gov/psd/data/composites/day/" target="_blank"&gt;NCEP Reanalysis plotter&lt;/a&gt;, an amazingly useful tool that is used to investigative the climate system and day-to-day weather.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;Here’s a short tutorial&lt;/b&gt;:
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;figure class="tmblr-full" data-orig-height="776" data-orig-width="1240" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/ZTU8fjP.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://64.media.tumblr.com/ce08a4d8520d0d03871b24e8af400a61/tumblr_inline_p7fx4aTV4M1srua81_540.png" data-orig-height="776" data-orig-width="1240" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/ZTU8fjP.png"/&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.esrl.noaa.gov/psd/data/composites/day/" target="_blank"&gt;Using the NCEP Reanalysis plotter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Go ahead, immerse yourself in this new and amazing interactive weather world that we are so fortunate to have in 2018.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Temperature Anomaly&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Do you live in the eastern North America? If so, you’ve were subject to some of the coldest temperatures (with respect to normal) on the globe during December and January 2018. Siberia, a place that is already brutally cold during winter, was also colder than average.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
On the flip side, the Arctic (winter), Europe (winter), eastern Australia (summer), and New Zealand (summer) have had above average temperatures during December-January. In fact, January was New Zealand’s warmest month of any month on record (nationwide records began in 1909).
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-lang="en"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;New Zealand just had its hottest month in at least 109 years. The nationwide anomaly of +3.1°C or +5.6°F was also the largest on record. &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/climate?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" target="_blank"&gt;#climate&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ZLabe?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" target="_blank"&gt;@ZLabe&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Weather_West?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" target="_blank"&gt;@Weather_West&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://t.co/bXmZJODZ4M" target="_blank"&gt;https://t.co/bXmZJODZ4M&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Ben Noll (@BenNollWeather) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/BenNollWeather/status/959239378219425793?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" target="_blank"&gt;February 2, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
See the blue patch to the west of South America? That’s associated with a climate signature known as La Niña, defined by cooler that normal sea temperatures in that part of the world that has wide-reaching impacts on a global scale.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Temperature Difference from Normal 🌡️&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;figure class="tmblr-full" data-orig-height="800" data-orig-width="1200" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/fGTMNL7.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://64.media.tumblr.com/e2ec961335c9c7cfea5cf182a666c179/tumblr_inline_p7fx4bjzSX1srua81_540.png" data-orig-height="800" data-orig-width="1200" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/fGTMNL7.png"/&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.esrl.noaa.gov/psd/data/composites/day/" target="_blank"&gt;Using the NCEP Reanalysis plotter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;Data source&lt;/b&gt;: &lt;a href="https://www.esrl.noaa.gov/psd/data/composites/day/" target="_blank"&gt;NCEP Reanalysis Plotter&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;Data used to create this plot&lt;/b&gt;: &lt;a href="https://github.com/Dreamsh0t/Weather_Stuff/raw/master/compday.pqW831uq5f.nc" target="_blank"&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;Python code&lt;/b&gt;: &lt;a href="https://plot.ly/~Dreamshot/9144/import-plotly-plotly-version-/" target="_blank"&gt;Jupyter notebook&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/cpsievert/Weather_Stuff/blob/master/air-temp-plot.R" target="_blank"&gt;Make this in R&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Rainfall Anomaly 🌧&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
We can apply the same techniques that we used to create the temperature anomaly map above to precipitation (rain and snow).
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
The map below looks at precipitation as a difference from normal for the period December to January 2018.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
The Western Pacific had wetter than normal conditions chiefly because of La Niña. La Niña is associated with warmer than average sea surface temperatures near the Philippines, Papua New Guinea, and across Southeast Asia. These warm seas result in more rising motion than average in the atmosphere, which culminates in rainy conditions.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
In direct contrast, there is quite a bit of brown shading about southern Africa as Cape Town approaches &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2018/01/30/world/africa/cape-town-day-zero.html" target="_blank"&gt;Day Zero&lt;/a&gt;. In addition, California sticks out along the West Coast of North America for being a much drier than normal location.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-lang="en"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Wildfires are not at all common in northern California during mid-winter, when vegetation is normally very moist. But recent record warmth and prolonged dry spell have dried fuels to near/below record low levels for Feb. &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/CAwx?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" target="_blank"&gt;#CAwx&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/CAfire?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" target="_blank"&gt;#CAfire&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/PUnA5W1acF" target="_blank"&gt;https://t.co/PUnA5W1acF&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Daniel Swain (@Weather_West) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Weather_West/status/963288074959519744?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" target="_blank"&gt;February 13, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Precipitation Difference from Normal&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;figure class="tmblr-full" data-orig-height="800" data-orig-width="1200" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/qFeSskg.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://64.media.tumblr.com/ca1edbcb66f93b9ad12cda8f71251b47/tumblr_inline_p7fx4cTRNX1srua81_540.png" data-orig-height="800" data-orig-width="1200" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/qFeSskg.png"/&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.esrl.noaa.gov/psd/data/composites/day/" target="_blank"&gt;Using the NCEP Reanalysis plotter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;Data source&lt;/b&gt;: &lt;a href="https://www.esrl.noaa.gov/psd/data/composites/day/" target="_blank"&gt;NCEP Reanalysis Plotter&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;Data used to create this plot&lt;/b&gt;: &lt;a href="https://github.com/Dreamsh0t/Weather_Stuff/raw/master/compday.uD1lrjCi2B.nc" target="_blank"&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;Python code&lt;/b&gt;: &lt;a href="https://plot.ly/~Dreamshot/9149/import-plotly-plotly-version-/" target="_blank"&gt;Jupyter notebook&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/cpsievert/Weather_Stuff/blob/master/precip-plot.R" target="_blank"&gt;Make this in R&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Zoom&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
While you can always zoom in on a global projection, maybe you’re looking for something more localized. In this case, you can set your latitude and longitude as such: &lt;a href="https://gist.github.com/Dreamsh0t/e53a3687bf4046cfd9c5bca527a505a2%22" target="_blank"&gt;Python code snippet&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
This the resulting graph will be a zoom to North America. For further detail, you can add state borders like this: &lt;a href="https://gist.github.com/Dreamsh0t/33781dfac968e6da9ed819b991db8e2e" target="_blank"&gt;Python code snippet&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Here’s a closer look at southern Africa where Cape Town where the water taps are expected to run dry on June 4th. After three years of low rainfall and drought or near-drought conditions, locals and visitors are limited to 50 liters (about 13 gallons) of water per day. For some perspective, the average American uses about 380 liters per day or almost 8 times the Cape Town restricted amount.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-lang="en"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Current daily consumption is 526 million litres per day. Keep it up Cape Town! Together we can defeat &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/DayZero?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" target="_blank"&gt;#DayZero&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/ThinkWaterCT?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" target="_blank"&gt;#ThinkWaterCT&lt;/a&gt; and view this week’s dashboard here: &lt;a href="https://t.co/Yj9ZUoU0UD" target="_blank"&gt;https://t.co/Yj9ZUoU0UD&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/gVuA3qOqNd" target="_blank"&gt;pic.twitter.com/gVuA3qOqNd&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— City of Cape Town (@CityofCT) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/CityofCT/status/963731177709490176?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" target="_blank"&gt;February 14, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;figure class="tmblr-full" data-orig-height="700" data-orig-width="1000" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/Pr44LYf.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://64.media.tumblr.com/2c51626784ba3a45f42d017d7b84fffc/tumblr_inline_p7fx4ctEmv1srua81_540.png" data-orig-height="700" data-orig-width="1000" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/Pr44LYf.png"/&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Python code: &lt;a href="https://plot.ly/~Dreamshot/9158/import-plotly-plotly-version-/" target="_blank"&gt;Jupyter notebook&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Mercator projections, like the graphs above, are popular because they preserve direction and are ideal for navigation. They also have further educational value&amp;ndash;such as being a good way of learning the shapes of nations.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
However, Mercator maps misrepresent the size of countries and are poorly defined at the poles.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
For a different perspective, Plotly user &lt;a href="https://plot.ly/~empet/" target="_blank"&gt;empet&lt;/a&gt; mapped the flat Earth onto a sphere for a 3-D experience.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Precipitation Difference from Normal in 3-D&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;figure class="tmblr-full" data-orig-height="800" data-orig-width="800" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/9eqCBVo.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://64.media.tumblr.com/c4b3b0b330adc6fa8b69f48816ab1afa/tumblr_inline_p7fx4eHfNt1srua81_540.png" data-orig-height="800" data-orig-width="800" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/9eqCBVo.png"/&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Sunshine Anomaly 🌞&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Outgoing longwave radiation (OLR) is a measure of the amount of energy emitted to space by earth’s surface, oceans and atmosphere. OLR is a good proxy for clear skies — the larger (on the positive side) the OLR anomaly, the more unusually clear it might have been at a given location. Conversely, a large negative anomaly might imply more cloud cover than normal and frequent thunderstorms or rain.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Below, we investigate OLR as a difference from normal for the period December 2017-January 2018.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;Above normal sunshine&lt;/b&gt;: New Zealand, Queensland, Zimbabwe, Zambia, Portugal, western USA, Alaska.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;Below normal sunshine&lt;/b&gt;: Central America, northern Africa, eastern Canada, western India, Philippines and South Asia, western Australia.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;OLR Difference from Normal&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;figure class="tmblr-full" data-orig-height="800" data-orig-width="1200" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/kMY2tD1.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://64.media.tumblr.com/781ab0ec67ac879182062c4249bc62a2/tumblr_inline_p7fx4euVhX1srua81_540.png" data-orig-height="800" data-orig-width="1200" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/kMY2tD1.png"/&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;Data source&lt;/b&gt;: &lt;a href="https://www.esrl.noaa.gov/psd/data/composites/day/" target="_blank"&gt;NCEP Reanalysis Plotter&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;Data used to create this plot&lt;/b&gt;: &lt;a href="https://github.com/Dreamsh0t/Weather_Stuff/raw/master/compday.KsNOdsJTz1.nc" target="_blank"&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;Python code&lt;/b&gt;: &lt;a href="https://plot.ly/~Dreamshot/9152" target="_blank"&gt;Jupyter notebook&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/cpsievert/Weather_Stuff/blob/master/radiation-plot.R" target="_blank"&gt;Make this in R&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;OLR Difference from Normal in 3-D&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;figure class="tmblr-full" data-orig-height="800" data-orig-width="800" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/G4J49vu.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://64.media.tumblr.com/59845c2db81fed2be307349ed31a74c1/tumblr_inline_p7fx4frGmH1srua81_540.png" data-orig-height="800" data-orig-width="800" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/G4J49vu.png"/&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://plot.ly/~empet/14813/heatmap-plot-on-a-spherical-map/" target="_blank"&gt;Learn how to make this spherical plot&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/cpsievert/Weather_Stuff/blob/master/radiation-plot-3D.R" target="_blank"&gt;Make this in R&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Sea Surface Temperature Anomaly&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Sea surface temperatures are the main driver of climate variability in the global tropics (10ºN-10ºS latitude) and play a major role in the global sub-tropics and midlatitudes as well.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Here, we can identify that a La Niña is present by the ‘cool pool’ of water found along the coast of western South America and into the eastern and central equatorial Pacific. La Niña, which is part of the natural El Niño-Southern Oscillation (ENSO) cycle, is considered to be a climate driver.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
What is not totally natural is the ‘red blob’ between Australia and New Zealand —— known as the Tasman Sea marine heatwave. Although this climate feature’s development was fueled by the ENSO cycle, the extent of the anomaly was the largest ever observed, almost certainly influenced upward by the tailwind that is anthropogenic global warming.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;figure class="tmblr-full" data-orig-height="800" data-orig-width="1200" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/fI38Vdt.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://64.media.tumblr.com/9e42dfcd4a7bc7b9829a75e22e6d58bc/tumblr_inline_p7fx4fn4lU1srua81_540.png" data-orig-height="800" data-orig-width="1200" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/fI38Vdt.png"/&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;Data source&lt;/b&gt;: &lt;a href="https://www.esrl.noaa.gov/psd/data/composites/day/" target="_blank"&gt;NCEP Reanalysis Plotter&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;Data used to create this plot&lt;/b&gt;: &lt;a href="https://github.com/Dreamsh0t/Weather_Stuff/raw/master/compday.7bwhd4Pxxr.nc" target="_blank"&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;Python code&lt;/b&gt;: &lt;a href="https://plot.ly/~Dreamshot/9161" target="_blank"&gt;Jupyter notebook&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/cpsievert/Weather_Stuff/blob/master/sst-plot.R" target="_blank"&gt;Make this in R&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Forecast Wind Speed and Direction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
The weather goes as the wind blows. Using weather data in Plotly, not only can you diagnose cyclones, but zoom to low levels to see how much of a breeze is forecast in your town.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
The plot below was originally created by Plotly user ToniBois and the 3-D version below was created by &lt;a href="https://plot.ly/~empet" target="_blank"&gt;empet&lt;/a&gt;. If you look carefully, you’ll notice &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hurricane_Hermine" target="_blank"&gt;Hurricane Hermine&lt;/a&gt; (September 2016) swirling perilously off of the East Coast of the United States.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
The data used to create this plot comes from the &lt;a href="http://www.nco.ncep.noaa.gov/pmb/products/gfs/" target="_blank"&gt;NCEP Products Inventory&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;figure class="tmblr-full" data-orig-height="800" data-orig-width="800" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/dtn5IhA.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://64.media.tumblr.com/49f2dccea5a0d8e140bdef9d4773e405/tumblr_inline_p7fx4giou31srua81_540.png" data-orig-height="800" data-orig-width="800" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/dtn5IhA.png"/&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Colorscales&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Looking for the right colorscale to complement your weather map? Look no further: &lt;a href="https://react-colorscales.getforge.io/." target="_blank"&gt;https://react-colorscales.getforge.io/.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
The “CMOCEAN” and “DIVERGENT” colorscales are recommended for weather and climate charts. For the temperature chart, we used “balance”
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;figure class="tmblr-full" data-orig-height="45" data-orig-width="317" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/oDfmg0L.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://64.media.tumblr.com/4905f7ad3fb2f8f13f0a7ec1148e3846/tumblr_inline_p7fx4gmyr41srua81_540.png" data-orig-height="45" data-orig-width="317" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/oDfmg0L.png"/&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
For the precipitation chart, we used “BrBG”
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;figure class="tmblr-full" data-orig-height="45" data-orig-width="303" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/cMvtG4o.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://64.media.tumblr.com/6fe3f7dafe29372372b4f458f4a42481/tumblr_inline_p7fx4gu0SB1srua81_540.png" data-orig-height="45" data-orig-width="303" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/cMvtG4o.png"/&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
For the outgoing longwave radiation chart, we used “RdYlBu”
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;figure class="tmblr-full" data-orig-height="43" data-orig-width="302" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/FkbcmzM.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://64.media.tumblr.com/7c91537fe2f058a0382c2b72555f72e7/tumblr_inline_p7fx4hH5kp1srua81_540.png" data-orig-height="43" data-orig-width="302" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/FkbcmzM.png"/&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
For the sea surface temperature chart, we used “curl”
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;figure data-orig-height="45" data-orig-width="288" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/v5F3hfw.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://64.media.tumblr.com/96175389e5739eea456b5dd5b363d560/tumblr_inline_p7fx4hT0ZZ1srua81_540.png" data-orig-height="45" data-orig-width="288" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/v5F3hfw.png"/&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Weather and climate maps in Plotly add a new layer to the interrogation of our atmosphere. When it comes to weather maps, Plotly’s point of difference comes in its ability to hover-over and interact with specific data points on the fly, instead of looking at a legend and ‘ballparking’ a value.</description><link>https://blog.plotly.com/post/171585173862</link><guid>https://blog.plotly.com/post/171585173862</guid><pubDate>Tue, 06 Mar 2018 03:38:40 -0500</pubDate><category>weather</category><category>climate</category><category>climate change</category><category>data science</category><category>data</category><category>datavisualization</category></item><item><title>Where science meets art</title><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure class="tmblr-full" data-orig-height="500" data-orig-width="736" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/mM9mhxd.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://64.media.tumblr.com/8abaa42943b66510c74999baa946ce46/tumblr_inline_p7lffgnxfZ1srua81_540.jpg" data-orig-height="500" data-orig-width="736" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/mM9mhxd.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Data visualizations such graphs, charts, presentations, and reports represent the intersection point of your company’s data, statistics, and numbers (i.e. &lt;i&gt;science&lt;/i&gt;) and its brand, style, and personality (i.e. &lt;i&gt;art&lt;/i&gt;). However, this “marriage” of science and art will only be a successful one if the platform it is presented on is simple, effective, and beautiful.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;i&gt;“Design is not just what it looks like and feels like. Design is how it works.”&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
-Steve Jobs
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
This is where Plotly’s &lt;a href="https://plot.ly/dashboards-and-reports/" target="_blank"&gt;dashboards&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://plot.ly/dashboards-and-reports/" target="_blank"&gt;reports&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://plot.ly/online-presentation-tool/" target="_blank"&gt;presentations&lt;/a&gt; come in — to bridge the gap between what your creation looks and feels like, and how it works. Plotly gives you the tools and examples to make beautiful dashboards and reports, even if you’re not trained in design.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
In this post, we’ll teach you how to be situationally aware when it comes to choosing graph types. Additionally, we’ll show you how easy it is to apply your brand’s style guide, from the logo to the color palette, to a Plotly product. Inspiration for this post stems from IBM’s Design Language &lt;a href="https://www.ibm.com/design/language/experience/data-visualization" target="_blank"&gt;data visualization guidelines&lt;/a&gt; and therefore we created some IBM-branded graphs, reports, and presentations in Plotly.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
We recently provided some &lt;a href="https://medium.com/@plotlygraphs/maximizing-the-data-ink-ratio-in-dashboards-and-slide-deck-7887f7c1fab" target="_blank"&gt;dashboard and slide deck templates&lt;/a&gt; that you can use — now we’ll expand on that work, personalizing your figures and applying industry-leading techniques to ensure the best visualizations possible.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;How it works&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Let’s go through several different chart types. We’ll address how to best utilize each type of graph according to &lt;a href="https://www.ibm.com/design/language/experience/data-visualization/chart-models" target="_blank"&gt;IBM’s data visualization language&lt;/a&gt;. We’ll later use these to construct our Dashboard and Report.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;Line chart, costs vs revenues&lt;/b&gt;: “Line graphs are used to track changes over short and long periods of time. When smaller changes exist, it’s better to use line graphs than bar graphs. Line graphs can also be used to compare changes over the same period of time for more than one group.”&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;figure class="tmblr-full" data-orig-height="500" data-orig-width="700" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/why46Ik.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://64.media.tumblr.com/c6e437379bf37f86ecdae5f7007ad474/tumblr_inline_p7lffhtviS1srua81_540.png" data-orig-height="500" data-orig-width="700" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/why46Ik.png"/&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;Line chart, units sold over time&lt;/b&gt;: “Avoid [line charts] if not comparing values over time, as it might create confusion. Select a bar graph in this case.”&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;figure class="tmblr-full" data-orig-height="500" data-orig-width="700" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/4bjJx18.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://64.media.tumblr.com/6bd4765b7003d04971ee10f11900a078/tumblr_inline_p7lffhO6XY1srua81_540.png" data-orig-height="500" data-orig-width="700" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/4bjJx18.png"/&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;Bar chart, revenue by year&lt;/b&gt;: “Rectangular bars with lengths proportional to the values they represent. Bar graphs should be used to compare different values that are hierarchically equivalent. Using a colored element among gray elements makes the focus of the chart clear to the reader.”&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;figure class="tmblr-full" data-orig-height="500" data-orig-width="700" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/H1E3GnH.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://64.media.tumblr.com/e0ae7094f5c6cd218c601443707437a2/tumblr_inline_p7lffhlOKN1srua81_540.png" data-orig-height="500" data-orig-width="700" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/H1E3GnH.png"/&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;Stacked bar chart, evaluation of manager by department&lt;/b&gt;: “A variant of the bar graph, where each rectangle is divided in multiple parts. Stacked bar charts are good for comparing elements across categories. In this example, a diverging palette is especially effective — the two opposing values have a positive/negative connotation.”&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;figure class="tmblr-full" data-orig-height="500" data-orig-width="700" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/OMvGJ25.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://64.media.tumblr.com/e167cb3875e1dd58b52f7e014d4f6e86/tumblr_inline_p7lffhvFR91srua81_540.png" data-orig-height="500" data-orig-width="700" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/OMvGJ25.png"/&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;Pie chart, comparison of revenue subdivision&lt;/b&gt;: “Use only when the different values add up to a total and there is a need to highlight percentages.”&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;figure class="tmblr-full" data-orig-height="500" data-orig-width="700" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/jLJh7eP.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://64.media.tumblr.com/fc4e5d10ef868b853145e2e068721a1b/tumblr_inline_p7lffikxlm1srua81_540.png" data-orig-height="500" data-orig-width="700" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/jLJh7eP.png"/&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;Bubble chart, students by faculty&lt;/b&gt;: “Used to show values among categories or groups with circles, avoiding any kind of axis. Use it as alternative to bar chart.”&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;figure class="tmblr-full" data-orig-height="500" data-orig-width="700" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/9wD7tTs.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://64.media.tumblr.com/3b1dfd1286d926129d18c0bd585a2179/tumblr_inline_p7lffi1TeA1srua81_540.png" data-orig-height="500" data-orig-width="700" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/9wD7tTs.png"/&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;Map, temperature variations across the USA&lt;/b&gt;: “Cartography is used to display geographical data. Use it when the focus of the analysis is geography, and when it’s important to zoom in on different places.”&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;figure class="tmblr-full" data-orig-height="500" data-orig-width="700" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/L2JcLYk.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://64.media.tumblr.com/9362a00c563efef3a01482155aa0a0c5/tumblr_inline_p7lffiRbF01srua81_540.png" data-orig-height="500" data-orig-width="700" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/L2JcLYk.png"/&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;What it looks like&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Notice we’ve applied IBM’s color palette and logo to our dashboard and slide deck below [click here to reference the color palette]. If you’re on a Mac, you can use Digital Color Meter to ‘color pick’ off your screen. Windows users might try paint.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Pro tip: simple touches like this not only make your figures look more sleek but also reputable, professional—it readies it for the big stage (i.e. a presentation for the execs) in a jiffy.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a href="https://plot.ly/dashboard/Dreamshot:9119/present" target="_blank"&gt;Dashboard&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;figure class="tmblr-full" data-orig-height="804" data-orig-width="524" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/PglzD78.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://64.media.tumblr.com/aa9051d9884aaf5b89231cd71cba3f97/tumblr_inline_p7lffivrli1srua81_540.png" data-orig-height="804" data-orig-width="524" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/PglzD78.png"/&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a href="https://plot.ly/~Dreamshot/9120/ibm/#/6?_k=dkpt5n" target="_blank"&gt;Slide Deck&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
When using Slide Deck, make your graphs as large as possible and use at least 50 size-font for slide titles; match your charts background color to the color of the slide deck (we recommend white or light gray).
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Your presentation should tell a story and not be a lecture — your goal should be to not only convey information to your audience, but inject some of your passion and expertise about the topic(s) into them. Consider it a journey that you are taking together and reach the finish line at the same time!
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
A limited text-plentiful graphic combination will set you on the right path…
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;figure class="tmblr-full" data-orig-height="581" data-orig-width="984" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/4gjQH7h.gif"&gt;&lt;img src="https://64.media.tumblr.com/a5a098d9e1b766da15636fe6763f7cdf/tumblr_inline_p7lffjaiAF1srua81_540.gif" data-orig-height="581" data-orig-width="984" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/4gjQH7h.gif"/&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</description><link>https://blog.plotly.com/post/169844075917</link><guid>https://blog.plotly.com/post/169844075917</guid><pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2018 04:38:23 -0500</pubDate><category>dataviz</category><category>datascience</category><category>data</category><category>presentation</category><category>dashboard</category><category>datavisualization</category></item><item><title>Maximizing the Data-Ink Ratio in Dashboards and Slide Deck</title><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;“Above all else, show the data.&amp;ldquo;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
-Edward Tufte, 1983
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Once referred to by the New York Times as the “Leonardo da Vinci of data,” the work of data visualization expert Edward Tufte has long been an inspiration to Plotly.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
One of Tufte’s key principals is that good graphics present their message as simply as possible. To do this, he defined the “data-ink ratio” to turn this ‘so called’ simplicity into more practical ideas.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;Definition 1:&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;Data-ink: the non-erasable core of a graphic.&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;Definition 2:&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;Data-ink ratio =&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;1. Data-ink divided by the total ink used to print the graphic.&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;2. The proportion of a graphic’s ink devoted to the non-redundant display of data information.&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;3. One minus the proportion of a graphic that can be erased without loss of data information.&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;!-- more --&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Because the non-erasable portion of a graph is subjective, Tufte follows up his principal of data-ink with the Five Laws of Data-Ink:
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;1. Above all else show the data.&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;2. Maximize the data-ink ratio.&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;3. Erase non-data ink.&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;4. Erase redundant data-ink.&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;5. Revise and edit.&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;figure class="tmblr-full" data-orig-height="460" data-orig-width="640" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/A54ZEPb.gif"&gt;&lt;img src="https://64.media.tumblr.com/1d10cd7d97a9719cd072097913640260/tumblr_inline_p7lffhqfBX1srua81_540.gif" data-orig-height="460" data-orig-width="640" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/A54ZEPb.gif"/&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
We’ve already demonstrated in a &lt;a href="https://plotlyblog.tumblr.com/post/143370337552/above-all-else-show-the-data" target="_blank"&gt;previous post&lt;/a&gt; how to apply these techniques to graphs in Plotly, but we’ve yet to demonstrate it using dashboards and slide decks. Until now.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
In this post, find &lt;a href="https://plot.ly/dashboards-and-reports/" target="_blank"&gt;3 dashboard&lt;/a&gt; and 3 &lt;a href="https://plot.ly/online-presentation-tool/" target="_blank"&gt;slide deck&lt;/a&gt; templates (that you can use!) that follow Tufte’s maxims.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;1. &lt;a href="https://plot.ly/~Dreamshot/9044/simple-presentation/#/?_k=ng06sp" target="_blank"&gt;Simple Slide Deck&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;figure class="tmblr-full" data-orig-height="900" data-orig-width="1440" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/ClQqkZq.gif"&gt;&lt;img src="https://64.media.tumblr.com/a5d3da884d3f5f304501f0871998ccda/tumblr_inline_p7lffje8NY1srua81_540.gif" data-orig-height="900" data-orig-width="1440" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/ClQqkZq.gif"/&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Minimalist by design, our Simple Slide Deck template is optimized to clearly present interactive charts, tables, and data. We’ve eliminated all non-data ink.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
If you’d like to use the slide deck above and make it your own, you can download it as a.json file &lt;a href="https://plot.ly/~Dreamshot/9044/simple-presentation/#/?_k=6yxzyh" target="_blank"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. Then, if you haven’t already, download &lt;a href="https://plot.ly/online-presentation-tool/" target="_blank"&gt;Spectacle Editor&lt;/a&gt; and open it.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
If you need more guidance, check out our previous post on &lt;a href="https://medium.com/@plotlygraphs/turn-scroll-fest-into-no-mess-with-dashboards-presentations-f382af0bb46f" target="_blank"&gt;using Spectacle Editor&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;2. &lt;a href="https://plot.ly/dashboard/Dreamshot:9035/present" target="_blank"&gt;Simple Report&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;figure class="tmblr-full" data-orig-height="823" data-orig-width="540" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/FHQSWE1.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://64.media.tumblr.com/f187eae21db7cbd4a2b3e008cb3e3242/tumblr_inline_p7lffjeMe41srua81_540.png" data-orig-height="823" data-orig-width="540" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/FHQSWE1.png"/&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;i&gt;“Clutter and confusion are not attributes of data—they are shortcomings of design.”&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
-Edward Tufte
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Edit the dashboard and save your own version &lt;a href="https://plot.ly/dashboard/Dreamshot:9035/view" target="_blank"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;3. &lt;a href="https://plot.ly/~Dreamshot/9000/vibrant-presentation/#/?_k=r4adyj" target="_blank"&gt;Vibrant Slide Deck&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;figure class="tmblr-full" data-orig-height="900" data-orig-width="1440" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/geYQB32.gif"&gt;&lt;img src="https://64.media.tumblr.com/5741f4e045528b1ad83f0f9f1d2f20b7/tumblr_inline_p7lffkOV4Z1srua81_540.gif" data-orig-height="900" data-orig-width="1440" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/geYQB32.gif"/&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;i&gt;“There is no such thing as information overload. There is only bad design.”&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
-Edward Tufte
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;4. &lt;a href="https://plot.ly/dashboard/Dreamshot:9033/present" target="_blank"&gt;Vibrant Report&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;figure class="tmblr-full" data-orig-height="823" data-orig-width="540" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/9cZ14tK.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://64.media.tumblr.com/604ae39e846a2a3796152dfc74fb770a/tumblr_inline_p7lffoi9WI1srua81_540.png" data-orig-height="823" data-orig-width="540" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/9cZ14tK.png"/&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;i&gt;“Never underestimate your audience. It’s the most common mistake made by presenters. It is not about you anymore. It’s about your audience’s relationship with your content.”&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
-Edward Tufte
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;5. &lt;a href="https://plot.ly/~Dreamshot/9025/minimalist-presentation/#/?_k=2c8s6w" target="_blank"&gt;Minimalist Slide Deck&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;figure class="tmblr-full" data-orig-height="900" data-orig-width="1440" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/VrLdsu3.gif"&gt;&lt;img src="https://64.media.tumblr.com/5b6d8d111ccd9356ec0a5bae1562affc/tumblr_inline_p7lffpZMgW1srua81_540.gif" data-orig-height="900" data-orig-width="1440" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/VrLdsu3.gif"/&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;i&gt;“Zero out your interface.”&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
-Edward Tufte
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;6. &lt;a href="https://plot.ly/dashboard/Dreamshot:9032/present" target="_blank"&gt;Minimalist Report&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;figure class="tmblr-full" data-orig-height="823" data-orig-width="540" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/o8RyQBg.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://64.media.tumblr.com/d35972b8ff543d3f01b09144d1aa5b60/tumblr_inline_p7lffpQn6h1srua81_540.png" data-orig-height="823" data-orig-width="540" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/o8RyQBg.png"/&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;i&gt;“There are two goals when presenting data: convey your story and establish credibility.”&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
-Edward Tufte
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
By way of Plotly’s &lt;a href="https://plot.ly/online-presentation-tool/" target="_blank"&gt;Slide Deck&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://plot.ly/dashboards-and-reports/" target="_blank"&gt;Dashboard &amp;amp; Reporting&lt;/a&gt; features, you can present your data in both an enriching and aesthetically pleasing manner. Long gone are the days of worrying about whether your flash drive is going to work or if the computer is Windows or Mac — Plotly, and your graphs, slide decks, and dashboards, all exist in the cloud.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
And if folks want a copy of your work afterword? Easy. Send online slide decks with interactive charts to your team, stakeholders, or customers.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Plotly gives you the tools and examples to make beautiful dashboards and reports, even if you’re not trained in design. If you’re still not convinced, &lt;a href="ttps://plot.ly/products/consulting-and-oem/" target="_blank"&gt;we’d love to chat&lt;/a&gt;.</description><link>https://blog.plotly.com/post/168250236207</link><guid>https://blog.plotly.com/post/168250236207</guid><pubDate>Wed, 06 Dec 2017 04:18:47 -0500</pubDate><category>Presentation</category><category>dataviz</category><category>data science</category><category>data analysis</category><category>data</category></item><item><title>Assessing Global Health, One 📈 at a Time</title><description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="http://www.healthdata.org/" target="_blank"&gt;Institute for Health Metrics and Evaluation website&lt;/a&gt; is a treasure trove of data. On a semi-regular basis, the institute publishes &lt;a href="http://www.healthdata.org/results/data-visualizations" target="_blank"&gt;data visualizations&lt;/a&gt; using the daily freely available on the website.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
While the data is “freely available” on the charts, most of it isn’t downloadable or “unlocked” as such. By re-plotting it in Plotly, we “free the data,” so to speak, opening it up to future investigation as other users can easily download it, play with it, and explore it.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
In this post, we present five charts that speak volumes about the state of health around the globe, examining in particular key areas such as healthy life expectancy, the prevalence of overweight adults, smoking prevalence, high-risk drinking prevalence, and deaths in the United States.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Plotly graphs are now embeddable in Medium, as demonstrated below. To learn how to embed can’t-miss Plotly graphs in Medium, check out our &lt;a href="https://medium.com/@plotlygraphs/seven-of-the-sexiest-graphs-ever-created-in-plotly-5808a6a9c1be" target="_blank"&gt;how-to post&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Make sure your Plotly graphs look as sharp on your desktop computer as they do on your mobile device &amp;ndash; our &lt;a href="https://medium.com/@plotlygraphs/creating-crisp-charts-for-mobile-c8266895c01" target="_blank"&gt;post on mobile charts&lt;/a&gt; has the details.
&lt;!-- more --&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;1. &lt;a href="https://plot.ly/~Dreamshot/8917/" target="_blank"&gt;Healthy Life Expectancy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;figure class="tmblr-full" data-orig-height="600" data-orig-width="1100" data-orig-src="http://i.imgur.com/RQYhcT6.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://64.media.tumblr.com/967cea2e26801e9a91d76fc06160a22f/tumblr_inline_p7lffgmds91srua81_540.png" data-orig-height="600" data-orig-width="1100" data-orig-src="http://i.imgur.com/RQYhcT6.png"/&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Did you know? With an average healthy life expectancy (HLE) of nearly 74 years, &lt;a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC4130084/" target="_blank"&gt;Japan leads the world&lt;/a&gt;. On the flip side, the Kingdom of Lesotho, a &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lesotho" target="_blank"&gt;landlocked country in southern Africa&lt;/a&gt;, holds the distinction for having the globe’s lowest average HLE at 41.19 years.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Iceland has the 2nd highest average HLE at 72.95 years and the Central African Republic the 2nd lowest at 43.19 years.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;2. &lt;a href="https://plot.ly/%7EDreamshot/8916/" target="_blank"&gt;The Prevalence of Overweight Adults&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;figure class="tmblr-full" data-orig-height="500" data-orig-width="700" data-orig-src="http://i.imgur.com/ohicBQ2.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://64.media.tumblr.com/3f5d4ca5acfacd7a57172ac7b4f123e6/tumblr_inline_p7lffhXOjn1srua81_540.png" data-orig-height="500" data-orig-width="700" data-orig-src="http://i.imgur.com/ohicBQ2.png"/&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Kuwait holds the distinction of having the highest prevalence (79%) of overweight adults in the world (BMI ≥ 25 for adults aged 20+). The overweight and obesity epidemic has been investigated in this &lt;a href="http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/ijpo.12090/abstract" target="_blank"&gt;journal article&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Despite this, Kuwait sports a fairly average HLE of 69.56 years.
Egypt also has a near-global high prevalence of overweight adults at 70.9%. Perhaps this high value can be attributed to a high carbohydrate and calorie diet, as speculated about by &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2016/oct/07/egypt-obesity-battle-calories-overweight" target="_blank"&gt;The Guardian&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
To the contrary, &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Burundi" target="_blank"&gt;Burundi&lt;/a&gt; in south central Africa, has the lowest prevalence of overweight adults at 6.3%.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;2a. &lt;a href="https://plot.ly/~Dreamshot/8924/" target="_blank"&gt;The Prevalence of Overweight Adults vs Healthy Life Expectancy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;figure class="tmblr-full" data-orig-height="500" data-orig-width="700" data-orig-src="http://i.imgur.com/ToCjgDA.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://64.media.tumblr.com/b853b646525efb61ef40363e0aa3574b/tumblr_inline_p7lffhQvym1srua81_540.png" data-orig-height="500" data-orig-width="700" data-orig-src="http://i.imgur.com/ToCjgDA.png"/&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;China and the U.S. have very nearly the same HLE, but being overweight is 38% more prevalent in the states. Meanwhile, the Philippines has an overweight prevalence of 26.9% but an HLE of just 62.05 years.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
HLE is likely more closely linked to things like local conditions, reliable access to healthcare, and nutrition than it is to being overweight.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;3. &lt;a href="https://plot.ly/~Dreamshot/8921/" target="_blank"&gt;Daily Smoking Prevalence&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;figure class="tmblr-full" data-orig-height="650" data-orig-width="1100" data-orig-src="http://i.imgur.com/y7Wp5dZ.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://64.media.tumblr.com/0505da29cd51d821d6d17383d9f6401d/tumblr_inline_p7lffi1sFj1srua81_540.png" data-orig-height="650" data-orig-width="1100" data-orig-src="http://i.imgur.com/y7Wp5dZ.png"/&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
At 45.6%, &lt;a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC3748435/" target="_blank"&gt;Greenland&lt;/a&gt; has the highest prevalence of smokers in the world. 14% less prevalent than Greenland, Macedonia has the second most smokers.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Meanwhile, smoking is least prevalent in Panama, with only 3.5% of the population identifying as smokers. &lt;a href="http://www.tobaccoatlas.org/country-data/panama/" target="_blank"&gt;A smoker in Panama&lt;/a&gt; would have to spend 13.1% the of national median income to purchase 10 of the cheapest cigarettes to smoke each day.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;3a. &lt;a href="https://plot.ly/~Dreamshot/8922/" target="_blank"&gt;Daily Smoking Prevalence vs Healthy Life Expectancy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;figure class="tmblr-full" data-orig-height="650" data-orig-width="1100" data-orig-src="http://i.imgur.com/vnxSwAH.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://64.media.tumblr.com/8fafa82678cd2383736c7c9e78996256/tumblr_inline_p7lffjQtaz1srua81_540.png" data-orig-height="650" data-orig-width="1100" data-orig-src="http://i.imgur.com/vnxSwAH.png"/&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
India has a daily smoking prevalence of 9.8% while Greece is sky high at 31.2%. Despite this, India has an HLE of 58.12 years and Greece 71.13.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;4. &lt;a href="https://plot.ly/%7EDreamshot/8920/" target="_blank"&gt;High Risk Alcohol Consumption&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;figure class="tmblr-full" data-orig-height="600" data-orig-width="1100" data-orig-src="http://i.imgur.com/OCWn3D6.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://64.media.tumblr.com/0ba28dd49c458e2800bf89db4cae78a7/tumblr_inline_p7lffjt8FP1srua81_540.png" data-orig-height="600" data-orig-width="1100" data-orig-src="http://i.imgur.com/OCWn3D6.png"/&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Belarus in Eastern Europe is home to the world’s heaviest drinkers. High risk alcohol consumption is pegged at 28.7%. It is speculated that &lt;a href="http://belarusdigest.com/story/who-belarusians-are-heaviest-drinkers-world-17958" target="_blank"&gt;80% of murders and grave injuries&lt;/a&gt; in Belarus are committed under the influence of alcohol. Only 11% of Belarusians completely abstain from alcohol.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Mauritania in western Africa has the distinction of having the least prevalent amount of high-risk drinkers — this is because it is a dry country.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;4a. &lt;a href="https://plot.ly/~Dreamshot/8923/" target="_blank"&gt;High Risk Alcohol Consumption vs Healthy Life Expectancy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;figure class="tmblr-full" data-orig-height="650" data-orig-width="1100" data-orig-src="http://i.imgur.com/uB2BQqb.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://64.media.tumblr.com/f61a84a4be48f99e4b4aac8e2fd3ef45/tumblr_inline_p7lffjnFiC1srua81_540.png" data-orig-height="650" data-orig-width="1100" data-orig-src="http://i.imgur.com/uB2BQqb.png"/&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
It likely isn’t a coincidence that the three countries where high risk drinking is most prevalent (Russia, Ukraine, Belarus) are not setting healthy life expectancy records.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;5. &lt;a href="https://plot.ly/%7EDreamshot/8714/" target="_blank"&gt;Deaths by State&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;figure class="tmblr-full" data-orig-height="500" data-orig-width="700" data-orig-src="http://i.imgur.com/mBKT8tX.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://64.media.tumblr.com/daee64b81afcc7539ae31b5260bcdfc9/tumblr_inline_p7lffjpmuj1srua81_540.png" data-orig-height="500" data-orig-width="700" data-orig-src="http://i.imgur.com/mBKT8tX.png"/&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Prevalence of all-cause death in the U.S. is highest across the mid-south, Southeast, and Appalachia. It is interesting that the region is well aligned with the CDC-identified diabetes belt. Within the &lt;a href="https://www.cdc.gov/diabetes/pdfs/data/diabetesbelt.pdf" target="_blank"&gt;diabetes belt&lt;/a&gt;, 11.7% of the people have diagnosed diabetes. Outside the belt, 8.5% have diagnosed diabetes.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;6. &lt;a href="https://plot.ly/dashboard/Dreamshot:8925/present" target="_blank"&gt;Crossfilter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;figure class="tmblr-full" data-orig-height="791" data-orig-width="1438" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/g8FVvaC.gif"&gt;&lt;img src="https://64.media.tumblr.com/c822940b80fbadc982e4fabea4100828/tumblr_inline_p7lffk6R3S1srua81_540.gif" data-orig-height="791" data-orig-width="1438" data-orig-src="https://i.imgur.com/g8FVvaC.gif"/&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Crossfilter is a visual analysis technique for multidimensional data that can help clarify correlations between dimensions.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
To use crossfilter, simply click-and-drag on any of the charts and maps in this report. Data sharing common rows between the charts will highlight in red, helping pinpoint complex relationships between various health indicators and location on the globe.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
You can &lt;a href="https://plot.ly/dashboard/jackp:18099/view" target="_blank"&gt;learn more about Crossfilter&lt;/a&gt; and try it for yourself &lt;a href="https://plot.ly/dashboard/Dreamshot:8925/present" target="_blank"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Plotly is built by computational scientists with degrees and research expertise from McGill, Harvard, Stanford, and other world-class institutions. Making no-compromise open-source software for scientific visualization is our full-time job and passion. Want to support our work? Consider purchasing a Pro plan. For less than half the cost of a Tableau license, you’ll get support from our engineering staff and time-saving ways to save and share your work with colleagues, advisors, or managers.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://plot.ly/education/" target="_blank"&gt;Pro Plans for University students and instructors ($59/year)&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://plot.ly/products/cloud/" target="_blank"&gt;Pro Plans for industry users ($396/year)&lt;/a&gt;</description><link>https://blog.plotly.com/post/167009132857</link><guid>https://blog.plotly.com/post/167009132857</guid><pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 05:49:50 -0400</pubDate><category>health</category><category>smoking</category><category>drinking</category><category>stats</category><category>data</category><category>plotly</category></item><item><title>🤖 might just be your next co-worker</title><description>&lt;p&gt;1.8 million robots were in operation globally during 2015 according the the International Federation of Robotics, a number that is forecast to balloon to 2.6 million in the year 2019.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
While these “automatically controlled, reprogrammable machines” may not make workers in certain industries immediately redundant, the data show that robotic penetration is trending upward. The consequences of this leap in technology loom large for the worker.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/IR51p5u.jpg"/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;i&gt;Baxter is the flagship product built by Rethink Robotics and is billed as America’s first adaptive manufacturing robot. Source: &lt;a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/business/technology/new-robots-in-the-workplace-job-creators-or-job-terminators/2013/03/06/a80b8f34-746c-11e2-8f84-3e4b513b1a13_story.html?utm_term=.4066b21eb973" target="_blank"&gt;The Washington Post&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Later in 2017, the Brookings Metro program is expected to release a new state and metro mapping of where the effects of automation may be most disruptive, using some high-quality estimates of the susceptibility of occupations to substitution.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
For an opinion on the impact of robots, artificial intelligence, and machine learning, give Brookings’ Darrel M West’s &lt;a href="https://www.brookings.edu/wp-content/uploads/2016/06/robotwork.pdf" target="_blank"&gt;piece&lt;/a&gt; a read.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
In the meantime, we explore data from the &lt;a href="https://ifr.org/" target="_blank"&gt;International Federation of Robots&lt;/a&gt; (some made available by &lt;a href="https://www.brookings.edu/blog/the-avenue/2017/08/14/where-the-robots-are/" target="_blank"&gt;Brookings&lt;/a&gt;) showing where robot have so far made their significant impression.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
As you’ll learn below, their incidence is well-aligned with the United States’ highly automated advanced manufacturing sector.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;!-- more --&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;1. &lt;a href="https://plot.ly/~Dreamshot/8936/" target="_blank"&gt;Where the robots are&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/o4dwSH2.png"/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Michigan had the most industrial robots in 2015, with over 27,600 in operation. In fact, the high bot concentration across the Upper Midwest and Mid-South aligns well with the automotive industry which employs about half of all industrial robots in use (see Robots by industry below). Hawaii (83) edged out Wyoming (84) for the fewest industrial robots in 2015.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;2. &lt;a href="https://plot.ly/~Dreamshot/8937/" target="_blank"&gt;Robotic trends&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/LBPtqTk.png"/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Industrial robot use is increasing most quickly where it is already prevalent. Between 2010 and 2015, Michigan amassed over 16,700 new bots. Ohio (11,900) and Indiana (11,400) are a distant 2nd and 3rd, respectively. California is an honorable mention with nearly a 10,200-bot increase. Wyoming added a paltry 30 bots between 2010 and 2015.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;3. &lt;a href="https://plot.ly/~Dreamshot/8946/" target="_blank"&gt;Where a robot is most likely to be your colleague&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/XxdfE2S.png"/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
The Elkhart-Goshen Metropolitan Statistical Area was the epicenter of robotic activity in 2015, where for every 1,000 workers was 35.9 bots. Here’s a little known fact about the area:
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
“Elkhart is best known for two industries: recreational vehicles and musical instruments. It has been referenced as the “RV Capital of the World” and the “Band Instrument Capital of the World” for decades.” 🤖
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Thus, the clustering across the Upper Midwest makes a lot of sense.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
But what about the South? Take east Tennessee for instance, Morristown &amp;ndash; here, 3 of the top 4 employers fit the employ-a-robot mold: poultry processing (Koch Foods), aluminum piston manufacturing (MAHLE Engine Components), and power steering systems (JTEKT Automotive).
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;4. &lt;a href="https://plot.ly/~Dreamshot/8947/" target="_blank"&gt;“Robot-as-a-colleague” trends&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/OtR5tR7.png"/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
The largest annualized percentage change of total industrial robots between 2010 and 2015 was found in northwest Alabama. In Florence-Muscle Shoals, AL, specifically, where the increase was a dramatic 45% during the 5-year period. A diverse manufacturing center, this NW Alabama region calls manufacturing its &lt;a href="http://advantagealabama.com/county/077/lauderdale/edpa-advantage-alabama-county.html" target="_blank"&gt;2nd largest industry&lt;/a&gt; by payroll.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Chambersburg in central Pennsylvania is another up and coming bot-center. Here, manufacturing facilities are common and include machinery production, metal fabrication, and food processing.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;5. &lt;a href="https://plot.ly/~Dreamshot/8941/" target="_blank"&gt;Robots by industry&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/D3XfQh9.png"/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Approximately 62% of the globe’s estimated operational stock of robots were found in the automotive industry in 2015. Between 2010 and 2015, the electronics industry experienced the largest percentage gain (135%) in operational robot use.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;6. &lt;a href="https://plot.ly/~Dreamshot/8939/" target="_blank"&gt;Global robot stock increasing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/JP9Ukte.png"/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
By 2019, the world is estimated to have 2.6 million robots in operation. This would be well over two-fold decade-over-decade increase and over a three-fold increase since the turn of the century.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;7. &lt;a href="https://plot.ly/~Dreamshot/8951/" target="_blank"&gt;Who’s winning the race?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/7lztEzk.png"/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
The Republic of Korea, as of 2015, lead the world with 531 robots per 10,000 employees in the manufacturing industry.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
However, robots in South Korea aren’t just limited to one industry&amp;ndash;recently, they were commissioned to aid tourists and &lt;a href="http://www.ctvnews.ca/sci-tech/robots-to-aid-tourists-and-clean-floors-at-south-korean-airport-1.3487697" target="_blank"&gt;clean the floors&lt;/a&gt; at Incheon International Airport.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/QtlM7lb.jpg"/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;i&gt;Troika, a self-driving robot made by LG Electronics, at Incheon International Airport in South Korea.&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Singapore, 2nd in the global robot race, is home to &lt;a href="http://www.straitstimes.com/singapore/asias-first-retail-robot-launched-to-help-relieve-manpower-shortages" target="_blank"&gt;Asia’s first retail bot&lt;/a&gt; ‘XYZrobot,’ who will greet and help customers at electronics shop Newstead.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
In conclusion: robots are here to stay. With an open mind, we’ll be able adapt to a world that includes more of them. And perhaps with a touch of ingenuity, we’ll be better off because of it.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;i&gt;&amp;ldquo;I think while the technology kills the jobs we don’t want, it creates this opening to find new ways to deploy people that we’ve never thought of before. And I think that’s an exciting opportunity. We have so many human issues that we can’t deal with, and those aren’t jobs today. I think there’s all kinds of redeployment that’s good for the human race when we think it through.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&amp;ndash;Jeff Hoffman, Co-Founder of Priceline.com
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Plotly is built by computational scientists with degrees and research expertise from McGill, Harvard, Stanford, and other world-class institutions. Making no-compromise open-source software for scientific visualization is our full-time job and passion. Want to support our work? Consider purchasing a Pro plan. For less than half the cost of a Tableau license, you’ll get support from our engineering staff and time-saving ways to save and share your work with colleagues, advisors, or managers.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://plot.ly/education/" target="_blank"&gt;Pro Plans for University students and instructors ($59/year)&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://plot.ly/products/cloud/" target="_blank"&gt;Pro Plans for industry users ($396/year)&lt;/a&gt;</description><link>https://blog.plotly.com/post/165493522252</link><guid>https://blog.plotly.com/post/165493522252</guid><pubDate>Mon, 18 Sep 2017 21:08:47 -0400</pubDate><category>robots</category><category>technology</category><category>manufacturing</category><category>robotics</category><category>brookings</category><category>data</category><category>datascience</category></item><item><title>Creating Crisp Graphs for Mobile</title><description>&lt;p&gt;According to comScore’s &lt;a href="https://www.comscore.com/Insights/Presentations-and-Whitepapers/2017/2017-US-Cross-Platform-Future-in-Focus" target="_blank"&gt;2017 U.S. Cross-Platform Future in Focus&lt;/a&gt;, as of December 2016, 69% of digital media is consumed via a smartphone or tablet, with the remaining 31% going to desktop computers.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
This is in stark contrast to data from late 2013, when the smartphone/tablet vs desktop media consumption battle was very nearly 50%/50%.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;a href="https://plot.ly/~Dreamshot/8706/" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/Jd5T6es.png" alt="Digital_Media_Growth"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Amidst the height of the digital age, sharp mobile graphics are more critical than ever.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
So the next time you’re building a Plotly masterpiece, consider using our new “mobile” graph feature. It’s super easy and will ensure that your graphs look as fly on mobile as they will on the 100 inch big screen.
&lt;!-- more --&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What You Don’t Want Your Graph to Look Like&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
While the above graph looks fantastic on a laptop or desktop, that’s just a small segment of the potential viewers. Without being touched up using Plotly’s mobile tool, the graph looks about as bad as Donald’s decisions around global warming. Okay, maybe not that bad, but check this out:
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/CLYKRG1.png" alt="bad_example"/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
But no stress, because in a few screenshots we’ll show you how to finesse that mess into something that’s sure to impress…
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/LTyWB1w.png" alt="good_example"/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;1. Under the style dropdown, select “Mobile.”&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/nUxqolE.png" alt=""/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;2. In the “Mobile” menu, select “add a view.”&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/2kuQoyh.png" alt=""/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;3. Within your “new (mobile) view,” change the max width. Bear in mind that most mobile devices have a width of 480px or less.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/Iaq37Pj.png" alt=""/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;4. Under the style dropdown, select “Layout” then “Canvas.” Make sure your canvas size is set to “Custom” and that your view is “View 1.” Then, change the width of your graph to the same size that you specified in step 3.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/6trsxSR.png" alt=""/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;5. You’ll notice that our previously added notes look horrid. For crisp graphs on mobile, get rid of them.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/ljCQzyM.png" alt=""/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;6. Back in the “Layout” menu now, we’ve changed the “title and fonts” size. We’ve also erased or significantly shortened our axis labels.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/HAfuAkL.png" alt=""/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;7. You can adjust the “Margins and Padding” to best suit your graph. Typically, 50–50–25–25–0 looks the best on mobile, as pictured below.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/hvEVbzF.png" alt=""/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;8. You’re done. Look how sharp the mobile version looks now, along with an equally sharp desktop version.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/E1Ubh8i.gif" alt=""/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
But what happens if you tilt your mobile device horizontally to get a better view of a graph?
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Watch how responsive Plotly graphs are to such a change 🔮
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/Y05TP8y.gif" alt=""/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Plotly is built by computational scientists with degrees and research expertise from McGill, Harvard, Stanford, and other world-class institutions. Making no-compromise open-source software for scientific visualization is our full-time job and passion. Want to support our work? Consider purchasing a Pro plan. For less than half the cost of a Tableau license, you’ll get support from our engineering staff and time-saving ways to save and share your work with colleagues, advisors, or managers.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Pro Plans for University students and instructors ($59/year)
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Pro Plans for industry users ($396/year)</description><link>https://blog.plotly.com/post/162041235517</link><guid>https://blog.plotly.com/post/162041235517</guid><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jun 2017 06:43:06 -0400</pubDate><category>data</category><category>dataviz</category><category>datascience</category><category>mobile</category><category>media</category></item><item><title>Data Bites: 7 TV Shows that Jumped the Shark</title><description>&lt;p&gt;There is a fine line between keeping your viewers interested, intrigued, and emotionally invested and crossing the line with a stunt whose main purpose is to spark their waning interest.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
If a television series has pulled off the latter, it is (at best) fighting an uphill battle and, at worst, on its way off the air.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
These critical junctures occur frequently in the world of TV entertainment, but the moment when a television show attempts to draw attention to or create publicity for something that is perceived as not warranting the attention it is known as “jumping the shark.”
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Furthermore, the idiom typically refers to something that is past its peak in quality or relevance and popularity.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
In this post, we sift through seasons’ worth of IMDB ratings for various shows that supposedly “jumped the shark,” including &lt;a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0063878/" target="_blank"&gt;The Brady Bunch&lt;/a&gt; (1969–1974), &lt;a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0411008/" target="_blank"&gt;Lost&lt;/a&gt; (2004–2010), &lt;a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0455275/" target="_blank"&gt;Prison Break&lt;/a&gt; (2005–2009), &lt;a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0088571/" target="_blank"&gt;Moonlighting&lt;/a&gt; (1985–1989), &lt;a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0106179/" target="_blank"&gt;The X Files&lt;/a&gt; (1993-present), &lt;a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0773262/" target="_blank"&gt;Dexter&lt;/a&gt; (2006–2013), and &lt;a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0386676/" target="_blank"&gt;The Office&lt;/a&gt; (2005–2013).
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Motivation for this post stems from articles on TheRichest, RollingStone, and SCREENRANT about TV shows that may have jumped the shark.
&lt;!-- more --&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
The graphs below all feature an image to help identify the TV show. Check out how easy it is to add an image to a graph in Plotly:
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/JXIhdrv.gif" alt="Image"/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Learn how to add images to your charts in &lt;a href="https://plot.ly/python/logos/" target="_blank"&gt;Python&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://plot.ly/r/logos/" target="_blank"&gt;R&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h1&gt;1. The Brady Bunch&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;a href="https://plot.ly/~Dreamshot/8656/" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/aEAWGvT.png" alt="The_Brady_Bunch"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Here’s what &lt;a href="http://www.therichest.com/expensive-lifestyle/entertainment/10-shocking-examples-of-tv-shows-jumping-the-shark/" target="_blank"&gt;TheRichest&lt;/a&gt; had to say about The Brady Bunch and its rating fallout:
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;i&gt;During the fifth season, Cousin Oliver was brought in as a member of the family. It was seen as such a big shark-jumping moment that it even caused a new term to be coined. “Cousin Oliver Syndrome” is known as what happens when a show brings in a new character to re-attract fans, and the gimmick didn’t pay off: after just six episodes, Cousin Oliver was removed from the show.&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h1&gt;2. Lost&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;a href="https://plot.ly/~Dreamshot/8650/" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/7V6jvpp.png" alt="Lost"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Lost is an interesting case. The rating trend a flat line through the whole series, but still the show is considered a shark jumper by &lt;a href="http://www.rollingstone.com/tv/lists/jumping-the-shark-20141002/lost-20141002" target="_blank"&gt;RollingStone&lt;/a&gt;:
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;i&gt;No one agrees when exactly Lost lost its mojo, because there is no one JTS moment that stands above the rest. Was it when the survivors met the Others and they didn’t make any sense? Or when the infamously annoying Nikki and Paulo materialized on the scene? Or when Claire got amnesia? Or when the Island traveled back in time? Or when Locke was resurrected? Or when it turned out that all the evil in the world was being held back by a literal cork? Or when… The point is, Lost disappointed us at least as many times as it bowled us over.&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h1&gt;3. Prison Break&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;a href="https://plot.ly/~Dreamshot/8646/" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/IqhhEDQ.png" alt="Prison_Break"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Prison Break exhibited a steep decline in show ratings over the course of its 4 season run. &lt;a href="http://screenrant.com/best-tv-shows-series-jumped-shark/" target="_blank"&gt;SCREENRANT&lt;/a&gt; declared it a shark jumper:
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;i&gt;Another high-concept show of the 2000s, Prison Break was another instant hit. The story of the two brothers, one sentenced to death for a crime he did not commit, and the other who devises an elaborate plan to help his brother escape prison and clear his name drew in big audiences. At the end of the first season, the brothers, along with several others, escape in a tunnel dug beneath the walls of the prison.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
The second season followed a very different format and met with mixed reactions. Some praised the change in direction, feeling that they couldn’t stay in the prison forever. Others felt that the show had become too different to the original formula and had become a show about fugitives as opposed to prisoners. At the end of season 2, several prisoners were recaptured and imprisoned in Panama.
Despite running for a further 2 seasons, most viewers agreed that the show declined in quality sometime during season 2.&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h1&gt;4. Moonlighting&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;a href="https://plot.ly/~Dreamshot/8648/" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/u8PGDWS.png" alt="Moonlighting"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;i&gt;Moonlighting was the definitive will-they-won’t-they show, with most of the attention being given to the chemistry between co-stars Bruce Willis and Cybill Sheppard. The show was a mixture of drama, comedy, and romance, and was considered to be one of the first successful examples of comedy-drama, or “dramedy.”
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Despite being a massive hit, once the two leads entered into a relationship, the show was in trouble. While the investigations of the private detective agency had been central to the show, along with successful gimmicks such as their “breaking the fourth wall,” the main audience draw was waiting for the couple to give in to the sexual chemistry between them.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
When the couple finally got together in season 3, there were behind the scenes complications which added to the shows problems. Cybill Sheppard was off having twins, so they had to shoot her scenes in advance, causing much fewer scenes with her and Bruce Willis. Also, Willis was making Die Hard. When that was a massive success, his interest in making a weekly show waned, due to his blooming movie career.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
-&lt;a href="http://screenrant.com/best-tv-shows-series-jumped-shark/" target="_blank"&gt;SCREENRANT&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h1&gt;5. The X Files&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;a href="https://plot.ly/~Dreamshot/8654/" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/5NOqheF.png" alt="X_Files"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;i&gt;In a way, the fact that this show named one of their episodes “Jump the Shark” says it all. If you have to name an episode of your show that, it’s a pretty big example of self-realization. You could use several episodes as examples as to how The X-Files tried desperately to regain the luster it once had, but the most obvious ones are probably through their first movie in 1998, or the episode where Mulder leaves following the seventh season. To break up one of the most distinctive pairings on TV is a bold move, and one that didn’t exactly pay off the way The X-Files’ producers had hoped.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
-&lt;a href="http://www.therichest.com/expensive-lifestyle/entertainment/10-shocking-examples-of-tv-shows-jumping-the-shark/" target="_blank"&gt;TheRichest&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h1&gt;6. Dexter&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;a href="https://plot.ly/~Dreamshot/8658/" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/QI3V7lN.png" alt="Dexter"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;Au revoir, unholy Trinity (Season 4, Episode 12)&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Facile argument: Dexter was ruined the moment its second season revealed itself, early on, as a weak re-brew of everything those first 12 episodes had so beautifully concocted. (Kill, cover-up, stalk worse killer, rinse, repeat.) But the true shark-leap was the moment that distinguished gentleman actor John Lithgow was knocked off at the end of Season Four. Many memorable stars came and went in Showtime’s serial-murderer drama, but in his single-season run as the Trinity Killer, Lithgow repeatedly stole the show — and then was forced to vacate it (at the same time as some crucial co-stars), leaving a huge void in his wake. You knew it was coming, yet the series never really recovered from the loss, and only worsened in its damnably formulaic approach as it bled out over four more long seasons.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
-&lt;a href="http://www.rollingstone.com/tv/lists/jumping-the-shark-20141002/dexter-20141002" target="_blank"&gt;RollingStone&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h1&gt;7. The Office&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;a href="https://plot.ly/~Dreamshot/8662/" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/CzXpPjj.png" alt="The_Office"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;Jim and Pam tie the knot (Season 6, Episode 4)&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
In its heyday, Greg Daniels’s mockumentary sitcom was one of the best comedies on television, balancing cringe comedy and sweet-natured character studies. But that perfect blend began to sour around the same time as those crazy kids Jim and Pam finally got hitched; they consequently morphed into being annoying jerks, and we lost our audience surrogates into this world of socially delayed salesmen and bumbling accountants. The stakes became so low that the show had to start jumping through hoops, and the cringe humor became just plain cringeworthy. By the time the show’s boss Michael Scott (and Steve Carell) departed for greener pastures, The Office was already a shell of its former self.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
-&lt;a href="http://www.rollingstone.com/tv/lists/jumping-the-shark-20141002/dexter-20141002" target="_blank"&gt;RollingStone&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
An example of a show that never jumped the shark:
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;Bates Motel&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
A recently completed series, Bates Motel, is a prime example of a show that brought just the right amount of suspense and surprise without doing the shark jump. The ratings below speak for themselves.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;a href="https://plot.ly/~Dreamshot/8664/" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/xVDfF77.png" alt="Bates_Motel"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Plotly is built by computational scientists with degrees and research expertise from McGill, Harvard, Stanford, and other world-class institutions. Making no-compromise open-source software for scientific visualization is our full-time job and passion. Want to support our work? Consider purchasing a Pro plan. For less than half the cost of a Tableau license, you’ll get support from our engineering staff and time-saving ways to save and share your work with colleagues, advisors, or managers.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://plot.ly/education/" target="_blank"&gt;Pro Plans for University students and instructors ($59/year)&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://plot.ly/products/cloud/" target="_blank"&gt;Pro Plans for industry users ($396/year)&lt;/a&gt;</description><link>https://blog.plotly.com/post/161089856647</link><guid>https://blog.plotly.com/post/161089856647</guid><pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2017 06:46:08 -0400</pubDate><category>television</category><category>media</category><category>popculture</category><category>data</category><category>datascience</category><category>datavisualization</category></item><item><title>Taking the World’s Pulse on Climate Change</title><description>&lt;p&gt;As a meteorologist who doubles as a blogger and content creator for Plotly, I’m naturally drawn to data that deals with the atmosphere, both in the space of weather and climate.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
A brief introduction: I’m Ben Noll (&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/BenNollWeather" target="_blank"&gt;https://twitter.com/BenNollWeather&lt;/a&gt;), a meteorologist for the National Institute of Water and Atmospheric Research in New Zealand. I routinely make short-term weather forecasts (minutes to weeks) and climate projections (seasonal to annual time scales).
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
The weather is something that never goes out of style: it affects all of us every day, in one way or another. You may not think of it much during the long stretches of dry and sunny weather during the summer and autumn — but when you get an unexpected 10 minute shower during your picnic, curse the weatherman!
&lt;!-- more --&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
I get it. It comes with the territory. But I assure you: weather (and climate) forecasting is far more accurate than it was even 10 years ago. We’ve come a long way. But as with all crafts, we have room to improve, particularly when it comes to communication (of extremes).
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;a href="https://plot.ly/~Dreamshot/8302/model-skill-northern-hemisphere-500-hpa-day-5-30-day-running-mean/" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/hecSDXg.png" alt="Model_Skill"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
The plot above shows something called anomaly correlation — just a fancy phrase that implies weather model skill — for the world’s three most accurate weather models. It may seem a bit noisy, but here’s the takeaway: since the start of the time series (2010), all three models have a positive (skill) trendline.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
When Yale recently released its Climate Opinion Maps describing the “geographic variation in opinions on climate change at state and local scales in the USA,” I felt it would be an ideal creative outlet and also a chance to make some killer content for Plotly.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
At the same time, I thought it would be an excellent opportunity to share some projections for later in 2017 and how it might affect the Earth’s weather, climate and you.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h1&gt;What is Climate Change and Global Warming?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Climate change, according to NASA, is a change in the typical or average weather of a region or city and/or Earth. Not only is this phrase associated with a warming Earth, but also changing precipitation patterns, sea levels, sea ice, and more.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
One of the largest components of our changing climate is global warming, or referring to surface temperature increases from both natural (El Niño) and anthropogenic (greenhouse gases) causes. There’s no denying that we live on a warming Earth. Land temperatures are modulated by sea temperatures, which are also rising. Both are being influenced by carbon pollution, which continues to break records year after year. The monthly average carbon dioxide concentration for March 2017 was 407 parts per million (ppm).
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;a href="https://plot.ly/~Dreamshot/2050/temperature-global-ocean-heat-content-atmospheric-co-2-global-surface-temperatur/" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/f8gHI34.png" alt="Climate_Change"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Seven in ten Americans think global warming is occurring. One in ten does not.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;a href="https://plot.ly/~Dreamshot/8613/do-you-think-global-warming-is-happening/" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/SY6mOAH.png" alt="Is_Global_Warming_Occurring"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Are human activities the main cause?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
There’s no denying the distinctive, positive relationship between global temperatures and atmospheric carbon dioxide concentration. Some individuals that are not in favor of anthropogenic climate change refer to warming oceans as the guiding hand for increased global temperatures. Warming oceans certainly play a large role, but it begs the question: why are ocean temperatures warming?
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
While the Earth’s climate has exhibited marked “natural” changes, with time scales varying from many millions of years down to a few years, the recent warming is most likely attributable to carbon pollution. Furthermore, El Niño events, which I’ll cover in more detail further down, are associated with semi-permanent upward steps in global temperatures, initially caused by a warming of sea surface temperatures in the eastern and central equatorial Pacific Ocean. Research has shown that El Niño events may be increasing in frequency due to human-induced climate change.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
States that are most convinced that global warming is caused by human activities:
&lt;br/&gt;
California (59%)
Maryland (58%)
New York (58%)
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
States that are least convinced that global warming is caused by human activities:
&lt;br/&gt;
Wyoming (42%)
Utah (43%)
West Virginia (44%)
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;a href="https://plot.ly/~Dreamshot/8595/global-warming-is-caused-mostly-by-human-activities/" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/r5ryCSK.png" alt="Is_Global_Warming_Caused_By_Humans"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Is global warming harming you now or will it within the next 10 years (from 2016)?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
A question posed in the Yale survey, residents of New York (57%), California (56%), and Maryland (55%) had the most bullish opinion in the “yes” direction. On the other hand, North Dakota (39%), Wyoming (39%), and West Virginia (40%) weren’t as convinced.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;a href="https://plot.ly/~Dreamshot/8597/global-warming-is-already-harming-people-in-the-us-now-or-within-10-years-2016/" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/icKZeNU.png" alt="Is_Global_Warming_Harming_Humans"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
While no one weather event is caused by climate change, all events are influenced by climate change since the atmosphere is now warmer and moister than it was in the past. Climate change increases the likelihood of extreme rainfall, given the appropriate weather setup. Research suggests that there will be up to 8% more intense rain for every 1°C of warming.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Since averages are a product of the extremes and extremes are expected to increase in the coming decades, it may involve more impactful tropical cyclones. Yale polled 996 resident’s of Connecticut’s coast who live in coastal flood zones and experienced a hurricane or tropical storm previously, asking the question, “generally speaking, when a hurricane or tropical storm is approaching your city or town, how worried do you feel (1–7)?
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
The results were skewed toward the mid-upper part of the scale, with “5” receiving 22% of the vote. Since a warmer climate will hold more water vapor, climate change indirectly yield more concern and worry amongst coastal residents when it comes to tropical storms and hurricanes.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/BOe51wK.png" alt="Worried_About_Hurricanes"/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Natural Influences&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
El Niño, a climate driver associated with a band of warm ocean water that develops in the central and east-central equatorial Pacific, has been associated with semi-permanent upward step changes in global temperature during and following the “event.” An El Niño event typically takes 3–6 months to develop, reaches a peak during November to January, and then declines for the following 3–6 months. The temperature rises associated with El Niño events have been disproportionate to the temperature falls during the opposite climate driver, La Niña.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
The natural effects from El Niño events are likely enhanced by greenhouse gas emissions, or the anthropogenic warming that continuously works in the background. And the impact(s) from El Niño events may not be entirely natural anymore — research indicates that there may be an increasing frequency of extreme El Niño events due to greenhouse warming.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Global climate modeling is now suggesting that another El Niño event is possible later in 2017, in very quick succession to the strong El Niño that occurred during 2015–16.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;a href="https://plot.ly/~Dreamshot/8602/when-a-hurricane-or-tropical-storm-is-approaching-your-town-how-worried-do-you-f/" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/WdFbinY.png" alt="El_Nino"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Such an outcome would result in yet another upward step in global temperatures, but starting from the new “baseline” that was established by the super El Niño observed during 2015–16.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;a href="https://plot.ly/~Dreamshot/8627/mid-march-iricpc-model-based-probabilistic-enso-forecast/" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/EvtEH1x.png" alt="El_Nino"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Trump not fussed&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
During his first two months in office, U.S. President Trump rolled back key Obama-era greenhouse gas regulations. Without these rules in place, the United States will likely fall far short of its 2015 Paris Agreement pledge: to lower emissions by at least 26 percent below 2005 levels by 2025.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
“Mr. Trump instructed the Environmental Protection Agency to reverse course on the Obama administration’s biggest climate change policy, the Clean Power Plan, which aimed to cut emissions from existing coal- and gas-fired power plants,” writes Nadja Popovich of the New York Times.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;If implemented to its fullest extent, the plan would have reduced carbon emissions by nearly 650 megatons by 2025 — just under halfway to the Paris pledge, according to an analysis by Climate Interactive.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;a href="https://plot.ly/~Dreamshot/8593/cleaner-power-plants-obama-era-policies-for-reducing-greenhouse-gas-emissions/" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/qnHBoMu.png" alt="Paris_Agreement"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
In the meantime, as global temperatures continue to rise, so will the number of “hot days” and likelihood for heat waves. For some, winters will become milder and the growing season longer. However, it goes well beyond just warmer temperatures — but how ecosystems will cope and respond, how we grow our food, and where and when we get our water. All those things will change, some more gradually than others.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
With respect to Earth’s lifeforms, the words cope and adapt may have never been more relevant. For those that can do this most efficiently will best set themselves up for the future on the ever-changing planet that we call home.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;a href="https://plot.ly/~Dreamshot/8633/estimated-of-adults-who-support-funding-research-into-renewable-energy-sources-2/" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/qGThB0V.png" alt="Renewable_Energy"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Plotly is built by computational scientists with degrees and research expertise from McGill, Harvard, Stanford, and other world-class institutions. Making no-compromise open-source software for scientific visualization is our full-time job and passion. Want to support our work? Consider purchasing a Pro plan. For less than half the cost of a Tableau license, you’ll get support from our engineering staff and time-saving ways to save and share your work with colleagues, advisors, or managers.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Pro Plans for University students and instructors ($59/year)
&lt;br/&gt;
Pro Plans for industry users ($396/year)</description><link>https://blog.plotly.com/post/159786388702</link><guid>https://blog.plotly.com/post/159786388702</guid><pubDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2017 07:15:10 -0400</pubDate><category>weather</category><category>climate</category><category>climate change</category><category>climate science</category><category>data</category><category>data science</category><category>data analysis</category><category>data visualization</category><category>data viz</category></item><item><title>Teach Yourself Code-Free Chart Animations with Secret Messages</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Plotly&amp;rsquo;s latest invention? Something akin to &amp;ldquo;invisible ink.&amp;rdquo; That&amp;rsquo;s right &amp;ndash; Plotly users can harness our new animation functionality to create charts, code-free (!), with secret messages.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
One of the earliest writers to mention invisible ink was &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Aeneas_Tacticus" target="_blank"&gt;Aeneas Tacticus&lt;/a&gt; over 2400 years ago. Since then, several others applied varying techniques to craft secret messages: Pliny the Elder and the Roman poet Ovid gave advice on the use of plant juices and milk to write secret messages, similar to what George Washington used during the American Revolution.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
But this is not &lt;a href="http://www.mountvernon.org/george-washington/the-revolutionary-war/spying-and-espionage/spy-techniques-of-the-revolutionary-war/" target="_blank"&gt;George Washington&amp;rsquo;s invisible ink&lt;/a&gt; &amp;ndash; this is the 21st century edition:
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
1. Keep your hands clean: no sticky substances like plant juice and milk needed to create it.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
2. No ultraviolet light needed to read it.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
3. All digital! Super flash.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;h1&gt;From this:&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/LSc7kaP.jpg" alt="Invisible_Ink"/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;h1&gt;To this:&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/Qcp6IJo.gif" alt="Invisible_Ink"/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Plotly&amp;rsquo;s animated graphs can take your stories to the next level. And you don&amp;rsquo;t have to be a programming mastermind to do it. Though animations are supported in R and &lt;a href="https://plot.ly/python/animations/" target="_blank"&gt;Python&lt;/a&gt;, you can also make them in &lt;a href="https://plot.ly/create/" target="_blank"&gt;Plotly&amp;rsquo;s GUI&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
In this post, we&amp;rsquo;ll demonstrate how to use Plotly&amp;rsquo;s GUI to create code-free chart animations with secret messages and show you a few of our favorites. We&amp;rsquo;d love to see what you come up with! Tweet us @PlotlyGraphs.
&lt;!-- more --&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
To learn how to create a secret message chart of your own, scroll toward the bottom of this post.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h1&gt;1. Perfect for the person who wants to keep their birthday a bit of a secret. 😉&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/IVVLlwc.gif" alt=""/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h1&gt;2. Friday is beer-o'clock. Here&amp;rsquo;s your invite to the pub!&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/V4FYDwY.gif" alt=""/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h1&gt;3. Do you ♥️ secret message graphs as much as us?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/M18QHZs.gif" alt=""/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h1&gt;4. X Wins!&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src="http://imgur.com/Lv4NhBq.gif" alt=""/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h1&gt;5. Revolutionary love notes ;)&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/heNlAQ0.gif" alt=""/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h1&gt;6. A Phrase to Plot by&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/b2PQrrv.gif" alt=""/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Now that you&amp;rsquo;ve de-coded our messages, you&amp;rsquo;re just 8 steps away from creating a &amp;ldquo;secret message chart&amp;rdquo; of your own. Follow along below to see how it is done.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
1. Load up &lt;a href="https://plot.ly/create/" target="_blank"&gt;Plotly&lt;/a&gt;. 
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src="http://imgur.com/y5xOaEI.png" alt=""/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
2. Number your columns. Column &amp;ldquo;A&amp;rdquo; should have as many numbers as the letters of your message. For instance, the message &amp;ldquo;hello&amp;rdquo; would be numbered 1, 2, 3, 4, 5. Column &amp;ldquo;B&amp;rdquo; is responsible for the placement of your letters. If you&amp;rsquo;d like them to all be on the same line, label &amp;ldquo;B&amp;rdquo; all 1. If you&amp;rsquo;d like to start up higher with some letters (like we did in this example), label your first word all 3, second word all 2, and third word all 1. 
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src="http://imgur.com/neMn3EG.png" alt=""/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
3. Choose your chart type: &lt;b&gt;animation&lt;/b&gt; and create.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src="http://imgur.com/T6ZjF4P.png" alt=""/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
4. In the style dropdown, select axes and select a custom range that fits your message. For instance, our message has 11 letters so our x axis extends past 11. It is also on 3 separate lines, so our y axis extends to 4. 
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src="http://imgur.com/VHYRxmJ.png" alt=""/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
5. Also in the style dropdown, select traces and you&amp;rsquo;ll find a variety of symbols that you can use to cover up the letters in your secret message. Pick your favorite, but be sure that it is a solid color so it hides the letter(s) properly!
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src="http://imgur.com/niE2dkf.png" alt=""/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
6. Pay attention to this part - it is critical in order to construct your message! Within the style dropdown, select &amp;ldquo;notes.&amp;rdquo; In notes, hit &amp;ldquo;+annotation&amp;rdquo; in the upper right. Next, pick &amp;ldquo;automatically positioned labels.&amp;rdquo; After that, click on the symbol that you are currently on and watch as an annotation appears. This is where you&amp;rsquo;ll now insert the first letter of your phrase. Keep doing this for as many letters as your word has. 
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src="http://imgur.com/zS3Lemd.png" alt=""/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
7. Finally, within &amp;ldquo;style&amp;rdquo; &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; axes, remember to turn off your grid lines (for a cleaner look) and turn off the tick labels too! Use the slider to ensure that the animation is to your liking. 
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src="http://imgur.com/a6ck17J.png" alt=""/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
8. The last step is to admire your graph. And make a GIF out of it. Here&amp;rsquo;s ours: &lt;a href="https://plot.ly/~Dreamshot/8550/." target="_blank"&gt;https://plot.ly/~Dreamshot/8550/.&lt;/a&gt; 
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/M18QHZs.gif" alt=""/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Plotly is built by computational scientists with degrees and research expertise from McGill, Harvard, Stanford, and other world-class institutions. Making no-compromise open-source software for scientific visualization is our full-time job and passion. Want to support our work? Consider purchasing a Pro plan. For less than half the cost of a Tableau license, you’ll get support from our engineering staff and time-saving ways to save and share your work with colleagues, advisors, or managers.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://plot.ly/education/" target="_blank"&gt;Pro Plans for University students and instructors ($59/year)&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://plot.ly/products/cloud/" target="_blank"&gt;Pro Plans for industry users ($396/year)&lt;/a&gt;</description><link>https://blog.plotly.com/post/158922956607</link><guid>https://blog.plotly.com/post/158922956607</guid><pubDate>Tue, 28 Mar 2017 05:15:45 -0400</pubDate><category>animation</category><category>graphs</category><category>gif</category><category>secret</category><category>message</category><category>secretmessage</category></item><item><title>Bioinformaticians in Plotly</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Bioinfo-what?! At Plotly, we&amp;rsquo;re proud of our diverse and talented user base. In this post, we show off the work of our bioinformaticians. 
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
In case you didn&amp;rsquo;t know:
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;Bioinformatics&lt;/b&gt; is an interdisciplinary field that develops methods and software tools for understanding biological data. As an interdisciplinary field of science, bioinformatics combines computer science, statistics, mathematics, and engineering to analyze and interpret biological data.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/IPK6zJS.png" alt="Bioinformatics"/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;center&gt;Source: &lt;a href="http://bioinformatics.uconn.edu/" target="_blank"&gt;UCONN&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Plotly happens to serve a large bioinformatics and biostats research community. These users leverage the uniquely interactive features of plotly charts for dendrograms, heatmaps, volcano plots, and other visualizations common in this field.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
In this post, we show off 7 resources in Python and R created by Plotly bioinformatics and biostats researchers by way of a Spectacle Editor presentation. You can make a &lt;a href="https://plot.ly/powerpoint-online/" target="_blank"&gt;similar presentation with your Plotly graphs&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;!-- more --&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href="https://plot.ly/~Dreamshot/8505" target="_blank"&gt;Presentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/zWFnDBE.gif" alt="Bioinformatics_Presentation"/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h1&gt;1. &lt;a href="https://plot.ly/~johnchase/22/visualizing-bioinformatics-data-with-plo/" target="_blank"&gt;Jupyter notebook: Visualizing bioinformatics data with plotly and python&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/EOZM0pU.png" alt="Bioinformatics"/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h1&gt;2. &lt;a href="http://moderndata.plot.ly/interactive-volcano-plots-r-plotly/" target="_blank"&gt;Zoom &amp;amp; hover in volcano plots&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/hwnuPHY.png" alt="Bioinformatics"/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h1&gt;3. &lt;a href="https://cran.r-project.org/web/packages/heatmaply/vignettes/heatmaply.html" target="_blank"&gt;Interactive dendrograms in R &amp;amp; Python&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/vR6C6vO.png" alt="Bioinformatics"/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h1&gt;4. &lt;a href="https://github.com/asherkhb/plotly-demo/blob/master/2016-09-13_python-presentation.pdf" target="_blank"&gt;Toggle lines and distributions with the legend&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/I6NaSbD.png" alt="Bioinformatics"/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h1&gt;5. &lt;a href="https://plot.ly/r/3d-scatter-plots/" target="_blank"&gt;Take it to the 3rd dimension&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/o9kbATv.png" alt="Bioinformatics"/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h1&gt;6. &lt;a href="https://cran.r-project.org/web/packages/manhattanly/" target="_blank"&gt;Interactive Manhattan Plots&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/sLhWdJt.png" alt="Bioinformatics"/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h1&gt;7. &lt;a href="https://plot.ly/ipython-notebooks/bioinformatics/" target="_blank"&gt;Gene Expression Heatmaps&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/oE5Pl0Y.png" alt="Bioinformatics"/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Plotly is built by computational scientists with degrees and research expertise from McGill, Harvard, Stanford, and other world-class institutions. Making no-compromise open-source software for scientific visualization is our full-time job and passion. Want to support our work? Consider purchasing a Pro plan. For less than half the cost of a Tableau license, you’ll get support from our engineering staff and time-saving ways to save and share your work with colleagues, advisors, or managers.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://plot.ly/education/" target="_blank"&gt;Pro Plans for University students and instructors ($59/year)&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="https://plot.ly/products/cloud/" target="_blank"&gt;Pro Plans for industry users ($396/year)&lt;/a&gt;</description><link>https://blog.plotly.com/post/157856891917</link><guid>https://blog.plotly.com/post/157856891917</guid><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 04:35:48 -0500</pubDate><category>bioinformatics</category><category>biology</category><category>science</category><category>presentation</category><category>graphs</category><category>Plotly</category></item><item><title>3 Minimalist Dashboards with Great Style</title><description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Dashboards have become popular in recent years as uniquely powerful tools for communicating important information at a glance. Although dashboards are potentially powerful, this potential is rarely realized,&amp;rdquo; says principal of the consultancy &lt;a href="https://www.perceptualedge.com/" target="_blank"&gt;Perceptual Edge&lt;/a&gt; Steven Few. 
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&amp;ldquo;The greatest display technology in the world won&amp;rsquo;t solve this if you fail to use effective visual design. And if a dashboard fails to tell you precisely what you need to know in an instant, you&amp;rsquo;ll never use it, even if it&amp;rsquo;s filled with cute gauges, meters, and traffic lights. Don&amp;rsquo;t let your investment in dashboard technology go to waste.&amp;rdquo; 
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Therefore, instead of presenting a vertical &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href="http://blog.plot.ly/post/155665028982/turn-scroll-fest-into-no-mess-with-dashboards" target="_blank"&gt;freight train&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; of graphs and content at your next board meeting, craft a &amp;ldquo;virtual display of the most important information needed to achieve your objectives; consolidated and arranged on a single screen so the information can be monitored at a glance.&amp;rdquo;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/mgtB8eH.png" alt="Stephen_Few"/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;i&gt;Dashboard from &lt;a href="http://www.dashboardinsight.com/news/news-articles/interview-with-stephen-few-dashboard-design-challenges.aspx" target="_blank"&gt;Stephen Few&lt;/a&gt; that combines several bullet graphs along with Edward Tufte’s sparklines to convey a great deal of information in a small amount of space.&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Surprise (&amp;amp; &lt;a href="http://blog.plot.ly/post/150766895902/make-your-next-presentation-pop" target="_blank"&gt;wow&lt;/a&gt;) your colleagues at your next meeting by using &lt;a href="https://plot.ly/dashboards/" target="_blank"&gt;Plotly dashboards&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://plot.ly/powerpoint-online/" target="_blank"&gt;presentations&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
In this post, we show off 3 separate dashboards, influenced by &lt;a href="https://plot.ly/dashboard/Dreamshot:8437/view" target="_blank"&gt;Dribbble&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://plot.ly/dashboard/Dreamshot:8462/view" target="_blank"&gt;FiveThirtyEight&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://plot.ly/dashboard/Dreamshot:8484/view" target="_blank"&gt;NTHSA&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;!-- more --&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;1. Dribbble&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
This dashboard allows you to instantaneously take your organization&amp;rsquo;s pulse.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Using Plotly&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href="https://plot.ly/streaming/" target="_blank"&gt;Streaming API&lt;/a&gt;, you can set your sales data up to update automatically following each transaction. Use a heatmap to track each member of your sales team&amp;rsquo;s performance and the &amp;ldquo;slice&amp;rdquo; (pie chart) to monitor what types of sales your team is making.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="https://plot.ly/dashboard/Dreamshot:8437/view" target="_blank"&gt;Dashboard&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/OGOPFiQ.png" alt="Dribbble_Dashboard"/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="https://plot.ly/~Dreamshot/8443" target="_blank"&gt;Presentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/gGsqqtJ.gif" alt="Dribbble_Presentation"/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;2. FiveThirtyEight&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
This FiveThirtyEight dashboard is a great example of how you can spice up your blog posts using Plotly&amp;rsquo;s dashboards. Since our dashboards are 100% customizable, you can match your company&amp;rsquo;s theme very easily.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Furthermore, your content is:
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
1. In One Place: It is reported that web users spend 80% of their time looking at information above the page fold. That should be incentive enough to produce a compact article and reduce the scrolling that is necessary. Plotly embeddable dashboards &amp;amp; presentations can help you accomplish this! 
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
2. Social Media Gold: Set your data into action and make an animated GIF of your dashboard for Twitter. 
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
3. Downright Stylish: Plotly graphs and dashboards use D3.js, the gold standard of interactive web graphics.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="https://plot.ly/dashboard/Dreamshot:8462/view" target="_blank"&gt;Dashboard&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/FL2C35U.png" alt="FiveThirtyEight_Dashboard"/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="https://plot.ly/~Dreamshot/8463#/?_k=kje2ul" target="_blank"&gt;Presentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/bjIlQVy.gif" alt="FiveThirtyEight_Presentation"/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;3. National Highway Traffic Safety Administration&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Our final example showcases National Highway Traffic Safety Administration data in both a dashboard and presentation. The dashboard &amp;ldquo;tells you precisely what you need to know in an instant,&amp;rdquo; following Few&amp;rsquo;s advice to a t: U.S. road fatalities are decreasing. The dashboard spectacularly accomplishes its goal of being a &amp;ldquo;virtual display of the most important information.&amp;rdquo; 
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="https://plot.ly/dashboard/Dreamshot:8484/view" target="_blank"&gt;Dashboard&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/sNDqNVx.png" alt="NHTSA_Dashboard"/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="https://plot.ly/~Dreamshot/8490#/0?_k=cl566k" target="_blank"&gt;Presentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/igJf1Kv.gif" alt="NHTSA_Presentation"/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;  
If you liked this post, please consider sharing. If you&amp;rsquo;d like to learn how to make these graphs, visit &lt;a href="https://plot.ly/" target="_blank"&gt;our website&lt;/a&gt; or check out &lt;a href="http://help.plot.ly/" target="_blank"&gt;our tutorials&lt;/a&gt;. We have tutorials that show you how to &lt;a href="http://help.plot.ly/embed-graphs-in-websites/" target="_blank"&gt;make and embed graphs&lt;/a&gt; in your website, blog, or apps. To learn more about how companies are using Plotly Enterprise across different industries, see our &lt;a href="https://plot.ly/products/enterprise/customer-stories/" target="_blank"&gt;customer stories.&lt;/a&gt;</description><link>https://blog.plotly.com/post/156971660857</link><guid>https://blog.plotly.com/post/156971660857</guid><pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2017 05:33:51 -0500</pubDate><category>dataviz</category><category>graphs</category><category>bigdata</category><category>datanalytics</category><category>dashboard</category></item><item><title>Turn Scroll-Fest into No-Mess with Dashboards &amp; Presentations</title><description>&lt;p&gt;When someone asks you how your weekend was, you don&amp;rsquo;t start off by (potentially) boring them with the unnecessary details of how your Aunt Sally&amp;rsquo;s train was late and you wasted your afternoon waiting &amp;ndash; no! 
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Generally speaking, you&amp;rsquo;ll say &amp;ldquo;it was great&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;it wasn&amp;rsquo;t so good,&amp;rdquo; and then go into more detail if the asker inquires further.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
We dare you to take this seemingly unrelated piece of advice and apply it to your blog posts and articles. 
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/vdY29Xe.png" alt="get_to_the_point"/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Instead of creating a vertical &amp;ldquo;freight train&amp;rdquo; of graphs and content in your next blog post, consolidate the most important bits and get to the point faster using &lt;a href="https://plot.ly/dashboards/" target="_blank"&gt;Plotly dashboards&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://plot.ly/powerpoint-online/" target="_blank"&gt;presentations&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
In this post, we demonstrate how a &lt;a href="http://pitchbook.com/news/articles/a-snapshot-of-the-us-pe-middle-market-in-11-charts" target="_blank"&gt;PitchBook article&lt;/a&gt;, chock-full of cool graphs and informative text, can easily be spun into a &lt;a href="https://plot.ly/dashboard/Dreamshot:8424" target="_blank"&gt;Plotly dashboard&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://plot.ly/~Dreamshot/8423/pitchbook-1/" target="_blank"&gt;presentation&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
The resulting content is: 
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
1. In One Place: It is &lt;a href="https://www.nngroup.com/articles/scrolling-and-attention/" target="_blank"&gt;reported&lt;/a&gt; that web users spend 80% of their time looking at information above the page fold. That should be incentive enough to produce a compact article and reduce the scrolling that is necessary. Plotly embeddable dashboards &amp;amp; presentations can help you accomplish this!
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
2. Social Media Gold: Set your data into action and make an &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/plotlygraphs/status/816851871600099328" target="_blank"&gt;animated GIF of your dashboard&lt;/a&gt; for Twitter. 
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
3. Downright Stylish: Plotly graphs and dashboards use D3.js, the gold standard of interactive web graphics. See for yourself, below!
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;Dashboard:&lt;/b&gt; &lt;a href="https://plot.ly/dashboard/Dreamshot:8424" target="_blank"&gt;https://plot.ly/dashboard/Dreamshot:8424&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;Presentation:&lt;/b&gt; &lt;a href="https://plot.ly/~Dreamshot/8423/pitchbook-1/#/?_k=tu4ldl" target="_blank"&gt;https://plot.ly/~Dreamshot/8423/pitchbook-1/#/?_k=tu4ldl&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;!-- more --&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;1. Making a Dashboard with Plotly is Super Easy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Our &lt;a href="http://help.plot.ly/create-a-dashboard/" target="_blank"&gt;10-step tutorial&lt;/a&gt; should have you rolling along in minutes.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/kq0KJzu.gif" alt="Create_Dashboard"/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;2. Turn Scroll-Fest into No-Mess&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Instead of forcing readers to scroll and view individual graphs, a dashboard can help you to maximize your space. 
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;3. Cleverly Customizable&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
You can re-size, re-shape, and re-style the dashboard to match that of your organization. We did just that in our &lt;a href="http://pitchbook.com/news/articles/a-snapshot-of-the-us-pe-middle-market-in-11-charts" target="_blank"&gt;PitchBook example&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/BfUOJie.gif" alt="Customize_Dashboard"/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;4. Content that is Perfect for Presentations&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Alternatively, you could embed a presentation in your article to truly eliminate the length and make the read completely undaunting to your readers. Plotly and Formidable&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href="https://plot.ly/powerpoint-online/" target="_blank"&gt;Spectacle Editor&lt;/a&gt; allows you to do just that. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Simply create your graphs on Plotly, download &lt;a href="https://images.plot.ly/spectacle-editor/Spectacle.Editor-0.1.3.dmg" target="_blank"&gt;Spectacle Editor&lt;/a&gt;, and bring your presentation to life.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
For more details on best Spectacle Editor practices, check out &lt;a href="https://medium.com/@plotlygraphs/make-your-next-presentation-pop-8ff6e2371886#.aemumw3rp" target="_blank"&gt;our guide&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/jINq60S.gif" alt="Powerpoint_Online"/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;5. Presentations that Define Utility&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
Not really digging the presentation-embed in your article? Cool, when you share the link to your post on social media, include include an animated GIF of your presentation with it! Or, use it to build the best talk during your company&amp;rsquo;s next seminar and come away looking like the smartest person in the room. No more blurry, detail-lacking graphs &amp;ndash; easy pan and zoom functions make it so even the person sitting in the way back can see exactly the moment that business was booming the most.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/1jlD6hl.png" alt="Graph_Zoom"/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;6. Gamechanging for Social Media&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
If you article has 15 images, which are you going to use? It can be a tough decision. We want the decision to be easier and to boost engagement across your social media platforms. Quite easily take a screenshot (or two) of your Plotly dashboard and share that with your Tweet. GIFs are in, so if you have the technical know-how, pop one of those babies in and watch the retweets roll in.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/CmoaG15.png" alt="Social_Media_Graph"/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;  
If you liked this post, please consider sharing. If you&amp;rsquo;d like to learn how to make these graphs, visit &lt;a href="https://plot.ly/" target="_blank"&gt;our website&lt;/a&gt; or check out &lt;a href="http://help.plot.ly/" target="_blank"&gt;our tutorials&lt;/a&gt;. We have tutorials that show you how to &lt;a href="http://help.plot.ly/embed-graphs-in-websites/" target="_blank"&gt;make and embed graphs&lt;/a&gt; in your website, blog, or apps. To learn more about how companies are using Plotly Enterprise across different industries, see our &lt;a href="https://plot.ly/products/enterprise/customer-stories/" target="_blank"&gt;customer stories.&lt;/a&gt;</description><link>https://blog.plotly.com/post/155665028982</link><guid>https://blog.plotly.com/post/155665028982</guid><pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2017 03:43:23 -0500</pubDate><category>graphs</category><category>presentations</category><category>data visualization</category><category>dataviz</category><category>data science</category><category>bigdata</category><category>style</category></item><item><title>3 Dashboards on Clean Energy</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Plotly dashboards give you the glitz &amp;amp; glamour of D3 charts without having to write a line of code. They can match your brand perfectly and are shareable with simple web links. We wanted an alternative to the usual dashboard platforms that feel heavy, kludgy, expensive, and clunky. Plotly dashboards aren&amp;rsquo;t your dad&amp;rsquo;s dashboards: They&amp;rsquo;re built for today&amp;rsquo;s web and make you look like the smartest person in the room.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;center&gt;
&lt;a href="https://plot.ly/dashboards/" target="_blank"&gt;
&lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/RBlX7TW.gif" alt="Dashboard"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
We present to you 3 Plotly dashboards on clean energy, with inspiration from &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/TheEconomist" target="_blank"&gt;The Economist&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;center&gt;________________&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.ucsusa.org/global_warming/science_and_impacts/science/each-countrys-share-of-co2.html#.WDViW9zgCq8" target="_blank"&gt;The United States is 2nd&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
2nd usually implies something good; for instance 2nd place in a race, runner-up in a basketball tournament, or the silver medalist in an Olympic event. However, in the case of total carbon dioxide emissions, 2nd is not the place you want to be in.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
The United States, in 2011, was responsible for 17% of the world&amp;rsquo;s carbon dioxide emissions. There is no question that population plays a role in CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; emissions; however, the U.S. placed 3rd in the per capita CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; emissions category. 
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt; 
President Obama has unleashed a variety of &lt;a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/blog/2010/04/13/building-a-new-foundation-energy-and-environment" target="_blank"&gt;aggressive tactics to reduce carbon emissions&lt;/a&gt;, such as the creation of new &amp;ldquo;clean energy&amp;rdquo; jobs and technologies and the initiative to make America more energy independent. In 2015, he announced new, &lt;a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/the-press-office/2015/08/03/fact-sheet-president-obama-announce-historic-carbon-pollution-standards" target="_blank"&gt;historic carbon emission standards&lt;/a&gt; for power plants.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Despite his unprecedented steps to attempt to combat climate change, efforts &amp;ndash;both domestically and internationally&amp;ndash; may sadly be too little, too late. 
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
It goes without saying that Mother Nature is pulling off some unprecented stuff of her own this year:
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;center&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-lang="en"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;This is not normal. Global &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/seaice?src=hash" target="_blank"&gt;#seaice&lt;/a&gt; area&amp;hellip;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;(via &lt;a href="https://t.co/qwD3k8Ku3h" target="_blank"&gt;https://t.co/qwD3k8Ku3h&lt;/a&gt;) &lt;a href="https://t.co/LppEwpCidm" target="_blank"&gt;pic.twitter.com/LppEwpCidm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Zack Labe (@ZLabe) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ZLabe/status/798913080168095744" target="_blank"&gt;November 16, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
The globe is on track for its warmest year on record and no country is immune to the effects of a changing climate, not even the most isolated:
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;center&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-lang="en"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Striking warmth: With data in through October, 2016 remains on track to be the WARMEST year on record (107 years) in &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/NewZealand?src=hash" target="_blank"&gt;#NewZealand&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href="https://t.co/jN9Sg4G9TH" target="_blank"&gt;pic.twitter.com/jN9Sg4G9TH&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Niwa Weather (@NiwaWeather) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/NiwaWeather/status/794310282390609920" target="_blank"&gt;November 3, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
These interactive dashboards were made using Plotly&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href="https://plot.ly/dashboards/" target="_blank"&gt;web app&lt;/a&gt;. To securely share dashboards, graphs and data within a team and make &lt;a href="https://plot.ly/dashboards" target="_blank"&gt;interactive dashboards&lt;/a&gt;, sign up for a Plotly &lt;a href="https://plot.ly/products/cloud/" target="_blank"&gt; Professional plan&lt;/a&gt; or contact us about &lt;a href="https://plot.ly/product/enterprise/" target="_blank"&gt;Plotly On-Premise&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;!-- more --&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;1. &lt;a href="https://plot.ly/dashboard/Dreamshot:8381/view" target="_blank"&gt;CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Emissions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
America is often lambasted as a carbon villain, writes &lt;a href="http://www.economist.com/blogs/graphicdetail/2015/08/daily-chart-washing-away-coal-blowing-away-carbon" target="_blank"&gt;The Economist&lt;/a&gt;. And for good reason: The country is responsible for 15% of global CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; emissions. Nevertheless, it is a leader in non-hydropower renewable energy [see next dashboard]. 
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
The graph in the bottom left shows some promise. Note how CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; emissions have decreased in recent years, mostly coinciding with Obama&amp;rsquo;s presidency and his largely unprecedented climate initiatives. 
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
The graph in the bottom right indicates that coal is behind about 20% of American CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; emissions.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;a href="https://plot.ly/dashboard/Dreamshot:8381/view" target="_blank"&gt;
&lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/wMlLrq9.gif" alt="Emissions"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;2. &lt;a href="https://plot.ly/dashboard/Dreamshot:8377/view" target="_blank"&gt;Renewable Energy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
The use of coal [dashboard above] has tailed off very slightly in recent years. As such, production from renewables has slowly picked up. Electricity generation by way of wind in 2014 was 400% greater than it was in 2000. 
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Brazil is the global leader in renewable energy, generating nearly 80% of its energy in that fashion &amp;ndash; led by hydropower. 
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Brazil, Canada, and Germany are the only countries that generate more than 20% of energy through renewables (as of 2013).
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;a href="https://plot.ly/dashboard/Dreamshot:8377/view" target="_blank"&gt;
&lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/RcP6CXY.gif" alt="Renewable Energy"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;3. &lt;a href="https://plot.ly/dashboard/Dreamshot:8376/view" target="_blank"&gt;A Bright Future?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
The Economist reported that global investment in renewable energy rose by a sixth in 2014, to $270 billion. Most impressive was the rise shown by developing countries &amp;ndash; the year-over-year change was about (+) $25 billion. 
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
New investment in renewable energy has increased by about 400% since the year 2004 (!)
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
The graph on the right indicates that the cost of the generation of energy through the use of solar power has actually fallen below that of oil. Of course, the prevalence of solar energy instruments is still low &amp;ndash;and minuscule compared to oil&amp;ndash; but continued growth is anticipated. 
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;a href="https://plot.ly/dashboard/Dreamshot:8376/view" target="_blank"&gt;
&lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/A98cyWk.gif" alt="Outlook"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;  
If you liked this post, please consider sharing. If you&amp;rsquo;d like to learn how to make these graphs, visit &lt;a href="https://plot.ly/" target="_blank"&gt;our website&lt;/a&gt; or check out &lt;a href="http://help.plot.ly/" target="_blank"&gt;our tutorials&lt;/a&gt;. We have tutorials that show you how to &lt;a href="http://help.plot.ly/embed-graphs-in-websites/" target="_blank"&gt;make and embed graphs&lt;/a&gt; in your website, blog, or apps. To learn more about how companies are using Plotly Enterprise across different industries, see our &lt;a href="https://plot.ly/products/enterprise/customer-stories/" target="_blank"&gt;customer stories.&lt;/a&gt;</description><link>https://blog.plotly.com/post/154071336762</link><guid>https://blog.plotly.com/post/154071336762</guid><pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2016 05:07:12 -0500</pubDate><category>climate change</category><category>data</category><category>data analytics</category><category>graphs</category></item></channel></rss>
