<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<rdf:RDF
 xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
 xmlns="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/"
 xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
 xmlns:taxo="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/taxonomy/"
 xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
 xmlns:syn="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
 xmlns:admin="http://webns.net/mvcb/"
>

<channel rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/">
<title>cond-mat.soft updates on arXiv.org</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">Condensed Matter -- Soft Condensed Matter (cond-mat.soft) updates on the arXiv.org e-print archive</description>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:date>2022-11-03T20:30:00-05:00</dc:date>
<dc:publisher>help@arxiv.org</dc:publisher>
<dc:subject>Condensed Matter -- Soft Condensed Matter</dc:subject>
<syn:updateBase>1901-01-01T00:00+00:00</syn:updateBase>
<syn:updateFrequency>1</syn:updateFrequency>
<syn:updatePeriod>daily</syn:updatePeriod>
<items>
 <rdf:Seq>
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01453" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01517" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01605" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01983" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.02019" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2201.06864" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2205.06575" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.16787" />
 </rdf:Seq>
</items>
<image rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif" />
</channel>
<image rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif">
<title>arXiv.org</title>
<url>http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif</url>
<link>http://arxiv.org/</link>
</image>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01453">
<title>Generation and propagation of solitary waves in nematic liquid crystals. (arXiv:2211.01453v1 [cond-mat.soft])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01453</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Solitons in nematic liquid crystals offer intriguing opportunities for
transport and sensing in microfluidic systems. Little is known about the
elementary conditions that are needed to create solitons in nematic materials.
In this work, theory, simulations and experiments are used to study the
generation and propagation of solitary waves (or &quot;solitons&quot;) in nematic liquid
crystals upon the application of an alternating current (AC) electric field. We
find that these solitary waves exhibit &quot;butterfly&quot;-like or &quot;bullet&quot;-like
structures that travel in the direction perpendicular to the applied electric
field. Such structures propagate over long distances without losing their
initial shape. The theoretical model adopted here serves to identify some of
the key requirements that are needed to generate solitons in the absence of
electrostatic interactions. These include surface imperfections that introduce
a twist in the director, unequal elastic constants, and negative anisotropic
dielectric permittivity. The results of simulations are shown to be in good
agreement with our own experimental observations, serving to establish the
validity of the theoretical concepts advanced in this work.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Tang_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xingzhou Tang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Mozaffari_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ali Mozaffari&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Atzin_N/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Noe Atzin&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Das_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Soumik Das&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Abbott_N/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Nicholas L. Abbott&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Pablo_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Juan J. de Pablo&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01517">
<title>Hydration of a side-chain-free n-type semiconducting ladder polymer driven by electrochemical doping. (arXiv:2211.01517v1 [cond-mat.mtrl-sci])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01517</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We study the organic electrochemical transistors (OECTs) performance of the
ladder polymer, poly(benzimidazobenzophenanthroline) (BBL) in an attempt to
better understand how an apparently hydrophobic side-chain-free polymer is able
to operate as an OECT with favorable redox kinetics in an aqueous environment.
We examine two BBLs of different molecular masses from different sources. Both
BBLs show significant film swelling during the initial reduction step. By
combining electrochemical quartz crystal microbalance (eQCM) gravimetry,
in-operando atomic force microscopy (AFM), and both ex-situ and in-operando
grazing incidence wide-angle x-ray scattering (GIWAXS), we provide a detailed
structural picture of the electrochemical charge injection process in BBL in
the absence of any hydrophilic side-chains. Compared with ex-situ measurements,
in-operando GIWAXS shows both more swelling upon electrochemical doping than
has previously been recognized, and less contraction upon dedoping. The data
show that BBL films undergo an irreversible hydration driven by the initial
electrochemical doping cycle with significant water retention and lamellar
expansion that persists across subsequent oxidation/reduction cycles. This
swelling creates a hydrophilic environment that facilitates the subsequent fast
hydrated ion transport in the absence of the hydrophilic side-chains used in
many other polymer systems. Due to its rigid ladder backbone and absence of
hydrophilic side-chains, the primary BBL water uptake does not significantly
degrade the crystalline order, and the original dehydrated, unswelled state can
be recovered after drying. The combination of doping induced hydrophilicity and
robust crystalline order leads to efficient ionic transport and good stability.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Guo_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jiajie Guo&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Flagg_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Lucas Q. Flagg&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Tran_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Duyen K. Tran&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Chen_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Shinya E. Chen&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Li_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ruipeng Li&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Kolhe_N/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Nagesh B. Kolhe&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Giridharagopal_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Rajiv Giridharagopal&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Jenekhe_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Samson A. Jenekhe&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Richter_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Lee J. Richter&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Ginger_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;David S. Ginger&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01605">
<title>Cooperative Motions and Topology-Driven Dynamical Arrest in Prime Knots. (arXiv:2211.01605v1 [cond-mat.soft])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01605</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Knots are entangled structures that cannot be untangled without a cut.
Topological stability of knots is one of the many examples of their important
properties that can be used in information storage and transfer. Knot dynamics
is important for understanding general principles of entanglement as knots
provide an isolated system where tangles are highly controlled and easily
manipulated. To unravel the dynamics of these entangled topological objects,
the first step is to identify the dominant motions that are uniquely guided by
knot structure and its complexity. We identify and classify motions into three
main groups -- orthogonal, aligned, and mixed motions, which often act in
unison, orchestrating the complex dynamics of knots. The balance between these
motions is what creates an identifiable signature for every knot. As knot
complexity increases, the carefully orchestrated dynamics is gradually
silenced, eventually reaching a state of topologically driven dynamical arrest.
Depending on their complexity, knots undergo a transition from nearly
stochastic motions to either non-random or even quasiperiodic dynamics before
culminating in dynamical arrest. Here, we show for the first time that
connectivity alone can lead to a topology-driven dynamical arrest in knots of
high complexity. Unexpectedly, we noticed that some knots undergo cooperative
motions as they reach higher complexity, uniquely modulating conformational
patterns of a given knot. Together, these findings demonstrate a link between
topology and dynamics, presenting applications to nanoscale materials.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Park_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Hyo Jung Park&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Lappala_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Anna Lappala&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01983">
<title>Order and density fluctuations near the boundary in sheared dense suspensions. (arXiv:2211.01983v1 [cond-mat.soft])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01983</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We introduce a novel approach to reveal ordering fluctuations in sheared
dense suspensions, using line scanning in a combined rheometer and laser
scanning confocal microscope. We validate the technique with a moderately dense
suspension, observing modest shear-induced ordering and a nearly linear flow
profile. At high concentration ($\phi = 0.55$) and applied stress just below
shear thickening, we report ordering fluctuations with high temporal
resolution, and directly measure a decrease in order with distance from the
suspension&apos;s bottom boundary as well as a direct correlation between order and
particle concentration. Higher applied stress produces shear thickening with
large fluctuations in boundary stress which we find are accompanied by dramatic
fluctuations in suspension flow speeds. The peak flow rates are independent of
distance from the suspension boundary, indicating that they likely arise from
transient jamming that creates solid-like aggregates of particles moving
together, but only briefly because the high speed fluctuations are interspersed
with regions flowing much more slowly, suggesting that shear thickening
suspensions possess complex internal structural dynamics, even in relatively
simple geometries.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Miller_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Joia M. Miller&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Blair_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Daniel L. Blair&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Urbach_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jeffrey S. Urbach&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.02019">
<title>Extending the analogy between intracellular motion in mammalian cells and glassy dynamics. (arXiv:2211.02019v1 [cond-mat.soft])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.02019</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The physics of how molecules, organelles, and foreign objects move within
living cells has been extensively studied in organisms ranging from bacteria to
human cells. In mammalian cells, in particular, cellular vesicles move across
the cell using motor proteins that carry the vesicle down the cytoskeleton to
their destination. We have recently noted several similarities between the
motion of such vesicles and that in disordered, &quot;glassy&quot;, systems, but it
remains unclear whether that is a general observation or something specific to
certain vesicles in one particular cell type. Here we follow the motion of
mitochondria, the organelles responsible for cell energy production, in several
mammalian cell types over timescales ranging from 50 ms up to 70 s. Qualitative
observations show that single mitochondria remain stalled, remaining within a
spatially limited region, for extended periods of time, before moving longer
distances relatively quickly. Analysing this motion quantitatively, we observe
a displacement distribution that is roughly Gaussian for shorter distances
($\lesssim$ 0.05 $\mu$m) but which exhibits exponentially decaying tails at
longer distances (up to 0.40 $\mu$m). We show that this behaviour is
well-described by a model originally developed to describe the motion in glassy
systems. These observations are extended to in total 3 different objects
(mitochondria, lysosomes and nano-sized beads enclosed in vesicles), 3
different mammalian cell types, from 2 different organisms (human and mouse).
We provide further evidence that supports glass-like characteristics of the
motion by showing a difference between the time it takes to move a longer
distance for the first time and subsequent times, as well as a weak ergodicity
breaking of the motion. Overall, we demonstrate the ubiquity of glass-like
motion in mammalian cells, providing a different perspective on intracellular
motion.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Corci_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;B. Corci&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Hooiveld_O/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;O. Hooiveld&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Dolga_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;A. M. Dolga&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+%7B%5CAA%7Dberg_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;C. &amp;#xc5;berg&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2201.06864">
<title>Acoustic monitoring of the gelation of a colloidal suspension. (arXiv:2201.06864v2 [cond-mat.soft] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2201.06864</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Because they are sensitive to mechanical properties of materials and can
propagate even in opaque systems, acoustic waves provides us with a powerful
characterization tool in numerous fields. Common techniques mostly rely on
time-of-flight measurements and do not exploit the spectral content: however,
sound speed and attenuation spectra contain rich information. Such an acoustic
spectroscopy already exists and allows to retrieve subtle information on
systems of well-known physico-chemistry, but modeling becomes out of reach for
industrial systems. In this article, we use a simple empirical approach to
monitor the gelation of silica suspensions: we show that the gelation time
obtained from acoustic measurements is proportional to this determined with
more conventional rheological characterization. Such a results thus opens the
way for in-situ monitoring of time-evolving systems in industrial context with
acoustic methods only.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Belicard_N/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Nicolas B&amp;#xe9;licard&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Niemet_Mabiala_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Marc Junior Ni&amp;#xe9;met-Mabiala&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Tourvieille_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jean-No&amp;#xeb;l Tourvieille&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Lidon_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Pierre Lidon&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2205.06575">
<title>Experimental and numerical investigation of bubble migration in shear flow: deformability-driven chaining and repulsion. (arXiv:2205.06575v2 [cond-mat.soft] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2205.06575</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We study the interaction-induced migration of bubbles in shear flow and
observe that bubbles suspended in elastoviscoplastic emulsions organise into
chains aligned in the flow direction, similarly to particles in viscoelastic
fluids. To investigate the driving mechanism, we perform experiments and
simulations on bubble pairs, using suspending fluids with different rheological
properties. First, we notice that, for all fluids, the interaction type depends
on the relative position of the bubbles. If they are aligned in the vorticity
direction, they repel, if not, they attract each other. The simulations show a
similar behavior in Newtonian fluids as in viscoelastic and elastoviscoplastic
fluids, as long as the capillary number is sufficiently large. This shows that
the interaction-related migration of the bubbles is strongly affected by the
bubble deformation. We suggest that the cause of migration is the interaction
between the heterogeneous pressure fields around the deformed bubbles, due to
capillary pressure.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Feneuil_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Blandine Feneuil&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Iqbal_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Kazi Tassawar Iqbal&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Jensen_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Atle Jensen&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Brandt_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Luca Brandt&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Tammisola_O/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Outi Tammisola&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Carlson_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Andreas Carlson&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.16787">
<title>Unexpected bending behavior of 2D lattice materials. (arXiv:2210.16787v2 [cond-mat.soft] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.16787</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Architected 2D lattice materials are appealing for shape-shifting
applications due to the tunable sign of Poisson&apos;s ratio. It is commonly
believed that the positive and negative Poisson&apos;s ratios lead to anticlastic
and synclastic curvatures respectively when the material is bent in one
direction. Here, taking 2D beam lattices with star-shaped unit cells as
examples, we show theoretically and demonstrate experimentally that this is not
always true. At a fixed Poisson&apos;s ratio, we find a transition between
anticlastic and synclastic bending curvatures controlled by the beam&apos;s
cross-sectional aspect ratio. Such an unexpected behavior roots in the
competition between torsion and bending of the beams, and can be well captured
by a Cosserat continuum model.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Yao_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yu Yao&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Ni_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yong Ni&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+He_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ling-hui He&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
</rdf:RDF>