<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?><?xml-stylesheet href="http://www.blogger.com/styles/atom.css" type="text/css"?><feed xmlns='http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom' xmlns:openSearch='http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/' xmlns:blogger='http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008' xmlns:georss='http://www.georss.org/georss' xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005" xmlns:thr='http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0'><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-582368152716771238</id><updated>2022-11-05T11:39:25.751-05:00</updated><category term="Commentary"/><category term="Economists"/><category term="Monetary Policy"/><category term="Politics and economics"/><category term="Regulation"/><category term="Inflation"/><category term="Academic Articles"/><category term="Finance"/><category term="Taxes"/><category term="Financial Reform"/><category term="Banking"/><category term="pandemic"/><category term="Macro"/><category term="Stimulus"/><category term="Growth"/><category term="Health economics"/><category term="Interesting Papers"/><category term="Thesis topics"/><category term="Inequality"/><category term="Environment"/><category term="Euro"/><category term="European Debt Crisis"/><category term="Cronyism"/><category term="Energy"/><category term="Op-eds"/><category term="Debt"/><category term="Unemployment"/><category term="Micro vs. macro"/><category term="Trade"/><category term="Videos"/><category term="Talks"/><category term="housing"/><category term="Podcasts"/><category term="Labor"/><category term="Nobel"/><category term="Freedom"/><category term="Interviews"/><category term="Cancel culture"/><category term="Immigration"/><category term="econometrics"/><category term="negative interest rates"/><category term="Social Programs"/><category term="Teaching"/><category term="off-topic"/><category term="art"/><category term="nepotism"/><category term="writing"/><category term="Essays"/><category term="Fiscal Theory"/><category term="Real Estate"/><category term="Trading"/><category term="Language"/><category term="Posts to other blogs"/><category term="education"/><category term="academic freedom"/><title type='text'>The Grumpy Economist</title><subtitle type='html'>John Cochrane&#39;s blog</subtitle><link rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#feed' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://johnhcochrane.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/582368152716771238/posts/default'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://johnhcochrane.blogspot.com/'/><link rel='hub' href='http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/'/><link rel='next' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/582368152716771238/posts/default?start-index=26&amp;max-results=25'/><author><name>John H. Cochrane</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/04842601651429471525</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='25' height='32' src='//4.bp.blogspot.com/-hxC_w91OloY/X8aKsZcuFcI/AAAAAAAADHs/CANi5RE5-n8t7QGX1CzX9vgEg1Bd22tpwCK4BGAYYCw/s220/john_cochrane_forweb.jpg'/></author><generator version='7.00' uri='http://www.blogger.com'>Blogger</generator><openSearch:totalResults>1270</openSearch:totalResults><openSearch:startIndex>1</openSearch:startIndex><openSearch:itemsPerPage>25</openSearch:itemsPerPage><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-582368152716771238.post-9135287195906136410</id><published>2022-11-04T10:30:00.003-05:00</published><updated>2022-11-04T11:44:46.681-05:00</updated><category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="academic freedom"/><category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Politics and economics"/><title type='text'>Academic Freedom Conference Opening Statement</title><content type='html'>&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Opening remarks, &lt;a href=&quot;https://johnhcochrane.blogspot.com/2022/11/academic-freedom-conference.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Conference on Academic Freedom&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;John H. Cochrane&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;Nov 4 2022&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the Academic Freedom Conference. I’m John Cochrane, one of the co-organizers of this conference.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;First, let us offer thanks. Most of all, we thank the Stanford GSB and its dean Jon Levin for sponsoring this conference, and sticking with us through some turbulence. We also thank the institutions listed here for sponsorship, and several generous donors. We thank the&lt;a href=&quot;https://cli.stanford.edu/events/conference-symposium/academic-freedom-conference/organizing-committee&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; organizing committee&lt;/a&gt;, which helped to identify and recruit speakers and consulted extensively. We thank all our speakers, and all of you, especially those who have traveled to be here. Most of all, Ivan Marinovic did all the hard work of putting the conference together. Thank you Ivan!&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I am, of course, not going to tell you what to say and not say. But any conversation is more productive if we focus it and try to keep to the point.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We gather as a group that believes academic freedom is important and under threat. But we don’t fully understand the problem or what to do about it. So, we are here to share experiences in different universities, fields, and from a diversity of viewpoints, to understand and define the problem, and to find practical solutions.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We are not here to have a philosophical discussion whether academic freedom is important, and whether it is threatened. We here start from the premise that the core mission of the scholarly community is to uncover new knowledge, to debate and refine knowledge, to pass on knowledge to the next generation, and more importantly to pass on the habits and norms of critical inquiry and scholarly debate that produce true knowledge. We here start from the premise that we are losing academic freedom, and that threatens this core scholarly mission. If those of you listening on zoom or the critics of this conference wish to debate these issues, go ahead and run a different conference. Every biology conference does not start with an evolution vs. creationism debate. Time is short, and focus will make us more productive.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is a conference on academic freedom, with a lesser emphasis on free speech of political opinions. Cancellation, ostracism, and disciplinary action for political opinions, and canceling outside popular speakers are in the news. But our core question is limitations on the scholarly enterprise of research, teaching, publication, fact-finding, logical analysis, and criticism. This enterprise is damaged when scholars are canceled for political opinions, or opinions on matters like university hiring and admissions. But our focus goes beyond this to emphasize less visible but perhaps more insidious restrictions on academic activity, including direct institutional actions, by self-censorship in fear, or by good people being driven out of the academic enterprise.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is a conference on academic freedom, and not free speech and censorship in the media, on twitter, and in the general society. That is an important political problem in our democracy, but it’s not the focus of our conference. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is a conference on academic freedom, and not centrally on the substance of contentious issues. We have some noted speakers who have been criticized for their views. But we’re here primarily to learn from their experience of censorship, not to debate the merits of the particular views and research findings that got them in trouble.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Academic freedom is a problem of institutions. Twitter-mob students are visible. But the key restrictions on academic freedom lie with university leaders, university bureaucracies, hiring and promotion procedures; and beyond universities to funding agencies, professional organizations, and journals. I hope we can discuss and remedy dysfunction in all these institutions.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The nexus between politics and academic freedom is a deep and troublesome question.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We designed this conference to be non-partisan. Truth knows no politics, we thought; it is likely to unsettle verities on all sides, and we know many self-identified leftists as well as rightists and libertarians who are concerned. We don’t know and didn’t ask what your politics are. We did however, make a special effort to invite people who self-identify as politically left or progressive and concerned with academic freedom. We also made a special effort to reach out to many of the people who have criticized some of our speakers; among others Stanford faculty who publicly denounced Jay Bhattacharya and Scott Atlas.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The non-response and refusals from this group was astounding, and surprising to us. If this group does not seem “balanced” to you it is by refusal to participate, not by lack of invitation.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;One prominent Stanford professor, active in university academic freedom issues, spoke for many, telling us “I can’t be seen on the program with right-wing nutjobs like.…” and named a few of our speakers. At an academic freedom conference. There’s half the problem in a nutshell.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are now faculty protest letters and demands in the faculty senate that Stanford distance itself from this conference. Critics involved the media. They complain that we are “closed,” for restricting attendance when the room got full, and for restricting media to preserve space for participants, though these are routine for academic conferences. [The Stanford&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://gef.stanford.edu&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;global energy forum&lt;/a&gt; of the last two days is explicitly “invitation only” without complaint, and without Bjorn Lomborg or Steve Kooning.] They complain about some of our speakers’s deplorable, to them, views. People with such views should, apparently, never allowed to speak on anything. They cherry pick one or two hated speakers, to declare us “unbalanced.” But have any of them looked up the other 35 speakers on the program? &amp;nbsp;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.chronicle.com/article/a-conference-says-academic-freedom-is-in-danger-critics-say-the-event-is-part-of-the-problem&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Chronicle of Higher Education &lt;/a&gt;declared this conference a “threat to democracy.” Even the Hoover Institution declined to support or co-host this conference, deeming it “too political.”&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The attempt failed. Stanford’s leaders have supported us, for which we are grateful, so we are still here. But young untenured faculty figured out they should not be seen here. Several more deregistered from the conference after we decided to stream the proceedings, citing fear of repercussions.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The irony of trying to censor the free speech conference has not occurred to them. The hypocrisy of labeling this and only this conference “political,” and demanding that this and only this conference include “wider voices,” not the long list of highly one-sided political events at Stanford, [for example, the “&lt;a href=&quot;https://wcc.stanford.edu/events-programs/stanford-gender-equity-and-justice-summit&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Gender Equity and Justice Summit&lt;/a&gt;”] likewise escapes them. Well, I guess &quot;logic&quot; is not politically fashionable, but do we have to be so obvious about it? &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We were naive. Just in setting up a conference to talk about academic freedom, we got to experience part of the problem.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I think we cannot avoid the elephant in the room. The threat to academic freedom is political, as it has always been. Free scholarship undermines narratives that sustain or are used to claim political power. &amp;nbsp;Though in the past this threat has come from both left and right, and though there are some dumb and illiberal restrictions coming from Republican state legislatures, the main threats to academic freedom inside the university, professional societies, and government agencies predominantly come from a particular far-left political ideology, and most of the forbidden subjects today threaten their narrative. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Well, I think so. Maybe I’m wrong. My point is, we should talk about this too.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Some organizational notes:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can say what you want, but you can’t talk as long as you want. Please abide by the time limits. Moderators, please be ruthless in enforcing time limits. Please leave ample time for questions and comments from the floor. That discussion is much of the point of this event. I anticipate there will be far more comments than we can accommodate, so I encourage moderators to take a group of 5 or so comments at a time. Panelists, please keep responses short.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Each session will start on time, and end on time. At breaks, please return to the room promptly without being nagged, so we can keep to the schedule and everyone gets a chance to be heard.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Be aware that this conference is streamed, and video will be available later as well. We &amp;nbsp;originally preferred no recording and Chatham house rules. But various pressures make that impossible, and we realized there is no way to ensure privacy. So, we accepted the loss of spontaneity that a record imposes, in return for the transparency that it provides. It proves what is not said here as much as it records what is said.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Covid still runs among us, and in a group this size there is a good probability that someone is infectious. Let this be a super-spreader event of ideas, but not of disease. If you are not feeling well, please do us all a favor and watch the live stream from out of the room. If you have any doubts, please take a test. (There are a bunch at the sign in desk.) In this tolerant free-speech group, let us respect people’s individual choices to wear a mask.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;OK. Tell us what’s going on in your field, your university, your department, your curriculum committee, your classroom, your professional society, your journals, your funding agency, and tell us how we can work together to fix it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><link rel='replies' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://johnhcochrane.blogspot.com/feeds/9135287195906136410/comments/default' title='Post Comments'/><link rel='replies' type='text/html' href='https://johnhcochrane.blogspot.com/2022/11/academic-freedom-conference-opening.html#comment-form' title='7 Comments'/><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/582368152716771238/posts/default/9135287195906136410'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/582368152716771238/posts/default/9135287195906136410'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://johnhcochrane.blogspot.com/2022/11/academic-freedom-conference-opening.html' title='Academic Freedom Conference Opening Statement'/><author><name>John H. Cochrane</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/04842601651429471525</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='25' height='32' src='//4.bp.blogspot.com/-hxC_w91OloY/X8aKsZcuFcI/AAAAAAAADHs/CANi5RE5-n8t7QGX1CzX9vgEg1Bd22tpwCK4BGAYYCw/s220/john_cochrane_forweb.jpg'/></author><thr:total>7</thr:total></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-582368152716771238.post-5695844736625964108</id><published>2022-11-03T10:55:00.001-05:00</published><updated>2022-11-03T13:22:18.973-05:00</updated><category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="academic freedom"/><category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Commentary"/><category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Politics and economics"/><title type='text'>Academic Freedom Conference</title><content type='html'>&lt;p&gt;On Friday and Saturday Nov. 4/5, the Stanford GSB Classical Liberalism Initiative will host a two day conference on Academic Freedom. &lt;a href=&quot;https://cli.stanford.edu/events/conference-symposium/academic-freedom-conference&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Conference website here&lt;/a&gt;, and I copy and paste the schedule below. &amp;nbsp;The room is beyond full, so we can&#39;t issue more in-person invitations. Because of that and the threat of protests (yes, a loud group at Stanford wants to silence the academic freedom / free speech conference), &amp;nbsp;we will not be able to accommodate walk-ins.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But the event will be live-streamed. If you want to watch, &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLScyQu5pf9LbobfSKtLsNZKNLjgBclFnjwPaJmvgE5WtTB9f3w/viewform&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;register here&lt;/a&gt; and we&#39;ll send you a link.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is a separate effort from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.blogger.com/blog/post/edit/582368152716771238/5116837823746666453#&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;academic freedom declaration&lt;/a&gt; I &lt;a href=&quot;https://johnhcochrane.blogspot.com/2022/11/academic-freedom-letter.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;blogged &amp;nbsp;yesterday&lt;/a&gt;, though many of the same organizers are involved.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Academic Freedom Conference&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Academic freedom, open inquiry, and freedom of speech are under threat as they have not been for decades. Visibly, academics are “canceled,” fired, or subject to lengthy disciplinary proceedings in response to academic writing or public engagement. Less visibly, funding agencies, university bureaucracies, hiring procedures, promotion committees, professional organizations, and journals censor some kinds of research or demand adherence to political causes. Many parts of universities have become politicized or have turned into ideological monocultures, excluding people, ideas, or kinds of work that challenge their orthodoxy. Younger researchers are afraid to speak and write and don’t investigate promising ideas that they fear will endanger their careers.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The two-day Academic Freedom Conference, arranged by the organizing committee, aims to identify ways to restore academic freedom, open inquiry, and freedom of speech and expression on campus and in the larger culture and restore the open debate required for new knowledge to flourish. The conference will focus on the organizational structures leading to censorship and stifling debate and how to repair them.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Schedule&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a name=&#39;more&#39;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Friday, November 4, 2022&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;8:20am - 8:30am PDT Opening Remarks: John H. Cochrane&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;8:30am - 9:00am PDT Why it has Gotten Harder to Find the Truth&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Jonathan Haidt Professor, Ethical Leadership at New York University Stern School of Business&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;9:00am - 10:00am PDT Academic Freedom in STEM&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Anna Krylov Professor, Chemistry at University of Southern California&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Luana Maroja Professor, Biology at Williams University&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mimi St Johns Undergraduate Student, Stanford University=&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Jerry Coyne Professor Emeritus, Biology at University of Chicago&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Moderator: Sergiu Klainerman. Professor of Mathematics, Princeton&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;10:15am - 11:00am PDT Peter Thiel &quot;The End of the Future&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Peter Thiel Partner at Founders Fund&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;11:00am - 12:00pm PDT Academic Freedom: Practical Solutions&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Richard Lowery Associate Professor of Finance · McCombs School of Business&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dorian Abbot Associate Professor of Geophysical Sciences, University of Chicago&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;John Hasnas Professor of Business and Professor of Law (by courtesy) | Executive Director, Georgetown Institute for the Study of Markets and Ethics, Georgetown University&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Peter Arcidiacono William Henry Glasson Professor of Economics, Duke University&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Moderator: Anne Beyer Professor of Accounting, Stanford&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;12:00pm - 2:30pm PDT Lunch: The Radicalization of the Academy&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lee Jussim Distinguished Professor of Psychology, Rutgers University&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;2:30pm - 3:30pm PDT Are the Humanities Liberal?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Solveig Gold Thomas W. Smith Postdoctoral Research Associate, Princeton University&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Joseph H. Manson Professor of Anthropology, UCLA&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;John Rose Associate Director of The Civil Discourse Project at Duke&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Moderator: Jennifer Burns Professor of History, Stanford&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;3:45pm - 4:45pm PDT The Economics of Academic Freedom&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Niall Ferguson Milbank Family Senior Fellow at the Hoover Institution&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;John H. Cochrane Senior Fellow, Hoover Institution, Stanford University&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tyler Cowen Professor of Economics at George Mason University and at the Center for the Study of Public Choice&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Moderator: Rob Reich Professor of Political Science, Stanford&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;5:00pm - 6:00pm PDT The State of Higher Education: USA, UK, Canada&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;John M. Ellis Professor Emeritus of German Literature, University of California, Santa Cruz&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Gad Saad Professor of Marketing, Concordia University (Montreal)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Eric Kaufmann Professor of Politics, University of London&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Moderator: Ivan Marinovic Professor of Accounting, Stanford&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Saturday, November 5, 2022&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;8:30am - 9:30am PDT Academic Freedom Applications: Climate Science and Biomedical Sciences&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Noah Diffenbaugh Senior Fellow, Stanford Woods Institute for the Environment&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Bjorn Lomborg Founding Director Copenhagen Consensus&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Jay Bhattacharya Professor of Health Policy, Stanford University&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;John Ioannidis Professor of Medicine, Stanford University&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Moderator: John H. Cochrane Senior Fellow, Hoover Institution&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;9:30am - 10:15am PDT The War on the West: a conversation&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Douglas Murray Author and Journalist&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Jordan Peterson Professor of Psychology, University of Toronto (Emeritus)&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;10:45am - 12:00pm PDT Academic Freedom: What Is It and What Is It For?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Greg Lukianoff President and CEO of the Foundation for Individual Rights and Expression (FIRE)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nadine Strossen John Marshall Harlan II Professor of Law, Emerita, New York Law School and Senior Fellow, FIRE (Foundation for Individual Rights and Expression)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Richard Shweder Harold Higgins Swift Distinguished Service Professor of Human Development, University of Chicago&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hollis Robbins Dean, College of Humanities, University of Utah&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Moderator: Brandice Cane-Wrone Professor of Political Science and Senior Fellow at the Hoover Institution&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;12:30pm - 2:30pm PDT Lunch: Scott Atlas &quot;Academia, Science, and Public Health: Will Trust Return?&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Scott Atlas Robert Wesson Senior Fellow at the Hoover Institution&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;2:30pm - 3:15pm PDT Rationality and Academic Freedom&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Steven Pinker Johnstone Family Professor in the Department of Psychology at Harvard University&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;3:30pm - 4:30pm PDT Academic Freedom in Law and Legal Education&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ilya Shapiro Senior Fellow and Director of Constitutional Studies, Manhattan Institute&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Michael McConnell Richard and Frances Mallery Professor and Director of the Constitutional Law Center, Stanford University&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Eugene Volokh Gary T. Schwartz Distinguished Professor of Law, University of California Los Angeles&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Moderator: Jeffrey Zwiebel Professor of Finance, Stanford&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;4:30pm - 5:30pm PDT The Cost of Academic Dissent&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Joshua Katz Senior Fellow American Enterprise Institute&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Frances Widdowson Independent Researcher&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Amy Wax Robert Mundheim Professor of Law, University of Pennsylvania&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Elizabeth Weiss Professor of Anthropology, San Jose State University&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Moderator: Harald Uhlig Professor of Economics, University of Chicago&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><link rel='replies' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://johnhcochrane.blogspot.com/feeds/5695844736625964108/comments/default' title='Post Comments'/><link rel='replies' type='text/html' href='https://johnhcochrane.blogspot.com/2022/11/academic-freedom-conference.html#comment-form' title='8 Comments'/><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/582368152716771238/posts/default/5695844736625964108'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/582368152716771238/posts/default/5695844736625964108'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://johnhcochrane.blogspot.com/2022/11/academic-freedom-conference.html' title='Academic Freedom Conference'/><author><name>John H. Cochrane</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/04842601651429471525</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='25' height='32' src='//4.bp.blogspot.com/-hxC_w91OloY/X8aKsZcuFcI/AAAAAAAADHs/CANi5RE5-n8t7QGX1CzX9vgEg1Bd22tpwCK4BGAYYCw/s220/john_cochrane_forweb.jpg'/></author><thr:total>8</thr:total></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-582368152716771238.post-5116837823746666453</id><published>2022-11-02T22:55:00.005-05:00</published><updated>2022-11-03T10:25:45.328-05:00</updated><category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Cancel culture"/><category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Commentary"/><category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Economists"/><category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Politics and economics"/><title type='text'>Academic Freedom Letter</title><content type='html'>&lt;p&gt;Some colleagues and I created an open letter on Academic Freedom. If you share our views, you are invited to sign.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The bottom line: we call for universities and professional associations to adopt &lt;i&gt;and implement &lt;/i&gt;the&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://freeexpression.uchicago.edu&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Chicago Principles&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;of free speech, the&lt;a href=&quot;https://provost.uchicago.edu/reports/report-universitys-role-political-and-social-action&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp;Kalven Report&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt;requirement for institutional neutrality on political and social matters, and the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://provost.uchicago.edu/sites/default/files/documents/reports/shilsrpt_0.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Shils report&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;making academic contribution the sole basis for hiring and promotion. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We include professional societies. That means you, American Economic Association and American Finance Association: With all your committees on improving the profession, you need one big one to defend the most important and imperiled part of the scholarly enterprise, academic freedom.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The letter, below, is not as comprehensive and detailed as you might like, but we worked to keep it short.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The official letter and list of signatories &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/document/d/1_vTk2EPGqe_4pjj9KntQLKAKO8ZqfL0Pquj89TlazYA/edit?usp=sharing&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;lives here&lt;/a&gt;. If you would like to sign, you can do so by &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSfh0gtHHwLk2sD4Z2EUKA2y8M-nzem_MZhbVaL3zEzCFhnj9w/viewform&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;filling out this form&lt;/a&gt;. It&#39;s moderated so may take a day or two for your signature to show.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We are up to 626 signatures (11/3). When the number stabilizes we&#39;ll try to make a public fuss about the letter.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Update:&lt;/i&gt; A special plea. I have several responses from left/liberal/democrat colleagues who say they would sign, but don&#39;t want to have their names on a letter that doesn&#39;t have enough other left/liberal/democrat names on it and does have well known deplorables. (How you know 626 people&#39;s politics is beyond me, but ok.) That reaction tells us a big part of the problem. &amp;nbsp;All along we have tried very hard to reach out to self-described left/liberal/democrat colleagues, who privately bemoan what&#39;s going on but are too afraid to be seen in public. But why not fix it: if some of you sign perhaps that will give courage for more of you to sign. Take it over, get together with your friends, add lots of signatures, make this your cause, prove that we can stand together for freedom!&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Restoring Academic Freedom&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The mission of the university is the pursuit of truth and the advancement and dissemination of knowledge. A robust culture of free speech and academic freedom is essential to that mission: Intellectual progress often threatens the status quo and is resisted. Bad ideas are only weeded out by unfettered critical analysis.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, academic freedom and freedom of speech are rapidly declining in academic institutions, including universities, professional societies, journals, and funding agencies. Researchers whose findings challenge dominant narratives find it increasingly hard to get published, funded, hired, or promoted. They, and teachers who question current orthodoxies, are harassed in person and online, ostracized, subjected to opaque university disciplinary procedures, fired, or canceled by other means. Employment, promotion, and funding are increasingly subject to implicit or explicit political litmus tests, including approval from bureaucrats seeking to impose a social agenda such as specific views of social justice or DEI principles. Activism is replacing inquiry and debate. &amp;nbsp;An increasing number of simple facts and ideas cannot even be mentioned without risk of retribution.&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a name=&#39;more&#39;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Public high-profile victims are the tip of the iceberg. An atmosphere of fear and self-censorship pervades academia. Many faculty and students believe they cannot voice their views, question dogmas, investigate certain topics, or question the loss of academic freedom without risking ostracization and damage to their careers. Knowledge is lost, and many talented scholars are leaving academia.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Universities and professional societies are failing to resist such illiberal forces–which have arisen many times throughout history, from all sides of the political spectrum –and to defend academic freedom and freedom of speech.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Many universities and professional organizations now qualify their support for freedom: free speech, they say, so long as the speech does not offend or exclude; free speech, so long as it does not challenge institutionally approved narratives and conceptions of social justice; free speech, but only within narrow credentialed boundaries. These restrictions are counterproductive, even to their goal of advancing a particular ideology. People infer from censorship a desire to protect lies from being exposed. Historically, censorship has supported monstrous regimes and their ideologies. Bad ideas are only defeated by argument and persuasion, not by suppression. True justice and freedom cannot exist without each other. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The loss of academic freedom results in part from a leadership crisis. While many university leaders issue statements that support open debate, they nonetheless oversee and expand politicized bureaucracies that harass, intimidate, and punish those who express views deemed to be incorrect and enforce ideological conformity in hiring and promotions. A boilerplate generic defense of free speech does little good if at the same time university administrators conduct investigations in secret, without due process, and based on anonymous complaints; if administrators publicly ostracize the victim to all potential future employers. Boards of trustees, alumni organizations, donors, government granting agencies, and other institutional stakeholders likewise fail to uphold the principles of academic freedom.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Universities and professional organizations are instead moving headlong into institutional political and ideological activism. Departments and other university units make public statements of political views, thus effectively branding as heretics -and even bigots- members who may question those causes. Increasingly, centers and “accelerators” are devoted to political and policy advocacy, advocacy of the supporting ideologies, and suppression of competing ideas. Professional organizations and journals announce, all too often, &amp;nbsp;that certain kinds of research, no matter how methodologically valid, may not be published, and have turned to advocacy. University bureaucracies demand that certain authors be included and others excluded from reading lists and classroom discussion.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;What can be done?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We call for all Universities, academic associations, journals, and national academies to adopt the “Chicago Trifecta,” consisting of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://freeexpression.uchicago.edu&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Chicago Principles&lt;/a&gt; of free speech, the&lt;a href=&quot;https://provost.uchicago.edu/reports/report-universitys-role-political-and-social-action&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; Kalven Report &lt;/a&gt;requirement for institutional neutrality on political and social matters, and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://provost.uchicago.edu/sites/default/files/documents/reports/shilsrpt_0.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Shils report&lt;/a&gt; making academic contribution the sole basis for hiring and promotion. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Kalven report emphasizes, &amp;nbsp;“To perform its mission in society, a university must sustain an extraordinary environment of freedom of inquiry and maintain an independence from political fashions, passions, and pressures.’’ &amp;nbsp;The University and its administrative subunits must abstain from taking position on the political issues of the day: &amp;nbsp;“While the university is the home and sponsor of critics, it is not itself the critic and therefore cannot take collective action on the issues of the day without endangering the conditions for its existence and effectiveness.”&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“The neutrality of the university as an institution arises … not from lack of courage nor out of indifference and insensitivity. &amp;nbsp;It arises out of respect for free inquiry and the obligation to cherish a diversity of viewpoints.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We also call for faculty to create (or join existing) non-partisan associations, aimed at defending these values on campus, and at a national level such as FIRE, the Academic Freedom Alliance, Heterodox Academy, FAIR and ACTA. Professional organizations should prioritize the defense of academic freedom and free speech of their members.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Many universities have officially adopted the Chicago Principles. Robust structures must be developed to uphold these principles. Faculty under fire from student groups, other faculty, deans and administrators, or university staff, must be able to effectively assert their freedom of speech and inquiry by appealing to those statements.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Universities must deploy safeguards to ensure that administrators work to uphold these principles rather than to undermine them. &amp;nbsp;University disciplinary procedures must become transparent, following basic centuries-old protections of the accused such as the right to see and challenge evidence, confront witnesses against them, the right to representation, and innocence until proven guilty.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;University leaders must also promote and institutionalize free speech and academic freedom by concrete actions. Freedom is a culture, not merely a set of rules, and a culture must be nurtured. Free speech, free inquiry, tolerance for opposing views, meeting such views with argument, logic and fact, abstaining from ad-hominem attacks, character assassination, doxing and other unethical behavior must be highlighted in the orientation materials for all new students and employees. Freedom comes with a culture of responsibility, but responsibilities are better enforced by social norms than by extensive rules enforced by non-academic bureaucrats. &amp;nbsp;If community members or groups petition school leaders for the sanction or punishment of a faculty member or a student for expressing their point of view, university leaders should publicly and clearly respond with a statement affirming that the University is a place to discuss and debate all views, and that an attempt to punish others for having “incorrect” views is incompatible with the community standards of the school. &amp;nbsp;The University should also commit to all students, faculty, and employees, that it will not punish or sanction free expression. &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='replies' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://johnhcochrane.blogspot.com/feeds/5116837823746666453/comments/default' title='Post Comments'/><link rel='replies' type='text/html' href='https://johnhcochrane.blogspot.com/2022/11/academic-freedom-letter.html#comment-form' title='11 Comments'/><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/582368152716771238/posts/default/5116837823746666453'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/582368152716771238/posts/default/5116837823746666453'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://johnhcochrane.blogspot.com/2022/11/academic-freedom-letter.html' title='Academic Freedom Letter'/><author><name>John H. Cochrane</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/04842601651429471525</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='25' height='32' src='//4.bp.blogspot.com/-hxC_w91OloY/X8aKsZcuFcI/AAAAAAAADHs/CANi5RE5-n8t7QGX1CzX9vgEg1Bd22tpwCK4BGAYYCw/s220/john_cochrane_forweb.jpg'/></author><thr:total>11</thr:total></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-582368152716771238.post-6648999554920055650</id><published>2022-11-02T21:40:00.004-05:00</published><updated>2022-11-04T11:48:08.626-05:00</updated><category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Commentary"/><category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Fiscal Theory"/><category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Growth"/><category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Micro vs. macro"/><category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Monetary Policy"/><title type='text'>We&#39;re all supply siders now -- Summers and Poilievre</title><content type='html'>&lt;p&gt;Larry Summers wrote an interesting&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/opinions/2022/10/31/inflation-interest-rates-economy-federal-reserve/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;oped at the Washington Post.&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;Mostly, he still is of the adaptive-expectations ISLM view that interest rates must exceed current inflation before inflation will decline. (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.blogger.com/blog/posts/582368152716771238&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;The issue here&lt;/a&gt;.) But listen to this:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Questions of macroeconomic policy are not about values but judgments about the ultimate effects of various actions. As Fed chair during the early 1980s, Paul Volcker famously tamed out-of-control inflation at the cost of a severe recession. But he did so not because he cared less about unemployment or worker incomes than his predecessors did but because he rightly recognized that delay in containing inflation would only mean more pain down the road.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Would we all recognize common goals, but differences on cause and effect to get there. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;That’s why it’s vital that the Federal Reserve not waver. Chair Jerome H. Powell has vowed to impose sufficiently restrictive monetary policy to return inflation to within range of the Fed’s 2 percent target. The more confident that workers, businesses and markets are that the Fed will follow through on that, the less painful the process will be.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Within the conventional monetary policy community, praise for Volcker and the view, basically, that the Fed should focus on inflation and the labor market will take care of itself is sensible, but remarkably Reaganish.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The tidbit that I found most interesting&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Finally, the crisis of inflation should not be wasted. A bright spot in the dismal inflation period of the 1970s was the collaboration of Stephen G. Breyer (then counsel to the Senate Judiciary Committee), Sen. Edward M. Kennedy (D-Mass.) and the Carter administration on airline deregulation. In this era, high inflation should be a spur to regulatory changes — from addressing Jones Act increases in shipping costs, to strategic tariffs, to rules that force oil and gas to be transported via truck rather than pipeline, to punitive zoning restrictions — that will both reduce prices and make the economy work better.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;As you know I&#39;ve been preaching that &quot;supply side&quot; growth is the central problem and also the key to reducing inflation. Larry hasn&#39;t quite gotten to the latter, but this is the economist most identified with &quot;secular stagnation,&quot; &quot;hysteresis&quot; and the view that all we need to do is borrow or print more money and hand it out to create growth. Now deregulation and the supply side is the key to growth.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Larry is starting to sound like a Reagan Republican! &amp;nbsp;I&#39;m sure he would say circumstances have changed -- that was ZLB (zero lower bound on interest rates), this is inflation. That&#39;s a consistent view. But inflation should wake us all up as it has Larry: All the old verities are over, there is only supply now, and that comes mostly from getting out of the way, as Larry recommends, not new &quot;investments&quot; of more borrowed money thrown down ratholes.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;***&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Pierre Poilievre, the leader of Canada&#39;s Conservative party,&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://nationalpost.com/opinion/pierre-poilievre-spending-must-be-capped-to-end-liberal-induced-inflation&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;wrote a great Oped in the National Post&lt;/a&gt;. Now that Liz Truss has imploded, perhaps Poilievre will become the international hope for a successful free market libertarian politician.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Finance Minister Chrystia Freeland wants us to believe she has had an epiphany. After years of ignoring my warnings that Liberal deficit spending would cause inflation to balloon, followed by interest rates, she now claims to agree with me in a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thestar.com/politics/federal/2022/10/19/chrystia-freeland-warns-cabinet-ministers-new-programs-must-be-funded-by-budget-cuts.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;leaked letter&lt;/a&gt; to fellow ministers. Even her boss, Prime Minister Justin Trudeau, is uttering words unthinkable to him not long ago: “&lt;a href=&quot;https://globalnews.ca/news/9217165/canada-fiscal-responsibility-trudeau-recession/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;fiscal responsibility&lt;/a&gt;.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;The cost of government is driving up the cost of living. A half-trillion dollars of inflationary deficits have sent more dollars chasing fewer goods, which always leads to higher prices.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;We&#39;re all FTPLers (fiscal theory of the price level) now, some sooner than others. A clear explanation of how central banks create money and buy treasury debt follows. Then&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;the Bank of Canada must pay interest — at the going rate. Because rates are now rising, the central bank is now losing money and will need a bailout from the federal government for the first time in history — something I predicted would happen two years ago.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fiscal constraints on monetary policy. Nice.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Liberals like to say that all this inflation is the result of the Russian invasion of Ukraine. But less than 0.3 per cent of Canada’s trade is with those two countries, and the things that they produce are things we already have — food and energy. In fact, the higher commodity prices should have helped our resource-heavy economy, but for the fact that the Trudeau government has hit farmers with fertilizer tariffs and carbon taxes and blocked or bungled every single pipeline or LNG export terminal proposed in seven years.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Beside my thread, but an important point. His bottom line&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Instead of creating more cash, we need our economy to produce more of what cash buys: more food, energy and homes. That means removing gatekeepers that have made Canada the second slowest country in all the OECD to get a building permit. As prime minister I would challenge all three levels of government to work together to offer the fastest building permits in the OECD. This would mean going from 250 days to 28 days to beat the now first-placed South Korea....We would remove taxes and tariffs on farmers’ fuel and fertilizer....Finally, we would reform our taxes to reward work, savings, and investment so our workers and businesses can produce more of the goods we need.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;Simply put, we would stop creating cash and start creating more of what cash buys: food, homes, energy, manufactured goods and more. That is the only path to bigger buying power for paycheques and savings.&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;FTPL and deregulation-focused supply side growth. Well, us free market libertarians are like Chicago Cubs fans, there&#39;s always hope!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><link rel='replies' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://johnhcochrane.blogspot.com/feeds/6648999554920055650/comments/default' title='Post Comments'/><link rel='replies' type='text/html' href='https://johnhcochrane.blogspot.com/2022/11/were-all-supply-siders-now-summers-and.html#comment-form' title='9 Comments'/><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/582368152716771238/posts/default/6648999554920055650'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/582368152716771238/posts/default/6648999554920055650'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://johnhcochrane.blogspot.com/2022/11/were-all-supply-siders-now-summers-and.html' title='We&#39;re all supply siders now -- Summers and Poilievre'/><author><name>John H. Cochrane</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/04842601651429471525</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='25' height='32' src='//4.bp.blogspot.com/-hxC_w91OloY/X8aKsZcuFcI/AAAAAAAADHs/CANi5RE5-n8t7QGX1CzX9vgEg1Bd22tpwCK4BGAYYCw/s220/john_cochrane_forweb.jpg'/></author><thr:total>9</thr:total></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-582368152716771238.post-5231495697597721439</id><published>2022-11-02T21:13:00.002-05:00</published><updated>2022-11-02T21:13:17.303-05:00</updated><category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Commentary"/><category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Debt"/><category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Economists"/><category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Fiscal Theory"/><category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Monetary Policy"/><title type='text'>Ip on FTPL</title><content type='html'>&lt;p&gt;Greg Ip gives nice coverage of fiscal theory of the price level in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wsj.com/articles/to-solve-inflation-first-solve-deficits-this-theory-advises-11667391310&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Wall Street Journal&lt;/a&gt;..&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m sad he left out &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/030439329190007B&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Eric Leeper&#39;s defining work&lt;/a&gt;, which really even more than Sargent and Wallace started modern FTPL. Eric described monetary policy with interest rates, not money supplies, and integrated FTPL with the now dominant new-Keyensian tradition.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Naturally I&#39;m a bit rankled by&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;But FTPL is frustratingly difficult to apply to real life.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;and&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;A theory that doesn’t predict inflation but explains it only after the fact by invoking hard-to-measure attitudes isn’t that satisfying, and certainly no better than mainstream macroeconomic models.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Well, that also means no worse than mainstream models. And&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.johnhcochrane.com/news-op-eds-all/inflation-nro&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; I was publicly warning of inflation &lt;/a&gt;in April 2021, though I&#39;m too much of an academic to make much of one data point. The FTPL analysis of the ZLB is, I think more convincing.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yes it would be nice if FTPL could tell you just when too much debt is too much. It would also be nice if the theory of finance could tell you just what a stock should be worth. And it would be nice if any theory, or the Fed itself, did a good job of predicting inflation.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A nice nugget,&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;fiscal stimulus had some role in pushing inflation up, and as the Fed raises interest rates to combat that inflation, it will worsen deficits. Britain had to abandon deficit-financed tax cuts over fears they would drive inflation and interest rates higher. French Finance Minister Bruno Le Maire recently warned: “Central banks’ restrictive policies are ineffective if public finances continue to expand.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;It seems we&#39;re all FTPLers now.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But I&#39;m whining. For the length it&#39;s excellent. This is a hard topic and most journalists get things wrong. &amp;nbsp;And I am grateful for the publicity.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><link rel='replies' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://johnhcochrane.blogspot.com/feeds/5231495697597721439/comments/default' title='Post Comments'/><link rel='replies' type='text/html' href='https://johnhcochrane.blogspot.com/2022/11/ip-on-ftpl.html#comment-form' title='5 Comments'/><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/582368152716771238/posts/default/5231495697597721439'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/582368152716771238/posts/default/5231495697597721439'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://johnhcochrane.blogspot.com/2022/11/ip-on-ftpl.html' title='Ip on FTPL'/><author><name>John H. Cochrane</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/04842601651429471525</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='25' height='32' src='//4.bp.blogspot.com/-hxC_w91OloY/X8aKsZcuFcI/AAAAAAAADHs/CANi5RE5-n8t7QGX1CzX9vgEg1Bd22tpwCK4BGAYYCw/s220/john_cochrane_forweb.jpg'/></author><thr:total>5</thr:total></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-582368152716771238.post-7076132104168883412</id><published>2022-10-28T10:30:00.000-05:00</published><updated>2022-10-28T10:30:02.359-05:00</updated><category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="art"/><category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Economists"/><category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Euro"/><category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="European Debt Crisis"/><title type='text'>Economics Art</title><content type='html'>&lt;p&gt;I was researching the European Stability Mechanism this morning for a paper on the evolution of the euro, and I ran across this gem of economics art on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.esm.europa.eu/how-we-decide/esm/governance&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;ESM webpage&lt;/a&gt;. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEhFFgfqjJp_xynFkzHmG_XLKuBzcbxx2jXJITp4V_gVWITnK79Oc2fnSBiZ9PwBPnVxQEFBjq8fiSR5fK08oKzuAMOkQwJKieo-1sMge_OGe6YuHCNNlblfAGgEr9NeXqTn72Vy-db4pmvZ9zEgk1ozuAJUAuuYFlAYoUzHc9wpykrT1w_6usiWkNA/s1268/Screen%20Shot%202022-10-28%20at%208.23.45%20AM.png&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;1268&quot; data-original-width=&quot;1174&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEhFFgfqjJp_xynFkzHmG_XLKuBzcbxx2jXJITp4V_gVWITnK79Oc2fnSBiZ9PwBPnVxQEFBjq8fiSR5fK08oKzuAMOkQwJKieo-1sMge_OGe6YuHCNNlblfAGgEr9NeXqTn72Vy-db4pmvZ9zEgk1ozuAJUAuuYFlAYoUzHc9wpykrT1w_6usiWkNA/w592-h640/Screen%20Shot%202022-10-28%20at%208.23.45%20AM.png&quot; width=&quot;592&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;Put on your mechanical engineer hat for a moment. This is a set of gears that &lt;i&gt;literally cannot turn&lt;/i&gt;. To say nothing of the wisdom of putting belts on gears. Perhaps this is a subtle cry for help?&amp;nbsp;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;(The ESM is sort of europe&#39;s internal IMF that can lend money to strapped governments with conditions.)&amp;nbsp;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</content><link rel='replies' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://johnhcochrane.blogspot.com/feeds/7076132104168883412/comments/default' title='Post Comments'/><link rel='replies' type='text/html' href='https://johnhcochrane.blogspot.com/2022/10/economics-art.html#comment-form' title='13 Comments'/><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/582368152716771238/posts/default/7076132104168883412'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/582368152716771238/posts/default/7076132104168883412'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://johnhcochrane.blogspot.com/2022/10/economics-art.html' title='Economics Art'/><author><name>John H. Cochrane</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/04842601651429471525</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='25' height='32' src='//4.bp.blogspot.com/-hxC_w91OloY/X8aKsZcuFcI/AAAAAAAADHs/CANi5RE5-n8t7QGX1CzX9vgEg1Bd22tpwCK4BGAYYCw/s220/john_cochrane_forweb.jpg'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEhFFgfqjJp_xynFkzHmG_XLKuBzcbxx2jXJITp4V_gVWITnK79Oc2fnSBiZ9PwBPnVxQEFBjq8fiSR5fK08oKzuAMOkQwJKieo-1sMge_OGe6YuHCNNlblfAGgEr9NeXqTn72Vy-db4pmvZ9zEgk1ozuAJUAuuYFlAYoUzHc9wpykrT1w_6usiWkNA/s72-w592-h640-c/Screen%20Shot%202022-10-28%20at%208.23.45%20AM.png" height="72" width="72"/><thr:total>13</thr:total></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-582368152716771238.post-825285511729202178</id><published>2022-10-25T09:48:00.009-05:00</published><updated>2022-10-28T09:04:47.570-05:00</updated><category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Commentary"/><category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Growth"/><category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="housing"/><category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Inflation"/><category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Labor"/><category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Macro"/><category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Micro vs. macro"/><category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Politics and economics"/><category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Taxes"/><title type='text'>Truss Tragedy</title><content type='html'>&lt;p&gt;(at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/tragedy-liz-truss-right-policy-goals-bad-messaging-politics-by-john-h-cochrane-and-jon-hartley-2022-10?utm_source=twitter&amp;amp;utm_medium=organic-social&amp;amp;utm_campaign=page-posts-oct22&amp;amp;utm_post-type=link&amp;amp;utm_format=16:9&amp;amp;utm_creative=quote-card&amp;amp;utm_post-date=2022-10-25&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Project Syndicate&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Liz Truss Tragedy&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;The former British prime minister’s downfall holds important lessons for growth-minded policymakers in the United States, Europe, and elsewhere. While her diagnosis of the country’s economic problem was spot on, she fatally mismanaged both the politics and the messaging of her policy response.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;STANFORD – Liz Truss’s stint as British prime minister is over, but she was right that the United Kingdom needs growth. Her downfall is tragic, because growth is the only path out of the country’s economic dilemma.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The UK is surprisingly poor. Its &lt;a href=&quot;https://ourworldindata.org/grapher/gdp-per-capita-worldbank?tab=chart&amp;amp;country=USA~GBR&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;GDP per capita &lt;/a&gt;is just $43,000, compared to $60,000 in the United States. The average British home is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.businessinsider.com/ons-english-homes-are-a-third-of-the-size-of-american-homes-2017-10&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;one-third&lt;/a&gt; the size of the average US home. Worse, the country’s economy is not growing. Its GDP per capita is lower than it was in 2007.&lt;a href=&quot;https://fred.stlouisfed.org/series/RTFPNAGBA632NRUG&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; Productivity &lt;/a&gt;– the underlying source of economic growth – has been flat for over a decade.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The UK desperately needs supply-side reforms. Surging inflation tells us that demand-side stimulus is a spent force.&amp;nbsp;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a name=&#39;more&#39;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If anything, Truss’s proposed reforms were too mild. A &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2022/oct/03/liz-truss-abandon-plan-scrap-45p-top-rate-income-tax-tory-revolt-kwasi-kwarteng-chancellor&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;40% top marginal income tax rate&lt;/a&gt; (down from 45%) would not make the UK a low-tax free-market Shangri-La, especially considering that it would also still have a 20% value-added tax (VAT), national insurance taxes, property taxes, corporate taxes, and more. Recall that US President Ronald Reagan and Speaker of the House Tip O’Neill (a Democrat) cut the top federal marginal rate from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.history.com/this-day-in-history/reagan-signs-economic-recovery-tax-act-erta&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;70% to 28%&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Truss also proposed free-market “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2022/sep/30/liz-truss-to-push-ahead-with-unlimited-investment-zones-despite-costs-row&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;investment zones&lt;/a&gt;.” But if one accepts that pro-investment tax and planning conditions are good in blighted areas, why not the whole country?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The UK is at a post-Brexit crossroads. Will it become a free-trade, entrepreneurial, financial hub – a “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.courthousenews.com/will-u-k-become-a-singapore-on-the-thames-rival-to-europe/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Singapore on Thames&lt;/a&gt;”? Or does Brexit mean protecting and subsidizing inefficient businesses and places even more than the European Union allows?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, we now know the answer. Truss’s critics have no counterproposal that has any chance of reigniting growth. The stage is set for further high-tax, high-subsidy, over-regulated decline.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As sound as Truss’s plans were in economic-policy terms, her government’s handling of the messaging and the politics was spectacularly inept. That is an important lesson for those of us who want to see more growth-oriented policies in the US, Canada, and Europe.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;One obvious mistake was Truss’s announcement of a £&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2022-09-03/truss-spending-may-contribute-to-60-billion-shortfall-ft-says&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;60 billion&lt;/a&gt; ($68 billion) blowout to hold down gas prices. That is not a good way to launch a pro-growth revolution.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;She then moved on to “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.npr.org/2022/10/23/1130782408/how-liz-truss-aggressive-tax-cutting-policy-led-to-her-downfall&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;tax cuts&lt;/a&gt;,” predictably raising the ire of the high-tax intelligentsia. In announcing the policy, neither Truss nor her chancellor of the Exchequer, Kwasi Kwarteng, explained the point of lowering tax rates. For example, Kwarteng &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ft.com/content/3c067e28-e33a-4bda-9f2e-81a109966b20&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;sold &lt;/a&gt;tax cuts as “putting money back into people’s pockets.” But such Keynesian stimulus is the last thing the country needs amid historic inflation. Kwarteng should have explained that lower tax rates improve the incentives to work, save, invest, start a business, or, in the case of corporate taxes, move a business to the UK or keep it there. (Ideally, one cuts tax rates but broadens the base, maintaining revenues until spending falls.)&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you can’t explain that clearly and consistently, you either don’t understand or believe your own message, or you think voters are too dumb to comprehend it. Either way, your revolution will fail. In the face of predictable, implacable hostility from the entrenched left-wing media and economic commentariat, a free-market revolution needs great communicators.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;By starting with taxes and subsidies, Truss and Kwarteng guaranteed that nobody would pay attention to the most important parts of the plan: the essential pro-growth regulatory reforms that they had described in the 2012 book &lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://link.springer.com/book/10.1057/9781137032249&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Britannia Unchained&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;. Britain’s housing restrictions, as in the US, lead to absurdly high prices, which stymies many businesses and the workers they might hire. The situation is especially harmful to less-advantaged people who cannot afford to live near high-productivity jobs. Truss had also &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reuters.com/world/uk/new-uk-pm-truss-wants-more-oil-gas-extraction-north-sea-2022-09-07/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;planned&lt;/a&gt; to bring back North Sea oil production and lift the UK’s ban on fracking. These are sensible responses to a global energy crisis.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The lesson is that growth-minded policymakers should start with microeconomic reforms. Everyone can see that over-regulation and restrictions on housing and energy production are hobbling supply. Even climate-change activists are noticing that it is &lt;a href=&quot;https://theconversation.com/onshore-wind-farm-restrictions-continue-to-stifle-britains-renewable-energy-potential-147812&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;too difficult&lt;/a&gt; to get permits for windmills and transmission lines. Everyone can see that schools are awful and&lt;a href=&quot;https://yougov.co.uk/topics/society/articles-reports/2021/06/02/current-state-english-school-system&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; getting worse&lt;/a&gt;. Workers as well as business owners and managers can see that labor&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.researchgate.net/publication/5135628_Employment_Regulations_through_the_Eyes_of_Employers_Do_They_Matter_and_How_Do_Firms_Respond_to_Them&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; regulations&lt;/a&gt; are straitjacketing their workplaces. People can see in everyday experience how social-program disincentives lead some people not to work at all.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Patiently explaining these problems to voters can also make for good politics. We all long for simple mind-the-store competence in our governments. Fixing dysfunction is a visible achievement that works right away, with no short-run cost.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Truss’s handling of the politics was even worse than her marketing. Margaret Thatcher and Reagan faced the same withering scorn from the chattering classes, and they had to endure years of hardship before their reforms took root. But they held firm.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Truss’s critics seized on UK bond-market hiccups, though these were tiny compared to those of the 1980s. They also were largely attributable to the Bank of England &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reuters.com/markets/europe/bank-england-raises-rates-225-despite-likely-recession-2022-09-22/#:~:text=The%20BoE&#39;s%20Monetary%20Policy%20Committee,a%20smaller%20rise%20to%202%25.&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;raising rates&lt;/a&gt;, and to a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2022-10-06/how-uk-pension-fund-risks-almost-toppled-britain-s-bond-market&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;pension &lt;/a&gt;risk regulation fiasco. [Previous posts ending &lt;a href=&quot;https://johnhcochrane.blogspot.com/2022/10/more-uk-finance-regulatory-failure.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.] Nonetheless, Truss quickly gave in. By starting with an energy blowout to placate the left, she already encouraged her opponents to go in for the kill. When a shark is on your trail, you don’t offer it a foot and then assume that you’ll both get along. When an iron lady was needed, Truss proved to be made of straw.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The US, too, is a high-tax, over-regulated, over-subsidized, high-debt, slow-growth economy. For us, too, supply-side reforms are the only way out. Yet many of our conservative voices now pander to voters by advocating big-government big-tax nationalism, protectionism, subsidies, and crony capitalism, albeit directed in different directions than the left.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For those of us who still understand that the only real solution lies in economic freedom and small, competent government, Truss’s downfall offers important lessons. We must heed them so that we don’t blow our chance if we get one.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;John H. Cochrane is a senior fellow of the Hoover Institution and an adjunct scholar at the CATO Institute.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Jon Hartley is a PhD student in economics at Stanford University and a research fellow at the Foundation for Research on Equal Opportunity.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;****&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;PS, every bone in my body wanted to join the chorus yelling &amp;nbsp;&quot;Hooray for fiscal theory of the price level, here come the bond market vigilantes I&#39;ve been warning about for 20 years&quot; in response to the interest rate hiccups surrounding Truss&#39; plan. But in honesty I cannot. The tax cuts were small, UK debt to GDP less than the US, similar tax cuts and raises have come and gone with nary a peep from the bond market -- Trump for example -- and the UK still borrows at negative rates. Look at interest rates in 1980. It doesn&#39;t add up. FTPL references debt to long-term ability to repay. You can&#39;t just pick and choose data points that coincide with your story and ignore the others. The point of asset markets is that nobody really knows why they move. Maybe it&#39;s true, but I need some indication that these small tax cuts really are the fiscal cliff.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Update: &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wsj.com/articles/rishi-sunak-wont-frack-u-k-natural-gas-liz-truss-russia-vladimir-putin-11666901841&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Rishi Sunk won&#39;t allow fracking&lt;/a&gt;&quot; WSJ. Here we go.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</content><link rel='replies' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://johnhcochrane.blogspot.com/feeds/825285511729202178/comments/default' title='Post Comments'/><link rel='replies' type='text/html' href='https://johnhcochrane.blogspot.com/2022/10/truss-tragedy.html#comment-form' title='29 Comments'/><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/582368152716771238/posts/default/825285511729202178'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/582368152716771238/posts/default/825285511729202178'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://johnhcochrane.blogspot.com/2022/10/truss-tragedy.html' title='Truss Tragedy'/><author><name>John H. Cochrane</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/04842601651429471525</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='25' height='32' src='//4.bp.blogspot.com/-hxC_w91OloY/X8aKsZcuFcI/AAAAAAAADHs/CANi5RE5-n8t7QGX1CzX9vgEg1Bd22tpwCK4BGAYYCw/s220/john_cochrane_forweb.jpg'/></author><thr:total>29</thr:total></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-582368152716771238.post-3165473979682898461</id><published>2022-10-25T09:29:00.001-05:00</published><updated>2022-10-25T09:29:22.604-05:00</updated><category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Commentary"/><category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Inflation"/><category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Monetary Policy"/><title type='text'>Inflation Expectations</title><content type='html'>&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEjKSTzApO8oDUDOV0VKxQNdL8Vx1OxW9gzq4_SOY82OfkrfJGYNlF1ZQ4mKtcr7HOwbX2BtO8a2wSh5-ufgI0x2K7kgWJB4s-Mon20DNWc60lGOtMuNq5uAXKG4JDAVZlP_rRvYy7HBCrlmW6v337Az1DQNkddkYh-h1CQ80Kuzse3PZ54AkHhPgrU/s1624/Screen%20Shot%202022-10-25%20at%207.18.07%20AM.png&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;1118&quot; data-original-width=&quot;1624&quot; height=&quot;440&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEjKSTzApO8oDUDOV0VKxQNdL8Vx1OxW9gzq4_SOY82OfkrfJGYNlF1ZQ4mKtcr7HOwbX2BtO8a2wSh5-ufgI0x2K7kgWJB4s-Mon20DNWc60lGOtMuNq5uAXKG4JDAVZlP_rRvYy7HBCrlmW6v337Az1DQNkddkYh-h1CQ80Kuzse3PZ54AkHhPgrU/w640-h440/Screen%20Shot%202022-10-25%20at%207.18.07%20AM.png&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;From Torsten Slok at Apollo Global Management. The picture says it all, but Torsten&#39;s commentary is especially good:&amp;nbsp;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Inflation will be coming down over the coming quarters. This is what the Fed is predicting, that is what the consensus is expecting, and that is what we are predicting. The problem is that this has been the forecast ever since inflation started going up in April 2021, see chart below. Given how systematically wrong inflation forecasts have been over the past 18 months, there are good reasons to be cautious about the current forecast.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;It is also how market expectations have evolved. Is inflation inherently unpredictable? Are we collectively in thrall of the same wrong model? Does &quot;expectation&quot; mean the same thing in models and surveys? Are market risk premiums really important? &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</content><link rel='replies' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://johnhcochrane.blogspot.com/feeds/3165473979682898461/comments/default' title='Post Comments'/><link rel='replies' type='text/html' href='https://johnhcochrane.blogspot.com/2022/10/inflation-expectations.html#comment-form' title='12 Comments'/><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/582368152716771238/posts/default/3165473979682898461'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/582368152716771238/posts/default/3165473979682898461'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://johnhcochrane.blogspot.com/2022/10/inflation-expectations.html' title='Inflation Expectations'/><author><name>John H. Cochrane</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/04842601651429471525</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='25' height='32' src='//4.bp.blogspot.com/-hxC_w91OloY/X8aKsZcuFcI/AAAAAAAADHs/CANi5RE5-n8t7QGX1CzX9vgEg1Bd22tpwCK4BGAYYCw/s220/john_cochrane_forweb.jpg'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEjKSTzApO8oDUDOV0VKxQNdL8Vx1OxW9gzq4_SOY82OfkrfJGYNlF1ZQ4mKtcr7HOwbX2BtO8a2wSh5-ufgI0x2K7kgWJB4s-Mon20DNWc60lGOtMuNq5uAXKG4JDAVZlP_rRvYy7HBCrlmW6v337Az1DQNkddkYh-h1CQ80Kuzse3PZ54AkHhPgrU/s72-w640-h440-c/Screen%20Shot%202022-10-25%20at%207.18.07%20AM.png" height="72" width="72"/><thr:total>12</thr:total></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-582368152716771238.post-5414580019437232550</id><published>2022-10-14T17:12:00.010-05:00</published><updated>2022-10-20T08:52:42.488-05:00</updated><category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Banking"/><category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Commentary"/><category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Finance"/><category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Financial Reform"/><category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Politics and economics"/><title type='text'>More UK finance regulatory failure</title><content type='html'>&lt;p&gt;In previous blog posts&lt;a href=&quot;https://johnhcochrane.blogspot.com/2022/09/a-familiar-finance-fable-in-uk-bonds.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; here &lt;/a&gt;and &lt;a href=&quot;https://johnhcochrane.blogspot.com/2022/10/uk-finance-fable-update.html&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, I criticized UK financial regulators for missing simple leverage and margin requirements in UK pension funds. To be clear, I don&#39;t criticize the people. The point is, if after 10 years of intense regulation, a group of really smart and dedicated people can&#39;t see plain old leverage, the whole project of regulating risks is broken. And it&#39;s not just the UK. The Fed bailed out money market funds in 2020. Again.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I insinuated the regulators were not paying attention. I was wrong. It turns out they &lt;i&gt;were &lt;/i&gt;paying attention. Which makes the failure all the more stark. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In Friday&#39;s Wall Street Journal, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wsj.com/articles/as-bond-investors-bets-blow-up-they-might-usher-in-era-of-higher-rates-11665658801&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Greg Ip writes&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;In 2018, the Bank of England investigated whether a big rise in interest rates would trigger a cascade of forced selling by bond investors, destabilizing the financial system. The answer was no,&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;That they &lt;i&gt;did&lt;/i&gt; think about it, and they missed it anyway is even more damning for the regulate-risks project.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a name=&#39;more&#39;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Part of the explanation:&amp;nbsp;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;even if long-term rates rose a full percentage point in a week, which had never happened in records going back to 1990.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the days surrounding the British government’s tax-cut announcement on Sept. 23, yields on British government bonds, called gilts, gyrated as much as 1.27 points in a single day&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is part of the problem of regulation. Regulators test a single number, 1.00000 percent rise. But 1.27%? The world ends. Also it&#39;s fairly easy to make a strategy that is safe up to 1.0000 percent but blows up at 1.0001 percent.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;“The speed and scale of the moves in gilt yields was unprecedented,” the bank explained in a letter to Parliament. The refrain sounded familiar: the stock market crash of 1987, the near-failure of hedge fund Long-Term Capital Management in 1998, and the housing and mortgage crisis of 2007-09 were all precipitated by financial prices moving violently, by magnitudes outside historical experience.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Isn&#39;t the point of regulation and stress testing to worry about &quot;unprecedented&quot; events? After all, one might trust markets to think about precedented events. And, as the rest of the paragraph points out, it does seem like we&#39;re getting 100 year floods every 2 or 3 years these days.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The regulators even thought about derivatives and margin. Kudos. They just got the answer wrong.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;In its November, 2018 financial stability report, the Bank of England included a lengthy analysis of leverage at pension funds, hedge funds, insurance companies and other “nonbanks.” It was mostly concerned that margin calls could lead to forced sales of assets that the market couldn’t absorb without big price moves. It concluded any such selling would be small “as a proportion of the total demand on market liquidity,” even if rates rose a full percentage point in a single day or week, which “has never been experienced in 10-year sterling swap rates looking back to 1990. Even over a month, it would be a 1-in-1,000 event,” plenty of time for a relatively smooth adjustment, BOE wrote.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Is it cheeky to point out that climate risk to the financial system has never happened in 1000 years? &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;In part thanks to those benign assumptions, the notional value of LDIs soared from £400 billion in 2011 to £1.6 trillion, equivalent to $1.7 trillion, last year, a staggering sum. This indirectly put downward pressure on long-term interest rates, making investors’ expectation of low rates partly self-fulfilling. But as high inflation sent rates higher this year, the opposite happened. LDI positions began to lose money. The jump in yields following the tax-cut announcement triggered widespread margin calls and forced liquidation of positions. A strategy that had once amplified downward pressure on rates is now doing the opposite.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;When regulators bless risk taking, that absolves market participants of a lot of due diligence. Like the FDA approving a pill. So regulatory blindness can make matters even worse.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Again, it&#39;s not the people, it&#39;s the system. Allowing massive leverage but trusting regulators to regulate risk is broken. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;***&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A lesson in bond yields vs. bond prices for your MBA class.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mike Johannes at Columbia sends a great trio of graphs:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEiSRaKIg3uU9kYjpz7SrKnfgC8AMHBpTl0HGiB9ppqo4iU2cmC_b-k3-R_WjBKkc_UU5UVOUN1yTKN8XIIAbnvjzjO2mdSODEHC8TyG2H52EzKE4O2Hf9uwcb60ej1S-R_bvqlGKFa_quAaqrpTLD2bk4feM_stHVu9tL_nAWRUN3dHytHcMc-1Ce4/s1916/image001.gif&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;910&quot; data-original-width=&quot;1916&quot; height=&quot;304&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEiSRaKIg3uU9kYjpz7SrKnfgC8AMHBpTl0HGiB9ppqo4iU2cmC_b-k3-R_WjBKkc_UU5UVOUN1yTKN8XIIAbnvjzjO2mdSODEHC8TyG2H52EzKE4O2Hf9uwcb60ej1S-R_bvqlGKFa_quAaqrpTLD2bk4feM_stHVu9tL_nAWRUN3dHytHcMc-1Ce4/w640-h304/image001.gif&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is the UK sovereign yield curve. Reading from the bottom, 28, 6, 2 months ago, and now. Looking at the long end, it rises from 1% to a bit over 3%. 3% long-term yields used to be considered very low. This is a disaster? Aha, at low yields, small rises in yield mean big declines in prices. Here are the prices:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEhApHGz3OKkXqK0OrjgxHp8FsjfcBtpaOUEsClYOpyLut5YWQr4gHvgNwtmJ07BCJ__xT7kPi9QCRSrH77Ub407Y4nk1dr8ZHz7DLI0c3iFYK2t-hYB48xGCnpYoirknUAm0gYueNEvOrmeoN03oqRQPQnPUf7w0WB5Ls8EXTkCko4G3Yc0U7OklOo/s1916/screenshot_1665409436027%20(002).gif&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;910&quot; data-original-width=&quot;1916&quot; height=&quot;304&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEhApHGz3OKkXqK0OrjgxHp8FsjfcBtpaOUEsClYOpyLut5YWQr4gHvgNwtmJ07BCJ__xT7kPi9QCRSrH77Ub407Y4nk1dr8ZHz7DLI0c3iFYK2t-hYB48xGCnpYoirknUAm0gYueNEvOrmeoN03oqRQPQnPUf7w0WB5Ls8EXTkCko4G3Yc0U7OklOo/w640-h304/screenshot_1665409436027%20(002).gif&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The price of nominal bonds has gone from 100 to 29!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEjBW1pTPD6d_lInnb4wrsd-Az-hlc-30l5qtrxPrvAOXcBIaVQ_gRM4jYkVXk2ZIU2nXinNugDxzfHHXtmlKwX_QCFbevPD_8DmhZAATkHbZA7H6N_99vUyXmKkd1ki8TiCWBznowwzosFlM3qVATLmWd68kZt9dvmuHaxEotdhnpl6_ecDSrtgD4g/s1916/screenshot_1665409352764%20(002).gif&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;910&quot; data-original-width=&quot;1916&quot; height=&quot;304&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEjBW1pTPD6d_lInnb4wrsd-Az-hlc-30l5qtrxPrvAOXcBIaVQ_gRM4jYkVXk2ZIU2nXinNugDxzfHHXtmlKwX_QCFbevPD_8DmhZAATkHbZA7H6N_99vUyXmKkd1ki8TiCWBznowwzosFlM3qVATLmWd68kZt9dvmuHaxEotdhnpl6_ecDSrtgD4g/w640-h304/screenshot_1665409352764%20(002).gif&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;The price of indexed bonds went from 400 to 100.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now time to say something nice: The UK government made out like a bandit here. I&#39;ve been yelling for over a decade that the US should issue long term bonds, precisely to insure against interest rate rises. The UK did that. On a mark to market basis, bondholder loss=government gain. The UK locked in a lot of astoundingly low-interest borrowing. Pensions may be in trouble, but long term debt is great for governments. So long, that is, as the government doesn&#39;t turn around and bail out everyone to whom it sold long term debt!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;*****&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Update:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the comments, SRP points to a great post by &lt;a href=&quot;https://streetwiseprofessor.com/clearing-is-not-a-harmless-bunny-i-told-you-that-i-told-you-that-i-told-you-ad-infinitum-that-i-told-you-so/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Streetwise Professor&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;nbsp;AKA Craig Pirrong, who argues that derivatives margin was the central problem, not leverage. In his story, a typical pension fund has fixed long term liabilities, pensions. Rather than buy bonds, borrow against bonds, and invest in stocks, as I asserted, the typical fund just buys stocks and then a big receive-fixed pay-floating swap to cover its pension obligations. It&#39;s the same thing economically, but achieved via the swap contract. Now, interest rates rise, and the swap contract needs massive cash collateral. I hope I got this right.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;The instability was centered on UK pension funds engaged in a strategy called Liability Directed Investment (LDI)–which should now be renamed Liquidity Danger Investment. In a nutshell, in LDI defined benefit pension funds hedge the interest rate risk in their liabilities through interest rate swaps that are cleared or otherwise margined daily on a mark-to-market basis, rather than investing in fixed income securities that generate cash flows that match the liabilities. The funds hold non-fixed income assets (sometimes referred to as “growth assets”) in lieu of fixed income. ...&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;On a MTM basis, the funds are hedged: a rise in interest rates causes a decline in the present value of the liabilities, which matches a decline in the value of the swaps. Even if there is a duration match, however, there is not a liquidity match. A rise in interest rates generates no cash inflow on the liabilities (even though they have declined in value), but the clearing/margining of the swaps leads to a variation margin outflow: the funds have to stump up cash to meet VM obligations.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;And this has happened in a big way due to interest rate increases driven by central bank tightening and the deteriorating fiscal situation in the UK (which has been exacerbated substantially by the energy situation, and the British government’s commitment to absorb a large fraction of energy costs). This led to big margin calls . . . which the funds did not have cash to cover. So, cue a fire sale: the funds dumped their most liquid assets–UK government gilts–which overwhelmed the risk bearing capacity/liquidity of that market, leading to a further spurt in interest rates . . . which led to more VM obligations. Etc., etc., etc.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;But note here that the funds have to have substantial gilts to sell. So they&#39;re not entirely investing in equities and swapping the interest rates.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;The BofE piece also suggests that the underlying issue here is pension fund underfunding. In essence, the pension funds needed to jack up returns to close their funding gap. So instead of investing in fixed income assets with cash flows that mirrored those of its pension liabilities, the funds invested in higher returning assets like equities. Just investing in fixed income would have locked in the funding gap: investing in equities increased the odds of becoming fully funded. But just investing in equities alone would have subjected the funds to substantial interest rate risk. So the LDI strategies were intended to immunize them against this risk.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><link rel='replies' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://johnhcochrane.blogspot.com/feeds/5414580019437232550/comments/default' title='Post Comments'/><link rel='replies' type='text/html' href='https://johnhcochrane.blogspot.com/2022/10/more-uk-finance-regulatory-failure.html#comment-form' title='12 Comments'/><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/582368152716771238/posts/default/5414580019437232550'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/582368152716771238/posts/default/5414580019437232550'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://johnhcochrane.blogspot.com/2022/10/more-uk-finance-regulatory-failure.html' title='More UK finance regulatory failure'/><author><name>John H. Cochrane</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/04842601651429471525</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='25' height='32' src='//4.bp.blogspot.com/-hxC_w91OloY/X8aKsZcuFcI/AAAAAAAADHs/CANi5RE5-n8t7QGX1CzX9vgEg1Bd22tpwCK4BGAYYCw/s220/john_cochrane_forweb.jpg'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEiSRaKIg3uU9kYjpz7SrKnfgC8AMHBpTl0HGiB9ppqo4iU2cmC_b-k3-R_WjBKkc_UU5UVOUN1yTKN8XIIAbnvjzjO2mdSODEHC8TyG2H52EzKE4O2Hf9uwcb60ej1S-R_bvqlGKFa_quAaqrpTLD2bk4feM_stHVu9tL_nAWRUN3dHytHcMc-1Ce4/s72-w640-h304-c/image001.gif" height="72" width="72"/><thr:total>12</thr:total></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-582368152716771238.post-1649604217690395350</id><published>2022-10-14T09:00:00.003-05:00</published><updated>2022-10-14T09:50:08.889-05:00</updated><category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Banking"/><category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Commentary"/><category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Economists"/><category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Finance"/><category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Financial Reform"/><category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Nobel"/><title type='text'>Nobels and financial crises</title><content type='html'>&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;(At &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nationalreview.com/2022/10/what-this-years-nobel-economists-can-teach-us-about-financial-crises/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;National Review&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;What This Year’s Nobel Economists Can Teach Us about Financial Crises&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This week, economists are celebrating the Nobel Prize given to Ben Bernanke, Doug Diamond and Phil Dybvig for their work on banking.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Bernanke pointed out that banks matter. In the Great Depression, banks failed, and there was nobody left who knew how to make new loans. The economy contracted, not just for lack of money or for animal spirits of investors, but for lack of credit. Diamond and Dybvig wrote the classic economic model of bank runs, which shows how banks can fail even when they are “illiquid” rather than “insolvent.” The logic works like this: The bank has invested our money in illiquid projects, so if I suspect others are going to run to get their money out, I run to get mine out first before it’s all gone.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But it is no insult to say that these are not eternal verities. The papers were written about 40 years ago. Each was the launching pad for a vast and important investigation. Indeed, Nobel Prizes largely recognize that sort of lasting influence on subsequent work. But that subsequent investigation opens new possibilities. Newton is no less profound for having been followed by Einstein. Each also sought to understand the world as it was, which is how one should start. But there are other possibilities for how the world might be — and how it might be better.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a name=&#39;more&#39;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Economics might seem obvious. George Bailey and Michael Banks understood bank runs, didn’t they? Economic analysis lets us see all the ingredients that a banking crisis needs, and therefore how they might be avoided. Bank failure and bank runs are actually fragile phenomena. A lot has to go wrong. There are lots of ways to fix them [i.e. not just bailouts and deposit insurance].&amp;nbsp;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Bankruptcy does not mean a giant crater where there once was a bank. It means reorganization. Stockholders and creditors lose money, and valuable operations continue under new management. Why, if the Farmers and Mechanics bank of Nowhere Nebraska failed in the Great Depression, did Chase or Citi not swoop in, buy the assets at a discount, and keep employed the people that Bernanke pointed out had unique and detailed knowledge of how to make profitable loans? Because interstate and branch banking was illegal. Banks could not list stock on exchanges, and had to find new capital from local businesspeople, whose businesses were failing. But all that has changed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Diamond and Dybvig’s 1983 article, being a beautiful essay in economic theory, is even more stark. As you read the article, you will be struck by the number of assumptions needed to get a bank run going. Each is necessary. If people are lining up to get money out, why does the bank not borrow against its valuable illiquid assets? Before the Fed, clearinghouses were set up just for this purpose. Why does the bank not issue additional equity? Why can’t the bank sell loans, rather than accept half-built houses that it does not know how to finish? Why doesn’t the bank get money to invest by issuing floating-value securities instead of first-come-first-serve deposits? Why not &amp;nbsp;suspend payments? All of these channels and more must be turned off to get a bank run going. Showing clearly just what it takes to get a run going is Diamond and Dybvig’s masterful insight.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Diamond and Dybvig showed how deposit insurance, the expedient implemented in the 1930s, could stop bank runs. If the government stands behind deposits, there is no need to run, One concludes more generally that government as a lender of last resort, creditor bailouts, and government recapitalization can stop crises, as Bernanke showed personally in 2008.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But do not conclude that these are the only, or best ways to stop financial crises. [They didn&#39;t say that.] Moreover, deposit insurance and bailouts stop a crisis once it is happening. But they lead to too much risk-taking by financial institutions, and by depositors who know they don’t have to worry about the bank’s investments. We need a better system.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The current patch is to have regulators try to keep banks from taking too many risks. But we have seen that mechanism fail over and over again. Regulators failed to see mortgages build up; they failed to see that Greek debt might not be so hot for banks to hold; they failed to “stress test” a pandemic, leading to a second massive bailout; they failed to see the possibility of an energy price increase. They didn’t even fix money-market funds, bailed out again in 2020, and the simplest to fix. Last week, we saw that U.K. regulators failed to see plain-vanilla leverage in pension funds. We shall soon see who else is exposed to sharp interest-rate rises in ways that the regulators have not foreseen.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The model — allow lots of run-prone assets, stop runs with deposit insurance and bailouts, stop risk-taking with regulation — has run its course. The next bailout will be so big, it is questionable that our governments can do it without major inflation or sovereign-credit stress.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It’s time for another idea from the 1930s, and analyzed in the 2000s with the kinds of contemporary tools our Nobelists brought forth: Banks should fund risky investments by issuing equity, now extremely liquid. Run-prone securities like deposits should be backed 100 percent by reserves or short-term Treasury securities. (Details in &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.johnhcochrane.com/research-all/toward-a-run-free-financial-systemnbsp&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Toward a Run-Free Financial System&lt;/a&gt;.&quot;)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It’s a simple model; it requires next to no regulation; and we can end private financial crises forever. (“Private” because sovereign debt is another matter, and another sort of crisis.) Bernanke, Diamond, and Dybvig’s work paved the way for this current insight. We can appreciate their analysis without setting in stone the solutions that they analyzed, which were largely just the ones that had already been settled on by previous political decisions.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><link rel='replies' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://johnhcochrane.blogspot.com/feeds/1649604217690395350/comments/default' title='Post Comments'/><link rel='replies' type='text/html' href='https://johnhcochrane.blogspot.com/2022/10/nobels-and-financial-crises.html#comment-form' title='14 Comments'/><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/582368152716771238/posts/default/1649604217690395350'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/582368152716771238/posts/default/1649604217690395350'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://johnhcochrane.blogspot.com/2022/10/nobels-and-financial-crises.html' title='Nobels and financial crises'/><author><name>John H. Cochrane</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/04842601651429471525</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='25' height='32' src='//4.bp.blogspot.com/-hxC_w91OloY/X8aKsZcuFcI/AAAAAAAADHs/CANi5RE5-n8t7QGX1CzX9vgEg1Bd22tpwCK4BGAYYCw/s220/john_cochrane_forweb.jpg'/></author><thr:total>14</thr:total></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-582368152716771238.post-7899214761100277728</id><published>2022-10-10T09:18:00.006-05:00</published><updated>2022-10-10T09:18:58.198-05:00</updated><category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Commentary"/><category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Politics and economics"/><title type='text'>Mind the store</title><content type='html'>&lt;p&gt;On the same page in today&#39;s WSJ:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;One third of DC bus riders &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wsj.com/articles/the-d-c-bus-fare-is-a-polite-suggestion-evasion-budget-shortfall-enforcement-action-virginia-maryland-11665341012?mod=opinion_lead_pos4&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;don&#39;t bother to pay the fare&lt;/a&gt;. Also in &lt;a href=&quot;https://nypost.com/2022/05/22/mta-losing-119m-and-counting-to-fare-evasion-officials-say/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;New York&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The State Department is so dysfunctional that &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wsj.com/articles/the-other-immigration-crisis-endless-visa-waits-delays-embassies-consulates-processing-reform-canada-businesses-talent-11665338857?mod=opinion_lead_pos9&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;processing visa requests takes years&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;In New Delhi, an appointment for a nonimmigrant visitor visa takes more than 800 calendar days, or nearly three years; for a student visa, nearly 450 days. The Cato Institute found that more than half of U.S. embassies and consulates world-wide have a waiting time greater than six months for a visitor or business visa appointment, compared with 1% before the pandemic. More than 1 in 4 have a waiting time of a year or more.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;In March Congress enacted the EB-5 Reform and Integrity Act of 2022 to streamline the immigrant-visa process for foreign investors who commit significant capital to the U.S. But that reform is swamped by slow administration. U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services advises applicants that 80% of cases (excluding Chinese nationals, who take even longer to process) are resolved within 52 months, or nearly 4½ years.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;A central part of the immigration problem is that asylum claims languish in courts for years. And regular criminal courts also take years. Either spend the money to administer the laws, or change the laws (immigration and visas in particular) to not require administration that we can&#39;t provide. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;These are just two tips of the iceberg of general incompetence in many parts of our government. &amp;nbsp;Not all: I&#39;ve had some pleasant interactions with very well run low-level government offices lately. It can be done.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Wanted for the elections: politicians who will campaign simply to administer competently and remedy dysfunction. Efficient government offices, court systems, transit systems and so forth are also crucial infrastructure. Don&#39;t lead new grand causes, just mind the store.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</content><link rel='replies' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://johnhcochrane.blogspot.com/feeds/7899214761100277728/comments/default' title='Post Comments'/><link rel='replies' type='text/html' href='https://johnhcochrane.blogspot.com/2022/10/mind-store.html#comment-form' title='12 Comments'/><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/582368152716771238/posts/default/7899214761100277728'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/582368152716771238/posts/default/7899214761100277728'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://johnhcochrane.blogspot.com/2022/10/mind-store.html' title='Mind the store'/><author><name>John H. Cochrane</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/04842601651429471525</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='25' height='32' src='//4.bp.blogspot.com/-hxC_w91OloY/X8aKsZcuFcI/AAAAAAAADHs/CANi5RE5-n8t7QGX1CzX9vgEg1Bd22tpwCK4BGAYYCw/s220/john_cochrane_forweb.jpg'/></author><thr:total>12</thr:total></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-582368152716771238.post-5167912231335591442</id><published>2022-10-06T16:49:00.003-05:00</published><updated>2022-10-06T16:58:00.468-05:00</updated><category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Commentary"/><category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Finance"/><category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Financial Reform"/><title type='text'>UK finance fable update</title><content type='html'>&lt;p&gt;Update to my &lt;a href=&quot;https://johnhcochrane.blogspot.com/2022/09/a-familiar-finance-fable-in-uk-bonds.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;previous post on the UK treasury imbrogli&lt;/a&gt;o:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://committees.parliament.uk/publications/30136/documents/174584/default/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;The Bank of England explains,&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;saying about as much as I did. Pension funds levered up, lost money when treasury prices fell, needed to post collateral, and then started selling en masse. The explanation starts with lovely central-bankerese (my italics):&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;Against the backdrop of an&lt;i&gt;&amp;nbsp;unprecedented&amp;nbsp;&lt;/i&gt;[really? Literally never?]&amp;nbsp;&lt;i&gt;repricing&lt;/i&gt;&amp;nbsp;[translation: fall in prices] in UK assets, the Bank announced a temporary and targeted intervention on Wednesday 28 September to&amp;nbsp;&lt;i&gt;restore market functioning&amp;nbsp;&lt;/i&gt;in long-dated government bonds and&amp;nbsp;reduce risks from &lt;i&gt;contagion to credit conditions&amp;nbsp;&lt;/i&gt;for UK households and businesses.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;It goes on to a hilarious graph to explain how you lose money when you borrow to lever up a portfolio:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEgAI1cFcZcjac6FBY6qdOg1nw5IGU9Mz-v1p2PeNE_VGqmY7CHavRLY_PBmLjAvLT9SWO98ZxbjiUYs9PZuFPOt8aT5CzPilvuCJYXTMHCFAOKFIqcW5Aak7g9LZFk1wknONctBKKgl-hP6S3_UpPn6OpmORmb7LftRxID1nQZziVnUTpWwPwZJiR4/Screen%20Shot%202022-10-06%20at%202.14.03%20PM.png&quot; style=&quot;display: block; padding: 1em 0px; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;0&quot; data-original-width=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEgAI1cFcZcjac6FBY6qdOg1nw5IGU9Mz-v1p2PeNE_VGqmY7CHavRLY_PBmLjAvLT9SWO98ZxbjiUYs9PZuFPOt8aT5CzPilvuCJYXTMHCFAOKFIqcW5Aak7g9LZFk1wknONctBKKgl-hP6S3_UpPn6OpmORmb7LftRxID1nQZziVnUTpWwPwZJiR4/s600/Screen%20Shot%202022-10-06%20at%202.14.03%20PM.png&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt; Why is this so funny? Notice on the left hand side a gap between assets and liabilities, yet in the fourth bar there is a positive &quot;capital&quot; bar. &amp;nbsp;Accounting 101, assets = liabilities, including capital. I guess UK regulations operate differently.&amp;nbsp;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;But enough fun, let&#39;s get to the point. In answer to my question, roughly &quot;you&#39;re supposed to be this great gargantuan regulator, how could you miss something so simple?,&quot; the bank offers, deep in the report, this:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;div&gt;The FPC has previously identified underlying vulnerabilities in the system of market- based finance, a number of which were exposed in the ‘dash for cash’ episode in March 20202. The Bank and the FPC strongly support and engage with the important programme of domestic and international work to understand and, where necessary, address those vulnerabilities.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;The FPC conducted an assessment of the risks from leverage in the non-bank financial system in 2018, and highlighted the need to monitor risks associated with the use of leverage by LDI funds.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;div&gt;It&#39;s so nice you&#39;ve been studying this. But then double, how did this happen?&amp;nbsp;&lt;span&gt;&lt;a name=&#39;more&#39;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;div&gt;Whilst the PRA regulates bank counterparties of LDI funds, the Bank does not directly regulate pension schemes, LDI managers or LDI funds. Pension schemes and LDI managers are regulated by The Pensions Regulator (TPR) and the Financial Conduct Authority (FCA). LDI funds themselves are typically based outside the UK. In this context, given our financial stability mandate, and as stated in the FPC’s November 2018 Financial Stability Report, the Bank has worked with other domestic regulators – including TPR and the FCA – on enhancing monitoring of the risks. That included working with TPR on a survey of DB pension schemes in 2019, and prompting work to improve DB pension liquidity risk management. Given that LDI funds are largely not based in the UK, this also underlines the importance of work on this topic being pursued internationally.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;div&gt;In short, &amp;nbsp;&quot;where is your homework?&quot; &quot;Jimmy was supposed to write up the lab report.&quot; Really, though, if you were working on it, and knew about it, it&#39;s doubly shocking that nobody did anything about it.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;div&gt;... it should also be recognised that the scale and speed of repricing leading up to Wednesday 28 September far exceeded historical moves, and therefore exceeded price moves that are likely to have been part of risk management practices or regulatory stress tests. &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;div&gt;The 30 year nominal gilt yield rose by 160 basis points in just a few days, having only had a yield of around 1.2% at the start of the year. On Wednesday 28 September the intraday range of the yield on 30 year gilts of 127 basis points was higher than the annual range for 30 year gilts in all but 4 of the last 27 years. In the 2018 assessment noted above, the FPC assessed the capacity of the biggest derivatives users among UK pension schemes to cover the posting of variation margin calls on OTC interest rate derivatives from up to a 100 basis point instantaneous increases in rates across all maturities and in all currencies. Other tests and risk management practices have similarly assumed a maximum of a 100 basis point move in such a short time period.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;div&gt;In short, once again &quot;it&#39;s a 100 year flood that nobody could have imagined.&quot; The sort of flood that seems to happen about once a year. And 100 basis points is an awfully round number. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;div&gt;There has been significant progress, both domestically and internationally, on the regulation and monitoring of the non-bank sector in recent years. Much of this has been led by the Financial Stability Board, which set out its analysis of risks relating to non- banks and a program of work last year and is due to report on next steps in November. &amp;nbsp;Through the work of the FPC and the Bank more widely, as well as that of the FCA, the UK has been actively engaging with this programme. This episode underlines the necessity of this work leading to effective policy outcomes.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;div&gt;The eternal call for more research.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;A last thought. If some people are clearly selling in distress, why are others not buying? Why is your fire sale not my buying opportunity. Well, imagine if every Saturday, when garage sales start at 9 am, the Fed or Bank of England swoops in and buys up all the good stuff at inflated prices. There is then no point in cruising the garage sales any more, and then every time someone wants to sell anything the Fed or Bank of England &lt;i&gt;has &lt;/i&gt;to swoop in and buy.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Why do Chase, Citi, Goldman Sachs, or multi-strategy &amp;nbsp;hedge funds not keep some spare balance sheet capacity around to swoop in and buy in these events? Well, knowledge that the Fed and Bank of England will always swoop in first and cut off the profits might well be a part of the answer. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;I repeat. The model that financial institutions can lever up, but omniscient regulators will foresee risks, is irretrievably broken. If you need more research on this one, we&#39;ll never get there. We are firmly in the regime of lever to your heart&#39;s content, the Fed and BoE, and thus taxpayers, will offer a free put option on losses. Until, someday soon, they too run out of bailout money.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;I should change the tone of this post -- let us not blame the BoE and Fed. They are smart, they are human, they are doing their best. It&#39;s just that the best that these great people can do, with 15 years since 2008 to do it, is not enough for this most simple task. And woefully inadequate for the much larger task they have set themselves.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='replies' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://johnhcochrane.blogspot.com/feeds/5167912231335591442/comments/default' title='Post Comments'/><link rel='replies' type='text/html' href='https://johnhcochrane.blogspot.com/2022/10/uk-finance-fable-update.html#comment-form' title='18 Comments'/><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/582368152716771238/posts/default/5167912231335591442'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/582368152716771238/posts/default/5167912231335591442'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://johnhcochrane.blogspot.com/2022/10/uk-finance-fable-update.html' title='UK finance fable update'/><author><name>John H. Cochrane</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/04842601651429471525</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='25' height='32' src='//4.bp.blogspot.com/-hxC_w91OloY/X8aKsZcuFcI/AAAAAAAADHs/CANi5RE5-n8t7QGX1CzX9vgEg1Bd22tpwCK4BGAYYCw/s220/john_cochrane_forweb.jpg'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEgAI1cFcZcjac6FBY6qdOg1nw5IGU9Mz-v1p2PeNE_VGqmY7CHavRLY_PBmLjAvLT9SWO98ZxbjiUYs9PZuFPOt8aT5CzPilvuCJYXTMHCFAOKFIqcW5Aak7g9LZFk1wknONctBKKgl-hP6S3_UpPn6OpmORmb7LftRxID1nQZziVnUTpWwPwZJiR4/s72-c/Screen%20Shot%202022-10-06%20at%202.14.03%20PM.png" height="72" width="72"/><thr:total>18</thr:total></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-582368152716771238.post-9009626193680467803</id><published>2022-10-04T19:34:00.006-05:00</published><updated>2022-10-06T10:11:12.948-05:00</updated><category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Commentary"/><category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Economists"/><category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Energy"/><category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Environment"/><category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Finance"/><category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Monetary Policy"/><title type='text'>Out of the box risks</title><content type='html'>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://policytensor.substack.com/p/a-nuclear-zugzwang&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Policy Tensor&lt;/a&gt; on the consequences of a Russian nuke (&lt;a href=&quot;https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2022/10/monday-assorted-links-374.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;HT Marginal Revolution&lt;/a&gt;) was very interesting:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Consider the least escalatory option, that of a “demonstration detonation”: Russian forces air-burst (to avoid the nuclear fallout that results from a ground detonation) a tactical nuclear weapon with sub-kiloton yield (ie, no bigger than a big conventional weapon) over uninhabited territory somewhere in south-eastern Ukraine. This would be consistent with Russia’s “escalate-to-deescalate” doctrine ... What happens then?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Precisely because it is such a dramatic break with precedent, even a demonstration detonation would radically change the character of the Russo-Western conflict over Ukraine. New Yorkers and Berliners etc, are likely to flee the cities. Everywhere, in Europe and America, supermarkets would likely empty within hours. Many local authorities may institute civil defense measures, even as federal governments everywhere urge calm. A widespread breakdown of law and order would be a real possibility; especially in America, where it would be attended by partisan passions and finger-pointing....&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Not to bash a hobby horse, but the Fed, SEC, FDIC and so forth are now obsessed with climate risk to the financial system. Chatting with colleagues at the Fed, it is astonishing how much and how detailed the research is in to climate (really weather) scenarios, much of this directed by higher-ups.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Today I will not criticize that effort. Maybe pianos do fall from the sky. &amp;nbsp;What is striking to me, verified in every conversation I have with people in these institutions (please prove me wrong!) is that nobody at these institutions&amp;nbsp;&lt;i&gt;is doing any analysis of any other risk.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This seems like a useful one, for example. Any nuclear explosion is going to make the ATMs go dark. Is anyone at the Fed gaming this out? What if (when) China blockades Taiwan? What about a massive cyberattack on the banking system, a deliberate attempt to cause a run (Russian disinformation that a major bank has had all its account information wiped out, get your cash now)? A new pandemic that looks more like 1350 than the flu? &amp;nbsp;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a name=&#39;more&#39;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So a positive suggestion: Let the climate risk to the financial system efforts continue, but broaden them to all out of the box shocks to the financial system. Game them out, then let&#39;s assign some probability. I would guess this one at 5% or so. It&#39;s certainly worth asking, &quot;are we ready?&quot;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I do not worry so much about the massive climate financial risk effort. If they do it honestly, I suspect they will only produce careful qualitative refutation that says climate, for all its problems, is not a risk to the financial system. A lot of time gets wasted in central bank research anyway. But a good worry about climate-financial risk taking over all the attention is that nobody is paying any attention to far more likely scenarios. As the UK was not watching plain old collateral in derivatives contracts, and we&#39;ll see about whether the rest of Europe managed to oversee plain old borrow short lend long risk.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;(To clarify, after some comments. Yes, economists are writing papers about this sort of thing. But it is not even conceived of in central bank risk analysis and systemic stress tests.)&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;BTW, on a game theory note, I&#39;m less persuaded &amp;nbsp;by the rest of Policy Tensor&#39;s argument that the Russian nuclear step is quite so likely. Look one more step down the game tree. The goal is to restore Russia&#39;s status as world power. But losing a war in Ukraine that can only be stopped by a demonstrated resort to nuclear terrorism is not a long-run strategy to be a great power. It would be a Pearl-Harbor wake up to the West. And Russia would be even more a pariah, and in fact show even more evidently how utterly powerless it is in any other way. The goal of great-power respect would not be achieved. It would only become absolutely everybody&#39;s enemy.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Update:&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Correction. There is in fact a good deal of attention to cybersecurity risks. There is for example an&amp;nbsp;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Calibri;&quot;&gt;Office of Cybersecurity and Critical Infrastructure Protection at the Department of Treasury. There is&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;no need to overstate the issue. Thanks to correspondent.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</content><link rel='replies' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://johnhcochrane.blogspot.com/feeds/9009626193680467803/comments/default' title='Post Comments'/><link rel='replies' type='text/html' href='https://johnhcochrane.blogspot.com/2022/10/out-of-box-risks.html#comment-form' title='14 Comments'/><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/582368152716771238/posts/default/9009626193680467803'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/582368152716771238/posts/default/9009626193680467803'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://johnhcochrane.blogspot.com/2022/10/out-of-box-risks.html' title='Out of the box risks'/><author><name>John H. Cochrane</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/04842601651429471525</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='25' height='32' src='//4.bp.blogspot.com/-hxC_w91OloY/X8aKsZcuFcI/AAAAAAAADHs/CANi5RE5-n8t7QGX1CzX9vgEg1Bd22tpwCK4BGAYYCw/s220/john_cochrane_forweb.jpg'/></author><thr:total>14</thr:total></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-582368152716771238.post-6998827941075226110</id><published>2022-10-03T12:57:00.009-05:00</published><updated>2022-10-10T09:02:43.827-05:00</updated><category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Commentary"/><category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Economists"/><category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Nobel"/><title type='text'>Sowell Nobel Redux</title><content type='html'>&lt;p&gt;Nobel Prize season is around the corner. Last year, &lt;a href=&quot;https://johnhcochrane.blogspot.com/2021/10/sowell-nobel.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;I blogged in favor of Tom Sowell&lt;/a&gt;. I update, with some edits.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dear Nobel Committee: How can you&amp;nbsp;&lt;i&gt;not&lt;/i&gt;&amp;nbsp;give the prize to&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tsowell.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Tom Sowell&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt;this year?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tom&#39;s work evidently merits a Nobel purely as a contribution to economics, covering many issues. But we can&#39;t ignore what year it is. Race is a forefront issue of our time. How can you&lt;i&gt;&amp;nbsp;not&lt;/i&gt;&amp;nbsp;give the prize to the living economist who has written the most penetrating economic analysis of race?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yes, he&#39;s a free-market economist, and thus characterized as conservative. His deeply fact-based research is &amp;nbsp;uncomfortable to The Narrative. For example, groups that white people cannot tell apart have profoundly different outcomes in the US. Nigerian immigrants are among the highest achieving ethnic groups in the US. West Indians do well. Asians of different waves of immigration and different countries -- Chinese, Laotians, Vietnamese -- show profound differences. Tom has thousands of such facts, impeccably documented.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But you&#39;re the Nobel Committee. You care about Science, about facts, about logic, not about cheers from the Davos crowd. You care about issues that are important, as you should, but you do not care about embracing one or the other political narrative&#39;s answers to those questions. You care about the reputation of your Prize, for courageously recognizing great research, even if its surprising conclusions upset established orders. And, to your credit, you have given the prize to economists of widely different political enthusiasms through the years. &amp;nbsp;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a name=&#39;more&#39;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Why not? I grant, Tom&#39;s work is unusual. The Nobel Prize is, justly, conservative (that&#39;s praise in my vocabulary). Prizes prosper by widespread view that they are given to people who deserve them. Most (not all) Nobels in economics go to people who, if you ask around the faculty lunchrooms at the top economics department, are those who people would instantly mention. And rightly so. But that fact gives a bit of tilt toward methodological work. People in their productive 30s and 40s are likely to mention their mentors who gave them the tools to write the papers that got them where they are. It gives a bit of tilt toward people who produce a lot of graduate students. &amp;nbsp;Tom did not mentor an army of young assistant professors, nor did he invent a theoretical framework or econometric technique. He writes books, and taught us about how the world works. (&lt;i&gt;Knowledge and Decisions&lt;/i&gt;&amp;nbsp;is an excellent work of theory, but not an extendable mathematical framework.)&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But the Nobel isn&#39;t always like that, and does occasionally celebrate persuasive and important fact-based and logic-based books. Indeed, as I infer, the Prize occasionally makes a bit of a subtle point about what&#39;s important and what kind of work the rest of us might do. That Tom&#39;s work is important, and his style of work is worth emulating is a useful point. And perhaps the committee is a bit aghast at the wokeness that is starting to infect even economics.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For example, the American Economics Association, via its&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.aeaweb.org/news/member-announcements-june-5-2020&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;statement from the American Economic Association Executive Committee&lt;/a&gt;, has compiled an officially sanctioned &lt;a href=&quot;https://diversifyingecon.org/history-of-race-and-racism/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp;reading list on racism and the experience of Black Americans&lt;/a&gt;. Members of the AEA Executive Committee have pledged to continue to educate themselves in part by reading works from the list and to seek to integrate work by diverse authors in course syllabi, and &quot;ask all economists to make the same pledge.&quot; This list is in use at semi-mandatory &amp;nbsp;DEI training sessions, reportedly including the Federal Reserve. But this officially-endorsed reading list to this day brazenly omits Sowell. Or Walter Williams. Or Glenn Loury. Or Roland Fryer. &amp;nbsp;And here I am succumbing to racism that says the author&#39;s skin color matters to his or her or their conclusions. Or Gary Becker. Or Bob Fogel. Maybe the committee would like to say that Sowell and related work should be at least included on a comprehensive officially sanctioned reading list offered by an &lt;i&gt;economics&lt;/i&gt; association.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;While Tom is hardy, he is 92. None of us last forever. Nor does your opportunity to recognize one of the most important economists of our time. This is the year.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;********&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Update: If you don&#39;t know Tom, and don&#39;t want to face an overwhelming volume of primary sources, his&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Thomas_Sowell&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Wikipedia page&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;is not bad. Twitter commenters complain that he appears on Fox News. Well, Paul Krugman appears in the New York Times. Within a respectable range, really, we need to start keeping political commentary separate from scientific contribution, like other hobbies.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Update: Well, they didn&#39;t give it to Tom, but Bernanke, Diamond, Dybvig is a fine prize for great work.&lt;/p&gt;</content><link rel='replies' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://johnhcochrane.blogspot.com/feeds/6998827941075226110/comments/default' title='Post Comments'/><link rel='replies' type='text/html' href='https://johnhcochrane.blogspot.com/2022/10/sowell-nobel-redux.html#comment-form' title='29 Comments'/><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/582368152716771238/posts/default/6998827941075226110'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/582368152716771238/posts/default/6998827941075226110'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://johnhcochrane.blogspot.com/2022/10/sowell-nobel-redux.html' title='Sowell Nobel Redux'/><author><name>John H. Cochrane</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/04842601651429471525</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='25' height='32' src='//4.bp.blogspot.com/-hxC_w91OloY/X8aKsZcuFcI/AAAAAAAADHs/CANi5RE5-n8t7QGX1CzX9vgEg1Bd22tpwCK4BGAYYCw/s220/john_cochrane_forweb.jpg'/></author><thr:total>29</thr:total></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-582368152716771238.post-7035245267377066042</id><published>2022-09-30T11:10:00.012-05:00</published><updated>2022-10-06T16:50:14.921-05:00</updated><category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Commentary"/><category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Debt"/><category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Finance"/><title type='text'>A familiar finance fable in UK bonds </title><content type='html'>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-11264825/Is-real-scandal-financiers-able-risk-pensions-asks-GUY-ADAMS.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Guy Adams in the Daily Mail &lt;/a&gt;has an intriguing story of what&#39;s going on in UK bond markets. &amp;nbsp;It&#39;s intriguing because it&#39;s so utterly familiar. And it reveals that all the masses of regulation and armies of regulators aimed at preventing exactly this sort of thing from happening again and again have failed again.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;UC pensions take in contributions when people are young, invest them, and then pay out fixed amounts when people get old. They hold large quantities of government bonds, currently 1.5 trillion pounds per Adams. That&#39;s a good strategy: if you have fixed payments to make, invest in risk free assets that provide fixed payments, and ignore the mark to market. But it fell apart in a classic way.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Leverage&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As often is the case, however, they didn&#39;t have enough assets to pay out the promises. So... Lever up! Pensions used their government bonds as collateral, borrowed money, and invested that money in more government bonds or, to a lesser extent, in stocks or other investments.&amp;nbsp;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a name=&#39;more&#39;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So now rather than a portfolio that matches liabilities (pension payments) with assets (government bond coupons), you have a portfolio that is making a bet on declining interest rates and rising stock prices.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;How many times have CEOS and university presidents set (average) rate of return targets, and just levered up to meet them? Risk 101.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It paid off. For a while.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;in the ten years to January, while stocks recovered from the financial crisis, the proportion of pension schemes which were under-funded fell from 80 per cent to around 20 per cent.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;During the Covid crisis in 2020, the yield of gilts (then regarded as a ‘safe haven’) fell to almost zero, meaning that their value rose substantially.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yet, as ever in the world of investing, greater rewards tend to carry greater risk. And with pension funds becoming more and more comfortable using LDIs to dramatically ‘leverage’ their holdings – at times using them to purchase £3 of gilts for every £1 they actually invested – they would inevitably become sensitive to changes in market conditions. ...&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;I.e. rising interest rates. &amp;nbsp;This is a huge bet. The pensions are borrowing short term to buy long-term bonds. Small changes in long-term interest rates can imply huge changes in long-term bond prices.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;By early this week, gilts which had been worth £3.50 in January were valued at as little as 50p.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now wait a minute, you say, interest rates haven&#39;t gone up that much. But long term bond prices are very sensitive to small changes in interest rates, especially when interest rates are low. For example, a 30 year zero coupon bond paying 100 pounds is worth 100 pounds when the interest rate is zero. If the interest rate goes up to 2%, that is the same thing as the price going down to 100/(1.02)^30 = 55.2 pounds, half the original value. Borrowing to invest in long-term bonds is a very risky strategy on a mark to market basis.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Selling options&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;When interest rates are zero, they can&#39;t go down any more. So, you can see that leveraging in to long-term bonds in a time of low interest rates has a quite skewed distribution of returns. You can make a little bit of money most of the time, if interest rates stay low or go down a hair more. But when interest rates rise, you can lose a lot of money all of a sudden. This is a tried and true method of boosting fund performance. For a while. &quot;Write out of the money puts.&quot; &quot;Short volatility.&quot; &quot;Write insurance.&quot; &quot;Collect pennies in front of a steam roller.&quot; Then of course the grim reaper comes and it all falls apart massively.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Collateral&amp;nbsp;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Well, wait, you ask. Who cares about mark to market? The market value of the pension fund&#39;s liabilities -- the pensions -- has also gone down. The mismatch is &amp;nbsp;bad, but not that bad.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Oh yes it is. When the value of the government bonds used as collateral falls by half, the fund has to come up with&lt;i&gt; cash &lt;/i&gt;to cover the mark to market losses on their collateral:&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;This [loss] in turn meant that pension funds were required to hold less cash as collateral for the bonds they kept in LDIs, allowing more money to be returned to their pot.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Again, in plainer English. You have 1,000 pounds of bonds. You use that as collateral to borrow 1000 pounds, and invest in another 1000 pounds of bonds. The bond prices fall to 500 pounds. Now you have to come up with 500 pounds cash, right now, to replace the missing collateral on your loan. You must sell the &amp;nbsp;500 pounds of bonds you bought immediately. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;For pension funds which held LDIs, this caused immediate problems. The UK gilts they were using as collateral on other investments were suddenly worth an awful lot less and cash was needed to plug the gap. Unfortunately, the only way they could raise cash was to sell large quantities of gilts, which in turn had the effect of driving the price even lower.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is a risk-management failure that happens over and over. Even seemingly good hedges or ``arbitrage&#39;&#39; &amp;nbsp;strategies fall apart because you have to post extra collateral when markets move against you.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Spiral&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Of course, that meant they needed even more loot. And so a sort of vicious circle was created. ‘I have called it the death spiral,’ Mackenzie said last night. ‘That’s what we were in. A sort of volatility vortex. It became self-fulfilling. Pension funds were essentially eating themselves.’&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;For a few short hours, early on Wednesday, the market became effectively paralysed. That forced the Bank of England to take dramatic action, stepping in as a sort of ‘buyer of last resort’ and agreeing to plough about £65billion into gilts over the coming weeks.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;div&gt;Now wait a minute, you say, especially if you got your degree at the University of Chicago. If people are selling in a panic and driving prices down, why doesn&#39;t Goldman or Blackrock stop playing ESG games for 5 minutes and scoop up the bonds? Well, they don&#39;t, at least fully, and at the very high frequency we&#39;re taking about. Collateral has to be posted daily. &amp;nbsp;(Just why they don&#39;t is a very good question.)&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;i&gt;Creative finance&amp;nbsp;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The scheme was called &quot;Leveraged Liability-Driven Investments,&quot; and involved a lot of fees. I presume the fees and complexity are necessary to get around regulations that said funds have to hold government bonds to match their payouts and not take risks. Yes, we&#39;re holding those bonds. We just incidentally borrowed against them to buy something else, and unwind the regulation.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;The genius of these products was that, despite performing solidly, they looked extremely conservative – at least on paper. Government bonds are among the most reliable investments. The world of pensions is designed to be dull. While the sheer volume of gilts being packaged into these products was unprecedented, regulators and the vast majority of observers saw nothing in the way of red flags.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;But really, is it that hard to see though? &amp;nbsp;We teach every MBA the lesson of mortgage-backed securities held by &quot;special purpose vehicles&quot; that issued overnight debt and how that fell apart.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Prophets ignored&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Perhaps regulators can complain that nobody could see it coming. But as usual at least some people did see through the scheme.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;One day in May 2019, a Dutch financier named Hans Van Zwol hit ‘send’ on a document outlining what he suggested was a ‘terrible’ threat to the global economy....&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;... the bespectacled fund manager had become concerned about a range of complex products known in the trade as ‘Leveraged Liability-Driven Investments’ or LDIs.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yet neither the industry nor regulators seemed to act. Indeed, as recently as July, an article by a writer in the Financial Times noted that: ‘LDI managers claim that their activities pose no systemic risk and I read the Bank of England financial policy committee’s silence as agreement.’&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Events of recent days would, of course, prove them (and the Government) quite wrong. Negligent, even.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Well, prophets are only recognized ex-post. But regulators cannot say that it was impossible to see.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;i&gt;The coverup&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;I was a loud critic of the Dodd-Frank approach to regulation, arguing for lots of equity rather than continued high leverage and the fantasy that regulators would really really see asset risks building up next time. That has obviously failed once again. But at least they had the decency to notice something went wrong, to say the words &quot;moral hazard&quot; and to do &lt;i&gt;something&lt;/i&gt; about it.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;The Fed engaged in a massive bailout in 2020, and nobody is peeping a word about it other than congratulating the Fed for saving the world once again. Why did the world need saving, in all the ways that Dodd-Frank and stress tests were supposed to prevent? Silence.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;div&gt;As the dust settles, and taxpayers count the cost, there will naturally be calls for a prompt investigation into how pension funds were allowed to invest billions in such high-risk products. Smooth financiers, who for years profited from these exotic deals, will shrug their shoulders while politicians deflect and regulators seek others to blame.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;History, meanwhile, suggests no one will be properly held accountable. And therein lies the real scandal. For as so often when financial markets implode, the outrageous fact is that this was well and truly a crisis foretold.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;div&gt;As with the FDA and the CDC we have entered the CYA era of government, in which nobody can admit mistakes or reform institutions.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;i&gt;Over and over&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;I italicized the headings to emphasize how common this story is. Over and over, plus ça change, plus c&#39;est la même chose. And now the same crew, having missed debt financed mortgage backed securities in special purpose vehicles (2008), having missed banks loading up on Greek debt (2010), having completely missed that a pandemic or other supply shock might cause trouble (2020), having missed that energy prices might rise or war might break out (2022), is off on the quest to stress test banks for climate change.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;i&gt;Update&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ft.com/content/8b34f3fc-ec08-4d6f-864b-a482217a841a&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Great coverage by Robert Armstrong&lt;/a&gt; at FT Unhinged. Armstrong adds the use of derivatives to goose the portfolios, and points out that the 1% or more interest rate moves happened in a matter of days, really pushing the collateral channel. He also asks why central banks don&#39;t directly control long-term rates rather than, or rather than just, short term rates. It&#39;s a good question.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/opinion/articles/2022-09-30/hardly-a-surprise-pension-funds-stoked-the-uk-rout&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Great coverage here by Allison Schrager&lt;/a&gt; at Bloomberg. HT Casey Mulligan.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://johnhcochrane.blogspot.com/2022/10/uk-finance-fable-update.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;More update here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='replies' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://johnhcochrane.blogspot.com/feeds/7035245267377066042/comments/default' title='Post Comments'/><link rel='replies' type='text/html' href='https://johnhcochrane.blogspot.com/2022/09/a-familiar-finance-fable-in-uk-bonds.html#comment-form' title='18 Comments'/><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/582368152716771238/posts/default/7035245267377066042'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/582368152716771238/posts/default/7035245267377066042'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://johnhcochrane.blogspot.com/2022/09/a-familiar-finance-fable-in-uk-bonds.html' title='A familiar finance fable in UK bonds '/><author><name>John H. Cochrane</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/04842601651429471525</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='25' height='32' src='//4.bp.blogspot.com/-hxC_w91OloY/X8aKsZcuFcI/AAAAAAAADHs/CANi5RE5-n8t7QGX1CzX9vgEg1Bd22tpwCK4BGAYYCw/s220/john_cochrane_forweb.jpg'/></author><thr:total>18</thr:total></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-582368152716771238.post-648202177752490084</id><published>2022-09-29T18:57:00.001-05:00</published><updated>2022-09-30T09:51:02.113-05:00</updated><category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Commentary"/><category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Economists"/><category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Inflation"/><category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Regulation"/><title type='text'>Supply and inflation</title><content type='html'>&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.aei.org/carpe-diem/chart-of-the-day-or-century-8/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Mark Perry recently updated&lt;/a&gt; a fabulous chart:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;table align=&quot;center&quot; cellpadding=&quot;0&quot; cellspacing=&quot;0&quot; class=&quot;tr-caption-container&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.aei.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/cpi2022junea-3.png?x91208&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;800&quot; data-original-width=&quot;742&quot; height=&quot;800&quot; src=&quot;https://www.aei.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/cpi2022junea-3.png?x91208&quot; width=&quot;742&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;Not all inflation is the same.&amp;nbsp;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Some interpretations, from Mark. Tradeable (international competition) / non tradeable; government intervention / free market; durable goods / services:&amp;nbsp;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;a. The greater (lower) the degree of government involvement in the provision of a good or service the greater (lower) the price increases (decreases) over time, e.g., hospital and medical costs, college tuition, childcare with both large degrees of government funding/regulation and large price increases vs. software, electronics, toys, cars and clothing with both relatively less government funding/regulation and falling prices. As somebody on Twitter commented:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Blue lines&lt;/b&gt; = prices subject to free-market forces. &lt;b&gt;Red lines&lt;/b&gt; = prices subject to regulatory capture by government. Food and beverages are debatable either way. &lt;b&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/b&gt; remind me why socialism is so great again.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;b. Prices for manufactured goods (cars, clothing, appliances, furniture, electronic goods, toys) have experienced large price declines over time relative to overall inflation, wages, and prices for services (education, medical care, and childcare).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;c. The greater the degree of international competition for tradeable goods, the greater the decline in prices over time, e.g., toys, clothing, TVs, appliances, furniture, footwear, etc.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;d. From Twitter comments this week (2022).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;*Thank goodness the government doesn’t subsidize TVs or toys, or toy TVs.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;*Almost every line that went up, has had some type of government involvement, while the lines going down have more to do with capitalism.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;*And as always, the more regulated, the more expensive things become.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;There is a big distributional impact here. Less well off people buy more blue stuff, rich people more red stuff.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The implications for greater protection, less immigration, industrial policy, and subsidies are pretty clear.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Update:&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I have been sloppy, about one of my own pet peeves. This graph is about relative prices, not about inflation. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='replies' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://johnhcochrane.blogspot.com/feeds/648202177752490084/comments/default' title='Post Comments'/><link rel='replies' type='text/html' href='https://johnhcochrane.blogspot.com/2022/09/supply-and-inflation.html#comment-form' title='31 Comments'/><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/582368152716771238/posts/default/648202177752490084'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/582368152716771238/posts/default/648202177752490084'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://johnhcochrane.blogspot.com/2022/09/supply-and-inflation.html' title='Supply and inflation'/><author><name>John H. Cochrane</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/04842601651429471525</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='25' height='32' src='//4.bp.blogspot.com/-hxC_w91OloY/X8aKsZcuFcI/AAAAAAAADHs/CANi5RE5-n8t7QGX1CzX9vgEg1Bd22tpwCK4BGAYYCw/s220/john_cochrane_forweb.jpg'/></author><thr:total>31</thr:total></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-582368152716771238.post-2902111882865538038</id><published>2022-09-25T14:27:00.002-05:00</published><updated>2022-09-26T10:00:08.032-05:00</updated><category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Commentary"/><category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Fiscal Theory"/><category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Inflation"/><category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Monetary Policy"/><title type='text'>WSJ stability oped -- full text</title><content type='html'>&lt;p&gt;Now that 30 days have passed, I can post the full text of &quot;Nobody Knows How Interest Rates Affect Inflation&quot; in the &lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wsj.com/articles/nobody-knows-how-interest-rates-affect-inflation-unstable-stable-seal-pendulum-1970s-spirals-expectations-federal-reserve-11661368265?mod=opinion_lead_pos7&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Wall Street Journal&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/i&gt;August 25. A &lt;a href=&quot;https://johnhcochrane.blogspot.com/2022/08/wsj-inflation-stability-oped-with.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;previous post&lt;/a&gt; has a summary with pretty pictures.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;***&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A grand economic experiment is under way. Can the Federal Reserve contain inflation without raising interest rates much higher than they are now?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Conventional wisdom says that as long as interest rates are below the rate of inflation, inflation will rise. Inflation in July was 8.5%, measured as the one-year change in the consumer price index. The Fed has raised the federal funds rate only from 0.08% in March to 2.33% in August. According to the conventional view, that isn’t nearly enough. Higher rates are needed, now.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This conventional view holds that the economy is inherently unstable. The Fed is like a seal, balancing a ball (inflation) on its nose (interest rates). To keep the ball from falling, the seal must quickly move its nose.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In a newer view, the economy is stable, like a pendulum. Even if the Fed does nothing, so long as there are no more shocks, inflation will eventually peter out. The Fed can reduce inflation by raising interest rates, but interest rates need not exceed inflation to prevent an inflationary spiral. This newer view is reflected in most economic models of recent decades. It accounts for the Fed’s projections and explains the Fed’s sluggish response. Stock and bond markets also foresee inflation fading away without large interest-rate rises.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So which view is correct? In normal times, it’s hard to tell. Whether seal or pendulum, inflation and interest rates move up or down together in the long run, and they jiggle around each other in the short run.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Advocates for the conventional view argue that the Fed raised interest rates too little in response to inflationary shocks in the 1970s. Only when the Fed raised interest rates substantially above inflation for several years in the early 1980s, provoking two deep recessions, did inflation finally subside. The sooner we get to it, they say, the better.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Advocates for the stable view point to recent decades of steady inflation at zero interest rates in the U.S., Europe and Japan. When deflation appeared and central banks couldn’t move rates much below zero, conventional analysts warned of a “deflation spiral.” It never happened. Why should an inflation spiral break out now?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In both theories, expected inflation matters: If people expect higher inflation next year, they buy or raise prices today. The central assumption behind the unstable inflation-spiral theory is that people expect next year’s inflation to be pretty much the same as last year’s inflation—what economists call “adaptive expectations.” A driver who looks in the rearview mirror to judge where the road is will quickly veer off to one side or another.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The central assumption behind the stable theory is that people think more broadly about future inflation. They’re not clairvoyant, but they don’t ignore useful information and aren’t much worse at forecasting inflation than, say, Fed economists are. If a driver looks forward through the windshield, even a dirty windshield, the car tends to get back on the road.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Economists don’t know for sure whether the economy is stable or unstable, whether inflation can fade away without interest rates substantially above inflation. In that light, the Fed’s actions make some sense. If you really don’t know how interest rates affect inflation, it’s natural to raise rates slowly. Inflation may subside on its own. If not, you can keep raising rates.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If inflation fades, the conventional view will be seriously undermined. If it spirals, absent other shocks, the new view is in trouble. But a good experiment requires everyone to leave the test tube alone. Unfortunately, we are likely to see some new shock: a virus, a war, a financial crisis or a fiscal blowout. Inflation will then rise or fall for reasons having nothing to do with spirals, stability and interest rates.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Mr. Cochrane is a senior fellow at Stanford University’s Hoover Institution and an adjunct scholar of the Cato Institute. His book “The Fiscal Theory of the Price Level” is out in January.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Update:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Economists wondering what the heck I&#39;m talking about and where are the equations should read &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.johnhcochrane.com/research-all/inflation-neutrality&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&quot;Expectations and the Neutrality of Interest rates.&quot;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><link rel='replies' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://johnhcochrane.blogspot.com/feeds/2902111882865538038/comments/default' title='Post Comments'/><link rel='replies' type='text/html' href='https://johnhcochrane.blogspot.com/2022/09/wsj-stability-oped-full-text.html#comment-form' title='12 Comments'/><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/582368152716771238/posts/default/2902111882865538038'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/582368152716771238/posts/default/2902111882865538038'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://johnhcochrane.blogspot.com/2022/09/wsj-stability-oped-full-text.html' title='WSJ stability oped -- full text'/><author><name>John H. Cochrane</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/04842601651429471525</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='25' height='32' src='//4.bp.blogspot.com/-hxC_w91OloY/X8aKsZcuFcI/AAAAAAAADHs/CANi5RE5-n8t7QGX1CzX9vgEg1Bd22tpwCK4BGAYYCw/s220/john_cochrane_forweb.jpg'/></author><thr:total>12</thr:total></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-582368152716771238.post-2023207336800236439</id><published>2022-09-23T13:24:00.001-05:00</published><updated>2022-09-23T16:50:20.750-05:00</updated><category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Commentary"/><category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Economists"/><category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Environment"/><category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Euro"/><title type='text'>Brexit might not have been such a bad idea after all -- EU insanity</title><content type='html'>&lt;p&gt;I was for Fixit, not Brexit. The EU is a great idea. They put together articles of confederation, empowering an out of control bureaucracy. OK, we did that too, minus the bureaucracy part. Try again, with a real constitution, a real federal government, clear separation of powers, checks and balances, and a careful list of limitations, not long vague aspirations.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Europe has not taken that suggestion, nor the hint offered by the Brits leaving. The latest evidence is a tiny puff in this hurricane of hot air, which I found on &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/emilyjblanchard/status/1573260938077442048&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;this tweet&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEhd4H-zA6r-mSvYoHIWMzEguB6whqnwn5c_-7JNg89_G_ZuVpd9mlNF19EccRoeA9qqkk8wMjISl4fSBCIOanHatCzz_J323NPD0k3XF8JCmArPmgNZmOOut-a1mwkNtEZfMZC8o-XHUVCTP_R2jHFeSaRU7pYnxByNRb-YxJY57rKV8GxS9fr8gZo/s1250/Screen%20Shot%202022-09-23%20at%2010.32.10%20AM.png&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;1250&quot; data-original-width=&quot;1206&quot; height=&quot;320&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEhd4H-zA6r-mSvYoHIWMzEguB6whqnwn5c_-7JNg89_G_ZuVpd9mlNF19EccRoeA9qqkk8wMjISl4fSBCIOanHatCzz_J323NPD0k3XF8JCmArPmgNZmOOut-a1mwkNtEZfMZC8o-XHUVCTP_R2jHFeSaRU7pYnxByNRb-YxJY57rKV8GxS9fr8gZo/s320/Screen%20Shot%202022-09-23%20at%2010.32.10%20AM.png&quot; width=&quot;309&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;That sounds interesting, in a waste time on twitter while procrastinating getting to work sort of way. And I was encouraged--EC bureaucracies looking for outside advice, breaking out of the bubble seems like a good idea. Hey, maybe I&#39;ll apply, I thought.&amp;nbsp;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;I followed the &lt;a href=&quot;https://single-market-economy.ec.europa.eu/calls-expression-interest/deadline-20221010-call-expression-interest-expert-economic-advice-dg-internal-market-industry_en&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;link to the official announcement&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and it offers in a nutshell what&#39;s going on in EU &quot;policy-making,&quot; (and a hint why I hate that word)&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;div&gt;The latest communication on industrial policy strategy (&lt;a href=&quot;https://ec.europa.eu/info/sites/default/files/communication-industrial-strategy-update-2020_en.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;COM(2021) 350final&lt;/a&gt;) has shifted the attention towards an ecosystem approach to industrial policy, focusing on industrial ecosystems and their complex interconnections related, among other things, to entrepreneurship (and SMEs), innovation, skills, value creation and social impact.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;div&gt;After mulling over the obvious reality of war, supply chains, etc.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;div&gt;..a reactive stance is not sufficient and needs to be complemented by a forward-looking reflection aimed at properly considering externalities and risk factors to be prepared for - and therefore more and more resilient against - possible additional challenges (for instance in terms of disruptions and shortages but also new, far from impossible health crises), remaining consistent with crucial long-term objectives. Progress is more than innovation and EU competitiveness, more than continuous growth and geopolitical predominance. [Who are you kidding?] &lt;i&gt;It is also quality of life, sustainable production and energy generation, digitally advanced (but also digitally safe and fair) infrastructure, “enlightened” decision-making at corporate level eventually influenced by well-informed choices at consumer level&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;div&gt;My emphasis. The subject is a bit mysterious in all these passive sentences, but I believe it is &quot;EU industrial policy.&quot; I&#39;m glad it will take on scare-quote enlightened decision making at the corporate level and allow eventually for some &quot;well-informed&quot; choices &quot;at the consumer level.&quot; That&#39;s you with the pitchforks. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;div&gt;This may imply putting into question traditional policy yardsticks such as the focus on industrial sectors as done with the shift towards an ecosystem approach,&lt;i&gt; [the focus on] on the overarching principle of economic efficiency as a first best for resources allocation e.g. by factoring in risks associated to critical strategic dependencies,&lt;/i&gt; or the focus on traditional stakeholders (for instance, by including a wider set of actors, in a truly ecosystem mindset going beyond industrial activity and including other relevant players, such as universities, research centres, and even the role of local communities). This may be more effectively inspired by policy missions, rather than sectoral or even social cleavages.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;div&gt;Well, no wonder they need some outside economists if they&#39;re going to perfectly foresee &quot;critical strategic dependencies&quot; in the &quot;ecosystem,&quot; such as, oh, maybe Russia might turn off the gas some day. &amp;nbsp;&quot;Policy missions, rather than sectoral or even social cleavages?&quot; I have no idea what that means.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;div&gt;This may also imply some reshuffling in policy priorities, for instance by having some ethical yardsticks considered upfront (namely, but not only, with respect to innovation), &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;by having ethical yardsticks considered upfront.&quot; Don&#39;t you love passive voice? &quot;namely... with respect to innovation&quot; is truly chilling. That means, before you can innovate, the great directorate of industrial policy will decide if your innovation is &quot;ethical,&quot; as it affects &quot;stakeholders&quot; and the &quot;industrial ecosystem.&quot; What is the chance James Watt&#39;s steam engine will make it past that?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;div&gt;by enshrining sustainability considerations (and related externalities often ignored in the past) in trade-offs underlying corporate choices, by thoroughly considering social impact of public and private investment as a major element of choice. &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Passive means us. Can any investment get past this? Oh yes,&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;div&gt;“Social cheerleading” and “greenwashing” should become strictly unfeasible, starting from becoming easily detectable. This may imply rethinking the incentives and mechanisms to better align public goals and private behaviour. It may also imply refining our metric to measure progress.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Heavens, we wouldn&#39;t want to have any greenwashing here.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;If addressed only from a national perspective, all the challenges and reflections above would seem and would be unsurmountable. A truly coordinated European approach exploiting the potential of the Single Market would be of the utmost importance...&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Now you know why the Brits left.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;div&gt;What follows is a non-exhaustive list of examples of themes of interest to DG GROW within the broad areas defined above: [edited here] &amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;div&gt;• Industrial policy in the Single Market: moving forward avoiding fragmentation and minimising short-term losses&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Aha, so industrial policy involve &quot;short term&quot; losses!&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;div&gt;• A mission-oriented Single Market to increase ownership, generate momentum and help prioritising actions aimed at improving its functioning&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;div&gt;Ownership can be transferred, but how can ownership be increased? Otherwise as empty a sentence as I&#39;ve seen in a long time.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;div&gt;• Strategic dependencies, monitoring risks and building supply chains resilience&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;div&gt;Yes, you did such a great job on that one by banning fracking and decommissioning nuclear power.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;div&gt;• Dependencies and the search for new economic models&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;• Alternative purposeful business practices&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Just savor the empty words. Or are they Orwellian and full of meaning?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;div&gt;• Unlocking the green business case; the role of the Single Market&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;• Investment needs to leap forward&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;A Great Leap Forward? How are you going to leap forward given the previous page that says, basically, all investment must stop?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;div&gt;• New metrics to measure economic progress&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;We haven&#39;t dug ourselves into a 20 meter hole. It&#39;s only a tenth of a furlong! &amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;I am tempted to apply. I offer this: &quot;Cut the BS, get out of the way, quit and get some real jobs. The pretense of technocratic competence to understand and manipulate such a huge Rube-Goldberg view of the world is just laughable.&quot; Send the 15,0000 euro check to Hoover.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;I originally thought this would be illegal. &lt;a href=&quot;https://cadmus.eui.eu/handle/1814/65947&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;But on a little research,&lt;/a&gt; the Lisbon Treaty, which was supposed to improve the EU, takes a big step backwards.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;div&gt;The Lisbon Treaty introduced in its Art. 3 new language into primary law that expresses the ambition to give the EU a stronger social dimension.1 In comparison to its predecessor provision of Art. 4 (1) of the Treaty Establishing the European Community, which solely relied on the ‘principle of an open market economy with free competition’, the basic objectives of the EU were broadened. Art. 3 TEU now includes objectives that come across as a promise to rebalance market and non-market values through the foundational provisions of the European Union. In line with other wide-ranging objectives, like fighting social exclusion, this article includes the eye-catching sentence that the EU aims for ‘a highly competitive social market economy’ that seeks to achieve ‘full employment and social progress’&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;div&gt;Liz Truss may struggle to convince the UK that to fix supply you have to fix supply (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wsj.com/articles/tories-struggle-to-get-britains-economic-mojo-back-taxes-revival-plan-prime-minister-liz-truss-voters-regulation-economic-turn-11663856682&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;great WSJ commentary by Joe Sternmberg here&lt;/a&gt;) but at least she knows where to go. Europe still seems lost in the fog. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;This is of course likely to go nowhere, to just employ PhD economists to write reports nobody reads. But who knows, having missed a real estate bust, a sovereign debt crisis, a pandemic, an energy crisis and a war, the ECB is doubling down on climate change stress tests, so you never know what foolishness can actually make it into policy.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;And it&#39;s not all so bad. Ukrainians look East vs. West. A bunch of bureaucratic tomfoolery looks a whole lot better than what Vlad the Impaler has to offer. Go Europe. Some day, fixit.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='replies' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://johnhcochrane.blogspot.com/feeds/2023207336800236439/comments/default' title='Post Comments'/><link rel='replies' type='text/html' href='https://johnhcochrane.blogspot.com/2022/09/brexit-might-not-have-been-such-bad.html#comment-form' title='11 Comments'/><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/582368152716771238/posts/default/2023207336800236439'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/582368152716771238/posts/default/2023207336800236439'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://johnhcochrane.blogspot.com/2022/09/brexit-might-not-have-been-such-bad.html' title='Brexit might not have been such a bad idea after all -- EU insanity'/><author><name>John H. Cochrane</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/04842601651429471525</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='25' height='32' src='//4.bp.blogspot.com/-hxC_w91OloY/X8aKsZcuFcI/AAAAAAAADHs/CANi5RE5-n8t7QGX1CzX9vgEg1Bd22tpwCK4BGAYYCw/s220/john_cochrane_forweb.jpg'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEhd4H-zA6r-mSvYoHIWMzEguB6whqnwn5c_-7JNg89_G_ZuVpd9mlNF19EccRoeA9qqkk8wMjISl4fSBCIOanHatCzz_J323NPD0k3XF8JCmArPmgNZmOOut-a1mwkNtEZfMZC8o-XHUVCTP_R2jHFeSaRU7pYnxByNRb-YxJY57rKV8GxS9fr8gZo/s72-c/Screen%20Shot%202022-09-23%20at%2010.32.10%20AM.png" height="72" width="72"/><thr:total>11</thr:total></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-582368152716771238.post-3069080608786776078</id><published>2022-09-21T10:42:00.000-05:00</published><updated>2022-09-21T10:42:02.719-05:00</updated><category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Economists"/><category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Growth"/><category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Health economics"/><category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="housing"/><category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Interesting Papers"/><category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Labor"/><category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Taxes"/><category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Unemployment"/><title type='text'>Gramm, Early and the Unfixable Problem</title><content type='html'>&lt;p&gt;Phil Gramm and John Early have a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wsj.com/articles/child-poverty-data-are-missing-something-refundable-tax-credit-tranfser-payments-census-estimates-household-income-11663689293&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;new WSJ oped,&lt;/a&gt; based on their smashing &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Myth-American-Inequality-Government-Biases/dp/1538167387&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;new book&lt;/a&gt;. Both are based on an astounding fact: &lt;i&gt;The numbers used by the Census Bureau, and countless following researchers, to define income inequality and poverty do not include taxes, which reduce income of the rich, and transfers, which increase income of the poor.&lt;/i&gt; The latter, obviously, matters to just how many Americans fall in the Census Bureau&#39;s definition of poverty.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Specifically, in the oped, the new refundable tax credit cannot, by arithmetic, do anything to alleviate measured child poverty because&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;the income numbers used to calculate the official poverty rates don’t count refundable tax credits as income to the recipients. &quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is wonderful for advocates of ever larger transfer programs, as it creates a problem that can never be measured to be fixed!&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The more general issue&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Census Bureau fails to count two-thirds of all government transfer payments to households in the income numbers it uses to calculate not only poverty levels but also income inequality and income growth. In addition to not counting refundable tax credits, which are paid by checks from the U.S. Treasury, the official Census Bureau measure doesn’t count food stamps, Medicaid, the Children’s Health Insurance Program, rent subsidies, energy subsidies and health-insurance subsidies under the Affordable Care Act. In total, benefits provided in more than 100 other federal, state and local transfer payments aren’t counted by the Census Bureau as income to the recipients&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;The book goes on to show how this startling omission overturns just about everything you&#39;ve heard from the hyperventilating classes about income inequality. Granted, spending zillions on rotten health insurance that people value much less than a dollar per dollar is not quite the same as cash, but there are lots of cash or cash equivalent transfers in there.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A question I do not know the answer to: Do means-tested programs count as &quot;income&quot; the transfers from other means-tested programs? If a program is only available to, say, those with less than $50,000 per year income, does that figure include any other means-tested programs? &amp;nbsp;Even the ones that send cash, rather than in-kind transfers such as rent, energy, and health insurance subsidies? I suspect largely no. If not, the incentives for means-tested programs are far worse than even they appear. Facts welcome.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;One might easily respond that ok, but evil capitalism created wider pre-tax pre-transfer inequality, and only by the grace of larger and larger transfers has some measure of stability been restored. Well, which is the cause and which is the effect -- wider pre-tax pre-transfer inequality, or the large expansion of means-tested programs, all of which add to the stupendous marginal tax rates facing Americans with less opportunity? The book goes on to argue convincingly the latter. I&#39;ll cover that later. Noting here, they anticipate the argument.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</content><link rel='replies' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://johnhcochrane.blogspot.com/feeds/3069080608786776078/comments/default' title='Post Comments'/><link rel='replies' type='text/html' href='https://johnhcochrane.blogspot.com/2022/09/gramm-early-and-unfixable-problem.html#comment-form' title='22 Comments'/><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/582368152716771238/posts/default/3069080608786776078'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/582368152716771238/posts/default/3069080608786776078'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://johnhcochrane.blogspot.com/2022/09/gramm-early-and-unfixable-problem.html' title='Gramm, Early and the Unfixable Problem'/><author><name>John H. Cochrane</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/04842601651429471525</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='25' height='32' src='//4.bp.blogspot.com/-hxC_w91OloY/X8aKsZcuFcI/AAAAAAAADHs/CANi5RE5-n8t7QGX1CzX9vgEg1Bd22tpwCK4BGAYYCw/s220/john_cochrane_forweb.jpg'/></author><thr:total>22</thr:total></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-582368152716771238.post-4029392288303418595</id><published>2022-09-15T10:50:00.001-05:00</published><updated>2022-09-18T11:22:38.839-05:00</updated><category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Commentary"/><category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Fiscal Theory"/><category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Inflation"/><category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Monetary Policy"/><title type='text'>Fisherian Intuition</title><content type='html'>&lt;script src=&quot;https://polyfill.io/v3/polyfill.min.js?features=es6&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; id=&quot;MathJax-script&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/npm/mathjax@3/es5/tex-mml-chtml.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;p&gt;Interest rate neutrality is easy to state in equations but hard to digest intuitively.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The equation says that interest rate = real rate plus expected inflation, \[i_t = r + E_t\pi_{t+1.}\]In one direction this is easy: If people expect a lot of inflation, then they demand higher nominal \(i_t\) interest rates to compensate for the declining value of the dollar. That leaves the real \(r\) interest rate unchanged.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;(Note: this post uses mathjax equations. If you can&#39;t see them, come to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://johnhcochrane.blogspot.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;original&lt;/a&gt;.)&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But in our economy the Fed sets the nominal interest rate and the rest must adjust. In the short run with sticky prices and other frictions the real rate may change, but eventually the real rate is set by real things and expected inflation must rise. &amp;nbsp;We can study that long run by leaving out &amp;nbsp;the sticky prices and other frictions, and then expected inflation rises right away.&lt;i&gt; Rises.&lt;/i&gt; Higher interest rates &lt;i&gt;raise&lt;/i&gt; inflation. How does that really work? What&#39;s the economic force?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Standard intuition says overwhelmingly that higher interest rates cause people to spend less which lowers inflation. &amp;nbsp;The equations seem like they&#39;re hiding some sort of sophistry.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;(Fed Chair Powell explains the standard view well while&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=gW6I9BnIgEU&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;sparring with Senator Warren here&lt;/a&gt;. The clip is great on several dimensions. No, the Fed cannot increase supply. No, none of what Senator Warren talks of will make a dent in supply either. The elephant in the room, massive fiscal stimulus, is not mentioned by either party. Just why each is silent on that is an interesting question.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is a lovely case that &lt;i&gt;individual &lt;/i&gt;causality goes in the opposite direction of &lt;i&gt;equilibrium&lt;/i&gt; causality. That happens a lot in macroeconomics and can cause a lot of confusion. It also is an interesting case of mistaking expected inflation for unexpected inflation. Along with confusing relative prices for inflation, that&#39;s common and easy to do. Hence this post.&amp;nbsp;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a name=&#39;more&#39;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Start with the consumer first order condition, or &quot;IS curve&quot; of new-Keynesian models, \[ x_t = E_t x_{t+1} - \sigma (i_t - E_t \pi_{t+1}-r) \] with \(x=\) consumption, output or output gap after linearization, \(i=\) nominal interest rate, \(\pi=\) inflation and \(r\) equal the discount rate or long-term real interest rate. To the individual, the interest rate and expected inflation -- the price levels \(p_t\) and \(p_{t+1}\) and thus \(\pi_{t+1}=p_{t+1}-p_t\) -- are given, exogenous. (Minus not divided by, these are all in logs.) The consumer chooses consumption \(x\) subject to a budget constraint. If the Fed raises interest rates and prices do not yet adjust, then the consumer wishes to lower consumption today \(x_t\) and raise consumption tomorrow \(x_{t+1}\). That is the standard intuition, and correct. &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now, a desire to lower consumption today pushes down the price level today, and consuming more tomorrow pushes up the price level tomorrow. More deeply, let&#39;s pair this first order condition with equilibrium in an endowment economy, with constant \(x_t=x\). In English, fix supply -- there is only so much output \(x\) to go around so prices have to adjust until people are content to buy what&#39;s on the shelves, no more and no less. &amp;nbsp;(We can also pair it with the Phillips curve, and then specify flexible prices.) The current price level \(p_t\) falls relative to the expected future price level \(p_{t+1}\) until the consumer&#39;s demand equals supply, so \( E_t\pi_{t+1} = i_t+r\). &lt;i&gt;Expected inflation rises to meet the interest rate. &lt;/i&gt;As promised, and by exactly the conventional mechanism.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This logic tells us that the higher interest rate produces higher future inflation, from this year to next year. Now, you can get higher inflation by a lower initial price \(p_t\) or from a higher later price \(p_{t+1}\). &amp;nbsp;The graph below shows the two possibilities, and (green) an intermediate possibility.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEgxnrDxSaacY8gokEVsaBj_7FQEoxXW36OugzIwxCN09DjW33owCvF4dexUJMmYnjWMByJMIFVWXiqKhZqJBGnHAasTjnveSkdhGM2fYgdLdpNtRLlWoLNgwALuLYhp5F4E-qrGcvVHNoS9WzyEB-DLagHt1DWzu8T1gYF5dFgc1iucGlSwvF_Wz9A/s934/Screen%20Shot%202022-08-25%20at%2010.06.27%20PM.png&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;600&quot; data-original-width=&quot;934&quot; height=&quot;206&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEgxnrDxSaacY8gokEVsaBj_7FQEoxXW36OugzIwxCN09DjW33owCvF4dexUJMmYnjWMByJMIFVWXiqKhZqJBGnHAasTjnveSkdhGM2fYgdLdpNtRLlWoLNgwALuLYhp5F4E-qrGcvVHNoS9WzyEB-DLagHt1DWzu8T1gYF5dFgc1iucGlSwvF_Wz9A/s320/Screen%20Shot%202022-08-25%20at%2010.06.27%20PM.png&quot; width=&quot;320&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;So the original intuition can be right: Higher interest rates might well depress current demand and lower \(p_t\). (Blue line) That produces lower&amp;nbsp;&lt;i&gt;ex post&amp;nbsp;&lt;/i&gt;inflation \( \pi_t=p_t-p_{t-1}\) and higher&amp;nbsp;&lt;i&gt;expected&lt;/i&gt;&amp;nbsp;inflation \(E_t\pi_{t+1}=E_t(p_{t+1}-p_t)\). The intervention can well &quot;lower inflation,&quot; in this sense. This is how standard (new-Keynesian) models work.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If we stop here, the confusion is just semantic. As often in life, you can resolve a lot of seemingly intractable arguments just by defining terms more carefully. Higher interest rates can lower current inflation. Sticky prices and other frictions can draw out this period of decline. As for the price recovery, and higher future inflation, well, we often do see that -- inflation comes back as it did in the 1970s -- or maybe the Fed doesn&#39;t leave interest rates alone long enough to see it. The long run is a long time.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But there is another possibility. Maybe the higher expected inflation all comes from a higher future price level, not a lower current price level; the red line not the blue line. Which is it-- higher \(p_{t+1}\) or lower \(p_t\)? This first order condition is not enough to answer this question. You need either new-Keynesian equilibrium selection policies or fiscal theory to determine which one it is. In either case, it comes down to fiscal policy. To have an unexpected decline in inflation, Congress must raise tax revenue or cut spending to pay off bondholders in more valuable money. If Congress refuses, we get the top line, more future inflation, no inflation reduction today. If Congress goes along, we can get the bottom line. Fiscal and monetary policies always work in tandem.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But this post is about the narrow question: Why do higher interest rates raise &lt;i&gt;expected future&lt;/i&gt; inflation? If it happens by lowering the current price level, producing an unexpected deflation, that&#39;s consistent with the question. So part of the intuitive problem was understanding the question, and in the verbal debate one side (conventional, implicitly) was talking about unexpected current inflation, while the other (Fisherian) side was talking about expected future inflation. Both can be right! &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;To the individual, the price levels and expected inflation are exogenous and the consumption \(x\) decision is endogenous. In equilibrium, the endowment \(x\) is exogenous, and the price levels and expected inflation follow. This is the same clever reversal of the famous Lucas asset pricing model. The individual chooses consumption seeing asset prices. In equilibrium, changes in the endowment cause changes in asset prices.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;(Thanks to the colleagues who pressed me to find a good intuition for this result.)&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><link rel='replies' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://johnhcochrane.blogspot.com/feeds/4029392288303418595/comments/default' title='Post Comments'/><link rel='replies' type='text/html' href='https://johnhcochrane.blogspot.com/2022/09/fisherian-intuition.html#comment-form' title='15 Comments'/><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/582368152716771238/posts/default/4029392288303418595'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/582368152716771238/posts/default/4029392288303418595'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://johnhcochrane.blogspot.com/2022/09/fisherian-intuition.html' title='Fisherian Intuition'/><author><name>John H. Cochrane</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/04842601651429471525</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='25' height='32' src='//4.bp.blogspot.com/-hxC_w91OloY/X8aKsZcuFcI/AAAAAAAADHs/CANi5RE5-n8t7QGX1CzX9vgEg1Bd22tpwCK4BGAYYCw/s220/john_cochrane_forweb.jpg'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEgxnrDxSaacY8gokEVsaBj_7FQEoxXW36OugzIwxCN09DjW33owCvF4dexUJMmYnjWMByJMIFVWXiqKhZqJBGnHAasTjnveSkdhGM2fYgdLdpNtRLlWoLNgwALuLYhp5F4E-qrGcvVHNoS9WzyEB-DLagHt1DWzu8T1gYF5dFgc1iucGlSwvF_Wz9A/s72-c/Screen%20Shot%202022-08-25%20at%2010.06.27%20PM.png" height="72" width="72"/><thr:total>15</thr:total></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-582368152716771238.post-7473441376625645918</id><published>2022-09-14T17:54:00.004-05:00</published><updated>2022-09-15T10:38:00.555-05:00</updated><category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="off-topic"/><title type='text'>Email feed restored</title><content type='html'>&lt;p&gt;A while ago, Google turned off the ability to receive the Grumpy Economist, and all the other blogger blogs, by email. I have now figured out how to restore it. I moved over to &lt;a href=&quot;http://follow.it&quot;&gt;follow.it&lt;/a&gt;. If the import of the old email feed worked as it is supposed to, you&#39;re receiving this in your email once again. If not, you can click on the huge button to the right to get Grumpy by email. (I&#39;ll figure out how to make that prettier sooner or later.) I also announce each new blog post on twitter, and if you prefer that you can click the twitter link to follow me there.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Follow.it encourages me to pass along all the &quot;great additional features&quot; you can use, &lt;a href=&quot;https://follow.it/johnhcochrane?action=followPub&amp;amp;filter&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. You can&amp;nbsp;now &quot;define filters and more delivery channels, e.g... receive your news via Telegram, news page etc. (many others to follow soon).&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Thanks to several devoted readers who wrote to complain, nudging me to figure this out. If it still doesn&#39;t work, either comment here or email me directly.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If I link &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://follow.it&quot;&gt;Feedburner alternative&lt;/a&gt;&quot; and &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://follow.it&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Feedburner replacement&lt;/a&gt;&quot; to follow.it, &amp;nbsp;they give me a $10 USD credit. Done! &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;More substance on the way soon!&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Update&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;You will receive an email that looks like this. It invites you to click a link. This is a legitimate email.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEjXN4FyEWUHg1v-XjUByzQ-Zfk8bQeatM1U0vAg5iGnYVJhLGxZbTbwK27n4wPgLefqIXjsxlOjvEDtWmiyZt9iw5s9AjP4gSd5yLN9K-93qC3LUw98CV-r1RDynlji-fjLA1QdjoQO2i7KdPdb6azNmzGuanG2qp1OkPn2P4guVJ7gMafQ2eEPMcs/s1810/Screen%20Shot%202022-09-15%20at%208.35.32%20AM.png&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;844&quot; data-original-width=&quot;1810&quot; height=&quot;186&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEjXN4FyEWUHg1v-XjUByzQ-Zfk8bQeatM1U0vAg5iGnYVJhLGxZbTbwK27n4wPgLefqIXjsxlOjvEDtWmiyZt9iw5s9AjP4gSd5yLN9K-93qC3LUw98CV-r1RDynlji-fjLA1QdjoQO2i7KdPdb6azNmzGuanG2qp1OkPn2P4guVJ7gMafQ2eEPMcs/w400-h186/Screen%20Shot%202022-09-15%20at%208.35.32%20AM.png&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><link rel='replies' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://johnhcochrane.blogspot.com/feeds/7473441376625645918/comments/default' title='Post Comments'/><link rel='replies' type='text/html' href='https://johnhcochrane.blogspot.com/2022/09/email-feed-restored.html#comment-form' title='5 Comments'/><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/582368152716771238/posts/default/7473441376625645918'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/582368152716771238/posts/default/7473441376625645918'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://johnhcochrane.blogspot.com/2022/09/email-feed-restored.html' title='Email feed restored'/><author><name>John H. Cochrane</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/04842601651429471525</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='25' height='32' src='//4.bp.blogspot.com/-hxC_w91OloY/X8aKsZcuFcI/AAAAAAAADHs/CANi5RE5-n8t7QGX1CzX9vgEg1Bd22tpwCK4BGAYYCw/s220/john_cochrane_forweb.jpg'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEjXN4FyEWUHg1v-XjUByzQ-Zfk8bQeatM1U0vAg5iGnYVJhLGxZbTbwK27n4wPgLefqIXjsxlOjvEDtWmiyZt9iw5s9AjP4gSd5yLN9K-93qC3LUw98CV-r1RDynlji-fjLA1QdjoQO2i7KdPdb6azNmzGuanG2qp1OkPn2P4guVJ7gMafQ2eEPMcs/s72-w400-h186-c/Screen%20Shot%202022-09-15%20at%208.35.32%20AM.png" height="72" width="72"/><thr:total>5</thr:total></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-582368152716771238.post-2636489935894278774</id><published>2022-09-09T18:50:00.000-05:00</published><updated>2022-09-09T18:50:08.942-05:00</updated><category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Banking"/><category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Commentary"/><category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Environment"/><category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="European Debt Crisis"/><category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Financial Reform"/><category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Inflation"/><title type='text'>Energy Agony</title><content type='html'>&lt;p&gt;Two era-defining articles popped up in today&#39;s Wall Street Journal.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wsj.com/articles/the-coming-global-crisis-of-climate-policy-europe-germany-energy-prices-bankruptcy-winter-subsidies-borrowing-green-nuclear-11662651070&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;the coming global crisis of climate policy,&lt;/a&gt;&quot; Joseph Sternberg writes&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;...Anyone who still thinks climate change is a greater threat than climate policy to financial stability deserves to be exiled to a peat-burning yurt in the wilderness.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;...the world’s central banks and other regulators are in the middle of a major push to introduce various forms of climate stress testing into their oversight. ...The fad is for quantifying, with preposterous faux-precision, the costs of reinsuring flood risks, or fire, or the depressed corporate profits of a dystopian hotter future.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Well, if you seek “climate risk” to financial stability, look around you. It has arrived, although in exactly the opposite manner to what our current crop of eco-financiers predicted....&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;The U.K. may be facing a wave of business bankruptcies exceeding anything witnessed during the post-2008 panic and recession...The culprit is energy prices...Matters are probably worse in Germany,...&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Banks and other financial firms inevitably will find themselves right at the edge of the water if or when a tsunami of energy-price bankruptcies washes ashore.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a name=&#39;more&#39;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;If you&#39;ve been living in that solar-heated yurt, you may not be aware that central banks and financial regulators (SEC) are moving headlong to de-fund fossil fuel investments via regulation. The fig leaf for this activity is the notion that fossil fuel companies, though funded almost entirely by common equity, pose &quot;risks&quot; to the financial system. (Lots on this in previous blog posts, click the &quot;environment&quot; tag.)&amp;nbsp;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Getting transition risk wrong.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sternberg got a detail wrong and unintentionally pulled a punch. Writing,&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Federal Reserve, Bank of England and European Central Bank, among others, want to know how global temperature variations a century hence might weigh on Citi’s or Barclays’ or Deutsche Bank’s capital and risk weightings today.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Actually, no. The &quot;climate financial risk&quot; stress tests aren&#39;t quite that transparently dumb, since bank balance sheets don&#39;t have risks more than 5 to 10 years out. Instead they start with the theory that extreme weather events will cause financial problems in this shorter horizon. When it&#39;s pointed out that even the IPCC says that the probability distribution of weather really isn&#39;t changing that fast, and economists point out that floods and hurricanes have never caused a financial system crash, they admit that&#39;s really not going to happen. They move on to stress test &quot;transition risk,&quot; that governments might pass climate policies so extreme that they cause a financial meltdown.&amp;nbsp;&lt;i&gt;This is exactly what is just about to happen.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;That observation is the really devastating one: They were supposed to stress test &quot;transition risk.&quot; But governments&amp;nbsp;&lt;i&gt;did&lt;/i&gt;&amp;nbsp;pass transition policies&amp;nbsp;that threaten a really big risk to the financial system. And &amp;nbsp;those were exactly the same policies that the aforementioned central banks wish to&amp;nbsp;&lt;i&gt;privilege&lt;/i&gt;&amp;nbsp;as a result of these &quot;stress tests,&quot; namely banning fossil fuels before replacements are available at scale and subsidizing electric cars, windmills and solar panels. But &lt;i&gt;they got the sign exactly wrong.&lt;/i&gt; The transition risk to the financial system is not that governments would bankrupt oil companies. Duh, restrict supply, the price goes up, not down. The transition risk is that oil companies are swimming in profits and everyone else is going to go bust. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Does anyone know what exactly any of this will mean for the financial system? Of course not. No one has seriously bothered to “stress test” catastrophic increases in energy prices.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;The unraveling of risk regulation.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Actually, the point is even deeper and more devastating. &amp;nbsp;What we are seeing is the fourth grand failure in 15 years of the whole idea that regulators can monitor bank assets and thereby keep the financial system safe. The financial crisis of 2008 erupted despite plenty of bank risk regulation. Rivers of new rules were adopted, including the US Dodd-Frank act and subsidiary regulations, along with stress tests, all aimed at regulators supervising bank assets. No sooner had the barn door been closed after the departing horse, but the European debt crisis broke out. This too was fundamentally a banking crisis: Allowing Greece to fail would have imperiled too many banks, French and German as well as Greek. So much for the asset risk regulators. 12 years of heightened regulation and stress tests later, along came covid-19, threatening another wave of bankruptcies, and another perceived threat to the financial system. No stress tester ever thought about &quot;what if there is a pandemic,&quot; despite their repeated eruption through human history. The Fed bailed out treasury markets, money market funds, individual companies, state and local governments, and even issued a Mario-Draghi-worthy &quot;whatever it takes&quot; to prop up the price of corporate bonds. This time nobody even had the decency to worry about containing moral hazard. And &lt;i&gt;that&lt;/i&gt; horse having just left the barn, here we are once more facing an even larger financial crisis... that not a single stress tester had the imagination to foresee as even a possibility.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I don&#39;t fault them, they&#39;re only human. The point: the whole project of counting on armies of bureaucrats to foresee risks and safeguard bank assets is hopeless. &amp;nbsp;If it&#39;s hopeless for real estate, soveriegn default, pandemic, and war (when our side has visibly invited the Trojan pipeline in), goodness gracious the idea that the same system can foresee &quot;climate risk to the financial system&quot; is ludicrous. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Fiscal crisis?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;What next? Well, stress testing having failed once again, here comes the bailout and stimulus, which seems to be our governments&#39; only response to anything.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;European governments aren’t blind to the energy-price threat—an awareness that, perversely, creates a threat of its own. The only politically viable solution for this winter will be subsidies on a monumental scale. Hundreds of billions of dollars for households and businesses (and utilities) across the Continent already have been announced, and desperate capitals won’t stop there. This will require substantial borrowing on top of the fisc-wrecking bond issuance during the pandemic.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;And also &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;...on top of the additional borrowing governments normally do during recessions to finance social-welfare assistance. All of this while interest rates start rising after resting for more than a decade on (or below) the floor.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;There is no lack of demand mysterious Keynesian economics afoot here. This is a good old fashioned shoot-self-in-foot supply shock. Borrowed or printed money cannot make a nation better off.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I have been opining that the next crisis, with trillions in bailout and stimulus might be the one in which investors finally say no more. We shall see.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Meanwhile, back in the UK; economic fallacies&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wsj.com/articles/u-k-government-to-cap-household-energy-prices-for-two-years-11662634632&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp;U.K. Government to Cap Household Energy Prices for Two Years&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;The U.K. government said it would cap household energy prices over the next two years, a costly bailout aimed at staving off a deep recession and bringing down inflation, but one that could add to growing worries about the British government’s financial health.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;The package, which economists say is likely to be worth more than $120 billion, ... also marks the first big act in office for new U.K. Prime Minister Liz Truss...&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ms. Truss was advertised as a libertarian. I see that lasted about 10 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Perhaps the most basic principle of sound economics is, &quot;&lt;i&gt;don&#39;t transfer income by distorting prices.&lt;/i&gt;&quot; Don&#39;t silence the incentive. If one wishes to cushion the effect of a shock, then send people money to keep their real incomes constant, but don&#39;t subsidize the thing in short supply.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yet the political system inexorably controls prices. Usually that means rationing, &amp;nbsp;though the UK may be able to import what people demand at the controlled prices instead.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Why? There must be a question to which this is an answer. And I suspect this is it: Citizens of a democracy don&#39;t really care about the effects of energy prices on overall income distribution. What they really want is to go about their business as before. They don&#39;t want a 2,000 pound check and still have to figure out a way to save gas. They want to drive to bloody work just as before. They don&#39;t want precisely the pain of substitution that relative prices would signal. And politicians of a democracy give them what they want.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this theory, politicians aren&#39;t dumb. They&#39;re doing what people want them to do.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;Bringing down inflation&quot; is another economic howler. What a brilliant idea! We can just stop inflation altogether! Just require that every store charge exactly what it did a year ago, and the government will borrow or print money to make up the difference! I hope you can see the problem here. Economic principle #2 for today: &lt;i&gt;Cheaper to the individual, at the point of sale, does not mean cheaper to society as a whole&lt;/i&gt;. You can pay at the pump or you can pay the tax man. This fallacy pervades the recent &quot;inflation reduction act&quot; in the US. Subsidies to solar panels, windmills, electric cars, and price caps on prescription drugs do not make them &quot;cheaper&quot; to society. It just changes where you pay.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;Growing worries&quot; You bet. We create inflation by printing up money and debt and handing it out. Then, to solve the problem we... print up more money and debt and hand it out. You can see where this is heading. Another economic principle: &lt;i&gt;there is always supply and demand.&lt;/i&gt;&amp;nbsp; Politicians blame &quot;supply&quot; for higher prices, but the prices would not be high if people were not demanding all those expensive goods, and willing and able to fork over the money.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Extraordinary challenges call for extraordinary measures, ensuring that the United Kingdom is never in this situation again,” Ms. Truss said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Or ensuring that the United Kingdom is perpetually in this situation, perhaps. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</content><link rel='replies' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://johnhcochrane.blogspot.com/feeds/2636489935894278774/comments/default' title='Post Comments'/><link rel='replies' type='text/html' href='https://johnhcochrane.blogspot.com/2022/09/energy-agony.html#comment-form' title='20 Comments'/><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/582368152716771238/posts/default/2636489935894278774'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/582368152716771238/posts/default/2636489935894278774'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://johnhcochrane.blogspot.com/2022/09/energy-agony.html' title='Energy Agony'/><author><name>John H. Cochrane</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/04842601651429471525</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='25' height='32' src='//4.bp.blogspot.com/-hxC_w91OloY/X8aKsZcuFcI/AAAAAAAADHs/CANi5RE5-n8t7QGX1CzX9vgEg1Bd22tpwCK4BGAYYCw/s220/john_cochrane_forweb.jpg'/></author><thr:total>20</thr:total></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-582368152716771238.post-2534484749764370186</id><published>2022-09-08T21:42:00.000-05:00</published><updated>2022-09-08T21:42:39.506-05:00</updated><category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Academic Articles"/><category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Economists"/><category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Essays"/><category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Fiscal Theory"/><category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Inflation"/><category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Macro"/><category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Monetary Policy"/><title type='text'>Expectations and the Neutrality of Interest Rates</title><content type='html'>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.johnhcochrane.com/research-all/inflation-neutrality&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Expectations and the Neutrality of Interest Rates&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;is a new paper. It&#39;s an essay, really, expanding on a lunch talk I was privileged to give at the Minneapolis Fed &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.minneapolisfed.org/~/media/assets/events/economic-research-conferences/foundations-of-monetary-policy-agenda.pdf?la=en&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&quot;Foundations of Monetary Policy&quot; conference&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;in honor of the 50th anniversary of Bob Lucas&#39; 1972 &quot;Expectations and the Neutrality of Money.&quot;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Abstract:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;Lucas (1972) is the pathbreaking analysis of the neutrality and temporary non-neutrality of money. But our central banks set interest rate targets, and do not even pretend to control money supplies. How is inflation determined under an interest rate target?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We finally have a complete theory of inflation under interest rate targets, that mirrors the long-run neutrality and frictionless limit of monetary theory: Inflation can be stable and determinate under interest rate targets, including a k percent rule, i. e. a peg. The zero bound era is confirmatory evidence. Uncomfortably, long-run neutrality means that higher interest rates eventually produce higher inflation, other things (and fiscal policy in particular) constant.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;With a Phillips curve, we have some non-neutrality as well: Higher nominal interest rates raise real rates and lower output. A good model in which higher interest rates temporarily lower inflation is a harder task. I exhibit one such model. It has the Lucas property that only unexpected interest rate rises can lower inflation. A better model, and empirical understanding, is as crucial to today&#39;s agenda as Lucas (1972) was in its day.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Much of this is contentious. The issues are crucial for policy: Can the Fed contain inflation without dramatically raising interest rates? Given the state of knowledge, a bit of humility is in order.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;The link also has slides, if you like those. In one slide, I managed to put together the 54 year project to (finally) produce a full theory of inflation under interest rate targets:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEjIWgofTBEpMcNgyEKNQ-CKNSUXTaLxkuTjx2hudGL58NC_ks-nel34jmGcMvV_6QN_1UWIh_otB20lr9TxvVryRxo5JVBK0O_e8KZ3Abrx3HtTDLOhdl7RDJT-A4Bkk_3loP33_tD0Wr0dflSHcMLS9nAEJqUBFtirwXZRigVCbgKkyifgeHv6KGg/s792/MN_slides.png&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;612&quot; data-original-width=&quot;792&quot; height=&quot;494&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEjIWgofTBEpMcNgyEKNQ-CKNSUXTaLxkuTjx2hudGL58NC_ks-nel34jmGcMvV_6QN_1UWIh_otB20lr9TxvVryRxo5JVBK0O_e8KZ3Abrx3HtTDLOhdl7RDJT-A4Bkk_3loP33_tD0Wr0dflSHcMLS9nAEJqUBFtirwXZRigVCbgKkyifgeHv6KGg/w640-h494/MN_slides.png&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><link rel='replies' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://johnhcochrane.blogspot.com/feeds/2534484749764370186/comments/default' title='Post Comments'/><link rel='replies' type='text/html' href='https://johnhcochrane.blogspot.com/2022/09/expectations-and-neutrality-of-interest.html#comment-form' title='16 Comments'/><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/582368152716771238/posts/default/2534484749764370186'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/582368152716771238/posts/default/2534484749764370186'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://johnhcochrane.blogspot.com/2022/09/expectations-and-neutrality-of-interest.html' title='Expectations and the Neutrality of Interest Rates'/><author><name>John H. Cochrane</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/04842601651429471525</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='25' height='32' src='//4.bp.blogspot.com/-hxC_w91OloY/X8aKsZcuFcI/AAAAAAAADHs/CANi5RE5-n8t7QGX1CzX9vgEg1Bd22tpwCK4BGAYYCw/s220/john_cochrane_forweb.jpg'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEjIWgofTBEpMcNgyEKNQ-CKNSUXTaLxkuTjx2hudGL58NC_ks-nel34jmGcMvV_6QN_1UWIh_otB20lr9TxvVryRxo5JVBK0O_e8KZ3Abrx3HtTDLOhdl7RDJT-A4Bkk_3loP33_tD0Wr0dflSHcMLS9nAEJqUBFtirwXZRigVCbgKkyifgeHv6KGg/s72-w640-h494-c/MN_slides.png" height="72" width="72"/><thr:total>16</thr:total></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-582368152716771238.post-808993832076594549</id><published>2022-09-02T14:23:00.004-05:00</published><updated>2022-09-03T13:21:28.843-05:00</updated><category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Academic Articles"/><category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Economists"/><category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Inflation"/><category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Monetary Policy"/><category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Thesis topics"/><title type='text'>Apartment inflation</title><content type='html'>&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;table align=&quot;center&quot; cellpadding=&quot;0&quot; cellspacing=&quot;0&quot; class=&quot;tr-caption-container&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEhmn7-_r3BXVVtfR1tcq8D9zOPP0AAgjFOUUv8wc7zxyb2sLj0Z659oA9zc4OA762RYbZVxDiUiARqdK4Uhi04X7DCurpjrdw7xuYuy5IXPuNXUoStYiCgz6H3Hzj6yqfAaEGFRrLV82Q5EmXEZj0KGGt_0nb9xa6DI5sVhSCDt4zvLxZmhsg/s800/RentYoYJuly2022.PNG&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;510&quot; data-original-width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;408&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEhmn7-_r3BXVVtfR1tcq8D9zOPP0AAgjFOUUv8wc7zxyb2sLj0Z659oA9zc4OA762RYbZVxDiUiARqdK4Uhi04X7DCurpjrdw7xuYuy5IXPuNXUoStYiCgz6H3Hzj6yqfAaEGFRrLV82Q5EmXEZj0KGGt_0nb9xa6DI5sVhSCDt4zvLxZmhsg/w640-h408/RentYoYJuly2022.PNG&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;tr-caption&quot; style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;This beautiful &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.calculatedriskblog.com/2022/08/pace-of-rent-increases-continues-to-slow.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;graph comes from calculatedriskblog.com&lt;/a&gt;. (Courtesy Andy Atkeson who used it in a nice discussion of a great paper by Ivan Werning at the Minneapolis Fed &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.minneapolisfed.org/~/media/assets/events/economic-research-conferences/foundations-of-monetary-policy-agenda.pdf?la=en&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Foundations of Monetary Policy conference&lt;/a&gt;.)&amp;nbsp;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The central lines that don&#39;t move so much are the average rent. This is the quantity used by the Bureau of Labor Statistics to compute the consumer price index. The blue and yellow lines are the rent of new leases.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The first thing this informs is the economic theory of &quot;sticky prices.&quot; Apartment rents are a classic &quot;sticky price;&quot; the rent is fixed in dollar terms for a year. So, landlords deciding how much rent to charge, and people deciding how much they&#39;re willing to pay, &amp;nbsp;balance rents now vs. higher rents in the future. If everyone believes that inflation will be 10% over the next year, then it makes sense to raise the rent 5% now, and to pay the 5% higher rent, because &amp;nbsp;the savings at the end of the year balance the cost in the beginning. (Obviously, the economics are much more subtle than this, but you get the idea.) And Voila&#39;, you see it.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The graph also says there is some predictability and nomentum to inflation. Inflation should not be a surprise to forecasters. If you see rents on new leases much above average rents, it&#39;s a pretty good bet that average rents will be rising in the future! This kind of phenomenon may be under exploited in formal inflation forecasting.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And, on the continuing speculation whether inflation will go away with interest rates still substantially below current inflation, the graph does seem a leading indicator that the rational expectations model is winning. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Clarification: &lt;/i&gt;Of course, the graph says nothing about causality; did new leases rise sharply because people expected inflation in average leases, or did new leases rise for other reasons, and we&#39;re just seeing the old theorem that marginal &amp;nbsp;&amp;gt; average when average is rising. But it is consistent with the expectations story, and illuminates that story nicely.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><link rel='replies' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://johnhcochrane.blogspot.com/feeds/808993832076594549/comments/default' title='Post Comments'/><link rel='replies' type='text/html' href='https://johnhcochrane.blogspot.com/2022/09/apartment-inflation.html#comment-form' title='6 Comments'/><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/582368152716771238/posts/default/808993832076594549'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/582368152716771238/posts/default/808993832076594549'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://johnhcochrane.blogspot.com/2022/09/apartment-inflation.html' title='Apartment inflation'/><author><name>John H. Cochrane</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/04842601651429471525</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='25' height='32' src='//4.bp.blogspot.com/-hxC_w91OloY/X8aKsZcuFcI/AAAAAAAADHs/CANi5RE5-n8t7QGX1CzX9vgEg1Bd22tpwCK4BGAYYCw/s220/john_cochrane_forweb.jpg'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEhmn7-_r3BXVVtfR1tcq8D9zOPP0AAgjFOUUv8wc7zxyb2sLj0Z659oA9zc4OA762RYbZVxDiUiARqdK4Uhi04X7DCurpjrdw7xuYuy5IXPuNXUoStYiCgz6H3Hzj6yqfAaEGFRrLV82Q5EmXEZj0KGGt_0nb9xa6DI5sVhSCDt4zvLxZmhsg/s72-w640-h408-c/RentYoYJuly2022.PNG" height="72" width="72"/><thr:total>6</thr:total></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-582368152716771238.post-1640689839047671105</id><published>2022-08-25T16:27:00.003-05:00</published><updated>2022-08-25T22:58:47.755-05:00</updated><category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Commentary"/><category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Fiscal Theory"/><category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Inflation"/><category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Monetary Policy"/><category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Op-eds"/><title type='text'>WSJ inflation stability oped -- with pictures</title><content type='html'>&lt;p&gt;&quot;Nobody Knows How Interest Rates Affect Inflation&quot; is a new oped in the&amp;nbsp;&lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wsj.com/articles/nobody-knows-how-interest-rates-affect-inflation-unstable-stable-seal-pendulum-1970s-spirals-expectations-federal-reserve-11661368265?mod=opinion_lead_pos7&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Wall Street Journal&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/i&gt;August 25. (Full version will be posted here Sept 25). It&#39;s a distillation of two recent essays, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.johnhcochrane.com/research-all/inflation-neutrality&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Expectations and the Neutrality of Interest Rates&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.johnhcochrane.com/research-all/inflation-past-present-future&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Inflation Past, Present, and Future&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and some recent talks.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Fed has only very slowly raised interest rates in response to inflation:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEhlEx-8BrkI-UEGjLwfpwCLS77_GGxCfFA5YmtxE87m8Ro4x2_AGBCWpmRqiRp9VrDu4ZOouo9jDzHrfgyI6OzbUiLjy93Pa2Z3w57yYXuz2Z6dXN2DJSpYrIPL_xC9XxmaINJpCMOrqYVIyBfsw4ytWSYlMY5uYlG6gEeFkE4V44yh_YNfCjBN53c/s1598/Screen%20Shot%202022-08-25%20at%202.00.19%20PM.png&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;732&quot; data-original-width=&quot;1598&quot; height=&quot;294&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEhlEx-8BrkI-UEGjLwfpwCLS77_GGxCfFA5YmtxE87m8Ro4x2_AGBCWpmRqiRp9VrDu4ZOouo9jDzHrfgyI6OzbUiLjy93Pa2Z3w57yYXuz2Z6dXN2DJSpYrIPL_xC9XxmaINJpCMOrqYVIyBfsw4ytWSYlMY5uYlG6gEeFkE4V44yh_YNfCjBN53c/w640-h294/Screen%20Shot%202022-08-25%20at%202.00.19%20PM.png&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;Does the Fed&#39;s slow reaction mean that inflation will spiral away, until the Fed raises interest rates above inflation? The traditional theory says yes. In this theory, inflation is unstable when the Fed follows an interest rate target. Unstable:&amp;nbsp;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEiis4-m78CgCvhmhc7733Xh9Sy8csSReoay_SX7rzV5Bwx8iBQwfnQ_FQJLpVoC_CJ1uHHCwfkdcU8Gnqi9kdvoYRmDIo_Myl7zcCcPhLwfvwIpEITrRxHKHTS9So2WyBWTtoffLoz8wVPCdvnuq4u2sDc7KScgbB0ocqhIYTcMw4CoIuxA7ZSK1PY/s1548/Screen%20Shot%202022-08-25%20at%202.00.37%20PM.png&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;548&quot; data-original-width=&quot;1548&quot; height=&quot;226&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEiis4-m78CgCvhmhc7733Xh9Sy8csSReoay_SX7rzV5Bwx8iBQwfnQ_FQJLpVoC_CJ1uHHCwfkdcU8Gnqi9kdvoYRmDIo_Myl7zcCcPhLwfvwIpEITrRxHKHTS9So2WyBWTtoffLoz8wVPCdvnuq4u2sDc7KScgbB0ocqhIYTcMw4CoIuxA7ZSK1PY/w640-h226/Screen%20Shot%202022-08-25%20at%202.00.37%20PM.png&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div&gt;In this view, the Fed must promptly raise interest rates above inflation to contain inflation, as the seal must move its nose more than one for one to get back under the ball. Until we get interest rates of 9% and more inflation will spiral upward.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;The view comes fundamentally from adaptive expectations. Inflation = expected inflation - (effect of high real interest rates, i.e. interest rate - expected inflation). If expected inflation is last year&#39;s inflation, you can see inflation spirals up until the real interest rate is positive.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;But an alternative view says that inflation is fundamentally stable. Stable:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEiBL7Zv1HCiGRLvB3tnld9f1FkTP_AoQ6UDh4Z_o9K1sqq0oOtLRGFn1UPc39CdzDHh8N8lU6Kh_N7goX0NZ9vDe-qv1tK2UwzdpqPDGsKj5fLpib3DsXT88gmpYKUpBCbPv6irV-AamQCUUg4JpfmYC1N5Cx9JJeqxtzwVU_PFX6N8_hA4g0DShlE/s1554/Screen%20Shot%202022-08-25%20at%202.00.56%20PM.png&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;672&quot; data-original-width=&quot;1554&quot; height=&quot;276&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEiBL7Zv1HCiGRLvB3tnld9f1FkTP_AoQ6UDh4Z_o9K1sqq0oOtLRGFn1UPc39CdzDHh8N8lU6Kh_N7goX0NZ9vDe-qv1tK2UwzdpqPDGsKj5fLpib3DsXT88gmpYKUpBCbPv6irV-AamQCUUg4JpfmYC1N5Cx9JJeqxtzwVU_PFX6N8_hA4g0DShlE/w640-h276/Screen%20Shot%202022-08-25%20at%202.00.56%20PM.png&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;In this view, a shock to inflation will eventually fade away even if the Fed does nothing. The Fed can help by raising interest rates, but it does not have to exceed inflation. (That is, so long as there is no new shock, like another fiscal blowout.) This view comes from rational expectations. That term has a bad connotation. It only means that people think broadly about the future, and are no worse than, say, Fed economists, at forecasting inflation. Story: If you drive looking in the rear view mirror (expected road = past road), you veer off the road, unstable. If you look forward, even badly, (expected road = future road), the car will eventually get back on the road.&amp;nbsp;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Econometric tests aren&#39;t that useful -- inflation and interest rates move together in the long run in both views, and jiggle around each other. Episodes are salient. The unstable view points to the 1970s:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEiXxH5sQ0l2a1HsL8eqo8TUKlfO4ItHLkI1NAYobSmllzk1GdO5xZRLwjLJCndpUz55dTZWrNx-XAGLvb7z-jybV1qDozF9rscnE7vrW87oGVzGvT8ffM4x9dUkQCsyQjsySbGI4wKhZCpleVBJuI55-Ijg2Du22RYHlniUMzKpo5LD1IjXIwe2YhY/s1614/Screen%20Shot%202022-08-25%20at%202.01.09%20PM.png&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;746&quot; data-original-width=&quot;1614&quot; height=&quot;296&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEiXxH5sQ0l2a1HsL8eqo8TUKlfO4ItHLkI1NAYobSmllzk1GdO5xZRLwjLJCndpUz55dTZWrNx-XAGLvb7z-jybV1qDozF9rscnE7vrW87oGVzGvT8ffM4x9dUkQCsyQjsySbGI4wKhZCpleVBJuI55-Ijg2Du22RYHlniUMzKpo5LD1IjXIwe2YhY/w640-h296/Screen%20Shot%202022-08-25%20at%202.01.09%20PM.png&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div&gt;The Fed reacted too slowly to shocks, the story goes, letting inflation spiral up until it finally got its nose under the ball in 1980, driving inflation back down again. But the stable view points to the 2010s:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEj7iusZh3608VTCcJcIloH2yKsYp1kdFiyqMevw1NwA_bBldK6RN4u5AEeWdL1w67KcTdYgroO7qc0TvP-G1XrXRsWTjwm9819moWaJr9TO29LKOC_1iuecZRDAZscV80SqaERWsiByXO-9KdhgmcWXExrX6wZVWSq6o-aMN_TaFhpyyAWuLJveOvY/s1630/Screen%20Shot%202022-08-25%20at%202.19.25%20PM.png&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;814&quot; data-original-width=&quot;1630&quot; height=&quot;320&quot; src=&quot;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEj7iusZh3608VTCcJcIloH2yKsYp1kdFiyqMevw1NwA_bBldK6RN4u5AEeWdL1w67KcTdYgroO7qc0TvP-G1XrXRsWTjwm9819moWaJr9TO29LKOC_1iuecZRDAZscV80SqaERWsiByXO-9KdhgmcWXExrX6wZVWSq6o-aMN_TaFhpyyAWuLJveOvY/w640-h320/Screen%20Shot%202022-08-25%20at%202.19.25%20PM.png&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div&gt;It&#39;s exactly the opposite situation. Deflation broke out. The Fed could not move interest rates below zero. The classic analysis screamed &quot;here comes the deflation spiral.&quot; It didn&#39;t happen. Wolf. If the deflation spiral did not break out, why will an inflation spiral break out now?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Not elsewhere: As I look at these, I start to have additional doubts about the classic story of the 1970s. The Fed did move interest rates one for one. Inflation did not simply spiral out of control. For example, note in 1975, inflation did come right back down again, even though interest rates never got above inflation. The simple spiral story does not explain why 1975 was briefly successful. Each of the waves of inflation also was sparked by new shocks.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Who is right? I don&#39;t pound my fist on the table, but stability, at least in the long run, is looking more and more likely to me. That says inflation will eventually go away, after the price level has risen enough to inflate away the recent debt blowout, even if the Fed never raises rates above inflation. In any case, it looks like we have another really significant episode all set up, to add to the 1970s and 2010s. If inflation spirals, stability is in trouble. If inflation fades away and interest rates never exceed inflation, the classic view is really in trouble. The ingredients are stirred, the test tube is on the table...&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;But, that&#39;s a conditional mean. A new shock could send inflation spiraling up again, just as may have happened in the 1970s. New virus, China invades Taiwan, financial crisis, sovereign debt crisis, another fiscal blowout -- if the US forgives college debt, why not forgive home loans? Credit cards? -- all could send inflation up again, and ruin this beautiful experiment.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='replies' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://johnhcochrane.blogspot.com/feeds/1640689839047671105/comments/default' title='Post Comments'/><link rel='replies' type='text/html' href='https://johnhcochrane.blogspot.com/2022/08/wsj-inflation-stability-oped-with.html#comment-form' title='29 Comments'/><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/582368152716771238/posts/default/1640689839047671105'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://www.blogger.com/feeds/582368152716771238/posts/default/1640689839047671105'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='https://johnhcochrane.blogspot.com/2022/08/wsj-inflation-stability-oped-with.html' title='WSJ inflation stability oped -- with pictures'/><author><name>John H. Cochrane</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/04842601651429471525</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='25' height='32' src='//4.bp.blogspot.com/-hxC_w91OloY/X8aKsZcuFcI/AAAAAAAADHs/CANi5RE5-n8t7QGX1CzX9vgEg1Bd22tpwCK4BGAYYCw/s220/john_cochrane_forweb.jpg'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEhlEx-8BrkI-UEGjLwfpwCLS77_GGxCfFA5YmtxE87m8Ro4x2_AGBCWpmRqiRp9VrDu4ZOouo9jDzHrfgyI6OzbUiLjy93Pa2Z3w57yYXuz2Z6dXN2DJSpYrIPL_xC9XxmaINJpCMOrqYVIyBfsw4ytWSYlMY5uYlG6gEeFkE4V44yh_YNfCjBN53c/s72-w640-h294-c/Screen%20Shot%202022-08-25%20at%202.00.19%20PM.png" height="72" width="72"/><thr:total>29</thr:total></entry></feed>