<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns:yt="http://www.youtube.com/xml/schemas/2015" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
 <link rel="self" href="http://www.youtube.com/feeds/videos.xml?channel_id=UCHnyfMqiRRG1u-2MsSQLbXA"/>
 <id>yt:channel:UCHnyfMqiRRG1u-2MsSQLbXA</id>
 <yt:channelId>UCHnyfMqiRRG1u-2MsSQLbXA</yt:channelId>
 <title>Veritasium</title>
 <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCHnyfMqiRRG1u-2MsSQLbXA"/>
 <author>
  <name>Veritasium</name>
  <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCHnyfMqiRRG1u-2MsSQLbXA</uri>
 </author>
 <published>2010-07-21T07:18:02+00:00</published>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:nmgFG7PUHfo</id>
  <yt:videoId>nmgFG7PUHfo</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCHnyfMqiRRG1u-2MsSQLbXA</yt:channelId>
  <title>The Most Important Algorithm Of All Time</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=nmgFG7PUHfo"/>
  <author>
   <name>Veritasium</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCHnyfMqiRRG1u-2MsSQLbXA</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-11-03T12:52:34+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-11-03T16:45:43+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>The Most Important Algorithm Of All Time</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/nmgFG7PUHfo?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i3.ytimg.com/vi/nmgFG7PUHfo/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>The Fast Fourier Transform is used everywhere but it has a fascinating origin story that could have ended the nuclear arms race. This video is sponsored by 80,000 Hours. Head to http://80000hours.org/veritasium to sign up for their newsletter and get sent a free copy of their in-depth career guide.

A huge thank you to Dr. Richard Garwin for taking the time to speak with us. 
Thanks to Dr. Steve Brunton of the University of Washington for his help with understanding the Fast Fourier Transform. 

Thanks to Dr. Cliff Thurber of the University of Wisconsin-Madison, Dr. Paul Richards of Columbia University, and Dr. Steven Gibbons of the Norwegian Geotechnical Institute for their expertise. 

Thanks to Grant Sanderson of 3Blue1Brown for his helpful feedback on the script. His great video on the Fourier Transform is here - https://youtu.be/spUNpyF58BY

▀▀▀
References:

Kristensen, H.M., Korda, M. (2022). Status of World Nuclear Forces. Federation of American Scientists (FAS). https://ve42.co/Stockpile2022

Barth, K. H. (1998). Science and politics in early nuclear test ban negotiations. Physics Today, 51(3), 34-39. - https://ve42.co/Barth1998

Schmalberger, T. (1991). In pursuit of a nuclear test ban treaty - https://ve42.co/Schmalberger1991

Bowers, D., &amp; Selby, N. D. (2009). Forensic seismology and the comprehensive nuclear-test-ban treaty. Annual Review of Earth and Planetary Sciences, 37, 209-236 - https://ve42.co/Bowers2009

Incorporated Research Institutions for Seismology (IRIS). (2022). How Often Do Earthquakes Occur? https://ve42.co/IRIS2022

Kimball, D. (2022). The Nuclear Testing Tally. Arms Control Association. https://ve42.co/TestTally2022

Kværna, T., &amp; Ringdal, F. (2013). Detection capability of the seismic network of the International Monitoring System for the Comprehensive Nuclear Test Ban Treaty. Bulletin of the Seismological Society of America, 103(2A), 759-772 - https://ve42.co/Kvrna2013

Sykes, L. R., &amp; Evernden, J. F. (1982). The verification of a comprehensive nuclear test ban. Scientific American, 247(4), 47-55 - https://ve42.co/Sykes1982

Peterson, J., &amp; Hutt, C. R. (2014). World-wide standardized seismograph network: a data users guide (p. 82). US Department of the Interior, US Geological Survey. - https://ve42.co/Peterson2014

Richards, P. G., &amp; Kim, W. Y. (2009). Monitoring for nuclear explosions. Scientific American, 300(3), 70-77 - https://ve42.co/Richards2009

Jacobsen, L. L., Fedorova, I., &amp; Lajus, J. (2021). The seismograph as a diplomatic object: The Soviet–American exchange of instruments, 1958–1964. Centaurus, 63(2), 277-295 - https://ve42.co/Jacobsen2021

Schwartz S. I. (1998). The Hidden Costs Of Our Nuclear Arsenal: Overview Of Project Findings. The Brookings Institution -  https://ve42.co/Schwartz1998

Ricón, J.L. (2016). The Soviet Union: Military Spending. Nintil - https://ve42.co/Nintil2016

Heideman, M. T., Johnson, D. H., &amp; Burrus, C. S. (1985). Gauss and the history of the fast Fourier transform. Archive for history of exact sciences, 265-277 - https://ve42.co/Heideman1985

Ford, D. (2004). Richard Garwin - Session IV. American Institute of Physics (AIP). - https://ve42.co/Ford2004

Aaserud, F. (1986). Richard Garwin - Session I. American Institute of Physics (AIP). - https://ve42.co/Aaserud1986

Goldstein, A. (1997). James W. Cooley, an oral history. IEEE History Center, Piscataway, NJ, USA - https://ve42.co/Goldstein1997

Cooley, J., Garwin, R., Rader, C., Bogert, B., &amp; Stockham, T. (1969). The 1968 Arden House workshop on fast Fourier transform processing. IEEE Transactions on Audio and Electroacoustics, 17(2), 66-76 - https://ve42.co/Cooley1969


▀▀▀
Special thanks to Patreon supporters: 
Louis Lebbos, Elliot MIller, RayJ Johnson, Brian Busbee, Jerome Barakos M.D., Amadeo Bee, TTST, Balkrishna Heroor, Chris LaClair, John H. Austin, Jr., OnlineBookClub.org, Matthew Gonzalez, Eric Sexton, John Kiehl, Diffbot, Gnare, Dave Kircher, Burt Humburg, Blake Byers, Dumky, Evgeny Skvortsov, Meekay, Bill Linder, Paul Peijzel, Josh Hibschman, Mac Malkawi, Mike Schneider, John Bauer, jim buckmaster, Juan Benet, Sunil Nagaraj, Richard Sundvall, Lee Redden, Stephen Wilcox, Marinus Kuivenhoven, Michael Krugman, Cy 'kkm' K'Nelson, Sam Lutfi, Ron Neal

▀▀▀
Written by Derek Muller &amp; Felicity Nelson
Filmed by Derek Muller &amp; Raquel Nuno
Animation by Ivy Tello, Jakub Misiek, Alex Drakoulis, and Fabio Albertelli
Edited by Albert Leung &amp; Derek Muller
Research Assistant: Katie Barnshaw
Additional video/photos supplied by Pond5 and Getty Images
Music from Epidemic Sound
Produced by Derek Muller, Petr Lebedev, and Emily Zhang</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="120217" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="2128221"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:NdWFCygzr8k</id>
  <yt:videoId>NdWFCygzr8k</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCHnyfMqiRRG1u-2MsSQLbXA</yt:channelId>
  <title>Why do we launch rockets from Florida?</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=NdWFCygzr8k"/>
  <author>
   <name>Veritasium</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCHnyfMqiRRG1u-2MsSQLbXA</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-10-06T01:05:05+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-10-22T12:16:50+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Why do we launch rockets from Florida?</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/NdWFCygzr8k?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i3.ytimg.com/vi/NdWFCygzr8k/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>I always thought Florida seemed like a terrible place to launch anything from.</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="66278" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="1099285"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:16Ci_2bN_zc</id>
  <yt:videoId>16Ci_2bN_zc</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCHnyfMqiRRG1u-2MsSQLbXA</yt:channelId>
  <title>How Dangerous is a Penny Dropped From a Skyscraper?</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=16Ci_2bN_zc"/>
  <author>
   <name>Veritasium</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCHnyfMqiRRG1u-2MsSQLbXA</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-10-01T15:00:11+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-10-31T11:35:00+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>How Dangerous is a Penny Dropped From a Skyscraper?</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/16Ci_2bN_zc?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i2.ytimg.com/vi/16Ci_2bN_zc/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>This video is sponsored by Brilliant. You can get started for free, or the first 200 people to sign up via https://brilliant.org/veritasium get 20% off a yearly subscription. Check out Adam Savage's video: https://youtu.be/h_zytOcMwys

A massive thanks to Adam Savage and the whole Tested Crew – especially Kristen Lomasney, Ryan Kiser, and Joey Fameli. Thank you so much for coming out to the desert with us, and for inviting us to your cave! Check out the video we made with them on their channel – https://youtu.be/h_zytOcMwys

Another huge thanks to iFly Ontario for letting us shoot in your amazing windtunnel. Special thanks to Diana Rios, Treasa Telle, Michelle Brumley for having us and Anthony Jones, Torrell Henderson and Nate Roth for being great instructors. iFly run STEM education trips, where you can experience terminal velocity first hand  – https://www.iflyworld.com/programs/stem-field-trips/

Thanks to Inland Empire Film Services and the San Bernardino County Film Office for portions of the video shot in the County of San Bernardino.

The raindrop video is from Alistair McClymont’s gorgeous artwork “Raindrop” – ​​https://alistairmcclymont.com/artwork/raindrop/

Video of the raindrop breaking apart is from the coolest paper i’ve read in a while –  Villermaux, E., &amp; Bossa, B. (2009). Single-drop fragmentation determines size distribution of raindrops. Nature physics, 5(9), 697-702. – https://ve42.co/Villermaux



▀▀▀
References:
Altair. (2019). Digital Debunking: Could a Penny Dropped Off the Top of the Empire State Building Actually Kill You? - https://ve42.co/Altair2019 


Braeunig, R.A. Atmosphere Properties. - https://ve42.co/AtmosProp


The Guardian. (2014). Brutal winter weather brings new challenge: ice falling from skyscrapers - https://ve42.co/WTCicicle


NASA. (2018). The Apollo 15 Hammer-Feather Drop - https://ve42.co/NASAmoondrop


Red Bull Stratos - https://ve42.co/RBStratos


Quealy, K., Sanger-KatzIn, M. (2015). In Other Countries, You’re as Likely to Be Killed by a Falling Object as by a Gun. New York Times. - https://ve42.co/NYTFallingObject


National Safety Council. (2022). Struck by Objects. - https://ve42.co/NSCStruck


Williams, A. (2019). What are your chances of being killed by hail in the US? - https://ve42.co/Williams2019


NewScientist. (2021). Can bullets fired upwards cause injuries when they return to earth? - https://ve42.co/CelebratoryGunFire

Chambers, J. (2020). Meet the Flechette – the Deadliest Weapon of World War I? - https://ve42.co/Flechette

Wikipedia. Lazy Dog (bomb). - https://ve42.co/LazyDog 

Gläser, N., Kneubuehl, B. P., Zuber, S., Axmann, S., Ketterer, T., Thali, M. J., &amp; Bolliger, S. A. (2011). Biomechanical examination of blunt trauma due to baseball bat blows to the head. Journal of Forensic Biomechanics, 2 - https://ve42.co/Glaser2011

Yoganandan, N., Pintar, F. A., SANCES JR, A. N. T. H. O. N. Y., Walsh, P. R., Ewing, C. L., Thomas, D. J., &amp; Snyder, R. G. (1995). Biomechanics of skull fracture. Journal of neurotrauma, 12(4), 659-668.

New York Times. (2014). Falling Tape Measure Kills Man at Jersey City Construction Site - The New York Times - https://ve42.co/NYTTapeMeasure

IMDb. (2006). &quot;MythBusters&quot; Bullets Fired Up (TV Episode). - https://ve42.co/MBgunfire 

▀▀▀
Special thanks to: Elliot MIller, Louis Lebbos, RayJ Johnson, Brian Busbee, Jerome Barakos M.D., Amadeo Bee, TTST, Balkrishna Heroor, Chris LaClair, John H. Austin, Jr., OnlineBookClub.org, Matthew Gonzalez, Eric Sexton, john kiehl, Nathan Lanza, Diffbot, Gnare, Dave Kircher, Burt Humburg, Blake Byers, Dumky, Evgeny Skvortsov, Meekay, Bill Linder, Paul Peijzel, Josh Hibschman, Mac Malkawi, Michael Schneider, jim buckmaster, Juan Benet, Robert Blum, Sunil Nagaraj, Richard Sundvall, Lee Redden, Stephen Wilcox, Marinus Kuivenhoven, Michael Krugman, Cy 'kkm' K'Nelson, Sam Lutfi, Ron Neal

▀▀▀
Written by Petr Lebedev, Derek Muller, and Emily Zhang
Filmed by Derek Muller, Trenton Oliver, Petr Lebedev, Emily Zhang, Raquel Nuno and Eddie Lopez
Animation by Ivy Tello, Mike Radjabov, Fabio Albertelli, and Jakub Misiek
Edited by Trenton Oliver and Derek Muller
FPV Drone Pilots: Sammie Saing and Josh Ewalt
Slow Motion Camera: Shawn Sanders and Anthony Corrales
Phantom slow motion camera &amp; lenses provided by Panny Hire L.A
Helicopter Pilots: Rick Shuster and Cliff Fleming
Helicopter Safety Officer: Ryan Hosking
Production Assistants: Roman Bacvic and Eddie Lopez
Research Assistant: Katie Barnshaw
Additional video/photos supplied by Pond5 and Getty Images
Music from Epidemic Sound
Produced by Derek Muller, Petr Lebedev, and Emily Zhang</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="274306" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="11249145"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:daaDuC1kbds</id>
  <yt:videoId>daaDuC1kbds</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCHnyfMqiRRG1u-2MsSQLbXA</yt:channelId>
  <title>World's Highest Jumping Robot</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=daaDuC1kbds"/>
  <author>
   <name>Veritasium</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCHnyfMqiRRG1u-2MsSQLbXA</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-08-31T13:00:16+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-09-13T15:21:37+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>World's Highest Jumping Robot</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/daaDuC1kbds?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i1.ytimg.com/vi/daaDuC1kbds/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>This tiny robot can jump higher than anything else in the world. This video is sponsored by Brilliant. The first 200 people to sign up via https://brilliant.org/veritasium get 20% off a yearly subscription.

Huge thanks to Dr. Elliot Hawkes and the rest of the group - Charles Xiao, Chris Keeley, Dr. Morgan Pope, and Dr. Günter Niemeyer - for having us at UCSB and showing us their high-flying jumper. This work was partially supported by an Early Career Faculty Grant from NASA’s Space Technology Research Grants Program.

▀▀▀
References:

Hawkes, E.W., Xiao, C., Peloquin, R., Keeley, C., Begley, M.R., Pope, M.T., &amp; Niemeyer, G. (2022). Engineered jumpers overcome biological limits via work multiplication. Nature, 604, 657-661. – https://rdcu.be/cMePc
https://ve42.co/Hawkes2022
Fernandez, S. (2022). Hitting New Heights. The Current, UC Santa Barbara. – https://ve42.co/Fernandez2022
Bushwick, S. (2022). Record-Breaking Jumping Robot Can Leap a 10-Story Building. Engineering, Scientific American. – https://ve42.co/Bushwick2022
Mack, E. (2022). This Robot Can Leap Nine Stories in One Jump, Will Go Even Higher on Moon. Science, CNET. – https://ve42.co/Mack2022
Ashby, M. (2020). Materials Selection in Mechanical Design (4th edition). Elsevier. 
Jumping robot leaps to record heights. Nature Video - https://ve42.co/NatureJumper
MultiMo-Bat Robot - https://ve42.co/MultiMoBat
Galago Jump - https://ve42.co/GalagoJump
Slingshot Spider - https://ve42.co/SlingshotSpider

▀▀▀
Special thanks to Patreon supporters: RayJ Johnson, Brian Busbee, Jerome Barakos M.D., Amadeo Bee, TTST, Balkrishna Heroor, Chris LaClair, John H. Austin, Jr., OnlineBookClub.org, Matthew Gonzalez, Eric Sexton, john kiehl, Nathan Lanza, Diffbot, Gnare, Dave Kircher, Burt Humburg, Blake Byers, Dumky, Evgeny Skvortsov, Meekay, Bill Linder, Paul Peijzel, Josh Hibschman, Mac Malkawi, Michael Schneider, jim buckmaster, Juan Benet, Robert Blum, Sunil Nagaraj, Richard Sundvall, Lee Redden, Stephen Wilcox, Marinus Kuivenhoven, Michael Krugman, Cy 'kkm' K'Nelson, Sam Lutfi, Ron Neal

▀▀▀
Written by Emily Zhang and Derek Muller
Filmed by Derek Muller and Trenton Oliver
Animation by Mike Radjabov and Ivy Tello
Edited by Trenton Oliver
Additional video/photos supplied by Pond5 and Getty Images
Music from Epidemic Sound
Produced by Derek Muller, Petr Lebedev, and Emily Zhang</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="153883" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="7731520"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:5eW6Eagr9XA</id>
  <yt:videoId>5eW6Eagr9XA</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCHnyfMqiRRG1u-2MsSQLbXA</yt:channelId>
  <title>The 4 things it takes to be an expert</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=5eW6Eagr9XA"/>
  <author>
   <name>Veritasium</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCHnyfMqiRRG1u-2MsSQLbXA</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-08-02T16:51:13+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-08-13T08:54:40+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>The 4 things it takes to be an expert</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/5eW6Eagr9XA?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i2.ytimg.com/vi/5eW6Eagr9XA/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>Which experts have real expertise? This video is sponsored by Brilliant. The first 200 people to sign up via https://brilliant.org/veritasium get 20% off a yearly subscription.

Thanks to https://www.chess24.com/ and Chessable for the clip of Magnus.

▀▀▀
Chase, W. G., &amp; Simon, H. A. (1973). Perception in chess. Cognitive psychology, 4(1), 55-81. – https://ve42.co/chess1

Calderwood, R., Klein, G. A., &amp; Crandall, B. W. (1988). Time pressure, skill, and move quality in chess. The American Journal of Psychology, 481-493. – https://ve42.co/chess2

Hogarth, R. M., Lejarraga, T., &amp; Soyer, E. (2015). The two settings of kind and wicked learning environments. Current Directions in Psychological Science, 24(5), 379-385. – https://ve42.co/Hogarth

Ægisdóttir, S., White, M. J., Spengler, P. M., Maugherman, A. S., Anderson, L. A., Cook, R. S., ... &amp; Rush, J. D. (2006). The meta-analysis of clinical judgment project: Fifty-six years of accumulated research on clinical versus statistical prediction. The Counseling Psychologist, 34(3), 341-382. – https://ve42.co/anderson1

Ericsson, K. A. (2015). Acquisition and maintenance of medical expertise: a perspective from the expert-performance approach with deliberate practice. Academic Medicine, 90(11), 1471-1486.  – https://ve42.co/anderson2

Goldberg, S. B., Rousmaniere, T., Miller, S. D., Whipple, J., Nielsen, S. L., Hoyt, W. T., &amp; Wampold, B. E. (2016). Do psychotherapists improve with time and experience? A longitudinal analysis of outcomes in a clinical setting. Journal of Counseling Psychology, 63(1), 1. – https://ve42.co/goldberg1

Ericsson, K. A., Krampe, R. T., &amp; Tesch-Römer, C. (1993). The role of deliberate practice in the acquisition of expert performance. Psychological Review, 100(3), 363. – https://ve42.co/anderson3

Egan, D. E., &amp; Schwartz, B. J. (1979). Chunking in recall of symbolic drawings. Memory &amp; Cognition, 7(2), 149-158. – https://ve42.co/chunking1

Tetlock, P. E. (2017). Expert political judgment. In Expert Political Judgment. Princeton University Press. – https://ve42.co/Tetlock

Melton, R. S. (1952). A comparison of clinical and actuarial methods of prediction with an assessment of the relative accuracy of different clinicians. Unpublished Ph.D. thesis, University of Minnesota. 

Meehl, E. P. (1954). Clinical versus Statistical Prediction: A Theoretical Analysis and a Review of the Evidence. University of Minnesota Press. – https://ve42.co/Meehl1954

Kahneman, D. (2011). Thinking, fast and slow. Farrar, Straus and Giroux. – https://ve42.co/Kahneman

▀▀▀
Special thanks to Patreon supporters: RayJ Johnson, Brian Busbee, Jerome Barakos M.D., Amadeo Bee, Julian Lee, Inconcision, TTST, Balkrishna Heroor, Chris LaClair, Avi Yashchin, John H. Austin, Jr., OnlineBookClub.org, Matthew Gonzalez, Eric Sexton, john kiehl, Diffbot, Gnare, Dave Kircher, Burt Humburg, Blake Byers, Dumky, Evgeny Skvortsov, Meekay, Bill Linder, Paul Peijzel, Josh Hibschman, Timothy O’Brien, Mac Malkawi, Michael Schneider, jim buckmaster, Juan Benet, Ruslan Khroma, Robert Blum, Richard Sundvall, Lee Redden, Vincent, Stephen Wilcox, Marinus Kuivenhoven, Michael Krugman, Cy 'kkm' K'Nelson, Sam Lutfi, Ron Neal 

▀▀▀
Written by Derek Muller and Petr Lebedev
Animation by Ivy Tello and Fabio Albertelli  
Filmed by Derek Muller and Raquel Nuno
Additional video/photos supplied by Getty Images
Music from Epidemic Sound (https://ve42.co/music)
Produced by Derek Muller, Petr Lebedev, and Emily Zhang</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="367805" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="6961499"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:EvknN89JoWo</id>
  <yt:videoId>EvknN89JoWo</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCHnyfMqiRRG1u-2MsSQLbXA</yt:channelId>
  <title>The Man Who Killed Millions and Saved Billions</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=EvknN89JoWo"/>
  <author>
   <name>Veritasium</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCHnyfMqiRRG1u-2MsSQLbXA</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-07-22T17:03:09+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-09-08T20:14:32+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>The Man Who Killed Millions and Saved Billions</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/EvknN89JoWo?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i2.ytimg.com/vi/EvknN89JoWo/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>Fritz Haber is the scientist who arguably most transformed the world. Part of this video is sponsored by Wren. Offset your carbon footprint on Wren: ​https://www.wren.co/start/veritasium1. For the first 100 people who sign up, I will personally pay for the first month of your subscription!

▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀
A huge thanks to Dan Charles for writing a fantastic biography of Fritz Haber, for taking the time to talk to us about it, and providing valuable feedback. This video would not be what it is without his contributions. http://site.danielcharles.us https://ve42.co/Charles

Thanks to Tom de Prinse from Explosions and Fire for helping us with the chemistry of explosives. If you like explosions and/or fire, you will love his channel. https://www.youtube.com/c/ExplosionsFire2

Thanks to Michael Kuiper of CSIRO for the animation of the composition of air - https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=j9JvX58aRfg

Special thanks to Sonya Pemberton, Karl Kruszelnicki, Mary Dobbie, Olivia McRae, and the patreon supporters for giving us feedback on the earlier version of this video.

▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀
References:

The primary reference used is Vaclav Smil’s excellent book, Enriching The Earth – 
Smil, V. (2004). Enriching the earth: Fritz Haber, Carl Bosch, and the transformation of world food production. MIT press. – https://ve42.co/Smil

Mastermind: The Rise and Fall of Fritz Haber, the Nobel Laureate Who Launched the Age of Chemical Warfare, by Dan Charles – https://ve42.co/Charles

Stoltzenberg, D. (2004). Fritz Haber: Chemist, Nobel Laureate, German, Jew. Chemical Heritage Foundation. – https://ve42.co/Stoltzenberg

Postgate, J. R. (1982). The fundamentals of nitrogen fixation. CUP Archive. – https://ve42.co/postgate

Miles, A. G. (1992). Biological nitrogen fixation. – https://ve42.co/Miles

Friedrich, B., &amp; Hoffmann, D. (2017). Clara Immerwahr: A life in the shadow of Fritz Haber. In One Hundred Years of Chemical Warfare: Research, Deployment, Consequences(pp. 45-67). Springer, Cham. – https://ve42.co/Friedrich2017

Da Silva, G. (2020). What is ammonium nitrate, the chemical that exploded in Beirut. Sci Am, 5. – https://ve42.co/Silva

Rodrigues, P., &amp; Micael, J. (2021). The importance of guano birds to the Inca Empire and the first conservation measures implemented by humans. – https://ve42.co/rodrigues

Allison, F. E. (1957). Nitrogen and soil fertility. Soil, the, 85-94. – https://ve42.co/Allison

Crookes, W. (1898). Address of the President before the British Association for the Advancement of Science, Bristol, 1898. Science, 8(200), 561-575. – https://ve42.co/Crookes

▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀
Special thanks to Patreon supporters: RayJ Johnson, Brian Busbee, Jerome Barakos M.D., Amadeo Bee, Julian Lee, Inconcision, TTST, Balkrishna Heroor, Chris LaClair, Avi Yashchin, John H. Austin, Jr., OnlineBookClub.org, Matthew Gonzalez, Eric Sexton, john kiehl, Diffbot, Gnare, Dave Kircher, Burt Humburg, Blake Byers, Dumky, Evgeny Skvortsov, Meekay, Bill Linder, Paul Peijzel, Josh Hibschman, Timothy O’Brien, Mac Malkawi, Michael Schneider, jim buckmaster, Juan Benet, Ruslan Khroma, Robert Blum, Richard Sundvall, Lee Redden, Vincent, Stephen Wilcox, Marinus Kuivenhoven, Michael Krugman, Cy 'kkm' K'Nelson, Sam Lutfi, Ron Neal 

▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀
Written by Petr Lebedev, Derek Muller, Felicity Nelson and Kovi Rose
Edited by Trenton Oliver
Animation by Jakub Mistek, Fabio Albertelli, Ivy Tello, Alex Drakoulis, Nils Ramses Kullack, and Charlie Davies
SFX by Shaun Clifford
Filmed by Petr Lebedev, Derek Muller and Raquel Nuno
Photo of nitrogen deficiency in rice from https://ve42.co/rice
Additional video/photos supplied by Getty Images
Music from Epidemic Sound: https://ve42.co/music</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="518680" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="14102548"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:iSNsgj1OCLA</id>
  <yt:videoId>iSNsgj1OCLA</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCHnyfMqiRRG1u-2MsSQLbXA</yt:channelId>
  <title>The Riddle That Seems Impossible Even If You Know The Answer</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=iSNsgj1OCLA"/>
  <author>
   <name>Veritasium</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCHnyfMqiRRG1u-2MsSQLbXA</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-06-30T12:20:58+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-07-27T02:26:52+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>The Riddle That Seems Impossible Even If You Know The Answer</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/iSNsgj1OCLA?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i2.ytimg.com/vi/iSNsgj1OCLA/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>The 100 Prisoners Riddle feels completely impossible even once you know the answer. This video is sponsored by Brilliant. The first 200 people to sign up via https://brilliant.org/veritasium get 20% off a yearly subscription.

Special thanks to Destin of Smarter Every Day (https://ve42.co/SED), Toby of Tibees (https://ve42.co/Tibees), and Jabril of Jabrils (https://ve42.co/Jabrils) for taking the time to think about this mind bending riddle.

Huge thanks to Luke West for building plots and for his help with the math. 
Huge thanks to Dr. Eugene Curtin and Dr. Max Warshauer for their great article on the problem and taking the time to help us understand it: https://ve42.co/CurtinWarshauer
Thanks to Dr. John Baez for his help with finding alternate ways to do the calculations.
Thanks to Simon Pampena for his input and analysis.

Other 100 Prisoners Riddle videos:
minutephysics: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=C5-I0bAuEUE
Vsauce2: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=kOnEEeHZp94
Stand-up Maths: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=a1DUUnhk3uE
TED-Ed: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vIdStMTgNl0

▀▀▀
References:
Original paper: Gál, A., &amp; Miltersen, P.B. (2003). The Cell Probe Complexity of Succinct Data Structures. BRICS, Department of Computer Science, University of Aarhus. All rights reserved. – https://ve42.co/GalMiltersen
Winkler, P. (2006). Seven Puzzles You Think You Must Not Have Heard Correctly. – https://ve42.co/Winkler2006
The 100 Prisoners Problem – https://ve42.co/100PWiki 
Golomb, S. &amp; Gaal, P. (1998). On the Number of Permutations on n Objects with Greatest Cycle Length k. Advances in Applied Mathematics, 20(1), 98-107. – https://ve42.co/Golomb1998
Lamb, E. (2012). Puzzling Prisoners Presented to Promote North America's Only Museum of Math. Observations, Scientific American. – https://ve42.co/Lamb2012
Permutations – https://ve42.co/PermutationsWiki
Probability that a random permutation of n elements has a cycle of length k greater than n/2, Math SE. – https://ve42.co/BaezProbSE
Counting Cycle Structures in Sn, Math SE. – https://ve42.co/CountCyclesSE
What is the distribution of cycle lengths in derangements? In particular, expected longest cycle, Math SE. – https://ve42.co/JorikiSE
The Manim Community Developers. (2021). Manim - Mathematical Animation Framework (Version v0.13.1). – https://www.manim.community/

▀▀▀
Special thanks to Patreon supporters: RayJ Johnson, Brian Busbee, Jerome Barakos M.D., Amadeo Bee, Julian Lee, Inconcision, TTST, Balkrishna Heroor, Chris LaClair, Avi Yashchin, John H. Austin, Jr., OnlineBookClub.org, Matthew Gonzalez, Eric Sexton, john kiehl, Diffbot, Gnare, Dave Kircher, Burt Humburg, Blake Byers, Dumky, Evgeny Skvortsov, Meekay, Bill Linder, Paul Peijzel, Josh Hibschman, Timothy O’Brien, Mac Malkawi, Michael Schneider, jim buckmaster, Juan Benet, Ruslan Khroma, Robert Blum, Richard Sundvall, Lee Redden, Vincent, Stephen Wilcox, Marinus Kuivenhoven, Michael Krugman, Cy 'kkm' K'Nelson, Sam Lutfi, Ron Neal

▀▀▀
Written by Derek Muller and Emily Zhang
Filmed by Derek Muller and Petr Lebedev
Animation by Ivy Tello and Jesús Rascón
Edited by Trenton Oliver
Additional video/photos supplied by Getty Images
Music from Epidemic Sound and Jonny Hyman
Produced by Derek Muller, Petr Lebedev, and Emily Zhang</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="299864" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="8099548"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:6etTERFUlUI</id>
  <yt:videoId>6etTERFUlUI</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCHnyfMqiRRG1u-2MsSQLbXA</yt:channelId>
  <title>The Absurd Search For Dark Matter</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6etTERFUlUI"/>
  <author>
   <name>Veritasium</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCHnyfMqiRRG1u-2MsSQLbXA</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-06-02T12:06:02+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-07-17T17:05:49+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>The Absurd Search For Dark Matter</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/6etTERFUlUI?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i3.ytimg.com/vi/6etTERFUlUI/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>This video is sponsored by Brilliant. The first 200 people to sign up via https://brilliant.org/veritasium get 20% off a yearly subscription. Astronomers think there should be 5 times as much dark matter as ordinary matter – a shadow universe that makes up most of the mass in the universe. But after decades of trying, no experiments have found any trace of dark matter – except one.

A massive thanks to the wonderful people at the ARC Centre of Excellence for Dark Matter Physics  https://www.centredarkmatter.org for showing us around and being on camera – Fleur Morrison, A/Prof Phillip Urquijo, Prof Elisabetta Barberio, Madeleine Zurowski and Grace Lawrence. 
Thanks to Leo Fincher-Johnson and everyone at the Stawell gold mine for having us.
Massive thanks to Prof. Geraint Lewis – Geraint has been Veritasium’s go-to expert for anything astrophysics and cosmology related. Please check out his website, and buy his books, they’re great –  https://www.geraintflewis.com
Thanks to Prof. Timothy Tait for the help to make sure we got the science right.
Thanks to Ingo Berg for illustrating the effect of dark matter on the rotation of a galaxy https://beltoforion.de/en/spiral_galaxy_renderer/spiral-galaxy-renderer.html

▀▀▀
Galaxy cluster simulation from IllustrisTNG – https://www.tng-project.org
Venn Diagram of Dark Matter from Tim Tait –  https://ve42.co/venn
The Bullet Cluster Image from Magellan, Hubble and Chandra telescopes – https://ve42.co/BC2
Bullet cluster animation from  Andrew Robertson / Institute for Computational Cosmology / Durham University – https://ve42.co/BC3

▀▀▀
Bernabei, R., Belli, P., Cappella, F., Cerulli, R., Dai, C. J., d’Angelo, A., ... &amp; Ye, Z. P. (2008). First results from DAMA/LIBRA and the combined results with DAMA/NaI. The European Physical Journal C, 56(3), 333-355. – https://ve42.co/DAMA2008

Zwicky, F. (1933). Die rotverschiebung von extragalaktischen nebeln. Helvetica physica acta, 6, 110-127. – https://ve42.co/Zwicky1

Zwicky, F. (1937). On the Masses of Nebulae and of Clusters of Nebulae. The Astrophysical Journal, 86, 217. – https://ve42.co/Zwicky2

Rubin, V. C., &amp; Ford Jr, W. K. (1970). Rotation of the Andromeda nebula from a spectroscopic survey of emission regions. The Astrophysical Journal, 159, 379. – https://ve42.co/Rubin1

Bosma, A., &amp; Van der Kruit, P. C. (1979). The local mass-to-light ratio in spiral galaxies. Astronomy and Astrophysics, 79, 281-286. – https://ve42.co/Bosma1

Milgrom, M. (1983). A modification of the Newtonian dynamics as a possible alternative to the hidden mass hypothesis. The Astrophysical Journal, 270, 365-370. – https://ve42.co/mond1

Sanders, R. H., &amp; McGaugh, S. S. (2002). Modified Newtonian dynamics as an alternative to dark matter. Annual Review of Astronomy and Astrophysics, 40(1), 263-317. – https://ve42.co/Mond2

M. Markevitch; A. H. Gonzalez; D. Clowe; A. Vikhlinin; L. David; W. Forman; C. Jones; S. Murray &amp; W. Tucker (2004). &quot;Direct constraints on the dark matter self-interaction cross-section from the merging galaxy cluster 1E0657-56&quot;. Astrophys. J. 606 (2): 819–824. – https://ve42.co/BC1

Great website about the CMB – http://background.uchicago.edu/~whu/intermediate/driving2.html

Galli, S., Iocco, F., Bertone, G., &amp; Melchiorri, A. (2009). CMB constraints on dark matter models with large annihilation cross section. Physical Review D, 80(2), 023505. – https://ve42.co/CMB1

Antonello, M., Barberio, E., Baroncelli, T., Benziger, J., Bignell, L. J., Bolognino, I., ... &amp; Xu, J. (2019). The SABRE project and the SABRE Proof-of-Principle. The European Physical Journal C, 79(4), 1-8. – https://ve42.co/SABRE1


▀▀▀
Special thanks to Patreon supporters: Inconcision, Kelly Snook, TTST, Ross McCawley, Balkrishna Heroor, Chris LaClair, Avi Yashchin, John H. Austin, Jr., OnlineBookClub.org, Dmitry Kuzmichev, Matthew Gonzalez, Eric Sexton, john kiehl, Anton Ragin, Diffbot, Micah Mangione, MJP, Gnare, Dave Kircher, Burt Humburg, Blake Byers, Dumky, Evgeny Skvortsov, Meekay, Bill Linder, Paul Peijzel, Josh Hibschman, Mac Malkawi, Michael Schneider, jim buckmaster, Juan Benet, Ruslan Khroma, Robert Blum, Richard Sundvall, Lee Redden, Vincent, Stephen Wilcox, Marinus Kuivenhoven, Clayton Greenwell, Michael Krugman, Cy 'kkm' K'Nelson, Sam Lutfi, Ron Neal

▀▀▀
Written by Derek Muller and Petr Lebedev
Edited by Trenton Oliver
Animation by Ivy Tello and Mike Radjabov
Filmed by Derek Muller and Petr Lebedev
Additional video/photos supplied by Getty Image
B-roll supplied by Stawell Gold Mine
Music from Epidemic Sound
Produced by Derek Muller, Petr Lebedev, and Emily Zhang</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="218607" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="5863167"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:Q1bSDnuIPbo</id>
  <yt:videoId>Q1bSDnuIPbo</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCHnyfMqiRRG1u-2MsSQLbXA</yt:channelId>
  <title>How did they actually take this picture? (Very Long Baseline Interferometry)</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Q1bSDnuIPbo"/>
  <author>
   <name>Veritasium</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCHnyfMqiRRG1u-2MsSQLbXA</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-05-12T14:52:13+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-09-06T13:18:59+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>How did they actually take this picture? (Very Long Baseline Interferometry)</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/Q1bSDnuIPbo?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i2.ytimg.com/vi/Q1bSDnuIPbo/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>This is an image of the supermassive black hole, Sagittarius A*, at the center of our Milky Way galaxy.
Visit https://www.kiwico.com/veritasium30 to get 30% off your first month of any crate!

▀▀▀
Image of Sgr A* from EHT collaboration
Event Horizon Telescope collaboration: https://ve42.co/EHT

Animations from The Relativistic Astrophysics group, Institute for Theoretical Physics,  Goethe-Universität Frankfurt. Massive thanks to Prof. Luciano Rezzolla, Dr Christian Fromm and Dr Alejandro Cruz-Osorio.

A huge thanks to Prof. Peter Tuthill and Dr Manisha Caleb for feedback on earlier versions of this video and helping explain VLBI.

Great video by Thatcher Chamberlin about VLBI here – https://youtu.be/Y8rAHTvpJbk

Animations and simulations with English text:
L. R. Weih &amp; L. Rezzolla (Goethe University Frankfurt)
https://youtu.be/jvftAadCFRI

Video of stars going around Sgr A* from European Southern Observatory
https://www.eso.org/public/videos/eso1825e/

Video zooming into the center of our galaxy from European Southern Observatory
https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dXAU0gzsPOw

Video of observation of M87 courtesy of:
C. M. Fromm, Y. Mizuno &amp; L. Rezzolla (Goethe University Frankfurt)
https://youtu.be/meOKmzhTcIY

Video of observation of SgrA* courtesy of
C. M. Fromm, Y. Mizuno &amp; L. Rezzolla (Goethe University Frankfurt)
Z. Younsi (University College London)
https://youtu.be/VnsZj9RvhFU

Video of telescopes in the array 2017:
C. M. Fromm &amp; L. Rezzolla (Goethe University Frankfurt)
https://youtu.be/Ame7fzBuFnk

Animations and simulations (no text):
L. R. Weih &amp; L. Rezzolla (Goethe University Frankfurt)
https://youtu.be/XmvpKFSvB7A


▀▀▀
Special thanks to Patreon supporters: Inconcision, Kelly Snook, TTST, Ross McCawley, Balkrishna Heroor, Chris LaClair, Avi Yashchin, John H. Austin, Jr., OnlineBookClub.org, Dmitry Kuzmichev, Matthew Gonzalez, Eric Sexton, john kiehl, Anton Ragin, Diffbot, Micah Mangione, MJP, Gnare, Dave Kircher, Burt Humburg, Blake Byers, Dumky, Evgeny Skvortsov, Meekay, Bill Linder, Paul Peijzel, Josh Hibschman, Mac Malkawi, Michael Schneider, jim buckmaster, Juan Benet, Ruslan Khroma, Robert Blum, Richard Sundvall, Lee Redden, Vincent, Stephen Wilcox, Marinus Kuivenhoven, Clayton Greenwell, Michael Krugman, Cy 'kkm' K'Nelson, Sam Lutfi, Ron Neal

▀▀▀
Written by Derek Muller
Animation by Ivy Tello, Mike Radjabov, Maria Raykova
Filmed by Petr Lebedev</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="190031" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="4540323"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:oI_X2cMHNe0</id>
  <yt:videoId>oI_X2cMHNe0</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCHnyfMqiRRG1u-2MsSQLbXA</yt:channelId>
  <title>How Electricity Actually Works</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=oI_X2cMHNe0"/>
  <author>
   <name>Veritasium</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCHnyfMqiRRG1u-2MsSQLbXA</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-04-29T13:59:54+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-08-03T23:51:20+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>How Electricity Actually Works</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/oI_X2cMHNe0?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i4.ytimg.com/vi/oI_X2cMHNe0/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>This video is sponsored by Brilliant. The first 200 people to sign up via https://brilliant.org/veritasium get 20% off a yearly subscription.

Special thanks to:
Bruce Sherwood, Ruth Chabay, Aaron Titus, and Steve Spicklemore
https://matterandinteractions.org
VPython simulation: http://tinyurl.com/SurfaceCharge

Thanks to Ansys for help with the simulations: https://www.ansys.com/products/electronics/ansys-hfss

Huge thanks to Richard Abbott from Caltech for all his modeling 

Electrical Engineering YouTubers:
Electroboom: https://www.youtube.com/c/Electroboom
Alpha Phoenix: https://www.youtube.com/c/AlphaPhoenixChannel
eevblog: https://www.youtube.com/c/EevblogDave
Ben Watson: https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCgZUVIEtBnnBpFWJuxl_E5g
Big Clive: https://www.youtube.com/c/Bigclive
Z Y: https://www.youtube.com/user/ZongyiYang
NYU Quantum Technology Lab
https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCk7io8SN3ZwKvkpnMCbIGsA
Dr. Ben Miles
https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCUeZBocfxALSUdOgNJB5ySA
Further analysis of the large circuit is available here: https://ve42.co/bigcircuit

Special thanks to Dr Geraint Lewis for bringing up this question in the first place and discussing it with us. Check out his and Dr Chris Ferrie’s new book here: https://ve42.co/Universe2021

▀▀▀
References:
A great video about the Poynting vector by the Science Asylum: https://youtu.be/C7tQJ42nGno

Sefton, I. M. (2002). Understanding electricity and circuits: What the text books don’t tell you. In Science Teachers’ Workshop. -- https://ve42.co/Sefton

Feynman, R. P., Leighton, R. B., &amp; Sands, M. (1965). The feynman lectures on physics; vol. Ii, chapter 27. American Journal of Physics, 33(9), 750-752. -- https://ve42.co/Feynman27

Hunt, B. J. (2005). The Maxwellians. Cornell University Press.

Müller, R. (2012). A semiquantitative treatment of surface charges in DC circuits. American Journal of Physics, 80(9), 782-788. -- https://ve42.co/Muller2012

Galili, I., &amp; Goihbarg, E. (2005). Energy transfer in electrical circuits: A qualitative account. American journal of physics, 73(2), 141-144. -- https://ve42.co/Galili2004

Deno, D. W. (1976). Transmission line fields. IEEE Transactions on Power Apparatus and Systems, 95(5), 1600-1611. -- https://ve42.co/Deno76

▀▀▀
Special thanks to Patreon supporters: Inconcision, Kelly Snook, TTST, Ross McCawley, Balkrishna Heroor, Chris LaClair, Avi Yashchin, John H. Austin, Jr., OnlineBookClub.org, Dmitry Kuzmichev, Matthew Gonzalez, Eric Sexton, john kiehl, Anton Ragin, Diffbot, Micah Mangione, MJP, Gnare, Dave Kircher, Burt Humburg, Blake Byers, Dumky, Evgeny Skvortsov, Meekay, Bill Linder, Paul Peijzel, Josh Hibschman, Mac Malkawi, Michael Schneider, jim buckmaster, Juan Benet, Ruslan Khroma, Robert Blum, Richard Sundvall, Lee Redden, Vincent, Stephen Wilcox, Marinus Kuivenhoven, Clayton Greenwell, Michael Krugman, Cy 'kkm' K'Nelson, Sam Lutfi, Ron Neal

▀▀▀
Written by Derek Muller
Edited by Derek Muller
Filmed by Trenton Oliver and Petr Lebedev
Animation by Mike Radjabov and Ivy Tello
Additional video/photos supplied by Getty Images
Music from Epidemic Sound and Jonny Hyman
Produced by Derek Muller, Petr Lebedev, and Emily Zhang</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="291441" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="7038276"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:IV3dnLzthDA</id>
  <yt:videoId>IV3dnLzthDA</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCHnyfMqiRRG1u-2MsSQLbXA</yt:channelId>
  <title>The Man Who Accidentally Killed The Most People In History</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=IV3dnLzthDA"/>
  <author>
   <name>Veritasium</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCHnyfMqiRRG1u-2MsSQLbXA</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-04-22T15:37:40+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-10-22T18:30:12+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>The Man Who Accidentally Killed The Most People In History</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/IV3dnLzthDA?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i2.ytimg.com/vi/IV3dnLzthDA/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>One scientist caused two environmental disasters and the deaths of millions. A part of this video is sponsored by Wren. Offset your carbon footprint on Wren: ​https://www.wren.co/start/veritasium. For the first 100 people who sign up, I will personally pay for the first month of your subscription!

Massive thanks to Prof. Francois Tissot for suggesting we make a video on the topic of isotope geochemistry. Huge thanks to Prof. Bruce Lanphear for consulting with us on lead and cardiovascular diseases. Thanks to the Caltech Archives for the audio of Patterson’s interview. Thanks to Vincent Mai for lending us your Snatoms kit. Thanks to Rayner Moss for the help with the fire-piston.

Patterson’s 1995 interview audio courtesy of the Archives, California Institute of Technology.

▀▀▀
Other great resources you should check out:
Bill Bryson has a chapter in his fantastic “A Short History of Nearly Everything”
Radiolab have a wonderful podcast: https://www.wnycstudios.org/podcasts/...
Cosmos: A Spacetime Odyssey has a wonderful episode – S1E7 which does a great job of telling the story of Clair Patterson
A fantastic Mental floss article – https://www.mentalfloss.com/article/9...

▀▀▀
References:

Much of the lead-crime hypothesis data is from Rick Nevin’s work – https://ricknevin.com/

WHO factsheet on lead poisoning – https://www.who.int/news-room/fact-sh...

WHO press release about the end of leaded gasoline https://news.un.org/en/story/2021/08/...

UNICEF report – https://ve42.co/UNICEF

Needleman, H. (2004). Lead poisoning. Annu. Rev. Med., 55, 209-222. https://ve42.co/Needleman1

Needleman, H. L. (1991). Human lead exposure. CRC Press. https://ve42.co/Needleman2

Needleman, H. L. et al. (1979). Deficits in psychologic and classroom performance of children with elevated dentine lead levels. New England journal of medicine, 300(13), 689-695. – https://ve42.co/Needleman3

Needleman, H. L. et al. (1996). Bone lead levels and delinquent behavior. Jama, 275(5), 363-369. https://ve42.co/Needleman4

Kovarik, W. J. (1993). The ethyl controversy: the news media and the public health debate over leaded gasoline, 1924-1926 https://ve42.co/Kovarik2

Edelmann, F. T. (2016). The life and legacy of Thomas Midgley Jr. In Papers and Proceedings of the Royal Society of Tasmania https://ve42.co/Edelmann

More, A. F. et al. (2017). Next‐generation ice core technology reveals true minimum natural levels of lead (Pb) in the atmosphere: Insights from the Black Death. GeoHealth, 1(4), 211-219. https://ve42.co/More1

McFarland, M. J., et al. (2022). PNAS 119(11), e2118631119. https://ve42.co/McFarland

Kovarik, W. (2005). Ethyl-leaded gasoline. International Journal of Occupational and Environmental Health, 11(4), 384-397. https://ve42.co/Kovarik3

Nevin, R. (2007). Understanding international crime trends: the legacy of preschool lead exposure. Environmental research, 104(3), 315-336. – https://ve42.co/Nevin2007

Ericson, J. E., et al. (1979). Skeletal concentrations of lead in ancient Peruvians. New England Journal of Medicine, 300(17), 946-951. – https://ve42.co/Ericson1

Patterson, Claire. The Isotopic Composition of Trace Quantities of Lead and Calcium https://ve42.co/Patterson1

Boutron, C. F., &amp; Patterson, C. C. (1986). Lead concentration changes in Antarctic ice during the Wisconsin/Holocene transition. Nature, 323(6085), 222-225. – https://ve42.co/Boulton1

Patterson, C. (1956). Age of meteorites and the earth. Geochimica et Cosmochimica Acta, 10(4), 230-237. – https://ve42.co/Patterson2

Lanphear, B. P. et al (2018). Low-level lead exposure and mortality in US adults: a population-based cohort study. The Lancet Public Health, 3(4), e177-e184. – https://ve42.co/Lanphear1

Schaule, B. K., &amp; Patterson, C. C. (1981). Lead concentrations in the northeast Pacific: evidence for global anthropogenic perturbations. Earth and Planetary Science Letters, 54(1), 97-116. – https://ve42.co/Schaule1

▀▀▀
Special thanks to Patreon supporters: Inconcision, Kelly Snook, TTST, Ross McCawley, Balkrishna Heroor, Chris LaClair, Avi Yashchin, John H. Austin, Jr., OnlineBookClub.org, Dmitry Kuzmichev, Matthew Gonzalez, Eric Sexton, john kiehl, Anton Ragin, Diffbot, Micah Mangione, MJP, Gnare, Dave Kircher, Burt Humburg, Blake Byers, Dumky, Evgeny Skvortsov, Meekay, Bill Linder, Paul Peijzel, Josh Hibschman, Mac Malkawi, Michael Schneider, jim buckmaster, Juan Benet, Ruslan Khroma, Robert Blum, Richard Sundvall, Lee Redden, Vincent, Stephen Wilcox, Marinus Kuivenhoven, Clayton Greenwell, Michael Krugman, Cy 'kkm' K'Nelson, Sam Lutfi, Ron Neal

▀▀▀
Written by Derek Muller, Petr Lebedev, Chris Stewart, and Katie Barnshaw
Edited by Trenton Oliver
Filmed by Petr Lebedev
Animation by Fabio Albertelli, Jakub Misiek, Iván Tello, Mike Radjabov, and Caleb Worcester
SFX by Shaun Clifford
Additional video/photos supplied by Getty Images
Music from Epidemic Sound
Produced by Derek Muller, Petr Lebedev, and Emily Zhang</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="724538" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="23178158"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:7ziWrneMYss</id>
  <yt:videoId>7ziWrneMYss</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCHnyfMqiRRG1u-2MsSQLbXA</yt:channelId>
  <title>How Horses Save Humans From Snakebites</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7ziWrneMYss"/>
  <author>
   <name>Veritasium</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCHnyfMqiRRG1u-2MsSQLbXA</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-03-22T11:55:53+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-07-23T16:52:53+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>How Horses Save Humans From Snakebites</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/7ziWrneMYss?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i4.ytimg.com/vi/7ziWrneMYss/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>This video is sponsored by Brilliant. The first 200 people to sign up via https://brilliant.org/veritasium get 20% off a yearly subscription. To make antivenom, you first need to collect venom from the world’s most deadly snakes.

Huge thanks to the Australian Reptile Park for having us over to film – special thanks to Zac Bower for milking all of these snakes for us and Caitlin Vine for organizing the shoot. Absolute legends. https://www.reptilepark.com.au

Huge thanks to Dr Timothy Jackson from the Australian Venom Research Unit for answering our questions, and fact checking the script. This video would not have been the same without you.

Thanks to Seqirus Australia for providing B-roll footage of the horses and the antivenom production.

▀▀▀
References:
Calmette, A. (1896). Le venin des serpents: Physiologie de l'envenimation, traitement des morsures venimeuses par le sérum des animaux vaccinés. Paris: Société d'éditions scientifiques.

Broad, A. J., Sutherland, S. K., &amp; Coulter, A. R. (1979). The lethality in mice of dangerous Australian and other snake venom. Toxicon, 17(6), 661-664. – https://ve42.co/Broad79

WHO Expert Committee on Biological Standardization. (2016). WHO guidelines for the production, control and regulation of snake antivenom immunoglobulins. Geneve, Switzerland. – https://ve42.co/WHO2016

Calmette, A. (1896). The treatment of animals poisoned with snake venom by the injection of antivenomous serum. British medical journal, 2(1859), 399. – https://ve42.co/Calmette1896

Hawgood, B. J. (1999). Doctor Albert Calmette 1863–1933: founder of antivenomous serotherapy and of antituberculous BCG vaccination. Toxicon, 37(9), 1241-1258. – https://ve42.co/Hawgood99

Pucca, M. B., Cerni, F. A., Janke, R., Bermúdez-Méndez, E., Ledsgaard, L., Barbosa, J. E., &amp; Laustsen, A. H. (2019). History of envenoming therapy and current perspectives. Frontiers in immunology, 1598. –  https://ve42.co/Pucca19

Kang, T. S., Georgieva, D., Genov, N., Murakami, M. T., Sinha, M., Kumar, R. P., ... &amp; Kini, R. M. (2011). Enzymatic toxins from snake venom: structural characterization and mechanism of catalysis. The FEBS journal, 278(23), 4544-4576. – https://ve42.co/Kang2011

Hawgood, B. J. (2007). Albert Calmette (1863–1933) and Camille Guerin (1872–1961): the C and G of BCG vaccine. Journal of medical biography, 15(3), 139-146. – https://ve42.co/Hawgood2007

Vonk, F. J., Admiraal, J. F., Jackson, K., Reshef, R., de Bakker, M. A., Vanderschoot, K., ... &amp; Richardson, M. K. (2008). Evolutionary origin and development of snake fangs. Nature, 454(7204), 630-633. – https://ve42.co/vonk2008

Bochner, R. (2016). Paths to the discovery of antivenom serotherapy in France. Journal of Venomous Animals and Toxins including Tropical Diseases, 22. – https://ve42.co/Bochner2016

Young, B. A., Herzog, F., Friedel, P., Rammensee, S., Bausch, A., &amp; van Hemmen, J. L. (2011). Tears of venom: hydrodynamics of reptilian envenomation. Physical review letters, 106(19), 198103. – https://ve42.co/Young2011

Madras Medical Journal, Volume Second, July-December 1870. Page 355

▀▀▀
Special thanks to Patreon supporters: Inconcision, Kelly Snook, TTST, Ross McCawley, Balkrishna Heroor, Chris LaClair, Avi Yashchin, John H. Austin, Jr., OnlineBookClub.org, Dmitry Kuzmichev, Matthew Gonzalez, Eric Sexton, john kiehl, Anton Ragin, Benedikt Heinen, Diffbot, Micah Mangione, MJP, Gnare, Dave Kircher, Burt Humburg, Blake Byers, Dumky, Evgeny Skvortsov, Meekay, Bill Linder, Paul Peijzel, Josh Hibschman, Mac Malkawi, Michael Schneider, jim buckmaster, Juan Benet, Ruslan Khroma, Robert Blum, Richard Sundvall, Lee Redden, Vincent, Stephen Wilcox, Marinus Kuivenhoven, Clayton Greenwell, Michael Krugman, Cy 'kkm' K'Nelson, Sam Lutfi, Ron Neal

▀▀▀
Written by Petr Lebedev and Derek Muller
Edited by Trenton Oliver
Filmed by Jason Tran and Petr Lebedev
Animation by Fabio Albertelli, Jakub Misiek,  Iván Tello and Mike Radjabov.
Molecule animation by Reciprocal Space – https://www.reciprocal.space
Additional video/photos supplied by Getty Image
B-roll supplied by Seqirus Australia
Music from Epidemic Sound and Jonny Hyman
Produced by Derek Muller, Petr Lebedev, and Emily Zhang</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="204738" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="12302041"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:GVsUOuSjvcg</id>
  <yt:videoId>GVsUOuSjvcg</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCHnyfMqiRRG1u-2MsSQLbXA</yt:channelId>
  <title>Future Computers Will Be Radically Different (Analog Computing)</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=GVsUOuSjvcg"/>
  <author>
   <name>Veritasium</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCHnyfMqiRRG1u-2MsSQLbXA</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-03-01T11:37:38+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-08-04T14:47:24+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Future Computers Will Be Radically Different (Analog Computing)</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/GVsUOuSjvcg?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i4.ytimg.com/vi/GVsUOuSjvcg/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>Visit https://brilliant.org/Veritasium/ to get started learning STEM for free, and the first 200 people will get 20% off their annual premium subscription. Digital computers have served us well for decades, but the rise of artificial intelligence demands a totally new kind of computer: analog.

Thanks to Mike Henry and everyone at Mythic for the analog computing tour! https://www.mythic-ai.com/
Thanks to Dr. Bernd Ulmann, who created The Analog Thing and taught us how to use it. https://the-analog-thing.org
Moore’s Law was filmed at the Computer History Museum in Mountain View, CA.
Welch Labs’ ALVINN video: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=H0igiP6Hg1k

▀▀▀
References:
Crevier, D. (1993). AI: The Tumultuous History Of The Search For Artificial Intelligence. Basic Books. – https://ve42.co/Crevier1993
Valiant, L. (2013). Probably Approximately Correct. HarperCollins. – https://ve42.co/Valiant2013
Rosenblatt, F. (1958). The Perceptron: A Probabilistic Model for Information Storage and Organization in the Brain. Psychological Review, 65(6), 386-408. – https://ve42.co/Rosenblatt1958
NEW NAVY DEVICE LEARNS BY DOING; Psychologist Shows Embryo of Computer Designed to Read and Grow Wiser (1958). The New York Times, p. 25. – https://ve42.co/NYT1958
Mason, H., Stewart, D., and Gill, B. (1958). Rival. The New Yorker, p. 45. – https://ve42.co/Mason1958
Alvinn driving NavLab footage – https://ve42.co/NavLab
Pomerleau, D. (1989). ALVINN: An Autonomous Land Vehicle In a Neural Network. NeurIPS, (2)1, 305-313. – https://ve42.co/Pomerleau1989
ImageNet website – https://ve42.co/ImageNet
Russakovsky, O., Deng, J. et al. (2015). ImageNet Large Scale Visual Recognition Challenge. – https://ve42.co/ImageNetChallenge
AlexNet Paper: Krizhevsky, A., Sutskever, I., Hinton, G. (2012). ImageNet Classification with Deep Convolutional Neural Networks. NeurIPS, (25)1, 1097-1105. – https://ve42.co/AlexNet
Karpathy, A. (2014). Blog post: What I learned from competing against a ConvNet on ImageNet. – https://ve42.co/Karpathy2014
Fick, D. (2018). Blog post: Mythic @ Hot Chips 2018. – https://ve42.co/MythicBlog
Jin, Y. &amp; Lee, B. (2019). 2.2 Basic operations of flash memory. Advances in Computers, 114, 1-69. – https://ve42.co/Jin2019
Demler, M. (2018). Mythic Multiplies in a Flash. The Microprocessor Report. – https://ve42.co/Demler2018
Aspinity (2021). Blog post: 5 Myths About AnalogML. – https://ve42.co/Aspinity
Wright, L. et al. (2022). Deep physical neural networks trained with backpropagation. Nature, 601, 49–555. – https://ve42.co/Wright2022
Waldrop, M. M. (2016). The chips are down for Moore’s law. Nature, 530, 144–147. – https://ve42.co/Waldrop2016

▀▀▀
Special thanks to Patreon supporters: Kelly Snook, TTST, Ross McCawley, Balkrishna Heroor, 65square.com, Chris LaClair, Avi Yashchin, John H. Austin, Jr., OnlineBookClub.org, Dmitry Kuzmichev, Matthew Gonzalez, Eric Sexton, john kiehl, Anton Ragin, Benedikt Heinen, Diffbot, Micah Mangione, MJP, Gnare, Dave Kircher, Burt Humburg, Blake Byers, Dumky, Evgeny Skvortsov, Meekay, Bill Linder, Paul Peijzel, Josh Hibschman, Mac Malkawi, Michael Schneider, jim buckmaster, Juan Benet, Ruslan Khroma, Robert Blum, Richard Sundvall, Lee Redden, Vincent, Stephen Wilcox, Marinus Kuivenhoven, Clayton Greenwell, Michael Krugman, Cy 'kkm' K'Nelson, Sam Lutfi, Ron Neal

▀▀▀
Written by Derek Muller, Stephen Welch, and Emily Zhang
Filmed by Derek Muller, Petr Lebedev, and Emily Zhang
Animation by Iván Tello, Mike Radjabov, and Stephen Welch
Edited by Derek Muller
Additional video/photos supplied by Getty Images and Pond5
Music from Epidemic Sound
Produced by Derek Muller, Petr Lebedev, and Emily Zhang</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="305299" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="8832134"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:IgF3OX8nT0w</id>
  <yt:videoId>IgF3OX8nT0w</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCHnyfMqiRRG1u-2MsSQLbXA</yt:channelId>
  <title>The Most Powerful Computers You've Never Heard Of</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=IgF3OX8nT0w"/>
  <author>
   <name>Veritasium</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCHnyfMqiRRG1u-2MsSQLbXA</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2021-12-21T19:32:53+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-05-19T01:41:04+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>The Most Powerful Computers You've Never Heard Of</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/IgF3OX8nT0w?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i2.ytimg.com/vi/IgF3OX8nT0w/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>Analog computers were the most powerful computers for thousands of years, relegated to obscurity by the digital revolution. This video is sponsored by Brilliant. The first 200 people to sign up via https://brilliant.org/veritasium get 20% off a yearly subscription.

Thanks to Scott Wiedemann for the lego computer instructions – https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=5X_Ft4YR_wU

Antikythera Archive &amp; Animations ©2005-2020 Images First Ltd. https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1ebB0tyrMa8 &quot;The Antikythera Cosmos&quot; (2021) follows the latest developments from the UCL Antikythera Research Team as they recreate a dazzling display of the ancient Greek Cosmos at the front of the Antikythera Mechanism.

Tides video from NASA – https://climate.nasa.gov/climate_resources/246/video-global-ocean-tides/

Ship animation from this painting – https://ve42.co/Agamemnon

Moore’s Law, the op-amp, and the Norden bombsight were filmed at the Computer History Museum in Mountain View, CA.

▀▀▀
References:

Freeth, T., Bitsakis, Y., Moussas, X., Seiradakis, J. H., Tselikas, A., Mangou, H., ... &amp; Edmunds, M. G. (2006). Decoding the ancient Greek astronomical calculator known as the Antikythera Mechanism. Nature, 444(7119), 587-591. – https://ve42.co/Freeth2006
Freeth, T., &amp; Jones, A. (2012). The cosmos in the Antikythera mechanism. ISAW Papers. – https://ve42.co/Freeth2012
Cartwright, D. E. (2000). Tides: a scientific history. Cambridge University Press. – https://ve42.co/tides
Thomson, W. (2017). Mathematical and physical papers. CUP Archive. – https://ve42.co/Kelvinv6
Parker, B. B. (2007). Tidal analysis and prediction. NOAA NOS Center for Operational Oceanographic Products and Services. - https://ve42.co/Parker2007
Parker, B. (2011). The tide predictions for D-Day. Physics Today, 64(9), 35-40. – https://ve42.co/Parker2011
Small, J. (2013). The Analogue Alternative. Routledge. – https://ve42.co/Small2013
Zorpette, G. (1989). Parkinson's gun director. IEEE Spectrum, 26(4), 43. – https://ve42.co/Zorpette89
Tremblay, M. (2009). Deconstructing the myth of the Norden Bombsight (Doctoral dissertation). – https://ve42.co/Tremblay
Gladwell, M. (2021). The Bomber Mafia. Little, Brown and Company. - https://ve42.co/Gladwell2021
Mindell, D. A. (2000). Automation’s finest hour: Radar and system integration in World War II. Systems, Experts, and Computers: The Systems Approach in Management and Engineering, World War II and After. Edited by A. C. Hughes and T. P. Hughes, 27-56. – https://ve42.co/Mindell
Haigh, T., Priestley, M., &amp; Rope, C. (2016). ENIAC in Action. The MIT Press. - https://ve42.co/Eniac2016
Soni, J., &amp; Goodman, R. (2017). A mind at play: how Claude Shannon invented the information age. Simon and Schuster. – https://ve42.co/Soni
Haigh, T. &amp; Ceruzzi, P. (2021). A New History of Modern Computing. The MIT Press. - https://ve42.co/ModernComputing
Rid, T. (2016). Rise of the Machines: a Cybernetic History. Highbridge. - https://ve42.co/Rid2016
Ulmann, B. (2013). Analog computing. Oldenbourg Wissenschaftsverlag. – https://ve42.co/Ulmann2013

▀▀▀
Special thanks to Patreon supporters: Dmitry Kuzmichev, Matthew Gonzalez, Baranidharan S, Eric Sexton, john kiehl, Daniel Brockman, Anton Ragin, S S, Benedikt Heinen, Diffbot, Micah Mangione, MJP, Gnare, Dave Kircher, Edward Larsen, Burt Humburg, Blak  Byers, Dumky, , Evgeny Skvortsov, Meekay, Bill Linder, Paul Peijzel, Mac Malkawi, Michael Schneider, Ludovic Robillard, jim buckmaster, Juan Benet, Ruslan Khroma, Robert Blum, Richard Sundvall, Lee Redden, Vincent, Stephen Wilcox, Marinus Kuivenhoven, Clayton Greenwell, Michael Krugman, Cy 'kkm' K'Nelson, Sam Lutfi, Ron Neal

Written by Derek Muller, Stephen Welch and Emily Zhang
Filmed by Derek Muller, Emily Zhang and Raquel Nuno
Animation by Fabio Albertelli, Jakub Misiek, Mike Radjabov, Iván Tello, Trenton Oliver
Edited by Derek Muller
Additional video supplied by Getty Images
Music from Epidemic Sound and Jonny Hyman
Produced by Derek Muller, Petr Lebedev and Emily Zhang</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="328906" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="8282789"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:ao2Jfm35XeE</id>
  <yt:videoId>ao2Jfm35XeE</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCHnyfMqiRRG1u-2MsSQLbXA</yt:channelId>
  <title>The Snowflake Mystery</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ao2Jfm35XeE"/>
  <author>
   <name>Veritasium</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCHnyfMqiRRG1u-2MsSQLbXA</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2021-12-01T07:35:28+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-07-22T03:01:07+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>The Snowflake Mystery</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/ao2Jfm35XeE?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i2.ytimg.com/vi/ao2Jfm35XeE/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>Dr Ken Libbrecht is the world expert on snowflakes, designer of custom snowflakes, snowflake consultant for the movie Frozen - his photos appear on postage stamps all over the world. This video is sponsored by Brilliant. The first 200 people to sign up via https://brilliant.org/veritasium get 20% off a yearly subscription.

Thanks to Dr Ken Libbrecht for showing us how to grow designer snowflakes. Obviously, this video would not have been possible without his help and his expertise.  His website is full of information about snowflakes http://snowcrystals.com. His new book is also available to purchase from here -- https://ve42.co/SnowCrystalsBook

▀▀▀
References:
Libbrecht, K. G. (2019). A Quantitative Physical Model of the Snow Crystal Morphology Diagram. arXiv preprint arXiv:1910.09067. -- https://ve42.co/Libbrecht2019

▀▀▀
Special thanks to Patreon supporters: Luis Felipe, Anton Ragin, Paul Peijzel, S S, Benedikt Heinen, Diffbot, Micah Mangione, Juan Benet, Ruslan Khroma, Richard Sundvall, Lee Redden, Sam Lutfi, MJP, Gnare, Nick DiCandilo, Dave Kircher, Edward Larsen, Burt Humburg, Blake Byers, Dumky, Mike Tung, Evgeny Skvortsov, Meekay, Ismail Öncü Usta, Crated Comments, Anna, Mac Malkawi, Michael Schneider, Oleksii Leonov, Jim Osmun, Tyson McDowell, Ludovic Robillard, Jim buckmaster, fanime96, Ruslan Khroma, Robert Blum, Vincent, Marinus Kuivenhoven, Alfred Wallace, Arjun Chakroborty, Joar Wandborg, Clayton Greenwell, Michael Krugman, Cy 'kkm' K'Nelson, Ron Neal 

Written by Derek Muller
Filmed by Derek Muller, Raquel Nuno, Trenton Oliver and Emily Zhang
Edited by Trenton Oliver
Animations by Ivàn Tello and Trenton Oliver
Additional video supplied by Getty Images
Music from Epidemic Sound
Produced by Derek Muller, Petr Lebedev and Emily Zhang</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="279306" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="7622189"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
</feed>
