<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xml:lang="en-US" xml:base="https://developers.facebook.com/" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><rights>Copyright (c) Meta Platforms, Inc. and affiliates.</rights><id>urn:uuid:6c306ca7-ff0b-4f7a-b371-92964eac0f14</id><title>Facebook Developers</title><subtitle>The latest news and announcements from Facebook Platform including APIs, SDKs, social plugins and Parse.</subtitle><updated>2022-11-01T21:36:40+00:00</updated><link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://developers.facebook.com/blog/"/><link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://developers.facebook.com/blog/feed/"/><author><name>Facebook Developers</name><uri>https://developers.facebook.com/</uri></author><icon>https://static.xx.fbcdn.net/rsrc.php/yv/r/B8BxsscfVBr.ico</icon><logo>https://static.xx.fbcdn.net/rsrc.php/v3/y1/r/xGN4CvUH3Nz.png</logo><entry><id>tag:developers.facebook.com,2022-11-01:blog:p10226482869954644</id><title>Access Levels for Gaming Apps</title><updated>2022-11-01T21:36:40+00:00</updated><published>2022-11-01T23:00:00+00:00</published><link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://developers.facebook.com/blog/post/2022/11/01/meta-access-levels-for-gaming-apps/"/><summary>Meta is continuously making strides to further safeguard people’s data and improve experiences on our platform. Building on changes previously announced in Graph API v11 update, today we are announcing the rollout of access levels for Gaming developers, an update to how developers control the level of data access with regard to permissions and features within their apps. Gaming apps include Gaming Services, Instant Games, Cloud Games, and Canvas apps.</summary></entry><entry><id>tag:developers.facebook.com,2022-11-01:blog:p10226477620423409</id><title>Plug and Play LA announces program with Meta to Transform the Future of Business Messaging</title><updated>2022-11-01T01:03:13+00:00</updated><published>2022-11-01T17:00:00+00:00</published><link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://developers.facebook.com/blog/post/2022/11/01/plug-and-play-la-program-with-meta/"/><summary>Every week, Meta estimates that it connects over 1 billion users around the world to businesses through the power of messaging. This scale opens up a tremendous opportunity for startups to innovate and create value by transforming how people and businesses interact online.</summary></entry><entry><id>tag:developers.facebook.com,2022-10-31:blog:p5615152708541844</id><title>Sending Messages via WhatsApp in Your Node.js Application</title><updated>2022-10-26T18:28:18+00:00</updated><published>2022-10-31T16:00:00+00:00</published><link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://developers.facebook.com/blog/post/2022/10/31/sending-messages-with-whatsapp-in-your-nodejs-application/"/><summary>This article describes how the Cloud API, hosted by Meta, Meta’s integration of the WhatsApp Business Platform, can be used in a Node.js application to provide the capability to send and manage WhatsApp messages sent and received via the Cloud API.</summary></entry><entry><id>tag:developers.facebook.com,2022-10-31:blog:p5478255302250347</id><title>Introducing the Product Tagging API for Reels to the Instagram Platform</title><updated>2022-10-30T16:24:55+00:00</updated><published>2022-10-31T17:00:00+00:00</published><link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://developers.facebook.com/blog/post/2022/10/31/introducing-product-tagging-api-for-reels-to-the-instagram-platform/"/><summary>[THE FIRST PARAGRAPH OF THE POST]</summary></entry><entry><id>tag:developers.facebook.com,2022-10-25:blog:p10221458672766743</id><title>Introducing Intellectual Property Reporting API: empowering rights holders to streamline reporting</title><updated>2022-10-20T23:09:48+00:00</updated><published>2022-10-25T13:00:00+00:00</published><link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://developers.facebook.com/blog/post/2022/10/25/introducing-intellectual-property-reporting-api/"/><summary>We know that rights holders of copyrights and trademarks are always seeking new ways to efficiently combat intellectual property infringement. So today we’re announcing the Intellectual Property (IP) Reporting API, a solution that allows rights holders and their agents to build custom systems for reporting content that violates their intellectual property rights.</summary></entry><entry><id>tag:developers.facebook.com,2022-10-24:blog:p10226321165472133</id><title>Sending Messages with WhatsApp in Your Python Applications</title><updated>2022-10-21T19:06:27+00:00</updated><published>2022-10-24T16:00:00+00:00</published><link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://developers.facebook.com/blog/post/2022/10/24/sending-messages-with-whatsapp-in-your-python-applications/"/><summary>WhatsApp Business Platform enables businesses to communicate more closely with their audiences, offering tools that allow you to automate the sending, receiving, and handling of incoming messages. For example, automated messaging allows you to welcome new customers or notify them when they contact you outside business hours.</summary></entry><entry><id>tag:developers.facebook.com,2022-10-18:blog:p10222481573060668</id><title>What’s New With Data Portability and our Transfer Your Information Tool</title><updated>2022-10-17T19:38:05+00:00</updated><published>2022-10-18T16:00:00+00:00</published><link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://developers.facebook.com/blog/post/2022/10/18/data-portability-and-our-transfer-your-information-tool/"/><summary>Today we have an interview with William Morland, a software engineer who works on data portability at Meta. Below, he talks about the work he does on our Transfer Your Information tool, a key control that allows people to transfer their data from Meta-owned apps to other platforms.</summary></entry><entry><id>tag:developers.facebook.com,2022-10-13:blog:p10160235219918688</id><title>Meet the Developers: Linux Kernel Team (Song Liu)</title><updated>2022-10-11T01:33:00+00:00</updated><published>2022-10-13T16:00:00+00:00</published><link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://developers.facebook.com/blog/post/2022/10/13/meet-the-developers-linux-kernel-team-song-liu/"/><summary>For today’s interview, we have Song Liu, a software engineer on the Kernel team at Meta. Song Liu recently presented at the Linux Plumbers Conference (LPC) on Kernel Live Patching at Scale.</summary></entry><entry><id>tag:developers.facebook.com,2022-10-11:blog:p10226126680130121</id><title>Recap the Meta Avatars announcements from Meta Connect 2022</title><updated>2022-10-05T19:56:13+00:00</updated><published>2022-10-11T19:00:00+00:00</published><link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://developers.facebook.com/blog/post/2022/10/11/recap-the-meta-avatars-announcements-from-meta-connect-2022/"/><summary>Learn about all of the highlights, announcements, and feature roadmap for Meta Avatars from Meta Connect 2022.</summary></entry><entry><id>tag:developers.facebook.com,2022-10-10:blog:p10158596252001761</id><title>Introducing an important update to Instagram Sharing to Stories</title><updated>2022-10-10T19:05:13+00:00</updated><published>2022-10-10T21:00:00+00:00</published><link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://developers.facebook.com/blog/post/2022/10/10/introducing-important-update-to-Instagram-sharing-to-stories/"/><summary>Instagram is now requiring that all developers have access to a registered Facebook App with Basic settings configured in order to continue using Share to Stories.</summary></entry></feed>
