<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<rdf:RDF
 xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
 xmlns="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/"
 xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
 xmlns:taxo="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/taxonomy/"
 xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
 xmlns:syn="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
 xmlns:admin="http://webns.net/mvcb/"
>

<channel rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/">
<title>astro-ph.HE updates on arXiv.org</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">Astrophysics -- High Energy Astrophysical Phenomena (astro-ph.HE) updates on the arXiv.org e-print archive</description>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:date>2022-11-03T20:30:00-05:00</dc:date>
<dc:publisher>help@arxiv.org</dc:publisher>
<dc:subject>Astrophysics -- High Energy Astrophysical Phenomena</dc:subject>
<syn:updateBase>1901-01-01T00:00+00:00</syn:updateBase>
<syn:updateFrequency>1</syn:updateFrequency>
<syn:updatePeriod>daily</syn:updatePeriod>
<items>
 <rdf:Seq>
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01393" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01396" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01398" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01447" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01460" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01493" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01511" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01516" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01520" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01540" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01619" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01697" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01737" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01740" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01766" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01790" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01810" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01836" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01861" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01894" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01927" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.02007" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.02010" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.02028" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.02036" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/1811.04975" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2009.10813" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2202.02059" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2202.02060" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2202.04498" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2205.08174" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2206.11266" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2207.00102" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2208.03999" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2208.08423" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2208.09506" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.12875" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.15569" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.00940" />
 </rdf:Seq>
</items>
<image rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif" />
</channel>
<image rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif">
<title>arXiv.org</title>
<url>http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif</url>
<link>http://arxiv.org/</link>
</image>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01393">
<title>Exploring diffuse radio emission in galaxy clusters and groups with the uGMRT and the SKA. (arXiv:2211.01393v1 [astro-ph.CO])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01393</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Diffuse radio emission has been detected in a considerable number of galaxy
clusters and groups, revealing the presence of pervasive cosmic magnetic
fields, and of relativistic particles in the large-scale structure (LSS) of the
Universe. Since cluster radio emission is faint and steep spectrum, its
observations are largely limited by the instrument sensitivity and frequency of
observation, leading to a dearth of information, more so for lower-mass
systems. The unprecedented sensitivity of recently commissioned low-frequency
radio telescope arrays, aided by the development of advanced calibration and
imaging techniques, have helped in achieving unparalleled image quality. At the
same time, the development of sophisticated numerical simulations and the
availability of supercomputing facilities have paved the way for
high-resolution numerical modeling of radio emission, and the structure of the
cosmic magnetic fields in LSS, leading to predictions matching the capabilities
of observational facilities. In view of these rapidly-evolving scenerio in
modeling and observations, in this review, we summarise the role of the new
telescope arrays and the development of advanced imaging techniques and discuss
the detections of various kinds of cluster radio sources. In particular, we
discuss observations of the cosmic web in the form of supercluster filaments,
studies of emission in poor clusters and groups of galaxies, and of ultra-steep
spectrum sources. We also review the current theoretical understanding of
various diffuse cluster radio sources and the associated magnetic field and
polarization. As the statistics of detections improve along with our
theoretical understanding, we update the source classification schemes based on
their intrinsic properties. We conclude by summarising the role of the upgraded
GMRT and our expectations from the upcoming Square Kilometre Array (SKA)
observatories.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Paul_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Surajit Paul&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Kale_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ruta Kale&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Datta_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Abhirup Datta&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Basu_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Aritra Basu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Sur_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Sharanya Sur&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Parekh_V/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Viral Parekh&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Gupta_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Prateek Gupta&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Chatterjee_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Swarna Chatterjee&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Salunkhe_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Sameer Salunkhe&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Iqbal_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Asif Iqbal&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Pandey_Pommier_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Mamta Pandey-Pommier&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Raja_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ramij Raja&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Rahaman_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Majidul Rahaman&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Raychaudhury_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Somak Raychaudhury&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Nath_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Biman B. Nath&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Majumdar_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Subhabrata Majumdar&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01396">
<title>Prospects for a precise equation of state measurement from Advanced LIGO and Cosmic Explorer. (arXiv:2211.01396v1 [astro-ph.HE])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01396</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Gravitational-wave observations of neutron star mergers can probe the nuclear
equation of state by measuring the imprint of the neutron star&apos;s tidal
deformability on the signal. We investigate the ability of future
gravitational-wave observations to produce a precise measurement of the
equation of state from binary neutron star inspirals. Since measurability of
the tidal effect depends on the equation of state, we explore several equations
of state that span current observational constraints. We generate a population
of binary neutron stars as seen by a simulated Advanced LIGO-Virgo network, as
well as by a planned Cosmic Explorer observatory. We perform Bayesian inference
to measure the parameters of each signal, and we combine measurements across
each population to determine $R_{1.4}$, the radius of a $1.4M_{\odot}$ neutron
star. We find that with 321 signals the LIGO-Virgo network is able to measure
$R_{1.4}$ to better than 2% precision for all equations of state we consider,
however we find that achieving this precision could take decades of
observation, depending on the equation of state and the merger rate. On the
other hand we find that with one year of observation, Cosmic Explorer will
measure $R_{1.4}$ to better than 0.6% precision. In both cases we find that
systematic biases, such as from an incorrect mass prior, can significantly
impact measurement accuracy and efforts will be required to mitigate these
effects.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Finstad_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Daniel Finstad&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+White_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Laurel V. White&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Brown_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Duncan A. Brown&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01398">
<title>Connecting small-scale to large-scale structures of fast neutrino-flavor conversion. (arXiv:2211.01398v1 [astro-ph.HE])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01398</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We present a systematic study of fast neutrino-flavor conversion (FFC) with
both small-scale and large-scale numerical simulations in spherical symmetry.
We find that FFCs can, in general, reach in a quasi-steady state, and these
features in the non-linear phase are not characterized by the growth rate of
FFC instability but rather angular structures of electron neutrino lepton
number (ELN) and heavy one (XLN). Our result suggests that neutrinos can almost
reach a flavor equipartition even in cases with low growth rate of instability
(e.g., shallow ELN crossing) and narrow angular regions (in momentum space)
where flavor conversions occur vigorously. This exhibits that ELN and XLN
angular distributions can not provide a sufficient information to determine
total amount of flavor conversion in neutrinos and antineutrinos of all
flavors. Based on the results of our numerical simulations, we provide a new
approximate scheme of FFC that is designed so that one can easily incorporate
effects of FFCs in existing classical neutrino transport codes for the study of
core-collapse supernova (CCSN) and binary neutron star merger (BNSM). The
scheme has an ability to capture key features of quasi-steady state of FFCs
without solving quantum kinetic neutrino transport, which will serve to
facilitate access to FFCs for CCSN and BNSM theorists.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Nagakura_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Hiroki Nagakura&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Zaizen_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Masamichi Zaizen&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01447">
<title>Quantifying the evidence against a mass gap between black holes and neutron stars. (arXiv:2211.01447v1 [astro-ph.HE])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01447</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The lack of objects between $2\,M_{\odot}$ and $5\,M_{\odot}$ in the joint
mass distribution of compact objects has been termed &quot;mass gap&quot;, and attributed
mainly to the characteristics of the supernova mechanism precluding their
birth. However, recent observations show that a number of candidates reported
to lie inside the &quot;gap&quot; may fill it, suggesting instead a paucity that may be
real or largely a result of small number statistics. We quantify in this work
the individual candidates and evaluate the joint probability of a mass gap. Our
results show that an absolute mass gap is not present, to a very high
confidence level. It remains to be seen if a relative paucity of objects stands
in the future, and how this population can be related to the formation
processes, which may include neutron star mergers, collapse of a neutron star
to a black hole and others.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Sa_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;L. M. de S&amp;#xe1;&lt;/a&gt; (1), &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Bernardo_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;A. Bernardo&lt;/a&gt; (1), &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Bachega_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;R. R. A. Bachega&lt;/a&gt; (1), &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Horvath_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;J. E. Horvath&lt;/a&gt; (1), &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Rocha_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;L. S. Rocha&lt;/a&gt; (1 and 2), &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Moraes_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;P. H. R. S. Moraes&lt;/a&gt; (3) ((1) S&amp;#xe3;o Paulo, (2) Bonn, (3) Santo Andr&amp;#xe9;)</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01460">
<title>Possible optical counterparts of ULXs in NGC 1672. (arXiv:2211.01460v1 [astro-ph.SR])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01460</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;In this study, we use archival data from HST, Chandra, XMM-Newton, and
Swift-XRT, to probe the nature of 9 (X1-X9) candidate ULXs in NGC 1672. Our
study focuses on using the precise source positions obtained via improved
astrometry based on {\it Chandra} and HST observations to search for and
identify optical counterparts for these ULXs.Unique optical counterparts are
identified for X2 an{d X6; two potential counterparts were determined for X1,
X5 and X7 within the respective error radii while no optical counterparts were
found for the remaining four sources. Based on spectral energy distributions
(SEDs), X-ray and optical temporal analyses, some evidences about the nature of
X1 and X2 were obtained.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Allak_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;S. Allak&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Akyuz_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;A. Akyuz&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Sonbas_E/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;E. Sonbas&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Dhuga_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;K. S. Dhuga&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01493">
<title>Magnetic fields and relativistic electrons fill entire galaxy cluster. (arXiv:2211.01493v1 [astro-ph.CO])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01493</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The hot plasma within merging galaxy clusters is predicted to be filled with
shocks and turbulence that may convert part of their kinetic energy into
relativistic electrons and magnetic fields generating synchrotron radiation.
Analyzing Low Frequency Array (LOFAR) observations of the galaxy cluster Abell
2255, we show evidence of radio synchrotron emission distributed over very
large scales of at least 5 megaparsec. The pervasive radio emission witnesses
that shocks and turbulence efficiently transfer kinetic energy into
relativistic particles and magnetic fields in a region that extends up to the
cluster outskirts. The strength of the emission requires a magnetic field
energy density at least 100 times higher than expected from a simple
compression of primordial fields, presumably implying that dynamo operates
efficiently also in the cluster periphery. It also suggests that nonthermal
components may contribute substantially to the pressure of the intracluster
medium in the cluster periphery.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Botteon_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;A. Botteon&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Weeren_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;R. J. van Weeren&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Brunetti_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;G. Brunetti&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Vazza_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;F. Vazza&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Shimwell_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;T. W. Shimwell&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Bruggen_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;M. Br&amp;#xfc;ggen&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Rottgering_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;H. J. A. R&amp;#xf6;ttgering&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Gasperin_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;F. de Gasperin&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Akamatsu_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;H. Akamatsu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Bonafede_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;A. Bonafede&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Cassano_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;R. Cassano&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Cuciti_V/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;V. Cuciti&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Dallacasa_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;D. Dallacasa&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Gennaro_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;G. Di Gennaro&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Gastaldello_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;F. Gastaldello&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01511">
<title>The Cosmic-Ray Induced Sputtering Process On Icy Grains. (arXiv:2211.01511v1 [astro-ph.EP])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01511</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;In molecular cloud cores, the cosmic ray (CR) induced sputtering via CR
ion-icy grain collision is one of the desorption processes for ice molecules
from mantles around dust grains. The efficiency of this process depends on the
incident CR ion properties as well as the physicochemical character of the ice
mantle. Our main objective is the examination of the sputtering efficiency for
H$_2$O and CO ices found in molecular cloud cores. In the calculation routine,
we consider a multi-dimensional parameter space that consists of thirty CR ion
types, five different CR ion energy flux distributions, two separate ice mantle
components (pure H$_2$O and CO), three ice formation states, and two sputtering
regimes (linear and quadratic). We find that the sputtering behavior of H$_2$O
and CO ices is dominated by the quadratic regime rather than the linear regime,
especially for CO sputtering. The sputtering rate coefficients for H$_2$O and
CO ices show distinct variations with respect to the adopted CR ion energy flux
as well as the grain size-dependent mantle depth. The maximum radius of the
cylindrical latent region is quite sensitive to the effective electronic
stopping power. The track radii for CO ice are much bigger than H$_2$O ice
values. In contrast to the H$_2$O mantle, even relatively light CR ions ($Z
\geq 4$) may lead to a track formation within the CO mantle, depending on ${\rm
S_{\rm e,eff}}$. We suggest that the latent track formation threshold can be
assumed as a separator between the linear and the quadratic regimes for
sputtering.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Ozgun_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Arslan &amp;#xd6;zg&amp;#xfc;n&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Seyit_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Hocuk Seyit&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Paola_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Caselli Paola&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Ibrahim_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;K&amp;#xfc;&amp;#xe7;&amp;#xfc;k &amp;#x130;brahim&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01516">
<title>Afterglow Polarization from Off-Axis GRB Jets. (arXiv:2211.01516v1 [astro-ph.HE])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01516</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;As we further our studies on Gamma-ray bursts (GRBs), both on theoretical
models and observational tools, more and more options begin to open for
exploration of its physical properties. As transient events primarily dominated
by synchrotron radiation, it is expected that the synchrotron photons emitted
by GRBs should present some degree of polarization throughout the evolution of
the burst. Whereas observing this polarization can still be challenging due to
the constraints on observational tools, especially for short GRBs, it is
paramount that the groundwork is laid for the day we have abundant data. In
this work, we present a polarization model linked with an off-axis spreading
top-hat jet synchrotron scenario in a stratified environment with a density
profile $n(r)\propto r^ {-k}$. We present this model&apos;s expected temporal
polarization evolution for a realistic set of afterglow parameters constrained
within the values observed in the GRB literature for four degrees of
stratification $k=0,1,1.5 {\rm \, and\,} 2$ and two magnetic field
configurations with high extreme anisotropy. We apply this model and predict
polarization from a set of GRBs exhibiting off-axis afterglow emission. In
particular, for GRB 170817A, we use the available polarimetric upper limits to
rule out the possibility of a extremely anisotropic configuration for the
magnetic field.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Pedreira_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;A. C. Caligula do E. S. Pedreira&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Fraija_N/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;N. Fraija&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Galvan_Gamez_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;A. Galvan-Gamez&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Kamenetskaia_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;B. Betancourt Kamenetskaia&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Veres_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;P. Veres&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Dainotti_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;M. G. Dainotti&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Dichiara_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;S. Dichiara&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Becerra_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;R. L. Becerra&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01520">
<title>Deep Residual Networks for Gravitational Wave Detection. (arXiv:2211.01520v1 [gr-qc])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01520</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Traditionally, gravitational waves are detected with techniques such as
matched filtering or unmodeled searches based on wavelets. However, in the case
of generic black hole binaries with non-aligned spins, if one wants to explore
the whole parameter space, matched filtering can become impractical, which sets
severe restrictions on the sensitivity and computational efficiency of
gravitational-wave searches. Here, we use a novel combination of
machine-learning algorithms and arrive at sensitive distances that surpass
traditional techniques in a specific setting. Moreover, the computational cost
is only a small fraction of the computational cost of matched filtering. The
main ingredients are a 54-layer deep residual network (ResNet), a Deep Adaptive
Input Normalization (DAIN), a dynamic dataset augmentation, and curriculum
learning, based on an empirical relation for the signal-to-noise ratio. We
compare the algorithm&apos;s sensitivity with two traditional algorithms on a
dataset consisting of a large number of injected waveforms of non-aligned
binary black hole mergers in real LIGO O3a noise samples. Our machine-learning
algorithm can be used in upcoming rapid online searches of gravitational-wave
events in a sizeable portion of the astrophysically interesting parameter
space. We make our code, AResGW, and detailed results publicly available at
https://github.com/vivinousi/gw-detection-deep-learning.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Nousi_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Paraskevi Nousi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Koloniari_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Alexandra E. Koloniari&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Passalis_N/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Nikolaos Passalis&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Iosif_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Panagiotis Iosif&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Stergioulas_N/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Nikolaos Stergioulas&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Tefas_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Anastasios Tefas&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01540">
<title>A note on the anti-glitch of magnetar SGR 1935+2154. (arXiv:2211.01540v1 [astro-ph.HE])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01540</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The magnetar SGR 1935+2154 is reported to have an anti-glitch, accompanied by
fast radio bursts, and transient pulsed radio emission. In the wind braking
model, this triplet event tell people that (1) SGR 1935+2154 does not have a
strong particle wind and can be approximated by magnetic dipole braking in the
persistent state; (2) Its anti-glitch is due to an enhanced particle wind,
similar to the first anti-glitch in magnetars; (3) Its transient pulsed radio
emission may due to enlarged and decreasing emission beam during the outburst.
The enhanced particle acceleration potential and pulsar death line may not be
the dominate factor.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Tong_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;H. Tong&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01619">
<title>The Steady-State Multi-TeV Diffuse Gamma-Ray Emission Predicted with GALPROP and Prospects for the Cherenkov Telescope Array. (arXiv:2211.01619v1 [astro-ph.HE])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01619</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Cosmic Rays (CRs) interact with the diffuse gas, radiation, and magnetic
fields in the interstellar medium (ISM) to produce electromagnetic emissions
that are a significant component of the all-sky flux across a broad wavelength
range. The Fermi Large Area Telescope (LAT) has measured these emissions at GeV
$\gamma$-ray energies with high statistics. Meanwhile, the High-Energy
Stereoscopic System (H.E.S.S.) telescope array has observed large-scale
Galactic diffuse emission in the TeV $\gamma$-ray energy range. The emissions
observed at GeV and TeV energies are connected by the common origin of the CR
particles injected by the sources, but the energy dependence of the mixture
from the general ISM (true `diffuse&apos;), those emanating from the relatively
nearby interstellar space about the sources, and the sources themselves, is not
well understood. In this paper, we investigate predictions of the broadband
emissions using the GALPROP code over a grid of steady-state 3D models that
include variations over CR sources, and other ISM target distributions. We
compare, in particular, the model predictions in the VHE ($\geq$100 GeV)
$\gamma$-ray range with the H.E.S.S. Galactic plane survey (HGPS) after
carefully subtracting emission from catalogued $\gamma$-ray sources. Accounting
for the unresolved source contribution, and the systematic uncertainty of the
HGPS, we find that the GALPROP model predictions agree with lower estimates for
the HGPS source-subtracted diffuse flux. We discuss the implications of the
modelling results for interpretation of data from the next generation Cherenkov
Telescope Array (CTA).
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Marinos_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;P. D. Marinos&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Rowell_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;G. P. Rowell&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Porter_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;T. A. Porter&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Johannesson_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;G. J&amp;#xf3;hannesson&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01697">
<title>Mapping the circumnuclear regions of the Circinus galaxy with the Imaging X-ray Polarimetry Explorer. (arXiv:2211.01697v1 [astro-ph.HE])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01697</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We report on the Imaging X-ray Polarimetry Explorer (IXPE) observation of the
closest and X-ray brightest Compton-thick active galactic nucleus (AGN), the
Circinus galaxy. We find the source to be significantly polarized in the 2--6
keV band. From previous studies, the X-ray spectrum is known to be dominated by
reflection components, both neutral (torus) and ionized (ionization cones). Our
analysis indicates that the polarization degree is $28 \pm 7$ per cent (at 68
per cent confidence level) for the neutral reflector, with a polarization angle
of $18{\deg} \pm 5{\deg}$, roughly perpendicular to the radio jet. The
polarization of the ionized reflection is unconstrained. A comparison with
Monte Carlo simulations of the polarization expected from the torus shows that
the neutral reflector is consistent with being an equatorial torus with a
half-opening angle of 45{\deg}-55{\deg}. This is the first X-ray polarization
detection in a Seyfert galaxy, demonstrating the power of X-ray polarimetry in
probing the geometry of the circumnuclear regions of AGNs, and confirming the
basic predictions of standard Unification Models.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Ursini_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;F. Ursini&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Marinucci_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;A. Marinucci&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Matt_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;G. Matt&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Bianchi_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;S. Bianchi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Marin_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;F. Marin&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Marshall_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;H. L. Marshall&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Middei_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;R. Middei&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Poutanen_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;J. Poutanen&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Rosa_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;A. De Rosa&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Gesu_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;L. Di Gesu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Garcia_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;J. A. Garc&amp;#xed;a&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Ingram_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;A. Ingram&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Kim_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;D. E. Kim&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Krawczynski_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;H. Krawczynski&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Puccetti_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;S. Puccetti&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Soffitta_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;P. Soffitta&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Svoboda_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;J. Svoboda&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Tombesi_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;F. Tombesi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Weisskopf_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;M. C. Weisskopf&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Barnouin_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;T. Barnouin&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Perri_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;M. Perri&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Podgorny_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;J. Podgorny&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Ratheesh_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;A. Ratheesh&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Zaino_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;A. Zaino&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Agudo_I/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;I. Agudo&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Antonelli_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;L. A. Antonelli&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Bachetti_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;M. Bachetti&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Baldini_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;L. Baldini&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Baumgartner_W/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;W. H. Baumgartner&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Bellazzini_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;R. Bellazzini&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Bongiorno_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;S. D. Bongiorno&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Bonino_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;R. Bonino&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Brez_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;A. Brez&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Bucciantini_N/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;N. Bucciantini&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Capitanio_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;F. Capitanio&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Castellano_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;S. Castellano&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Cavazzuti_E/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;E. Cavazzuti&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Ciprini_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;S. Ciprini&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Costa_E/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;E. Costa&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Monte_E/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;E. Del Monte&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Lalla_N/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;N. Di Lalla&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Marco_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;A. Di Marco&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Donnarumma_I/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;I. Donnarumma&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Doroshenko_V/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;V. Doroshenko&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Dovciak_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;M. Dov&amp;#x10d;iak&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Ehlert_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;S. R. Ehlert&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Enoto_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;T. Enoto&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Evangelista_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Y. Evangelista&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Fabiani_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;S. Fabiani&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Ferrazzoli_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;R. Ferrazzoli&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Gunji_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;S. Gunji&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Heyl_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;J. Heyl&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Iwakiri_W/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;W. Iwakiri&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Jorstad_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;S. G. Jorstad&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Karas_V/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;V. Karas&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Kitaguchi_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;T. Kitaguchi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Kolodziejczak_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;J. J. Kolodziejczak&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Monaca_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;F. La Monaca&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Latronico_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;L. Latronico&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Liodakis_I/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;I. Liodakis&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Maldera_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;S. Maldera&lt;/a&gt;, et al. (35 additional authors not shown)</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01737">
<title>Selected results from IceCube. (arXiv:2211.01737v1 [astro-ph.HE])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01737</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Neutrino astronomy saw its birth with the discovery by IceCube of a diffuse
flux at energies above 60 TeV with intensity comparable to a predicted upper
limit to the flux from extra-galactic sources of ultra-high energy cosmic rays
(UHECRs). While such an upper limit corresponds to the case of calorimetric
sources, in which cosmic rays lose all their energy into photo-pion production,
the first statistically significant coincident observation between neutrinos
and gamma rays was observed from a blazar of intriguing nature. A
very-high-energy muon event, of most probable neutrino energy of 290 TeV for an
$E^{-2.13}$ spectrum, alerted other observatories triggering a large number of
investigations in many bands of the electromagnetic (EM) spectrum. A high
gamma-ray state from the blazar was revealed soon after the event and in a
follow-up to about 40 days. A posteriori observations also in the optical and
radio bands indicated a rise of the flux from the TXS 0506+056 blazar. A
previous excess of events of the duration of more than 100~d was observed by
IceCube with higher significance than the alert itself. These observations
triggered more complex modeling than simple one-zone proton synchrotron models
for proton acceleration in jets of active galactic nuclei (AGNs) and more
observations across the EM spectrum. A second piece of evidence was a steady
excess of about 50 neutrino events with reconstructed soft spectrum in a sample
of lower energy well-reconstructed muon events than the alert event. A hot spot
was identified in a catalog of 110 gamma-ray intense emitters and starburst
galaxies in a direction compatible with NGC 1068 with a significance of
$2.9\sigma$. NGC 1068 hosts a mildly relativistic jet in a starburst galaxy,
seen not from the jet direction but rather through the torus. This Seyfert II
galaxy is at only 14.4~Mpc from the Earth. We discuss these observations.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Montaruli_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Teresa Montaruli&lt;/a&gt; (for the IceCube Collaboration)</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01740">
<title>Formation and Thermodynamic Evolution of plasmoids in active region jets. (arXiv:2211.01740v1 [astro-ph.SR])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01740</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We have carried out a comprehensive study of the temperature structure of
plasmoids, which successively occurred in recurrent active region jets. The
multithermal plasmoids were seen to be travelling along the multi-threaded
spire as well as at the footpoint region in the EUV/UV images recorded by the
Atmospheric Imaging Assembly (AIA). The Differential Emission Measure (DEM)
analysis was performed using EUV AIA images, and the high-temperature part of
the DEM was constrained by combining X-ray images from the X-ray telescope
(XRT/Hinode). We observed a systematic rise and fall in brightness, electron
number densities and the peak temperatures of the spire plasmoid during its
propagation along the jet. The plasmoids at the footpoint (FPs) (1.0-2.5 MK)
and plasmoids at the spire (SPs) (1.0-2.24 MK) were found to have similar peak
temperatures, whereas the FPs have higher DEM weighted temperatures (2.2-5.7
MK) than the SPs (1.3-3.0 MK). A lower limit to the electron number densities
of plasmoids - SPs (FPs) were obtained that ranged between
3.4-6.1$\times$10$^{8}$ (3.3-5.9$\times$10$^{8}$) cm$^{-3}$ whereas for the
spire, it ranged from 2.6-3.2$\times$10$^{8}$ cm$^{-3}$. Our analysis shows
that the emission of these plasmoids starts close to the base of the jet(s),
where we believe that a strong current interface is formed. This suggests that
the blobs are plasmoids induced by a tearing-mode instability.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Mulay_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Sargam M. Mulay&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Tripathi_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Durgesh Tripathi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Mason_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Helen Mason&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Zanna_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Giulio Del Zanna&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Archontis_V/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Vasilis Archontis&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01766">
<title>Scalarization. (arXiv:2211.01766v1 [gr-qc])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01766</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Scalarization is a mechanism that endows strongly self-gravitating bodies,
such as neutron stars and black holes, with a scalar field configuration. It
resembles a phase transition in that the scalar configuration only appears when
a certain quantity that characterizes the compact object, e.g., its compactness
or spin, is beyond a threshold. We provide a critical and comprehensive review
of scalarization, including the mechanism itself, theories that exhibit it, its
manifestation in neutron stars, black holes, and their binaries, potential
extension to other fields, and a thorough discussion of future perspectives.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Doneva_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Daniela D. Doneva&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Ramazanoglu_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Fethi M. Ramazano&amp;#x11f;lu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Silva_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Hector O. Silva&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Sotiriou_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Thomas P. Sotiriou&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Yazadjiev_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Stoytcho S. Yazadjiev&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01790">
<title>The observed polarization direction depending on geometrical and kinematic parameters of relativistic jets. (arXiv:2211.01790v1 [astro-ph.HE])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01790</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The study of the polarization direction is crucial in the issue of restoring
the spatial structure of the magnetic field in the active galaxy parsec-scale
jets. But, due to relativistic effects, the magnetic field projected onto the
celestial sphere in the source reference frame cannot be assumed to be
orthogonal to the observed direction of the electric vector in the wave.
Moreover, the local axis of the jet component may not coincide with its motion
direction, which affects the observed polarization direction. In this article,
we analyze the transverse to jet distributions of the electric vector in the
wave, obtained as a result of modeling with different jet kinematic and
geometrical parameters for a helical magnetic field with a different twist
angle and for a toroidal magnetic field in the center, surrounded by a varying
thickness sheath, penetrated by a poloidal field. We obtained: 1) the shape of
the electric vector transverse distribution depends in a complex way on the
angles of the jet axis and the velocity vector with the line of sight; 2)
ambiguity in determining the twist direction of the helical magnetic field
under using only the distributions of the electric vector in the wave; 3) both
considered magnetic field topologies can reproduce both the ``spine-sheath&apos;&apos;
polarization structure and individual bright details with the longitudinal to
the jet axis polarization direction.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Butuzova_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Marina S. Butuzova&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01810">
<title>Observational Signatures of Frame Dragging in Strong Gravity. (arXiv:2211.01810v1 [gr-qc])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01810</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Objects orbiting in the presence of a rotating massive body experience a
gravitomagnetic frame-dragging effect, known as the Lense-Thirring effect, that
has been experimentally confirmed in the weak-field limit. In the strong-field
limit, near the horizon of a rotating black hole, frame dragging becomes so
extreme that all objects must co-rotate with the black hole&apos;s angular momentum.
In this work, we perform general relativistic numerical simulations to identify
observable signatures of frame dragging in the strong-field limit that appear
when infalling gas is forced to flip its direction of rotation as it is being
accreted. In total intensity images, infalling streams exhibit &quot;S&quot;-shaped
features due to the switch in the tangential velocity. In linear polarization,
a flip in the handedness of spatially resolved polarization ticks as a function
of radius encodes a transition in the magnetic field geometry that occurs due
to magnetic flux freezing in the dragged plasma. Using a network of telescopes
around the world, the Event Horizon Telescope collaboration has demonstrated
that it is now possible to directly image black holes on event horizon scales.
We show that the phenomena described in this work would be accessible to the
next-generation Event Horizon Telescope (ngEHT) and extensions of the array
into space, which would produce spatially resolved images on event horizon
scales with higher spatial resolution and dynamic range.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Ricarte_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Angelo Ricarte&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Palumbo_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Daniel C. M. Palumbo&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Narayan_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ramesh Narayan&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Roelofs_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Freek Roelofs&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Emami_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Razieh Emami&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01836">
<title>Expected Signature For the Lorentz Invariance Violation Effects on $\gamma-\gamma$ Absorption. (arXiv:2211.01836v1 [astro-ph.HE])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01836</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;There are still some important unanswered questions about the unexpected very
high energy $\gamma$-ray signatures. To help understand the mechanism, focusing
on the linear and quadratic perturbation mode for subliminal case, the present
paper revisited the expected signature for the Lorentz invariance violation
effects on $\gamma-\gamma$ absorption in TeV spectra of Gamma-ray bursts
(GRBs). We note that the existence of minimum photon energy threshold for the
pair production process leads up to a break energy, which is sensitive to the
quantum gravity energy scale. We suggest that energy spectral break in the few
tens of TeV is a rough observational diagnostic for the LIV effects. The
expected spectra characteristics are applied to a GRB 221009A. The results show
that the cosmic opacity with Lorentz invariance violation effects considered
here is able to roughly reproduce the observed $\gamma$-ray spectra for the
source, which enabled us to constrain the lower limit of the linear values of
energy scale at $E_{\rm QG,1}=3.35\times10^{20}$ GeV for the linear
perturbation and $E_{\rm QG,2}=9.19\times10^{13}$ GeV for the quadratic
perturbation. This value corresponds to a break energy $E_{\rm \gamma,
break,1}\simeq 55.95~\rm TeV$ for the linear and $E_{\rm \gamma, break,2}\simeq
73.66~\rm TeV$ for the quadratic in the observed frame respectively.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Zheng_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Y.G. Zheng&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Kang_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;S.J. Kang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Zhu_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;K.R. Zhu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Yang_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;C.Y. Yang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Bai_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;J.M. Bai&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01861">
<title>Influences of mass transfer stability criterion on double white dwarf populations. (arXiv:2211.01861v1 [astro-ph.SR])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01861</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Mass transfer stability is an essential issue in binary evolution. Ge et al.
studied critical mass ratios for dynamically stable mass transfer by
establishing adiabatic mass loss model and found that the donor stars on the
giant branches tend to be more stable than that based on the composite
polytropic stellar model. We would investigate the influence of mass transfer
stability on the formation and properties of DWD populations. We performed a
series of binary population synthesis, where the critical mass ratios from
adiabatic mass loss model (Ge&apos;s model) and that from the composite polytropic
model are adopted, respectively. For Ge&apos;s model, most of the DWDs are produced
from the stable non-conservative Roche lobe overflow plus common envelope (CE)
ejection channel (RL+CE channel) regardless of the CE ejection efficiency
$\alpha_{CE}$. While the results of the polytropic model strongly depend on the
adopted value of $\alpha_{ CE}$. We find DWDs produced from the RL+CE channel
have comparable WD masses and the mass ratio distribution peaks at around 1.
Based on the magnitude-limited sample of DWDs, the space densities for the
detectable DWDs and those with extremely low-mass WD (ELM WD) companions in
Ge&apos;s model is $1347$ and $473 kpc^{-3}$, respectively, close to observations.
While the polytropic model overpredicts space density of DWDs by a factor of
about $2-3$. We also find that the results of DWD merger rate distribution in
Ge&apos;s model reproduce the observations better than that of the polytropic model,
and the merger rate of DWDs with ELM WD companions in the Galaxy is about
$1.8\times 10^{-3} yr^{-1}$ in Ge&apos;s model, which is comparable to the
observation estimation. We confirm that the mass transfer stability plays
important roles in the formation and properties of DWD populations, and then in
the progenitors of SNe Ia and detectable GW sources.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+LI_Z/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Zhenwei LI&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Chen_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xuefei Chen&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Ge_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Hongwei Ge&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Chen_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Hai-Liang Chen&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Han_Z/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Zhanwen Han&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01894">
<title>Evidence of Periodic Variability in Gamma-ray Emitting Blazars with Fermi-LAT. (arXiv:2211.01894v1 [astro-ph.HE])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01894</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;It is well known that blazars can show variability on a wide range of time
scales. This behavior can include periodicity in their $\gamma$-ray emission,
whose clear detection remains an ongoing challenge, partly due to the inherent
stochasticity of the processes involved and also the lack of adequately-well
sampled light curves. We report on a systematic search for periodicity in a
sample of 24 blazars, using twelve well-established methods applied to
Fermi-LAT data. The sample comprises the most promising candidates selected
from a previous study, extending the light curves from nine to twelve years and
broadening the energy range analyzed from $&amp;gt;$1 GeV to $&amp;gt;$0.1 GeV. These
improvements allow us to build a sample of blazars that display a period
detected with global significance $\gtrsim3\,\sigma$. Specifically, these
sources are PKS 0454$-$234, S5 0716+714, OJ 014, PG 1553+113, and PKS
2155$-$304. Periodic $\gamma$-ray emission may be an indication of modulation
of the jet power, particle composition, or geometry but most likely originates
in the accretion disk, possibly indicating the presence of a supermassive black
hole binary system.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Penil_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;P. Pe&amp;#xf1;il&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Ajello_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;M. Ajello&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Buson_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;S. Buson&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Dominguez_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;A. Dom&amp;#xed;nguez&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Westernacher_Schneider_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;J.R. Westernacher-Schneider&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Zrake_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;J. Zrake&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01927">
<title>Modeling Solids in Nuclear Astrophysics with Smoothed Particle Hydrodynamics. (arXiv:2211.01927v1 [astro-ph.IM])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01927</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Smoothed Particle Hydrodynamics (SPH) is a frequently applied tool in
computational astrophysics to solve the fluid dynamics equations governing the
systems under study. For some problems, for example when involving asteroids
and asteroid impacts, the additional inclusion of material strength is
necessary in order to accurately describe the dynamics. In compact stars, that
is white dwarfs and neutron stars, solid components are also present. Neutron
stars have a solid crust which is the strongest material known in nature.
However, their dynamical evolution, when modeled via SPH or other computational
fluid dynamics codes, is usually described as a purely fluid dynamics problem.
Here, we present the first 3D simulations of neutron-star crustal toroidal
oscillations including material strength with the Los Alamos National
Laboratory SPH code FleCSPH. In the first half of the paper, we present the
numerical implementation of solid material modeling together with standard
tests. The second half is on the simulation of crustal oscillations in the
fundamental toroidal mode. Here, we dedicate a large fraction of the paper to
approaches which can suppress numerical noise in the solid. If not minimized,
the latter can dominate the crustal motion in the simulations.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Sagert_I/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Irina Sagert&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Korobkin_O/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Oleg Korobkin&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Tews_I/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ingo Tews&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Tsao_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Bing-Jyun Tsao&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Lim_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Hyun Lim&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Falato_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Michael J. Falato&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Loiseau_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Julien Loiseau&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.02007">
<title>A Bayesian inference of relativistic mean-field model for neutron star matter from observation of NICER and GW170817/AT2017gfo. (arXiv:2211.02007v1 [astro-ph.HE])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.02007</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The observations of optical and near-infrared counterparts of binary neutron
star mergers not only enrich our knowledge about the abundance of heavy
elements in the Universe, or help reveal the remnant object just after the
merger as generally known, but also can effectively constrain dense nuclear
matter properties and the equation of state (EOS) in the interior of the
merging stars. Following the relativistic mean-field description of nuclear
matter, we perform the Bayesian inference of the EOS and the nuclear matter
properties using the first multi-messenger event GW170817/AT2017gfo, together
with the NICER mass-radius measurements of pulsars. The kilonova is described
by a radiation-transfer model with the dynamical ejecta, and light curves
connect with the EOS through the quasi-universal relations between the ejecta
properties (the ejected mass, velocity, opacity or electron fraction) and
binary parameters (the mass ratio and reduced tidal deformability). It is found
that the posterior distributions of the reduced tidal deformability from the
AT2017gfo analysis display a bimodal structure, with the first peak enhanced by
the GW170817 data, leading to slightly softened posterior EOSs, while the
second peak cannot be achieved by a nuclear EOS with saturation properties in
their empirical ranges. The inclusion of NICER data in our analyses results in
stiffened EOS posterior because of the massive pulsar PSR J0740+6620. We give
results at nuclear saturation density for the nuclear incompressibility, the
symmetry energy and its slope, as well as the nucleon effective mass, from our
analysis of those observational data.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Zhu_Z/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Zhenyu Zhu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Li_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ang Li&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+liu_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Tong liu&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.02010">
<title>On ALP scenarios and GRB 221009A. (arXiv:2211.02010v1 [astro-ph.HE])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.02010</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The extraordinarily bright gamma-ray burst GRB 221009A was observed by a
large number of observatories, from radio frequencies to gamma-rays. Of
particular interest are the reported observations of photon-like air showers of
very high energy: an 18 TeV event in LHAASO and a 251 TeV event at Carpet-2.
Gamma rays at these energies are expected to be absorbed by pair-production
events on background photons when travelling intergalactic distances. Several
works have sought to explain the observations of these events, assuming they
originate from GRB 221009A, by invoking axion-like particles (ALPs). We
reconsider this scenario and account for astrophysical uncertainties due to
poorly known magnetic fields and background photon densities. We find that,
robustly, the ALP scenario cannot simultaneously account for an 18 TeV and a
251 TeV photon from GRB 221009A.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Carenza_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Pierluca Carenza&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Marsh_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;M.C. David Marsh&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.02028">
<title>Neutrino Origin of LHAASO&apos;s 18 TeV GRB221009A Photon. (arXiv:2211.02028v1 [hep-ph])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.02028</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;LHAASO collaboration detected photons with energy above 10 TeV from the most
recent gamma-ray burst (GRB), GRB221009A. Given the redshift of this event,
$z\sim 0.15$, photons of such energy are expected to interact with the diffuse
extragalactic background light (EBL) well before reaching Earth. In this paper
we provide the first neutrino-related explanation of the most energetic 18 TeV
event reported by LHAASO. We find that the minimal viable scenario involves
both mixing and transition magnetic moment portal between light and sterile
neutrinos. The production of sterile neutrinos occurs efficiently via mixing
while the transition magnetic moment portal governs the decay rate in the
parameter space where tree-level decays via mixing to non-photon final states
are suppressed. Our explanation of this event, while being consistent with the
terrestrial constraints, points to the non-standard cosmology.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Brdar_V/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Vedran Brdar&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Li_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ying-Ying Li&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.02036">
<title>White dwarf binaries suggest a common envelope efficiency $\alpha \sim 1/3$. (arXiv:2211.02036v1 [astro-ph.SR])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.02036</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Common envelope (CE) evolution, which is crucial in creating short period
binaries and associated astrophysical events, can be constrained by reverse
modeling of such binaries&apos; formation histories. Through analysis of a sample of
well-constrained white dwarf (WD) binaries with low-mass primaries (7 eclipsing
double WDs, 2 non-eclipsing double WDs, 1 WD-brown dwarf), we estimate the CE
energy efficiency $\alpha_{\rm{CE}}$ needed to unbind the hydrogen envelope. We
use grids of He- and CO-core WD models to determine the masses and cooling ages
that match each primary WD&apos;s radius and temperature. Assuming gravitational
wave-driven orbital decay, we then calculate the associated ranges in post-CE
orbital period. By mapping WD models to a grid of red giant progenitor stars,
we determine the total envelope binding energies and possible orbital periods
at the point CE evolution is initiated, thereby constraining $\alpha_{\rm CE}$.
Assuming He-core WDs with progenitors of 0.9 - 2.0 $M_\odot$, we find
$\alpha_{\rm CE} \! \sim \! 0.2-0.4$ is consistent with each system we model.
Significantly higher values of $\alpha_{\rm{CE}}$ are required for higher mass
progenitors and for CO-core WDs, so these scenarios are deemed unlikely. Our
values are mostly consistent with previous studies of post-CE WD binaries, and
they suggest a nearly constant and low envelope ejection efficiency for CE
events that produce He-core WDs.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Scherbak_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Peter Scherbak&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Fuller_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jim Fuller&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/1811.04975">
<title>Effective sound speed in relativistic accretion discs around rotating black holes. (arXiv:1811.04975v3 [astro-ph.HE] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/1811.04975</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;For axially symmetric accretion maintained in the hydrostatic equilibrium
along the vertical direction in the Kerr metric, the radial Mach number does
not become unity at the critical point. The sonic points are, thus, formed at a
radial distance different from that where the critical points are formed. We
propose that a modified dynamical sound speed can be defined through the linear
perturbation of the full space-time dependent equations describing the
aforementioned accretion flow structure. The linear stability analysis of such
fluid equations leads to the formation of an wave equation which describes the
propagation of linear acoustic perturbation. The speed of propagation of such
perturbation can be used as the effective sound speed which makes the value of
the Mach number to be unity when evaluated at the critical points. This allows
the critical points to coalesce with the sonic points. We study how the spin
angular momentum of the black hole (the Kerr parameter) influences the value of
the effective sound speed.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Maity_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Susovan Maity&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Shaikh_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Md Arif Shaikh&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Das_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Tapas Kumar Das&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2009.10813">
<title>Launching the VASCO citizen science project. (arXiv:2009.10813v2 [astro-ph.IM] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2009.10813</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The Vanishing \&amp;amp; Appearing Sources during a Century of Observations (VASCO)
project investigates astronomical surveys spanning a time interval of 70 years,
searching for unusual and exotic transients. We present herein the VASCO
Citizen Science Project, which can identify unusual candidates driven by three
different approaches: hypothesis, exploratory, and machine learning, which is
particularly useful for SETI searches. To address the big data challenge, VASCO
combines three methods: the Virtual Observatory, user-aided machine learning,
and visual inspection through citizen science. Here we demonstrate the citizen
science project and its improved candidate selection process, and we give a
progress report. We also present the VASCO citizen science network led by
amateur astronomy associations mainly located in Algeria, Cameroon, and
Nigeria. At the moment of writing, the citizen science project has carefully
examined 15,593 candidate image pairs in the data (ca. 10\% of the candidates),
and has so far identified 798 objects classified as ``vanished&apos;&apos;. The most
interesting candidates will be followed up with optical and infrared imaging,
together with the observations by the most potent radio telescopes.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Villarroel_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Beatriz Villarroel&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Pelckmans_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Kristiaan Pelckmans&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Solano_E/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Enrique Solano&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Laaksoharju_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Mikael Laaksoharju&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Souza_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Abel Souza&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Dom_O/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Onyeuwaoma Nnaemeka Dom&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Laggoune_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Khaoula Laggoune&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Mimouni_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jamal Mimouni&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Mattsson_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Lars Mattsson&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Soodla_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Johan Soodla&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Castillo_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Diego Castillo&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Shultz_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Matthew E. Shultz&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Aworka_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Rubby Aworka&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Comeron_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;S&amp;#xe9;bastien Comer&amp;#xf3;n&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Geier_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Stefan Geier&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Marcy_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Geoffrey Marcy&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Gupta_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Alok C. Gupta&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Bergstedt_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Josefine Bergstedt&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Bar_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Rudolf E. B&amp;#xe4;r&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Buelens_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Bart Buelens&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Enriquez_E/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Emilio Enriquez&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Mellon_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Christopher K. Mellon&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Prieto_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;M. Almudena Prieto&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Wamalwa_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Dismas Simiyu Wamalwa&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Ward_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Martin J. Ward&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2202.02059">
<title>The Hydrogen-Poor Superluminous Supernovae from the Zwicky Transient Facility Phase-I Survey: I. Light Curves and Measurements. (arXiv:2202.02059v2 [astro-ph.HE] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2202.02059</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;During the Zwicky Transient Facility (ZTF) Phase-I operation, 78
hydrogen-poor superluminous supernovae (SLSNe-I) were discovered in less than
three years, making up the largest sample from a single survey. This paper
(Paper I) presents the data, including the optical/ultraviolet light curves and
classification spectra, while Paper II in this series will focus on the
detailed analysis of the light curves and modeling. Our photometry is primarily
taken by the ZTF in the $g,r,i$ bands, and with additional data from other
ground-based facilities and Swift. The events of our sample cover a redshift
range of $z = 0.06 - 0.67$, with a median and $1\sigma$ error (16\% and 84\%
percentiles) $z_{\rm med} = 0.265^{+0.143}_{-0.135}$. The peak luminosity
covers $-22.8\,{\rm mag} \leq M_{g,\rm peak} \leq -19.8$\,mag, with a median
value of $-21.48^{+1.13}_{-0.61}$\,mag. Their light curves evolve slowly with
the mean rest-frame rise time of $t_{\rm rise} = 41.9\pm17.8$\,days. The
luminosity and time scale distributions suggest that low luminosity SLSNe-I
with peak luminosity $\sim -20$\,mag or extremely fast rising events
($&amp;lt;10$\,days) exist but are rare. We confirm previous findings that slowly
rising SLSNe-I also tend to fade slowly. The rest-frame color and temperature
evolution show large scatters, suggesting that the SLSN-I population may have
diverse spectral energy distributions. The peak rest-frame color shows a
moderate correlation with the peak absolute magnitude, i.e. brighter SLSNe-I
tend to have bluer colors. With optical and ultraviolet photometry, we
construct bolometric luminosity and derive a bolometric correction relation
generally applicable for converting $g,r$-band photometry to bolometric
luminosity for SLSNe-I.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Chen_Z/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Z. H. Chen&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Yan_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Lin Yan&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Kangas_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;T. Kangas&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Lunnan_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;R. Lunnan&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Schulze_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;S. Schulze&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Sollerman_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;J. Sollerman&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Perley_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;D. A. Perley&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Chen_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;T.-W. Chen&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Taggart_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;K. Taggart&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Hinds_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;K. R. Hinds&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Gal_Yam_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;A. Gal-Yam&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Wang_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;X. F. Wang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Andreoni_I/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;I. Andreoni&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Bellm_E/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;E. Bellm&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Bloom_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;J. S. Bloom&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Burdge_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;K. Burdge&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Burgos_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;A. Burgos&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Cook_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;D. Cook&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Dahiwale_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;A. Dahiwale&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+De_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;K. De&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Dekany_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;R. Dekany&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Dugas_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;A. Dugas&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Frederik_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;S. Frederik&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Fremling_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;C. Fremling&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Graham_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;M. Graham&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Hankins_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;M. Hankins&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Ho_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;A. Ho&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Jencson_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;J. Jencson&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Karambelkar_V/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;V. Karambelkar&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Kasliwal_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;M. Kasliwal&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Kulkarni_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;S. Kulkarni&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Laher_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;R. Laher&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Rusholme_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;B. Rusholme&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Sharma_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Y. Sharma&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Taddia_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;F. Taddia&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Tartaglia_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;L. Tartaglia&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Thomas_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;B. P. Thomas&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Tzanidakis_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;A. Tzanidakis&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Roestel_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;J. Van Roestel&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Walter_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;R. Walter&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Yang_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Y. Yang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Yao_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Y. H. Yao&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Yaron_O/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;O. Yaron&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2202.02060">
<title>The Hydrogen-Poor Superluminous Supernovae from the Zwicky Transient Facility Phase-I Survey: II. Light Curve Modeling and Characterization of Undulations. (arXiv:2202.02060v2 [astro-ph.HE] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2202.02060</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We present analysis of the light curves (LCs) of 77 hydrogen-poor
superluminous supernovae (SLSNe-I) discovered during the Zwicky Transient
Facility Phase-I operation. We find that the majority (67\%) of the sample can
be fit equally well by both magnetar and ejecta-circumstellar medium (CSM)
interaction plus $^{56}$Ni decay models. This implies that LCs alone can not
unambiguously constrain the physical power sources for a SLSN-I. However, 23\%
of the sample show inverted V-shape, steep declining LCs or features of long
rise and fast post-peak decay, which are better described by the CSM+Ni model.
The remaining 10\% of the sample favor the magnetar model. Moreover, our
analysis shows that the LC undulations are quite common, with a fraction of
$18-44\% $ in our gold sample. Among those strongly undulating events, about
62\% of them are found to be CSM-favored, implying that the undulations tend to
occur in the CSM-favored events. Undulations show a wide range in energy and
duration, with median values (and 1$\sigma$ errors) being as
$1.7\%^{+1.5\%}_{-0.7\%}\,\rm E_{\rm rad,total}$ and
$28.8^{+14.4}_{-9.1}$\,days, respectively. Our analysis of the undulation time
scales suggests that intrinsic temporal variations of the central engine can
explain half of the undulating events, while CSM interaction can account for
the majority of the sample. Finally, all of the well-observed He-rich SLSNe-Ib
have either strongly undulating LCs or the LCs are much better fit by the
CSM+Ni model. These observations imply that their progenitor stars have not had
enough time to lose all of the He-envelopes before supernova explosions, and
H-poor CSM are likely to present in these events.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Chen_Z/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Z. H. Chen&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Yan_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Lin Yan&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Kangas_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;T. Kangas&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Lunnan_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;R. Lunnan&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Sollerman_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;J. Sollerman&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Schulze_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;S. Schulze&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Perley_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;D. A. Perley&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Chen_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;T.-W. Chen&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Taggart_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;K. Taggart&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Hinds_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;K. R. Hinds&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Gal_Yam_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;A. Gal-Yam&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Wang_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;X. F. Wang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+De_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;K. De&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Bellm_E/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;E. Bellm&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Bloom_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;J. S. Bloom&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Dekany_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;R. Dekany&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Graham_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;M. Graham&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Kasliwal_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;M. Kasliwal&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Kulkarni_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;S. Kulkarni&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Laher_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;R. Laher&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Neill_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;D. Neill&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Rusholme_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;B. Rusholme&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2202.04498">
<title>Analytic thin wall false vacuum decay rate. (arXiv:2202.04498v4 [hep-th] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2202.04498</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We derive a closed-form false vacuum decay rate at one loop in the thin wall
limit, where the true and false vacua are nearly degenerate. We obtain the
bounce configuration in $D$ dimensions, together with the Euclidean action with
a higher order correction, counter-terms and renormalization group running. We
extract the functional determinant via the Gel&apos;fand-Yaglom theorem for low and
generic orbital multipoles. The negative and zero eigenvalues appear for low
multipoles and the translational zeroes are removed. We compute the
fluctuations for generic multipoles, multiply and regulate the orbital modes.
We find an explicit finite renormalized decay rate in $D = 3, 4$ and give a
closed-form expression for the finite functional determinant in any dimension.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Ivanov_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Aleksandar Ivanov&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Matteini_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Marco Matteini&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Nemevsek_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Miha Nemev&amp;#x161;ek&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Ubaldi_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Lorenzo Ubaldi&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2205.08174">
<title>Turbulent diffusion of streaming cosmic rays in compressible, partially ionised plasma. (arXiv:2205.08174v2 [astro-ph.GA] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2205.08174</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Cosmic rays (CRs) are a dynamically important component of the interstellar
medium (ISM) of galaxies. The $\sim$GeV CRs that carry most CR energy and
pressure are likely confined by self-generated turbulence, leading them to
stream along magnetic field lines at the ion Alfv\&apos;en speed. However, the
consequences of self-confinement for CR propagation on galaxy scales remain
highly uncertain. In this paper, we use a large ensemble of
magnetohydrodynamical turbulence simulations to quantify how the basic
parameters describing ISM turbulence -- the sonic Mach number, $\mathcal{M}$
(plasma compressibility), Alfv\&apos;en Mach number, $\mathcal{M}_{A0}$ (strength of
the large-scale field with respect to the turbulence), and ionisation fraction
by mass, $\chi$ -- affect the transport of streaming CRs. We show that the
large-scale transport of CRs whose small-scale motion consists of streaming
along field lines is well described as a combination of streaming along the
mean field and superdiffusion both along (parallel to) and across
(perpendicular to) it; $\mathcal{M}_{A0}$ drives the level of anisotropy
between parallel and perpendicular diffusion and $\chi$ modulates the magnitude
of the diffusion coefficients, while in our choice of units, $\mathcal{M}$ is
unimportant except in the sub-Alfv\&apos;enic ($\mathcal{M}_{A0} \lesssim 0.5$)
regime. Our finding that superdiffusion is ubiquitous potentially explains the
apparent discrepancy between CR diffusion coefficients inferred from
measurements close to individual sources compared to those measured on larger,
Galactic scales. Finally, we present empirical fits for the diffusion
coefficients as a function of plasma parameters that may be used as sub-grid
recipes for global interstellar medium, galaxy or cosmological simulations.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Sampson_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Matt L. Sampson&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Beattie_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;James R. Beattie&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Krumholz_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Mark R. Krumholz&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Crocker_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Roland M. Crocker&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Federrath_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Christoph Federrath&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Seta_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Amit Seta&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2206.11266">
<title>Equation of state for hot hyperonic neutron star matter. (arXiv:2206.11266v3 [astro-ph.HE] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2206.11266</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The FSU2H equation-of-state model, originally developed to describe cold
neutron star matter with hyperonic cores, is extended to finite temperature.
Results are presented for a wide range of temperatures and lepton fractions,
which cover the conditions met in protoneutron star matter, neutron star
mergers and supernova explosions. It is found that the temperature effects on
the thermodynamical observables and the composition of the neutron star core
are stronger when the hyperonic degrees of freedom are considered. An
evaluation of the temperature and density dependence of the thermal index leads
to the observation that the so-called $\Gamma$ law, widely used in neutron star
merger simulations, is not appropriate to reproduce the true thermal effects,
specially when hyperons start to be abundant in the neutron star core. To make
finite temperature equations of state easily accessible, simple
parameterizations of the thermal index for nucleonic and hyperonic
$\beta$-stable neutrino-free matter are provided.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Kochankovski_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Hristijan Kochankovski&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Ramos_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Angels Ramos&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Tolos_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Laura Tolos&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2207.00102">
<title>Solving the multi-messenger puzzle of the AGN-starburst composite galaxy NGC 1068. (arXiv:2207.00102v3 [astro-ph.HE] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2207.00102</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Multi-wavelength observations indicate that some starburst galaxies show a
dominant non-thermal contribution from their central region. These active
galactic nuclei (AGN)-starburst composites are of special interest, as both
phenomena on their own are potential sources of highly-energetic cosmic rays
and associated gamma-ray and neutrino emission. In this work, a homogeneous,
steady-state two-zone multi-messenger model of the non-thermal emission from
the AGN corona as well as the circumnuclear starburst region is developed and
subsequently applied to the case of NGC 1068, which has recently shown some
first indications of high-energy neutrino emission. Here, we show that the
entire spectrum of multi-messenger data - from radio to gamma-rays including
the neutrino constraint - can be described very well if both, starburst and AGN
corona, are taken into account. Using only a single emission region is not
sufficient.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Eichmann_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Bj&amp;#xf6;rn Eichmann&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Oikonomou_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Foteini Oikonomou&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Salvatore_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Silvia Salvatore&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Dettmar_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ralf-J&amp;#xfc;rgen Dettmar&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Tjus_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Julia Becker Tjus&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2208.03999">
<title>Evaluating chemically homogeneous evolution in stellar binaries: Electromagnetic implications -- Ionizing photons, SLSN-I, GRB, Ic-BL. (arXiv:2208.03999v2 [astro-ph.SR] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2208.03999</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We investigate the occurrence of rapid-rotation induced chemically
homogeneous evolution (CHE) due to strong tides and mass accretion in binaries.
To this end, we generalize the relation in Packet (1981) to calculate the
minimum angular momentum (AM) accretion required by a secondary star to
experience accretion-induced CHE. Contrary to traditionally assumed 5-10
percent accretion of initial mass ($Z \lesssim 0.004$, $M \gtrsim$ 20
M$_{\odot}$) for spinning up the accretor (resulting in CHE) this value can
drop to $\sim$ 2 percent for efficient AM accretion while for certain systems
it could be substantially larger. We conduct a population study using
\textsc{bpass} by evolving stars under the influence of strong tides in
short-period binaries and also account for the updated effect of
accretion-induced spin-up. We find accretion CHE (compared to tidal CHE) to be
the dominant means of producing homogeneous stars even at 10 percent AM
accretion efficiency during mass transfer. Unlike tidal CHE, it is seen that CH
stars arising due to accretion can retain a larger fraction of their AM till
core collapse. Thus we show that accretion CHE could be an important formation
channel for energetic electromagnetic transients like GRBs, Ic-BL (SLSN-I,
Ic-BL) under the collapsar (magnetar) formalism and a single CH star could lead
to both the transients under their respective formation scenario. Lastly, we
show that under the current treatment of CHE, the emission rate of ionizing
photons by such stars decreases more rapidly at higher metallicities than
previously predicted.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Ghodla_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Sohan Ghodla&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Eldridge_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;J. J. Eldridge&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Stanway_E/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Elizabeth R. Stanway&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Stevance_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;H&amp;#xe9;lo&amp;#xef;se F. Stevance&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2208.08423">
<title>Galactic contribution to the high-energy neutrino flux found in track-like IceCube events. (arXiv:2208.08423v2 [astro-ph.HE] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2208.08423</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Astrophysical sources of neutrinos detected by large-scale neutrino
telescopes remain uncertain. While there exist statistically significant
observational indications that a part of the neutrino flux is produced by
blazars, numerous theoretical studies suggest also the presence of potential
Galactic point sources. Some of them have been observed in gamma rays above 100
TeV. Moreover, cosmic-ray interactions in the Galactic disk guarantee a diffuse
neutrino flux. However, these Galactic neutrinos have not been unambiguously
detected so far. Here we examine whether such a Galactic component is present
among the observed neutrinos of the highest energies. We analyze public
track-like IceCube events with estimated neutrino energies above 200 TeV. We
examine the distribution of arrival directions of these neutrinos in the
Galactic latitude b with the help of a simple unbinned, non-parametric test
statistics, the median |b| over the sample. This distribution deviates from
that implied by the null hypothesis of the neutrino flux isotropy, and is
shifted towards lower b with the p-value of 4*10^{-5}, corresponding to the
statistical significance of 4.1 sigma. There exists a significant component of
the high-energy neutrino flux of Galactic origin, matching well the
multi-messenger expectations from Tibet-ASgamma observations of diffuse
Galactic gamma rays at hundreds of TeV. Together with the previously
established extragalactic associations, the Galactic component we report here
implies that the neutrino sky is rich and is composed of contributions from
various classes of sources.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Kovalev_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Y. Y. Kovalev&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Plavin_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;A. V. Plavin&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Troitsky_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;S. V. Troitsky&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2208.09506">
<title>The double white dwarf merger progenitors of SDSS J2211+1136 and ZTF J1901+1458. (arXiv:2208.09506v2 [astro-ph.SR] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2208.09506</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Double white dwarf (DWD) mergers are possibly the leading formation channel
of massive, rapidly rotating, high-field magnetic white dwarfs (HFMWDs).
However, the direct link connecting a DWD merger to any observed HFMWD is still
missing. We here show that the HFMWDs SDSS J221141.80+113604.4 (hereafter
J2211+1136) and ZTF J190132.9+145808.7 (hereafter J1901+1458), might be DWD
merger products. J2211+1136 is a $1.27\, M_\odot$ WD with a rotation period of
$70.32$ s and a surface magnetic field of $15$ MG. J1901+1458 is a
$1.327$--$1.365\, M_\odot$ WD with a rotation period of $416.20$ s, and a
surface magnetic field in the range $600$--$900$ MG. With the assumption of
single-star evolution, the currently measured WD masses and surface
temperatures, the cooling ages of J2211+1136 and J1901+1458 are, respectively,
$2.61$--$2.85$ Gyr and $10$--$100$ Myr. We hypothesize that these WDs are DWD
merger products and compute the evolution of the post-merged configuration
formed by a central WD surrounded by a disk. We show that the post-merger
system evolves through three phases depending on whether accretion, mass
ejection (propeller), or magnetic braking dominates the torque onto the central
WD. We calculate the time the WD spends in each of these phases and obtain the
accretion rate and disk mass for which the WD rotational age, i.e., the total
time elapsed since the merger to the instant where the WD central remnant
reaches the current measured rotation period, agrees with the estimated WD
cooling age. We infer the mass values of the primary and secondary WD
components of the DWD merger that lead to a post-merger evolution consistent
with the observations.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Sousa_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;M. F. Sousa&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Coelho_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;J. G. Coelho&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Araujo_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;J. C. N. de Araujo&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Kepler_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;S. O. Kepler&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Rueda_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;J. A. Rueda&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.12875">
<title>Fermi Gamma-ray Space Telescope. (arXiv:2210.12875v3 [astro-ph.HE] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.12875</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The Fermi Gamma-ray Space Telescope, a key mission in multiwavelength and
multimessenger studies, has been surveying the gamma-ray sky from its low-Earth
orbit since 2008. Its two scientific instruments, the Gamma-ray Burst Monitor
(GBM) and the Large Area Telescope (LAT), cover 8 orders of magnitude in photon
energy. The GBM consists of 12 Sodium Iodide detectors and 2 Bismuth Germinate
detectors, covering the 10 keV - 40 MeV energy range, arrayed on two sides of
the spacecraft so as to view the entire sky that is not occulted by the Earth.
The LAT is a pair production telescope based on silicon strip trackers, a
Cesium Iodide calorimeter, and a plastic scintillator anticoincidence system.
It covers the energy range from about 20 MeV to more than 500 GeV, with a field
of view of about 2.4 steradians. Thanks to their huge fields of view, the
instruments can observe the entire sky with a cadence of about an hour for GBM
and about three hours for LAT. All gamma-ray data from Fermi become public
immediately, enabling a broad range of multiwavelength and multimessenger
research. Over 3000 gamma-ray bursts (GRBs), including GRB 170817A associated
with a neutron star merger detected in gravitational waves, and 5000
high-energy sources, including the blazar TXS 0506+056 associated with
high-energy neutrinos, have been detected by the Fermi instruments. The Fermi
Science Support Center provides a wide array of resources to enable scientific
use of the data, including background models, source catalogs, analysis
software, documentation, and a Help Desk.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Thompson_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;David J. Thompson&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Wilson_Hodge_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Colleen A. Wilson-Hodge&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.15569">
<title>Deciphering the Archeological Record: Further Evidence for Ultra-High-Energy Cosmic Ray Acceleration in Starburst-Driven Superwinds. (arXiv:2210.15569v2 [astro-ph.HE] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.15569</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Very recently, the Pierre Auger and Telescope Array collaborations reported
strong evidence for a correlation between the highest energy cosmic rays and
nearby starburst galaxies, with a global significance post-trial of
$4.6\sigma$. It is well known that the collective effect of supernovae and
winds from massive stars in the central region of these galaxies drives a
galactic-scale superwind that can shock heat and accelerate ambient
interstellar or circumgalactic gas. In previous work we showed that, for
reasonable source parameters, starburst-driven superwinds can be the carriers
of ultra-high-energy cosmic ray acceleration. In this paper we assess the
extent to which one can approach the archaeological ``inverse&apos;&apos; problem of
deciphering properties of superwind evolution from present-day IR emission of
their host galaxies. We show that the Outer Limits galaxy NGC 891 could provide
``smoking gun evidence&apos;&apos; for the starburst-driven superwind model of
ultra-high-energy cosmic rays.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Anchordoqui_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Luis Alfredo Anchordoqui&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.00940">
<title>Continuous gravitational wave detection to understand the generation mechanism of fast radio bursts. (arXiv:2211.00940v1 [astro-ph.HE] CROSS LISTED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.00940</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Since the unexpected discovery of fast radio bursts (FRBs), researchers have
proposed varied theories and models to explain their phenomena. One such model
that has recently been developed incorporates the so-called
Gertsenshtein-Zel&apos;dovich (GZ) effect, which states that when gravitational
waves traverse the pulsar magnetosphere, a portion of their gravitational
radiation is transformed into electromagnetic (EM) radiation. The observed
properties of FRBs are consistent with the properties of this EM radiation,
implying, remarkably, that the GZ effect can account for both repeating and
non-repeating FRBs. If this model is correct, the pulsar&apos;s properties should
not change over time, and it would continue to emit both EM dipole and
gravitational quadrupole radiation for a long period of time. This article
targets the gravitational radiation produced by the pulsar mechanism and shows
that several proposed gravitational wave detectors can detect these
gravitational waves. If such detections are performed in the future from the
positions of FRBs, it will validate the GZ process for FRB production and can
rule out several other FRB theories.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Kalita_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Surajit Kalita&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Weltman_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Amanda Weltman&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
</rdf:RDF>