<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?><rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0"><channel><title>The Official Google Blog</title><link>https://blog.google/</link><description>Insights from Googlers into our products, technology, and the Google culture.</description><atom:link href="https://blog.google/rss/" rel="self"/><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2022 10:51:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://blog.google/static/blogv2/images/google.png</url><title>The Keyword</title><link>https://blog.google/</link></image><item><title>How Gen Z is fighting online misinformation in Asia-Pacific</title><link>https://blog.google/products/news/how-gen-z-is-fighting-online-misinformation-in-asia-pacific/</link><description>&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;div class="block-paragraph"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="denea"&gt;Last week marked the UNESCO Global Media and Information Literacy Week— perfect timing for our recently concluded Google News Initiative (GNI) &lt;a href="https://www.verificationchallenge.com/"&gt;Youth Verification Challenge&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="bi65d"&gt;The Challenge is for those aged 15 to 24 across the Asia Pacific region, and presents teams with a series of tutorials and quizzes on identifying online misinformation. This year, over 4,000 participants from 28 countries took part, learning about fact-checking tools used in the real world. Each team had the chance to &lt;a href="https://newsonair.withgoogle.com/events/youth-verification-challenge-en?tab=chapter1"&gt;hone&lt;/a&gt; their investigative skills and &lt;a href="https://newsonair.withgoogle.com/events/youth-verification-challenge-en?tab=chapter2"&gt;learn&lt;/a&gt; from experts.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="a90sk"&gt;We spoke with the winning team from India — made up of students Royal, Amitabh, and Rooka — about their thoughts on fact-checking. Royal attends the National Institute of Technology Karnataka, while Amitabh is a student at the Gaya College of Engineering, and Rooka studies at the Jawaharlal Nehru Technological University. Together they became the self-named team “Espionage Experts”, and experts they truly were! They had to solve more than 200 problems in order to win first place.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="daptv"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="4a92"&gt;&lt;b&gt;How can news be more engaging for a younger audience?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="emmge"&gt;By providing a concise explanation of the story, news can definitely be enjoyable for younger audiences. Simple story formats, explainers and background context makes news easier to digest, but to truly engage younger audiences, media organizations need to consider more diverse points of view and experiment with different kinds of story-telling formats. They can give us a call if they want some tips!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="3krl7"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="1vles"&gt;&lt;b&gt;How aware do you think Gen Z is when it comes to online misinformation?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="cr13d"&gt;We think the younger generation needs to be even more aware, as many people appear to be falling for misinformation online. Events like the Youth Verification Challenge are great initiatives that can be conducted to inform youths about how to discern true stories from misinformation in an engaging manner.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="fvagl"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="biru1"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Why do you think fact-checking is important?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="bc81h"&gt;Fact-checking is very important in the present world. We believe that true stories should and must prevail. It is important for us to get into a habit of fact-checking, given the cognitive biases that make us (unfortunately) receptive to fake news. Fact-checking can help mitigate the threat that misinformation poses to factual accuracy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="403j0"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="89t1g"&gt;&lt;b&gt;How will the team continue to bring fact-checking skills in their daily routine?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="c1q6l"&gt;We are really passionate about sharing our experiences and the skills we picked up from the Youth Verification Challenge, and aspire to help our communities get better at fact-checking, too. Beyond encouraging people around us to use fact-checking tools like Google’s Fact Check Explorer, we will also focus on developing new skills to adapt to external trends in today’s digital world. The tools and strategies we use now will change when technology and the world of disinformation inevitably changes. Things are evolving fast and we all have to keep up!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="al071"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="5itud"&gt;Through the Youth Verification Challenge, we hope to keep encouraging younger internet users to fight misinformation as they equip themselves with the tools to approach the internet with confidence.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2022 10:51:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.google/products/news/how-gen-z-is-fighting-online-misinformation-in-asia-pacific/</guid><category>Google News Initiative</category><category>Google in Asia</category><media:content height="540" url="https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/Screen_Shot_2022-11-04_at_10.53.12_AM.max-600x600.png" width="540"/><og xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#"><type>article</type><title>How Gen Z is fighting online misinformation in Asia-Pacific</title><description></description><image>https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/Screen_Shot_2022-11-04_at_10.53.12_AM.max-600x600.png</image><site_name>Google</site_name><url>https://blog.google/products/news/how-gen-z-is-fighting-online-misinformation-in-asia-pacific/</url></og><author xmlns:author="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><name>Irene Liu</name><title>Head of APAC, News Lab</title><department/><company/></author></item><item><title>Look to Speak launches in Ukraine</title><link>https://blog.google/outreach-initiatives/accessibility/look-to-speak-launches-in-ukraine/</link><description>&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;div class="block-paragraph"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="rxv34"&gt;Nearly two years ago, Google launched &lt;a href="https://blog.google/outreach-initiatives/accessibility/look-to-speak/"&gt;Look to Speak&lt;/a&gt;, an Android app that allows people to use their eyes to select pre-written phrases and have them spoken aloud. Since then, the app has launched in 18 additional languages. Most recently, we made the app available in Ukrainian to help refugees and veterans of the war.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="8l7gf"&gt;As a speech and language therapist working at Google, I’ve seen how technology can help people express their everyday needs, feelings and identity. To hear from someone about how Look to Speak can be particularly helpful in Ukraine where people are dealing with the injuries and side effects of war, I spoke with Oksana Lyalka, the founder and president of the Ukrainian Society for Speech and Language Therapy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="fe5n2"&gt;&lt;b&gt;What is the situation like for veterans and refugees of the war in Ukraine who have speech and motor impairments?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="233ke"&gt;Due to direct injuries and conditions caused by the war, the number of people with both motor and speech impairments are likely increasing. In addition, indirect impact like stress and malnutrition causes an increased risk of strokes, which can also lead to motor and speech impairments — and access to care remains limited. Also, for many refugees who left Ukraine and are in foreign countries, it’s difficult to get the help they need because many of them already have chronic impairments and their insurance does not cover therapy for communication disorders in another country. Plus, communication is a language-specific impairment. Meaning, it’s difficult to get the help they need in their native language outside of Ukraine.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="es3l4"&gt;&lt;b&gt;What are the specific challenges that people are facing?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="5gtrb"&gt;They are mainly left on their own with speech and motor impairments. Because: 1) There’s a shortage of speech language therapists. 2) There are even fewer who understand what these patients deal with. 3) Therapy is costly and not everyone has the resources to afford it, especially in war time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="3uvf1"&gt;&lt;b&gt;How could a tool like Look to Speak be helpful in Ukraine?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="fp0rr"&gt;When someone has only a speech disorder, they can still write to communicate. But when there are also motor disorders like we’ve discussed, people can end up with no way to communicate. With Look to Speak, even if someone can’t communicate using their mouth, they can communicate with their eyes. This allows caregivers and others in their environment to listen and understand in new ways. Communication is a two-way process, and the Look to Speak app can act as a bridge.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="djkeq"&gt;&lt;b&gt;The First Lady of Ukraine Olena Zelenska on the Look to Speak app:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="6p7uc"&gt;"One of everyone’s fundamental needs is the ability to communicate and interact with those around them. For most people, it is unnoticeable and automatic, similar to breathing. However, due to various factors, a person may lose this ability and be unable to talk or use a computer, tablet, mobile phone, or other devices. Especially now, in times when the war daily multiplies the chances of finding oneself in such conditions, we as a society must unite and help each other as much as we can to overcome these terrible circumstances. One of the examples of Ukraine's responsible cooperation with world technological leaders is the localization of Google’s Look to Speak app. It helps people with motor and speech impairments to communicate using their eye movements. It is good to know that Ukrainian public organizations in health care, medical institutions, and everyone who needs it can use advanced digital solutions now adapted to the needs of Ukrainian users. I am sure that initiatives like Look to Speak will not only provide new opportunities for our citizens but will also serve as a model for other technological companies that are now supporting Ukraine."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="6cj3d"&gt;To learn more about Look to Speak in Ukraine, watch &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1EvL8VqFHCI"&gt;this video&lt;/a&gt; in Ukrainian.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.google/outreach-initiatives/accessibility/look-to-speak-launches-in-ukraine/</guid><category>Accessibility</category><media:content height="540" url="https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/LTS_thumbnail_221025a_1.max-600x600.jpg" width="540"/><og xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#"><type>article</type><title>Look to Speak launches in Ukraine</title><description>Learn about Look to Speak, an Android app which enables people to use their eyes to select pre-written phrases and have them spoken aloud.</description><image>https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/LTS_thumbnail_221025a_1.max-600x600.jpg</image><site_name>Google</site_name><url>https://blog.google/outreach-initiatives/accessibility/look-to-speak-launches-in-ukraine/</url></og><author xmlns:author="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><name>Richard Cave</name><title>Speech &amp; Language Therapist</title><department/><company/></author></item><item><title>Expanding opportunities for Indigenous communities</title><link>https://blog.google/outreach-initiatives/grow-with-google/native-american-history-month-2022-digital-skills-training/</link><description>&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;div class="block-paragraph"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="k9f7k"&gt;November is Native American Heritage Month in the U.S. and is an opportune time to educate and raise awareness about the achievements and unique challenges that Tribal Nations face — both historically and presently — and how tribal citizens have worked together to overcome those challenges. One such example is the impact the pandemic has had on tribal economies and Native American-owned businesses.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="94vcb"&gt;As the President of the National Congress of American Indians (NCAI) — a long-time partner of Google — I’ve met many Native artisans and small-business owners over the past two years, who once had thriving businesses but now struggle to transition to online platforms to keep their businesses afloat. According to the &lt;a href="https://www.census.gov/newsroom/press-releases/2021/characteristics-of-employer-businesses.html"&gt;U.S. Census&lt;/a&gt;, Native American-owned businesses contribute over $35 billion to the economy and employ over 200,000 people, yet &lt;a href="https://www.ncaied.org/covid-19/survey-results-detail-covid-19s-impact-on-indian-countrys-economy/"&gt;one in six&lt;/a&gt; businesses (16.7%) have reported complete revenue losses due to the lingering impacts of the pandemic. Now, more than ever, our businesses require adequate resources for them to thrive, and there is no denying that technology is helping create that pathway forward.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="dtou4"&gt;I’m thrilled to share that the &lt;a href="http://grow.google/digitalcoaches"&gt;Grow with Google Digital Coaches program&lt;/a&gt;, which equips businesses with robust digital skills to unlock growth opportunities, is expanding to train Native-led businesses with the help of a dedicated Digital Coach from the community. We’ll be able to further support Native-led businesses thanks to a new grant from Google.org to help NCAI strengthen digital skill training.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-image_full_width"&gt;&lt;div class="h-c-page"&gt;&lt;div class="article-image h-c-grid__col--10 h-c-grid__col--offset-1 h-c-grid__col-l--offset-2 h-c-grid__col-l--8"&gt;&lt;a class="article-image--link"&gt;&lt;img alt="Headshot of Jake Foreman, a Grow with Google Indigenous Community Digital Coach" class="article-image--full" data-loading='{
                "mobile": "https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/Google_Indigenous_Community_Coach_Headshot_1.max-500x500.png",
                "desktop": "https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/Google_Indigenous_Community_Coach_Headshot.max-1000x1000.png"
              }' loading="lazy" src=" https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/Google_Indigenous_Community_Coach_Headshot_1.max-100x100.png " tabindex="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-paragraph"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="k9f7k"&gt;I’m honored to introduce Henry Jake Foreman as Grow with Google’s first-ever Indigenous Community Digital Coach. As a Digital Coach, Jake will empower tribal small businesses with monthly digital skills workshops, local hands-on coaching opportunities, and events for businesses to come together and learn from one another. Jake is an Absentee Shawnee citizen who resides in Albuquerque, New Mexico, and is a Program Director at &lt;a href="https://nmccap.org/"&gt;New Mexico Community Capital&lt;/a&gt;. As a trainer for NCAI’s training program, incubated with support from Grow with Google, Jake has helped hundreds of Native American entrepreneurs in New Mexico develop skill sets to support and build their businesses. We’re excited to see Grow with Google build on the success of that collaboration as they expand the Digital Coaches program. Jake will now bring these trainings directly to tribal communities across Indian Country and partner with NCAI to host monthly national webinars beginning in 2023.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="lfb8"&gt;In addition, Google.org is providing a $750,000 grant to support NCAI’s own institutional capacity and positioning in the Indigenous digital skilling space. NCAI will directly invest this into IT capabilities to foster a community of learning and distill best IT practices to contribute toward the broader ecosystem. This investment builds on the previous $1.25M in grants used to help support Native-owned businesses — all done in service of helping more Indigenous people to achieve success and help bridge Indian Country’s digital divide.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="649pa"&gt;Because Native-led businesses serve as the backbone for many tribal communities, it was a very special moment to first share this news with tribal leaders, NCAI members and Native youth at our NCAI 79th Annual Convention &amp;amp; Marketplace earlier this week. At the conference, we also had the pleasure of hosting Jake’s first digital skills workshop as a new Digital Coach. Undoubtedly, these tailored workshops and resources will help our businesses thrive online and grow tremendously. To learn more and sign up, visit &lt;a href="http://g.co/grow/digitalcoachIC"&gt;g.co/grow/digitalcoachIC&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-perspective_qa"&gt;&lt;div class="uni-related-article-tout h-c-page" data-component="uni-related-article-tout"&gt;&lt;section class="h-c-grid"&gt;&lt;a class="uni-related-article-tout__wrapper h-c-grid__col h-c-grid__col--8 h-c-grid__col-m--6 h-c-grid__col-l--6 h-c-grid__col--offset-2 h-c-grid__col-m--offset-3 h-c-grid__col-l--offset-3 uni-click-tracker" data-analytics='{
                      "event": "page interaction",
                      "category": "article lead",
                      "action": "related article - inline",
                      "label": "article: celebrate-native-american-artists-in-chrome-and-chromeos"
                    }' href="https://blog.google/products/chrome/celebrate-native-american-artists-in-chrome-and-chromeos/"&gt;&lt;div class="uni-related-article-tout__inner-wrapper"&gt;&lt;p class="uni-related-article-tout__eyebrow h-c-eyebrow"&gt;Related Article&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="uni-related-article-tout__content-wrapper"&gt;&lt;div class="uni-related-article-tout__image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;div class="uni-related-article-tout__image" data-loading='{
              "mobile": "https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/Chrome_Themes_NAHM_Blog_Header_V2-01_C7pWxge.max-500x500.png",
              "desktop": "https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/Chrome_Themes_NAHM_Blog_Header_V2-01_C7pWxge.max-500x500.png"
            }' style="background-image: url('https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/Chrome_Themes_NAHM_Blog_Header_V2-01_C7pWxge.max-100x100.png')"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="uni-related-article-tout__content"&gt;&lt;h4 class="uni-related-article-tout__header h-has-bottom-margin"&gt;Celebrate Native American artists in Chrome and ChromeOS&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p class="uni-related-article-tout__body"&gt;To celebrate Native American Heritage Month, we commissioned Native American artists to create a collection of themes for Chrome and ChromeOS.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="cta module-cta h-c-copy uni-related-article-tout__cta muted"&gt;&lt;span class="nowrap"&gt;Read Article&lt;svg class="icon h-c-icon" role="presentation"&gt;&lt;use xlink:href="#mi-arrow-forward" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/section&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.google/outreach-initiatives/grow-with-google/native-american-history-month-2022-digital-skills-training/</guid><category>Small Business</category><category>Grow with Google</category><media:content height="540" url="https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/Hero_image_DQJhGbl.max-600x600.png" width="540"/><og xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#"><type>article</type><title>Expanding opportunities for Indigenous communities</title><description>Google is expanding opportunities for Indigenous communities through dedicated training and coaching for Indigenous business owners.</description><image>https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/Hero_image_DQJhGbl.max-600x600.png</image><site_name>Google</site_name><url>https://blog.google/outreach-initiatives/grow-with-google/native-american-history-month-2022-digital-skills-training/</url></og><author xmlns:author="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><name>Fawn Sharp</name><title>President of the National Congress of American Indians</title><department/><company/></author></item><item><title>Celebrate Native American artists in Chrome and ChromeOS</title><link>https://blog.google/products/chrome/celebrate-native-american-artists-in-chrome-and-chromeos/</link><description>&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;div class="block-paragraph"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="j8ez7"&gt;It’s &lt;a href="https://events.withgoogle.com/digital-coach-ic/"&gt;Native American Heritage Month&lt;/a&gt; in the U.S., a time when we honor the history, traditions and contributions of Native Americans. As a citizen of the Cherokee Nation, I celebrate this month by taking time to reflect and express gratitude for my ancestors, the resilience of my tribe and other Indigenous people, and future generations carrying our tribal traditions forward.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="1m4qk"&gt;As a product manager at Google, I’m also proud of how we’re celebrating across our products. On Google Assistant, for example, just say “Happy Native American Heritage Month” or “Give me a fact about Native American Heritage” throughout the month of November to hear a collection of historical facts and stories from the Native American community. Meanwhile, a recent &lt;a href="https://www.google.com/doodles/celebrating-indigenous-north-american-stickball"&gt;Doodle&lt;/a&gt; on Google’s homepage celebrated the history of Stickball, a traditional sport created by Indigenous tribes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-image_full_width"&gt;&lt;div class="h-c-page"&gt;&lt;div class="article-image h-c-grid__col-l--4 h-c-grid__col--6 h-c-grid__col-l--offset-4 h-c-grid__col--offset-3"&gt;&lt;a class="article-image--link"&gt;&lt;img alt="An image of a recent Doodle on Google’s homepage with 5 abstract characters playing Stickball, a traditional sport created by Indigenous tribes." class="article-image--medium" data-loading='{
                "mobile": "https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/celebrating-stickball-6753651837109530-2x.max-500x500.png",
                "desktop": "https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/celebrating-stickball-6753651837109530-2x.max-1000x1000.png"
              }' loading="lazy" src=" https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/celebrating-stickball-6753651837109530-2x.max-100x100.png " tabindex="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-paragraph"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="rqjra"&gt;We also commissioned five Native American artists to create a collection of themes for Chromebooks and Chrome browser. This collection has a special meaning to me because it showcases important traditions and reminds me of home. Richard D. York’s piece “ᎤᎧᏖᎾ (Uktena, or Horned Serpent)” in particular brings me back to my childhood listening to the stories of Uktena and other tales from my elders. A more solemn work, “A Lot Meant,” reminded me of growing up in Oklahoma and how historical policies like &lt;a href="https://www.archives.gov/milestone-documents/dawes-act#:~:text=Also%20known%20as%20the%20General,granted%20allotments%20of%20reservation%20land."&gt;allotment&lt;/a&gt; impacted my family and so many others.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="14vhr"&gt;Now available globally, these themes reflect the unique experiences and identities of each artist. Here’s what they shared about their work:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-image_carousel"&gt;&lt;div class="h-c-page article-module" data-component="uni-image-carousel"&gt;&lt;div class="article-module glue-pagination h-c-carousel h-c-carousel--simple h-c-carousel--dark ng-cloak" data-glue-pagination-config="{cyclical: true}"&gt;&lt;div class="h-c-carousel__wrap"&gt;&lt;ul class="glue-carousel ng-cloak" data-glue-carousel-options="{pointerTypes: ['touch', 'mouse'], jump: true}"&gt;&lt;li class="h-c-carousel__item article-carousel__slide"&gt;&lt;figure class="h-c-grid"&gt;&lt;div aria-label="A Chromebook wallpaper showing three ravens — colored red, green and blue — flying against a crescent moon." class="article-carousel__slide-img h-c-grid__col h-c-grid__col--10 h-c-grid__col--offset-1" data-loading='{
                      "mobile": "https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/2_Crystal_Worl_RGB_Ravens_V2_Q6HOSbE.max-1000x1000.png",
                      "desktop": "https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/2_Crystal_Worl_RGB_Ravens_V2_Q6HOSbE.max-2000x2000.png"
                    }' style="background-image: url(https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/2_Crystal_Worl_RGB_Ravens_V2_Q6HOSbE.max-200x200.png);"&gt;&lt;span class="h-u-visually-hidden"&gt;A Chromebook wallpaper showing three ravens — colored red, green and blue — flying against a crescent moon.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption class="article-carousel__caption h-c-grid__col h-c-grid__col--10 h-c-grid__col-l--8 h-c-grid__col--offset-1 h-c-grid__col-l--offset-2"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="hjkz5"&gt;“Primary Ravens” by Crystal Worl&lt;br/&gt;“These three primary ravens of red, green and blue come together to create a broad array of colors. Together they are tricksters, mischievous, curious; on this snowy evening, they are perhaps scheming to create something new.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li class="h-c-carousel__item article-carousel__slide"&gt;&lt;figure class="h-c-grid"&gt;&lt;div aria-label="A Chrome browser wallpaper showing a raven outlined in white against a red-orange background." class="article-carousel__slide-img h-c-grid__col h-c-grid__col--10 h-c-grid__col--offset-1" style="background-image: url(https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/James_P._Johnson_Raven_Yeil.max-800x800.png);"&gt;&lt;span class="h-u-visually-hidden"&gt;A Chrome browser wallpaper showing a raven outlined in white against a red-orange background.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption class="article-carousel__caption h-c-grid__col h-c-grid__col--10 h-c-grid__col-l--8 h-c-grid__col--offset-1 h-c-grid__col-l--offset-2"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="2oemw"&gt;“Yéil (Raven)” by James P. Johnson&lt;br/&gt;“I belong to the Dakl'aweidi Clan (Killerwhale) and follow the Tlingit art form of my ancestors. Everything I do is inspired by my son Elias, who was born with a life-threatening genetic disorder called Cystic fibrosis. Gunalcheesh.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li class="h-c-carousel__item article-carousel__slide"&gt;&lt;figure class="h-c-grid"&gt;&lt;div aria-label="A Chrome browser wallpaper showing a geometric box containing an image of a desert landscape against the horizon." class="article-carousel__slide-img h-c-grid__col h-c-grid__col--10 h-c-grid__col--offset-1" style="background-image: url(https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/Michael_Namingha_Yupkoyvi.max-800x800.png);"&gt;&lt;span class="h-u-visually-hidden"&gt;A Chrome browser wallpaper showing a geometric box containing an image of a desert landscape against the horizon.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption class="article-carousel__caption h-c-grid__col h-c-grid__col--10 h-c-grid__col-l--8 h-c-grid__col--offset-1 h-c-grid__col-l--offset-2"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="2oemw"&gt;“Yupkoyvi (Chaco Canyon)” by Michael Namingha&lt;br/&gt;“I was inspired by the changing landscape of the West. Yupkoyvi, ‘the place beyond the horizon,’ is sacred to the Hopi and Puebloan people, and is under threat by oil and gas development. We have a duty to protect this land.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li class="h-c-carousel__item article-carousel__slide"&gt;&lt;figure class="h-c-grid"&gt;&lt;div aria-label="A Chromebook wallpaper with an image of a coyote on a hillside with a constellation of stars in the background." class="article-carousel__slide-img h-c-grid__col h-c-grid__col--10 h-c-grid__col--offset-1" style="background-image: url(https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/2_Noah_Lee_Constellation_Mix_V2.max-2000x2000.png);"&gt;&lt;span class="h-u-visually-hidden"&gt;A Chromebook wallpaper with an image of a coyote on a hillside with a constellation of stars in the background.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption class="article-carousel__caption h-c-grid__col h-c-grid__col--10 h-c-grid__col-l--8 h-c-grid__col--offset-1 h-c-grid__col-l--offset-2"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="2oemw"&gt;“Constellation Mix” by Noah Lee&lt;br/&gt;“In Diné folklore, the ‘Holy People’ are deities that created the constellations and the impatient coyote, a chaotic trickster, scattered the stars into a mess. In this theme, the milky way reflects a pathway from earth to heaven.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li class="h-c-carousel__item article-carousel__slide"&gt;&lt;figure class="h-c-grid"&gt;&lt;div aria-label="A Chrome browser wallpaper with an abstract image of a dragon with shades of green, blue, yellow, purple and white." class="article-carousel__slide-img h-c-grid__col h-c-grid__col--10 h-c-grid__col--offset-1" style="background-image: url(https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/Richard_D._York_Uktena.max-800x800.png);"&gt;&lt;span class="h-u-visually-hidden"&gt;A Chrome browser wallpaper with an abstract image of a dragon with shades of green, blue, yellow, purple and white.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption class="article-carousel__caption h-c-grid__col h-c-grid__col--10 h-c-grid__col-l--8 h-c-grid__col--offset-1 h-c-grid__col-l--offset-2"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="2oemw"&gt;“ᎤᎧᏖᎾ (Horned Serpent)” by Richard D. York&lt;br/&gt;“ᎤᎧᏖᎾ (Horned Serpent) is a malevolent dragon of Cherokee stories. Whoever captures its crystal becomes a great healer. Sequoyah, inventor of the Cherokee writing system, worked to help our people and preserve our culture. Saving our culture is like facing ᎤᎧᏖᎾ.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;div class="h-c-carousel__paginate glue-pagination-previous uni-click-tracker" data-analytics='{
            "event": "page interaction",
            "category": "interaction",
            "action": "image carousel",
            "label": "arrow - left click"
           }' data-glue-pagination-label="Previous" data-glue-pagination-update-model="false"&gt;&lt;div class="h-c-carousel__paginate-wrap"&gt;&lt;svg class="h-c-icon h-c-icon--keyboard-arrow-left" role="img"&gt;&lt;use xlink:href="#mi-keyboard-arrow-right"&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="h-c-carousel__paginate glue-pagination-next uni-click-tracker" data-analytics='{
            "event": "page interaction",
            "category": "interaction",
            "action": "image carousel",
            "label": "arrow - right click"
           }' data-glue-pagination-label="Next" data-glue-pagination-update-model="false"&gt;&lt;div class="h-c-carousel__paginate-wrap"&gt;&lt;svg class="h-c-icon h-c-icon--keyboard-arrow-right" role="img"&gt;&lt;use xlink:href="#mi-keyboard-arrow-right"&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="h-c-carousel__navigation"&gt;&lt;div class="glue-pagination-page-list uni-click-tracker" data-analytics='{
            "event": "page interaction",
            "category": "interaction",
            "action": "image carousel",
            "label": "arrow - dot click"
           }'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-paragraph"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="j8ez7"&gt;To apply one of these themes (or others from &lt;a href="https://chrome.google.com/webstore/category/collection/artist_themes"&gt;Black&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://chrome.google.com/webstore/category/collection/latino_artist_themes"&gt;Latino&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://chrome.google.com/webstore/category/collection/lgbtq_themes"&gt;LGBTQ+&lt;/a&gt; artists) to your Chrome browser, visit the &lt;a href="https://chrome.google.com/webstore/category/collection/native_american_artists_collection"&gt;Chrome Web Store collection&lt;/a&gt;, select a theme and click "Add to Chrome." You can also open a new tab and click the “Customize Chrome” button on the bottom right to explore background collections. To apply one of these wallpapers to your Chromebook, right-click your desktop, choose "Set wallpaper and style," then select "Native American Artists.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-perspective_qa"&gt;&lt;div class="uni-related-article-tout h-c-page" data-component="uni-related-article-tout"&gt;&lt;section class="h-c-grid"&gt;&lt;a class="uni-related-article-tout__wrapper h-c-grid__col h-c-grid__col--8 h-c-grid__col-m--6 h-c-grid__col-l--6 h-c-grid__col--offset-2 h-c-grid__col-m--offset-3 h-c-grid__col-l--offset-3 uni-click-tracker" data-analytics='{
                      "event": "page interaction",
                      "category": "article lead",
                      "action": "related article - inline",
                      "label": "article: native-american-history-month-2022-digital-skills-training"
                    }' href="https://blog.google/outreach-initiatives/grow-with-google/native-american-history-month-2022-digital-skills-training/"&gt;&lt;div class="uni-related-article-tout__inner-wrapper"&gt;&lt;p class="uni-related-article-tout__eyebrow h-c-eyebrow"&gt;Related Article&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="uni-related-article-tout__content-wrapper"&gt;&lt;div class="uni-related-article-tout__image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;div class="uni-related-article-tout__image" data-loading='{
              "mobile": "https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/Hero_image_DQJhGbl.max-500x500.png",
              "desktop": "https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/Hero_image_DQJhGbl.max-500x500.png"
            }' style="background-image: url('https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/Hero_image_DQJhGbl.max-100x100.png')"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="uni-related-article-tout__content"&gt;&lt;h4 class="uni-related-article-tout__header h-has-bottom-margin"&gt;Expanding opportunities for Indigenous communities&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p class="uni-related-article-tout__body"&gt;Google is expanding opportunities for Indigenous communities through dedicated training and coaching for Indigenous business owners.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="cta module-cta h-c-copy uni-related-article-tout__cta muted"&gt;&lt;span class="nowrap"&gt;Read Article&lt;svg class="icon h-c-icon" role="presentation"&gt;&lt;use xlink:href="#mi-arrow-forward" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/section&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.google/products/chrome/celebrate-native-american-artists-in-chrome-and-chromeos/</guid><category>Google Assistant</category><category>Chromebooks</category><category>Diversity and Inclusion</category><category>Chrome</category><media:content height="540" url="https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/Chrome_Themes_NAHM_Blog_Header_V2-01_C7pWxge.max-600x600.png" width="540"/><og xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#"><type>article</type><title>Celebrate Native American artists in Chrome and ChromeOS</title><description>To celebrate Native American Heritage Month, we commissioned Native American artists to create a collection of themes for Chrome and ChromeOS.</description><image>https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/Chrome_Themes_NAHM_Blog_Header_V2-01_C7pWxge.max-600x600.png</image><site_name>Google</site_name><url>https://blog.google/products/chrome/celebrate-native-american-artists-in-chrome-and-chromeos/</url></og><author xmlns:author="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><name>Blair Huffman</name><title>Cherokee Nation, Group Product Manager, ChromeOS</title><department/><company/></author></item><item><title>3 ways to keep audiences engaged in a content-driven world</title><link>https://blog.google/products/ads-commerce/engage-audience-in-content-driven-world/</link><description>&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;div class="block-paragraph"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="5ffiz"&gt;Consumers navigate a widening variety of digital content from text to image to video—and they choose to spend their time in the experiences that feel most natural and intuitive for them. Working with Ipsos, we've identified three ways to keep your audience engaged across platforms throughout the holiday season, plus new retail-ready formats and creative tools to help you drive growth into the new year.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-image_carousel"&gt;&lt;div class="h-c-page article-module" data-component="uni-image-carousel"&gt;&lt;div class="article-module glue-pagination h-c-carousel h-c-carousel--simple h-c-carousel--dark ng-cloak" data-glue-pagination-config="{cyclical: true}"&gt;&lt;div class="h-c-carousel__wrap"&gt;&lt;ul class="glue-carousel ng-cloak" data-glue-carousel-options="{pointerTypes: ['touch', 'mouse'], jump: true}"&gt;&lt;li class="h-c-carousel__item article-carousel__slide"&gt;&lt;figure class="h-c-grid"&gt;&lt;div aria-label="A carousel that shows three research insights about consumer behavior in Google feeds" class="article-carousel__slide-img h-c-grid__col h-c-grid__col--10 h-c-grid__col--offset-1" data-loading='{
                      "mobile": "https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/E02802031_Google_BPM_Ipsos_Consumer_Insigh.max-1000x1000_yMKYpV4.jpg",
                      "desktop": "https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/E02802031_Google_BPM_Ipsos_Consumer_Insigh.max-1000x1000_yMKYpV4.jpg"
                    }' style="background-image: url(https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/E02802031_Google_BPM_Ipsos_Consumer_Insights.max-200x200_33NSKC8.jpg);"&gt;&lt;span class="h-u-visually-hidden"&gt;A carousel that shows three research insights about consumer behavior in Google feeds&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption class="article-carousel__caption h-c-grid__col h-c-grid__col--10 h-c-grid__col-l--8 h-c-grid__col--offset-1 h-c-grid__col-l--offset-2"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="olwpy"&gt;Source: Google/Ipsos, Consumer Feed Behavior Research, August 2022&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li class="h-c-carousel__item article-carousel__slide"&gt;&lt;figure class="h-c-grid"&gt;&lt;div aria-label="A carousel that shows three research insights about consumer behavior in Google feeds" class="article-carousel__slide-img h-c-grid__col h-c-grid__col--10 h-c-grid__col--offset-1" style="background-image: url(https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/E02802031_Google_BPM_Ipsos_Consumer_Insigh.max-1000x1000_qjqyffj.jpg);"&gt;&lt;span class="h-u-visually-hidden"&gt;A carousel that shows three research insights about consumer behavior in Google feeds&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption class="article-carousel__caption h-c-grid__col h-c-grid__col--10 h-c-grid__col-l--8 h-c-grid__col--offset-1 h-c-grid__col-l--offset-2"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="9tqcf"&gt;Source: Google/Ipsos, Consumer Feed Behavior Research, August 2022&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li class="h-c-carousel__item article-carousel__slide"&gt;&lt;figure class="h-c-grid"&gt;&lt;div aria-label="A carousel that shows three research insights about consumer behavior in Google feeds" class="article-carousel__slide-img h-c-grid__col h-c-grid__col--10 h-c-grid__col--offset-1" style="background-image: url(https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/E02802031_Google_BPM_Ipsos_Consumer_Insigh.max-1000x1000_q2Avp5W.jpg);"&gt;&lt;span class="h-u-visually-hidden"&gt;A carousel that shows three research insights about consumer behavior in Google feeds&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption class="article-carousel__caption h-c-grid__col h-c-grid__col--10 h-c-grid__col-l--8 h-c-grid__col--offset-1 h-c-grid__col-l--offset-2"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="9tqcf"&gt;Source: Google/Ipsos, Consumer Feed Behavior Research, August 2022&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;div class="h-c-carousel__paginate glue-pagination-previous uni-click-tracker" data-analytics='{
            "event": "page interaction",
            "category": "interaction",
            "action": "image carousel",
            "label": "arrow - left click"
           }' data-glue-pagination-label="Previous" data-glue-pagination-update-model="false"&gt;&lt;div class="h-c-carousel__paginate-wrap"&gt;&lt;svg class="h-c-icon h-c-icon--keyboard-arrow-left" role="img"&gt;&lt;use xlink:href="#mi-keyboard-arrow-right"&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="h-c-carousel__paginate glue-pagination-next uni-click-tracker" data-analytics='{
            "event": "page interaction",
            "category": "interaction",
            "action": "image carousel",
            "label": "arrow - right click"
           }' data-glue-pagination-label="Next" data-glue-pagination-update-model="false"&gt;&lt;div class="h-c-carousel__paginate-wrap"&gt;&lt;svg class="h-c-icon h-c-icon--keyboard-arrow-right" role="img"&gt;&lt;use xlink:href="#mi-keyboard-arrow-right"&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="h-c-carousel__navigation"&gt;&lt;div class="glue-pagination-page-list uni-click-tracker" data-analytics='{
            "event": "page interaction",
            "category": "interaction",
            "action": "image carousel",
            "label": "arrow - dot click"
           }'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-paragraph"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;h3 data-block-key="2yqti"&gt;1. Create more tailored experiences for deeper engagement&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="fc7ur"&gt;Over half of mobile consumers use Google and YouTube alongside other platforms when researching products or brands to try,&lt;footnote id="722e02a1-56db-4ad8-9528-565e7434dde7"&gt;[722e02]&lt;/footnote&gt;and 91% say they took action immediately after discovering new products or brands.&lt;footnote id="b8e752a3-9551-4f7d-9f92-4df038c6a9ec"&gt;[b8e752]&lt;/footnote&gt;Once they do, consumers also expect brands to deliver experiences that are &lt;b&gt;relevant and helpful&lt;/b&gt;. In fact, two in five say they enjoy exploring Google feeds for shopping ideas because they are more personalized.&lt;footnote id="1fe581d7-8b90-4dd1-84e1-b8d7d1165145"&gt;[1fe581]&lt;/footnote&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="7dv7u"&gt;With &lt;b&gt;product feeds for Discovery ads&lt;/b&gt; now &lt;a href="https://support.google.com/google-ads/answer/12561938"&gt;available&lt;/a&gt; in beta, advertisers can show shoppers items based on their interests and intent. Specifically, individual retailers can now use lifestyle images and short text with their Google Merchant Center catalog to deliver more relevant ad experiences. For example, a consumer interested in fitness and fashion might see sneakers in a variety of colors and styles from a new brand in their content feed on YouTube or the Google app.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-image_full_width"&gt;&lt;div class="h-c-page"&gt;&lt;div class="article-image__is-caption h-c-grid__col--10 h-c-grid__col--offset-1 h-c-grid__col-l--offset-2 h-c-grid__col-l--8"&gt;&lt;a class="article-image--link"&gt;&lt;video alt="Discovery Puma" autoplay="" class="article-image__media" loop="" muted="" playsinline="" src="https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/original_videos/FINAL_MP4_Discovery3Panel_Puma_1022.mp4" tabindex="0" title="An animated visual that shows an example of PUMA’s ads across YouTube, Discover and Gmail" type="video/mp4"&gt;Video format not supported&lt;/video&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption class="article-image__caption article-image__is-caption-image h-c-grid__col--8 h-c-grid__col--offset-2 h-c-grid__col-l--6 h-c-grid__col-l--offset-3"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="odgfp"&gt;An example of ads for Puma across YouTube, Discover, and Gmail.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-paragraph"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="0srhm"&gt;Puma switched to product feeds from standard Discovery ads to promote its catalog during key seasons, and saw a +46% increase in return-on-ad-spend while lowering costs by 19%. “Product feeds for Discovery ads offered more ways to expand our social-style assets across new platforms,” says Ashley Anderson, Senior Director of Digital Marketing at Puma. “Personalization and great performance made it easy to efficiently scale our spend.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="8dc8o"&gt;For tips to help you craft engaging Discovery ads with product feeds, see our &lt;a href="https://support.google.com/google-ads/answer/10547315"&gt;creative best practices&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-paragraph"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;h3 data-block-key="2yqti"&gt;2. Take an asset-first approach for bigger creative impact&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="483tb"&gt;Keeping today's consumer engaged across platforms requires creative finesse at scale—and a multi-asset approach for campaigns like social and video to enable more visual and authentic storytelling. Nearly half of consumers say they are more likely to purchase a new product or brand they see in a video ad.&lt;footnote id="1adffc2a-74c8-47f8-bd77-bd83ece5995d"&gt;[1adffc]&lt;/footnote&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="56bet"&gt;You can now scale your assets to &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/creators/shorts/"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Shorts&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, YouTube's new short-form video experience, to drive visual momentum with consumers watching everything from workout clips to recipe walkthroughs. You can make the most of this mobile canvas by bringing your best vertical video and image assets to the Shorts experience with Video action and now Discovery campaigns for images.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="6dqf5"&gt;We've seen this asset-first creative approach across campaigns drive better results: more than 60% of advertisers who combine Video action campaigns with Discovery ads see incremental conversions at or below their original cost-per-action.&lt;footnote id="e34b9273-f192-4b33-87ee-9c259d45c78e"&gt;[e34b92]&lt;/footnote&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-paragraph_with_image"&gt;&lt;div class="article-module h-c-page"&gt;&lt;div class="h-c-grid uni-paragraph-wrap"&gt;&lt;div class="uni-paragraph h-c-grid__col h-c-grid__col--8 h-c-grid__col-m--6 h-c-grid__col-l--6 h-c-grid__col--offset-2 h-c-grid__col-m--offset-3 h-c-grid__col-l--offset-3" data-component="uni-article-paragraph"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-image_full_width"&gt;&lt;div class="h-c-page"&gt;&lt;div class="article-image__is-caption h-c-grid__col-l--6 h-c-grid__col--8 h-c-grid__col-l--offset-3 h-c-grid__col--offset-2"&gt;&lt;a class="article-image--link"&gt;&lt;img alt="An image that shows the research insight about consumers’ preference for authentic and diverse creative" class="article-image--large" data-loading='{
                "mobile": "https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/new_E02802031_Google_BPM_Ipsos_Consumer_Insi.max-500x500.jpg",
                "desktop": "https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/new_E02802031_Google_BPM_Ipsos_Consumer_In.max-1000x1000.jpg"
              }' loading="lazy" src=" https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/new_E02802031_Google_BPM_Ipsos_Consumer_Insi.max-100x100.jpg " tabindex="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption class="article-image__caption article-image__is-caption-image h-c-grid__col--8 h-c-grid__col--offset-2 h-c-grid__col-l--6 h-c-grid__col-l--offset-3"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="s4bpr"&gt;Source: Google/Ipsos, Consumer Feed Behavior Research, August 2022&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-paragraph"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;h3 data-block-key="ylobm"&gt;3. Upgrade your storytelling with authentic and diverse representation&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="593a5"&gt;And last, but not least: building assets to scale doesn't have to mean relying on stock photos and generic visuals. 43% of consumers say that they are more likely to click on ads featuring people from a variety of backgrounds,&lt;footnote id="bd5d5d14-087b-4c11-a335-dfe9e7b5416c"&gt;[bd5d5d]&lt;/footnote&gt;and over half say that they are more likely to click on ads that feature people using a product.&lt;footnote id="094bee3b-05d5-436b-99f2-230ee8ac224b"&gt;[094bee]&lt;/footnote&gt;For the biggest impact with your audience, frame your visuals and calls to action around the wide variety of consumers who reflect your market.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="e7d2b"&gt;We're committed to helping you build more helpful and relevant ads that help consumers engage with your business. Check out our latest tools and resources below to learn how you can:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li data-block-key="a45h3"&gt;Build compelling creative variations at scale with &lt;a href="https://adscreativestudio.google.com/nav/selectaccount?authuser=0&amp;amp;pli=1"&gt;Ads Creative Studio&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li data-block-key="2q8pk"&gt;Adapt your existing assets for YouTube Shorts with our &lt;a href="https://ads.google.com/aw/video/builder"&gt;video creation&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://ads.google.com/aw/video/autotrim"&gt;enhancement tools&lt;/a&gt; available in the &lt;a href="https://support.google.com/google-ads/answer/11898516"&gt;Asset Library&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li data-block-key="856gk"&gt;Finally, get richer creative insights to help you optimize your assets for better performance with &lt;a href="https://support.google.com/google-ads/answer/2454049"&gt;asset reporting&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://support.google.com/google-ads/answer/11372871"&gt;audience asset insights&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="aou82"&gt;We hope these insights and creative tools help you drive growth now and in the new year with more effective, engaging ads.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.google/products/ads-commerce/engage-audience-in-content-driven-world/</guid><category>Display Ads</category><category>Google Ads</category><category>Video Ads</category><media:content height="540" url="https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/E02802031_Google_BPM_Ipsos_Consumer_Insights.max-600x600_2V8GxyF.jpg" width="540"/><og xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#"><type>article</type><title>3 ways to keep audiences engaged in a content-driven world</title><description>Learn the latest insights on what keeps consumers engaged in the digital world today, and explore the creative potential that Google offers.</description><image>https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/E02802031_Google_BPM_Ipsos_Consumer_Insights.max-600x600_2V8GxyF.jpg</image><site_name>Google</site_name><url>https://blog.google/products/ads-commerce/engage-audience-in-content-driven-world/</url></og><author xmlns:author="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><name>Arthur Gerigk</name><title>Sr. Director of Product Management</title><department/><company/></author></item><item><title>Telling powerful African stories through color</title><link>https://blog.google/outreach-initiatives/arts-culture/telling-powerful-african-stories-through-color/</link><description>&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;div class="block-paragraph"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="yvx7l"&gt;African culture is joyful, expressive and vivid, and intrinsically linked to color – from rallying shades of liberation to evocative hues of optimism, color is embraced as an unspoken language. With a vibrant palette and gift for storytelling, as Africans, we tell powerful stories through color, and it is this unique phenomenon that led to the development of the ‘&lt;a href="https://goo.gle/coloursofafrica"&gt;Colors of Africa&lt;/a&gt;’ project. This ambitious initiative shares stories from Africa by Africans.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="c2l4l"&gt;Design Indaba collaborated with Google Arts &amp;amp; Culture on this brand-new, cross-continental project. In order to tell the full story of such a diverse continent, we approached 60 African creatives and asked them each to create a unique work that depicts their home country through the symbolism of color.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="17o8t"&gt;At the same time we asked what being African meant to them. The resulting works and thoughts offer personal insights into African lived experience and add the &lt;a href="https://artsandculture.google.com/experiment/qQG6gURIKJ0Rfg"&gt;ever evolving kaleidoscope&lt;/a&gt; that is the African continent.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="t30v"&gt;The stories of each creative have been woven into a colorful tapestry which is available on &lt;a href="https://artsandculture.google.com/project/colours-of-africa"&gt;Google Arts &amp;amp; Culture&lt;/a&gt;. And this bespoke, online exhibit dives into the artist’s experience of their country – as well as navigating the intricacies of life as an African. In addition to the exhibits, you can spin the kaleidoscope to explore and collect the colors of Africa. Experience the different countries and travel through Africa guided by the eyes of local artists.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="7heb6"&gt;Each work is a personal and completely unique experience of a country. Discover some of the colors of Africa below:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-image_carousel"&gt;&lt;div class="h-c-page article-module" data-component="uni-image-carousel"&gt;&lt;div class="article-module glue-pagination h-c-carousel h-c-carousel--simple h-c-carousel--dark ng-cloak" data-glue-pagination-config="{cyclical: true}"&gt;&lt;div class="h-c-carousel__wrap"&gt;&lt;ul class="glue-carousel ng-cloak" data-glue-carousel-options="{pointerTypes: ['touch', 'mouse'], jump: true}"&gt;&lt;li class="h-c-carousel__item article-carousel__slide"&gt;&lt;figure class="h-c-grid"&gt;&lt;div aria-label="Photo of artwork by Kenyan fashion designer Anyango Mpinga showing a many shaded purple dress in a large bell jar against a purple background of the same abstract print" class="article-carousel__slide-img h-c-grid__col h-c-grid__col--10 h-c-grid__col--offset-1" data-loading='{
                      "mobile": "https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/image-_wEvPMb3yoIAXg-large_1.max-1000x1000.jpg",
                      "desktop": "https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/image-_wEvPMb3yoIAXg-large_1.max-2000x2000.jpg"
                    }' style="background-image: url(https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/image-_wEvPMb3yoIAXg-large_1.max-200x200.jpg);"&gt;&lt;span class="h-u-visually-hidden"&gt;Photo of artwork by Kenyan fashion designer Anyango Mpinga showing a many shaded purple dress in a large bell jar against a purple background of the same abstract print&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption class="article-carousel__caption h-c-grid__col h-c-grid__col--10 h-c-grid__col-l--8 h-c-grid__col--offset-1 h-c-grid__col-l--offset-2"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="p2dnp"&gt;&lt;a href="https://artsandculture.google.com/asset/IQG0DzHDTcF4_Q"&gt;30 Shades of Purple&lt;/a&gt; by Kenyan fashion designer Anyango Mpinga&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li class="h-c-carousel__item article-carousel__slide"&gt;&lt;figure class="h-c-grid"&gt;&lt;div aria-label="Image showing a woman writing in a notebook, which is a still from a video by Egyptian artist Ghada Wali titled Red Cairo Rides where she takes viewers on a trip into Cairo and all  its complexities and contradictions, through a red lens." class="article-carousel__slide-img h-c-grid__col h-c-grid__col--10 h-c-grid__col--offset-1" style="background-image: url(https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/GW3_b42UjQq.max-2000x2000.png);"&gt;&lt;span class="h-u-visually-hidden"&gt;Image showing a woman writing in a notebook, which is a still from a video by Egyptian artist Ghada Wali titled Red Cairo Rides where she takes viewers on a trip into Cairo and all its complexities and contradictions, through a red lens.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption class="article-carousel__caption h-c-grid__col h-c-grid__col--10 h-c-grid__col-l--8 h-c-grid__col--offset-1 h-c-grid__col-l--offset-2"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="vvdi7"&gt;&lt;a href="https://artsandculture.google.com/preview/asset/BQE-EPJuHuUz5Q"&gt;Red Cairo Rides&lt;/a&gt; by Egyptian artist Ghada Wali (video)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li class="h-c-carousel__item article-carousel__slide"&gt;&lt;figure class="h-c-grid"&gt;&lt;div aria-label="Image of an artwork titled Águ – the color(s) of water by architect Patti Anahoy depicting different shades of blue in a type of pixelated image." class="article-carousel__slide-img h-c-grid__col h-c-grid__col--10 h-c-grid__col--offset-1" style="background-image: url(https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/1_Cabo_Verde_pictures_hwqlhgx.max-800x800.png);"&gt;&lt;span class="h-u-visually-hidden"&gt;Image of an artwork titled Águ – the color(s) of water by architect Patti Anahoy depicting different shades of blue in a type of pixelated image.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption class="article-carousel__caption h-c-grid__col h-c-grid__col--10 h-c-grid__col-l--8 h-c-grid__col--offset-1 h-c-grid__col-l--offset-2"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="vvdi7"&gt;&lt;a href="https://artsandculture.google.com/preview/asset/JgG3J5Tty-qIww"&gt;Águ – the color(s) of water&lt;/a&gt; by architect Patti Anahoy&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li class="h-c-carousel__item article-carousel__slide"&gt;&lt;figure class="h-c-grid"&gt;&lt;div aria-label="Still shot of video artwork by Selim Harbi depicting several nomadic/touareg people playing musical instruments." class="article-carousel__slide-img h-c-grid__col h-c-grid__col--10 h-c-grid__col--offset-1" style="background-image: url(https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/image-LAHISDWvVybLsg-large_1.max-2000x2000.jpg);"&gt;&lt;span class="h-u-visually-hidden"&gt;Still shot of video artwork by Selim Harbi depicting several nomadic/touareg people playing musical instruments.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption class="article-carousel__caption h-c-grid__col h-c-grid__col--10 h-c-grid__col-l--8 h-c-grid__col--offset-1 h-c-grid__col-l--offset-2"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="vfx05"&gt;&lt;a href="https://artsandculture.google.com/preview/asset/LAHISDWvVybLsg"&gt;Colours of the Invisible&lt;/a&gt; by Selim Harbi&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li class="h-c-carousel__item article-carousel__slide"&gt;&lt;figure class="h-c-grid"&gt;&lt;div aria-label="Black and white photo depicting person with white cloth over them and a black background." class="article-carousel__slide-img h-c-grid__col h-c-grid__col--10 h-c-grid__col--offset-1" style="background-image: url(https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/image-lwGghjw_i639SA-large_WoRzq86.max-2000x2000.jpg);"&gt;&lt;span class="h-u-visually-hidden"&gt;Black and white photo depicting person with white cloth over them and a black background.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption class="article-carousel__caption h-c-grid__col h-c-grid__col--10 h-c-grid__col-l--8 h-c-grid__col--offset-1 h-c-grid__col-l--offset-2"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="qx9pu"&gt;&lt;a href="https://artsandculture.google.com/asset/BQH2MBvBHCM1MQ"&gt;White is the Spirit of Sudan&lt;/a&gt; by Sudanese designer Mayada Adil El Sayed&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;div class="h-c-carousel__paginate glue-pagination-previous uni-click-tracker" data-analytics='{
            "event": "page interaction",
            "category": "interaction",
            "action": "image carousel",
            "label": "arrow - left click"
           }' data-glue-pagination-label="Previous" data-glue-pagination-update-model="false"&gt;&lt;div class="h-c-carousel__paginate-wrap"&gt;&lt;svg class="h-c-icon h-c-icon--keyboard-arrow-left" role="img"&gt;&lt;use xlink:href="#mi-keyboard-arrow-right"&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="h-c-carousel__paginate glue-pagination-next uni-click-tracker" data-analytics='{
            "event": "page interaction",
            "category": "interaction",
            "action": "image carousel",
            "label": "arrow - right click"
           }' data-glue-pagination-label="Next" data-glue-pagination-update-model="false"&gt;&lt;div class="h-c-carousel__paginate-wrap"&gt;&lt;svg class="h-c-icon h-c-icon--keyboard-arrow-right" role="img"&gt;&lt;use xlink:href="#mi-keyboard-arrow-right"&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="h-c-carousel__navigation"&gt;&lt;div class="glue-pagination-page-list uni-click-tracker" data-analytics='{
            "event": "page interaction",
            "category": "interaction",
            "action": "image carousel",
            "label": "arrow - dot click"
           }'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-paragraph"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="n1yjc"&gt;I invite you to discover more about each artist and artwork on the &lt;a href="https://artsandculture.google.com/project/colours-of-africa"&gt;dedicated hub&lt;/a&gt; on Google Arts &amp;amp; Culture, or travel through the kaleidoscope &lt;a href="https://artsandculture.google.com/experiment/qQG6gURIKJ0Rfg"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and share your colors with the world.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.google/outreach-initiatives/arts-culture/telling-powerful-african-stories-through-color/</guid><category>Arts &amp; Culture</category><category>Google in Africa</category><og xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#"><type>article</type><title>Telling powerful African stories through color</title><description>Design Indaba curates a new project on Google Arts &amp; Culture called ‘Colors of Africa’, a project of 60 specially-curated artworks which have been produced by 60 leading African creatives. Each creative has been  invited to contribute a work that captures the colour and character of their home country.</description><site_name>Google</site_name><url>https://blog.google/outreach-initiatives/arts-culture/telling-powerful-african-stories-through-color/</url></og><author xmlns:author="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><name>Ravi Naidoo</name><title>Founder &amp; CEO, Design Indaba</title><department/><company/></author></item><item><title>Easily track your packages with new Gmail features</title><link>https://blog.google/products/gmail/package-tracking/</link><description>&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;div class="block-paragraph"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="0kvti"&gt;Does this scenario sound familiar? You spend hours shopping for the perfect gift, &lt;a href="https://blog.google/products/shopping/holiday-shopping-deals"&gt;find a great deal&lt;/a&gt; and place the order. And as you wait for your package to arrive, you end up repeating the same steps: searching your inbox for the confirmation email, finding the tracking number and following a string of links to see your delivery status.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="v908"&gt;With the holiday season coming up fast, it won’t be long before your inbox is filled with more order and shipping confirmations, tracking numbers and even the occasional delay notification. So this year, Gmail is introducing new features to help you save time and stay on top of all your shipments.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="d37n8"&gt;In the coming weeks, Gmail will show a simple, helpful view of your package tracking and delivery information right in your inbox. For orders with tracking numbers, Gmail will prominently display your current delivery status in your inbox list view and in a summary card at the top of individual emails. Package tracking will be available across most major U.S. shipping carriers and will provide important details at a glance, such as estimated arrival date and status — like “Label created,” “Arriving tomorrow” or “Delivered today.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-image_full_width"&gt;&lt;div class="h-c-page"&gt;&lt;div class="article-image h-c-grid__col-l--4 h-c-grid__col--6 h-c-grid__col-l--offset-4 h-c-grid__col--offset-3"&gt;&lt;a class="article-image--link"&gt;&lt;img alt="A mobile view of a Gmail inbox showing an email from “TinkerTot Toys” with a delivery label. The email opens to show a summary card at the top with a “Shipped” delivery status." class="article-image--medium" src=" https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/original_images/PTGTMgif.gif " tabindex="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-paragraph"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="0kvti"&gt;You can opt in to receive package tracking updates right from your inbox or in Gmail settings. Gmail will then automatically look up order statuses using your tracking numbers and surface them in your inbox. You can opt out at any time through your Gmail settings.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-image_full_width"&gt;&lt;div class="h-c-page"&gt;&lt;div class="article-image h-c-grid__col-l--4 h-c-grid__col--6 h-c-grid__col-l--offset-4 h-c-grid__col--offset-3"&gt;&lt;a class="article-image--link"&gt;&lt;img alt="A mobile view of Gmail shows the option to opt in to track packages in Gmail." class="article-image--medium" data-loading='{
                "mobile": "https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/OPt_inTL_GTM_TTT_short.max-500x500.png",
                "desktop": "https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/OPt_inTL_GTM_TTT_short.max-1000x1000.png"
              }' loading="lazy" src=" https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/OPt_inTL_GTM_TTT_short.max-100x100.png " tabindex="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-paragraph"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="0kvti"&gt;We also know how it feels to be waiting on a package, only to discover that it was delayed. In the coming months, Gmail will help eliminate some of that surprise. It’ll proactively show a delay label and bring the email to the top of your inbox so you don’t miss a beat (or a package).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="475hi"&gt;There’s a lot to keep track of during the holidays. But with these new features, and even more to come in Gmail, we hope to cross at least one of those to-do’s off your list — so you can spend less time waiting by the door and more time celebrating with your loved ones.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2022 16:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.google/products/gmail/package-tracking/</guid><category>Shopping</category><category>Gmail</category><media:content height="540" url="https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/GettyImages-1149029937.max-600x600.jpg" width="540"/><og xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#"><type>article</type><title>Easily track your packages with new Gmail features</title><description>New Gmail features make it easier to track your packages.</description><image>https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/GettyImages-1149029937.max-600x600.jpg</image><site_name>Google</site_name><url>https://blog.google/products/gmail/package-tracking/</url></og><author xmlns:author="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><name>Ilya Brown</name><title>VP, Product</title><department>Gmail</department><company/></author></item><item><title>How Education Plus keeps schools safe online</title><link>https://blog.google/outreach-initiatives/education/workspace-security-benefits/</link><description>&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;div class="block-paragraph"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="8sj06"&gt;From virtual classes to in-person lessons, the best learning environments may look different. But they have a few things in common: inspiring teachers, engaged students and a safe space to learn.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-paragraph"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="8sj06"&gt;Over the last few years, spurred by COVID-19, millions of new users have come online to collaborate, create and learn. Because we support millions of education users every day, we think a lot about creating safe, digital-learning environments. It's only when users are safe online that learning can begin. It’s why our products are safe and secure by design, and why we continue to invest in this area.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-paragraph"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="8sj06"&gt;We commissioned Forrester Consulting to conduct a Total Economic Impact study around Google Workspace for Education Plus, our most comprehensive edition of Google Workspace for Education. The study took a look at the security, administrative benefits and cost savings associated with it, and this is what it found: Education Plus helps reduce cyber threats, and the time to remediate them, for educational institutions worldwide.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-paragraph"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="8sj06"&gt;Additionally, Forrester found organizations using Education Plus were more efficient in administration, and eliminated the need to invest in other education technology providers. You can download &lt;a href="https://lp.cloudplatformonline.com/Gated-TEI-Report.html?utm_source=5d_the_keyword&amp;amp;utm_medium=blog&amp;amp;utm_campaign=FY22-Q4-global-bypass-other-dl-Education-Plus-web-launches-security-blog&amp;amp;utm_content=-&amp;amp;utm_term=-"&gt;The Total Economic Impact Study&lt;/a&gt; to read the entire report, and we’ve included some highlights below:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-paragraph"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li data-block-key="8sj06"&gt;&lt;b&gt;95% reduction in phishing incidents:&lt;/b&gt; Security and email filtering in Education Plus reduces phishing attempts by 95%, allowing IT staff to focus less on mitigating threats and more on optimizing security.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li data-block-key="a5tpq"&gt;&lt;b&gt;98% less time addressing phishing attacks:&lt;/b&gt; Quickly prevent, detect and remediate security incidents with our investigation tool. Email filtering in Education Plus helps IT staff focus on optimization instead of obstacles.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li data-block-key="8oj60"&gt;&lt;b&gt;300 hours saved annually on administrative tasks:&lt;/b&gt; Education Plus helps administrators produce administrative, educational and security reports up to 80% faster with the investigation tool and Vault.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li data-block-key="93m65"&gt;&lt;b&gt;$73,000 in time saved from improved security:&lt;/b&gt; The time usually spent searching for and deleting phishing emails and resolving incidents saved 35 weeks of IT time.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-paragraph"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;h3 data-block-key="8sj06"&gt;Get hands-on with Education Plus, and&lt;br/&gt; understand the impact&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-paragraph"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="8sj06"&gt;Want to see how Education Plus could benefit your organization? Check out our new &lt;a href="https://edu.google.com/workspace-for-education/editions/education-plus/roi-calculator?utm_source=5d_the_keyword&amp;amp;utm_medium=blog&amp;amp;utm_campaign=FY22-Q4-global-bypass-other-dl-Education-Plus-web-launches-security-blog&amp;amp;utm_content=-&amp;amp;utm_term=-"&gt;Education Plus Impact Calculator&lt;/a&gt; to calculate potential benefits and cost savings. Simply answer a set of 10 questions and you’ll receive a downloadable, custom impact report for your institution.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-image_full_width"&gt;&lt;div class="h-c-page"&gt;&lt;div class="article-image h-c-grid__col-l--6 h-c-grid__col--8 h-c-grid__col-l--offset-3 h-c-grid__col--offset-2"&gt;&lt;a class="article-image--link"&gt;&lt;img alt="Gif of Google Workspace for Education Plus impact calculator. The user answers four administrative efficiency questions and sees a monetary amount on the next screen of how much they could save in collaboration costs." class="article-image--large" src=" https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/original_images/Calculator.gif " tabindex="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-paragraph"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="8sj06"&gt;And whether you’re just learning about Education Plus or an existing customer, we’re announcing a new &lt;a href="https://edu.google.com/workspace-for-education/interactive-demos?utm_source=5d_the_keyword&amp;amp;utm_medium=blog&amp;amp;utm_campaign=FY-Qr-campaignname_cta.&amp;amp;utm_content=-&amp;amp;utm_term=-"&gt;product demo experience&lt;/a&gt; for the premium features of Google Workspace for Education. Available to anyone, experience the real product interface and how your institution could use premium features including the investigation tool, security dashboard, advanced admin controls, Google Meet and originality reports.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-image_full_width"&gt;&lt;div class="h-c-page"&gt;&lt;div class="article-image h-c-grid__col-l--6 h-c-grid__col--8 h-c-grid__col-l--offset-3 h-c-grid__col--offset-2"&gt;&lt;a class="article-image--link"&gt;&lt;img alt="Gif of Google Workspace for Education Plus product demo focused on Google Meet. The user sees a Google Meet interface, and is prompted to use the “Q&amp;amp;A” feature to ask a question to the rest of the Meet attendees." class="article-image--large" src=" https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/original_images/Demos.gif " tabindex="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-paragraph"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="8sj06"&gt;Ready to create a safer digital learning experience for your school? Learn more and calculate the potential benefits and cost savings with our &lt;a href="https://edu.google.com/workspace-for-education/editions/education-plus/roi-calculator?utm_source=5d_the_keyword&amp;amp;utm_medium=blog&amp;amp;utm_campaign=FY22-Q4-global-bypass-other-dl-Education-Plus-web-launches-security-blog&amp;amp;utm_content=-&amp;amp;utm_term=-"&gt;Education Plus Impact Calculator&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://edu.google.com/workspace-for-education/interactive-demos?utm_source=5d_the_keyword&amp;amp;utm_medium=blog&amp;amp;utm_campaign=FY-Qr-campaignname_cta.&amp;amp;utm_content=-&amp;amp;utm_term=-"&gt;product demo experience&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2022 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.google/outreach-initiatives/education/workspace-security-benefits/</guid><category>Education</category><category>Google Workspace</category><category>Safety &amp; Security</category><media:content height="540" url="https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/Blog_Header_RKNfQWi.max-600x600.png" width="540"/><og xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#"><type>article</type><title>How Education Plus keeps schools safe online</title><description>Education Plus helps to strengthen security, simplify management and improve collaboration.</description><image>https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/Blog_Header_RKNfQWi.max-600x600.png</image><site_name>Google</site_name><url>https://blog.google/outreach-initiatives/education/workspace-security-benefits/</url></og><author xmlns:author="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><name>Devin Regis</name><title>Google Workspace for Education team</title><department/><company/></author></item><item><title>Google’s new Viger office is an homage to Montréal</title><link>https://blog.google/inside-google/company-announcements/googles-new-viger-office-is-an-homage-to-montreal/</link><description>&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;div class="block-paragraph"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="lwlvn"&gt;Google first laid down roots in Québec in 2004, when three engineers worked out of shared coworking spaces no larger than vestibules — including me, I’m employee number five in Montréal! Over the years Google expanded. For many years, we called McGill College home, and it became a place where team members shared milestones, forged community and built software that touches the lives of so many in Québec and around the globe.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-paragraph"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="lwlvn"&gt;Today, we’re proud to continue our commitment as we enter a new frontier for Google in Québec, by celebrating the official opening of Google Montréal Viger. Viger is a sustainability-focused office located in downtown Montréal, on the periphery of the city’s beloved Old Port. &lt;b&gt;We’re also announcing $2.75 million towards Québec’s tech ecosystem and digital skills training.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-paragraph"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="lwlvn"&gt;The new office is home to a variety of teams that work on some of the most crucial products and services Google offers worldwide, including cybersecurity, AI research, Chrome and Cloud.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="8ckoc"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-paragraph"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;h3 data-block-key="lwlvn"&gt;Explore Google Montréal’s Viger space&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-paragraph"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="lwlvn"&gt;Montréal is often referred to as a medley of neighbourhoods, each with its own distinct identity. The retrofitted historical building pays homage to Montréal by reflecting the essence of five of the city’s most beloved neighbourhoods — Little Italy, Le Village, Le Plateau, Chinatown and Old Port. Every inch of the office celebrates the spirit of this vibrant city from the &lt;i&gt;Farine Five Roses&lt;/i&gt; style Google Montréal sign when you enter the lobby, to the playful nods, traditional elements and architectural detailing of historic neighborhoods like Chinatown's flock and damask, Little Italy's artisan markets, Old Port's industrial roots, and Le Village's festive spirit.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-image_full_width"&gt;&lt;div class="h-c-page"&gt;&lt;div class="article-image h-c-grid__col--10 h-c-grid__col--offset-1 h-c-grid__col-l--offset-2 h-c-grid__col-l--8"&gt;&lt;a class="article-image--link"&gt;&lt;img alt="interior image of cafeteria" class="article-image--full" data-loading='{
                "mobile": "https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/_Q3A2547-HDR7.max-500x500.jpg",
                "desktop": "https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/_Q3A2547-HDR7.max-1000x1000.jpg"
              }' loading="lazy" src=" https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/_Q3A2547-HDR7.max-100x100.jpg " tabindex="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-paragraph"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="lwlvn"&gt;The building is equipped with the latest LEED Gold sustainability standards, and includes enhanced ventilation that helps conserve energy and sustainably sourced furniture and materials. Throughout the space you can discover carefully curated art from Québec artists, which aims to inspire employees and strengthen connections that Google maintains with local makers. Some of the artists featured include Nadia Myre, a Montréal-based member of the Kitigan Zibi Anishinabeg First Nation, and Bryan Beyung, a street artist and painter born in Montréal into a Chinese-Cambodian refugee family.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-paragraph"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="lwlvn"&gt;To acknowledge Indigenous connection and stewardship to the land where Google Montréal exists, and to help remind Google team members of this history, we named many of our meeting rooms after local tree species in the Kanienʼkéha (Mohawk) language. The name selection process was conducted in consultation with the nearby Mohawk community of Kahnawake. A native Kanienʼkéha speaker helped ensure spellings were correct, and traditions and cultural practices were respected.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-image_full_width"&gt;&lt;div class="h-c-page"&gt;&lt;div class="article-image h-c-grid__col--10 h-c-grid__col--offset-1 h-c-grid__col-l--offset-2 h-c-grid__col-l--8"&gt;&lt;a class="article-image--link"&gt;&lt;img alt="interior area with couches and chairs" class="article-image--full" data-loading='{
                "mobile": "https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/_Q3A2232-HDR7.max-500x500.jpg",
                "desktop": "https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/_Q3A2232-HDR7.max-1000x1000.jpg"
              }' loading="lazy" src=" https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/_Q3A2232-HDR7.max-100x100.jpg " tabindex="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-paragraph"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;h3 data-block-key="lwlvn"&gt;Supporting Québec’s tech ecosystem&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-paragraph"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="lwlvn"&gt;Today, we are also excited to announce a commitment to Québec’s tech ecosystem of over $2.75 million. This funding will support curiosity-driven research that tackles some of the most important 21st century challenges and catalyze Québec’s future digital builders and innovators:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-paragraph"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li data-block-key="lwlvn"&gt;Google Canada is committed to pushing the boundaries of deep learning research and is renewing its collaboration with &lt;a href="https://mila.quebec/en/"&gt;Mila&lt;/a&gt; by providing a $1.5M grant for 2023. The funding will help support fundamental AI research projects in areas like AI for Humanity, climate change and sustainable agriculture. Support will also be provided to increase successful participation of students and faculty from underrepresented groups in computing research careers.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-paragraph"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="lwlvn"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Google.org Support:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-paragraph"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li data-block-key="lwlvn"&gt;To create new opportunities for students across Québec looking to build digital skills, Google.org is providing a grant to &lt;a href="https://digitalmoment.org/"&gt;Digital Moment&lt;/a&gt; (formerly Kids Code Jeunesse) to help their organization launch The Quebec Digital Literacy Project, a program aimed to equip teachers &amp;amp; students in grades 3-12 with digital skills.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li data-block-key="bbu2p"&gt;To help job seekers in Québec gain the technical and digital skills required in the current job market, Google is now offering the &lt;a href="https://www.coursera.org/professional-certificates/gestion-de-projet-de-google"&gt;Project Management&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.coursera.org/professional-certificates/soutien-des-ti-de-google"&gt;IT Support&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://grow.google/intl/fr-CA_ca/"&gt;Google Career Certificates&lt;/a&gt; in French. The courses will be available to the public on Coursera, a global online learning platform. Google.org will also provide a grant to &lt;a href="https://npowercanada.ca/"&gt;NPower Canada&lt;/a&gt; to deliver the Google Career Certificates in Québec. NPower Canada will offer need-based scholarships to the programs that will be distributed through local workforce development nonprofits&lt;a href="https://www.maisondelamitie.ca/"&gt;La Maison de l’Amitié&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://aimcroitqc.org/en/home/"&gt;AIM CROIT&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li data-block-key="dffi"&gt;Google and Google.org are providing additional support to local Québec organizations, like Startup Montreal, Pathways to Education, E2 Adventures, UpstartED, AI4Good Lab and Resilience Montréal. These organizations work to tackle digital skilling, fostering startup communities, STEM education, job training and often support some of Québec’s most underrepresented communities.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-paragraph"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="lwlvn"&gt;For over 16 years, I’ve watched our team in Québec grow and work on some of Google’s most beloved products. Today, I’m proud to continue this journey and expand our commitment to Québec’s tech ecosystem. I look forward to what the next 20 years brings.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2022 14:15:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.google/inside-google/company-announcements/googles-new-viger-office-is-an-homage-to-montreal/</guid><category>Company announcements</category><media:content height="540" url="https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/_Q3A2309-HDR7.max-600x600.jpg" width="540"/><og xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#"><type>article</type><title>Google’s new Viger office is an homage to Montréal</title><description>We're officially opening Google Montréal Viger, a sustainability-focused office located in downtown Montréal.</description><image>https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/_Q3A2309-HDR7.max-600x600.jpg</image><site_name>Google</site_name><url>https://blog.google/inside-google/company-announcements/googles-new-viger-office-is-an-homage-to-montreal/</url></og><author xmlns:author="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><name>Fabrice Jaubert</name><title>Google Montréal Site Lead</title><department/><company/></author></item><item><title>How we're using AI to help address the climate crisis</title><link>https://blog.google/outreach-initiatives/sustainability/cop27-adaptation-efforts/</link><description>&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;div class="block-paragraph"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="wglz8"&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="6d6jq"&gt;Communities around the world are facing the effects of climate change — from devastating floods and wildfires to challenges around food security. As global leaders meet in Egypt for &lt;a href="https://cop27.eg/#/"&gt;COP27&lt;/a&gt;, a key area of focus will be on how we can work together to address the climate change crisis &lt;a href="https://blog.google/outreach-initiatives/sustainability/COP27-Google-climate-action/"&gt;and implement sustainable solutions&lt;/a&gt;. At Google, we’re investing in technologies that can help communities prepare for and respond to climate-related disasters and threats.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 data-block-key="b3tua"&gt;Tools to alert people and governments about immediate risks&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="afqpq"&gt;Natural disasters are increasing in frequency and intensity due to climate change. As part of our &lt;a href="https://crisisresponse.google/"&gt;Crisis Response&lt;/a&gt; efforts, we're working to bring trusted information to people in critical moments to keep them safe and informed. To do so, we rely on the research and development of our AI-powered technologies and longstanding partnerships with frontline emergency workers and organizations. Here’s a look at some of our crisis response efforts and new ways we’re expanding these tools.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li data-block-key="69je"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Floods:&lt;/b&gt; Catastrophic &lt;a href="http://g.co/floods"&gt;damage from flooding&lt;/a&gt; affects more than 250 million people every year. In 2018, we launched our flood &lt;a href="https://blog.google/technology/ai/expanding-our-ml-based-flood-forecasting/"&gt;forecasting initiative&lt;/a&gt; that &lt;a href="https://hess.copernicus.org/articles/26/4013/2022/"&gt;uses machine learning models&lt;/a&gt; to provide people with detailed alerts. In 2021, we sent 115 million flood alert notifications to 23 million people over Search and Maps, helping save countless lives. Today, we’re expanding our flood forecasts to river basins in 18 additional countries across Africa, Latin America and Southeast Asia. We’re also announcing the global launch of the new &lt;a href="http://g.co/floodhub"&gt;FloodHub&lt;/a&gt;, a platform that displays flood forecasts and shows when and where floods may occur to help people directly at risk and provide critical information to aid organizations and governments. This expansion in geographic coverage is possible thanks to our recent breakthroughs in AI-based flood forecasting models, and we’re committed to expanding to more countries.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-image_full_width"&gt;&lt;div class="h-c-page"&gt;&lt;div class="article-image__is-caption h-c-grid__col--10 h-c-grid__col--offset-1 h-c-grid__col-l--offset-2 h-c-grid__col-l--8"&gt;&lt;a class="article-image--link"&gt;&lt;img alt="An image of a FloodHub map showing areas where riverine floods my occur" class="article-image--full" data-loading='{
                "mobile": "https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/Screen_Shot_2022-10-31_at_22.08.32_cuEwOVg.max-500x500.png",
                "desktop": "https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/Screen_Shot_2022-10-31_at_22.08.32_cuEwOVg.max-1000x1000.png"
              }' loading="lazy" src=" https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/Screen_Shot_2022-10-31_at_22.08.32_cuEwOVg.max-100x100.png " tabindex="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption class="article-image__caption article-image__is-caption-image h-c-grid__col--8 h-c-grid__col--offset-2 h-c-grid__col-l--6 h-c-grid__col-l--offset-3"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="ystsf"&gt;The new Google FloodHub at &lt;a href="https://g.co/floodhub"&gt;g.co/floodhub&lt;/a&gt; shows forecasts for riverine floods. Forecasts are now available in 18 additional countries: Brazil, Colombia, Sri Lanka, Burkina Faso, Cameroon, Chad, Democratic Republic of Congo, Ivory Coast, Ghana, Guinea, Malawi, Nigeria, Sierra Leone, Angola, South Sudan, Namibia, Liberia, South Africa.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-paragraph"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="wglz8"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li data-block-key="clrbq"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Wildfires:&lt;/b&gt; Wildfires affect hundreds of thousands of people each year, and are increasing in frequency and size. I &lt;a href="https://blog.google/products/search/mapping-wildfires-with-satellite-data/"&gt;experienced firsthand&lt;/a&gt; the need for accurate information when wildfires occur and this inspired our crisis response work. We detect wildfire boundaries using new AI models based on satellite imagery and show their real-time location in Search and Maps. Since July, we’ve covered more than 30 big wildfire events in the U.S. and Canada, helping inform people and firefighting teams with over 7 million views in Search and Maps. Today, wildfire detection is now available in the U.S., Canada, Mexico and parts of Australia.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-image_full_width"&gt;&lt;div class="h-c-page"&gt;&lt;div class="article-image__is-caption h-c-grid__col-l--6 h-c-grid__col--8 h-c-grid__col-l--offset-3 h-c-grid__col--offset-2"&gt;&lt;a class="article-image--link"&gt;&lt;img alt="Picture shows the location of the Pukatawagan fire in Manitoba, Canada." class="article-image--large" data-loading='{
                "mobile": "https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/boundary_tracking_graphics_1_xGJMBgH.max-500x500.png",
                "desktop": "https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/boundary_tracking_graphics_1_xGJMBgH.max-1000x1000.png"
              }' loading="lazy" src=" https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/boundary_tracking_graphics_1_xGJMBgH.max-100x100.png " tabindex="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption class="article-image__caption article-image__is-caption-image h-c-grid__col--8 h-c-grid__col--offset-2 h-c-grid__col-l--6 h-c-grid__col-l--offset-3"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="ystsf"&gt;The location of the Pukatawagan fire in Manitoba, Canada.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-paragraph"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li data-block-key="wglz8"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Hurricanes:&lt;/b&gt; Access to authoritative forecasts and safety information about hurricanes can be life-saving. In the days before a hurricane in North America or a typhoon in Japan, &lt;a href="https://crisisresponse.google/forecasting-and-alerts/"&gt;detailed forecasts&lt;/a&gt; from authoritative sources appear on &lt;a href="https://support.google.com/sosalerts/?hl=en"&gt;SOS Alerts&lt;/a&gt; in Search and Maps to show a storm’s predicted trajectory. We're also using machine learning to &lt;a href="https://ai.googleblog.com/2020/06/machine-learning-based-damage.html"&gt;analyze satellite imagery&lt;/a&gt; after disasters and identify which areas need help. When Hurricane Ian hit Florida in September, this technology was &lt;a href="https://www.wired.com/story/hurricane-ian-destroyed-homes-google-algorithms-sent-money/"&gt;deployed in partnership with Google.org grantee GiveDirectly&lt;/a&gt; to quickly allocate aid to those most affected.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3 data-block-key="eie89"&gt;Managing current and future climate impacts&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="4u6mn"&gt;Climate change poses a threat to our world's natural resources and food security. We’re working with governments, organizations and communities to provide information and technologies to help address these changes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li data-block-key="1j8bv"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Keeping cities greener and healthier:&lt;/b&gt; Extreme temperatures and poor air quality are increasingly common in cities and can impact public health. To mitigate this, our &lt;a href="https://blog.google/outreach-initiatives/sustainability/sustainability-2021/"&gt;Project Green Light&lt;/a&gt; uses AI to optimize traffic lights at intersections around the world with the aim to help minimize congestion and related pollution. &lt;a href="https://www.google.com/earth/outreach/special-projects/air-quality/"&gt;Project Air View&lt;/a&gt; also brings detailed air quality maps to scientists, policymakers and communities. And we’re working to expand our Environmental Insights Explorer’s &lt;a href="https://insights.sustainability.google/labs/treecanopy"&gt;Tree Canopy Insights&lt;/a&gt; tool to hundreds of cities by the end of this year so they can use &lt;a href="https://www.epa.gov/heatislands/using-trees-and-vegetation-reduce-heat-islands"&gt;trees to lower street-level temperatures&lt;/a&gt; and improve quality of life.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li data-block-key="b19bb"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Meeting the world’s growing demand for food:&lt;/b&gt; &lt;a href="https://mineral.ai/"&gt;Mineral&lt;/a&gt; — a project from X, Alphabet’s moonshot factory — is working to build a more sustainable and productive food system. The team is joining diverse data sets in radically new ways — from soil and weather data to drone and satellite images — and using AI to reveal insights never before possible about what’s happening with crops. As part of our &lt;a href="http://g.co/startups/sdg"&gt;Startups For Sustainable Development&lt;/a&gt; program, we’re also supporting startups addressing food security. These include startups like &lt;a href="https://events.withgoogle.com/startups-for-sustainable-development/oko/"&gt;OKO,&lt;/a&gt; which provides crop insurance to keep farmers in business in case of adverse weather events and has reached tens of thousands of farmers in Mali and Uganda.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li data-block-key="bhjpg"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Helping farmers protect their crops:&lt;/b&gt; Pest infestations can threaten entire crops and impact the livelihoods of millions. In collaboration with InstaDeep and the Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations, our team at the Google AI Center in Ghana is using AI to better detect locust outbreaks so that it's possible to implement control measures. In India, Google.org Fellows worked with &lt;a href="https://www.wadhwaniai.org/"&gt;Wadhwani AI&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href="https://www.fastcompany.com/90640843/google-is-helping-deploy-ai-to-prevent-pests-devastating-indian-crops"&gt;create an AI-powered app&lt;/a&gt; that helps identify and treat infestations of pests, resulting in a 20% reduction in pesticide sprays and a 26% increase in profit margins for farmers. Google Cloud is also &lt;a href="https://blog.google/products/google-cloud/helping-farmers-with-cloud-technology-up-close-and-global/"&gt;working with agricultural technology companies&lt;/a&gt; to use machine learning and cloud services to improve crop yields.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li data-block-key="1a1ks"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Analyzing a changing planet:&lt;/b&gt; Using Google Cloud and Google Earth Engine, organizations and businesses can better assess and manage climate risks. For example, &lt;a href="https://cloud.google.com/blog/topics/sustainability/how-the-us-forest-service-uses-google-cloud"&gt;the U.S. Forest Service&lt;/a&gt; uses these tools to analyze land-cover changes to better respond to new wildfire threats and monitor the impacts of invasive insects, diseases and droughts. Similarly, the Bank of Montreal is &lt;a href="https://sustainabilityleaders.bmo.com/en/news-insights/sustainable-finance/mitigating-physical-impacts-climate-change-spatial-finance/"&gt;integrating climate data&lt;/a&gt; — like precipitation trends — into its business strategy and risk management for clients.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="f83l4"&gt;AI already plays a critical role in addressing many urgent, climate-related challenges. It is important that we continue to invest in research and raise awareness about why we are doing this work. Google Arts &amp;amp; Culture has collaborated with artists on the &lt;a href="http://g.co/culturemeetsclimate"&gt;Culture meets Climate&lt;/a&gt; collection so everyone can explore more perspectives on climate change. And at COP27 we hope to generate more awareness and engage in productive discussions about how to use AI, innovations, and &lt;a href="https://www.datacommons.org/"&gt;shared data&lt;/a&gt; to help global communities address the changing climate.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-perspective_qa"&gt;&lt;div class="uni-related-article-tout h-c-page" data-component="uni-related-article-tout"&gt;&lt;section class="h-c-grid"&gt;&lt;a class="uni-related-article-tout__wrapper h-c-grid__col h-c-grid__col--8 h-c-grid__col-m--6 h-c-grid__col-l--6 h-c-grid__col--offset-2 h-c-grid__col-m--offset-3 h-c-grid__col-l--offset-3 uni-click-tracker" data-analytics='{
                      "event": "page interaction",
                      "category": "article lead",
                      "action": "related article - inline",
                      "label": "article: cop27-google-climate-action"
                    }' href="https://blog.google/outreach-initiatives/sustainability/cop27-google-climate-action/"&gt;&lt;div class="uni-related-article-tout__inner-wrapper"&gt;&lt;p class="uni-related-article-tout__eyebrow h-c-eyebrow"&gt;Related Article&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="uni-related-article-tout__content-wrapper"&gt;&lt;div class="uni-related-article-tout__image-wrapper"&gt;&lt;div class="uni-related-article-tout__image" data-loading='{
              "mobile": "https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/EUE-APW-120721-953-Edit.max-500x500.jpg",
              "desktop": "https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/EUE-APW-120721-953-Edit.max-500x500.jpg"
            }' style="background-image: url('https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/EUE-APW-120721-953-Edit.max-100x100.jpg')"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="uni-related-article-tout__content"&gt;&lt;h4 class="uni-related-article-tout__header h-has-bottom-margin"&gt;Accelerating climate action at Google and beyond&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p class="uni-related-article-tout__body"&gt;A new paper we published today shares updates on the work we have been doing as part of our third decade of climate action.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="cta module-cta h-c-copy uni-related-article-tout__cta muted"&gt;&lt;span class="nowrap"&gt;Read Article&lt;svg class="icon h-c-icon" role="presentation"&gt;&lt;use xlink:href="#mi-arrow-forward" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/section&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2022 14:05:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.google/outreach-initiatives/sustainability/cop27-adaptation-efforts/</guid><category>Sustainability</category><category>AI</category><media:content height="540" url="https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/V1-0016_E002C005_190621DR_NY813.00000256_1.max-600x600.jpg" width="540"/><og xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#"><type>article</type><title>How we're using AI to help address the climate crisis</title><description>Here’s a look at how we’re investing in technologies to help communities prepare for and respond to climate-related disasters and threats.</description><image>https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/V1-0016_E002C005_190621DR_NY813.00000256_1.max-600x600.jpg</image><site_name>Google</site_name><url>https://blog.google/outreach-initiatives/sustainability/cop27-adaptation-efforts/</url></og><author xmlns:author="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><name>Yossi Matias</name><title>VP Engineering &amp; Research and Crisis Response Lead</title><department/><company/></author></item><item><title>3 ways AI is scaling helpful technologies worldwide</title><link>https://blog.google/technology/ai/ways-ai-is-scaling-helpful/</link><description>&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;div class="block-paragraph"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="c7r58"&gt;I was first introduced to neural networks as an undergraduate in 1990. Back then, many people in the AI community were excited about the potential of neural networks, which were impressive, but couldn’t yet accomplish important, real-world tasks. I was excited, too! I did my senior thesis on using parallel computation to train neural networks, thinking we only needed 32X more compute power to get there. I was &lt;i&gt;way&lt;/i&gt; off. At that time, we needed &lt;i&gt;1 million times&lt;/i&gt; as much computational power.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-paragraph"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="c7r58"&gt;A short 21 years later, with exponentially more computational power, it was time to take another crack at neural networks. In 2011, I and a few others at Google started training very large neural networks using millions of randomly selected frames from videos online. The results were &lt;a href="https://blog.google/technology/ai/using-large-scale-brain-simulations-for/"&gt;remarkable&lt;/a&gt;. Without explicit training, the system automatically learned to recognize different objects (especially cats, the Internet is full of cats). This was one transformational discovery in AI among a long string of successes that is still ongoing — at Google and elsewhere.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-paragraph"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="c7r58"&gt;I share my own history of neural networks to illustrate that, while progress in AI might feel especially fast right now, it’s come from a long arc of progress. In fact, prior to 2012, computers had a really difficult time seeing, hearing, or understanding spoken or written language. Over the past 10 years we’ve made especially &lt;a href="https://blog.google/technology/ai/decade-deep-learning-and-whats-next/"&gt;rapid progress in AI&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-paragraph"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="c7r58"&gt;Today, we’re excited about many recent advances in AI that Google is leading — not just on the technical side, but in responsibly deploying it in ways that help people around the world. That means deploying AI &lt;a href="https://cloud.google.com/blog/products/ai-machine-learning"&gt;in Google Cloud&lt;/a&gt;, in our products from &lt;a href="https://blog.google/intl/en-in/pixel-7-pixel-7-pro/"&gt;Pixel phones&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href="https://blog.google/products/search/search-on-2022-announcements/"&gt;Google Search&lt;/a&gt;, and in many fields of science and other human endeavors.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-paragraph"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="c7r58"&gt;We’re aware of the challenges and risks that AI poses as an emerging technology. We were the first major company to release and operationalize a set of &lt;a href="https://ai.google/principles/"&gt;AI Principles&lt;/a&gt;, and following them has actually (and some might think counterintuitively) allowed us to focus on making rapid progress on technologies that can be helpful to everyone. Getting AI right needs to be a collective effort — involving not just researchers, but domain experts, developers, community members, businesses, governments and citizens.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-paragraph"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="c7r58"&gt;I’m happy to make announcements in three transformative areas of AI today: first, using AI to make technology accessible in many more languages. Second, exploring how AI might bolster creativity. And third, in AI for Social Good, including climate adaptation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="19vk7"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-paragraph"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;h3 data-block-key="c7r58"&gt;1. Supporting 1,000 languages with AI&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-paragraph"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="c7r58"&gt;Language is fundamental to how people communicate and make sense of the world. So it’s no surprise it’s also the most natural way people engage with technology. But more than 7,000 languages are spoken around the world, and only a few are well represented online today. That means traditional approaches to training language models on text from the web fail to capture the diversity of how we communicate globally. This has historically been an obstacle in the pursuit of our mission to make the world’s information universally accessible and useful.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-paragraph"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="c7r58"&gt;That’s why today we’re announcing the 1,000 Languages Initiative, an ambitious commitment to build an AI model that will support the 1,000 most spoken languages, bringing greater inclusion to billions of people in marginalized communities all around the world. This will be a many years undertaking – some may even call it a moonshot – but we are already making meaningful strides here and see the path clearly. Technology has been changing at a rapid clip – from the way people use it to what it’s capable of. Increasingly, we see people finding and sharing information via new modalities like images, videos, and speech. And our most advanced language models are multimodal – meaning they’re capable of unlocking information across these many different formats. With these seismic shifts come new opportunities.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-image_full_width"&gt;&lt;div class="h-c-page"&gt;&lt;div class="article-image h-c-grid__col--10 h-c-grid__col--offset-1 h-c-grid__col-l--offset-2 h-c-grid__col-l--8"&gt;&lt;a class="article-image--link"&gt;&lt;img alt="spinning globe with languages" class="article-image--full" src=" https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/original_images/GoogleAI_GlobeAnimation.gif " tabindex="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-paragraph"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="c7r58"&gt;As part of our this initiative and our focus on multimodality, we’ve developed a Universal Speech Model — or USM — that’s trained on over 400 languages, making it the largest language coverage seen in a speech model to date. As we expand on this work, we’re partnering with communities across the world to source representative speech data. We &lt;a href="https://africa.googleblog.com/2022/10/voice-typing-for-african-languages.html"&gt;recently announced&lt;/a&gt; voice typing for 9 more African languages on Gboard by working closely with researchers and organizations in Africa to create and publish data. And in South Asia, we are actively working with local governments, NGOs, and academic institutions to eventually collect representative audio samples from across all the regions’ dialects and languages.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="eidmd"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-paragraph"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;h3 data-block-key="c7r58"&gt;2. Empowering creators and artists with AI&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-paragraph"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="c7r58"&gt;AI-powered generative models have the potential to unlock creativity, helping people across cultures express themselves using video, imagery, and design in ways that they previously could not.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-paragraph"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="c7r58"&gt;Our researchers have been hard at work developing models that lead the field in terms of quality, generating images that human raters prefer over other models. We recently shared important breakthroughs, applying our diffusion model to video sequences and generating long coherent videos for a sequence of text prompts. We can combine these techniques to produce video — for the first time, today we’re sharing AI-generated super-resolution video:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-image_full_width"&gt;&lt;div class="h-c-page"&gt;&lt;div class="article-image h-c-grid__col--10 h-c-grid__col--offset-1 h-c-grid__col-l--offset-2 h-c-grid__col-l--8"&gt;&lt;a class="article-image--link"&gt;&lt;video alt="Phenaki" autoplay="" class="article-image__media" loop="" muted="" playsinline="" src="https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/original_videos/Google-AI-Phenaki__Imagen-15fps.mp4" tabindex="0" title="AI super generated video" type="video/mp4"&gt;Video format not supported&lt;/video&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-paragraph"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="c7r58"&gt;We’ll soon be bringing our text-to-image generation technologies to AI Test Kitchen, which provides a way for people to learn about, experience, and give feedback on emerging AI technology. We look forward to hearing feedback from users on these demos in AI Test Kitchen Season 2. You’ll be able to build themed cities with “City Dreamer” and design friendly monster characters that can move, dance, and jump with “Wobble” — all by using text prompts.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-paragraph"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="c7r58"&gt;In addition to 2D images, text-to-3D is now a reality with DreamFusion, which produces a three-dimensional model that can be viewed from any angle and can be composited into any 3D environment. Researchers are also making significant progress in the audio generation space with AudioLM, a model that learns to generate realistic speech and piano music by listening to audio only. In the same way a language model might predict the words and sentences that follow a text prompt, AudioLM can predict which sounds should follow after a few seconds of an audio prompt.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-paragraph"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="c7r58"&gt;We're collaborating with creative communities globally as we develop these tools. For example, we're working with writers using Wordcraft, which is built on our state-of-the-art dialog system LaMDA, to experiment with AI-powered text generation. You can read the first volume of these stories at the &lt;a href="http://g.co/research/wordcraft"&gt;Wordcraft Writers Workshop&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="5fj9b"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-paragraph"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;h3 data-block-key="c7r58"&gt;3. Addressing climate change and health challenges with AI&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-paragraph"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="c7r58"&gt;AI also has great potential to address the effects of climate change, including helping people adapt to new challenges. One of the worst is wildfires, which affect hundreds of thousands of people today, and are increasing in frequency and scale.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-paragraph"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="c7r58"&gt;Today, I’m excited to share that we’ve advanced our use of satellite imagery to train AI models to identify and track wildfires in real time, helping predict how they will evolve and spread. We’ve launched this wildfire tracking system in the U.S., Canada, Mexico, and are rolling out in parts of Australia, and since July we’ve covered more than 30 big wildfire events in the U.S. and Canada, helping inform our users and firefighting teams with over 7 million views in Google Search and Maps.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-image_full_width"&gt;&lt;div class="h-c-page"&gt;&lt;div class="article-image h-c-grid__col-l--4 h-c-grid__col--6 h-c-grid__col-l--offset-4 h-c-grid__col--offset-3"&gt;&lt;a class="article-image--link"&gt;&lt;img alt="wildfire alert on phone" class="article-image--medium" src=" https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/original_images/Google-AI-Wildfire.gif " tabindex="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-paragraph"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="c7r58"&gt;We’re also using AI to forecast floods, another extreme weather pattern exacerbated by climate change. We’ve already &lt;a href="https://blog.google/technology/ai/expanding-our-ml-based-flood-forecasting/"&gt;helped communities&lt;/a&gt; to predict when floods will hit and how deep the waters will get — in 2021, we sent 115 million flood alert notifications to 23 million people over Google Search and Maps, helping save countless lives. Today, we’re sharing that we’re now expanding our coverage to more countries in South America (Brazil and Colombia), Sub-Saharan Africa (Burkina Faso, Cameroon, Chad, Democratic Republic of Congo, Ivory Coast, Ghana, Guinea, Malawi, Nigeria, Sierra Leone, Angola, South Sudan, Namibia, Liberia, and South Africa), and South Asia (Sri Lanka). We’ve used an AI technique called transfer learning to make it work in areas where there’s less data available. We’re also announcing the global launch of Google &lt;a href="http://g.co/floodhub"&gt;FloodHub&lt;/a&gt;, a new platform that displays when and where floods may occur. We’ll also be bringing this information to Google Search and Maps in the future to help more people to reach safety in flooding situations.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-image_full_width"&gt;&lt;div class="h-c-page"&gt;&lt;div class="article-image h-c-grid__col-l--4 h-c-grid__col--6 h-c-grid__col-l--offset-4 h-c-grid__col--offset-3"&gt;&lt;a class="article-image--link"&gt;&lt;img alt="flood alert on a phone" class="article-image--medium" data-loading='{
                "mobile": "https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/Google-AI-Flood.max-500x500.png",
                "desktop": "https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/Google-AI-Flood.max-1000x1000.png"
              }' loading="lazy" src=" https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/Google-AI-Flood.max-100x100.png " tabindex="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-paragraph"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="c7r58"&gt;Finally, AI is helping provide ever more access to healthcare in under-resourced regions. For example, we’re researching ways AI can help read and analyze outputs from low-cost ultrasound devices, giving parents the information they need to identify issues earlier in a pregnancy. We also plan to continue to partner with caregivers and public health agencies to expand access to diabetic retinopathy screening through our Automated Retinal Disease Assessment tool (ARDA). Through ARDA, we’ve successfully screened more than 150,000 patients in countries like India, Thailand, Germany, the United States, and the United Kingdom across deployed use and prospective studies — more than half of those in 2022 alone. Further, we’re exploring how AI can help your phone detect respiratory and heart rates. This work is part of Google Health’s broader vision, which includes &lt;a href="https://blog.google/technology/health/check-up-ai-developments-2022/"&gt;making healthcare more accessible&lt;/a&gt; for anyone with a smartphone.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="346ur"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-paragraph"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;h3 data-block-key="c7r58"&gt;AI in the years ahead&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-paragraph"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="c7r58"&gt;Our advancements in neural network architectures, machine learning algorithms and new approaches to hardware for machine learning have helped AI solve important, real-world problems for billions of people. Much more is to come. What we’re sharing today is a hopeful vision for the future — AI is letting us reimagine how technology can be helpful. We hope you’ll join us as we explore these new capabilities and use this technology to improve people’s lives around the world.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2022 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.google/technology/ai/ways-ai-is-scaling-helpful/</guid><category>AI</category><media:content height="540" url="https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/ai_neural_network_hero-02.max-600x600.jpg" width="540"/><og xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#"><type>article</type><title>3 ways AI is scaling helpful technologies worldwide</title><description>Decades of research have led to today’s rapid progress in AI. Today, we’re announcing three new ways people are poised to benefit.</description><image>https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/ai_neural_network_hero-02.max-600x600.jpg</image><site_name>Google</site_name><url>https://blog.google/technology/ai/ways-ai-is-scaling-helpful/</url></og><author xmlns:author="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><name>Jeff Dean</name><title>Google Senior Fellow and SVP, Google Research</title><department/><company/></author></item><item><title>New features for parents and kids on Google Assistant</title><link>https://blog.google/products/assistant/new-features-for-parents-and-kids-on-google-assistant/</link><description>&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;div class="block-paragraph"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="oplnf"&gt;Earlier this week, I was in the kitchen watching my kids — at the (very fun) ages of seven and 11 — engaged in a conversation with our Google Assistant. My son, who has recently discovered a love of karaoke, asked it to play music so he could practice singing along to his favorite band, BTS. He and his sister ask it all kinds of questions: “How tall is the Eiffel Tower?” “How much do elephants weigh?” “Where was the Declaration of Independence signed?”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="3jevs"&gt;Whether we’re dictating a text message in the car or starting a timer while cooking at home, one thing is true: Voice plays an increasingly important role in the way we get things done — not just for us, but for our kids, too. It allows them to indulge their curiosities, learn new things and tap into their creative, inquisitive minds — all without having to look at a screen. As a mom, I see firsthand how kids’ relationship with technology starts by discovering the power of their own voice. And as today’s kids grow up in a world surrounded by technology, we want to help them have safer, educational and natural conversational experiences with Assistant. Here’s how we’re doing it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 data-block-key="3e5kk"&gt;Parental controls for safer, age-appropriate content&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="f29rb"&gt;Since we know kids — like my own — tend to use their families’ shared devices, we take very seriously our responsibility to help parents protect them from harmful and inappropriate content. Building on that &lt;a href="https://blog.google/technology/families/giving-kids-and-teens-safer-experience-online/"&gt;long-standing commitment&lt;/a&gt;, we’re rolling out a number of new features that will make it safer for your kids to interact with Assistant.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="7tptn"&gt;To give parents more control and peace of mind over the interactions their children have on Google speakers and smart displays, we’re introducing &lt;a href="https://support.google.com/assistant/answer/11560114"&gt;parental controls&lt;/a&gt; for Google Assistant. In the coming weeks through the Google Home, Family Link and Google Assistant apps on Android and iOS, you can modify media settings, enable or disable certain Assistant functionality and set up downtime for your kids.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-image_full_width"&gt;&lt;div class="h-c-page"&gt;&lt;div class="article-image h-c-grid__col-l--4 h-c-grid__col--6 h-c-grid__col-l--offset-4 h-c-grid__col--offset-3"&gt;&lt;a class="article-image--link"&gt;&lt;img alt="The home screen of Google Assistant parental controls displaying different options, including Media, Assistant features, Downtime and Assistant devices." class="article-image--medium" data-loading='{
                "mobile": "https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/Parental_Controls.max-500x500.png",
                "desktop": "https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/Parental_Controls.max-1000x1000.png"
              }' loading="lazy" src=" https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/Parental_Controls.max-100x100.png " tabindex="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-paragraph"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="oplnf"&gt;After selecting your child’s account, you can choose the music and video providers they can access — such as YouTube Kids, YouTube and YouTube Music — and your kids will only be able to explore content from those pre-selected providers. You can also decide whether you want your children to listen to &lt;a href="https://support.google.com/googlenest/answer/11560114#zippy="&gt;news and podcasts on their devices.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="eln5m"&gt;Through parental controls, you can also control the specific Assistant features your kids can use — like restricting them from making phone calls or choosing what kind of answers they get from Assistant. And to encourage a healthy relationship between kids and technology, just say, “Hey Google, open Assistant settings.” From there, navigate to parental controls, and you can block off time when they shouldn’t use their devices, just like you can do on personal &lt;a href="https://support.google.com/families/answer/7103340?hl=en"&gt;Android devices and Chromebooks&lt;/a&gt;. Whether you have parental controls turned on or not, we always make sure you’re in control of your &lt;a href="https://safety.google/assistant/"&gt;privacy settings&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 data-block-key="1m4b2"&gt;Educational and fun conversations with Kids Dictionary&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="3rltd"&gt;“What does telescope mean?” “What is the definition of ‘fluorescent’?”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="fgo7r"&gt;Kids are naturally inquisitive and often turn to their Assistant to define words like these when they’re not sure what they mean. To help make those interactions even more engaging, we're introducing Kids Dictionary, which gives simplified and age-appropriate answers across speakers, smart displays and mobile devices.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="4t7t"&gt;With Kids Dictionary, children’s interactions with Assistant can be both educational and fun, allowing them to fuel their interests and learn new things. When your child is &lt;a href="https://support.google.com/assistant/answer/9071584"&gt;voice matched&lt;/a&gt; and Assistant detects their voice asking about a definition, it will automatically respond using this experience in Kids Dictionary.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-image_full_width"&gt;&lt;div class="h-c-page"&gt;&lt;div class="article-image h-c-grid__col--10 h-c-grid__col--offset-1 h-c-grid__col-l--offset-2 h-c-grid__col-l--8"&gt;&lt;a class="article-image--link"&gt;&lt;img alt="A text bubble asks “Hey Google, what does telescope mean?” A Nest Hub Max is shown next to the text bubble, displaying a picture of a telescope and its definition." class="article-image--full" data-loading='{
                "mobile": "https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/KidsDictionary_Edit.max-500x500.png",
                "desktop": "https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/KidsDictionary_Edit.max-1000x1000.png"
              }' loading="lazy" src=" https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/KidsDictionary_Edit.max-100x100.png " tabindex="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-paragraph"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="oplnf"&gt;Whether they’re doing their homework or simply curious about a new word they saw in a book, they’re only a “Hey Google” away from a little more help.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 data-block-key="5iprl"&gt;Kid-friendly voices for more engaging interactions&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="anttd"&gt;Kids today are growing up with technology, so it’s important that their experiences are developmentally appropriate. In addition to our increased efforts around safety and education, we’re also introducing &lt;a href="https://support.google.com/assistant/answer/7544506"&gt;four new kid-friendly voices&lt;/a&gt;. These new voices, which we designed alongside kids and parents, were developed with a diverse range of accents to reflect different communities and ways of speaking. And like a favorite teacher, these voices speak in slower and more expressive styles to help with storytelling and aid comprehension.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="6h4tb"&gt;To activate one of Assistant’s new kid-friendly voices, kids can simply say, “Hey Google, change your voice!” Parents can also help their child navigate to Assistant settings, where they can select a new voice from the options available.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="c79is"&gt;Like all parents, I’m always amazed by my kids’ insatiable curiosity. And every day, I see that curiosity come to life in the many questions they ask our Assistant. We’re excited to not only provide a safer experience, but an educational and engaging one, too — and to continue our work to truly build an Assistant for everyone.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-video"&gt;&lt;div class="h-c-page h-c-page--mobile-full-bleed"&gt;&lt;div class="h-c-grid"&gt;&lt;div class="h-c-grid__col h-c-grid__col-l--10 h-c-grid__col-l--offset-1"&gt;&lt;div class="article-module uni-article-video uni-article-video--body" data-component="uni-article-yt-player" data-page-title="" data-video-id="75y81X_H83s"&gt;&lt;div class="uni-article-video__embed-container hidden"&gt;&lt;div id="uni-article-yt-player-75y81X_H83s"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;a class="h-c-video h-c-video--marquee uni-article-video__custom-wrapper" role="link" tabindex="0"&gt;&lt;div class="uni-article-video__aspect-image"&gt;&lt;img alt="Google Assistant’s four new kid-friendly voices introduce themselves and share instructions for changing your Assistant’s voice settings." data-loading='{
                        "mobile": "https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/Kid-friendly_voices_video_thumbnail.max-500x500.png",
                        "desktop": "https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/Kid-friendly_voices_video_thumbnail.max-1000x1000.png"
                      }' loading="lazy" src="https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/Kid-friendly_voices_video_thumbnail.max-100x100.png"/&gt;&lt;div class="uni-article-video__dimmer"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;svg class="uni-article-video__play-button--active" role="img"&gt;&lt;use xlink:href="#yt_video_play_button_no_hole"&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;svg class="uni-article-video__play-button" role="img"&gt;&lt;use xlink:href="#yt_video_play_button"&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;div class="uni-article-video__duration loading"&gt;&lt;svg class="uni-article-video__duration-icon" role="img"&gt;&lt;use xlink:href="#yt_video_duration"&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;span class="uni-article-video__duration-time"&gt;10:25&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2022 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.google/products/assistant/new-features-for-parents-and-kids-on-google-assistant/</guid><category>Google Assistant</category><media:content height="540" url="https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/PARENTAL_CONTROLS_FINAL_DISPLAY.max-600x600.png" width="540"/><og xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#"><type>article</type><title>New features for parents and kids on Google Assistant</title><description>Parental controls, kid-friendly voices and a kids dictionary are coming to Google Assistant.</description><image>https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/PARENTAL_CONTROLS_FINAL_DISPLAY.max-600x600.png</image><site_name>Google</site_name><url>https://blog.google/products/assistant/new-features-for-parents-and-kids-on-google-assistant/</url></og><author xmlns:author="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><name>Sissie Hsiao</name><title>Vice President</title><department>Google Assistant</department><company/></author></item><item><title>The inside story of how Google bathrooms became classrooms</title><link>https://blog.google/inside-google/life-at-google/inside-story-learning-on-the-loo/</link><description>&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;div class="block-paragraph"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="mnvsm"&gt;As a software engineer at Google, Daniele Midi spends most of his time working on developing smart home products. But every week he also sets aside time to help Googlers learn something new from a surprising classroom: the bathroom. Daniele is the editor-in-chief of Learning on the Loo (LotL), a volunteer-driven series of one-page lessons that show up in Google bathrooms in every office across the globe. The “episodes," as they're called, hang inside each restroom and cover subjects from productivity tips for Gmail to avoiding bias in decision making.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="61q8k"&gt;The ultimate mission of LotL is to improve Googlers’ lives at work. Daniele first got involved as an intern in 2015, helping with distributing new episodes in his office. Soon after, he joined the small editorial team, and eventually stepped up to lead it. Today, LotL releases new episodes twice a month, on topics that deal with productivity, career and personal development.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="40jrb"&gt;LotL launched in 2007 and drew inspiration from &lt;a href="https://testing.googleblog.com/2007/01/introducing-testing-on-toilet.html"&gt;Testing on the Toilet (TotT)&lt;/a&gt;, another Google institution, but a more tailored one. TotT began after a group of Googlers wanted to get input on how engineers could write better tests to ensure their code was working. One of those Googlers somewhat jokingly suggested posting tips about writing better tests in bathrooms. The idea caught on. Today, engineer Andrew Trenk heads up TotT, which now covers topics like coding best practices in addition to testing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="fp2e9"&gt;TotT and LotL have a few things in common — for instance, the length. “A challenge is often getting everything to fit on one page,” Andrew says. “This also happens to be what makes the content so useful: Authors are forced to limit themselves to only their most critical points.” And like TotT, LotL aims to be actionable, with quick tips Googlers can use right away.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="5og6h"&gt;One example episode: “Effective meetings,” published May 17, 2022, written by Oded Niv. This episode shares tips for what to do and why, both before the meeting starts (“set a prioritized list of goals and activities”) and during the meeting (“politely keep the focus on the agenda”).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="kc8"&gt;An episode titled “Are you writing clearly?” was published August 2, 2022, and written by Nancy Fann-Im. Tips include “Less is more,” “Write like you speak” and “Be direct.” “Even executives appreciate brevity over jargon,” Nancy writes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="ciejt"&gt;All Googlers can submit LotL episode ideas via a form that asks things like whether their lesson is applicable to Googlers everywhere and what the takeaways are. It also includes the note that at least one image or meme is required. Daniele and his team of three other Googlers read through the submissions. Once they accept a proposal, the author or authors work on the one-page copy, edited by the LotL team.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="60e1v"&gt;“I think people would be surprised at the level of scrutiny each episode goes through,” Daniele says. LotL even began an open editing group, so any Googler can give suggestions on upcoming episodes via Google Docs. “It’s particularly helpful to get feedback on whether a lesson makes sense globally,” Daniele explains. “Local office culture in the U.S., for example, is different from office culture in Korea.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="b3hv4"&gt;Once the LotL team finalizes an episode, they send it to a cadre of Googler volunteers and local facilities teams across the globe who print and distribute it. (Each LotL is also available online and via email for Googlers.) From submission to launch day, the process takes a minimum of three to four weeks.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="39hi9"&gt;Like so much about work, LotL had to evolve once the pandemic started. When people began working from home in 2020, LotL went entirely digital, and the content shifted. LotL proposals focusing on everything from at-home office setup to coping with the ongoing stress of the COVID-19 pandemic poured in. “It was a challenging time, for sure, but it was really wonderful to see how many Googlers wanted to share ideas to help each other, too,” Daniele says.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="ena7q"&gt;Learning on the Loo remains a source of common ground for Googlers everywhere — and according to Daniele, it’s one that receives an encouraging amount of positive attention. “We recently added a short feedback form to our site,” Daniele says. “People will drop us emails that say, ‘Hey, I loved this, thank you so much!’ I just think that’s really, really cool.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2022 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.google/inside-google/life-at-google/inside-story-learning-on-the-loo/</guid><category>Life at Google</category><media:content height="540" url="https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/learning_on_the_loo_hero_1.max-600x600.jpg" width="540"/><og xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#"><type>article</type><title>The inside story of how Google bathrooms became classrooms</title><description>Learning on the Loo, a series of one-pagers with quick lessons in productivity, career and personal development, is a fixture in many Google office bathrooms across the globe.</description><image>https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/learning_on_the_loo_hero_1.max-600x600.jpg</image><site_name>Google</site_name><url>https://blog.google/inside-google/life-at-google/inside-story-learning-on-the-loo/</url></og><author xmlns:author="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><name>Molly McHugh-Johnson</name><title>Contributor</title><department>The Keyword</department><company/></author></item><item><title>New ways to find holiday deals on Google</title><link>https://blog.google/products/shopping/holiday-shopping-deals/</link><description>&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;div class="block-paragraph"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="srk52"&gt;The holiday season is upon us, and many are already getting into the (shopping) spirit. Deals are particularly top of mind this year: Among Americans planning to shop for the holidays, 43% are planning to look for deals and sales more than last year.&lt;footnote id="72d1b6ad-a178-484e-8dbb-94155ba77008"&gt;[72d1b6]&lt;/footnote&gt;So we’re sharing a few new features to help you easily find those discounts and get the perfect gift at the right price.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 data-block-key="3275p"&gt;New labels for coupons and promotions&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="ffhd0"&gt;Coupon codes are a great way to save, but finding them — and making sure they work — can be challenging. To help shoppers save money and time, we’re bringing promotions front and center in product searches.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-image_full_width"&gt;&lt;div class="h-c-page"&gt;&lt;div class="article-image h-c-grid__col--10 h-c-grid__col--offset-1 h-c-grid__col-l--offset-2 h-c-grid__col-l--8"&gt;&lt;a class="article-image--link"&gt;&lt;img alt="A mobile search for “shop holiday party dresses” loads colorful results. The screen scrolls down to a red dress option with a special offer label, clicks the item and copies a coupon code." class="article-image--full" src=" https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/original_images/Promotion_Badge_-_Coupon_Clipping_-_Shop_Holiday_Party_Dress_1.gif " tabindex="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-paragraph"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="srk52"&gt;Our new promotion badge will show up in Search on items running a promotion (like “15% off with coupon code HOLIDAYS”). While in the past we’ve shown when items are on sale or the price has dropped, you can now see specific promotions and compare them to others right in Search.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="79ghc"&gt;We’re also adding a new coupon clipping feature, which allows you to easily copy promo codes when you’re ready to buy. These new features will roll out in the coming weeks.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-paragraph"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;h2 data-block-key="srk52"&gt;Compare deals side by side&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="5odpm"&gt;For the past year, more than half of U.S. shoppers have visited multiple websites before settling on what and where to buy.&lt;footnote id="6b9a3d1c-3cdf-4d83-8eb4-58de2a3d6efc"&gt;[6b9a3d]&lt;/footnote&gt;We’re bringing you a new, easy way to cut down on all that research time and compare shopping deals across retailers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-image_full_width"&gt;&lt;div class="h-c-page"&gt;&lt;div class="article-image h-c-grid__col--10 h-c-grid__col--offset-1 h-c-grid__col-l--offset-2 h-c-grid__col-l--8"&gt;&lt;a class="article-image--link"&gt;&lt;img alt="A mobile search for “shop women’s puffer jackets” scrolls down to a section labeled “deals” showing products with discounted prices from various merchants." class="article-image--full" src=" https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/original_images/Deal_comparison_-_Shop_womens_puffer_jackets_4C4oUdq.gif " tabindex="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-paragraph"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="6z0gq"&gt;If you search for a women’s puffer coat, for example, we’ll show you a side-by-side comparison of available puffer coat deals right in your results. This new view will roll out in the U.S. this month, just in time for the holidays.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-paragraph"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;h2 data-block-key="srk52"&gt;Get price insights&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="76ii"&gt;While it’s easy to get enticed by holiday sales, it can be hard to tell whether something is a good value. So we’re bringing our price insights feature to Search to help shoppers understand the prices they see and make better buying decisions. Now, you’ll quickly see how one merchant’s price compares to others’ and whether it’s low, typical or high for that product.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-image_full_width"&gt;&lt;div class="h-c-page"&gt;&lt;div class="article-image h-c-grid__col--10 h-c-grid__col--offset-1 h-c-grid__col-l--offset-2 h-c-grid__col-l--8"&gt;&lt;a class="article-image--link"&gt;&lt;img alt="A mobile search for “shop speaker jbl tune 130nc” shows results for speakers. It scrolls down to an “online stores” section, where the color “white” is selected from a drop-down menu and a graph shows different price ranges." class="article-image--full" src=" https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/original_images/Price_Insights_on_Search_-_Shop_jbl_tune_130nc.gif " tabindex="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-paragraph"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="6z0gq"&gt;And merchants, don’t forget you can always see how your deals are performing and review your business’ promotions wherever you manage your product listings on Google.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="fn3p5"&gt;These new features will make it easier to find great prices and check everything off your list this season.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2022 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.google/products/shopping/holiday-shopping-deals/</guid><category>Shopping</category><media:content height="540" url="https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/Option_5.max-600x600.jpg" width="540"/><og xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#"><type>article</type><title>New ways to find holiday deals on Google</title><description>New shopping features from Google make finding deals, sales, coupon codes and price comparisons easier than ever.</description><image>https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/Option_5.max-600x600.jpg</image><site_name>Google</site_name><url>https://blog.google/products/shopping/holiday-shopping-deals/</url></og><author xmlns:author="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><name>Shashi Thakur</name><title>VP/GM</title><department>Consumer Shopping</department><company/></author></item><item><title>Accelerating climate action at Google and beyond</title><link>https://blog.google/outreach-initiatives/sustainability/cop27-google-climate-action/</link><description>&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;div class="block-paragraph"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="2jq1m"&gt;Next week at &lt;a href="https://cop27.eg/#/"&gt;COP27&lt;/a&gt;, global leaders will gather in Egypt to build momentum for climate action. Climate change is one of humanity’s most urgent challenges, and this decade is critical in setting the world on a path to a sustainable future. Google is committed to reducing our own emissions and using technology to help everyone make sustainable choices.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="dq5c4"&gt;Today, we’re releasing a &lt;a href="https://www.gstatic.com/gumdrop/sustainability/google-2022-climate-action-progress-update.pdf"&gt;paper&lt;/a&gt; that shares updates on the work we have been doing as part of &lt;a href="https://blog.google/outreach-initiatives/sustainability/our-third-decade-climate-action-realizing-carbon-free-future/"&gt;our third decade of climate action&lt;/a&gt;. Here’s a look at our progress and ambitions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 data-block-key="cp4ni"&gt;Built to be sustainable&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="5iv0c"&gt;Sustainability has always been a core value for Google, and we know taking action starts with operating our business more sustainably.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="74iqt"&gt;Last year we announced our goal of achieving net-zero emissions across our operations and value chain — including our consumer hardware products — by 2030. We aim to reduce 50% of our combined scope 1&lt;footnote id="dd5395e2-42f7-4b8b-b115-2140526244e4"&gt;[dd5395]&lt;/footnote&gt;, scope 2&lt;footnote id="c32b8a73-a6bb-458f-8bbc-cdd48c00e4bd"&gt;[c32b8a]&lt;/footnote&gt;, and scope 3&lt;footnote id="19a61733-28bb-4f68-86ad-826be80ca69f"&gt;[19a617]&lt;/footnote&gt;absolute emissions (versus our 2019 baseline) before 2030, and plan to invest in nature-based and technology-based carbon removal solutions to neutralize our remaining emissions. There are three ways we are working towards this goal: advancing carbon-free energy (CFE), reducing emissions within our value chain, and addressing our residual emissions with carbon removal and other solutions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="4hfa2"&gt;Our net zero goal builds on two decades of climate action at Google. We started purchasing renewable energy in 2010, and in 2017 we became the first major company to match 100% of our annual electricity use with renewable energy purchases. We have continued to do so for &lt;a href="https://cloud.google.com/blog/topics/sustainability/5-years-of-100-percent-renewable-energy"&gt;five consecutive years&lt;/a&gt;, and in 2020 we set the even more ambitious goal of operating our data centers and office campuses on &lt;a href="https://sustainability.google/progress/energy/"&gt;24/7 CFE&lt;/a&gt; by 2030.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 data-block-key="a3f2t"&gt;Accelerate action through partners&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="1iejf"&gt;While we’re committed to reaching our goals, our impact is far greater when we work together. That’s why we collaborate with thousands of partners across multiple industries — from cities and governments to companies and nonprofits — to advance sustainability and climate progress.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="8mh4s"&gt;Over half of the global population lives in cities, and urban areas account for over two-thirds of global energy consumption and &lt;a href="https://www.worldbank.org/en/topic/urbandevelopment/overview#1"&gt;more than 70% of global carbon emissions&lt;/a&gt;. To help reduce these emissions, we aim to help more than 500 cities and local governments reduce an aggregate of 1 gigaton of carbon emissions annually by 2030. We are working to achieve this through tools like our &lt;a href="https://insights.sustainability.google/"&gt;Environmental Insights Explorer&lt;/a&gt;, which empowers cities and regions with actionable data and insights to reduce global emissions, and Project Green Light, an AI tool that provides recommendations for city planners to optimize traffic light timing to reduce stop-and-go traffic.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="70k5p"&gt;Likewise, many of the world’s biggest brands are working to operate more sustainably. Through Google Cloud, we’re helping customers minimize environmental impact. This summer we announced &lt;a href="https://cloud.google.com/blog/topics/sustainability/how-partners-benefit-from-google-cloud-ready-sustainability"&gt;Google Cloud Ready - Sustainability designation&lt;/a&gt; to showcase partners that are committed to helping organizations accelerate their sustainability programs.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="1919j"&gt;We are also building tools to strengthen communities’ response to extreme weather events. For example, our &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Mz0ikfuE_z0"&gt;forecasting initiative&lt;/a&gt; provides flood alerts and information to at-risk communities. During Pakistan’s severe flooding this year, we provided nationwide SOS alerts with links to the latest information from government authorities.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 data-block-key="aionb"&gt;Empowering everyone to make more sustainable choices&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="f5n84"&gt;The billions of people who use our products and services are looking for ways to live more sustainably, and &lt;a href="https://blog.google/outreach-initiatives/sustainability/sustainability-2021/"&gt;we want to make it easier for them to do so&lt;/a&gt;. In 2022, Google searches reached all-time highs for terms including “&lt;a href="https://trends.google.com/trends/explore?q=%2Fm%2F0h1dq_f&amp;amp;date=all"&gt;rooftop solar power&lt;/a&gt;,” “&lt;a href="https://trends.google.com/trends/explore?date=all&amp;amp;q=%2Fm%2F06xbd"&gt;solar energy&lt;/a&gt;,” “&lt;a href="https://trends.google.com/trends/explore?date=all&amp;amp;q=%2Fm%2F0bh99y_"&gt;electric bicycles&lt;/a&gt;,” and “&lt;a href="https://trends.google.com/trends/explore?date=all&amp;amp;geo=US&amp;amp;q=electric%20cars"&gt;electric cars&lt;/a&gt;.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="5tqsa"&gt;Last year, we rolled out &lt;a href="https://blog.google/products/maps/3-new-ways-navigate-more-sustainably-maps"&gt;eco-friendly routing&lt;/a&gt; on Google Maps in the U.S. and Canada, and this year it expanded to 40 countries across Europe. This tool gets people to their destinations as quickly as possible while minimizing fuel consumption. Already it has helped avoid an estimate of more than half a million metric tons of carbon emissions — that’s equivalent to &lt;a href="https://www.blog.google/around-the-globe/google-europe/eco-friendly-routing-in-europe/"&gt;taking approximately 100,000 fuel-based cars off the road&lt;/a&gt;&lt;footnote id="31542c0b-355b-4e2f-9579-0cf432f5e167"&gt;[31542c]&lt;/footnote&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="3cna5"&gt;As of this month, anyone with an eligible Nest thermostat in the continental U.S. can join &lt;a href="https://nestrenew.google.com/welcome/?utm_source=keyword-blog&amp;amp;utm_medium=google_oo&amp;amp;utm_campaign=third_decade_climate_action"&gt;Nest Renew&lt;/a&gt;, which can &lt;a href="https://blog.google/products/google-nest/nest-renew-clean-energy/"&gt;automatically shift their&lt;/a&gt; energy consumption to the times of day when grid electricity is cleaner or less expensive.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="3q12s"&gt;As we work to provide products and services that help people make sustainable choices and reduce their carbon footprints, we’ll continue improving our ability to measure the individual and collective impact of these decisions. This is important not only for Google, but also for the growing number of companies offering solutions to help their customers reduce emissions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 data-block-key="6fq32"&gt;A more sustainable future, for all&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="d8sq1"&gt;This year, we’ve seen major steps forward on climate policy in the U.S., Europe, and other regions. We are excited about the potential of new policy measures and corporate commitments that will help us reach historic emissions reductions in the next decade. The conversations at COP27 will be a critical moment to continue building momentum and move from pledges to progress.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="52rhh"&gt;Our aim is to make every day more sustainable through our operations, partnerships and products. We’re energized by the progress we’ve made so far, and more motivated than ever to do our part to accelerate the transition to a more sustainable future for all.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2022 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.google/outreach-initiatives/sustainability/cop27-google-climate-action/</guid><category>Sustainability</category><media:content height="540" url="https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/EUE-APW-120721-953-Edit.max-600x600.jpg" width="540"/><og xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#"><type>article</type><title>Accelerating climate action at Google and beyond</title><description>A new paper we published today shares updates on the work we have been doing as part of our third decade of climate action.</description><image>https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/EUE-APW-120721-953-Edit.max-600x600.jpg</image><site_name>Google</site_name><url>https://blog.google/outreach-initiatives/sustainability/cop27-google-climate-action/</url></og><author xmlns:author="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><name>Kate Brandt</name><title>Chief Sustainability Officer, Google</title><department/><company/></author></item><item><title>Helping to create a more resilient Europe</title><link>https://blog.google/outreach-initiatives/google-org/announcing-the-googleorg-impact-challenge-tech-for-social-good/</link><description>&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;div class="block-paragraph"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="4b6ra"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Helping to create a more resilient Europe&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="2dh1d"&gt;When Ukraine was invaded in February, a group of 15 Google employees dropped everything to do what they did best — write code. But unlike their day jobs of helping to build Google Maps or improve Google Search, this team of &lt;a href="https://www.google.org/our-approach/#fellowship"&gt;Google.org Fellows&lt;/a&gt; assisted the International Rescue Committee (IRC) to build out ‘&lt;a href="https://www.unitedforukraine.org/locale-select?target=%2F"&gt;United for Ukraine&lt;/a&gt;,’ an information service aimed squarely at helping the people fleeing Ukraine connect with critical information about food, water, and shelter. This project has since helped more than 200,000 people access critical information, including&lt;a href="https://blog.google/inside-google/company-announcements/continuing-to-support-ukrainians-in-challenging-times/"&gt;matching over 10,000 refugees to temporary accommodations&lt;/a&gt;. Ensuring that they’re prepared for the next crisis, the IRC team, with support from Google.org Fellows, also worked to shorten the time required to launch future versions of the site, meaning people impacted by a crisis can get potentially lifesaving information much faster.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="194uj"&gt;This is the kind of transformational innovation that a team of Google engineers working alongside issue area experts at nonprofits can achieve. We’ve seen how this combination of funding and the right technical expertise can support organisations using tech solutions to combat some of Europe’s biggest challenges, such as developing a&lt;a href="https://normative.io/"&gt;free carbon emissions calculator&lt;/a&gt; for businesses of all sizes, building a new &lt;a href="https://immersion-facile.beta.gouv.fr/"&gt;digital platform for jobseekers&lt;/a&gt;, and incorporating machine learning to automatically&lt;a href="https://fullfact.org/"&gt;flag false claims online&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="66e0s"&gt;This is what has inspired us to launch a new €15M &lt;b&gt;Google.org Impact Challenge: Tech for Social Good&lt;/b&gt;. European nonprofits, civic entities, academic and research institutions, and social enterprises can, for the first time, apply to receive pro bono technical help from a team of Google.org Fellows for up to six months, helping them transform their organisation’s work.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="lafa"&gt;For this new Impact Challenge, we’re particularly interested in seeing submissions from organisations focused on sustainability, economic opportunity, and cyber security — projects that will help to combat the threats of climate change, economic challenges, and the spread of online disinformation across Europe.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-video"&gt;&lt;div class="h-c-page h-c-page--mobile-full-bleed"&gt;&lt;div class="h-c-grid"&gt;&lt;div class="h-c-grid__col h-c-grid__col-l--10 h-c-grid__col-l--offset-1"&gt;&lt;div class="article-module uni-article-video uni-article-video--body" data-component="uni-article-yt-player" data-page-title="" data-video-id="BHJQvb2bueQ"&gt;&lt;div class="uni-article-video__embed-container hidden"&gt;&lt;div id="uni-article-yt-player-BHJQvb2bueQ"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;a class="h-c-video h-c-video--marquee uni-article-video__custom-wrapper" role="link" tabindex="0"&gt;&lt;div class="uni-article-video__aspect-image"&gt;&lt;img alt="A video with text saying The Google.org Impact Challenge: Tech For Social Good" data-loading='{
                        "mobile": "https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/GIC_Hero_Image.max-500x500.jpg",
                        "desktop": "https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/GIC_Hero_Image.max-1000x1000.jpg"
                      }' loading="lazy" src="https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/GIC_Hero_Image.max-100x100.jpg"/&gt;&lt;div class="uni-article-video__dimmer"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;svg class="uni-article-video__play-button--active" role="img"&gt;&lt;use xlink:href="#yt_video_play_button_no_hole"&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;svg class="uni-article-video__play-button" role="img"&gt;&lt;use xlink:href="#yt_video_play_button"&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;div class="uni-article-video__duration loading"&gt;&lt;svg class="uni-article-video__duration-icon" role="img"&gt;&lt;use xlink:href="#yt_video_duration"&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;span class="uni-article-video__duration-time"&gt;10:25&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-paragraph"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="4b6ra"&gt;When asked to reflect on the International Rescue Committee experience working with Google.org Fellows, IRC CEO David Miliband said: “With help from Google.org Fellows, we were able to rapidly broaden the reach of a digital platform for Ukrainian refugees, at a time when there was no time to spare. In just 3 months they helped us achieve half of our entire roadmap for the next 5 years.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="934l7"&gt;We’re now asking your organisation for the most ambitious and impactful technical project that you’ve never had the time nor the resources to pursue, and to imagine what would be possible if you had a team of Google.org Fellows working pro bono for six months full-time, as well as up to €3M in funding to make your project a reality.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="7u5dp"&gt;Learn more about the selection criteria and process &lt;a href="http://impactchallenge.withgoogle.com/techforsocialgood"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. We look forward to seeing organisations apply with their bold ideas for a more prosperous, green, and secure Europe.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2022 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.google/outreach-initiatives/google-org/announcing-the-googleorg-impact-challenge-tech-for-social-good/</guid><category>Google.org</category><category>Sustainability</category><category>Safety &amp; Security</category><media:content height="540" url="https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/GIC_Hero_Keyword.max-600x600.jpg" width="540"/><og xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#"><type>article</type><title>Helping to create a more resilient Europe</title><description>The Google.org Impact Challenge: Tech for Social Good is an open call for organisations helping to create a more resilient Europe.</description><image>https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/GIC_Hero_Keyword.max-600x600.jpg</image><site_name>Google</site_name><url>https://blog.google/outreach-initiatives/google-org/announcing-the-googleorg-impact-challenge-tech-for-social-good/</url></og><author xmlns:author="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><name>Rowan Barnett</name><title>Director, Google.org Europe, MIddle East, and Africa</title><department/><company/></author><author xmlns:author="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><name>Annette Kroeber-Riel </name><title>Vice President, Government Affairs and Public Policy for Europe</title><department/><company/></author></item><item><title>Google licenses content from news publishers under the EU Copyright Directive</title><link>https://blog.google/around-the-globe/google-europe/google-licenses-content-from-news-publishers-under-the-eu-copyright-directive/</link><description>&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;div class="block-paragraph"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="ng60t"&gt;We are continuing our broad program of complying with Article 15 of the 2019 European Directive on Copyright in the Digital Single Market by striking licensing agreements with owners of press publications. Alongside these efforts, we’re constantly updating our products to help people find information by linking to news sites and other websites.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="5jvng"&gt;Since my last message (see below), I am happy to say we’ve made more progress on our commitment to license press publisher content under the new law. We now have licensing agreements that cover more than 1,000 publications across eleven European countries, with many more discussions ongoing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="b0s1n"&gt;We also announced the recipients of the Google News Initiative’s &lt;a href="https://blog.google/outreach-initiatives/google-news-initiative/celebrating-the-success-of-47-european-news-innovators/"&gt;Innovation Challenge for Europe&lt;/a&gt;. Forty seven recipients across 21 countries in Europe are now embarking on innovation projects ranging from audience engagement to community building. This demonstrates a new wave of news innovation in Europe that’s focused on building relationships with readers, listeners or viewers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="b9pgs"&gt;When I wrote that last message, below, we were testing a &lt;a href="https://support.google.com/webmasters/answer/11317369"&gt;new tool&lt;/a&gt; in Germany and Hungary to help us reach press publishers. We explain how this works in the previous blog post below. We have since rolled it out in Romania, Estonia, Lithuania, Ireland and the Netherlands, with expansion to additional EU countries planned over the coming months.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="d2i89"&gt;Our licensing program under the 2019 European Directive on Copyright in the Digital Single Market will eventually cover all countries that transpose the Directive, and considers variances in language, cross-border usage, and the needs of publishers large and small. We’re encouraged by the progress that’s already been made, but know that plenty of work remains to be done. And we’re motivated by our publisher partners who are innovating and growing, as we continue to play our part in building a thriving European news ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="55n85"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="1t5em"&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;Previous post, published May 2022&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="181a0"&gt;For many years, Google has helped people find information by linking to news and other websites, and supported publishers and journalists through &lt;a href="http://blog.google/supportingnews"&gt;products, advertising technology and funding&lt;/a&gt;. Over the past year, we have also launched a licensing programme called &lt;a href="https://blog.google/products/news/google-news-showcase/"&gt;Google News Showcase&lt;/a&gt;, working with more than 750 publications across Europe.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="d19ic"&gt;Alongside these efforts, we have been &lt;a href="https://blog.google/around-the-globe/google-europe/googles-approach-to-europes-copyright-law/"&gt;negotiating with news publishers&lt;/a&gt; to license content under the European Copyright Directive, which EU countries are in the process of implementing into national law. So far, we have agreements that cover more than 300 national, local and specialist news publications in Germany, Hungary, France, Austria, the Netherlands and Ireland, with many more discussions ongoing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="f4k7r"&gt;We are now announcing the launch of a &lt;a href="https://support.google.com/webmasters/answer/11317369"&gt;new tool&lt;/a&gt; to make offers to thousands more news publishers, starting in Germany and Hungary, and rolling out to other EU countries over the coming months.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 data-block-key="fh5n5"&gt;How it works&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="1pbl0"&gt;The Directive allows search engines like Google to freely link to, and use “very short extracts” of press publishers' content. The law also creates new rights for publishers when longer previews of their content are used online - but without defining what exactly a short extract or a longer preview is.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="1lbpr"&gt;Despite this uncertainty, we announced last year that we will pay news publishers for &lt;a href="https://blog.google/around-the-globe/google-europe/googles-approach-to-europes-copyright-law/"&gt;content which goes beyond links and short extracts&lt;/a&gt;, as we are already doing in &lt;a href="https://blog.google/intl/de-de/unternehmen/engagement/web-tool-fuer-verlage-leistungsschutzrecht/"&gt;countries such as Germany&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="co97t"&gt;Through this new tool, which will be available via &lt;a href="https://support.google.com/webmasters/answer/11317369#using_search_console"&gt;Search Console&lt;/a&gt;, publishers will be offered an Extended News Preview (ENP) agreement with Google for this content. This will include information about what the offer is for, how to sign up and how to provide feedback.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="ej40s"&gt;All offers are based on consistent criteria which respect the law and existing copyright guidance, including how often a news website is displayed and how much ad revenue is generated on pages that also display previews of news content.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="3kjf6"&gt;As always, publishers continue to have &lt;a href="https://developers.google.com/search/docs/advanced/robots/intro"&gt;full control&lt;/a&gt; over whether or not their content appears in Google Search and how that content can be previewed. Publishers can change their preferences and enroll in the ENP program at any time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="7i7j3"&gt;Alongside our negotiations, we will continue to invest in products and programs to provide even more support for journalism in Europe and around the world. We recently announced the &lt;a href="https://blog.google/outreach-initiatives/google-news-initiative/innovation-challenge-europe/"&gt;Innovation Challenge for Europe&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href="https://www.inma.org/blogs/main/post.cfm/8-european-publishers-selected-for-google-news-initiative-subscriptions-academy-2022"&gt;Google News Initiative Subscriptions Academy&lt;/a&gt; which provides publishers with an intense 8-month program focused on digital growth. We look forward to working with publishers and journalists on all these efforts in the coming months, building on our long track record of &lt;a href="http://blog.google/supportingnews"&gt;support for journalism&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2022 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.google/around-the-globe/google-europe/google-licenses-content-from-news-publishers-under-the-eu-copyright-directive/</guid><category>Google in Europe</category><og xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#"><type>article</type><title>Google licenses content from news publishers under the EU Copyright Directive</title><description>Google is licensing content under the copyright law in Europe</description><site_name>Google</site_name><url>https://blog.google/around-the-globe/google-europe/google-licenses-content-from-news-publishers-under-the-eu-copyright-directive/</url></og><author xmlns:author="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><name>Sulina Connal</name><title>Managing Director, News and Publishing Partnerships</title><department/><company/></author></item><item><title>3 app measurement strategies for business growth</title><link>https://blog.google/products/ads-commerce/app-measurement-strategies-business-growth/</link><description>&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;div class="block-paragraph"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="dn7h2"&gt;Marketers are investing more in their apps. In fact, 81% of retailers and 75% of e-commerce companies plan to increase their investment in promoting their mobile apps over the next 12 months.&lt;footnote id="770168b9-7c8a-4b03-9a68-4495eb3fcd10"&gt;[770168]&lt;/footnote&gt;That’s why we’re introducing new tools to help you more accurately measure cross-platform conversions, strengthen campaign performance with privacy-focused measurement and adapt to shifts in platform standards on iOS and Android.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-paragraph"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;h3 data-block-key="dn7h2"&gt;Set up cross-platform conversion measurement&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-image_full_width"&gt;&lt;div class="h-c-page"&gt;&lt;div class="article-image h-c-grid__col--10 h-c-grid__col--offset-1 h-c-grid__col-l--offset-2 h-c-grid__col-l--8"&gt;&lt;a class="article-image--link"&gt;&lt;video alt="W2AC" autoplay="" class="article-image__media" loop="" muted="" playsinline="" src="https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/original_videos/W2AC_GIF.mp4" tabindex="0" title="Screen grab of the Web to App Connect interface, featuring tools to guide advertisers through conversion tracking and deep linking set up" type="video/mp4"&gt;Video format not supported&lt;/video&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-paragraph"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="dn7h2"&gt;People search across various sites and apps before taking action, with the average consumer switching five times between mobile web and apps in a 30 minute-session&lt;footnote id="8a20efc8-b41c-4265-b808-8ca8164e8b59"&gt;[8a20ef]&lt;/footnote&gt;. Without cross-platform &lt;a href="https://support.google.com/google-ads/answer/1722022"&gt;conversion tracking&lt;/a&gt;, you’ll have measurement gaps and limit optimization across your web and app campaigns. To help advertisers more easily set up conversion tracking, we’ve been alpha testing &lt;a href="https://support.google.com/google-ads/answer/12131000"&gt;Web to App Connect&lt;/a&gt;, a toolkit that guides advertisers through the process step by step.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="bo5co"&gt;It’s also essential to prioritize frictionless web-to-app experiences for customers that already have your app — which you can do with deep linking. For example, let’s say a customer is searching for new shoes on her mobile browser and sees your ad. With deep linking, she will land on the in-app product page and can check out faster, improving the customer experience and driving better campaign performance. On average, advertisers who have implemented deep linking are seeing over 2X uplift in conversion rate.&lt;footnote id="1ebf6706-480b-4fd0-bac4-2be887fcc59a"&gt;[1ebf67]&lt;/footnote&gt;Creating this smooth experience requires technical implementation, and Web to App Connect offers tools to help simplify this workflow.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="hm4v"&gt;Canadian Tire, one of the leading retailers in Canada, has already seen success implementing optimized experiences with Web to App Connect.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-pull_quote"&gt;&lt;div class="uni-pull-quote h-c-page"&gt;&lt;section class="h-c-grid"&gt;&lt;div class="uni-pull-quote__wrapper h-c-grid__col h-c-grid__col--8 h-c-grid__col-m--6 h-c-grid__col-l--6 h-c-grid__col--offset-2 h-c-grid__col-m--offset-3 h-c-grid__col-l--offset-3"&gt;&lt;div class="uni-pull-quote__inner-wrapper h-c-copy h-c-copy"&gt;&lt;q class="uni-pull-quote__text"&gt;Web to App Connect made it easier for my team to collaborate with our developers to ensure our app users aren’t having clunky experiences.&lt;/q&gt; &lt;cite class="uni-pull-quote__author"&gt;&lt;figure class="uni-pull-quote__author-photo"&gt;&lt;picture&gt;&lt;source media="(max-resolution: 1.5dppx)" sizes="48px" srcset="https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/ctlogo2022-100.max-100x100.png 48w"/&gt;&lt;source media="(min-resolution: 1.5dppx)" sizes="89px" srcset="https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/ctlogo2022-100.max-100x100.png 89w"/&gt;&lt;img alt="ctlogo2022-100" data-target="image" loading="lazy" sizes=" 48px,  89px" src="https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/ctlogo2022-100.max-100x100.png" srcset="https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/ctlogo2022-100.max-100x100.png 48w, https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/ctlogo2022-100.max-100x100.png 89w"/&gt;&lt;/picture&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;span class="uni-pull-quote__author-meta"&gt;&lt;strong class="h-u-font-weight-medium"&gt;Vera Bondareva&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt; Marketing Manager, Canadian Tire&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-paragraph"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="va4cb"&gt;Web to App Connect will be available in beta early next year. You can &lt;a href="https://services.google.com/fb/forms/w2ac_openbeta_interest_form/"&gt;express interest in being a part of the upcoming beta today&lt;/a&gt; and explore &lt;a href="https://support.google.com/google-ads/answer/12131000"&gt;this guide&lt;/a&gt; to learn more about the toolkit.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-paragraph"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;h3 data-block-key="va4cb"&gt;Optimize performance with privacy-focused measurement&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="1h3r2"&gt;To be set up for long-term success, today’s leading marketers should prioritize measurement solutions that both deliver performance and protect user privacy. &lt;a href="https://firebase.google.com/products/analytics"&gt;Google Analytics for Firebase&lt;/a&gt;, our privacy-forward measurement solution, provides powerful cross-platform measurement capabilities to help you understand how your users engage with your app and optimize your App campaign attribution, reach and performance.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="619ms"&gt;Vinted, a European marketplace for secondhand clothing, wanted to improve app performance by achieving more in-app actions and optimizing their cost per in-app action. After implementing and bidding on conversions from Google Analytics for Firebase, they were able to achieve 128% more in-app actions on iOS compared to their existing measurement solution, increase installs by 92%, and decrease their cost-per-engagement by 22%.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-pull_quote"&gt;&lt;div class="uni-pull-quote h-c-page"&gt;&lt;section class="h-c-grid"&gt;&lt;div class="uni-pull-quote__wrapper h-c-grid__col h-c-grid__col--8 h-c-grid__col-m--6 h-c-grid__col-l--6 h-c-grid__col--offset-2 h-c-grid__col-m--offset-3 h-c-grid__col-l--offset-3"&gt;&lt;div class="uni-pull-quote__inner-wrapper h-c-copy h-c-copy"&gt;&lt;q class="uni-pull-quote__text"&gt;After the transfer, we saw an immediate iOS performance impact and unlocked new opportunities.&lt;/q&gt; &lt;cite class="uni-pull-quote__author"&gt;&lt;figure class="uni-pull-quote__author-photo"&gt;&lt;picture&gt;&lt;source media="(max-resolution: 1.5dppx)" sizes="48px" srcset="https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/100-Logo_symbol_-_512x512_-_inverse1x.max-100x100.png 48w"/&gt;&lt;source media="(min-resolution: 1.5dppx)" sizes="96px" srcset="https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/100-Logo_symbol_-_512x512_-_inverse1x.max-100x100.png 96w"/&gt;&lt;img alt="100-Logo symbol - 512x512 - inverse@1x" data-target="image" loading="lazy" sizes=" 48px,  96px" src="https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/100-Logo_symbol_-_512x512_-_inverse1x.max-100x100.png" srcset="https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/100-Logo_symbol_-_512x512_-_inverse1x.max-100x100.png 48w, https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/100-Logo_symbol_-_512x512_-_inverse1x.max-100x100.png 96w"/&gt;&lt;/picture&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;span class="uni-pull-quote__author-meta"&gt;&lt;strong class="h-u-font-weight-medium"&gt;Ali Mehrabiyan&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt; Digital Marketing Manager, Vinted&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-paragraph"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="6j341"&gt;When you implement Google Analytics for Firebase, you also unlock exclusive features like &lt;a href="https://support.google.com/google-ads/answer/9865058"&gt;audience management&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://support.google.com/google-ads/answer/6268637#:~:text=Your%20target%20ROAS%20is%20the,traffic%20your%20ads%20may%20get"&gt;tROAS bidding&lt;/a&gt; for App campaigns. And over the next few months we’re rolling out additional benefits, including:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li data-block-key="f1lh3"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Maximized performance:&lt;/b&gt; You’ll have the ability to use additional consented, signed-in data to automatically improve App campaign ramp up and modeling to more efficiently reach consumers.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li data-block-key="f4c3"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Expanded inventory:&lt;/b&gt; Connected TV continues to grow in viewership, and by early next year, advertisers will get access to this key channel and the ability to measure performance across devices.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li data-block-key="5pq1n"&gt;&lt;b&gt;New audience lists:&lt;/b&gt; You’ll have the ability to more easily engage existing app users who have not been reached with push notifications.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-image_full_width"&gt;&lt;div class="h-c-page"&gt;&lt;div class="article-image h-c-grid__col--10 h-c-grid__col--offset-1 h-c-grid__col-l--offset-2 h-c-grid__col-l--8"&gt;&lt;a class="article-image--link"&gt;&lt;img alt="Screengrab of new audience list which enables Google Analytics for Firebase users to easily engage existing app users who have not been reached with push notifications" class="article-image--full" data-loading='{
                "mobile": "https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/Unnotifed_audience_list_updated_zoom_in_VLfE.max-500x500.png",
                "desktop": "https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/Unnotifed_audience_list_updated_zoom_in_VL.max-1000x1000.png"
              }' loading="lazy" src=" https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/Unnotifed_audience_list_updated_zoom_in_VLfE.max-100x100.png " tabindex="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-paragraph"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;h3 data-block-key="6j341"&gt;Adapt to shifts in platform standards on iOS and Android&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="3l3q8"&gt;User expectations for privacy continue to grow, and updates such as last year’s rollout of the &lt;a href="https://developer.apple.com/documentation/apptrackingtransparency"&gt;AppTrackingTransparency&lt;/a&gt; (ATT) framework on iOS have made measurement more complex. That’s why we’re supporting solutions that help advertisers navigate these changes, including the new &lt;a href="https://developer.apple.com/app-store/ad-attribution/"&gt;version 4.0 updates to SKAdNetwork&lt;/a&gt;, Apple’s measurement API.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="1eh38"&gt;Throughout 2023, we’re improving modeled reporting consistency for iOS app installs across measurement platforms in Google Ads. Next year, we’ll also release tools for advertisers using the Google Analytics for Firebase SDK, which streamline setting up SKAdNetwork conversion values and help better optimize their campaigns for in-app actions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="1kur2"&gt;Developing these new solutions will take time, but you can start taking steps today to get ahead. For example, to enhance conversion modeling and reporting accuracy, you can adopt &lt;a href="https://support.google.com/google-ads/answer/12119136"&gt;on-device conversion measurement&lt;/a&gt;, a privacy-preserving solution we released earlier this year. With on-device conversion measurement, user interactions with app ads can be matched to app conversions in a way that prevents user-identifying information from leaving a user's device. You can also start setting up SKAdNetwork conversion values yourself or work with a measurement partner, such as our &lt;a href="https://ads.google.com/lp/appcampaigns/attribution"&gt;App Attribution Partners&lt;/a&gt;. Lastly, explore &lt;a href="https://support.google.com/google-ads/answer/10384955"&gt;this guide&lt;/a&gt; to learn more best practices for your iOS App campaigns.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="7ocj4"&gt;And while nothing is changing today for Android App campaigns, we recently &lt;a href="https://support.google.com/google-ads/answer/12791813"&gt;provided an update&lt;/a&gt; on our participation in the &lt;a href="https://blog.google/products/android/introducing-privacy-sandbox-android/"&gt;Privacy Sandbox on Android&lt;/a&gt; initiative. We regularly share feedback with Android about its public proposals so that the new privacy-preserving technologies can help you reach the right audiences, and more accurately measure your campaign results with less reliance on tracking identifiers. And we’ll be sharing what we’ve learned throughout 2023 on the experiments we participate in.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2022 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.google/products/ads-commerce/app-measurement-strategies-business-growth/</guid><category>Google Ads</category><category>App Ads</category><media:content height="540" url="https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/GPM-_blog_post_-_Hero-v3_1.max-600x600.png" width="540"/><og xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#"><type>article</type><title>3 app measurement strategies for business growth</title><description>Marketers are investing more in their apps and should prioritize these three app measurement strategies to drive long-term business results.</description><image>https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/GPM-_blog_post_-_Hero-v3_1.max-600x600.png</image><site_name>Google</site_name><url>https://blog.google/products/ads-commerce/app-measurement-strategies-business-growth/</url></og><author xmlns:author="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><name>David Mitby</name><title>Director, Product Management, App Ads</title><department/><company/></author></item><item><title>Introducing two new solutions powered by Ads Data Hub</title><link>https://blog.google/products/marketingplatform/360/ads-data-hub-powered-solutions/</link><description>&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;div class="block-paragraph"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="hzyns"&gt;Ads Data Hub helps advertisers, agencies and measurement partners do customized analysis of campaigns while protecting user privacy. More than 3,000 brands, agencies, and measurement partners use cloud-based Ads Data Hub to perform analyses for their specific business objectives.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="2rk4r"&gt;Customers of Ads Data Hub have different needs, so we’ve created more specialized entry points to get started. Marketers require tools to quantify a consumer’s path to purchase and the ability to activate new audiences. At the same time, measurement partners conduct third-party assessment of metrics such as video viewability and audience reach.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="eucc7"&gt;To offer a more tailored experience, we are introducing an evolution to the Ads Data Hub core platform by introducing two dedicated solutions: Ads Data Hub for Marketers and Ads Data Hub for Measurement Partners.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 data-block-key="d742d"&gt;New solutions for more catered needs&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="eh32e"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Ads Data Hub for Marketers&lt;/b&gt; offers a new way for advertisers and agencies to analyze their data. With this solution, they can seamlessly access insights to better inform the way they purchase media. This means a simplified experience for marketers running queries and activating their first-party data.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="7cpfi"&gt;&lt;a href="https://marketingplatform.google.com/about/resources/riot-games-uses-google-marketing-platform-to-level-up-their-player-base/"&gt;Riot Games&lt;/a&gt;, for example, used Ads Data Hub for richer marketing analyses. The company centralized their insights and combined them with Display &amp;amp; Video 360 and Campaign Manager 360 data. This let Riot Games attribute credit to various ad touch points, accurately measure return on ad spend (ROAS), and establish a new benchmark showing that for every $1 Riot Games spent on Google media, it received $2 in revenue. Marketers, like Riot Games, perform these analyses regularly, with hundreds of thousands of queries run in 2022 alone.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="3sni5"&gt;Over time, new query templates, automated workflows, and updates to reporting will reduce the need for additional technical resources and decrease time to generate insights - with plans to implement &lt;a href="https://blog.google/products/marketingplatform/360/engage-your-first-party-audience-in-display-video-360/"&gt;Publisher Advertiser Identity Reconciliation&lt;/a&gt;, also known as PAIR. In addition to these improvements, marketers will soon be able to activate their audience segments on new inventory, including YouTube. As privacy expectations evolve, we will continue to build more solutions that enable advertisers and agencies to measure and activate their first-party data with Ads Data Hub for Marketers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="fkerc"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Ads Data Hub for Measurement Partners&lt;/b&gt; gives partners a new access point to provide YouTube measurement services on behalf of marketers, advertisers, agencies, or publishers. With this launch, it’ll be easier for partners to offer accurate measurement and deliver near real-time insights. For marketers, this means they can work with independent third-party partners to calculate and report on YouTube ad performance across devices, formats, and metrics.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="avuji"&gt;These third-party independent measurement services are available to marketers via our growing partner ecosystem. With Dynata, and other vendors, we have expanded measurement services on Ads Data Hub to enable cross-media solutions for YouTube. Customers will be able to analyze the performance of YouTube campaigns relative to other media channels (including linear TV, streaming TV, or online video sources). Another partner, DoubleVerify, has earned YouTube Video Viewability accreditation by the Media Rating Council (MRC), in addition to Ads Data Hub’s own &lt;a href="https://blog.google/products/ads-commerce/privacy-centric-measurement-youtube/"&gt;accreditation&lt;/a&gt; announced last year.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="2prs4"&gt;In 2023 we plan to integrate with new partners such as iSpot and VideoAmp, joining the list of measurement partners &lt;a href="https://developers.google.com/ads-data-hub/vendors/adh-vendors"&gt;already&lt;/a&gt; available with Ads Data Hub.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 data-block-key="a8l1o"&gt;Commitment to a privacy-centric future&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="ce2ji"&gt;Marketers and measurement partners will benefit from rigorous privacy checks that protect the personal data of users online while still being able to perform comprehensive analytics. These analyses, in addition to insight generation and audience activation, can all be performed with Ads Data Hub users only having access to aggregated data. By investing in privacy-centric solutions that address the specific needs of marketers and measurement partners, we've simplified the path to accurate measurement across YouTube and Google campaigns.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2022 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.google/products/marketingplatform/360/ads-data-hub-powered-solutions/</guid><category>Attribution</category><category>Google Marketing Platform</category><category>YouTube</category><media:content height="540" url="https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/E02789775_Google_GMP_ADH_Rebrand_Asset_Sep22.max-600x600_yCkO8tO.png" width="540"/><og xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#"><type>article</type><title>Introducing two new solutions powered by Ads Data Hub</title><description>Ads Data Hub’s new solutions deliver analytics for marketers to generate insights while enabling the third-party measurement ecosystem.</description><image>https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/E02789775_Google_GMP_ADH_Rebrand_Asset_Sep22.max-600x600_yCkO8tO.png</image><site_name>Google</site_name><url>https://blog.google/products/marketingplatform/360/ads-data-hub-powered-solutions/</url></og><author xmlns:author="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><name>Prema Sampath</name><title>Director</title><department>Product Management, Google Ads</department><company/></author></item><item><title>How Scrolla is making news more accessible to South Africans</title><link>https://blog.google/outreach-initiatives/google-news-initiative/how-scrolla-is-making-news-more-accessible-to-south-africans/</link><description>&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;div class="block-paragraph"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="3bxjn"&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;Editor’s note from Ludovic Blecher, Head of Google News Initiative Innovation:&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;i&gt;The&lt;/i&gt; &lt;a href="https://newsinitiative.withgoogle.com/innovation-challenges"&gt;&lt;i&gt;GNI Innovation Challenge&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;i&gt;program, is designed to stimulate forward-thinking ideas for the news industry. The story below by Mungo Soggot, CEO of Scrolla, is part of an&lt;/i&gt; &lt;a href="https://blog.google/outreach-initiatives/google-news-initiative/newsroom-stories-gni-innovation-challenge/"&gt;&lt;i&gt;innovator series&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;i&gt;sharing inspiring stories and lessons from funded projects.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt; The costs associated with paying for mobile phone data in many African countries are often incredibly high, making it prohibitive for lower income readers to access news. As our mission is to bring high quality news on mobile phones to underserved communities, we set out to create a new product for &lt;a href="https://scrolla.africa/"&gt;Scrolla.Africa&lt;/a&gt; which is light on data use. The new platform is called &lt;a href="https://lite.scrolla.africa/"&gt;Scrolla Data Lite&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="fb4k4"&gt;Our core readers are pay-as-you-go mobile users, who make up about 75% of the market in South Africa. We found that people on these expensive pay-as-you-go data services were extremely cautious about downloading anything or surfing online. So beyond using data for messaging services, the idea of browsing on mobiles for news is regarded as a privilege.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="3r7pm"&gt;As a mobile-only investigative and political reporting outlet, we were operating on a shoestring budget when we launched, so the data use issue was not something we had the technical capacity to address. We decided it had to wait until we had evolved the prototype and our editorial colleagues — Everson Luhanga and Phillip van Niekerk — had established Scrolla’s editorial ethos.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="4nv1r"&gt;Our big break came when we were selected for the Google News Initiative &lt;a href="https://newsinitiative.withgoogle.com/innovation-challenges/selected-projects/?region=middle-east-africa-turkey"&gt;Innovation Challenge for the Middle East, Turkey and Africa&lt;/a&gt; in 2021. We had a rough outline of how we would design a separate “Data Lite” site, which we used as the basis for our application. The Data Lite site doesn’t contain video or audio, and has stripped back features allowing for faster scrolling. The goals were to compress stories and images as much as possible and to automate the process so that our small team didn’t have to learn a new Content Management System (CMS). As a recipient of funding, we could build a Data Lite site far quicker and better than would have otherwise been possible, and bring in external engineering expertise to design the new platform.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="1uf54"&gt;The site ended up saving readers 90% on the data costs of our “full fat” site, when we compare the 100 kilobytes on page downloads on Data Lite to our usual 1 megabyte. And this meant the Data Lite site gave us about a sixfold increase in traffic compared with the full data site. We couldn’t use video or audio on the new Data Lite site, which remains its only drawback. When it came to images, we gave the editorial team strict guidelines to minimize data use without compromising user experience. This left room for error, so we then built in additional automated safeguards which ensured that uploaded images didn’t risk leaving readers with a spike in data costs.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="3qppi"&gt;Alongside data costs, language is an additional barrier in South Africa, so we publish in Zulu as well as English. Crucially, the GNI funding allowed us to design a system where we could include our Zulu content, together with English (a second language in South Africa), on one platform. The site had to be super easy to navigate and allow users to toggle between English and Zulu.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-image_full_width"&gt;&lt;div class="h-c-page"&gt;&lt;div class="article-image__is-caption h-c-grid__col-l--6 h-c-grid__col--8 h-c-grid__col-l--offset-3 h-c-grid__col--offset-2"&gt;&lt;a class="article-image--link"&gt;&lt;img alt="Picture shows a screen grab from the Zulu language mobile phone app." class="article-image--large" data-loading='{
                "mobile": "https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/Scrolla_Data_Lite_Zulu_1.max-500x500.jpg",
                "desktop": "https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/Scrolla_Data_Lite_Zulu_1.max-1000x1000.jpg"
              }' loading="lazy" src=" https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/Scrolla_Data_Lite_Zulu_1.max-100x100.jpg " tabindex="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption class="article-image__caption article-image__is-caption-image h-c-grid__col--8 h-c-grid__col--offset-2 h-c-grid__col-l--6 h-c-grid__col-l--offset-3"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="6bkd7"&gt;A screengrab of the Scrolla app featuring the Zulu language.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-paragraph"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="3bxjn"&gt;The biggest lesson we learned is it’s impossible to underestimate what a big deal these data costs are: to the extent that many readers are wary of downloading apps or touching the sort of advertisements which typically require a lot of data such as those with video. The GNI enabled us to build the site, and we're open to sharing the technology with other like-minded publications in Africa and beyond.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2022 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.google/outreach-initiatives/google-news-initiative/how-scrolla-is-making-news-more-accessible-to-south-africans/</guid><category>Google News Initiative</category><category>Google in Africa</category><media:content height="540" url="https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/scrolla_iGPwS2n.max-600x600.jpg" width="540"/><og xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#"><type>article</type><title>How Scrolla is making news more accessible to South Africans</title><description>News innovator Scrolla built a ‘Data Lite’ site to make it less expensive for people to access news in South Africa.</description><image>https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/scrolla_iGPwS2n.max-600x600.jpg</image><site_name>Google</site_name><url>https://blog.google/outreach-initiatives/google-news-initiative/how-scrolla-is-making-news-more-accessible-to-south-africans/</url></og><author xmlns:author="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><name>Mungo Soggot</name><title>CEO of Scrolla</title><department/><company/></author></item></channel></rss>