<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<rdf:RDF
 xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
 xmlns="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/"
 xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
 xmlns:taxo="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/taxonomy/"
 xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
 xmlns:syn="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
 xmlns:admin="http://webns.net/mvcb/"
>

<channel rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/">
<title>physics.app-ph updates on arXiv.org</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">Physics -- Applied Physics (physics.app-ph) updates on the arXiv.org e-print archive</description>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:date>2022-11-03T20:30:00-05:00</dc:date>
<dc:publisher>help@arxiv.org</dc:publisher>
<dc:subject>Physics -- Applied Physics</dc:subject>
<syn:updateBase>1901-01-01T00:00+00:00</syn:updateBase>
<syn:updateFrequency>1</syn:updateFrequency>
<syn:updatePeriod>daily</syn:updatePeriod>
<items>
 <rdf:Seq>
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01408" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01423" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01437" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01489" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01584" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01593" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01968" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2111.05841" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2111.08760" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2201.06864" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2209.15187" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.00560" />
 </rdf:Seq>
</items>
<image rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif" />
</channel>
<image rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif">
<title>arXiv.org</title>
<url>http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif</url>
<link>http://arxiv.org/</link>
</image>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01408">
<title>Design of a Modified Coupled Resonators Optical Waveguide Supporting a Frozen Mode. (arXiv:2211.01408v1 [physics.optics])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01408</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We design a three-way silicon optical waveguide with the Bloch dispersion
relation supporting a stationary inflection point (SIP). The SIP is a third
order exceptional point of degeneracy (EPD) where three Bloch modes coalesce
forming the frozen mode with greatly enhanced amplitude. The proposed design
consists of a coupled resonators optical waveguide (CROW) coupled to a parallel
straight waveguide. At any given frequency, this structure supports three pairs
of reciprocal Bloch eigenmodes, propagating and/or evanescent. In addition to
full-wave simulations, we also employ a so-called &apos;&apos;hybrid model&apos;&apos; that uses
transfer matrices obtained from full-wave simulations of sub-blocks of the unit
cell. This allows us to account for radiation losses and enables a design
procedure based on minimizing the eigenmodes&apos; coalescence parameter. The
proposed finite-length CROW displays almost unitary transfer function at the
SIP frequency, implying a nearly perfect conversion of the input light into the
frozen mode. The group delay and the effective quality factor at the SIP
frequency show an $N^{3}$ scaling, where $N$ is the number of unit cells in the
cavity. The frozen mode in the CROW can be utilized in various applications
like sensors, lasers and optical delay lines.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Nada_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Mohamed Y. Nada&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Mealy_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Tarek Mealy&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Islam_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Md Shafiqul Islam&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Vitebskiy_I/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ilya Vitebskiy&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Gibson_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ricky Gibson&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Bedford_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Robert Bedford&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Boyraz_O/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ozdal Boyraz&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Capolino_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Filippo Capolino&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01423">
<title>Theory of Truncation Resonances in Continuum Rod-based Phononic Crystals with Generally Asymmetric Unit Cells. (arXiv:2211.01423v1 [physics.app-ph])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01423</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Phononic crystals exhibit Bragg bandgaps, frequency regions within which wave
propagation is forbidden. In solid continua, such bandgaps are the outcome of
destructive interferences resulting from periodically alternating layers. Under
certain conditions, natural frequencies emerge within these bandgaps in the
form of high-amplitude localized vibrations near one boundary of the structure.
In this paper, we investigate the vibrational spectrum of finite phononic
crystals which take the form a one-dimensional rod, and explain the fundamental
factors that contribute to the origination of truncation resonances. By
identifying a unit cell symmetry parameter, we define a family of finite
phononic rods which share the same unit cell dispersion relation, yet distinct
truncated forms. A transfer matrix method is utilized to derive closed-form
expressions of the characteristic equations governing the natural frequencies
of the finite system and decipher the truncation resonances emerging across
different boundary conditions. The presented analysis establishes concrete
connections between the localized vibrations associated with a truncation
resonance, the corresponding boundary condition, and the overall configuration
of the truncated chain as dictated by the unit cell choice. The study provides
tools to predict, tune, and selectively design truncation resonances, to meet
the demands of various applications that require such truncation resonances.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Babaa_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Hasan B. Al Ba&amp;#x27;ba&amp;#x27;a&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Willey_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Carson L. Willey&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Chen_V/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Vincent W. Chen&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Juhl_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Abigail T. Juhl&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Nouh_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Mostafa Nouh&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01437">
<title>Multi-photon polymerization using upconversion nanoparticles for tunable feature-size printing. (arXiv:2211.01437v1 [physics.optics])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01437</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The recent development of light-based 3D printing technologies has marked a
turning point in additive manufacturing. Through photopolymerization, liquid
resins can be solidified into complex objects. Usually, the polymerization is
triggered by exciting a photoinitiator with ultraviolet (UV) or blue light. In
two-photon printing (TPP), the excitation is done through the non-linear
absorption of two photons; it enables printing 100-nm voxels but requires
expensive femtosecond lasers which strongly limits their broad dissemination.
Upconversion nanoparticles (UCNPs) have recently been proposed as an
alternative to TPP for photopolymerization but using continuous-wave lasers.
UCNPs convert near-infrared (NIR) into visible/UV light to initiate the
polymerization locally as in TPP. Here we provide a study of this multi-photon
mechanism and demonstrate how the non-linearity impacts the printing process.
In particular, we report on the possibility of fine-tuning the size of the
printed voxel by adjusting the NIR excitation intensity. Using gelatin-based
hydrogel, we are able to vary the transverse voxel size from 1.3 to 2.8 {\mu}m
and the axial size from 7.7 to 59 {\mu}m by adjusting the NIR power without
changing the degree of polymerization. This work opens up new opportunities for
speeding up the fabrication while preserving the minimum feature size with
cheap light sources.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Zhang_Q/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Qianyi Zhang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Boniface_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Antoine Boniface&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Parashar_V/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Virendra K. Parashar&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Gijs_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Martin A. M. Gijs&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Moser_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Christophe Moser&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01489">
<title>Chip-scale Simulations in a Quantum-correlated Synthetic Space. (arXiv:2211.01489v1 [physics.optics])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01489</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;An efficient simulator for quantum systems is one of the original goals for
the efforts to develop a quantum computer [1]. In recent years, synthetic
dimension in photonics [2] have emerged as a potentially powerful approach for
simulation that is free from the constraint of geometric dimensionality. Here
we demonstrate a quantum-correlated synthetic crystal, based upon a
coherently-controlled broadband quantum frequency comb produced in a chip-scale
dynamically modulated lithium niobate microresonator. The time-frequency
entanglement inherent with the comb modes significantly extends the
dimensionality of the synthetic space, creating a massive nearly 400 x 400
synthetic lattice with electrically-controlled tunability. With such a system,
we are able to utilize the evolution of quantum correlations between entangled
photons to perform a series of simulations, demonstrating quantum random walks,
Bloch oscillations, and multi-level Rabi oscillations in the time and frequency
correlation space. The device combines the simplicity of monolithic
nanophotonic architecture, high dimensionality of a quantum-correlated
synthetic space, and on-chip coherent control, which opens up an avenue towards
chip-scale implementation of large-scale analog quantum simulation and
computation [1,3,4] in the time-frequency domain.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Javid_U/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Usman A. Javid&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Lopez_Rios_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Raymond Lopez-Rios&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Ling_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jingwei Ling&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Graf_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Austin Graf&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Staffa_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jeremy Staffa&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Lin_Q/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Qiang Lin&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01584">
<title>Memory Window in Ferroelectric Field-Effect Transistors: Analytical Approach. (arXiv:2211.01584v1 [physics.app-ph])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01584</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;A memory window of ferroelectric field-effect transistors (FeFETs), defined
as a separation of the HIGH-state and the LOW-state threshold voltages, is an
important measure of the FeFET memory characteristics. In this study, we
theoretically investigate the relation between the FeFET memory window and the
P-E hysteresis loop of the ferroelectric gate insulator, and derive a compact
model explicitly described by material parameters. It is found that the memory
window is linearly proportional to the ferroelectric polarization for the small
polarization regime, and converges to the limit value of 2 x coercive field x
thickness when the remanent polarization is much larger than permittivity x
coercive field. We discuss additional factors that possibly influence the
memory window in actual devices such as the existence of interlayer (no direct
impact), interface charges (invalidity of linear superposition between the
ferroelectric and charge-trapping hysteresis), and minor-loop operation
(behavior equivalent to the generation of interface charges).
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Toprasertpong_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Kasidit Toprasertpong&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Takenaka_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Mitsuru Takenaka&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Takagi_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Shinichi Takagi&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01593">
<title>Electron Quantum Tunneling Sensors. (arXiv:2211.01593v1 [physics.app-ph])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01593</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Quantum tunneling sensors are typically ultra-sensitive devices which have
been specifically designed to convert a stimulus into an electronic signal
using the wondrous principles of quantum mechanical tunneling. In the early
1990s, William Kaiser developed one of the first micromachined quantum
tunneling sensors as part of his work with the Nasa Jet Propulsion Laboratory.
Since then, there have been scattered attempts at utilizing this phenomenon for
the development of a variety of physical and chemical sensors. Although these
devices demonstrate unique characteristics such as high sensitivity, the
principle of quantum tunneling often acts as a double-edged sword and is
responsible for certain drawbacks of this sensor family. In this review, we
briefly explain the underlying working principles of quantum tunneling and how
they are used to design miniaturized quantum tunneling sensors. We then proceed
to describe an overview of the various attempts at developing such sensors.
Next, we discuss their current need and recent resurgence. Finally, we describe
various advantages and shortcomings of these sensors and end this review with
an insight into the potential of this technology and prospects.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Banerjee_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Aishwaryadev Banerjee&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Mastrangelo_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Carlos H. Mastrangelo&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01968">
<title>Longitudinal waves dispersion control through the affine deformation of the interlaced wire medium. (arXiv:2211.01968v1 [physics.class-ph])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01968</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We have studied dispersion properties of interlaced wire media with geometry
deformed by affine transformation. It is revealed that the metamaterials
support eigenmodes with longitudinal polarization at low frequency range for
all deformations. The isofrequency surfaces of the matamaterial are centered at
the points at the edges of the Brillouin zone (not at Gamma-point) and have
shape of ellipsoids. The refraction indexes corresponding to the ellipsoids are
analysed both analytically and numerically.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Sakhno_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Denis Sakhno&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Koreshin_E/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Eugene Koreshin&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Belov_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Pavel A. Belov&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2111.05841">
<title>Physics-enhanced deep surrogates for PDEs. (arXiv:2111.05841v2 [cs.LG] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2111.05841</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We present a &apos;&apos;physics-enhanced deep-surrogate&apos;&apos; (&apos;&apos;PEDS&apos;&apos;) approach towards
developing fast surrogate models for complex physical systems, which is
described by partial differential equations (PDEs) and similar models.
Specifically, a unique combination of a low-fidelity, explainable physics
simulator and a neural network generator is proposed, which is trained
end-to-end to globally match the output of an expensive high-fidelity numerical
solver. We consider low-fidelity models derived from coarser discretizations
and/or by simplifying the physical equations, which are several orders of
magnitude faster than a high-fidelity &apos;&apos;brute-force&apos;&apos; PDE solver. The neural
network generates an approximate input, which is adaptively mixed with a
downsampled guess and fed into the low-fidelity simulator. In this way, by
incorporating the limited physical knowledge from the differentiable
low-fidelity model &apos;&apos;layer&apos;&apos;, we ensure that the conservation laws and
symmetries governing the system are respected by the design of our hybrid
system. Experiments on three test problems -- diffusion, reaction-diffusion,
and electromagnetic scattering models -- show that a PEDS surrogate can be up
to 3$\times$ more accurate than a &apos;&apos;black-box&apos;&apos; neural network with limited
data ($\approx 10^3$ training points), and reduces the data needed by at least
a factor of 100 for a target error of $5\%$, comparable to fabrication
uncertainty. PEDS even appears to learn with a steeper asymptotic power law
than black-box surrogates. In summary, PEDS provides a general, data-driven
strategy to bridge the gap between a vast array of simplified physical models
with corresponding brute-force numerical solvers, offering accuracy, speed,
data efficiency, as well as physical insights into the process.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Pestourie_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Rapha&amp;#xeb;l Pestourie&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Mroueh_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Youssef Mroueh&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Rackauckas_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Chris Rackauckas&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Das_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Payel Das&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Johnson_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Steven G. Johnson&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2111.08760">
<title>Field Synthesis with Azimuthally-Varying, Cascaded, Cylindrical Metasurfaces using a Wave Matrix Approach. (arXiv:2111.08760v2 [physics.app-ph] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2111.08760</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;In recent years, there has been extensive research on planar metasurfaces
capable of arbitrarily controlling scattered fields. However, rigorous studies
on conformal metasurfaces, such as those that are cylindrical, have been few in
number likely due to their more complex geometry. Here, wave propagation in
cascaded cylindrical structures consisting of layers of dielectric spacers and
azimuthally-varying metasurfaces (subwavelength patterned metallic claddings)
is investigated. A wave matrix approach, which incorporates the advantages of
both ABCD matrices and scattering matrices (S matrices), is adopted. Wave
matrices are used to model the higher order coupling between metasurface
layers, overcoming fabrication difficulties associated with previous works. The
proposed framework provides an efficient approach to synthesize the
inhomogeneous sheet admittances that realize a desired cylindrical field
transformation. Design examples are reported to illustrate the power and
potential applications of the proposed method in antenna design and stealth
technology.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Lin_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Chun-Wen Lin&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Grbic_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Anthony Grbic&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2201.06864">
<title>Acoustic monitoring of the gelation of a colloidal suspension. (arXiv:2201.06864v2 [cond-mat.soft] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2201.06864</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Because they are sensitive to mechanical properties of materials and can
propagate even in opaque systems, acoustic waves provides us with a powerful
characterization tool in numerous fields. Common techniques mostly rely on
time-of-flight measurements and do not exploit the spectral content: however,
sound speed and attenuation spectra contain rich information. Such an acoustic
spectroscopy already exists and allows to retrieve subtle information on
systems of well-known physico-chemistry, but modeling becomes out of reach for
industrial systems. In this article, we use a simple empirical approach to
monitor the gelation of silica suspensions: we show that the gelation time
obtained from acoustic measurements is proportional to this determined with
more conventional rheological characterization. Such a results thus opens the
way for in-situ monitoring of time-evolving systems in industrial context with
acoustic methods only.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Belicard_N/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Nicolas B&amp;#xe9;licard&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Niemet_Mabiala_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Marc Junior Ni&amp;#xe9;met-Mabiala&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Tourvieille_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jean-No&amp;#xeb;l Tourvieille&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Lidon_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Pierre Lidon&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2209.15187">
<title>Perspectives on Antiferromagnetic Spintronics. (arXiv:2209.15187v2 [cond-mat.mtrl-sci] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2209.15187</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Although the development of spintronic devices has advanced significantly
over the past decade with the use of ferromagnetic materials, the extensive
implementation of such devices has been limited by the notable drawbacks of
these materials. Antiferromagnets claim to resolve many of these shortcomings
leading to faster, smaller, more energy-efficient, and more robust electronics.
Antiferromagnets exhibit many desirable properties including zero net
magnetization, imperviousness to external magnetic fields, intrinsic
high-frequency dynamics with a characteristic precession frequency on the order
of terahertz (THz), and the ability to serve as passive exchange-bias materials
in multiple magnetoresistance (MR)- based devices. In this Perspective article,
we will discuss the fundamental physics of magnetic structures in
antiferromagnets and their interactions with external stimuli such as spin
current, voltage, and magnons. A discussion on the challenges lying ahead is
also provided along with an outlook of future research directions of these
systems.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Wang_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Kang Wang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Bheemarasetty_V/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Vineetha Bheemarasetty&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Duan_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Junhang Duan&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Zhou_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Shiyu Zhou&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Xiao_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Gang Xiao&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.00560">
<title>2D Janus Niobium Oxydihalide NbO$XY$: Multifunctional High-Mobility Piezoelectric Semiconductor for Electronics, Photonics and Sustainable Energy Applications. (arXiv:2211.00560v2 [cond-mat.mtrl-sci] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.00560</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Two-dimensional (2D) niobium oxydihalide NbOI$_2$ has been recently
demonstrated as an excellent in-plane piezoelectric and nonlinear optical
materials. Here we show that Janus niobium oxydihalide, NbO$XY$ (X, Y = Cl, Br,
I and X$\neq$Y), is a multifunctional anisotropic semiconductor family with
exceptional piezoelectric, electronic, photocatalytic and optical properties.
NbO$XY$ are stable and mechancially flexible monolayers with band gap around
the visible light regime of $\sim 1.9$ eV. The anisotropic carrier mobility of
NbO$XY$ lies in the range of $10^3 \sim 10^4$ cm$^2$V$^{-1}$s$^{-1}$, which
represents some of the highest among 2D semiconductors of bandgap $\gtrsim 2$
eV. Inversion symmetry breaking in Janus NbO$XY$ generates sizable out-of-plane
$d_{31}$ piezoelectric response while still retaining a strong in-plane
piezoelectricity. Remarkably, NbO$XY$ exhibits an additional out-of-plane
piezoelectric response, $d_{32}$ as large as 0.55 pm/V. G$_0$W$_0$-BSE
calculation further reveals the strong linear optical dichroism of NbO$XY$ in
the visible-to-ultraviolet regime. The optical absorption peaks with $14\sim18$
\% in the deep UV regime ($5\sim6$ eV), outperforming the vast majority of
other 2D materials. The high carrier mobility, strong optical absorption,
sizable built-in electric field and band alignment compatible with overall
water splitting further suggest the strengths of NbO$XY$ in energy conversion
application. We further propose a directional stress sensing device to
demonstrate how the out-of-plane piezoelectricity can be harnessed for
functional device applications. Our findings unveil NbO$XY$ as an exceptional
multifunctional 2D semiconductor for flexible electronics, optoelectronics, UV
photonics, piezoelectric and sustainable energy applications.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Su_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Tong Su&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Lee_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ching Hua Lee&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Guo_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;San-Dong Guo&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Wang_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Guangzhao Wang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Ong_W/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Wee-Liat Ong&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Zhao_W/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Weiwei Zhao&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Yang_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Shengyuan A. Yang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Ang_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yee Sin Ang&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
</rdf:RDF>