<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd"><channel><title><![CDATA[Foreign Exchanges: the Podcast]]></title><description><![CDATA[Foreign Exchanges is a newsletter and podcast that helps you stay on top of important stories happening around the world. Derek Davison interviews scholars, journalists, and other experts to make sense of international affairs and US foreign policy. <br/><br/><a href="https://fx.substack.com/s/foreign-exchanges?utm_medium=podcast">fx.substack.com</a>]]></description><link>https://fx.substack.com/s/foreign-exchanges</link><generator>Substack</generator><lastBuildDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2022 16:39:54 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://api.substack.com/feed/podcast/6479/s/519.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><author><![CDATA[Derek Davison]]></author><copyright><![CDATA[Derek Davison]]></copyright><language><![CDATA[en]]></language><webMaster><![CDATA[fx@substack.com]]></webMaster><itunes:new-feed-url>https://api.substack.com/feed/podcast/6479/s/519.rss</itunes:new-feed-url><itunes:author>Derek Davison</itunes:author><itunes:subtitle>Foreign Exchanges is a newsletter and podcast that helps you stay on top of important stories happening around the world. Derek Davison interviews scholars, journalists, and other experts to make sense of international affairs and US foreign policy.</itunes:subtitle><itunes:type>episodic</itunes:type><itunes:owner><itunes:name>Derek Davison</itunes:name><itunes:email>fx@substack.com</itunes:email></itunes:owner><itunes:explicit>No</itunes:explicit><itunes:category text="News"><itunes:category text="Politics"/></itunes:category><itunes:category text="History"/><itunes:image href="https://substackcdn.com/feed/podcast/6479/s/519/009247d23d966f249262bcd6a90c2ffb.jpg"/><item><title><![CDATA[Wrapping Up COP26, with Michael Franczak]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>I’m joined by historian Michael Franczak, Postdoctoral Fellow in Global Order at the University of Pennsylvania’s Perry World House, to recap the COP26 summit. Michael covered the first week of the conference for <em>Foreign Exchanges</em>, and if you missed his three dispatches please give them a read <a target="_blank" href="https://fx.substack.com/p/climate-change-with-an-american-face">here</a>, <a target="_blank" href="https://fx.substack.com/p/get-in-line-or-get-out-of-the-way">here</a>, and <a target="_blank" href="https://fx.substack.com/p/the-failure-to-adapt">here</a>. We discuss the history of the international environmental movement and the US role in it, Mike’s own experiences in Glasgow, and his assessment of what took place after he left—including a final agreement so watered down that the summit’s own president, Alok Sharma, actually <a target="_blank" href="https://www.reuters.com/business/cop/deeply-sorry-uks-sharma-offers-apology-last-minute-changes-climate-deal-2021-11-13/">apologized for it</a>. So I guess that means it was…really good?</p><p>Mike has a book coming out next June titled <em>Global Inequality and American Foreign Policy</em> in the 1970s, from Cornell University Press. It’s too soon for pre-orders but please keep an eye out for the book!</p><p>Our coverage of the summit was made possible by the support of FX subscribers. If you’ve appreciated that coverage please consider becoming a paid subscriber. Between this month’s special discount and <a target="_blank" href="https://fx.substack.com/p/new-offer-20-off-your-first-year">a couple of other perks</a> it’s never been a better time to subscribe.</p> <br/><br/>This is a public episode. If you’d like to discuss this with other subscribers or get access to bonus episodes, visit <a href="https://fx.substack.com/subscribe?utm_medium=podcast&#38;utm_campaign=CTA_2">fx.substack.com/subscribe</a>]]></description><link>https://fx.substack.com/p/wrapping-up-cop26-with-michael-franczak</link><guid isPermaLink="false">substack:post:44187299</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Derek Davison]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 17 Nov 2021 19:27:00 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://api.substack.com/feed/podcast/44187299/9ccd165f3b9c30ac9a9c332bcb901b9d.mp3" length="0" type="audio/mpeg"/><itunes:author>Derek Davison</itunes:author><itunes:explicit>No</itunes:explicit><itunes:duration>4869</itunes:duration><itunes:image href="https://substackcdn.com/feed/podcast/6479/post/44187299/4e2e0580d16c97a4d7b5e964e33da49f.jpg"/></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Bolsonaro Legacy Project, with Andrew Fishman]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>This week I’m pleased to welcome back <em>The Intercept’s</em> Andrew Fishman for an update on <em>Foreign Exchanges’</em> favorite world leader, Brazilian President Jair Bolsonaro. We’ll talk about Bolsonaro’s cratering poll numbers, fueled by a bungling response to COVID and anger over <a target="_blank" href="https://theintercept.com/2021/07/31/bolsonaro-brazil-covid-vaccine-corruption/">rampant corruption</a>.</p><p>We’ll talk about Lula’s legal vindication and his reemergence as the favorite to become Brazil’s next president. We’ll talk about the <a target="_blank" href="https://theintercept.com/2021/08/11/bolsonaro-brazil-congress-elections-2022/">alterations</a> Bolsonaro and his oligarch buddies are attempting to make to the Brazilian electoral system and about the likelihood of a coup should, as expected, Lula win next year’s presidential election. And we’ll talk about what may be Bolsonaro’s greatest contribution to mankind, the possibly irreversible destruction of the Amazon rain forest. Possibly one of the more depressing episodes this podcast has ever produced, and that’s saying something.</p> <br/><br/>This is a public episode. If you’d like to discuss this with other subscribers or get access to bonus episodes, visit <a href="https://fx.substack.com/subscribe?utm_medium=podcast&#38;utm_campaign=CTA_2">fx.substack.com/subscribe</a>]]></description><link>https://fx.substack.com/p/the-bolsonaro-legacy-project-with</link><guid isPermaLink="false">substack:post:39981871</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Derek Davison]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 13 Aug 2021 18:05:09 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://api.substack.com/feed/podcast/39981871/3e2594a3e8311da3cdc0592ac446c067.mp3" length="0" type="audio/mpeg"/><itunes:author>Derek Davison</itunes:author><itunes:explicit>No</itunes:explicit><itunes:duration>4087</itunes:duration><itunes:image href="https://substackcdn.com/feed/podcast/6479/post/39981871/f89626551f3b3938d60665fad45610bf.jpg"/></item><item><title><![CDATA[Tigray Update, with Terje Østebø]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>I’m very grateful that the University of Florida’s Terje Østebø was able to make his third <em>Foreign Exchanges</em> appearance this week to talk about the rapidly changing situation in Ethiopia’s Tigray region. When Terje and I <a target="_blank" href="https://fx.substack.com/p/ethiopias-tigray-conflict-with-terje">last spoke</a> the Ethiopian military, alongside elements of the Eritrean military and Amhara regional security forces, had driven the Tigray People’s Liberation Front out of Mekelle and seemed to be in control of most of the region. In the past couple of weeks that situation has been completely upended, with the TPLF now back in control of nearly all but the western portion of Tigray, currently held by the Amhara. Terje and I discuss the shocking speed of the TPLF’s turnaround, the dire humanitarian situation in Tigray, and the likelihood of further conflict.</p><p>Terje Østebø received his PhD in the History of Religion from Stockholm University, and is currently the chair of the Department of Religion and associate professor at the Center for African Studies and the Department of Religion, University of Florida. He is also the founding director of the UF Center for Global Islamic Studies. His research interests are Islam in contemporary Ethiopia, Islam, politics, and Islamic reformism in Ethiopia and the Horn of Africa, ethnicity and religion, as well as Salafism in Africa. He has lived in Ethiopia for 6 years, and has extensive field-research experience.</p><p>Terje’s major publications include “African Salafism: Religious Purity and the Politicization of Purity” in <em>Islamic Africa, </em>6, 1-2, 2015; <em>Muslim Ethiopia: The Christian Legacy, Identity Politics, and Islamic Reformism</em> (co-edited with Patrick Desplat), (Palgrave-Macmillan 2013); <em>Localising Salafism: Religious Change among Oromo Muslims in Bale, Ethiopia </em>(Brill 2012); <em>Islamism in the Horn of Africa: Assessing Ideology, Actors, and Objectives</em>,International Law and Policy Institute (2010). His latest book, <em>Islam, Ethnicity, and Conflict in Ethiopia: The Bale Insurgency (1963-1970)</em>, is now <a target="_blank" href="https://www.cambridge.org/us/academic/subjects/history/african-history/islam-ethnicity-and-conflict-ethiopia-bale-insurgency-1963-1970?format=HB">available for purchase</a>.</p> <br/><br/>This is a public episode. If you’d like to discuss this with other subscribers or get access to bonus episodes, visit <a href="https://fx.substack.com/subscribe?utm_medium=podcast&#38;utm_campaign=CTA_2">fx.substack.com/subscribe</a>]]></description><link>https://fx.substack.com/p/tigray-update-with-terje-steb</link><guid isPermaLink="false">substack:post:38577338</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Derek Davison]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 17:55:02 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://api.substack.com/feed/podcast/38577338/804f2ffc5429e8c6cebea77e759e713e.mp3" length="0" type="audio/mpeg"/><itunes:author>Derek Davison</itunes:author><itunes:explicit>No</itunes:explicit><itunes:duration>3395</itunes:duration><itunes:image href="https://substackcdn.com/feed/podcast/6479/post/38577338/8496c6af221084e8dc535c694e1bdb1f.jpg"/></item><item><title><![CDATA[International Justice for Thee, with Elizabeth Beavers]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>This week I’m joined by attorney and activist Elizabeth Beavers, who has just written a <a target="_blank" href="https://fellowtravelersblog.com/2021/06/28/ilhan-omar-was-right-the-ugly-reality-of-international-justice/">piece</a> for <em>Fellow Travelers</em> titled “Ilhan Omar was Right: The Ugly Reality of International ‘Justice’” that delves into the sordid relationship the United States has had with the International Criminal Court and really with the very concept of accountability for war crimes. We’ll talk about what she aptly calls “global justice apartheid,” unpack the frequently made claim that the domestic US legal system is capable of adjudicating American war crimes, and ask whether there’s any way to subject the US to to the same standards of international accountability that Washington demands of every other nation. You can find links to Elizabeth’s writing at her <a target="_blank" href="https://www.elizabethbeavers.com/">website</a> and follow her on <a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/_ElizabethRB">Twitter</a>.</p><p>Please stick around until the end for an important programming announcement.</p> <br/><br/>This is a public episode. If you’d like to discuss this with other subscribers or get access to bonus episodes, visit <a href="https://fx.substack.com/subscribe?utm_medium=podcast&#38;utm_campaign=CTA_2">fx.substack.com/subscribe</a>]]></description><link>https://fx.substack.com/p/international-justice-for-thee-with</link><guid isPermaLink="false">substack:post:38269661</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Derek Davison]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2021 16:42:21 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://api.substack.com/feed/podcast/38269661/c538690fa80270ecc9a3eee5e2855942.mp3" length="0" type="audio/mpeg"/><itunes:author>Derek Davison</itunes:author><itunes:explicit>No</itunes:explicit><itunes:duration>3776</itunes:duration><itunes:image href="https://substackcdn.com/feed/podcast/6479/post/38269661/8496c6af221084e8dc535c694e1bdb1f.jpg"/></item><item><title><![CDATA[Fellow Travelers and Killer Robots, with Kelsey Atherton and Andrew Leber]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>This week I’m joined by Andrew Leber from Harvard's Department of Government and defense technology journalist Kelsey Atherton to talk about a new briefing book produced by their excellent <a target="_blank" href="https://fellowtravelersblog.com/">Fellow Travelers Blog</a>. The book compiles several <a target="_blank" href="https://fellowtravelersblog.com/category/articles/policy-brief-2020/">policy briefs</a> commissioned by FTB over the past several months and is intended to provide some substance for progressive members of Congress looking to steer US foreign policy in a more progressive direction. Toward that end, they’ve started a GoFundMe to support publication and distribution costs, and if you’re able to help out in that regard please <a target="_blank" href="https://www.gofundme.com/f/help-publish-ftbs-foreignpolicy-briefing-book">do so</a>.</p><p>Because I can’t have Kelsey on without talking at least a little bit about drones, we spend a few minutes toward the end of our discussion on recent and somewhat sketchy <a target="_blank" href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/06/03/world/africa/libya-drone.html">reports</a> of <a target="_blank" href="https://www.popsci.com/technology/autonomous-machines-mistakes-un-institute-report/">autonomous drones</a> targeting fighters in Libya and the still nascent <a target="_blank" href="https://www.worldpoliticsreview.com/articles/29723/a-killer-robots-treaty-ban-just-got-a-boost">movement</a> to craft some international rules of the road about the use of weapons platforms that don’t necessarily require human intervention. We’ll also discuss the <a target="_blank" href="https://www.al-monitor.com/originals/2021/06/will-washington-buy-ankaras-drone-crescent-against-russia">proliferation</a> of relatively inexpensive mid-level drones (or in Kelsey’s words “the Honda Civic of drones”) and what it suggests about the future of warfare.</p><p>You can find <a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/AndrewMLeber">Andrew</a> and <a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/AthertonKD">Kelsey</a> on Twitter, and I highly recommend checking out Kelsey’s own Substack, <em>Wars of Future Past</em>.</p> <br/><br/>This is a public episode. If you’d like to discuss this with other subscribers or get access to bonus episodes, visit <a href="https://fx.substack.com/subscribe?utm_medium=podcast&#38;utm_campaign=CTA_2">fx.substack.com/subscribe</a>]]></description><link>https://fx.substack.com/p/fellow-travelers-and-killer-robots</link><guid isPermaLink="false">substack:post:37947586</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Derek Davison]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 23 Jun 2021 17:28:05 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://api.substack.com/feed/podcast/37947586/c49d79bb7ed7ea71df166aad760e6407.mp3" length="0" type="audio/mpeg"/><itunes:author>Derek Davison</itunes:author><itunes:explicit>No</itunes:explicit><itunes:duration>4679</itunes:duration><itunes:image href="https://substackcdn.com/feed/podcast/6479/post/37947586/8496c6af221084e8dc535c694e1bdb1f.jpg"/></item><item><title><![CDATA[Decision 1400, Part II: the Unvotening, with Séamus Malekafzali and Sina Toossi]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>What happens when an Islamic Republic decides that the “Republic” part maybe isn’t such a big deal? Journalist and <a target="_blank" href="https://fx.substack.com/p/decision-1400-with-seamus-malekafzali">returning guest</a> Séamus Malekafzali and Sina Toossi, senior research analyst at the National Iranian American Council (NIAC), join the program to discuss this Friday’s Iranian presidential election. We’ll talk about the field, such as it is, and how it came to be the way it is, and we’ll get into presumptive winner Ebrahim Raisi’s past and his potential future. Additionally we’ll discuss what Raisi’s (likely) presidency could mean for future US-Iranian relations.</p><p>You can find Sina on <a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/SinaToossi">Twitter</a> and at <a target="_blank" href="https://www.niacouncil.org/">NIAC</a>, where his <a target="_blank" href="https://www.niacouncil.org/tag/iran-unfiltered/">Iran Unfiltered</a> series is a great look into a media environment to which us Westerners don’t have many points of access. Séamus is also on <a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/Seamus_Malek">Twitter</a> and his <a target="_blank" href="https://malekafzali.substack.com/">Substack newsletter</a> is definitely worth a look if you’re interested in Iran.</p> <br/><br/>This is a public episode. If you’d like to discuss this with other subscribers or get access to bonus episodes, visit <a href="https://fx.substack.com/subscribe?utm_medium=podcast&#38;utm_campaign=CTA_2">fx.substack.com/subscribe</a>]]></description><link>https://fx.substack.com/p/decision-1400-part-ii-the-republic</link><guid isPermaLink="false">substack:post:37638728</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Derek Davison]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 16 Jun 2021 16:00:17 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://api.substack.com/feed/podcast/37638728/a0dfa4008fa0ff56eac600c16ffad790.mp3" length="0" type="audio/mpeg"/><itunes:author>Derek Davison</itunes:author><itunes:explicit>No</itunes:explicit><itunes:duration>4524</itunes:duration><itunes:image href="https://substackcdn.com/feed/podcast/6479/post/37638728/def7f2ea733ac92244a4db5bf2c93694.jpg"/></item><item><title><![CDATA[Yemen and Its Neighbors, with Annelle Sheline]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>This week I’m very pleased to welcome back Annelle Sheline, research fellow at the Quincy Institute and scholar of the Arab world. She’s written a <a target="_blank" href="https://foreignpolicy.com/2021/06/03/houthis-saudi-arabia-biden-yemen-policy-backward/">new piece</a> for <em>Foreign Policy</em> titled “Washington Has Yemen Policy Backwards,” in which she discusses the need for a new framework for peace talks that recognizes the reality of the Houthi victory. We’ll talk about the flaws in the old framework, based on UN Security Council Resolution 2216, and what she makes of the Biden administration’s handling of the Yemen war thus far. We’ll also get into some regional issues, in particular efforts by the UAE and Saudi Arabia to carve off chunks of Yemen for their own aims and the recent economic turmoil in Oman.</p><p>Annelle is a Research Fellow in the Middle East program at the Quincy Institute and an expert on religious and political authority in the Middle East and North Africa. She was previously the Zwan Postdoctoral Fellow at Rice University’s Baker Institute for Public Policy and has worked as a journalist in Egypt and Yemen. In addition to academic writing, she was written for <em>The Washington Post</em>, <em>The Nation</em>, <em>Foreign Policy</em>, <em>Politico</em>, <em>The National Interest</em>, and <em>The Globe Post, </em>and her analysis has been published by the Carnegie Endowment for International Peace, The Arab Gulf States Institute of Washington, Georgetown University’s Berkley Center for Religion, Peace & World Affairs, and the Baker Institute.</p> <br/><br/>This is a public episode. If you’d like to discuss this with other subscribers or get access to bonus episodes, visit <a href="https://fx.substack.com/subscribe?utm_medium=podcast&#38;utm_campaign=CTA_2">fx.substack.com/subscribe</a>]]></description><link>https://fx.substack.com/p/yemen-and-its-neighbors-with-annelle</link><guid isPermaLink="false">substack:post:37400699</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Derek Davison]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jun 2021 17:46:56 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://api.substack.com/feed/podcast/37400699/2ce087f97421aeceddb141ecd414731c.mp3" length="0" type="audio/mpeg"/><itunes:author>Derek Davison</itunes:author><itunes:explicit>No</itunes:explicit><itunes:duration>5040</itunes:duration><itunes:image href="https://substackcdn.com/feed/podcast/6479/post/37400699/8496c6af221084e8dc535c694e1bdb1f.jpg"/></item><item><title><![CDATA[News from the Sahel, with Alex Thurston]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Returning champion and <em>Foreign Exchanges</em> contributor Alex Thurston is here to discuss the apparent, though not yet totally confirmed, death of Boko Haram leader Abubakar Shekau and what it means for Nigeria. We’ll discuss Shekau’s role in Boko Haram’s rise and development, his notorious reputation, and what his (probable) death means for the rivalry between his branch of Boko Haram and the Islamic State West Africa Province, which very publicly split with Shekau in 2016. We’ll also spend some time talking about the overall deterioration in Nigeria’s internal security as well as the recent “coup-within-a-coup” in Mali and what that may portend for the future of civilian governance in Bamako.</p><p>For those who aren’t familiar, Alex is assistant professor of political science at the University of Cincinnati whose writing has appeared in numerous places, including here at <em>Foreign Exchanges</em>. His most recent piece looked at the implications of Shekau’s apparent death over at <em>Lawfare</em>. He is the author of three books: <em>Boko Haram: The History of an African Jihadist Movement</em>, <em>Salafism in Nigeria: Islam, Preaching, and Politics</em>, and most recently <em>Jihadists of North Africa and the Sahel</em>. You can also find him on <a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/sahelblog">Twitter</a>.</p> <br/><br/>This is a public episode. If you’d like to discuss this with other subscribers or get access to bonus episodes, visit <a href="https://fx.substack.com/subscribe?utm_medium=podcast&#38;utm_campaign=CTA_2">fx.substack.com/subscribe</a>]]></description><link>https://fx.substack.com/p/news-from-the-sahel-with-alex-thurston</link><guid isPermaLink="false">substack:post:37131103</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Derek Davison and Alex Thurston]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2021 18:11:05 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://api.substack.com/feed/podcast/37131103/9fd44cc4ac70319e234626590a206b0b.mp3" length="0" type="audio/mpeg"/><itunes:author>Derek Davison and Alex Thurston</itunes:author><itunes:explicit>No</itunes:explicit><itunes:duration>3926</itunes:duration><itunes:image href="https://substackcdn.com/feed/podcast/6479/post/37131103/8496c6af221084e8dc535c694e1bdb1f.jpg"/></item><item><title><![CDATA[In the (Think) Tank, with Eli Clifton]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>I’m joined by Eli Clifton, Senior Advisor at the Quincy Institute and Investigative Journalist at Large at its <em>Responsible Statecraft</em> outlet. He and Ben Freeman, Director of the Foreign Influence Transparency Initiative at the Center for International Policy, have produced a <a target="_blank" href="https://quincyinst.org/report/restoring-trust-in-the-think-tank-sector/">new report</a>, <em>Restoring Trust in the Think Tank Sector</em>, that makes three major recommendations for Washington think tanks to improve transparency in their operations. We’ll discuss the DC think tank community, the nature of the justifiably criticized “Revolving Door” between government and the private sector (you can read Eli’s most recent foray into that issue at <em>Responsible Statecraft</em>), and the recommendations Eli and Ben are making.</p> <br/><br/>This is a public episode. If you’d like to discuss this with other subscribers or get access to bonus episodes, visit <a href="https://fx.substack.com/subscribe?utm_medium=podcast&#38;utm_campaign=CTA_2">fx.substack.com/subscribe</a>]]></description><link>https://fx.substack.com/p/in-the-think-tank-with-eli-clifton</link><guid isPermaLink="false">substack:post:36834114</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Derek Davison]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 26 May 2021 16:10:59 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://api.substack.com/feed/podcast/36834114/879c011572de7efbd6adf08adfcb5913.mp3" length="0" type="audio/mpeg"/><itunes:author>Derek Davison</itunes:author><itunes:explicit>No</itunes:explicit><itunes:duration>4058</itunes:duration><itunes:image href="https://substackcdn.com/feed/podcast/6479/post/36834114/8496c6af221084e8dc535c694e1bdb1f.jpg"/></item><item><title><![CDATA[Gaza and the Palestinian Struggle, with Sandra Tamari and Darin Hussein]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>This week I’m grateful to be joined by Sandra Tamari (<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/SandraTamari1">@SandraTamari1</a>), executive director of the <a target="_blank" href="https://www.adalahjusticeproject.org">Adalah Justice Project</a>, and Darin Hussein (<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/DarinZeidan">@DarinZeidan</a>) in separate interviews. We’ll talk about the events of the past few weeks across Israel-Palestine and they’ll share their experiences of the Israeli occupation, the international response to it, and the work they’re doing to try to bring the Palestinian story to a wider audience.</p><p>Please check out the important work that Adalah is doing and <a target="_blank" href="https://www.adalahjusticeproject.org/donate">support it</a> if you can. Other valuable resources include the <a target="_blank" href="https://imeu.org/">Institute for Middle East Understanding</a> and <a target="_blank" href="https://decolonizepalestine.com/">DecolonizePalestine</a>. And if you haven’t read it, <a target="_blank" href="https://www.hrw.org/report/2021/04/27/threshold-crossed/israeli-authorities-and-crimes-apartheid-and-persecution#">here</a> is last month’s Human Rights Watch report classifying the Israeli government’s treatment of the Palestinians as apartheid.</p> <br/><br/>This is a public episode. If you’d like to discuss this with other subscribers or get access to bonus episodes, visit <a href="https://fx.substack.com/subscribe?utm_medium=podcast&#38;utm_campaign=CTA_2">fx.substack.com/subscribe</a>]]></description><link>https://fx.substack.com/p/gaza-and-the-palestinian-struggle</link><guid isPermaLink="false">substack:post:36694757</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Derek Davison]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 21 May 2021 18:40:05 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://api.substack.com/feed/podcast/36694757/0b3dd83c05c262ec948ab327933729d5.mp3" length="0" type="audio/mpeg"/><itunes:author>Derek Davison</itunes:author><itunes:explicit>No</itunes:explicit><itunes:duration>4446</itunes:duration><itunes:image href="https://substackcdn.com/feed/podcast/6479/post/36694757/f7feead207093bf5eed4b2e0fa9476a5.jpg"/></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Déby Dynasty, with Nathaniel Powell]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>This week I’m joined by historian Nathaniel Powell, author of <em>France's Wars in Chad: Military Intervention and Decolonization in Africa </em>(<a target="_blank" href="https://www.powells.com/book/frances-wars-in-chad-9781108488679">available now</a>), researcher at the Centre for War and Diplomacy at Lancaster University, and tweeter under the handle <a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/natkpowell">@natkpowell</a>. He’s here to talk about the death of longtime Chadian President/dictator Idriss Déby under somewhat murky circumnstances <a target="_blank" href="https://fx.substack.com/p/world-roundup-april-20-2021">last week</a> and the fallout of his sudden demise, including the <a target="_blank" href="https://fx.substack.com/p/world-roundup-april-21-2021">military coup</a> that installed Déby’s son, Mahamat, as Chad’s interim (for now) head of state.</p> <br/><br/>This is a public episode. If you’d like to discuss this with other subscribers or get access to bonus episodes, visit <a href="https://fx.substack.com/subscribe?utm_medium=podcast&#38;utm_campaign=CTA_2">fx.substack.com/subscribe</a>]]></description><link>https://fx.substack.com/p/the-deby-dynasty-with-nathaniel-powell</link><guid isPermaLink="false">substack:post:35823681</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Derek Davison]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 30 Apr 2021 18:39:09 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://api.substack.com/feed/podcast/35823681/c6a7227c6edc336abe411ee0bfe4def6.mp3" length="0" type="audio/mpeg"/><itunes:author>Derek Davison</itunes:author><itunes:explicit>No</itunes:explicit><itunes:duration>4051</itunes:duration><itunes:image href="https://substackcdn.com/feed/podcast/6479/post/35823681/8496c6af221084e8dc535c694e1bdb1f.jpg"/></item><item><title><![CDATA[Aspects of Afghan Withdrawal, with Mena Ayazi, Kate Kizer, and Fatemeh Aman]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>We're marking the end of America's longest war with what may be the longest episode of this podcast to date, featuring not one but two interviews. I'm first joined by Mena Ayazi of <a target="_blank" href="https://www.sfcg.org/">Search for Common Ground</a> and Kate Kizer of <a target="_blank" href="https://winwithoutwar.org/">Win Without War</a> (and <em>Foreign Exchanges</em>) to talk about Joe Biden's planned withdrawal from Afghanistan and how the United States could provide actual assistance to the Afghan people in lieu of endless war. Then I'm joined by Fatemeh Aman of the <a target="_blank" href="https://www.mei.edu/">Middle East Institute</a> to talk about the effect the withdrawal is likely to have in Afghanistan and throughout its geopolitical neighborhood.</p> <br/><br/>This is a public episode. If you’d like to discuss this with other subscribers or get access to bonus episodes, visit <a href="https://fx.substack.com/subscribe?utm_medium=podcast&#38;utm_campaign=CTA_2">fx.substack.com/subscribe</a>]]></description><link>https://fx.substack.com/p/aspects-of-afghan-withdrawal-with</link><guid isPermaLink="false">substack:post:35531563</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Derek Davison and Kate Kizer]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 23 Apr 2021 14:39:09 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://api.substack.com/feed/podcast/35531563/071e859c8678d2e1ff17d54dcab3e8fc.mp3" length="0" type="audio/mpeg"/><itunes:author>Derek Davison and Kate Kizer</itunes:author><itunes:explicit>No</itunes:explicit><itunes:duration>6020</itunes:duration><itunes:image href="https://substackcdn.com/feed/podcast/6479/post/35531563/745a7a593f3989bc5c96721b1ef4faa0.jpg"/></item><item><title><![CDATA[L'Affaire Jordan, with Annelle Sheline]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Today we’re very lucky to be joined by Annelle Sheline, Research Fellow for the Middle East at the Quincy Institute for Responsible Statecraft and a non-resident fellow at Rice University’s Baker Institute for Public Policy. Annelle’s research focuses on religious authority in the Middle East, particularly the intersection of religious and national identities in the Arab monarchies, and she’s done fieldwork in Egypt, Jordan, Morocco, Oman, Saudi Arabia, and Yemen.</p><p>One of the countries in that list has been particularly newsworthy of late, and somewhat surprisingly it’s Jordan. Annelle is here to provide some context for the alleged coup attempt that Jordanian authorities claimed to have thwarted over the weekend, including an examination of the key question: has former crown prince Hamzah bin Hussein really been plotting with unnamed foreign governments to overthrow his half-brother, King Abdullah II (shown above)? Suffice to say we’re both a bit skeptical. Annelle’s <em>Responsible Statecraft</em> piece on the coup and its potential to serve as a justification for a broad political crackdown is available <a target="_blank" href="https://responsiblestatecraft.org/2021/04/05/jordans-detention-of-coup-plotters-is-really-a-crackdown-on-dissent/">here</a> and you can find her on Twitter <a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/AnnelleSheline">here</a>.</p> <br/><br/>This is a public episode. If you’d like to discuss this with other subscribers or get access to bonus episodes, visit <a href="https://fx.substack.com/subscribe?utm_medium=podcast&#38;utm_campaign=CTA_2">fx.substack.com/subscribe</a>]]></description><link>https://fx.substack.com/p/laffaire-jordan-with-annelle-sheline</link><guid isPermaLink="false">substack:post:34885230</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Derek Davison]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 07 Apr 2021 22:04:41 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://api.substack.com/feed/podcast/34885230/eeb522034a36e3500a25b874c1ea220c.mp3" length="0" type="audio/mpeg"/><itunes:author>Derek Davison</itunes:author><itunes:explicit>No</itunes:explicit><itunes:duration>4341</itunes:duration><itunes:image href="https://substackcdn.com/feed/podcast/6479/post/34885230/07937da76f2804f0ed7d6123d3580920.jpg"/></item><item><title><![CDATA[Decision 1400, with Séamus Malekafzali]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Journalist Séamus Malekafzali joins me to try to get a head start on assessing the state of Iran’s June presidential election, a task that I acknowledge is a bit of a sucker’s game since the Guardian Council hasn’t started rejecting candidates yet. At this point the only thing we know for sure is that term-limited incumbent Hassan Rouhani won’t be sticking around.</p><p>But along the way we discuss the current direction of Iranian politics, the increasing politicization of the Islamic Revolutionary Guard Corps, and check in with a couple of prominent presidential candidates from years past, including once and would-be future President Mahmoud Ahmadinejad.</p><p>Check out Séamus’s writing on Iranian politics and other stories about the Middle East at his <a target="_blank" href="https://malekafzali.substack.com/">Substack newsletter</a>, and also check out his podcast, <em>The Greatest Sin</em>, <a target="_blank" href="https://www.greatestsinpod.com/">here</a> or at Spotify and Apple Podcasts.</p><p>(The episode title refers to the current year on the Iranian calendar, if that wasn’t clear.)</p> <br/><br/>This is a public episode. If you’d like to discuss this with other subscribers or get access to bonus episodes, visit <a href="https://fx.substack.com/subscribe?utm_medium=podcast&#38;utm_campaign=CTA_2">fx.substack.com/subscribe</a>]]></description><link>https://fx.substack.com/p/decision-1400-with-seamus-malekafzali</link><guid isPermaLink="false">substack:post:34379464</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Derek Davison]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 26 Mar 2021 20:06:40 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://api.substack.com/feed/podcast/34379464/e3e7cc615c3b5beec2741a02ee2dbac8.mp3" length="0" type="audio/mpeg"/><itunes:author>Derek Davison</itunes:author><itunes:explicit>No</itunes:explicit><itunes:duration>4341</itunes:duration><itunes:image href="https://substackcdn.com/feed/podcast/6479/post/34379464/c975a20a00863906c31139daa8d3ef4f.jpg"/></item><item><title><![CDATA[Wars on Terror, with Alex Thurston]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Returning champ and brand new FX contributor Alex Thurston, of the University of Cincinnati and <a target="_blank" href="https://sahelblog.wordpress.com/">Sahel Blog</a>, joins me to discuss his <a target="_blank" href="https://fx.substack.com/p/it-didnt-have-to-be-this-way">first FX column</a> and the similarities between America’s Forever War in Afghanistan and France’s Forever War in the Sahel. Alex also offers his perspective on Sunday’s presidential runoff in Niger and the unrest that has ensued, which diverges from what you’re likely to find in most Western media outlets. Enjoy!</p><p>Check out Alex’s latest book, <em>Jihadists of North Africa and the Sahel</em>, at <a target="_blank" href="https://bookshop.org/books/jihadists-of-north-africa-and-the-sahel-local-politics-and-rebel-groups/9781108726863">Bookshop.org</a> or wherever you buy books.</p> <br/><br/>This is a public episode. If you’d like to discuss this with other subscribers or get access to bonus episodes, visit <a href="https://fx.substack.com/subscribe?utm_medium=podcast&#38;utm_campaign=CTA_2">fx.substack.com/subscribe</a>]]></description><link>https://fx.substack.com/p/wars-on-terror-with-alex-thurston</link><guid isPermaLink="false">substack:post:32947456</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Derek Davison and Alex Thurston]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2021 16:55:30 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://api.substack.com/feed/podcast/32947456/9856a7ed3f44cda7f766585742b58663.mp3" length="0" type="audio/mpeg"/><itunes:author>Derek Davison and Alex Thurston</itunes:author><itunes:explicit>No</itunes:explicit><itunes:duration>4465</itunes:duration><itunes:image href="https://substackcdn.com/feed/podcast/6479/post/32947456/8496c6af221084e8dc535c694e1bdb1f.jpg"/></item><item><title><![CDATA[Ethiopia's Tigray Conflict, with Terje Østebø]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p><em>Thanks for listening! If you’re interested in more coverage of international affairs and US foreign policy, check out Foreign Exchanges at </em><em>Substack</em><em> and sign up for our free email list today:</em></p><p>This week I’m joined for the second time by the University of Florida’s Terje Østebø. The <a target="_blank" href="https://fx.substack.com/p/ethnic-federalism-and-ethiopian-politics">last time</a> Terje was on the podcast we talked about Ethiopia’s “ethnic federalist” political system and the tensions between it and the agenda of Prime Minister Abiy Ahmed. As most of you are probably aware, those tensions have since escalated into a full-blown armed conflict between the Ethiopian military and the Tigray People’s Liberation Front. Terje returns to discuss the TPLF’s background, the roots of this conflict, and where things stand in the wake of reports that Ethiopian forces have captured the Tigray regional capital, Mekelle.</p><p>Terje Østebø received his PhD in the History of Religion from Stockholm University, and is currently the chair of the Department of Religion and associate professor at the Center for African Studies and the Department of Religion, University of Florida. He is also the founding director of the UF Center for Global Islamic Studies. His research interests are Islam in contemporary Ethiopia, Islam, politics, and Islamic reformism in Ethiopia and the Horn of Africa, ethnicity and religion, as well as Salafism in Africa. He has lived in Ethiopia for 6 years, and has extensive field-research experience.</p><p>Terje’s major publications include “African Salafism: Religious Purity and the Politicization of Purity” in <em>Islamic Africa, </em>6, 1-2, 2015; <em>Muslim Ethiopia: The Christian Legacy, Identity Politics, and Islamic Reformism</em> (co-edited with Patrick Desplat), (Palgrave-Macmillan 2013); <em>Localising Salafism: Religious Change among Oromo Muslims in Bale, Ethiopia </em>(Brill 2012); <em>Islamism in the Horn of Africa: Assessing Ideology, Actors, and Objectives</em>,<em> </em>International Law and Policy Institute (2010). His latest book, <em>Islam, Ethnicity, and Conflict in Ethiopia: The Bale Insurgency (1963-1970)</em>, is now <a target="_blank" href="https://www.cambridge.org/us/academic/subjects/history/african-history/islam-ethnicity-and-conflict-ethiopia-bale-insurgency-1963-1970?format=HB">available for purchase</a> and seems particularly relevant at present.</p> <br/><br/>This is a public episode. If you’d like to discuss this with other subscribers or get access to bonus episodes, visit <a href="https://fx.substack.com/subscribe?utm_medium=podcast&#38;utm_campaign=CTA_2">fx.substack.com/subscribe</a>]]></description><link>https://fx.substack.com/p/ethiopias-tigray-conflict-with-terje</link><guid isPermaLink="false">substack:post:21257842</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Derek Davison]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 22:03:27 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://api.substack.com/feed/podcast/21257842/5a51c6700188df984e23f495c7c65729.mp3" length="0" type="audio/mpeg"/><itunes:author>Derek Davison</itunes:author><itunes:explicit>No</itunes:explicit><itunes:duration>3344</itunes:duration><itunes:image href="https://substackcdn.com/feed/podcast/6479/post/21257842/bda1d686ec6dd91cab218f2a59707e7e.jpg"/></item><item><title><![CDATA[Think Locally, Act Locally, with Alexander Thurston]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p><em>Thanks for listening! If you’re interested in more coverage of international affairs and US foreign policy, check out Foreign Exchanges at </em><em>Substack</em><em> and sign up for our free email list today:</em></p><p>Returning champion Alexander Thurston rejoins the podcast to talk about his new book, <em>Jihadists of North Africa and the Sahel: Local Politics and Rebel Groups</em>. He’s offering a different way to understand jihadist organizations that challenges the dominant narratives of the War on Terror, which flatten those organizations into global monoliths at the macro level and simplistically treat their recruits as brainwashed dupes at the micro level. Alex instead focuses on the regional and local factors that create and sustain jihadist groups, emphasizing their roles as political actors and their interactions with the societies around them.</p><p>Check out the book at <a target="_blank" href="https://bookshop.org/books/jihadists-of-north-africa-and-the-sahel-local-politics-and-rebel-groups/9781108726863">bookshop.org</a> or wherever you shop for books, and you can also check out Alex’s Sahel Blog at <a target="_blank" href="http://sahelblog.wordpress.com">WordPress</a>.</p> <br/><br/>This is a public episode. If you’d like to discuss this with other subscribers or get access to bonus episodes, visit <a href="https://fx.substack.com/subscribe?utm_medium=podcast&#38;utm_campaign=CTA_2">fx.substack.com/subscribe</a>]]></description><link>https://fx.substack.com/p/think-locally-act-locally-with-alexander</link><guid isPermaLink="false">substack:post:19228131</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Derek Davison and Alex Thurston]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2020 21:42:28 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://api.substack.com/feed/podcast/19228131/4923be92748dd7f3dcd224cfbfab0ac5.mp3" length="0" type="audio/mpeg"/><itunes:author>Derek Davison and Alex Thurston</itunes:author><itunes:explicit>No</itunes:explicit><itunes:duration>3894</itunes:duration><itunes:image href="https://substackcdn.com/feed/podcast/6479/post/19228131/298867cb13e1e510cc4bbeedb51114ef.jpg"/></item><item><title><![CDATA[Bolivia's Election and What's Next, with Thomas C. Field Jr.]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p><em>Thanks for listening! If you’re interested in more coverage of international affairs and US foreign policy, check out Foreign Exchanges at </em><em>Substack</em><em> and sign up for our free email list today:</em></p><p>Thomas C. Field Jr. of Embry-Riddle Aeronautical University joins me for the <a target="_blank" href="https://fx.substack.com/p/bolivia-since-morales-with-thomas">second time</a> to update us on the situation in Bolivia. Luis Arce, nominee of Evo Morales’ Movement for Socialism (MAS) party, won a decisive victory in last month’s election, potentially capping a year that saw Morales ousted in a right-wing putsch that then made every effort to stop MAS from returning to power. We look back on what happened to Morales and the destructive legacy that the Jeanine Áñez-led junta has left in its wake, and look ahead to the challenges that face Arce, from a revanchist Bolivian far right, to an economy devastated by mismanagement and COVID-19, to a regional political environment (largely overseen by the Organization for American States) that is designed to undermine left-wing governments.</p><p>Thomas is the author of From <em>Development to Dictatorship: Bolivia and the Alliance for Progress in the Kennedy Era</em> and co-editor of the recently published <em>Latin America and the Global Cold War</em>, both of which are available from Powell’s (<a target="_blank" href="https://www.powells.com/book/-9780801452604">here</a> and <a target="_blank" href="https://www.powells.com/book/-9781469655697">here</a>, respectively) and many other booksellers.</p> <br/><br/>This is a public episode. If you’d like to discuss this with other subscribers or get access to bonus episodes, visit <a href="https://fx.substack.com/subscribe?utm_medium=podcast&#38;utm_campaign=CTA_2">fx.substack.com/subscribe</a>]]></description><link>https://fx.substack.com/p/bolivias-election-and-whats-next</link><guid isPermaLink="false">substack:post:17324323</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Derek Davison]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 03 Nov 2020 18:46:08 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://api.substack.com/feed/podcast/17324323/d3ea7db5604304bb880fadf8febe8ff6.mp3" length="0" type="audio/mpeg"/><itunes:author>Derek Davison</itunes:author><itunes:explicit>No</itunes:explicit><itunes:duration>4749</itunes:duration><itunes:image href="https://substackcdn.com/feed/podcast/6479/post/17324323/b54473039afb00be07b0f1eecc2e43fc.jpg"/></item><item><title><![CDATA[Tomorrow: Tomorrow, the World, with Stephen Wertheim]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p><em>This is the web version of </em><em>Foreign Exchanges</em><em>, but did you know you can get it delivered right to your inbox? Sign up today:</em></p><p>This time around I’m joined by Stephen Wertheim, Deputy Director of Research and Policy at the Quincy Institute and a Research Scholar at the Saltzman Institute of War and Peace Studies at Columbia University. We’re discussing his brand new book, <em>Tomorrow, the World: The Birth of U.S. Global Supremacy</em>, which is, ironically enough, coming out tomorrow. In contrast to those who argue that America has always been overtly an imperial project and to those who argue that America reluctantly had empire thrust upon it in the 20th century, in the book Stephen argues that the American Empire stems from a conscious choice made by policymakers during World War II.</p><p>You can buy <em>Tomorrow, the World</em> direct from the <a target="_blank" href="https://www.hup.harvard.edu/catalog.php?isbn=9780674248663">publisher</a> or wherever you get your books, ebooks, and/or audiobooks. You can also get a preview of what’s in the book from Stephen’s <a target="_blank" href="https://www.nytimes.com/2020/10/15/opinion/america-global-power.html?auth=login-email&#38;login=email">latest piece</a> for the <em>New York Times</em>.</p><p>Or from, you know, this interview.</p> <br/><br/>This is a public episode. If you’d like to discuss this with other subscribers or get access to bonus episodes, visit <a href="https://fx.substack.com/subscribe?utm_medium=podcast&#38;utm_campaign=CTA_2">fx.substack.com/subscribe</a>]]></description><link>https://fx.substack.com/p/tomorrow-tomorrow-the-world-with</link><guid isPermaLink="false">substack:post:14534700</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Derek Davison]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2020 18:40:32 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://api.substack.com/feed/podcast/14534700/f60b1650ec28928d0cc6f723b29b5de4.mp3" length="0" type="audio/mpeg"/><itunes:author>Derek Davison</itunes:author><itunes:explicit>No</itunes:explicit><itunes:duration>4078</itunes:duration><itunes:image href="https://substackcdn.com/feed/podcast/6479/post/14534700/22e2a093d1a307d9c675a66ab79e2944.jpg"/></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Institutions Behind US Foreign Policy, with Daniel Bessner]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>University of Washington professor, Quincy Institute fellow, and (above all) Foreign Exchanges columnist Daniel Bessner joins me for a chat about his first two FX pieces, the development of US foreign policy and the foreign policy establishment in DC, and some of the structural obstacles to overhauling that foreign policy for leftists.</p><p>There are lots of links for this one:</p><p>* Daniel’s first two FX pieces are <a target="_blank" href="https://fx.substack.com/p/the-american-empire-and-existential">here</a> and <a target="_blank" href="https://fx.substack.com/p/realism-in-us-foreign-policy">here</a></p><p>* You can read his piece on the Military-Intellectual Complex at <em>The New Republic</em></p><p>* The Center for International Policy’s new study on the defense establishment’s funding of major think tanks is available <a target="_blank" href="https://3ba8a190-62da-4c98-86d2-893079d87083.usrfiles.com/ugd/3ba8a1_318530ca605142e68e653d93b5ad698f.pdf">here</a> as a PDF</p><p>* Finally, <a target="_blank" href="https://www.powells.com/book/democracy-in-exile-9780801453038">buy Daniel’s book</a>! Or wait for the audiobook! Or buy both!</p> <br/><br/>This is a public episode. If you’d like to discuss this with other subscribers or get access to bonus episodes, visit <a href="https://fx.substack.com/subscribe?utm_medium=podcast&#38;utm_campaign=CTA_2">fx.substack.com/subscribe</a>]]></description><link>https://fx.substack.com/p/the-institutions-behind-us-foreign</link><guid isPermaLink="false">substack:post:12230152</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Derek Davison and Daniel Bessner]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2020 18:04:45 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://api.substack.com/feed/podcast/12230152/21316e415bd417d7c5a1249a41b3d6e4.mp3" length="0" type="audio/mpeg"/><itunes:author>Derek Davison and Daniel Bessner</itunes:author><itunes:explicit>No</itunes:explicit><itunes:duration>3969</itunes:duration><itunes:image href="https://substackcdn.com/feed/podcast/6479/post/12230152/8496c6af221084e8dc535c694e1bdb1f.jpg"/></item><item><title><![CDATA[Alassane Ouattara and Politics in the Ivory Coast, with Jessica Moody (PODCAST 10-09-2020)]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p><em>This is the web version of Foreign Exchanges, but did you know you can get it delivered right to your inbox? Sign up today:</em></p><p>This week I’m joined by Jessica Moody, a PhD candidate at Kings College London whose work focuses on post-conflict Ivory Coast (Côte d’Ivoire for you francophones out there). She’s here to discuss the tensions surrounding President Alassane Ouattara’s (somewhat abrupt) decision to seek a constitutionally-questionable third term in the forthcoming (October 31) election, and the context for those tensions going back to the 1990s), as well as her thoughts on what’s likely to happen next.</p><p><em>Ouattara speaking at a 2017 US State Department event (State Department photo via Flickr)</em></p><p>Jessica is on Twitter and is a great source for news and analysis on Ivory Coast and West Africa in general: <a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/JessMoody89">@JessMoody89</a>.</p> <br/><br/>This is a public episode. If you’d like to discuss this with other subscribers or get access to bonus episodes, visit <a href="https://fx.substack.com/subscribe?utm_medium=podcast&#38;utm_campaign=CTA_2">fx.substack.com/subscribe</a>]]></description><link>https://fx.substack.com/p/alassane-ouattara-and-politics-in</link><guid isPermaLink="false">substack:post:8810919</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Derek Davison]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 09 Oct 2020 17:24:04 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://api.substack.com/feed/podcast/8810919/1ddfdc796014cc89151ad1a1d1d1a620.mp3" length="0" type="audio/mpeg"/><itunes:author>Derek Davison</itunes:author><itunes:explicit>No</itunes:explicit><itunes:duration>4209</itunes:duration><itunes:image href="https://substackcdn.com/feed/podcast/6479/post/8810919/922da7927e2d2d6ab8ad05cdd0d22a14.jpg"/></item><item><title><![CDATA[Conflict Flares Up in Nagorno-Karabakh, with Joshua Kucera (PODCAST 9-29-2020)]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p><em>This is the web version of Foreign Exchanges, but did you know you can get it delivered right to your inbox? Sign up today:</em></p><p>Today I’m joined by reporter Joshua Kucera of <a target="_blank" href="https://eurasianet.org/">Eurasianet</a>, a great source for news and analysis on the Caucasus and Central Asia. As you may be aware, fighting broke out several days ago between Armenian and Azerbaijani forces over the disputed Nagorno-Karabakh region. Josh gives us an update on that situation (current as of Tuesday evening, September 29, in the Caucasus) as well as some of the historical and political context to the Nagorno-Karabkh dispute and some perspective on the potential for this latest clash to escalate into a full-blown war or even a wider regional conflict.</p><p>This map of the situation as it’s been frozen in place since the 1990s Nagorno-Karabakh War ended may be helpful:</p><p><em>Source: Wikimedia Commons</em></p><p>You may also appreciate this photo of Armenian Prime Minister Nikol Pashinyan and Russian President Vladimir Putin pretending to like each other, which as you’ll see is relevant to the discussion:</p><p><em>Source: Russian government via Wikimedia Commons</em></p><p>Josh’s latest, which attempts to suss out what Azerbaijan is trying to accomplish with this latest round of fighting, is now available <a target="_blank" href="https://eurasianet.org/as-fighting-rages-what-is-azerbaijans-goal">at Eurasianet</a>. You can also find him on Twitter: <a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/joshuakucera">@joshuakucera</a>.</p> <br/><br/>This is a public episode. If you’d like to discuss this with other subscribers or get access to bonus episodes, visit <a href="https://fx.substack.com/subscribe?utm_medium=podcast&#38;utm_campaign=CTA_2">fx.substack.com/subscribe</a>]]></description><link>https://fx.substack.com/p/conflict-flares-up-in-nagorno-karabakh</link><guid isPermaLink="false">substack:post:5399857</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Derek Davison]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 29 Sep 2020 16:31:24 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://api.substack.com/feed/podcast/5399857/8e09761cd85e7cc754c7f64893c96684.mp3" length="0" type="audio/mpeg"/><itunes:author>Derek Davison</itunes:author><itunes:explicit>No</itunes:explicit><itunes:duration>4263</itunes:duration><itunes:image href="https://substackcdn.com/feed/podcast/6479/post/5399857/0b0677c5391de267bcf4a746fc7be8bb.jpg"/></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Coup in Mali, with Alex Thurston (PODCAST 8-26-2020)]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p><em>This is the web version of Foreign Exchanges, but did you know you can get it delivered right to your inbox? Sign up today:</em></p><p>FX’s regular analyst on all things related to the Sahel, Alex Thurston, joins me to discuss the August 18 coup in Mali, the ouster of former President Ibrahim Boubacar Keïta, and what may be on the horizon for Mali and the rest of the region.</p><p><em>Keïta voting in Mali’s 2018 presidential election (Voice of America via Wikimedia Commons)</em></p><p>As always, Alex’s <a target="_blank" href="https://sahelblog.wordpress.com">blog</a> is a great resource for those interested in the political ups and downs of the Sahel region. He also mentioned a recent <em>Jacobin</em> piece by historian Gregory Mann that is available <a target="_blank" href="https://www.jacobinmag.com/2020/08/mali-coup-ibk-keita-dicko-bamako">here</a>.</p> <br/><br/>This is a public episode. If you’d like to discuss this with other subscribers or get access to bonus episodes, visit <a href="https://fx.substack.com/subscribe?utm_medium=podcast&#38;utm_campaign=CTA_2">fx.substack.com/subscribe</a>]]></description><link>https://fx.substack.com/p/the-coup-in-mali-with-alex-thurston</link><guid isPermaLink="false">substack:post:902685</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Derek Davison and Alex Thurston]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2020 18:52:21 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://api.substack.com/feed/podcast/902685/1f59cf922d3264e2e801e6e0037d5d93.mp3" length="0" type="audio/mpeg"/><itunes:author>Derek Davison and Alex Thurston</itunes:author><itunes:explicit>No</itunes:explicit><itunes:duration>4383</itunes:duration><itunes:image href="https://substackcdn.com/feed/podcast/6479/post/902685/2502c419e474d0e5709a077d0468dca5.jpg"/></item><item><title><![CDATA[Ethnic Federalism and Ethiopian politics, with Terje Østebø (PODCAST 8-13-2020)]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p><em>This is the web version of Foreign Exchanges, but did you know you can get it delivered right to your inbox? Sign up today:</em></p><p>I’m very pleased to be joined this week by Terje Østebø of the University of Florida to discuss the roots and nature of Ethiopia’s “ethnic federalist” system and the impact that Prime Minister Abiy Ahmed’s political changes have had on it. If you’ve been following reports of violence in Ethiopia’s Oromo community or of the rise of nationalist movements among some of its smaller ethnic groups and felt like you would appreciate some deeper background into those stories, this is the interview for you.</p><p><em>Abiy during last year’s Russia-Africa Summit in Sochi (Russian government via Wikimedia Commons)</em></p><p>Terje Østebø received his PhD in the History of Religion from Stockholm University, and is currently the chair of the Department of Religion and associate professor at the Center for African Studies and the Department of Religion, University of Florida. He is also the founding director of the UF Center for Global Islamic Studies. His research interests are Islam in contemporary Ethiopia, Islam, politics, and Islamic reformism in Ethiopia and the Horn of Africa, ethnicity and religion, as well as Salafism in Africa. He has lived in Ethiopia for 6 years, and has extensive field-research experience. Major publications include <em>Islam, Ethnicity, and Conflict in Ethiopia: The Bale Insurgency (1963-1970) </em>(<a target="_blank" href="https://www.cambridge.org/core/books/islam-ethnicity-and-conflict-in-ethiopia/7A9B8C74C57FD7363C6EB148D39C1FE2">Cambridge University Press, 2020</a>); “African Salafism: Religious Purity and the Politicization of Purity” in <em>Islamic Africa, </em>6, 1-2, 2015; <em>Muslim Ethiopia: The Christian Legacy, Identity Politics, and Islamic Reformism</em> (co-edited with Patrick Desplat), (Palgrave-Macmillan 2013); <em>Localising Salafism: Religious Change among Oromo Muslims in Bale, Ethiopia </em>(Brill 2012); <em>Islamism in the Horn of Africa: Assessing Ideology, Actors, and Objectives, </em>International Law and Policy Institute (2010).</p> <br/><br/>This is a public episode. If you’d like to discuss this with other subscribers or get access to bonus episodes, visit <a href="https://fx.substack.com/subscribe?utm_medium=podcast&#38;utm_campaign=CTA_2">fx.substack.com/subscribe</a>]]></description><link>https://fx.substack.com/p/ethnic-federalism-and-ethiopian-politics</link><guid isPermaLink="false">substack:post:846356</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Derek Davison]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2020 19:55:12 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://api.substack.com/feed/podcast/846356/1e0d65395eaf8f8d803b2dfd355f2d24.mp3" length="0" type="audio/mpeg"/><itunes:author>Derek Davison</itunes:author><itunes:explicit>No</itunes:explicit><itunes:duration>3974</itunes:duration><itunes:image href="https://substackcdn.com/feed/podcast/6479/post/846356/41f57ae74839c64fcf319e7c72de41cd.jpg"/></item><item><title><![CDATA[Nuclear Modernization and the Future of Arms Control, with John Carl Baker (PODCAST 8-05-2020)]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p><em>This is the web version of Foreign Exchanges, but did you know you can get it delivered right to your inbox? Sign up today:</em></p><p>The Ploughshares Fund’s John Carl Baker returns to the show to talk about the push to modernize the US nuclear arsenal, what that entails, and how much it will cost. We then assess the wreckage the Trump administration has made in terms of arms control and what that means for the future, depending on what happens in November.</p><p><em>Then-US President Barack Obama signing the ratification of New START, February 2011 (Official White House Photo)</em></p><p>Plugs:</p><p>Check out the work <a target="_blank" href="https://ploughshares.org/">Ploughshares</a> and its partners are doing.</p><p>Sign up for the <a target="_blank" href="https://discontents.substack.com">Discontents</a> newsletter.</p><p>Check out what’s happening with <a target="_blank" href="https://www.optoutnews.org/">OptOut</a> and sign up for their <a target="_blank" href="https://optout.substack.com/">newsletter</a>.</p><p>If you’ve somehow come here and aren’t signed up for <a target="_blank" href="https://fx.substack.com">Foreign Exchanges</a>, please do that too.</p> <br/><br/>This is a public episode. If you’d like to discuss this with other subscribers or get access to bonus episodes, visit <a href="https://fx.substack.com/subscribe?utm_medium=podcast&#38;utm_campaign=CTA_2">fx.substack.com/subscribe</a>]]></description><link>https://fx.substack.com/p/nuclear-modernization-and-the-future</link><guid isPermaLink="false">substack:post:816991</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Derek Davison]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2020 18:20:33 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://api.substack.com/feed/podcast/816991/6e9b25d6a74c047ffed3dbaf4204132c.mp3" length="0" type="audio/mpeg"/><itunes:author>Derek Davison</itunes:author><itunes:explicit>No</itunes:explicit><itunes:duration>4778</itunes:duration><itunes:image href="https://substackcdn.com/feed/podcast/6479/post/816991/9452cf895841404ab074162b1cafd9d2.jpg"/></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Causes and Effects of the Korean War, with Owen Miller (PODCAST 7-22-2020)]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>I'm joined by Dr. Owen Miller, lecturer in Korean Studies at the School of Oriental and African Studies at the University of London, to mark the 70th anniversary of the start of the Korean War. Building in part off of his <a target="_blank" href="https://www.jacobinmag.com/2020/06/korean-war-seventieth-anniversary-north-korea-south">recent piece</a> for Jacobin, Owen helps me better understand the root causes of the Korean War, the factions involved, and the impact the conflict had on the Korean people.</p><p><em>A US Navy Douglas AD-4 Skyraider preparing to launch from the USS </em>Philippine Sea<em> for a strike mission in Korea in October 1950 (US Navy photo via Wikimedia Commons)</em></p> <br/><br/>This is a public episode. If you’d like to discuss this with other subscribers or get access to bonus episodes, visit <a href="https://fx.substack.com/subscribe?utm_medium=podcast&#38;utm_campaign=CTA_2">fx.substack.com/subscribe</a>]]></description><link>https://fx.substack.com/p/the-causes-and-effects-of-the-korean</link><guid isPermaLink="false">substack:post:750803</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Derek Davison]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2020 20:09:05 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://api.substack.com/feed/podcast/750803/2d8d61dd849114142891f63f22741714.mp3" length="0" type="audio/mpeg"/><itunes:author>Derek Davison</itunes:author><itunes:explicit>No</itunes:explicit><itunes:duration>4216</itunes:duration><itunes:image href="https://substackcdn.com/feed/podcast/6479/post/750803/0149e1ca493ae21c8b7926a8ce705a50.jpg"/></item><item><title><![CDATA[Blowing Back, with Brendan James and Noah Kulwin (PODCAST 7-15-2020)]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>I'm very pleased to be joined by <a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/deep_beige">Brendan James</a> and <a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/nkulw">Noah Kulwin</a>, co-hosts of the fantastic podcast "<a target="_blank" href="https://blowback.show/">Blowback</a>," covering the Iraq War and the utterly surreal political and media environment that both enabled the war and was fundamentally shaped by it.</p><p><em>Mission accomplished indeed (US Navy via Wikimedia Commons)</em></p><p>Episodes are currently being released every Monday on your favorite podcast outlet, but you can hear the full 10 part series plus get access to bonus episodes right now at <a target="_blank" href="https://www.stitcher.com/premium">Stitcher Premium</a> (sign up with the code "BLOWBACK" for a free one month preview).</p> <br/><br/>This is a public episode. If you’d like to discuss this with other subscribers or get access to bonus episodes, visit <a href="https://fx.substack.com/subscribe?utm_medium=podcast&#38;utm_campaign=CTA_2">fx.substack.com/subscribe</a>]]></description><link>https://fx.substack.com/p/blowing-back-with-brendan-james-and</link><guid isPermaLink="false">substack:post:722538</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Derek Davison]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2020 18:42:50 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://api.substack.com/feed/podcast/722538/e49ebddf8a1516108dffb3cd4019d76d.mp3" length="0" type="audio/mpeg"/><itunes:author>Derek Davison</itunes:author><itunes:explicit>No</itunes:explicit><itunes:duration>4733</itunes:duration><itunes:image href="https://substackcdn.com/feed/podcast/6479/post/722538/23f1c0c88f9248cd838d981825142637.jpg"/></item><item><title><![CDATA[Abdelmalek Droukdel's Legacy in the Sahel, with Alex Thurston (PODCAST 6-10-2020)]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p><em>This is the web version of Foreign Exchanges, but did you know you can get it delivered right to your inbox? Sign up today:</em></p><p>Returning guest and scholar of the Sahel Alex Thurston joins me to discuss the recently reported <a target="_blank" href="https://www.france24.com/en/20200605-french-forces-kill-al-qaeda-s-north-africa-chief-in-mali-ministry-says">death</a> of al-Qaeda in the Islamic Maghreb leader Abdelmalek Droukdel. Serendipitously, this subject coincides with Alex's forthcoming (probably in September) book, <em>Jihadists of North Africa and the Sahel: Local Politics and Rebel Groups</em>. He’s also written about Droukdel’s (probable) death <a target="_blank" href="https://sahelblog.wordpress.com/2020/06/09/on-the-reported-death-of-al-qaida-in-the-islamic-maghrebs-emir-abdelmalek-droukdel/">at his blog</a>. Twice, <a target="_blank" href="https://sahelblog.wordpress.com/2020/06/10/a-few-passages-on-abdelmalek-droukdel-from-my-forthcoming-book/">actually</a>. We delve into the history of AQIM and the diminishing role it's played as the center of jihadist gravity has shifted from Algeria into the Sahel region. The piece Alex mentions toward the end of the interview on the regional crisis surrounding the Fulani, from anthropologist Modibo Ghaly Cissé, is available <a target="_blank" href="https://africacenter.org/spotlight/understanding-fulani-perspectives-sahel-crisis/#author">here</a>.</p> <br/><br/>This is a public episode. If you’d like to discuss this with other subscribers or get access to bonus episodes, visit <a href="https://fx.substack.com/subscribe?utm_medium=podcast&#38;utm_campaign=CTA_2">fx.substack.com/subscribe</a>]]></description><link>https://fx.substack.com/p/abdelmalek-droukdels-legacy-in-the</link><guid isPermaLink="false">substack:post:544535</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Derek Davison and Alex Thurston]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 21:24:54 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://api.substack.com/feed/podcast/544535/35007a45ea94b0fa06c3b103d7ac854e.mp3" length="0" type="audio/mpeg"/><itunes:author>Derek Davison and Alex Thurston</itunes:author><itunes:explicit>No</itunes:explicit><itunes:duration>4826</itunes:duration><itunes:image href="https://substackcdn.com/feed/podcast/6479/post/544535/8496c6af221084e8dc535c694e1bdb1f.jpg"/></item><item><title><![CDATA[Bolivia since Morales, with Thomas C. Field Jr. (PODCAST 5-13-2020)]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p><em>This is the web version of Foreign Exchanges, but did you know you can get it delivered right to your inbox? Sign up today:</em></p><p>Latin America scholar Thomas C. Field Jr. joins me to discuss the last six or so months in Bolivia, from the disputed October election to the ouster of President Evo Morales to the machinations of the post-coup government that replaced him. You can find Thomas on Twitter @thomascfield and you can find his books at lots of places, but Powell’s has them <a target="_blank" href="https://www.powells.com/book/-9780801452604">here</a> and <a target="_blank" href="https://www.powells.com/book/-9781469655697">here</a>. Apologies for a few glitchy moments but in my defense this time they were caused by Skype, not me personally. That’s progress, at least.</p><p>I mentioned a couple of relevant interviews during the interview, one with southern Altiplano peasant workers leader Ramiro Huayta that you can find <a target="_blank" href="https://www.kawsachuncoca.com/index.php/2012-12-24-07-26-10/agencia-abi/item/1052-the-fight-to-save-bolivia-s-lithium">here</a> and another with MAS presidential candidate Luis Acre that’s available <a target="_blank" href="https://peoplesdispatch.org/2020/04/30/bolivias-socialist-presidential-candidate-luis-arce-speaks-about-elections-covid-19-and-fascist-oppression/">here</a>.</p> <br/><br/>This is a public episode. If you’d like to discuss this with other subscribers or get access to bonus episodes, visit <a href="https://fx.substack.com/subscribe?utm_medium=podcast&#38;utm_campaign=CTA_2">fx.substack.com/subscribe</a>]]></description><link>https://fx.substack.com/p/bolivia-since-morales-with-thomas</link><guid isPermaLink="false">substack:post:455499</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Derek Davison]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 13 May 2020 19:13:49 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://api.substack.com/feed/podcast/455499/92a950f149830e2ea145f6a1991fba58.mp3" length="0" type="audio/mpeg"/><itunes:author>Derek Davison</itunes:author><itunes:explicit>No</itunes:explicit><itunes:duration>5124</itunes:duration><itunes:image href="https://substackcdn.com/feed/podcast/6479/post/455499/8496c6af221084e8dc535c694e1bdb1f.jpg"/></item><item><title><![CDATA[COVID-19 in the Sahel, with Alex Thurston (PODCAST 5-06-2020)]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Returning guest Alex Thurston joins the show to discuss COVID-19 in the Sahel, how the region's militant groups have responded to the pandemic, and recent militant and military activity in Nigeria, Chad, Mali, and elsewhere. Be sure to check out Alex's <a target="_blank" href="https://sahelblog.wordpress.com">Sahel Blog</a> and follow him on Twitter: <a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/sahelblog">@sahelblog</a>.</p> <br/><br/>This is a public episode. If you’d like to discuss this with other subscribers or get access to bonus episodes, visit <a href="https://fx.substack.com/subscribe?utm_medium=podcast&#38;utm_campaign=CTA_2">fx.substack.com/subscribe</a>]]></description><link>https://fx.substack.com/p/covid-19-in-the-sahel-with-alex-thurston</link><guid isPermaLink="false">substack:post:437206</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Derek Davison and Alex Thurston]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 06 May 2020 18:28:57 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://api.substack.com/feed/podcast/437206/f29ebdd664d87191023ab5979a6b1999.mp3" length="0" type="audio/mpeg"/><itunes:author>Derek Davison and Alex Thurston</itunes:author><itunes:explicit>No</itunes:explicit><itunes:duration>4285</itunes:duration><itunes:image href="https://substackcdn.com/feed/podcast/6479/post/437206/8496c6af221084e8dc535c694e1bdb1f.jpg"/></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Bold and the Bolsonaros, with Andrew Fishman (PODCAST 4-27-2020)]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>I'm joined by Andrew Fishman, reporter for <a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/AndrewDFish">The Intercept</a> and managing editor for <a target="_blank" href="https://theintercept.com/brasil/">The Intercept Brasil</a>, to discuss the ongoing soap opera that is Brazilian President Jair Bolsonaro's haggard response to the coronavirus, as well as the new drama surrounding the recent resignation of ex-Justice Minister Sergio Moro.</p><p><em>It’s been a rough couple of weeks (Brazilian government via Wikimedia Commons)</em></p><p>You can follow Andrew on Twitter <a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/AndrewDFish">@AndrewDFish</a>.</p> <br/><br/>This is a public episode. If you’d like to discuss this with other subscribers or get access to bonus episodes, visit <a href="https://fx.substack.com/subscribe?utm_medium=podcast&#38;utm_campaign=CTA_2">fx.substack.com/subscribe</a>]]></description><link>https://fx.substack.com/p/the-bold-and-the-bolsonaros-with</link><guid isPermaLink="false">substack:post:411534</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Derek Davison]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2020 19:13:22 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://api.substack.com/feed/podcast/411534/f31f20d1afc6dea5e396360f1184e2eb.mp3" length="0" type="audio/mpeg"/><itunes:author>Derek Davison</itunes:author><itunes:explicit>No</itunes:explicit><itunes:duration>4008</itunes:duration><itunes:image href="https://substackcdn.com/feed/podcast/6479/post/411534/10abef1ac598170edfd6a1c58783a008.jpg"/></item><item><title><![CDATA[Challenging the "Intellectual Dark Web," with Michael Brooks (PODCAST 4-20-2020)]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>I'm joined by Michael Brooks, returning champion and host of <em>The Michael Brooks Show</em> as well as co-host of <em>The Majority Report with Sam Seder</em> and <a target="_blank" href="https://www.youtube.com/c/jacobinmagazineyt">Jacobin's</a> <em>Weekends with Ana Kasparian and Michael Brooks</em>. We're discussing his new book, <em>Against the Web: A Cosmopolitan Answer to the New Right</em>. We're talking the "Intellectual Dark Web," Sam Harris, Jordan Peterson, and how the left can counter their message. Michael’s book is out April 24 and is already available for pre-order from your favorite booksellers, for example <a target="_blank" href="https://redemmas.org/titles/34612-against-the-web---a-cosmopolitan-answer-to-the-new-right#">here</a>.</p><p>There’s a catch to this interview, unfortunately: because of some huge and as yet bafflingly unexplained (though I’m certain human error was involved) technical issues on my end I had to re-record my portion of the audio and trim a few sections where Michael and I are talking in quick succession. Fortunately his audio was fine, it’s just me who sounded like I was talking through a tin can. The result is a coherent interview that is a little choppier than I would like in parts, so please be advised of that. You may still hear a very low-quality version of me in the background a couple of times but thankfully I think I’ve eliminated most of it. My apologies.</p> <br/><br/>This is a public episode. If you’d like to discuss this with other subscribers or get access to bonus episodes, visit <a href="https://fx.substack.com/subscribe?utm_medium=podcast&#38;utm_campaign=CTA_2">fx.substack.com/subscribe</a>]]></description><link>https://fx.substack.com/p/challenging-the-intellectual-dark</link><guid isPermaLink="false">substack:post:391192</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Derek Davison]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2020 19:30:43 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://api.substack.com/feed/podcast/391192/c0f6623481a6551644878a9886fd35ba.mp3" length="0" type="audio/mpeg"/><itunes:author>Derek Davison</itunes:author><itunes:explicit>No</itunes:explicit><itunes:duration>4506</itunes:duration><itunes:image href="https://substackcdn.com/feed/podcast/6479/post/391192/8496c6af221084e8dc535c694e1bdb1f.jpg"/></item><item><title><![CDATA[Europe's Crisis of Solidarity, with David Adler (PODCAST 4-07-2020)]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>I’m joined by returning guest David Adler of the Democracy in Europe Movement to discuss how Europe has risen—or failed to rise—to the challenge posed by the COVID-19 pandemic. David offers his thoughts on the lack of collective action within Europe and what it might mean for the eurozone and the European Union moving forward, as well as some ideas for improving European institutions.</p><p>David’s Guardian piece (co-authored with Jerome Roos), which we reference in the interview, can be found <a target="_blank" href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/commentisfree/2020/mar/31/solidarity-members-eurozone-coronavirus-dutch-coronabond">here</a>. You can also follow him on <a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/davidrkadler">Twitter</a>.</p> <br/><br/>This is a public episode. If you’d like to discuss this with other subscribers or get access to bonus episodes, visit <a href="https://fx.substack.com/subscribe?utm_medium=podcast&#38;utm_campaign=CTA_2">fx.substack.com/subscribe</a>]]></description><link>https://fx.substack.com/p/europes-crisis-of-solidarity-with</link><guid isPermaLink="false">substack:post:357500</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Derek Davison]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 07 Apr 2020 15:22:02 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://api.substack.com/feed/podcast/357500/278a8ca8eda09a21494fb658ea201d1b.mp3" length="0" type="audio/mpeg"/><itunes:author>Derek Davison</itunes:author><itunes:explicit>No</itunes:explicit><itunes:duration>3226</itunes:duration><itunes:image href="https://substackcdn.com/feed/podcast/6479/post/357500/8496c6af221084e8dc535c694e1bdb1f.jpg"/></item><item><title><![CDATA[When Empires Get Sick, with Patrick Wyman (PODCAST 4-02-2020)]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>I’m joined by historian and podcaster Patrick Wyman, whose “The Fall of Rome” and “Tides of History” are two of the very best historical podcasts out there, to discuss pandemic diseases in Roman history. We’re talking the Antonine Plague, the Plague of Cyprian, and the Plague of Justinian, and what they meant to the Roman Empire and (especially in the latter case) to world history in general. Later, and apropos of nothing in particular, we discuss Patrick’s <a target="_blank" href="https://www.motherjones.com/media/2020/03/how-do-you-know-if-youre-living-through-the-death-of-an-empire/">recent piece</a> for <em>Mother Jones,</em> “How Do You Know If You’re Living Through the Death of an Empire?”</p><p><a target="_blank" href="https://wondery.com/shows/the-fall-of-rome-podcast/">The Fall of Rome</a> and <a target="_blank" href="https://wondery.com/shows/tides-of-history/">Tides of History</a> are both available via Wondery or wherever you get your podcasts, and I can’t recommend them enough. As Patrick notes toward the end of the interview he’s got a book coming out in the near future, so keep an eye out for that. You can find Patrick on Twitter <a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/Patrick_Wyman">@Patrick_Wyman</a>.</p> <br/><br/>This is a public episode. If you’d like to discuss this with other subscribers or get access to bonus episodes, visit <a href="https://fx.substack.com/subscribe?utm_medium=podcast&#38;utm_campaign=CTA_2">fx.substack.com/subscribe</a>]]></description><link>https://fx.substack.com/p/when-empires-get-sick-with-patrick</link><guid isPermaLink="false">substack:post:347466</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Derek Davison]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2020 16:35:23 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://api.substack.com/feed/podcast/347466/b5a08b4aa2cebbce12d987572e5f9357.mp3" length="0" type="audio/mpeg"/><itunes:author>Derek Davison</itunes:author><itunes:explicit>No</itunes:explicit><itunes:duration>4930</itunes:duration><itunes:image href="https://substackcdn.com/feed/podcast/6479/post/347466/8496c6af221084e8dc535c694e1bdb1f.jpg"/></item><item><title><![CDATA[War and Disease, with Kelsey Atherton (PODCAST 3-30-2020)]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p><em>This is the web version of Foreign Exchanges, but did you know you can get it delivered right to your inbox? Sign up today:</em></p><p>I’m joined by defense technology journalist Kelsey Atherton to talk about wars, pandemics, COVID-19, US sanctions, and his latest piece for Inkstick Media, “The Plague and the Long War,” which you can find <a target="_blank" href="https://inkstickmedia.com/the-plague-and-the-long-war/">here</a>. Kelsey writes a newsletter on the intersection between national security and technology for C4ISRNET called <em>Tomorrow Wars</em>, which you can find <a target="_blank" href="https://www.c4isrnet.com/artificial-intelligence/tomorrow-wars/">here</a>.</p> <br/><br/>This is a public episode. If you’d like to discuss this with other subscribers or get access to bonus episodes, visit <a href="https://fx.substack.com/subscribe?utm_medium=podcast&#38;utm_campaign=CTA_2">fx.substack.com/subscribe</a>]]></description><link>https://fx.substack.com/p/war-and-disease-with-kelsey-atherton</link><guid isPermaLink="false">substack:post:340933</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Derek Davison]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 17:17:46 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://api.substack.com/feed/podcast/340933/5f27bfc29e7199c380083489b5b542ba.mp3" length="0" type="audio/mpeg"/><itunes:author>Derek Davison</itunes:author><itunes:explicit>No</itunes:explicit><itunes:duration>4156</itunes:duration><itunes:image href="https://substackcdn.com/feed/podcast/6479/post/340933/8496c6af221084e8dc535c694e1bdb1f.jpg"/></item><item><title><![CDATA[Pandemic Politics, with John Feffer (PODCAST 3-26-2020)]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>This is the web version of Foreign Exchanges, but did you know you can get it delivered right to your inbox? Sign up today:</p><p>I’m joined by John Feffer, director of Foreign Policy in Focus (<a target="_blank" href="https://fpif.org">fpif.org</a>) at the Institute for Policy Studies, to talk about the COVID-19 pandemic and its worldwide political ramifications. John has written three recent pieces on the pandemic:</p><p>* <a target="_blank" href="https://fpif.org/will-the-coronavirus-kill-globalization/">Will the Coronavirus Kill Globalization?</a></p><p>* <a target="_blank" href="https://fpif.org/what-the-coronavirus-says-about-us/">What the Coronavirus Says about Us</a></p><p>* <a target="_blank" href="https://fpif.org/the-politics-of-the-coronavirus/">The Politics of the Coronavirus</a></p> <br/><br/>This is a public episode. If you’d like to discuss this with other subscribers or get access to bonus episodes, visit <a href="https://fx.substack.com/subscribe?utm_medium=podcast&#38;utm_campaign=CTA_2">fx.substack.com/subscribe</a>]]></description><link>https://fx.substack.com/p/pandemic-politics-with-john-feffer</link><guid isPermaLink="false">substack:post:331205</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Derek Davison]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 25 Mar 2020 21:08:39 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://api.substack.com/feed/podcast/331205/34a519a9248a9ac13b3913c5cfe63601.mp3" length="0" type="audio/mpeg"/><itunes:author>Derek Davison</itunes:author><itunes:explicit>No</itunes:explicit><itunes:duration>3760</itunes:duration><itunes:image href="https://substackcdn.com/feed/podcast/6479/post/331205/8496c6af221084e8dc535c694e1bdb1f.jpg"/></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Dollar's Role in American Empire, with David Adler and Daniel Bessner (PODCAST 2-04-2020)]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>David Adler of the Democracy in Europe Movement and the University of Washington’s Daniel Bessner join me to discuss the US dollar’s global influence and how that it with the more overtly military aspects of Empire USA. Their recent <em>The New Republic</em> <a target="_blank" href="https://newrepublic.com/article/156325/end-forever-war-end-dollars-global-dominance">piece</a> is called “To End Forever War, End the Dollar’s Global Dominance.” Enjoy!</p> <br/><br/>This is a public episode. If you’d like to discuss this with other subscribers or get access to bonus episodes, visit <a href="https://fx.substack.com/subscribe?utm_medium=podcast&#38;utm_campaign=CTA_2">fx.substack.com/subscribe</a>]]></description><link>https://fx.substack.com/p/the-dollars-role-in-american-empire</link><guid isPermaLink="false">substack:post:263074</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Derek Davison]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2020 18:57:03 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://api.substack.com/feed/podcast/263074/d8474e7b467ff05ae0b7d08a90a1d6b9.mp3" length="0" type="audio/mpeg"/><itunes:author>Derek Davison</itunes:author><itunes:explicit>No</itunes:explicit><itunes:duration>3501</itunes:duration><itunes:image href="https://substackcdn.com/feed/podcast/6479/post/263074/009247d23d966f249262bcd6a90c2ffb.jpg"/></item><item><title><![CDATA[Mauritania and the G5, with Alex Thurston: PODCAST 1-20-2020]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Returning guest Alex Thurston discusses the recent dust up between the leaders of the G5 Sahel nations and French President Emmanuel Macron, then guides us through an introduction to Mauritania and its current political crisis.</p><p>You can find Alex on Twitter at <a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/sahelblog">@sahelblog</a>. His recent <em>World Politics Review</em> piece on the squabbling at the top of Mauritanian politics can be found <a target="_blank" href="https://www.worldpoliticsreview.com/articles/28460/in-mauritania-president-ould-ghazouani-consolidates-power-irking-his-predecessor">here</a>.</p> <br/><br/>This is a public episode. If you’d like to discuss this with other subscribers or get access to bonus episodes, visit <a href="https://fx.substack.com/subscribe?utm_medium=podcast&#38;utm_campaign=CTA_2">fx.substack.com/subscribe</a>]]></description><link>https://fx.substack.com/p/mauritania-and-the-g5-with-alex-thurston</link><guid isPermaLink="false">substack:post:241050</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Derek Davison and Alex Thurston]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2020 01:47:10 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://api.substack.com/feed/podcast/241050/03455bbfe2714ec57776cd905c079377.mp3" length="0" type="audio/mpeg"/><itunes:author>Derek Davison and Alex Thurston</itunes:author><itunes:explicit>No</itunes:explicit><itunes:duration>4323</itunes:duration><itunes:image href="https://substackcdn.com/feed/podcast/6479/post/241050/8496c6af221084e8dc535c694e1bdb1f.jpg"/></item><item><title><![CDATA[Soleimani, the Airliner, and What's Happening inside Iran, with Fatemeh Aman: PODCAST 1-13-2020]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Fatemeh Aman, a non-resident fellow at the Atlantic Council and expert analyst on Iran and South Asia, joins me to discuss the effects that the assassination of Qassem Soleimani and the shooting down of Ukraine International Airlines Flight 752 are having inside Iran. She breaks down the protests, assesses the impact of the “Maximum Pressure” campaign, and offers some insights into Iranian politics as things stand right now. If you’ve been following Iran news lately I think you’ll find her perspective extremely valuable.</p> <br/><br/>This is a public episode. If you’d like to discuss this with other subscribers or get access to bonus episodes, visit <a href="https://fx.substack.com/subscribe?utm_medium=podcast&#38;utm_campaign=CTA_2">fx.substack.com/subscribe</a>]]></description><link>https://fx.substack.com/p/soleimani-the-airliner-and-whats</link><guid isPermaLink="false">substack:post:223896</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Derek Davison]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2020 20:42:57 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://api.substack.com/feed/podcast/223896/78f4009804ac6acba837ff1fd43640cd.mp3" length="0" type="audio/mpeg"/><itunes:author>Derek Davison</itunes:author><itunes:explicit>No</itunes:explicit><itunes:duration>3365</itunes:duration><itunes:image href="https://substackcdn.com/feed/podcast/6479/post/223896/009247d23d966f249262bcd6a90c2ffb.jpg"/></item><item><title><![CDATA[Luis Almagro, the OAS, and Bolivia, with Branko Marcetic: PODCAST 11-22-2019]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>In today’s episode I’m joined by journalist Branko Marcetic to discuss his <a target="_blank" href="https://inthesetimes.com/article/22181/oas-bolivia-coup-venezuela-maduro-trump-luis-almagro">new piece</a> at <em>In These Times</em> looking at the transformation of Luis Almagro, secretary-general of the Organization of American States, from foreign minister for a leftist government in Uruguay to useful tool of right-wing US foreign policy. We look particularly at the role the OAS has played in the coup that ousted former Bolivian President Evo Morales and at Almagro’s wild changes of opinion with respect to Venezuela.</p><p><em>OAS Secretary-General Luis Almagro testifying before the Senate Foreign Relations Committee in 2017 (Wikimedia Commons)</em></p><p>All of Foreign Exchanges’ interview episodes are available to the public, but if you’d like to support these shows and get access to the rest of FX’s content, please <a target="_blank" href="https://fx.substack.com/subscribe">subscribe</a>!</p> <br/><br/>This is a public episode. If you’d like to discuss this with other subscribers or get access to bonus episodes, visit <a href="https://fx.substack.com/subscribe?utm_medium=podcast&#38;utm_campaign=CTA_2">fx.substack.com/subscribe</a>]]></description><link>https://fx.substack.com/p/luis-almagro-the-oas-and-bolivia</link><guid isPermaLink="false">substack:post:177098</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Derek Davison]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2019 18:33:06 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://api.substack.com/feed/podcast/177098/758421719d6803685c200fb825999b44.mp3" length="0" type="audio/mpeg"/><itunes:author>Derek Davison</itunes:author><itunes:explicit>No</itunes:explicit><itunes:duration>3963</itunes:duration><itunes:image href="https://substackcdn.com/feed/podcast/6479/post/177098/aab757767bdbd111a574421fb51059e7.jpg"/></item><item><title><![CDATA[Drones, Killer Robots, and Nuclear AI, with Kelsey Atherton (PODCAST 9-04-2019)]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>I’m joined by defense technology journalist Kelsey Atherton of C4ISRNET to discuss several recent stories related to technology in the military, from the alleged need for a fully autonomous nuclear deterrent (!) to the Pentagon’s plan to create a domestic quadcopter industry from whole cloth. You can find Kelsey’s “Tomorrow Wars” newsletter <a target="_blank" href="https://www.c4isrnet.com/artificial-intelligence/tomorrow-wars/">here</a>, and you can find Kelsey himself on Twitter <a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/AthertonKD">here</a>. Enjoy!</p><p><strong>LINKS</strong></p><p>* <a target="_blank" href="https://warontherocks.com/2019/08/america-needs-a-dead-hand/">War on the Rocks</a>: “America Needs a ‘Dead Hand’”</p><p>* <a target="_blank" href="https://thebulletin.org/2019/08/strangelove-redux-us-experts-propose-having-ai-control-nuclear-weapons/">Bulletin of the Atomic Scientists</a>: “Strangelove Redux”</p><p>* <a target="_blank" href="https://www.theatlantic.com/technology/archive/2019/09/killer-robots-and-new-era-machine-driven-warfare/597130/?utm_medium=social&#38;utm_campaign=the-atlantic&#38;utm_term=2019-09-03T09%3A00%3A42&#38;utm_content=edit-promo&#38;utm_source=twitter">The Atlantic</a>: “Coming Soon to a Battlefield: Robots That Can Kill”</p><p>* <a target="_blank" href="https://www.nytimes.com/2018/11/15/magazine/autonomous-robots-weapons.html">New York Times Magazine</a>: “Are Killer Robots the Future of War?”</p><p>* <a target="_blank" href="https://www.nytimes.com/2019/08/28/opinion/military-war-tech-us.html">New York Times</a>: “Dear Tech Workers, U.S. Service Members Need Your Help”</p><p>* <a target="_blank" href="https://foreignpolicy.com/2019/08/27/pentagon-seeks-to-counter-chinas-drone-edge/">Foreign Policy</a>: “Pentagon Seeks to Counter China’s Drone Edge”</p><p>* <a target="_blank" href="https://www.fifthdomain.com/cyber/2019/08/26/can-congress-legislate-a-secure-technology-supply-chain-for-the-pentagon/">Fifth Domain</a>: “Can Congress legislate a secure technology supply chain for the Pentagon?”</p> <br/><br/>This is a public episode. If you’d like to discuss this with other subscribers or get access to bonus episodes, visit <a href="https://fx.substack.com/subscribe?utm_medium=podcast&#38;utm_campaign=CTA_2">fx.substack.com/subscribe</a>]]></description><link>https://fx.substack.com/p/drones-killer-robots-and-nuclear</link><guid isPermaLink="false">substack:post:117581</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Derek Davison]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2019 20:38:32 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://api.substack.com/feed/podcast/117581/7ee95e577b3294e7756ae1ca1b29d891.mp3" length="0" type="audio/mpeg"/><itunes:author>Derek Davison</itunes:author><itunes:explicit>No</itunes:explicit><itunes:duration>4675</itunes:duration><itunes:image href="https://substackcdn.com/feed/podcast/6479/post/117581/009247d23d966f249262bcd6a90c2ffb.jpg"/></item><item><title><![CDATA[The New Trade Paradigm, with Ryan Cooper (PODCAST 08-08-2019)]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>I welcome back Ryan Cooper (<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/ryanlcooper">@ryanlcooper</a>), national correspondent for <em>The Week</em> magazine and co-host of the exciting new <a target="_blank" href="https://leftanchor.podbean.com">Left Anchor</a> podcast (you can also check them out on <a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/leftanchor?lang=en">Twitter</a>). Ryan wrote a <a target="_blank" href="https://theweek.com/articles/856337/old-democratic-trade-paradigm-collapsing-good-riddance">piece</a> last week (his full archive is <a target="_blank" href="https://theweek.com/authors/ryan-cooper">here</a>) looking at the alternative to the ossified “free trade” consensus that’s emerging on the left in the Democratic primary, and he’ll walk us through the development of that consensus and why it’s so ripe to be challenged now.</p><p><em>Tom Friedman and </em><em>The Mustache of Understanding</em><em> make a cameo appearance</em></p><p>Yes, I know I introduce the episode as “August 7,” but that’s because we did in fact record the interview yesterday evening. I’d hoped to send it out yesterday in fact but by the time I got done with my usual amateur efforts at cleaning it up I decided it would be better to send it out in the morning. Enjoy!</p> <br/><br/>This is a public episode. If you’d like to discuss this with other subscribers or get access to bonus episodes, visit <a href="https://fx.substack.com/subscribe?utm_medium=podcast&#38;utm_campaign=CTA_2">fx.substack.com/subscribe</a>]]></description><link>https://fx.substack.com/p/the-new-trade-paradigm-with-ryan</link><guid isPermaLink="false">substack:post:102020</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Derek Davison]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2019 12:30:47 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://api.substack.com/feed/podcast/102020/470723ccd5ad2e14f70d1df4a141df4f.mp3" length="0" type="audio/mpeg"/><itunes:author>Derek Davison</itunes:author><itunes:explicit>No</itunes:explicit><itunes:duration>3601</itunes:duration><itunes:image href="https://substackcdn.com/feed/podcast/6479/post/102020/fd18b64e9cc6dfc552eabb39bd4bb75f.jpg"/></item><item><title><![CDATA[Quincy and the Blob, with Stephen Wertheim (PODCAST 7-26-2019)]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p><em>All of FX’s interviews are available to the public, but if you’d like to support the podcast and get access to exclusive content, subscribe today:</em></p><p>I’m joined by Stephen Wertheim (@stephenwertheim on Twitter), Co-Founder of the <a target="_blank" href="https://quincyinst.org">Quincy Institute for Responsible Statecraft</a>, Research Director of its Ending Endless War program and a Research Scholar at the Saltzman Institute of War and Peace Studies at Columbia University. Stephen has been trying to make sense of the Blob for a while now and he’s here to share his thoughts about an overly militarized, interventionist U.S. foreign policy establishment. We discuss the development of the Blob and the role he sees the new Quincy Institute playing in trying to bring new perspective to the foreign policy debate in DC. This episode also features a guest appearance by my dog, so be sure to listen for that. Enjoy!</p><p><em>Quincy’s logo, pilfered from their website</em></p> <br/><br/>This is a public episode. If you’d like to discuss this with other subscribers or get access to bonus episodes, visit <a href="https://fx.substack.com/subscribe?utm_medium=podcast&#38;utm_campaign=CTA_2">fx.substack.com/subscribe</a>]]></description><link>https://fx.substack.com/p/quincy-and-the-blob-with-stephen</link><guid isPermaLink="false">substack:post:93851</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Derek Davison]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2019 19:34:30 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://api.substack.com/feed/podcast/93851/97838adcab79a7518ee79c37d2cc981a.mp3" length="0" type="audio/mpeg"/><itunes:author>Derek Davison</itunes:author><itunes:explicit>No</itunes:explicit><itunes:duration>3884</itunes:duration><itunes:image href="https://substackcdn.com/feed/podcast/6479/post/93851/15992fd0053fb99e9eecfddf6c0bb3d1.jpg"/></item><item><title><![CDATA[PODCAST 6-21-2019: The Car Wash Scandal Scandal, with Andrew Fishman]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>I’m very pleased to welcome Andrew Fishman (<a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/AndrewDFish">@AndrewDFish</a>), managing editor for the <a target="_blank" href="https://theintercept.com/brasil/">Intercept Brasil</a>. He’s here to guide us through the bombshell reporting the Intercept is currently doing on the scandal involving the Operation Car Wash scandal (yes, it’s a scandal over a scandal) and what seems to have been the very politically motivated corruption prosecution of former Brazilian President Luiz Inácio Lula da Silva. That prosecution prevented Lula from running for president again in 2018 and paved the way for the election of far-right demagogue Jair Bolsonaro. We’ll talk about Lula, Operation Car Wash, and the timeline of events that brought them together, and then Andrew will take us into what the Intercept has learned about Lula’s case and the actions of its presiding judge (now Bolsonaro’s justice minister), Sérgio Moro. Enjoy!</p><p>For English readers, you can find the Intercept’s series on the Lula prosecution <a target="_blank" href="https://theintercept.com/2019/06/17/brazil-sergio-moro-lula-operation-car-wash/">here</a> (that’s part four but there are links to the previous three pieces). If you know Portuguese, you can go <a target="_blank" href="https://theintercept.com/2019/06/18/lava-jato-fingiu-investigar-fhc-apenas-para-criar-percepcao-publica-de-imparcialidade-mas-moro-repreendeu-melindra-alguem-cujo-apoio-e-importante/">here</a> and check out all seven parts published to date (the English series is a little behind).</p> <br/><br/>This is a public episode. If you’d like to discuss this with other subscribers or get access to bonus episodes, visit <a href="https://fx.substack.com/subscribe?utm_medium=podcast&#38;utm_campaign=CTA_2">fx.substack.com/subscribe</a>]]></description><link>https://fx.substack.com/p/podcast-6-21-2019-the-car-wash-scandal</link><guid isPermaLink="false">substack:post:76105</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Derek Davison]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2019 21:24:51 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://api.substack.com/feed/podcast/76105/d9215b734240d6cc29dad2e9fcc744b0.mp3" length="0" type="audio/mpeg"/><itunes:author>Derek Davison</itunes:author><itunes:explicit>No</itunes:explicit><itunes:duration>5317</itunes:duration><itunes:image href="https://substackcdn.com/feed/podcast/6479/post/76105/009247d23d966f249262bcd6a90c2ffb.jpg"/></item><item><title><![CDATA[PODCAST 6-18-2019: Xinjiang and the Uyghurs with Darren Byler]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>I’m very grateful to be joined in this episode by Darren Byler, lecturer in anthropology at the University of Washington. Darren’s research focuses on art and culture in Xinjiang and he’s done considerable field work in the region. He’s here to walk us quickly through Uyghur history, to talk about his own work in the region, and to give us a sense of the Chinese government’s campaign to stamp out Uyghur culture under the guise of “counter-terrorism.”</p><p><strong>LINKS:</strong></p><p>Darren has a website, “The Art of Life in Chinese Central Asia,” that covers art and politics in Northwest China and Central Asia and provides a digital home for Xinjiang artists to tell their stories and display their work. Check it out at <a target="_blank" href="https://livingotherwise.com">LivingOtherwise.com</a>.</p><p>Darren also writes a regular column on Xinjiang for supchina.com, which you can find <a target="_blank" href="https://supchina.com/tag/xinjiang-column/">here</a>.</p><p>Finally, his recent Guardian piece on high-tech state surveillance in Xinjiang is <a target="_blank" href="https://www.theguardian.com/news/2019/apr/11/china-hi-tech-war-on-muslim-minority-xinjiang-uighurs-surveillance-face-recognition">here</a>.</p> <br/><br/>This is a public episode. If you’d like to discuss this with other subscribers or get access to bonus episodes, visit <a href="https://fx.substack.com/subscribe?utm_medium=podcast&#38;utm_campaign=CTA_2">fx.substack.com/subscribe</a>]]></description><link>https://fx.substack.com/p/podcast-6-18-2019-xinjiang-and-the</link><guid isPermaLink="false">substack:post:74497</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Derek Davison]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2019 17:31:41 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://api.substack.com/feed/podcast/74497/f9cc45f92222ad595f7b09580338b174.mp3" length="0" type="audio/mpeg"/><itunes:author>Derek Davison</itunes:author><itunes:explicit>No</itunes:explicit><itunes:duration>3947</itunes:duration><itunes:image href="https://substackcdn.com/feed/podcast/6479/post/74497/009247d23d966f249262bcd6a90c2ffb.jpg"/></item><item><title><![CDATA[PODCAST 5-22-2019: (BONUS) Australia's election with Matt Brady]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>I’m joined by Australia’s own Matt Brady to discuss Saturday’s election and the sordid cast of characters involved in its decidedly unexpected outcome. We look at what happened to the Labor Party and what to expect now that Scott Morrison has a whole term ahead of him—at the risk of spoiling the ending, it’s not good. Enjoy!</p> <br/><br/>This is a public episode. If you’d like to discuss this with other subscribers or get access to bonus episodes, visit <a href="https://fx.substack.com/subscribe?utm_medium=podcast&#38;utm_campaign=CTA_2">fx.substack.com/subscribe</a>]]></description><link>https://fx.substack.com/p/podcast-5-22-2019-bonus-australias</link><guid isPermaLink="false">substack:post:62048</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Derek Davison]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2019 19:51:05 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://api.substack.com/feed/podcast/62048/e9136f0bb1eb342ddb51df9d24d2a677.mp3" length="0" type="audio/mpeg"/><itunes:author>Derek Davison</itunes:author><itunes:explicit>No</itunes:explicit><itunes:duration>2615</itunes:duration><itunes:image href="https://substackcdn.com/feed/podcast/6479/post/62048/009247d23d966f249262bcd6a90c2ffb.jpg"/></item><item><title><![CDATA[PODCAST 4-04-2019: Sahel update with Alex Thurston]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>I'm joined for either the first or third time by Alex Thurston from Miami University of Ohio to talk about inter-communal violence in Mali, Nigeria, and Burkina Faso, as well as an update on the Boko Haram(s) conflict in Nigeria. Alex is an expert on the Sahel region who writes at several places, but you should definitely check out his <a target="_blank" href="https://sahelblog.wordpress.com/">Sahel Blog</a> and his books:</p><p>* <em>Salafism in Nigeria </em>from <a target="_blank" href="http://www.cambridge.org/us/academic/subjects/politics-international-relations/african-government-politics-and-policy/salafism-nigeria-islam-preaching-and-politics?format=PB">Columbia University Press</a></p><p>* <em>Boko Haram: The History of an African Jihadist Movement </em>from <a target="_blank" href="https://press.princeton.edu/titles/11094.html">Princeton University Press</a></p><p>You can also follow him on <a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/sahelblog">Twitter</a>.</p><p>I’ve uploaded two previous interviews I did with Alex when I was at Patreon, which you can find most easily on our <a target="_blank" href="https://fx.substack.com/archive">Archive page</a>. And to answer your other question, we do now have an RSS feed for unlocked episodes, so please plug it in to your favorite podcast app: https://api.substack.com/feed/podcast?publication_id=6479. RSS feeds for subscribers are still in the works but should be available soon.</p> <br/><br/>This is a public episode. If you’d like to discuss this with other subscribers or get access to bonus episodes, visit <a href="https://fx.substack.com/subscribe?utm_medium=podcast&#38;utm_campaign=CTA_2">fx.substack.com/subscribe</a>]]></description><link>https://fx.substack.com/p/sahel-update-with-alex-thurston-foreign</link><guid isPermaLink="false">45983</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Derek Davison and Alex Thurston]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2019 20:38:17 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://api.substack.com/feed/podcast/45983/9c679e57b3e2a7b48cc4507d0b766a1b.mp3" length="0" type="audio/mpeg"/><itunes:author>Derek Davison and Alex Thurston</itunes:author><itunes:explicit>No</itunes:explicit><itunes:duration>3065</itunes:duration><itunes:image href="https://substackcdn.com/feed/podcast/6479/post/45983/8496c6af221084e8dc535c694e1bdb1f.jpg"/></item><item><title><![CDATA[Welcome to Foreign Exchanges: the Podcast]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Hey folks. This is just a short introductory message to welcome you here to Substack and explain a bit about how the podcast end of things is going to work. Mostly it’s an excuse for me to test out Substack’s podcasting feature before doing a real episode, which I will be doing later this week. I know there have been some questions about an RSS feed and I answer those as best I can in the audio. I’ll have more updates on that as I hear more from Substack. If you have additional questions/issues regarding podcasting please use the comments or email me: attwiw@gmail.com (I’ll be changing that but for now I’m still using it. Thanks for listening!</p> <br/><br/>This is a public episode. If you’d like to discuss this with other subscribers or get access to bonus episodes, visit <a href="https://fx.substack.com/subscribe?utm_medium=podcast&#38;utm_campaign=CTA_2">fx.substack.com/subscribe</a>]]></description><link>https://fx.substack.com/p/welcome-to-foreign-exchanges-the</link><guid isPermaLink="false">45369</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Derek Davison]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2019 19:05:45 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://api.substack.com/feed/podcast/45369/c6956ab8bf00fcbc597ceab84904ef2b.mp3" length="0" type="audio/mpeg"/><itunes:author>Derek Davison</itunes:author><itunes:explicit>No</itunes:explicit><itunes:duration>638</itunes:duration><itunes:image href="https://substackcdn.com/feed/podcast/6479/post/45369/009247d23d966f249262bcd6a90c2ffb.jpg"/></item><item><title><![CDATA[PODCAST 3-04-2019: Making Sense of Hanoi with John Carl Baker]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>We're a day earlier than usual with this week's first episode, but I like to get interviews out quickly because of the possibility they'll be overtaken by events.</p><p>As promised, I'm joined by John Carl Baker, a senior program officer at the Ploughshares Fund who works on North Korea, to discuss last week's failed US-DPRK summit in Hanoi. John walks us through the history of US-North Korea diplomacy back to the Clinton administration, offers his thoughts on the positives and negatives of the Trump approach toward North Korea, and suggests a better way forward that centers inter-Korean engagement and lets Koreans take the lead for a change. Enjoy!</p><p>John's recent <em>Defense One</em> piece with Ploughshares President Joe Cirincione, on Democrats' response to Trump's North Korea diplomacy, is <a href="https://www.defenseone.com/ideas/2019/02/trump-kim-summit-diplomacy-democrats-should-drop-politics-and-support-it/155102/" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">here</a>.</p> <br/><br/>This is a public episode. If you’d like to discuss this with other subscribers or get access to bonus episodes, visit <a href="https://fx.substack.com/subscribe?utm_medium=podcast&#38;utm_campaign=CTA_2">fx.substack.com/subscribe</a>]]></description><link>https://fx.substack.com/p/making-sense-of-hanoi-with-john-carl-16c</link><guid isPermaLink="false">25130887</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Derek Davison]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2019 21:00:02 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://api.substack.com/feed/podcast/50151/0416ed1c118723fbfa14a1371641a4e6.mp3" length="0" type="audio/mpeg"/><itunes:author>Derek Davison</itunes:author><itunes:explicit>No</itunes:explicit><itunes:duration>3609</itunes:duration><itunes:image href="https://substackcdn.com/feed/podcast/6479/post/50151/009247d23d966f249262bcd6a90c2ffb.jpg"/></item><item><title><![CDATA[PODCAST 1-24-2019: Guaido vs. Maduro with Jared Abbott]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>In something of an emergency episode brought on by the sudden onset of a political crisis in Venezuela, I'm joined by political scientist and DSA member Jared Abbott. Jared specializes in Latin America and just returned from doing fieldwork in Venezuela, and he's here to hopefully put recent events into some context. This episode is open to the public so feel free to share.</p><p>The <em>Jacobin </em>interview Jared mentions toward the end of the show can be found here: <a href="https://www.jacobinmag.com/2019/01/venezuela-maduro-chavez-military-intervention" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">https://www.jacobinmag.com/2019/01/venezuela-maduro-chavez-military-intervention</a></p> <br/><br/>This is a public episode. If you’d like to discuss this with other subscribers or get access to bonus episodes, visit <a href="https://fx.substack.com/subscribe?utm_medium=podcast&#38;utm_campaign=CTA_2">fx.substack.com/subscribe</a>]]></description><link>https://fx.substack.com/p/guaido-v-maduro-dawn-of-a-mess-with-3a2</link><guid isPermaLink="false">24203060</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Derek Davison]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2019 00:07:05 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://api.substack.com/feed/podcast/50161/b9cde58dbd2a5bbd64ece0a1ed8a0dad.mp3" length="0" type="audio/mpeg"/><itunes:author>Derek Davison</itunes:author><itunes:explicit>No</itunes:explicit><itunes:duration>4782</itunes:duration><itunes:image href="https://substackcdn.com/feed/podcast/6479/post/50161/009247d23d966f249262bcd6a90c2ffb.jpg"/></item><item><title><![CDATA[PODCAST 12-20-2018: Moroccan Islam, with Ann Marie Wainscott]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>For our final regular podcast of 2018, I'm joined by political scientist Ann Marie Wainscott of Miami University of Ohio. Ann is currently researching the religious sector in Iraq, but I wanted to talk about her past work in Morocco (ruled by King Mohammed VI, pictured). We talk about the Moroccan government's efforts to bureaucratize religious expression after the Casablanca bombings of 2003, Morocco's efforts to position itself as a "third pole" in the Islamic World, between and apart from the Saudi-Iran rivalry. Finally she helps shed some light on conditions in the Rif surrounding the 2016-2017 Hirak Rif protests and on recent developments in the frozen Western Sahara conflict. This one will be open to the public. Enjoy!</p><p>Ann's book is <em>Bureaucratizing Islam </em>from <a target="_blank" href="https://www.cambridge.org/core/books/bureaucratizing-islam/70BBBC09365C045A323B0DAE9B0CF18A">Cambridge University Press</a>. The 2017 <em>Journal of Politics and Religion </em>article she mentions can be found <a target="_blank" href="https://www.cambridge.org/core/journals/politics-and-religion/article/religious-regulation-as-foreign-policy-moroccos-islamic-diplomacy-in-west-africa/1F17F15E07C005AEE31FAE05C5CF6F8A">here</a> if you have some institutional access, and she's also got a 2015 <a target="_blank" href="https://www.tandfonline.com/eprint/GTf3Zxrc44TXBWAbIWFq/full">article</a> in the <em>Journal of North African Studies </em>on Islamic education in Morocco post-Casablanca. Check out her website, <a target="_blank" href="http://annmariewainscott.com/">annmariewainscott.com</a>, and give her a follow on Twitter, <a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/AnnMWainscott">@AnnMWainscott</a>.</p><p>Finally, since this is it for our regular podcasts in 2018, let me say Happy Holidays to you and yours, and see you in 2019!</p> <br/><br/>This is a public episode. If you’d like to discuss this with other subscribers or get access to bonus episodes, visit <a href="https://fx.substack.com/subscribe?utm_medium=podcast&#38;utm_campaign=CTA_2">fx.substack.com/subscribe</a>]]></description><link>https://fx.substack.com/p/podcast-12-20-2018-moroccan-islam</link><guid isPermaLink="false">47267</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Derek Davison]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2018 18:01:00 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://api.substack.com/feed/podcast/47267/3b1eff48d7281d9a83d3da9af916c92b.mp3" length="0" type="audio/mpeg"/><itunes:author>Derek Davison</itunes:author><itunes:explicit>No</itunes:explicit><itunes:duration>3279</itunes:duration><itunes:image href="https://substackcdn.com/feed/podcast/6479/post/47267/009247d23d966f249262bcd6a90c2ffb.jpg"/></item><item><title><![CDATA[PODCAST 12-11-2018: President Jupiter with Branko Marcetic]]></title><description><![CDATA[We're joined for the second time by <em>Jacobin</em> writer Branko Marcetic (<a href="https://twitter.com/BMarchetich" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">@BMarchetich</a>) to talk about French President Emmanuel Macron's tribulations, France's "yellow vest" protests, why austerity leads both to fascism and to a cooked planet, and of course why Vladimir Putin is behind all of it. Enjoy! <br/><br/>This is a public episode. If you’d like to discuss this with other subscribers or get access to bonus episodes, visit <a href="https://fx.substack.com/subscribe?utm_medium=podcast&#38;utm_campaign=CTA_2">fx.substack.com/subscribe</a>]]></description><link>https://fx.substack.com/p/president-jupiters-austerity-extravaganza-ff7</link><guid isPermaLink="false">23274146</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Derek Davison]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2018 22:10:49 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://api.substack.com/feed/podcast/50169/34d171377b2ef330e40f03e4975d30b5.mp3" length="0" type="audio/mpeg"/><itunes:author>Derek Davison</itunes:author><itunes:explicit>No</itunes:explicit><itunes:duration>3831</itunes:duration><itunes:image href="https://substackcdn.com/feed/podcast/6479/post/50169/009247d23d966f249262bcd6a90c2ffb.jpg"/></item><item><title><![CDATA[PODCAST 11-08-2018: Orthodox Christianity, explained (?), with Hannah Gais]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Freelance writer and Harvard Divinity School grad student Hannah Gais is back, so that makes two repeat guests on the podcast! She's going to try to explain to me how the Orthodox Church works, an effort that goes so well you can hear my dog literally howling by the end of it (I'm pretty sure she saw some kids outside). We talk about the schism between the Russian Orthodox Church and Ecumenical Patriarch Bartholomew I over Bartholomew's decision to allow Ukrainian church leaders to form their own autocephalous Orthodox Church separate from Moscow and try to Make Sense Of It All. Enjoy!</p><p>Hannah has also written a piece about the schism, which we discuss during the interview that you can find <a target="_blank" href="https://fx.substack.com/p/guest-post-inaccurate-conception">here</a>. You can find her on Twitter at <a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/hannahgais">@hannahgais</a>.</p> <br/><br/>This is a public episode. If you’d like to discuss this with other subscribers or get access to bonus episodes, visit <a href="https://fx.substack.com/subscribe?utm_medium=podcast&#38;utm_campaign=CTA_2">fx.substack.com/subscribe</a>]]></description><link>https://fx.substack.com/p/podcast-11-08-2018-orthodox-christianity</link><guid isPermaLink="false">48988</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Derek Davison]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 09 Nov 2018 02:23:00 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://api.substack.com/feed/podcast/48988/2fc8c3950cbc33314b91fd07e32ac2b9.mp3" length="0" type="audio/mpeg"/><itunes:author>Derek Davison</itunes:author><itunes:explicit>No</itunes:explicit><itunes:duration>3465</itunes:duration><itunes:image href="https://substackcdn.com/feed/podcast/6479/post/48988/009247d23d966f249262bcd6a90c2ffb.jpg"/></item><item><title><![CDATA[PODCAST 10-18-2018: War Online with Emerson Brooking]]></title><description><![CDATA[Today I'm joined in person by Emerson T. Brooking, co-author of a new book called <em>LikeWar: The Weaponization of Social Media</em>. We talk about  the ways social media is being used to make life worse, where we're heading in terms of how governments and other bad actors weaponize social media, and what we can do about it. Enjoy!<p>Buy the book: <a href="https://www.powells.com/book/-9781328695741" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">https://www.powells.com/book/-9781328695741</a></p><p>You can follow Emerson on Twitter at @etbrooking. And if you can, Emerson asked me to ask you to support Stacey Abrams, the Democrat running for governor of Georgia. Her actblue page is <a href="https://secure.actblue.com/donate/donate-to-stacey?refcode=website" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">here</a>.</p> <br/><br/>This is a public episode. If you’d like to discuss this with other subscribers or get access to bonus episodes, visit <a href="https://fx.substack.com/subscribe?utm_medium=podcast&#38;utm_campaign=CTA_2">fx.substack.com/subscribe</a>]]></description><link>https://fx.substack.com/p/war-online-with-emerson-brooking-d99</link><guid isPermaLink="false">22150845</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Derek Davison]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 18 Oct 2018 22:37:33 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://api.substack.com/feed/podcast/50183/8325478637b029bf6c8603532851fecc.mp3" length="0" type="audio/mpeg"/><itunes:author>Derek Davison</itunes:author><itunes:explicit>No</itunes:explicit><itunes:duration>5014</itunes:duration><itunes:image href="https://substackcdn.com/feed/podcast/6479/post/50183/009247d23d966f249262bcd6a90c2ffb.jpg"/></item><item><title><![CDATA[PODCAST 9-10-2018: Lula's Brazil with Michael Brooks]]></title><description><![CDATA[If you're a Michael Brooks fan, which you should be, then hopefully you've heard me on his show a few times now. Today I'm very grateful for the chance to turn the tables on him as we talk about Brazilian politics, corruption, Lula, and what has been an extraordinarily eventful presidential campaign. Enjoy!<p>Do yourselves a favor and check out The Michael Brooks Show, on <a href="https://michaelbrooksshow.libsyn.com" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">libsyn</a> and/or <a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCh2UY1hxlMr4_7Az_iQ82HQ" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">YouTube</a>. And if you're not already subscribing to Michael's Patreon, that's <a href="https://www.patreon.com/TMBS/overview">here</a>.</p> <br/><br/>This is a public episode. If you’d like to discuss this with other subscribers or get access to bonus episodes, visit <a href="https://fx.substack.com/subscribe?utm_medium=podcast&#38;utm_campaign=CTA_2">fx.substack.com/subscribe</a>]]></description><link>https://fx.substack.com/p/the-full-brazilian-with-michael-brooks-0d6</link><guid isPermaLink="false">21299415</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Derek Davison]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 10 Sep 2018 20:01:36 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://api.substack.com/feed/podcast/50193/ca7c4ec7b394ad99a73e9d0cd103703c.mp3" length="0" type="audio/mpeg"/><itunes:author>Derek Davison</itunes:author><itunes:explicit>No</itunes:explicit><itunes:duration>4648</itunes:duration><itunes:image href="https://substackcdn.com/feed/podcast/6479/post/50193/009247d23d966f249262bcd6a90c2ffb.jpg"/></item><item><title><![CDATA[PODCAST 9-04-2018: Understanding Mali with Alex Thurston]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Alex Thurston (@sahelblog on <a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/sahelblog">Twitter</a>) joins me again to try to make some sense of the dizzying array of extremist groups in Mali and to talk about the aftermath of the Malian presidential election last month, which saw Ibrahim Boubacar Keïta (pictured) reelected albeit with very low turnout. Be sure to check out Alex's <a target="_blank" href="https://sahelblog.wordpress.com/">Sahel Blog</a> and his books:</p><p>* <em>Salafism in Nigeria </em>from <a target="_blank" href="http://www.cambridge.org/us/academic/subjects/politics-international-relations/african-government-politics-and-policy/salafism-nigeria-islam-preaching-and-politics?format=PB">Columbia University Press</a></p><p>* <em>Boko Haram: The History of an African Jihadist Movement </em>from <a target="_blank" href="https://press.princeton.edu/titles/11094.html">Princeton University Press</a></p><p>Enjoy!</p> <br/><br/>This is a public episode. If you’d like to discuss this with other subscribers or get access to bonus episodes, visit <a href="https://fx.substack.com/subscribe?utm_medium=podcast&#38;utm_campaign=CTA_2">fx.substack.com/subscribe</a>]]></description><link>https://fx.substack.com/p/understanding-mali-with-alex-thurston</link><guid isPermaLink="false">45807</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Derek Davison and Alex Thurston]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 04:15:00 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://api.substack.com/feed/podcast/45807/acee1e26f5d80c4a81a43fde5e30aad4.mp3" length="0" type="audio/mpeg"/><itunes:author>Derek Davison and Alex Thurston</itunes:author><itunes:explicit>No</itunes:explicit><itunes:duration>3322</itunes:duration><itunes:image href="https://substackcdn.com/feed/podcast/6479/post/45807/8496c6af221084e8dc535c694e1bdb1f.jpg"/></item><item><title><![CDATA[PODCAST 8-23-2018: The War on Weapon States, with Michael Youhana]]></title><description><![CDATA[I'm joined by Michael Youhana to discuss his recent piece for the Fellow Travelers Blog, "Ending the War on Weapon States." We talk about what constitutes a Weapon State, how the War on Weapon States has impacted post-Cold War US foreign policy, and how to think about WMD and "rogue states" without falling into the usual Blob b******t. Apologies for a couple of spots where the audio is rough, one of us was fighting a lousy internet connection and the Skype quality suffered for it.<p>You can find Michael's Fellow Traveler's piece <a href="https://fellowtravelersblog.com/2018/08/09/ending-the-war-on-weapon-states/" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">here</a>.</p><p>Follow Michael on Twitter: @Michael_Youhana</p> <br/><br/>This is a public episode. If you’d like to discuss this with other subscribers or get access to bonus episodes, visit <a href="https://fx.substack.com/subscribe?utm_medium=podcast&#38;utm_campaign=CTA_2">fx.substack.com/subscribe</a>]]></description><link>https://fx.substack.com/p/the-war-on-weapon-states-with-michael_youhana-21f</link><guid isPermaLink="false">20944728</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Derek Davison]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 23 Aug 2018 21:15:25 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://api.substack.com/feed/podcast/50198/97c54f680f167c7dd7f01540881f995f.mp3" length="0" type="audio/mpeg"/><itunes:author>Derek Davison</itunes:author><itunes:explicit>No</itunes:explicit><itunes:duration>3398</itunes:duration><itunes:image href="https://substackcdn.com/feed/podcast/6479/post/50198/009247d23d966f249262bcd6a90c2ffb.jpg"/></item><item><title><![CDATA[PODCAST 8-14-2018: Left Foreign Policy with Kelsey Atherton]]></title><description><![CDATA[Unlocked for the public again because we've got another interview. Today I'm joined by defense technology reporter Kelsey Atherton, who you should be following <a href="https://twitter.com/AthertonKD" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">on Twitter</a>. We're talking about building a left-wing foreign policy vision, the new <a href="https://fellowtravelersblog.com" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">Fellow Travelers Blog</a> that aims to get that conversation going, Space Force, and drone madness. Enjoy!<p>Kelsey's piece on the Maduro incident is <a href="https://www.c4isrnet.com/unmanned/2018/08/07/a-drone-explosion-in-venezuela-brings-gimmick-drones-to-the-political-battlefield/" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">here</a>.</p><p>Fellow Travelers Blog on <a href="https://twitter.com/ftravelersblog" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">Twitter</a>.</p> <br/><br/>This is a public episode. If you’d like to discuss this with other subscribers or get access to bonus episodes, visit <a href="https://fx.substack.com/subscribe?utm_medium=podcast&#38;utm_campaign=CTA_2">fx.substack.com/subscribe</a>]]></description><link>https://fx.substack.com/p/left-foreign-policy-with-athertonkd-f8a</link><guid isPermaLink="false">20761159</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Derek Davison]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 14 Aug 2018 20:15:55 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://api.substack.com/feed/podcast/50200/27c5d156e672e7223bf2f67629b230d9.mp3" length="0" type="audio/mpeg"/><itunes:author>Derek Davison</itunes:author><itunes:explicit>No</itunes:explicit><itunes:duration>3502</itunes:duration><itunes:image href="https://substackcdn.com/feed/podcast/6479/post/50200/009247d23d966f249262bcd6a90c2ffb.jpg"/></item><item><title><![CDATA[PODCAST 8-07-2018: Boko Haram and Nigeria with Alex Thurston]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>I'm joined by Alex Thurston from Miami University of Ohio to talk about Boko Haram in particular and Nigeria in general. Alex is an expert on the Sahel region who writes at several places, but you should definitely check out his <a target="_blank" href="https://sahelblog.wordpress.com/">Sahel Blog</a> and his books:</p><p>* <em>Salafism in Nigeria </em>from <a target="_blank" href="http://www.cambridge.org/us/academic/subjects/politics-international-relations/african-government-politics-and-policy/salafism-nigeria-islam-preaching-and-politics?format=PB">Columbia University Press</a></p><p>* <em>Boko Haram: The History of an African Jihadist Movement </em>from <a target="_blank" href="https://press.princeton.edu/titles/11094.html">Princeton University Press</a></p><p>You can also follow him on <a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/sahelblog">Twitter</a>.</p> <br/><br/>This is a public episode. If you’d like to discuss this with other subscribers or get access to bonus episodes, visit <a href="https://fx.substack.com/subscribe?utm_medium=podcast&#38;utm_campaign=CTA_2">fx.substack.com/subscribe</a>]]></description><link>https://fx.substack.com/p/boko-haram-and-nigeria-with-alex</link><guid isPermaLink="false">45806</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Derek Davison and Alex Thurston]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 07 Aug 2018 04:13:00 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://api.substack.com/feed/podcast/45806/d90b5a1f01b689077a0f49553d8debab.mp3" length="0" type="audio/mpeg"/><itunes:author>Derek Davison and Alex Thurston</itunes:author><itunes:explicit>No</itunes:explicit><itunes:duration>3512</itunes:duration><itunes:image href="https://substackcdn.com/feed/podcast/6479/post/45806/8496c6af221084e8dc535c694e1bdb1f.jpg"/></item><item><title><![CDATA[PODCAST 7-24-2018: Trump in Europe with Branko Marcetic]]></title><description><![CDATA[Here's that interview I promised you all last week. I'm speaking with writer Branko Marcetic, who has been covering Donald Trump's trip to the NATO summit and his meeting with Vladimir Putin in Helsinki for Jacobin and In These Times. He's been doing some great work countering the overwrought conventional narratives about both events. We discuss what really happened in Brussels and Helsinki and talk about NATO's superfluous post-Cold War existence. This one is open to the public. Enjoy!<p>Links:</p><p>"<a href="https://www.jacobinmag.com/2018/07/nato-donald-trump-putin-cold-war" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">The Mysteriously Vanished NATO Critique</a>" for Jacobin<br/>"<a href="http://inthesetimes.com/article/21302/Donald_Trump_NATO_Summit_Russia_Cold_War_Media" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">The NATO Summit Wasn’t a Victory for Trump—It Was a Victory for Militarism</a>" for In These Times<br/>"<a href="http://inthesetimes.com/article/21311/Trump_Putin_Summit_Russia_Liberal_Establishment_Media_Russiagate" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">What the Liberal Establishment Gets Wrong About the Trump-Putin Summit</a>" also for In These Times</p><p>Follow Branko on <a href="https://twitter.com/BMarchetich" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">Twitter</a></p> <br/><br/>This is a public episode. If you’d like to discuss this with other subscribers or get access to bonus episodes, visit <a href="https://fx.substack.com/subscribe?utm_medium=podcast&#38;utm_campaign=CTA_2">fx.substack.com/subscribe</a>]]></description><link>https://fx.substack.com/p/trump-in-europe-with-bmarchetich-ba5</link><guid isPermaLink="false">20281592</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Derek Davison]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 24 Jul 2018 17:00:01 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://api.substack.com/feed/podcast/50207/cd8026085e1f871f2c92e2560c809ce7.mp3" length="0" type="audio/mpeg"/><itunes:author>Derek Davison</itunes:author><itunes:explicit>No</itunes:explicit><itunes:duration>3978</itunes:duration><itunes:image href="https://substackcdn.com/feed/podcast/6479/post/50207/009247d23d966f249262bcd6a90c2ffb.jpg"/></item><item><title><![CDATA[PODCAST 6-05-2018: Democratic Party Foreign Policy, with Ryan Cooper]]></title><description><![CDATA[I'm throwing this one open to the general public because I think it's a good discussion and because...I've got a guest! Yes, you get to listen to somebody else talk for a change! I'm very excited to be joined by Ryan Cooper, National Correspondent for <em>The Week</em> and deep thinker about left-wing politics, to discuss what he's learned about how new Democratic candidates are approaching foreign policy and how the party as a whole is approaching foreign policy in the Age of Trump.<p>If you're not reading Ryan's work regularly, you <a href="http://theweek.com/authors/ryan-cooper" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">should</a>. You can also follow him on Twitter.</p><p>If you're interested in developing a left foreign policy, check out <a href="https://fellowtravelersblog.com" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">Fellow Travelers</a>.</p><p>Finally, if you want to support the work that Matt Bruenig is doing in developing a left-wing think tank, his People's Policy Project is <a href="https://peoplespolicyproject.org" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">here</a>.</p><p>Enjoy!</p> <br/><br/>This is a public episode. If you’d like to discuss this with other subscribers or get access to bonus episodes, visit <a href="https://fx.substack.com/subscribe?utm_medium=podcast&#38;utm_campaign=CTA_2">fx.substack.com/subscribe</a>]]></description><link>https://fx.substack.com/p/democratic-party-foreign-policy-with-324</link><guid isPermaLink="false">19273601</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Derek Davison]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 05 Jun 2018 22:57:27 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://api.substack.com/feed/podcast/50222/861759aba725bf6068672ecce334d597.mp3" length="0" type="audio/mpeg"/><itunes:author>Derek Davison</itunes:author><itunes:explicit>No</itunes:explicit><itunes:duration>3844</itunes:duration><itunes:image href="https://substackcdn.com/feed/podcast/6479/post/50222/8496c6af221084e8dc535c694e1bdb1f.jpg"/></item><item><title><![CDATA[Derek on the District Sentinel 5-01-2018]]></title><description><![CDATA[As promised, I did a 20 minute spot with the District Sentinel guys earlier today to discuss Netanyahu's presentation yesterday. You can go check it out on <a href="https://www.patreon.com/posts/bonus-netanyahus-18531737">their Patreon</a> and also check out the other great work they're doing, but they were kind enough to let me also post the audio here for you guys as well. One thing I'll add here: I mentioned Netanyahu wanting his speech to get on Fox and Friends so he could be sure Trump saw it. I actually gave him too much credit, because it turns out Netanyahu himself appeared on Fox and Friends this morning to deliver his sales pitch directly at Trump. I did not know this when we were doing the interview. In my defense, you would need to drug and restrain me to get me to watch Fox and Friends. <br/><br/>This is a public episode. If you’d like to discuss this with other subscribers or get access to bonus episodes, visit <a href="https://fx.substack.com/subscribe?utm_medium=podcast&#38;utm_campaign=CTA_2">fx.substack.com/subscribe</a>]]></description><link>https://fx.substack.com/p/derek-on-the-district-sentinel-5-f69</link><guid isPermaLink="false">18533357</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Derek Davison]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 17:35:41 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://api.substack.com/feed/podcast/50230/0b7dc6cab8def7e7413d90204876ca84.mp3" length="0" type="audio/mpeg"/><itunes:author>Derek Davison</itunes:author><itunes:explicit>No</itunes:explicit><itunes:image href="https://substackcdn.com/feed/podcast/6479/post/50230/009247d23d966f249262bcd6a90c2ffb.jpg"/></item><item><title><![CDATA[PODCAST 4-23-2018: Armenians in the Middle East with @dankmtl]]></title><description><![CDATA[Today I'm pleased to be joined by Dan, aka Twitter user @dankmtl, for a crash course on the history of Armenian communities in the Middle East. Obviously we spend a fair amount of time on the Armenian Genocide, its causes and lingering effects, but we go all the way back to good old Tigranes the Great (see one of his coins above), who expanded Armenia to its largest extent in the first century BCE. This is a subject that can only be given the most cursory of treatments in a single podcast episode, but Dan is more than up to the challenge.<p>I was going to post this on Tuesday as usual, but events in Armenia are kind of overtaking the interview. As I say in a section I just added, ex-Armenian Prime Minister Serzh Sargsyan just resigned today after days of protests over his decision to switch over from president to PM in order to hang onto power. Dan and I did this interview on Sunday and talked briefly about the protests, but obviously we didn't have any idea he was about to step down. I figured I better get this out before anything else happens. Anyway, enjoy!</p> <br/><br/>This is a public episode. If you’d like to discuss this with other subscribers or get access to bonus episodes, visit <a href="https://fx.substack.com/subscribe?utm_medium=podcast&#38;utm_campaign=CTA_2">fx.substack.com/subscribe</a>]]></description><link>https://fx.substack.com/p/armenians-in-the-middle-east-featuring-f73</link><guid isPermaLink="false">18364245</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Derek Davison]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 23 Apr 2018 21:43:45 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://api.substack.com/feed/podcast/50232/e12898a4643ca8ce1289d15ff6e0d086.mp3" length="0" type="audio/mpeg"/><itunes:author>Derek Davison</itunes:author><itunes:explicit>No</itunes:explicit><itunes:duration>3796</itunes:duration><itunes:image href="https://substackcdn.com/feed/podcast/6479/post/50232/6ebc04a99f606ee681d1faeb64a27f3d.jpg"/></item><item><title><![CDATA[PODCAST 3-05-2018: John Feffer on Donald Trump and Majoritarianism]]></title><description><![CDATA[Today's episode is another interview and it is again going to be available to the public. I'm grateful to have been joined by John Feffer of the Institute for Policy Studies to talk about his recent piece for <a href="http://fpif.org/ideology-unites-trump-authoritarians-admires/" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">Foreign Policy in Focus</a> on Donald Trump's majoritarian politics and the spread of majoritarianism around the world (I know I mention "a couple of pieces" in my intro but consider that a function of the fact that I got about five hours of sleep last night and that my plan for the interview changed as we were recording it). John walks us through the concept of majoritarianism, examines the construction of a "majority" in the first place, and looks at majoritarianism's causes and a hopeful counter to it. You can find more of John's work at <a href="http://fpif.org" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">Foreign Policy in Focus</a>, <a href="http://lobelog.com" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">LobeLog</a>, and <a href="http://www.johnfeffer.com" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">his own website</a>. Enjoy!<p>I close with an appeal for you to support a new resolution in the US Senate offered by Bernie Sanders, Mike Lee, and Chris Murphy that could potentially end America's role in the ongoing Yemen atrocity. <a href="http://winwithoutwar.org" class="linkified" target="_blank">WinWithoutWar.org</a>'s petition is <a href="http://winwithoutwar.org/end-americas-secret-war-yemen/" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">here</a>. I know I usually post episodes on Tuesdays but because the petition is timely I wanted to get this episode out as soon as it was ready.</p> <br/><br/>This is a public episode. If you’d like to discuss this with other subscribers or get access to bonus episodes, visit <a href="https://fx.substack.com/subscribe?utm_medium=podcast&#38;utm_campaign=CTA_2">fx.substack.com/subscribe</a>]]></description><link>https://fx.substack.com/p/john-feffer-on-donald-trump-and-majoritarianism-b5d</link><guid isPermaLink="false">17383454</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Derek Davison]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 06 Mar 2018 00:00:59 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://api.substack.com/feed/podcast/50242/fcbdf36add72501519973409b9bd981c.mp3" length="0" type="audio/mpeg"/><itunes:author>Derek Davison</itunes:author><itunes:explicit>No</itunes:explicit><itunes:duration>3366</itunes:duration><itunes:image href="https://substackcdn.com/feed/podcast/6479/post/50242/009247d23d966f249262bcd6a90c2ffb.jpg"/></item><item><title><![CDATA[PODCAST 2-27-2018: Hannah Gais on Russiagate and Vladimir Putin ]]></title><description><![CDATA[We're lucky to be joined by freelance writer, full-time grad student, and Russian active measure Hannah Gais to talk about the 2016 election, Russiagate, Vladimir Putin, the state of US-Russia relations, and Russia's many crimes including killing God. I'm opening this episode to the general public for a change, so please share widely.<p>Hannah's Baffler piece, "Who's Afraid of the Russian Soul?" is <a href="https://thebaffler.com/this-american-carnage/whos-afraid-of-the-russian-soul-gais" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">here</a>.</p><p>Enjoy!</p> <br/><br/>This is a public episode. If you’d like to discuss this with other subscribers or get access to bonus episodes, visit <a href="https://fx.substack.com/subscribe?utm_medium=podcast&#38;utm_campaign=CTA_2">fx.substack.com/subscribe</a>]]></description><link>https://fx.substack.com/p/hannah-gais-on-russiagate-and-vladimir-de8</link><guid isPermaLink="false">17191827</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Derek Davison]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2018 00:00:59 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://api.substack.com/feed/podcast/50244/32cb8434b2d88394be3618d446bf0ed5.mp3" length="0" type="audio/mpeg"/><itunes:author>Derek Davison</itunes:author><itunes:explicit>No</itunes:explicit><itunes:duration>3873</itunes:duration><itunes:image href="https://substackcdn.com/feed/podcast/6479/post/50244/009247d23d966f249262bcd6a90c2ffb.jpg"/></item><item><title><![CDATA[PODCAST 2-01-2018: Jim Lobe on Neoconservatism]]></title><description><![CDATA[I'm proud to bring you our first interview! Veteran reporter Jim Lobe joins me to talk about neoconservatism, a subject on which he has been reporting and lecturing and giving interviews for many years now. We talk about defining neoconservatism, about its development from a niche intellectual movement on the leftish side of the spectrum into perhaps the dominant foreign policy ideology on the right, and about its ability to thrive despite its close association with the bar-none worst foreign policy decision in modern American history.<p>Jim's website, which you should know if you read my work, is <a href="http://lobelog.com" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">lobelog.com</a>, and the piece he references on Sheldon Adelson and Donald Trump is <a href="https://lobelog.com/has-trump-become-adelsons-perfect-little-puppet/" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank">here</a>. Enjoy!</p> <br/><br/>This is a public episode. If you’d like to discuss this with other subscribers or get access to bonus episodes, visit <a href="https://fx.substack.com/subscribe?utm_medium=podcast&#38;utm_campaign=CTA_2">fx.substack.com/subscribe</a>]]></description><link>https://fx.substack.com/p/jim-lobe-on-neoconservatism-attwiw-2ee</link><guid isPermaLink="false">16748771</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Derek Davison]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2018 01:00:01 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://api.substack.com/feed/podcast/50251/fbe0747db9d981eb574b93d9f420c8d8.mp3" length="0" type="audio/mpeg"/><itunes:author>Derek Davison</itunes:author><itunes:explicit>No</itunes:explicit><itunes:duration>4708</itunes:duration><itunes:image href="https://substackcdn.com/feed/podcast/6479/post/50251/009247d23d966f249262bcd6a90c2ffb.jpg"/></item></channel></rss>