<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"><channel><title>IEEE Spectrum</title><link>https://spectrum.ieee.org/</link><description>IEEE Spectrum</description><atom:link href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/feeds/topic/careers.rss" rel="self"></atom:link><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 14:41:26 -0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/eyJ0eXAiOiJKV1QiLCJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJpbWFnZSI6Imh0dHBzOi8vYXNzZXRzLnJibC5tcy8yNjg4NDUyMC9vcmlnaW4ucG5nIiwiZXhwaXJlc19hdCI6MTY5OTk5OTQzOX0.aimbeagNFKGtififsLPFvztNYGr1_NMvLOOT1mPOjEU/image.png?width=210</url><link>https://spectrum.ieee.org/</link><title>IEEE Spectrum</title></image><item><title>How This Startup Cut Production Costs of Millimeter Wave Power Amplifiers</title><link>https://spectrum.ieee.org/millimeter-wave-power-amplifier-startup</link><description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/group-of-people-standing-outside-under-a-tree-smiling-at-camera.jpg?id=32001512&width=1245&height=700&coordinates=0%2C0%2C0%2C469"/><br/><br/><p><a href="https://elvespeed.com/founder" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Diana Gamzina</a> is on a mission to drastically reduce the price of millimeter-wave power amplifiers. The vacuum-electronics devices are used for communication with distant space probes and for other applications that need the highest data rates available.</p><p>The amplifiers can cost as much as US $1 million apiece because they’re made using costly, high-precision manufacturing and manual assembly. Gamzina’s startup,<a href="https://elvespeed.com/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"> Elve</a>, is using advanced materials and new manufacturing technologies to lower the unit price.</p><hr/><p>It can take up to a year to produce one of the amplifiers using conventional manufacturing processes, but Elve is already making about one per week, Gamzina says. Elve’s process enables sales at about 10 percent of the usual price, making large-volume markets more accessible.</p><p>Launched in June 2020, the startup produces affordable systems for wireless connections that deliver optical fiber quality, or what Gamzina calls <em>elvespeed </em><em>connectivity</em>. The company’s name, she says, refers to atmospheric emission of light and very low frequency perturbations due to electromagnetic pulse sources. Elves can be seen as a flat ring glowing in Earth’s upper atmosphere. They appear for just a few milliseconds and can grow to be up to 320 kilometers wide.</p><p>Based in Davis, Calif., Elve employs 12 people as well as a handful of consultants and advisors.</p><p>For her work with amplifiers, Gamzina, an IEEE senior member, was recognized with this year’s<a href="https://vacuumelectronics.org/veysaward.html" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"> Vacuum Electronics Young Scientist Award</a> from the<a href="https://eds.ieee.org/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"> IEEE Electron Devices Society</a>. She received the award in April at the<a href="https://www.ieeeivec.org/index.html" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"> IEEE International Vacuum Electronics Conference</a>, in Monterey, Calif.</p><p>“Dr. Gamzina’s innovation and contributions to the industry are remarkable,” IEEE Member <a href="https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/author/37272687400" target="_blank">Jack Tucek</a>, general chair of the conference, said in a<a href="https://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20220510005453/en/Elve-CEO-Recognized-with-IEEE-Vacuum-Electronics-Young-Scientist-Award" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"> news release</a> about the award.</p><h2>Interactions between millimeter-wave signals and electrons</h2><p>In addition to running her company, Ganzima works as a staff scientist at the <a href="https://www6.slac.stanford.edu/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">SLAC National Accelerator Laboratory</a>, in Menlo Park, Calif.—a U.S. <a href="https://www.energy.gov/national-laboratories" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Department of Energy national lab</a> operated by Stanford University. It was in this role that she began speaking to industry representatives about how to expand the market for high-performance millimeter-wave amplifiers.</p><p>From those discussions, she found that lowering the price was key.</p><p>“Customers are paying between $250,000 and $1 million for each individual device,” she says. “When you hear these numbers, you realize why people don’t think this price is anywhere close to affordable for growing the market.”</p><p>Elve’s millimeter-wave power amplifier system weighs 4 kilograms, measures 23 centimeters by 15 cm by 8 cm, and is powered by a 28-volt DC input bus. The heart of the amplifier system is a set of traveling-wave tubes. TWTs are a subset of vacuum electronics that can amplify electromagnetic signals by more than a hundredfold over a wide bandwidth of frequencies. They’re commonly used for communications and radar imaging applications, Gamzina says.</p><p class="pull-quote">“Our ultimate goal is to be part of the terrestrial market such that the amplifiers are installed on cellphone towers, enabling high-data-rate communication in remote and rural locations all over the world.”</p><p>The TWT takes a millimeter-wave signal and makes it “interact with a high-energy electron beam so that the signal steals the energy from the electron beam. That’s how it gets amplified,” Gamzina says. “In some ways, it’s a simple concept, but it requires excellence in RF design, manufacturing, vacuum science, electron emission, and thermal management to make it all work.”</p><p>Elve’s millimeter-wave amplifiers enable communication with satellite networks and create long-distance ground-to-ground links.</p><p>“This allows enormous amounts of data to be sent, leading to higher data rates that are comparable to fiber or laser-type communication devices,” Gamzina says. “Another advantage is that the amplifier can operate in most inclement weather.”</p><p>The initial market for Elve’s amplifiers is the communications field, she says, especially for backhaul: the connections between base stations and the core network infrastructure.</p><p>“Our ultimate goal is to be part of the terrestrial market such that the amplifiers are installed on cellphone towers,” Gamzina says, “enabling high-data-rate communication in remote and rural locations all over the world.”</p><p>The company plans to develop millimeter-wave amplifiers for imaging and radar applications as well.</p><p class="shortcode-media shortcode-media-rebelmouse-image">
<img alt="a red device on a white background" class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="2636656805d5139450a4e44b2384684e" data-rm-shortcode-name="rebelmouse-image" id="40950" loading="lazy" src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/a-red-device-on-a-white-background.jpg?id=32001526&width=980"/>
<small class="image-media media-caption" placeholder="Add Photo Caption...">Elve’s power amplifier containers house a traveling-wave tube, electronic power conditioner, and a cooling system.</small><small class="image-media media-photo-credit" placeholder="Add Photo Credit...">Elve</small></p><h2>Building on research done at the SLAC Lab</h2><p>Gamzina’s work at Elve is related to research she is conducting at the SLAC lab as well as previous work she did as a development engineer with the millimeter-wave research group at the<a href="https://www.ucdavis.edu/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"> University of California, Davis</a>. There she studied vacuum devices that operate at terahertz frequencies for use as power sources in particle accelerators, broadcast transmitters, industrial heating, radar systems, and communication satellites. She also led research programs in additive manufacturing techniques. She holds three U.S. patents related to the manufacture of vacuum-electronics devices.</p><p>To learn how to launch a startup, she took a class at<a href="https://www.stanford.edu/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"> Stanford</a> on the subject and she attended a 10-week training course for founders offered by <a href="https://4thly.com/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">4thly</a>, a global startup accelerator. She also says she learned a few things as a youngster while helping out at her father’s hydraulic equipment manufacturing company.</p><p>Raising funds to keep one’s business afloat is difficult for many startups, but it wasn’t the case for Elve, Gamzina says.</p><p>“We have good market traction, a good product, and a good team,” she says. “There’s been a lot of interest in what we’re doing.”</p><p>What has been a concern, she says, is that the company is growing so rapidly, it might be difficult to scale up production.</p><p>“Making hundreds or thousands of these has been a challenge to even comprehend,” she says. “But we are ready to go from the state we’re in to the next big jump.”</p>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2022 18:00:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spectrum.ieee.org/millimeter-wave-power-amplifier-startup</guid><category>Ieee member news</category><category>Telecommunications</category><category>Career</category><category>Startups</category><category>Communications</category><category>Vacuum electronics</category><category>Millimeter wave power amplifiers</category><category>Type:ti</category><dc:creator>Kathy Pretz</dc:creator><media:content medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/group-of-people-standing-outside-under-a-tree-smiling-at-camera.jpg?id=32001512&amp;width=980"></media:content></item><item><title>Craig Partridge Is Still Working to Improve Internet Traffic</title><link>https://spectrum.ieee.org/craig-partridge-profile</link><description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/a-smiling-bearded-man-in-a-blue-turtleneck-stands-in-front-of-a-building.png?id=31965104&width=1245&height=700&coordinates=0%2C20%2C0%2C350"/><br/><br/><p><strong>For computer pioneer </strong><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/craig-partridge-3aa6602/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Craig Partridge</a>, pushing the envelope on interesting challenges has been his modus operandi. It’s what led him to make key contributions to the early Internet. Today he’s working on getting a better understanding of traffic flows in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Virtual_private_network" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">VPNs</a>. In addition, he is trying to figure out what causes high rates of packet errors, which often result in bad file transfers, and how to fix them. </p><p>Although his bachelor’s degree from <a href="http://harvard.edu/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Harvard</a> was in history, the computer electives he took convinced him he had both the aptitude and interest for a career in computing. And he was right. He focused on networking concepts and technologies while working at the ARPAnet and Internet pioneering firm Bolt Beranek & Newman (BBN), now <a href="https://www.raytheonintelligenceandspace.com/what-we-do/bbn" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Raytheon BBN Technologies</a>.</p><hr/><p>There, the IEEE Fellow collaborated with TCP/IP developer <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/philkarn" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Phil Karn</a> on TCP message round-trip time estimation. Partridge also led the team that designed and built the world’s first high-speed router.</p><p>“It was 1983, and BBN needed an additional person who could write TCP/IP code for the BSD [Berkeley Software Distribution] Unix operating system,” he says. “BBN had folks who wrote most of the original code, and they taught me what networking and TCP/IP was. That was something no grad school at the time could teach me.</p><p>“A lot of what I worked on 30 or more years ago is still used today,” Partridge notes proudly. “More generally, a lot of the Internet tech used today is entirely or almost entirely recognizable from what was created back then. That’s a very pleasant feeling.”</p><p>Partridge is an <a href="https://www.internethalloffame.org/inductees/craig-partridge" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Internet Hall of Fame</a> inductee for his work in designing how email is routed using domain names.</p><p>While working at BBN, he went on to earn a master’s and Ph.D. in computer science, both from Harvard. By 2018 Partridge was chief scientist for networking research at BBN, but he decided he didn’t want his tenure there to be the last chapter of his career. Later that year he joined <a href="https://www.colostate.edu" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Colorado State University</a> in Fort Collins, as chair of its department of computer science.</p><p>Partridge says it’s not uncommon for engineers to move from industry to academia later in their careers. They often want to “give back” by becoming professors, deans, or department chairs.</p><p>One of his assignments at CSU was to reexamine the school’s computer science curriculum. Among other improvements, the faculty now teaches courses in machine learning earlier. Virtual reality and virtual spaces courses were created, and the math requirements were revamped.</p><h2>Efforts to increase the number of women in computing</h2><p>Partridge says during the mid-1980s he became aware of some of the challenges that women face in computing careers. “At BBN, at one point, my project leader, my boss, and my boss’s vice president were all women,” he recalls. “A number of women in computing at the time commented to me how rare that was. It opened my eyes.</p><p>“So in 2017 when I was looking to shift from industry to academia, I made it clear in my interviews at various universities that one of my goals was to look for ways to leverage what I had seen and learned, to help bring more women into computing.”</p><p>“Our focus at Colorado State is on the students already on campus. We encourage them to apply to computer science. We are also improving our curriculum by following the <a href="https://anitab.org/braid" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">BRAID</a> (Building, Recruiting, and Inclusion for Diversity) principles.”</p><p>He says this effort has included figuring out how to make the introductory courses speak to a wider variety of students by covering the same material but using different examples and different presentations that relate to how they could use computing to solve problems that interest them. </p><p>“We are trying to get them to understand that just because you can create something new doesn’t mean that society wants it,” he says. “You must create it in a way that is more likely to benefit society.”</p><p>In the four years since introducing these changes, Partridge says about half the students taking the introductory courses are women, and the number of women majoring in computing has nearly doubled, from 12 percent to more than 20 percent.</p><h2>Conducting research in an academic setting</h2><p>Partridge also has continued to conduct research, which he finds very different from how he did research at BBN.</p><p>“You are trying to do research while trying to teach the students,” he says. “You could often do the research faster yourself, but then the student wouldn’t learn. By comparison, in industry I knew I had a team I could give a broad description to and get the right thing the first time. With students, by the time they get good at it, they are graduating.”</p><p> In 2011, in response to a decade-old request from <em>IEEE Spectrum</em> columnist and IEEE Fellow <a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/bob-lucky-obituary" target="_self">Robert Lucky </a>for a list of open research questions in networking, Partridge published “Forty Data Communications Research Questions” in <a href="https://www.acm.org/" target="_blank">ACM</a>’s <em><a href="https://www.sigcomm.org/publications/computer-communication-review" target="_blank">Computer Communication Review</a></em>.</p><p>Many of these questions remain as concerns. For example, one of his graduate students studied packet errors and discovered that checksums, which are used to detect corruption in the header of IPv4 packets, are bad at detecting certain kinds of errors that are likely to occur over asynchronous transfer mode. </p><p>“We are using that kind of experience again today to find the next generation of packet errors in data centers,” Partridge says.</p><p>He would like today’s engineers to pay more attention to edge computing, smart home infrastructure, vehicle safety systems, and walled-garden social networks, such as Instagram and Twitter. He says walled gardens are “social networks where people don't want to connect to people who don't want to connect with those who think differently.”</p><p>One challenge in preparing students for the world they will be working in, he says, “is getting them to understand that just because you can create something new doesn’t mean that society wants it.”</p><p><em>This article appears in the November 2022 print issue as “Craig Partridge.”</em></p><p><em>This article was updated from a previous version.</em></p>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2022 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spectrum.ieee.org/craig-partridge-profile</guid><category>Careers</category><category>Computer science</category><category>Type:departments</category><category>Vpn</category><dc:creator>Daniel P. Dern</dc:creator><media:content medium="image" type="image/png" url="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/a-smiling-bearded-man-in-a-blue-turtleneck-stands-in-front-of-a-building.png?id=31965104&amp;width=980"></media:content></item><item><title>A Serial Entrepreneur Shares Lessons Learned on His Road to Success</title><link>https://spectrum.ieee.org/serial-entrepreneur-on-lessons-learned</link><description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/portrait-of-a-man-in-a-black-blazer-and-a-blue-button-up-shirt-against-a-white-background.jpg?id=31890708&width=1245&height=700&coordinates=0%2C0%2C0%2C469"/><br/><br/><p>When <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/rarjunpillai/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Arjun Pillai</a> was a youngster, the words <em>entrepreneur</em> and <em>startup</em> weren’t part of his vocabulary. It wasn’t until he became an IEEE student member in 2006 that Pillai learned those terms. He served on several IEEE committees and had leadership positions in IEEE groups—which helped him discover his managerial instincts. He learned from other IEEE members what running a tech company entails. And he belatedly realized that his father, who ran a small rubber-band manufacturing company next to the family’s home in India, was an entrepreneur.</p><p>After learning more about what running a tech company entails from other IEEE members, Pillai decided he also wanted to become an entrepreneur, to create “something bigger than me.”</p><hr/><p>He helped launch two companies that develop software-as-a-service platforms—both of which he and his cofounders subsequently sold. </p><p>His most recent venture, <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/company/insent-ai/?lipi=urn%3Ali%3Apage%3Ad_flagship3_search_srp_all%3BuxxNjRF1T4m6IszPiMJTgg%3D%3D" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Insent</a>, was a business-to-business chat platform based in Denver; it was acquired last year by software and data company <a href="https://www.google.com/aclk?sa=l&ai=DChcSEwjgveSry5n6AhXG9sgKHYEiATgYABABGgJxdQ&sig=AOD64_3S3mJk_XJ_XoQDHEn7KDsH5kTHAw&q&adurl&ved=2ahUKEwjE6tyry5n6AhWLM1kFHc7LApgQ0Qx6BAgEEAE" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">ZoomInfo</a> of Vancouver, Wash. Pillai is now senior vice president of ZoomInfo’s products and growth department.</p><p>He credits IEEE with giving him leadership training and opportunities to hone his public-speaking skills. As an active volunteer with the <a href="https://ieeekerala.org/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">IEEE Kerala (India) Section</a>, he spoke at numerous conferences and meetings. He also served on the <a href="https://www.ieeer10.org/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">IEEE Region 10</a> <a href="https://newsletter.ieeer10.org/home_oct2021/r10-humanitarian-technology-activities-committee/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">humanitarian technology activities committee</a> and was vice chair of <a href="https://yp.ieee.org/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">IEEE Young Professionals</a>.</p><p>Thos activities helped him improve his English language skills, he says, as well as his interpersonal skills.</p><p>“IEEE helped me gain the confidence I needed to found my first startup, in 2012,” the senior member says.</p><h2>From systems engineer to CEO</h2><p>After graduating in 2010 with a bachelor’s degree in electronics and communication engineering from the <a href="https://cusat.ac.in/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Cochin University of Science and Technology</a> in India, Pillai joined IT company <a href="https://www.infosys.com/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Infosys</a>, in Bangalore, as a systems engineer. He left in 2012 and founded <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/company/profoundis/about/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Profoundis</a> with three former classmates: <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/jofin/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Jofin Joseph</a>, <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/nithinsamoommen/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Nithin Sam Oommen</a>, and <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/atmb4u/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Anoop Thomas Mathew</a>. The company, based in Cochin, aimed to help businesses and other organizations connect with customers.</p><p>“I was 23 years old. I was young and stupid and had no idea what I was getting into,” Pillai says, laughing. He served as chief executive, while Joseph was chief operating officer, Oommen was chief of data research, and Mathew was chief technology officer.</p><p>During the company’s first two years, it developed four products—a management system for online testimonials, a financial analytics platform for small and midsize businesses, an assignment system for college students, and a social media analytics tool—all of which failed to get any traction within their intended markets, Pillai says.</p><p class="pull-quote">“If the reason why you started a company is strong, it will get you through the hurdles you will face.”</p><p>“But we had to just keep going,” he says. “The failure didn’t really register as such. It was just another day at work.”</p><p>In 2015 Profoundis launched its fifth product, Vibe: sales software that helps businesses identify prospective customers. It proved to be a winner. Vibe collects data about companies from the Internet, organizes it into a searchable list, and makes it available to marketers and salespeople. More than 200 companies in dozens of countries have used it. The success of the product enabled the company to grow from seven employees to 72. <a href="https://www.fullcontact.com/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">FullContact</a>, a software company in Denver, acquired Profoundis nine months later.</p><p>“It was the first product acquisition in the history of my state of Kerala,” Pillai says.</p><p>After Profoundis was sold, Pillai joined FullContact as the head of data strategy, working in Denver. But he says he didn’t really enjoy working for another company.</p><p>“Once you’re an entrepreneur, you kind of have that bug all the time,” he says. He also struggled with the fact that it wasn’t his company anymore, he says. </p><p>“I didn’t do a good enough job transitioning from CEO to employee,” he says. “I always tell other entrepreneurs about my experience so they don’t make the same mistake. This was the most important thing I learned after selling my first company.”</p><p>Pillai left FullContact after two years and worked as a consultant until 2018, when he founded Insent with IEEE Member <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/prasanna081460" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Prasanna Venkatesan</a>. The two cofounders had met through their volunteer activities with IEEE a decade earlier.</p><p>The startup’s B2B platform used a combination of human and chatbot conversations to personalize a customer’s purchasing experience with a retailer. After the company was acquired, the platform was renamed ZoomInfo Chat.</p><p>ZoomInfo hired all of the startup’s employees.</p><p>In his new position, Pillai led the release of ZoomInfo Chat. He is currently managing the company’s data portfolio.</p><p>“ZoomInfo has the best business data assets in the world,” he says. “It’s the core of the company, so I have a big responsibility.”</p><p>Pillai also invests in startups including <a href="https://www.inflection.io/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Inflection</a>, <a href="https://www.savantlabs.io/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Savant Labs</a>, and <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/company/toplynehq" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Toplyne</a>. Inflection and Savant Labs are data analytics companies, while Toplyne develops software.</p><p>“Investing in others gives me the ability to learn about new industries,” he says.</p><h2>Advice for budding entrepreneurs</h2><p>Pillai says that running his own company gave him an unparalleled education on how to be a CEO, and he has learned from both his successes and his failures.</p><p>Pillai, who had no mentor to teach him how to run a company, is now a strong advocate for supporting budding entrepreneurs. For the past five years, he has been an ambassador for <a href="https://startupchile.org/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Start-Up Chile</a>, a government initiative that seeks to attract high-potential entrepreneurs to the country.</p><p>“I want to give back,” he says.</p><p>The biggest challenge for any startup, he says, is bringing together the right team, especially if you plan to launch the company with another person.</p><p>“Being cofounders is like being married,” he says. “If you choose the wrong person, running a successful startup together will be difficult.”</p><p>You need to pick people who share your passion and have a similar mindset, a positive attitude, and strong ethics, he says.</p><p>Other challenges include developing a product or service that makes sense for its intended market and securing enough funding so that you can release the product in a timely way while it still can make an impact.</p><p>He tells budding entrepreneurs to ensure they’re forming a company for the right reasons. Found a startup only if “you feel passionate about a problem that keeps you awake at night and that you believe you’re the only person who can solve,” he says. “If the reason why you started a company is strong, it will get you through the hurdles you will face.”</p><p>Pillai advises startup founders to take occasional breaks from work.</p><p>“In the four and a half years I was CEO of my first company, work was my life,” he says. He was so driven that he showed up once to an investor’s meeting while he was sick, instead of rescheduling it. He says he thinks that’s the reason the investor ended up backing away from the project.</p><p>Pillai says he wishes he had had a mentor to tell him that he needed to take it easy, and that things would work out in the end.</p><p>“Learning all of these lessons on my own was a humbling experience,” he says.</p>]]></description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2022 18:00:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spectrum.ieee.org/serial-entrepreneur-on-lessons-learned</guid><category>Ieee member news</category><category>Startups</category><category>Profile</category><category>Entrepreneurship</category><category>Careers</category><category>Ieee young professionals</category><category>Type:ti</category><dc:creator>Joanna Goodrich</dc:creator><media:content medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/portrait-of-a-man-in-a-black-blazer-and-a-blue-button-up-shirt-against-a-white-background.jpg?id=31890708&amp;width=980"></media:content></item><item><title>How Ted Hoff Invented the First Microprocessor</title><link>https://spectrum.ieee.org/ted-hoff</link><description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/man-in-white-striped-shirt-with-pocket-protector-seated-in-front-of-oscilloscope-and-other-electronics-equipment.jpg?id=31848732&width=1245&height=700&coordinates=0%2C16%2C0%2C640"/><br/><br/><p><strong>The rays of the rising sun</strong> have barely reached the foothills of Silicon Valley, but Marcian E. (Ted) Hoff Jr. is already up to his elbows in electronic parts, digging through stacks of dusty circuit boards. This is the monthly flea market at Foothill College, and he rarely misses it.</p><p>Ted Hoff is part of electronics industry legend. While a research manager at Intel Corp., then based in Mountain View, he realized that silicon technology had advanced to the point that, with careful engineering, a complete central processor could fit on a chip. Teaming up with Stanley Mazor and Federico Faggin, he created the first commercial microprocessor, <a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/chip-hall-of-fame-intel-4004-microprocessor" target="_self">the Intel 4004</a>.</p><h3></h3><br/><p>This article was first published as “Marcian E Hoff.” It appeared in the February 1994 issue of <em>IEEE Spectrum. </em>A <a href="https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/259493" target="_blank">PDF version</a> is available on IEEE Xplore. The photographs appeared in the original print version.</p><h3></h3><br/><p>But for Hoff, the microprocessor was merely one blip among many along the tracing of his long fascination with electronics. His passion for the field led him from New York City’s used electronics stores to elite university laboratories, through the intense early years of the microprocessor revolution and the tumult of the video game industry, and ultimately to his job today: high-tech private eye.</p><p>Fairly early in his childhood Hoff figured out that the best way to feel less like a kid—and a little more powerful—was to understand how things work. He started his explorations with chemistry. By the age of 12 he had moved on to electronics, building things with parts ordered from an Allied Radio Catalog, a shortwave radio kit, and surplus relays and motors salvaged from the garbage at his father’s employer, General Railway Signal Co., in Rochester, NY. Then in high school, working mostly with second­hand components, he built an oscilloscope, an achievement he parlayed into a technician’s job at General Railway Signal.</p><p>Hoff returned to that job during breaks from his undergraduate studies at <a href="https://www.rpi.edu/" target="_blank">Rensselaer Polytechnic Institute</a>, Troy, N.Y. Several summers began with Hoff entering the General Railway laboratory to find the researchers’ two best oscilloscopes broken. He would repair the state-of-the-art Tektronix 545s, then move on to more interesting stuff, like inventing an audio frequency railroad­train tracking circuit and a lightning protection unit that gave him two patents before he was out of his teens.</p><p>The best thing about the job, Hoff recalled, was the access it gave him to components that were beyond the budgets of most engineering students in the l950s—transistors, for instance, and even the just-introduced power transistor. He did an undergraduate thesis on transistors used as switches, and the cash prize he won for it quickly went for a Heathkit scope of his own.</p><h2>Early Neural Networks</h2><p>Hoff liked the engineering courses at Rensselaer, but not the narrow focus of the college itself. He wanted to broaden his perspective, both intellectually and geographically (he had never been more than a few miles west of Niagara Falls), so chose California’s <a href="https://www.stanford.edu/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Stanford University</a> for graduate school. While working toward his Ph.D. there, he did research in adaptive systems (which today are called neural networks) and, with his thesis advisor Bernard Widrow, racked up two more patents.</p><p class="pull-quote">“He had a toy train moving back and forth under computer control, balancing a broom­ stick. I saw him as a kooky inventor, a mad scientist.”<br/>—Stanley Mazor<br/></p><p>His Intel colleague Mazor, now training manager at Synopsys Inc., Mountain View, Calif., recalled meeting Hoff in his Stanford laboratory.</p><p>“He had a toy train moving back and forth under computer control, balancing a broomstick,” Mazor said. “I saw him as a kooky inventor, a mad scientist.”</p><p>After getting his degree, Hoff stayed at Stanford for six more years as a postdoctoral researcher, continuing the work on neural networks. At first, his group made the networks trainable by using a device whose resistance changed with the amount and direction of current applied. It consisted of a pencil lead and a piece of copper wire sitting in a copper sulfate and sulfuric acid solution, and they called it a memistor.</p><p class="pull-quote">“One result of all our work on microprocessors that has always pleased me is that we got computers away from those [computer center] people.”<br/>—Ted Hoff</p><p>The group soon acquired an IBM 1620 computer, and Hoff had his first experience in programming—and in bucking the system. He had to deal with officials at the campus computer center who thought all computers should be in one place, run by specialists who handled the boxes of punched cards delivered by researchers. The idea that a researcher should program computer systems interactively was anathema to them.</p><h3>Ted Hoff: Vital Stats</h3><br><p><strong>Name </strong></p><p><strong></strong>Marcian E. (Ted) Hoff Jr.<br/></p><p><strong>Date of birth </strong></p><p>Oct. 28, 1937</p><p><strong>Family </strong></p><p>Wife, Judy; three daughters, Carolyn, Lisa, and Jill</p><p><strong>Education</strong></p><p>BS, 1958, Rensselaer Polytechnic Institute, Troy, N.Y.; MS, 1959, Ph.D., 1962, Stanford University, California, all in electrical engineering</p><p><strong>First job</strong></p><p>Planting cabbages</p><p><strong>First electronics job</strong></p><p>Technician, General Railway Signal Co., Rochester, N.Y.</p><p><strong>Biggest surprise in career</strong></p><p>Media hysteria over the microprocessor</p><p><strong>Patents</strong></p><p>17</p><p><strong>Books recently read</strong></p><p><em>Introduction to Nuclear Reactor Theory</em> by John R. Lamarsh; A Compiler Generator by William M. McKeeman, James J. Horning, and David B. Wortman</p><p><strong>People most respected</strong></p><p>Intel Corp. founders Robert Noyce and Gordon Moore, Intel chief executive officer Andrew Grove</p><p><strong>Favorite restaurants</strong></p><p>Postrio and Bella Voce in San Francisco, Beausejour in Los Altos, Calif.</p><p><strong>Favorite movies</strong></p><p><em>2001</em>,<em> Dr. Strangelove</em></p><p><strong>Motto</strong></p><p>“If it works, it’s aesthetic”</p><p><strong>Leisure activities</strong></p><p>Playing with electronics; attending operas and concerts; going to the theater, body surfing in Hawaii; walking his Alaskan malamutes</p><p><strong>Car</strong></p><p>Porsche 944</p><p><strong>Management creed</strong></p><p>“The best motivation is self-motivation”</p><p><strong>Organizational memberships</strong></p><p>IEEE, Sigma Xi</p><p><strong>Major awards</strong></p><p>Stuart Balantine Medal of the Franklin Institute, IEEE Cledo Brunetti Award, IEEE Centennial Medal, IEEE Fellow</p><h3></h3><br><p>“One result of all our work on microprocessors that has always pleased me,” Hoff told <em>IEEE Spectrum</em>, “is that we got computers away from those people.”<br/></p><p>By 1968 student hostility to the government over the Vietnam War was growing and life for researchers on campus who, like Hoff, relied on government funding was looking as if it might get uncomfortable. Hoff had already been contemplating the possibilities of industrial jobs when he received a telephone call from Robert Noyce, who told him he was starting a new company, <a href="https://www.intel.com/content/www/us/en/homepage.html" target="_blank">Intel Corp</a>., and had heard Hoff might be interested in a job. He asked Hoff where the semiconductor integrated circuit business would find its next growth area. “Memories,” Hoff replied.</p><p>That was the answer Noyce had in mind (Intel was launched as a memory manufacturer), and that year he hired Hoff as a member of the technical staff, Intel’s 12th employee. Working on memory technology, Hoff soon received a patent for a cell for use in MOS random-access integrated circuit memory. Moving on to become manager of applications research, he had the first customer contact of his career.</p><p class="pull-quote">“Engineering people tend to have a very haughty attitude toward marketing, but I discovered you learn a tremendous amount if you keep your eyes and ears open in the field.” <br/>—Hoff</p><p>“Engineering people tend to have a very haughty attitude toward marketing,” Hoff said, “but I discovered you learn a tremendous amount if you keep your eyes and ears open in the field. Trying to understand what problems people are trying to solve is very helpful. People back in the lab who don’t have that contact are working at a disadvantage.”</p><h2>From 12 Chips to One Microprocessor</h2><p>One group of customers with whom Hoff made contact were from Busicom Corp., Tokyo. Busicom had hired Intel to develop a set of custom chips for a low-cost calculator and had sent three engineers to Santa Clara to work on the chip designs. Hoff was assigned to look after them, getting them pencils and paper, showing them where the lunchroom was—nothing technical.</p><p>But the technical part of Hoff’s mind has no off-switch, and he quickly concluded that the engineers were going in the wrong direction. Twelve chips, each with more than 3000 transistors and 36 leads, were to handle different elements of the calculator logic and controls, and he surmised the packaging alone would cost more than the targeted retail price of the calculator. Hoff was struck by the complexity of this tiny calculator, compared with the simplicity of the PDP-8 minicomputer he was currently using in another project, and he concluded that a simple computer that could handle the functions of a calculator could be designed with about 1900 transistors. Given Intel’s advanced MOS process, all these, he felt, could fit on a single chip.</p><h3></h3><br><div class="rblad-ieee_in_content"></div><h3></h3><br><img alt="Man sitting at patio table with large dog seated next to him. Laptop and coffee mug on table." class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="6d1418ca3ba18981624e1c2d8a5f483b" data-rm-shortcode-name="rebelmouse-image" id="9b51c" loading="lazy" src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/man-sitting-at-patio-table-with-large-dog-seated-next-to-him-laptop-and-coffee-mug-on-table.jpg?id=31784380&width=980"/><h3></h3><br><p>The Busicom engineers had no interest in dumping their design in favor of Hoff’s unproved proposal. But Hoff, with Noyce’s blessing, started working on the project. Soon Mazor, then a research engineer at Intel, joined him, and the two pursued Hoff’s ideas, developing a simple instruction set that could be implemented with about 2000 transistors. They showed that the one set of instructions could handle decimal addition, scan a keyboard, maintain a display, and perform other functions that were allocated to separate chips in the Busicom design.</p><p>In October 1969, Hoff, Mazor, and the three Japanese engineers met with Busicom management, visiting from Japan, and described their divergent approaches. Busicom’s managers chose Hoff’s approach, partly, Hoff said, because they understood that the chip could have varied applications beyond that of a calculator. The project was given the internal moniker “4004.”</p><p>Federico Faggin, now president and chief executive officer of Synaptics Inc., San Jose, Calif., was assigned to design the chip, and in nine months came up with working prototypes of a 4-bit, 2300-transistor “microprogrammable computer on a chip.” Busicom received its first shipment of the devices in February 1971.</p><p>Faggin recalled that when he began implementing the microprocessor, Hoff seemed to have lost interest in the project, and rarely interacted with him. Hoff was already working on his next project, the preliminary design of an 8-bit microprogrammable computer for Computer Terminals Corp., San Antonio, Texas, which, architected by Computer Terminals, was named the 8008. Hoff always “had to do very cutting-edge work,” Faggin told <em>Spectrum</em>. “I could see a tension in him to always be at the forefront of what was happening.”</p><p>In those early Intel days, Mazor recalled that Hoff had a number of ideas for projects, many of which, though not commercially successful, proved prescient: a RAM chip that would act like a digital camera and capture an image in memory, a video game with moving spaceships, a device for programming erasable programmable ROMs, and computer-aided design tools intended for logic simulation.</p><p class="pull-quote">The Intel marketing department they estimated that sales [of microprocessors] might total only 2000 chips a year.</p><p>Meanwhile, the microprocessor revolution was gearing up, albeit slowly. Hoff joined Faggin as a microprocessor evangelist, trying to convince people that general-purpose one chip computers made sense. Hoff said his toughest sell was to the Intel marketing department.</p><p>“They were rather hostile to the idea,” he recalled, for several reasons. First, they felt that all the chips Intel could make would go for several years to one company, so there was little point in marketing them to others. Second, they told Hoff, ‘‘We have diode salesman out there struggling like crazy to sell memories, and you want them to sell computers? You’re crazy.” And finally, they estimated that sales might total only 2000 chips a year.</p><p>But word went out. In May 1971 an article in <em>Datamation</em> magazine mentioned the product, and the following November Intel produced its first ad for the 4004 CPU and placed it in <em>Electronic News</em>. By 1972 stories about the miracle of what began being called the microprocessor started appearing regularly in the press, and Intel’s competitors followed its lead by launching microprocessor products of their own.</p><p class="pull-quote">Hoff never even considered patenting the microprocessor. To him the invention seemed to be obvious.</p><p>One step Hoff did not take at that time was apply for a patent, even though he had already successfully patented several inventions. (Later, with Mazor and Faggin he filed for and was granted a patent for a “memory system for a multi-chip digital computer.”)</p><p>Looking back, Hoff recalled that he never even considered patenting the microprocessor in those days. To him the invention seemed to be obvious, and obviousness was considered grounds for rejecting a patent application (though, Hoff said bitterly, the patent office currently seems to ignore that rule). It was obvious to Hoff that if in one year a computer could be built with 1000 circuits on100 chips, and if in the following year those 1000 circuits could be put onto10 chips, eventually those 1000 circuits could be con­ structed on one chip.</p><p>Instead of patenting, Hoff in March 1970 published an article in the proceedings of the 1970 IEEE International Convention that stated: “An entirely new approach to design of very small computers is made possible by the vast circuit complexity possible with MOS technology. With from 1000 to 6000 MOS devices per chip, an entire central processor may be fabricated on a single chip.”</p><p>But in December 1970, an independent inventor outside the cliquish semiconductor industry, Gilbert Hyatt, filed for a patent on a processor and mentioned that it was to be made on a single chip. In 1990, after numerous appeals and extensions, Hyatt was granted that patent and began collecting royalties from many microprocessor manufacturers. Currently, though history traces today’s microprocessor back to Hoff, Mazor, and Faggin, the legal rights to the invention belong to Hyatt.</p><h2>The Invention of the Codec</h2><p>While the microprocessor has proved to be his most celebrated achievement, Hoff does not view it as his biggest technical breakthrough. That designation he reserves for the single-chip analog-to-digital/ digital-to-analog coder/decoder (codec).</p><p>“Now that work was an exciting technical challenge,” Hoff recollected with some glee, “because there were so many who said it couldn’t be done.”</p><p>The project was kicked off by Noyce, who spotted the telephone industry as ripe for new technology, and urged Hoff to find an important product for that market. Studying telephone communications, Hoff and several other researchers saw that digitized voice transmission, then being used between central offices, depended on the use of complex expensive codecs that tied into electromechanical switches.</p><p>”We thought,” Hoff told <em>Spectrum</em>, “we could integrate this, the analog-to-digital conversion, on a chip, and then use these circuits as the basis for switching.”</p><p>Besides reducing the cost of the systems to the telephone company, such chips would enable companies to build small branch exchanges that handled switching electronically.</p><p>Hoff and his group developed a multiplexed approach to conversion in which a single converter is shared by the transmit and receive channels. They also established a number of other techniques for conversion and decoding that Hoff saw as not being obvious and for which he received patents.</p><p>With that project’s completion in 1980, after six years of effort, and its transfer to Intel’s manufacturing facility in Chandler, Ariz., Hoff became an Intel Fellow, free to pursue whatever technology interested him. What interested him was returning to his work on adaptive structures, combining the concepts he had wrestled with at Stanford with the power of the microprocessor in the service of speech recognition. After a year he built a recognition system that Intel marketed for several years.</p><p>A prime customer for the system was the automotive industry. Its inspectors used the systems to help them check out a car as it finally left the assembly line. When an inspector noted out loud various problems that needed fixing, the system would prompt him for further information, and log his responses in a computer.</p><h3></h3><br><div class="rblad-ieee_in_content"></div><h3></h3><br/><h2>From Intel to Atari</h2><p>
	Though his position as an Intel Fellow gave Hoff a fair amount of freedom, he found himself getting bored. Intel’s success in microprocessors by 1983 had turned it into a chip supplier, and other companies were designing the chips into systems.
</p><p>
	“I had always been more interested in systems than in chips,” Hoff said, “and I had been at Intel for 14 years, at a time when the average stay at a company in Silicon Valley was three years. I was overdue for a move.”
</p><p>
	Again, Hoff had not gone beyond thinking about leaving Intel when a new job came to him. <a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/pong" target="_self">Atari Inc</a>., Sunnyvale, Calif., then a booming video game company owned by Warner Communications Inc. and a major user of microprocessors, was looking for a vice president of corporate technology. In February 1983, after discussing the scope of the ideas that Atari researchers were pursuing, Hoff latched onto the opportunity.
</p><p>
	Intel from the start had a structured, highly controlled culture. At Atari, chaos reigned.
</p><p>
	Intel from the start had a structured, highly controlled culture. At Atari, chaos reigned. Under Hoff were research laboratories in Sunnyvale, Los Angeles, and Grass Valley, Calif.; Cambridge, Mass.; and New York City. Researchers were working on picture telephones, electronic aids for joggers, computer controls that gave tactile feedback, graphical environments akin to today’s virtual reality, digital sound synthesis, advanced personal computers, and software distribution via FM sidebands.
</p><p>
	But Hoff had barely had time to learn about all the research projects under way before the video game business took a well-publicized plunge. Without solid internal controls, Atari was unable to determine how well its games were selling at the retail point, and distributors were returning hundreds of thousands of cartridges and game machines. Hoff began receiving orders for staff cuts monthly.
</p><p>
	“It would have been one thing if I had known I had to cut back to, say, one-quarter the size of my group,” he told <em>Spectrum</em>. “But when every month you find you have to cut another chunk, morale really drops.”
</p><p>
	In July 1984, while Hoff was at his 30th high school reunion, Warner sold Atari to Jack Tramiel. Hoff then had to choose between convincing Tramiel that he could play a role in a narrowly focused company uninterested in funding futuristic research, and allowing Warner to buy out his contract. He chose the latter.
</p><p>
	Looking back, most of the people who were at Atari in those days now view them darkly. But Hoff recalls his year there as an enjoyable and ultimately useful experience. “Maybe I look at it more positively than I should,” he said, “but it turned out to be a good transition for me, and the life I have now is a very nice one.”
</p><p class="pull-quote">
	“Whenever you are working on one problem, there is always another problem over here that seems more interesting.”<br/>
	—Hoff
</p><p>
	He now spends half his time as a consultant and half pursuing technical projects of his own devising—a read­out device for machine tools, various types of frame grabbers, pattern recognition, and techniques for analog-to-digital conversion. This variegated schedule is perfect for him. He has always felt himself to be a generalist, and has had trouble focusing on just one technology.
</p><p>
	“It’s easy for me to get distracted,” he said. “Whenever you are working on one problem, there is always another problem over here that seems more interesting. But now it is more likely that my own projects get delayed, rather than things critical to other people and their employment.”
</p><p>
	Faggin for one is not surprised that such independent work appeals to Hoff. “He never was the gregarious type,” Faggin said. “He liked introverted work, the thinking, the figuring out of new things. That is what he is good at. I always was impressed how he was able to visualize an architecture for a new IC, practically on the spot.”
</p><p class="pull-quote">
	“He comes up with idea after idea, situation after situation. I think if he wanted to, Ted could sit down and crank out a patent a month.”<br/>
	—Gary Summers
</p><p>
	Said Gary Summers, president and chief executive officer of Teklicon Inc., Mountain View, the consulting firm that employs Hoff today: “He comes up with idea after idea, situation after situation. I think if he wanted to, Ted could sit down and crank out a patent a month.”
</p><p>
	“There is no doubt in my mind that he is a genius,” Mazor stated. Summers readily concurred.
</p><p>
	Hoff’s first project after Atari was a voice­controlled music synthesizer, which gave off the sound of a selected instrument when someone sang into it. Hoff’s biggest contribution to the project was a system that ensured that the emerging notes would be in tune, or at least harmonically complement the tune, even when the singer strayed off key. He scored another patent for this system, and the gadget was sold briefly through the Sharper Image catalog, but never became a big success.
</p><p>
	Hoff still contributes occasionally to product designs. At Teklicon, however, where he is vice president and chief technical officer, most of his consulting is done for lawyers. Hoff has a unique combination of long experience with electronic design and long-standing pack rat habits. His home workshop contains about eight personal computers of different makes and vintages, five oscilloscopes, including a vintage Tektronix 545 scope, 15000 ICs inventoried and filed, and shelves loaded with IC data books dating right back to the 1960s.
</p><p class="pull-quote">
	“If my washing machine breaks down, I call the repairman. Most clever engineers would buy the replacement gear and install it. Ted is capable of analyzing the reason the gear failed in the first place, redesigning a better gear from basic principles, carving it out of wood, casting it at his home, and dynamically balancing it on his lathe before installing it.”<br/>
	—Mazor
</p><p>
	When a lawyer shows him a patent disclosure, even one decades old, he can determine whether or not it could then have been “reduced to practice” and whether it provided sufficient information to allow “one of ordinary skill in the art” to practice the invention. Then he can build a model proving his conclusion, using vintage components from his collection, and demonstrate the model in court as an expert witness. This model-building can get very basic. On <em>Spectrum</em>’s visit, Rochelle salt crystals that Hoff attempted to grow for a recent court demonstration littered his workshop floor, next to metal-working equipment that he uses to build cases for his models.
</p><p>
	Hoff sees this ability to get down to basics as one of his strengths. “I relate things to fundamental principles,” he said. “People who don’t question the assumptions made going into a problem often end up solving the wrong problem.”
</p><p>
	Mazor said, “If my washing machine breaks down, I call the repairman. Most clever engineers would buy the replacement gear and install it. Ted is capable of analyzing the reason the gear failed in the first place, redesigning a better gear from basic principles, carving it out of wood, casting it at his home, and dynamically balancing it on his lathe before installing it.”
</p><p>
	Doing legal detective work appeals to Hoff for another reason: it gives him an excuse to hunt for interesting “antique” components at flea markets and electronics stores.
</p><p>
	Hoff cannot discuss the specifics of patent cases he has been involved with. Several recently were in the video game area; others have involved various IC companies. In a number of cases, Hoff was confident that his side was right, and his side still lost, so he felt little surprise when the microprocessor patent was granted to Hyatt. (After the award was made, though, he did sit down with Hyatt’s patent application and attempted to design a working microprocessor based on Hyatt’s disclosures. He found several incongruities—like a clock rate only suited to bipolar technology with logic that could only be rendered in MOS technology, and logic that required far too many transistors to put on a chip, proving in his mind that the award was incorrect.)
</p><p>
	Seeing someone else get credit for the microprocessor, particularly in recent media reports, “is irritating,” Hoff told <em>Spectrum</em>, “but I’m not going to let it bother me, because I know what I did, I know what all the other people on our project did, and I know what kind of company Intel is. And I know that I was where the action was.”<span class="ieee-end-mark"></span>
</p><p>
<em>Editor’s note: Hoff retired from Teklicon in 2007. He currently serves as a judge for the </em><a href="https://www.invent.org/collegiate-inventors/judging" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"><em>Collegiate Inventors Competition</em></a><em>, held annually by </em><a href="https://www.invent.org/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"><em>the National Inventors Hall of Fame</em></a><em>. These days, his main technical interests surround energy, water, and climate change.</em>
</p></br></br></br></br></br></br>]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 08 Oct 2022 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spectrum.ieee.org/ted-hoff</guid><category>Intel 4004</category><category>Ted hoff</category><category>Microprocessor</category><dc:creator>Tekla S. Perry</dc:creator><media:content medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/man-in-white-striped-shirt-with-pocket-protector-seated-in-front-of-oscilloscope-and-other-electronics-equipment.jpg?id=31848732&amp;width=980"></media:content></item><item><title>The Impact of Standard Essential Patents (SEPs)</title><link>https://clarivate.com/lp/dont-let-standards-slip-how-to-prioritize-your-efforts-when-everything-is-essential/?campaignname=Standards_Essential_Patents_LeadGen_IPG_Global_2022&amp;campaignid=7014N000001uvkS&amp;utm_campaign=Standards_Essential_Patents_LeadGen_IPG_Global_2022&amp;utm_source=third_party_email_IEEE&amp;utm_medium=paid</link><description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/image.png?id=27150766&width=980"/><br/><br/><p>As standard essential patents (SEPs) continue to accelerate and impact new industries beyond just telecommunications, it’s become increasingly challenging for stakeholders to wade through data sets, navigate data weaknesses and assess what’s truly essential in order to make the best commercial and licensing decisions.<u></u><u></u></p><p><a href="https://clarivate.com/lp/dont-let-standards-slip-how-to-prioritize-your-efforts-when-everything-is-essential/?campaignname=Standards_Essential_Patents_LeadGen_IPG_Global_2022&campaignid=7014N000001uvkS&utm_campaign=Standards_Essential_Patents_LeadGen_IPG_Global_2022&utm_source=third_party_email_IEEE&utm_medium=paid" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow" target="_blank">Download this free whitepaper now!</a></p><p>To help you navigate the complexities of SEPs, we’ve released a new standards essential patents paper covering:<u></u><u></u></p><ul><li>Challenges stemming from the significant growth in SEPs<u></u><u></u></li><li>Recent policy updates and long term needs to address systemic issues<u></u><u></u></li><li>What trends to expect in the SEP space going forward<u></u><u></u></li><li>Takeaways for SEP owners and implementers to tackle issues efficiently and effectively in the short term</li></ul>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Oct 2022 18:50:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://clarivate.com/lp/dont-let-standards-slip-how-to-prioritize-your-efforts-when-everything-is-essential/?campaignname=Standards_Essential_Patents_LeadGen_IPG_Global_2022&amp;campaignid=7014N000001uvkS&amp;utm_campaign=Standards_Essential_Patents_LeadGen_IPG_Global_2022&amp;utm_source=third_party_email_IEEE&amp;utm_medium=paid</guid><category>Clarivate</category><category>Innovation</category><category>Patents</category><category>Type:whitepaper</category><dc:creator>Clarivate</dc:creator><media:content medium="image" type="image/png" url="https://assets.rbl.ms/27150766/origin.png"></media:content></item><item><title>This Idea Wasn’t All Wet: The Sensing Water-Saving Showerhead Debuts</title><link>https://spectrum.ieee.org/water-saving-shower-head</link><description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/a-mounted-and-running-showerhead-that-says-oasense-and-has-a-blue-light-on-it.jpg?id=31831006&width=1245&height=700&coordinates=0%2C411%2C0%2C411"/><br/><br/><p>For Evan Schneider, the family dinner table is a good place for invention. “I’m always, ‘Wouldn’t it be cool if this or that,’” he says, “and people would humor me.”</p><p>In 2012, with California in the midst of a severe drought, Schneider, then a mechanical engineering graduate student at <a href="https://www.stanford.edu/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Stanford University</a>, once again tossed out a “cool idea.” He imagined a showerhead that would sense when the person showering moved out from under the stream of water. The showerhead would then automatically turn the water off, turning it back on again when the person moved back into range. With such a device, he thought, people could enjoy a long shower without wasting water.</p><p>“But turning the water on and off manually didn’t make sense in our house,” Schneider said. “We had separate knobs for hot and cold, and another one to switch from tub to shower, so you’d have to adjust the water every time you turned it back on. You’d waste more water than you saved. Plus a shower is a blissful time of relaxation. You don’t want to stop the party halfway.”</p><p>Ten years and many starts and stops later, that sensing showerhead is now shipping to customers from <a href="https://www.oasense.com/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Oasense</a>, a company incorporated in 2019.</p><p>“The general idea is really simple,” Schneider says. “A lot of people have said they also thought of this idea. And I’m sure that’s true, but there were a lot of devils in the details.” Oasense’s team has been granted several patents related to their device, the first filed by Schneider in 2016. </p><p>Schneider’s development path started soon after that dinner-table conversation. First, he confirmed that showers were a big part of water usage for a typical household, and that no such device was already on the market. He collected off-the-shelf components, including an infrared sensor scavenged from a high-end automatic faucet, designed a prototype in a CAD system, printed out the plastic parts using a 3D printer, and assembled it. With 4 AA batteries as a power source, the gadget would operate for about a year, thanks to his choice of a latching solenoid valve, one that uses power to switch from open to closed but doesn’t draw any power to hold in one state or another.</p><p>The prototype worked well enough that his parents were willing to throw out their standard showerhead. He assembled dozens of them and distributed them to friends and family—anyone willing to try.</p><p class="shortcode-media shortcode-media-rebelmouse-image">
<img alt="Man seated on box in garage with showerhead casings and parts laid out on the floor in front of him, he holds one showerhead." class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="76ba3df7a3727af13c157ff01851326e" data-rm-shortcode-name="rebelmouse-image" id="429da" loading="lazy" src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/man-seated-on-box-in-garage-with-showerhead-casings-and-parts-laid-out-on-the-floor-in-front-of-him-he-holds-one-showerhead.jpg?id=31831165&width=980"/>
<small class="image-media media-caption" placeholder="Add Photo Caption...">Oasense cofounder Ted Li assembles an early version of the company’s sensing showerhead.</small><small class="image-media media-photo-credit" placeholder="Add Photo Credit...">Oasense</small></p><p>In 2016, Schneider decided to run a <a href="https://www.kickstarter.com/" target="_blank">Kickstarter</a> campaign to see if the gadget could attract broad interest. The Kickstarter ultimately failed; it drew a decent number of potential buyers, but, says Schneider, “I had set the bar high, because I was busy doing other things, and if I switched to this, I wanted to make sure it would have a good chance of working out. It didn’t meet that bar; it raised about US $34,000 out of its $75,000 goal.”</p><p>So Schneider put his showerhead idea on hold. Instead, he focused on expanding a burgeoning small business that he was also passionate about—3D printing prototypes and various parts for hardware companies.</p><p>But the showerhead wasn’t done with him. In 2017 someone who Schneider had never met edited <a href="https://www.facebook.com/VT/videos/646639645508722/" target="_blank">the video from the Kickstarter pitch</a> and shared it on Facebook. This time, the video got far more attention—millions of views in just weeks.</p><p>Unfortunately, the timing couldn’t have been worse. Schneider was dealing with a flare-up of a chronic illness and his 3D printing business was at a critical growth period. “I had wanted this for years, but it was the worst time for it to happen,” he says.</p><p>“I still believed in the product,” Schneider continued, “but I knew it needed improvements and more attention than I was able to give it. I tried for a couple of weeks to reply to all these people contacting me, thousands of them, but it was too much. I was planning to shelve it.”</p><p>That’s when Chih-Wei Tang, a friend from Stanford’s mechatronics program who had been an early backer of the project on Kickstarter, reached out to Schneider. Tang, who was working as a technical product manager at the <a href="https://corporate.ford.com/operations/locations/silicon-valley.html" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Ford Greenfield Labs</a>, convinced Schneider that he could form a team capable of commercializing the product. Tang pulled in his friend Ted Li, who had just left <a href="https://www.apple.com/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Apple</a> after managing display technology for the iPhone and Apple Watch.</p><p>Tang and Li devoted themselves to the project full-time, Schneider helped part-time as needed. The three started by trying to better adapt an off-the-shelf sensor, but ended up designing a sensor suite with custom hardware and algorithms.</p><p>They incorporated as Oasense in December 2019 as cofounders. In late 2020, the company went out for funding, and brought in about $1 million from angel investors, friends, and family. In addition to the founders, Oasense now has four full-time and three part-time employees.</p><p class="shortcode-media shortcode-media-rebelmouse-image">
<img alt="3 smiling men in suit jackets" class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="70a9c15e58ef12fe97c7cd6256a3fb15" data-rm-shortcode-name="rebelmouse-image" id="16097" loading="lazy" src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/3-smiling-men-in-suit-jackets.jpg?id=31831170&width=980"/>
<small class="image-media media-caption" placeholder="Add Photo Caption...">Oasense cofounders [from left] Ted Li, Evan Schneider, and Chih-Wei Tang.</small><small class="image-media media-photo-credit" placeholder="Add Photo Credit...">Oasense</small></p><p>The current version of the device includes several sensors (across a wide range of light wavelengths) and software that allows the sensors to self-calibrate, since every shower environment is different in terms of light, reflectivity, size, and design. Calibration happens during warm-up, when the person showering is unlikely to be standing in the stream. A temperature sensor determines when this warm-up period is over and cuts the flow if the user hasn’t moved under the showerhead. The redesign also replaced the AA batteries with a turbine that generates power from the water flow and sends it to a small rechargeable battery sealed inside the device.</p><p>Says Tang, “It does seem like someone would have built this before, but it turns out to be really complicated. For example, one problem that affects the noise in the sensor signals is fog. In a hot shower, after 3 minutes, our original sensor was blinded by fog. When we designed our new sensors, we had to make sure that didn’t happen.</p><p>“And these sensors are power hungry and need to be on for the duration of the shower, whether water is flowing or not, so generator and sensor efficiency had to be maximized.”</p><p>Oasense officially launched its product, <a href="https://shop.oasense.com/products/reva-showerhead" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Reva</a>, in August. The company is working to figure out the best way to sell the gadget; it is now just doing <a href="https://shop.oasense.com/products/reva-showerhead" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">direct sales at $350</a> per self-installable unit.</p><p>“Two trends are coming together,” Tang says. “Sustainability is what everyone has to be about these days, and technology is invading every corner of our homes. Using technology, we designed sustainability into a product that doesn’t compromise quality or the experience, it just addresses the problem.”</p>]]></description><pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2022 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spectrum.ieee.org/water-saving-shower-head</guid><category>Gadgets</category><category>Conservation</category><category>Water</category><category>Consumer electronics</category><category>Startups</category><dc:creator>Tekla S. Perry</dc:creator><media:content medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/a-mounted-and-running-showerhead-that-says-oasense-and-has-a-blue-light-on-it.jpg?id=31831006&amp;width=980"></media:content></item><item><title>Stephen Welby: A Man on a Mission</title><link>https://spectrum.ieee.org/stephen-welby-profile</link><description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/a-smiling-man-in-a-suit-and-glasses.jpg?id=31832314&width=1245&height=700&coordinates=0%2C0%2C0%2C676"/><br/><br/><p>
	In his five years as IEEE’s executive director and chief operating officer, Stephen Welby has led the organization through a global pandemic, a changing publishing landscape, and soaring geopolitical tensions. Welby, an IEEE Fellow, is leaving at the end of the year to spend more time with his family while he explores his career options. The IEEE Board of Directors has named <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/sophiamuirhead/" target="_blank">Sophie Muirhead</a>, IEEE’s current general counsel and chief compliance officer, as his replacement.</p><p>
	Welby directs the daily operations of IEEE and its approximately 1,000 employees. While the IEEE Board of Directors sets the organization’s policies and strategic direction, the executive director’s job is to implement them and provide input about issues affecting the organization’s future.
</p><hr/><p>
	“I feel comfortable with stepping out of my role at this time because I feel that, in almost every way, thanks to the hard work of volunteers and staff, IEEE is stronger than when I arrived,” Welby says.
</p><p>
	IEEE’s mission of advancing technology for the benefit of humanity drew him to the organization, he says, after he served a term in the Obama administration as U.S. assistant secretary of defense for research and engineering.
</p><h3>About Stephen Welby</h3><br/><p>
<strong>Employer:</strong> IEEE
</p><p>
<strong>Title:</strong> Executive Director and Chief Operating Officer
</p><p>
<strong>Member grade:</strong> Fellow
</p><p>
<strong>Alma mater:</strong> The Cooper Union, New York, N.Y.
</p><p>
	The IEEE position “offered an opportunity to influence and engage a global community,” Welby says. “The work that IEEE is doing is important, and the ideas embedded in our mission statement are big drivers for ensuring that we leave a better world to future generations.
</p><p>
	“IEEE has an ambitious agenda: supporting our members around the world; deepening our technical engagement in emerging areas; building communities and disseminating technical information; meeting a growing demand for technical education; exploring new frontiers of technical standards; and engaging with the broader public about the critical role that technical professionals play in building a better world.”
</p><h2>A commitment to diversity and the open access publishing model</h2><p>
	Welby lists his most important accomplishments as helping to strengthen IEEE’s commitment to diversity, inclusion, and professional ethics; updating the organization’s publication model to increase its embrace of open access; and shoring up its financial footing.
</p><p>
	“IEEE is very considerate in trying to make sure that it is a voice for all of our members,” he says. “We’ve been taking steps to be as inclusive as possible and to find ways that people can participate and contribute—which ties back to our mission. We’ve got to find ways to be open, welcoming, and maybe more than encouraging to ensure that everybody can contribute to the best of their abilities.”
</p><p>
	During his tenure, the IEEE Board revised its 
	<a href="https://www.ieee.org/about/diversity-index.html" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">policy on diversity</a> to ensure that members have a safe, inclusive place for collegial discourse. Changes also were made to the <a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/board-of-directors-approves-revisions-to-the-ieee-code-of-ethics" target="_self">IEEE Code of Ethics </a> to focus members on key elements of the code, a commitment not to engage in harassment, and to protect the privacy of others.
</p><p class="pull-quote">
	“The work that IEEE is doing is important, and the ideas embedded in our mission statement are big drivers for ensuring that we leave a better world to future generations.”
</p><p>
	When Welby began working for IEEE, he says, the open access publishing movement was perceived as a threat, but today he sees it as an opportunity. The movement calls for making research publications available without fees for the reader.
</p><p>
	“This requires a shift to new business models to cover expenses that were previously funded with subscription fees,” he says. “IEEE has been responsive to this change in a careful, deliberate, and responsible way. We are offering a wide variety of opportunities and tools for people to engage with. The evolution of our publication activity has been about responding to community demands for new and diverse offerings.”
</p><p>
<span></span>Twenty open access journals have been launched in the past five years, for a total of 29 in the portfolio. Today they make up more than 20 percent of IEEE’s journal publishing output and that percentage is growing, Welby says.
</p><p>
	He says he is proud that IEEE is much stronger financially than when he started. In 2018, its total net assets were US $391 million, and by the end of last year it had more than $851 million, he says. He adds that he anticipates strong results for this year as well.
</p><p>
	“To support our mission in perpetuity, IEEE needs strong financial reserves—ideally reserves that are large enough to serve as reliable and stabilizing sources of revenue,” he says. “Doubling our reserves has been a significant accomplishment and represents an investment in our future and our long-term commitment to our mission.”
</p><p class="shortcode-media shortcode-media-rebelmouse-image">
<img alt="A smiling man stands in front of racks of servers" class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="e56498f718b700ffe74a5fab3754237c" data-rm-shortcode-name="rebelmouse-image" id="368f2" loading="lazy" src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/a-smiling-man-stands-in-front-of-racks-of-servers.jpg?id=31832322&width=980"/>
<small class="image-media media-caption" placeholder="Add Photo Caption...">Welby visits IEEE’s server room in its offices in Piscataway, N.J.</small><small class="image-media media-photo-credit" placeholder="Add Photo Credit...">Brad Trent</small>
</p><p>
	Other achievements, he says, include the 
	<a href="http://standards.ieee.org/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">IEEE Standards Association’s</a> facilitation of discussions about the responsible use of <a href="https://standards.ieee.org/initiatives/artificial-intelligence-systems/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">artificial intelligence</a>.
</p><p>
	Another is the work that IEEE-USA has done in helping to shape public policy concerning technology. He points to major U.S. legislation passed this year: the 
	<a href="https://www.congress.gov/bill/117th-congress/house-bill/5376/text" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Inflation Reduction Act</a>, and the <a href="https://www.congress.gov/bill/116th-congress/senate-bill/4982/text" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Creating Helpful Incentives for Producing Semiconductors for America and Foundries Act</a>. Welby predicts that other countries will make similar investments, and he says he hopes IEEE will support those as well.
</p><p>
	“IEEE is in an interesting spot relative to public policy in the United States, Europe, and elsewhere because we talk to the concerns of technologists, and about technology and how it impacts regulations and legislation,” he says. “We’re not arguing for a particular stakeholder; we’re arguing for investments in advancing technology. We’re engaged around the world in helping to ensure that research is adequately funded and that technical education gets the support it needs.”
</p><h2>The impact of the pandemic and global tensions</h2><p>
	Leading a global organization that depends on in-person meetings and events has proven especially challenging in recent years. After the coronavirus pandemic began spreading in 2020, the organization suddenly shifted its business model from building communities through in-person engagement to relying almost exclusively on digital delivery, Welby says.
</p><p>
	“IEEE has a reputation for being a conservative organization, for being slow to change, and sometimes for being overly rule-bound and bureaucratic,” he says. “But in the face of a global crisis, we adapted quickly. Staff and volunteers worked closely together to redesign and redeploy IEEE activities in a manner that allowed our communities to remain connected even while physically distancing themselves for safety. There was great trust, great collaboration, and great success.
</p><p>
	 “The ability to respond, to change, to evolve, and to adapt is one of IEEE’s great strengths,” he adds. “That makes me feel it will be ready to take on whatever the future brings and deliver on our mission.”
</p><p>
	Geopolitical tensions in recent years have impacted IEEE, he notes. Conflict among countries, trade restrictions, and proliferating international sanctions among nations have created new challenges for IEEE activities, he says.
</p><p>
	“We have worked hard to stay focused on IEEE’s role in supporting an international community of engineers and technical professionals that spans national borders and supports a global commitment to expanding the scientific and technical knowledge of humankind,” he says. “But IEEE also must operate in compliance with applicable laws and regulations while seeking clarification of those that appear misapplied in the IEEE context. At the same time, we are sympathetic to the hardships that international tension can place on our members.”
</p><p>
	Coordinating the enormous scope and scale of IEEE activities is complex. IEEE operates in 160 countries; has 46 societies and councils; has 343 sections in 10 geographic regions; maintains a portfolio of more than 1,075 technical standards; publishes 200 transactions, journals, and magazines; and holds more than 1,900 conferences and events.
</p><p>
	“Trying to maintain coordination and synchronization across this enormous portfolio, managing risk, and prioritizing resources is a continuous challenge,” Welby says.
</p><p>
	He says his one regret is that more progress has not been made in evolving IEEE’s membership model. The model has remained relatively unchanged since the organization was established in 1963. He points out that overall membership growth has largely flattened, despite the increased role that technology plays in society. Across IEEE there has been a decline in the share of members working in industry, while at the same time there has been recent strong growth in student membership.
</p><p>
	“We continue to rely on face-to-face interaction for many of our core membership activities, despite the growth of online, virtual, and digital communities,” Welby says. “Prospective volunteers are working longer hours [and] have family commitments. Plus, there are other activities competing for their time. The time and energy commitments that IEEE has traditionally demanded of its volunteers may not be a viable strategy in coming decades. It may be time to fundamentally rethink the structure of IEEE membership and explore different ways to engage our members.”
</p><p>
	He notes that those concerns have been studied and debated, and initiatives have been undertaken to explore alternative membership models. But, he says, there remains more work to do to develop consensus on the future of membership.
</p><h2>Meeting with industry leaders and engineering students</h2><p>
	Welby says he’ll miss the concentrated chaos of an IEEE Board meeting series, where many decisions—great and small—are debated and decided in a short period of time. He’ll also miss talking to audiences of thousands of people about important technical topics, he says, and meeting with leaders from government and industry.
</p><p>
	“I have had the opportunity to see the amazing diversity of our membership,” he says, “and the fantastic work that they do, and their impact on the world. I spent a lot of time talking to as many volunteers in different roles as I could. I have particularly enjoyed engaging with students around the world and seeing their enthusiasm, their creativity, and their optimism. They give me great hope for our future.”
</p><p>
	Welby adds that he could not have accomplished as much as he did without the support and confidence of the IEEE presidents and boards he served, the thousands of IEEE volunteers, his senior management team, and the professional staff members around the world “who brought their creativity, commitment, and technical skills to every task.”
</p><p>
	“I will leave it to others to assess how effective I have been,” he says. “But I have woken up every day for the last five years thinking about what I could do to improve and advance IEEE’s mission.”
</p>]]></description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2022 18:00:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spectrum.ieee.org/stephen-welby-profile</guid><category>Ieee member news</category><category>Careers</category><category>Steven welby</category><category>Diversity</category><category>Inclusion</category><category>Ethics</category><category>Open access</category><category>Type:ti</category><dc:creator>Kathy Pretz</dc:creator><media:content medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/a-smiling-man-in-a-suit-and-glasses.jpg?id=31832314&amp;width=980"></media:content></item><item><title>Inflation-Adjusted Income for U.S. Engineers Drops</title><link>https://spectrum.ieee.org/electrical-engineer-salary</link><description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/illustration-showing-a-dollar-symbol-surrounded-by-circuitboard-lines.png?id=31706643&width=1245&height=700&coordinates=0%2C969%2C0%2C969"/><br/><br/><p><strong>How much does</strong> a tech professional in the United States earn? In 2021, the median income of U.S. engineers and other tech professionals who were <a href="http://www.ieee.org/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">IEEE</a> members hit US $160,097, up from $154,443 in 2020. That bump in pay is revealed in the IEEE-USA 2022 Salary & Benefits Survey.</p><p>This apparent increase turns into a nearly $3,500 dip, however, when converted to real dollars [see chart, below]. It’s the first significant dip in median tech salary in terms of spending power recorded by IEEE-USA since 2013.</p><p>These numbers—and 65 more pages of detailed 2021 salary and job-satisfaction statistics—give readers of <a href="https://ieeeusa.org/product/ieee-usa-salary-benefits-survey-report-2022-edition/" target="_blank">the salary and benefits survey</a> a good sense of the United States’ tech employment landscape. The analysis is based on 3,057 responses from professionals working full time in their areas of technical competence; they reported their income, excluding overtime pay, bonuses, profit sharing, and side hustles. (When those are considered, the 2021 median income for these tech professionals was $167,988, according to the report.)</p><h3></h3><br/><h3>Bad News for Women in Engineering</h3><br/><p>The IEEE-USA 2022 Salary & Benefits Survey chronicles bad news for women in engineering, as their incomes fell further behind men’s in 2021. The gap in salaries between genders grew $5,900 (not adjusted for inflation) to $33,900. The gap is tricky to measure, given that men responding to the survey had more years of experience, as a group, than the women, and more women entering the engineering workforce could skew the median salary downward. However, the proportion of female engineers in the workforce remained flat (on a plateau at under 10 percent, where it’s been for the past 10 years), the survey report noted.</p><h3></h3><br/><div class="flourish-embed flourish-chart" data-src="visualisation/11071896?594662"><script src="https://public.flourish.studio/resources/embed.js"></script></div><h3>Racial Gaps in Engineering Salaries Narrow</h3><br/><p>The salary gap between Caucasian and African American engineers decreased by $11,000 to $13,000 in 2021, while the disparity between Caucasian and Hispanic engineers’ incomes fell by nearly $6,000 to $12,278.</p><h3></h3><br/><div class="flourish-embed flourish-chart" data-src="visualisation/11071853?594662"><script src="https://public.flourish.studio/resources/embed.js"></script></div><h3>Solid-State Circuits Engineering Is Hot</h3><br/><p>2021 was a good time to be an engineer working with solid-state circuitry; salaries in that technical field continued a steep climb and claimed the No. 1 spot on the salaries-by-specialty list. Last year’s No. 1 on that chart, consumer electronics, saw a decline in average salary. Engineers working with other circuits and devices, machine learning, image and video processing, and engineering in medicine and biology recorded big gains.</p><h3></h3><br/><h3>Engineering Job Satisfaction Dips</h3><br/><p>Overall job satisfaction for engineers surveyed by IEEE-USA fell in 2021, with the biggest drop-offs related to compensation and advancement opportunities. Satisfaction with the technical challenge of engineering jobs was up significantly, however.</p><h3></h3><br/><div class="flourish-embed flourish-chart" data-src="visualisation/11071766?594662"><script src="https://public.flourish.studio/resources/embed.js"></script></div><h3>Pacific Coast Engineering Salaries Jump Further Ahead</h3><br/><p>Median salaries for engineers in the Pacific region increased dramatically compared with the rest of the <br/>United States, climbing faster than hypothetically booming regions like the West South Central area, which includes Texas. These numbers were not adjusted for regional costs of living, however.</p><h3></h3><br><div class="flourish-embed flourish-chart" data-src="visualisation/11071737?594662"><script src="https://public.flourish.studio/resources/embed.js"></script></div></br>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2022 15:13:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spectrum.ieee.org/electrical-engineer-salary</guid><category>Careers</category><category>Salaries</category><category>Engineering jobs</category><category>Engineering salaries</category><category>Salary survey</category><dc:creator>Tekla S. Perry</dc:creator><media:content medium="image" type="image/png" url="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/illustration-showing-a-dollar-symbol-surrounded-by-circuitboard-lines.png?id=31706643&amp;width=980"></media:content></item><item><title>Ensuring Underwater Robots Survive in Hot Tropical Waters</title><link>https://spectrum.ieee.org/melanie-olsen-profile</link><description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/an-outdoor-photo-of-a-woman-holding-a-robotic-device.png?id=31700826&width=1245&height=700&coordinates=0%2C0%2C0%2C199"/><br/><br/><p>The hot, humid environment of tropical marine areas such as Australia’s Great Barrier Reef can wreak havoc on the marine autonomous systems. Underwater and surface MAS are used for marine monitoring, locating objects such as mines on the seafloor, and rescuing swimmers. </p><p>“Tropical conditions can cause systems to overheat or prevent high-density lithium batteries from recharging,” says Melanie Olsen, who is a project director of the <a href="https://www.aims.gov.au/about/facilities/reefworks" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Australian Institute of Marine Science’s (AIMS) ReefWorks</a>, a technology testing and evaluation facility in northern Australia. “And the microbial and small creatures that thrive in these tropical environments grow rapidly on underwater surfaces and degrade the sensor performance and the hydrodynamics of the robotics and autonomous systems.”</p><hr/><p>Developing technology that can stand up to these conditions is part of Olsen’s job, as is supporting ReefWorks’ broader mission of helping others move their autonomous systems out of the lab. It’s essential to test these systems and collect compliance evidence to demonstrate they meet regulatory requirements and can be certified for operations, says Olsen, an IEEE senior member. But there are very few places to test marine robotics, autonomous systems, and artificial-intelligence (RAS-AI) technologies, which hampers the growth of the industry, Olsen says. “It’s difficult for RAS-AI vendors to progress from a prototype to a commercial product because the pathway to a certified system is complex.” </p><p>That’s why AIMS established ReefWorks. The facility is used to test crewed and uncrewed tropical and marine vessels as well as robots, sensors, and other innovations. “We are Australia’s—and possibly the world’s—first such testing facility in the tropics,” Olsen says. Examples of underwater and surface MAS include the <a href="https://www.aims.gov.au/research/technology/reefscan/CoralAUV" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">ReefScan CoralAUV</a>, which is used for marine monitoring, and the <a href="https://wam-v.com" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Wave Adaptive Modular Vessel</a>, a surface vessel used for marine monitoring, locating mines and other objects on the seafloor, and rescuing swimmers.</p><p>AIMS has been testing equipment for over a decade, but this part of AIMS’s facilities opened to the public in December 2021. ReefWorks supports the entire development cycle, from digital-model validation and developmental testing to product and operational-level testing, Olsen says. Physical tests can be done at AIMS’s three marine field ranges, which offer different testing conditions. ReefWorks also has land-based facilities, plus the National Sea Simulator sensor test tank, and drone corridors between the at-sea ranges for verifying the performance of long-range marine autonomous systems.</p><p>“Our overall objective is to establish a sustainable marine autonomous systems [MAS] sector in Australia,” she says.</p><p>One of the ways ReefWorks helps its users make the most of their time on test ranges is to offer “digital twins” and virtual worlds. A digital twin is a virtual model of a real-world object, machine, or system that can be used to assess how the real-world counterpart is performing.</p><p>“Each of our test ranges is developing a digital twin,” Olsen says. “Developers will be able to conduct a test mission on the virtual range so when they get here, they can replay missions with real-time collected data, and validate their MAS digital-model performance.”</p><p>Olsen leads a team of five people and is currently recruiting another five. She expects the staff to triple in size in a few years as ReefWorks becomes more established in the region. </p><p>An IEEE senior member, Olsen is active with the <a href="https://r10.ieee.org/naus/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">IEEE Northern Australia Section</a>. She served as the section chair in 2020 and 2021, during which time the section achieved the <a href="https://www.ieeer10.org/awards-recognition-committee/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Region 10 Outstanding Small Section Award</a>.</p><h2>Integrating embedded AI and IOT edge computing</h2><p>Before joining AIMS, Olsen spent a decade in <a href="https://www.defence.gov.au/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Australia’s Department of Defence</a> (DOD) as a lead engineer working on future technologies and maritime electronic-warfare systems.</p><p>Olsen grew up in a farming family and wasn’t really exposed to computers or engineers until an EE lecturer from<a href="https://www.jcu.edu.au/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"> James Cook University</a>, in Australia, came to her rural high school to give a presentation. He brought along a remote-controlled quadrotor helicopter—a decade before quadcopters were commonplace.</p><p>The lecture led Olsen to pursue a bachelor’s degree in electrical, electronics, and computer systems, also from James Cook University, in Townsville. She went on to earn a master’s degree in systems engineering from Australia’s<a href="https://canberra.unsw.edu.au/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"> University of New South Wales, in Canberra</a>. In 2016, Olsen took a job at AIMS as an engineering team leader in technology development.</p><p> “I’m very passionate about new technologies and seeing them integrated in the field,” she says. “During my decade at the [Australian] DOD, I grew my skills in systems engineering to solve more complex technology-integration challenges. AIMS offered me an opportunity to apply these skills to the challenges facing the tropical marine environment.”</p><p class="pull-quote"> “We are Australia’s—and possibly the world’s—first such testing facility in the tropics.”</p><p>There are many similarities between what Olsen had been doing at DOD and her role at ReefWorks. “My work at both DOD and AIMS requires an understanding of how electronic subsystems work, determining what’s viable for the use case, understanding the importance of modeling and simulation, and being able to communicate engineering terminology to an interdisciplinary team,” she says. “Both roles are all about engineering problem-solving.”</p><p>Olsen is currently working on integrating embedded AI and Internet of Things edge computing into AIMS infrastructure. “Artificial intelligence is used to increase a marine autonomous system’s capabilities,” she says. “For example, AI is used to train a MAS to navigate and avoid colliding with coral reefs, other vessels, or other objects or to allow the MAS to identify specific marine species, reef areas suitable for reseeding, and marine mines.”</p><p>IoT edge computing is used to process data closer to its point of origin. “This has the potential to speed up the decision process for vessels and operators while minimizing the communications and data bandwidth needed, which are key limitations when operating in marine northern Australia,” Olsen says.</p><p>Since GPS doesn’t work underwater, another of her team’s projects is looking for additional ways to conduct accurate geospatial positioning and control for missions that don’t require marine autonomous systems to come to the surface.</p><p>“We’re only just starting to get a feel for what marine autonomous systems can do—not just for our tropical marine waters but in general,” she says. “There are grand challenges no one can solve right now, like dealing with ocean pollution and the impacts of climate change.”</p><h2>Robotics engineers needed</h2><p>There’s nowhere near enough robotics engineers in the world, Olsen says. She recommends that engineering students take courses that include group projects. </p><p>“Group projects help you grow your ability to solve problems outside your knowledge or expertise,” she says. “They teach you how to work as an interdisciplinary team, who to ask for help, and where to find it.”</p><p><em>This article appears in the October 2022 print issue as “Melanie Olsen.”</em></p>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2022 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spectrum.ieee.org/melanie-olsen-profile</guid><category>Ieee member</category><category>Careers</category><category>Type:departments</category><category>Ai</category><category>Robots</category><category>Robotics</category><dc:creator>Daniel P. Dern</dc:creator><media:content medium="image" type="image/png" url="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/an-outdoor-photo-of-a-woman-holding-a-robotic-device.png?id=31700826&amp;width=980"></media:content></item><item><title>A New One-Stop Resource for IEEE Life Members</title><link>https://spectrum.ieee.org/new-ieee-life-members-website</link><description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/a-photo-of-a-pair-of-women-and-an-older-man-in-front-of-a-tablet.jpg?id=31821584&width=1245&height=700&coordinates=0%2C0%2C0%2C469"/><br/><br/><p>The new<a href="https://life.ieee.org/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"> IEEE Life Members website</a> is a one-stop resource to keep the most experienced of members connected.</p><p>The life member designation is for those who have reached the age of 65 and have been with IEEE for such a period of time that the sum of their age and their years of membership equals or exceeds 100.</p><hr/><p>There are many benefits to being a life member. Dues, regional assessments, and society fees are waived. Life members receive reduced registration fees at conferences for which IEEE is the sole sponsor. In addition, the members can continue to participate in the <a href="https://www.ieee.org/membership/discounts/index.html" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">IEEE Member Discounts</a> program. They also retain all the other benefits of membership. </p><p>IEEE’s 35,000 life members provide professional and personal experiences and are an underutilized source of wisdom, says Life Member <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/ralph-wyndrum-41005065/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Ralph Wyndrum</a>, an IEEE Fellow who led the project to redesign the website.</p><p class="pull-quote">“IEEE’s 35,000 life members provide professional and personal experiences and are an underutilized source of wisdom.”</p><p>“As life members, we are uniquely experienced and available to serve as volunteers to the IEEE,” Wyndrum says, “and to those in the profession who would like to fast-track their career knowledge and advancement through formal and informal opportunities.”</p><p>IEEE Senior Member <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/howard-wolfman-5494b21/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Howard Wolfman</a>, chair of the <a href="https://mga.ieee.org/board-committees/committees/216-ieee-life-members-committee" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">IEEE Life Members Committee</a>, says that for about a year, the committee painstakingly reviewed all its activities, “reimagining a more intuitive and efficient way to connect our members and the public to the million years of professional and life experiences that IEEE life members have to offer.”</p>
<h2>Five ways to connect</h2><p>The new website is organized into five sections:</p><ul><li><a href="https://life.ieee.org/get-involved/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Ways to get involved.</a> There are many opportunities to participate, including helping others connect with senior leaders in the corporate and academic worlds, mentoring the next generation of engineers, and getting involved in technical and nontechnical <a href="https://life.ieee.org/get-involved/special-interest-groups/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">interest groups</a>. </li><li><a href="https://life.ieee.org/news-events/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">News and events.</a> Members are kept informed through a newsletter, announcements, and a calendar of upcoming meetings.</li><li><a href="https://life.ieee.org/awards-recognition/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Awards and recognitions.</a> Learn about the four awards that the Life Members Committee bestows to honor the work of its members. Also included is information about nominating a colleague. </li><li><a href="https://life.ieee.org/volunteers/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Volunteers.</a> For those who want to donate their time, there are several ways to do so. One is to join a section’s or council’s life member affinity group. The groups let life members contribute to the social good in their community, advance the professional interests of IEEE, and plan social and technical events.</li><li><a href="https://life.ieee.org/resources/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Resources.</a> This section of the website offers books, publications, videos, and continuing-education materials to help members stay technically current.</li></ul>
<h2>A new Collabratec community</h2><p>An online community for life members has launched on <a href="https://ieee-collabratec.ieee.org/app/home" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">IEEE Collabratec</a>, the organization’s professional networking and collaboration platform. <a href="https://ieee-collabratec.ieee.org/app/community/1348/IEEE-Life-Members-and-Friends/activities" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">IEEE Life Members and Friends</a> community provides opportunities to connect and engage in conversations of mutual interest with others, regardless of their physical location.</p>“In addition to improving connectivity and fellowship among our life members,” Wolfman says, “we have begun taking bold, new measures to support the next generation of innovators.” Throughout this year and next, he says, the Life Members Committee will collaborate with the <a href="https://www.ieeefoundation.org/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">IEEE Foundation</a> to raise funds to support leadership-development events and opportunities for IEEE’s student members.]]></description><pubDate>Tue, 13 Sep 2022 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spectrum.ieee.org/new-ieee-life-members-website</guid><category>Ieee member news</category><category>Ieee products services</category><category>Life members</category><category>Ieee collabratec</category><category>Ieee life member committee</category><category>Type:ti</category><dc:creator>Kathy Pretz</dc:creator><media:content medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/a-photo-of-a-pair-of-women-and-an-older-man-in-front-of-a-tablet.jpg?id=31821584&amp;width=980"></media:content></item><item><title>Aligning the Eyes of the Universe Machine</title><link>https://spectrum.ieee.org/james-webb-space-telescope-mirror</link><description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/a-person-on-a-cherry-picker-next-to-the-james-webb-space-telescope.jpg?id=31637785&width=1245&height=700&coordinates=0%2C197%2C0%2C272"/><br/><br/><p>
	The <a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/collections/james-webb-telescope/" target="_self">James Webb Space Telescope</a>, in just a few months of operation, has begun to change our view of the universe. Its images—more detailed than what was possible before—show space aglow with galaxies, some of them formed very soon after the big bang.
</p><p>
	None of this would be possible without the work of a team led by <a href="https://www.researchgate.net/scientific-contributions/D-Scott-Acton-2005553350" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Scott Acton</a>, the lead <a href="https://webb.nasa.gov/content/about/innovations/wavefront.html" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">wavefront sensing and control</a> scientist for the Webb at <a href="https://www.ball.com/aerospace/programs/astrophysics/webb" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Ball Aerospace & Technologies</a> in Colorado. He and his colleagues <a href="https://citeseerx.ist.psu.edu/viewdoc/download?doi=10.1.1.823.4123&rep=rep1&type=pdf" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">developed</a> <a href="https://www.jwst.nasa.gov/resources/JWSTTech.pdf" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">the systems</a> that align the 18 separate segments of the Webb’s primary mirror with its smaller secondary mirror and science instruments. To produce clear images in the infrared wavelengths the telescope uses, the segments have to be within <a href="https://jwst-docs.stsci.edu/jwst-observatory-hardware/jwst-wavefront-sensing-and-control" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">tens of nanometers</a> of the shape specified in the spacecraft design.
</p><p>
	Acton grew up in Wyoming and spent more than 20 years on the Webb team. <em>IEEE Spectrum</em> spoke with Acton after his team had finished aligning the telescope’s optics in space. This transcript has been edited for clarity and brevity.
</p><p>
<strong>Tell your story. What got you started?</strong>
</p><p>
<strong>Scott Acton:</strong> When I was seven-years-old, my dad brought home a new television. And he gave me the old television to take apart. I was just enthralled by what I saw inside this television. And from that moment on I was defined by electronics. You look inside an old television and there are mechanisms, there are smells and colors and sights and for a seven-year-old kid, it was just the most amazing thing I’d ever seen.
</p><p>
	Fast-forward 25 years and I’m working in the field of adaptive optics. And eventually that led to wavefront sensing and controls, which led to the Webb telescope.
</p><p class="shortcode-media shortcode-media-rebelmouse-image">
<img alt="sky with bright stars and gaseous activity" class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="cf0f79e1e2e89612e8fa9b62102b382e" data-rm-shortcode-name="rebelmouse-image" id="01a79" loading="lazy" src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/sky-with-bright-stars-and-gaseous-activity.jpg?id=31638587&width=980"/>
<small class="image-media media-caption" placeholder="Add Photo Caption...">Called the Cosmic Cliffs, Webb’s seemingly three-dimensional picture looks like craggy mountains on a moonlit evening. In reality, it is the edge of the giant, gaseous cavity within NGC 3324, and the tallest “peaks” in this image are about 7 light-years high.</small><small class="image-media media-photo-credit" placeholder="Add Photo Credit..."> NASA/ESA/CSA/STScI</small>
</p><p>
<strong>Talk about your work getting the telescope ready for flight. You worked on it for more than 20 years.</strong>
</p><p>
<strong>Acton: </strong>Well, we had to invent all of the wavefront sensing and controls. None of that technology really existed in 2001, so we started from the ground up with concepts and simple experiments. Then more complicated, very complicated experiments and eventually something known as TRL 6 technology—Technology Readiness Level 6—which demonstrated that we could do this in a flightlike environment. And then it was a question of taking this technology, algorithms, understanding it and implementing it into very robust procedures, documentation, and software, so that it could then be applied on the flight telescope.
</p><p>
<strong>What was it like finally to launch?</strong>
</p><p>
<strong>Acton:</strong> Well, I’ve got to say, there was a lot of nervousness, at least on my part. I was thinking we had a 70 percent chance of mission success, or something like that. It’s like sending your kid off to college—this instrument that we’d been looking at and thinking about.
</p><p>
	The Ariane 5 vehicle is so reliable. I didn’t think there was going to be any problem with it, but deployment starts, basically, minutes after launch. So, for me, the place to be was at a computer console [at the Space Telescope Science Institute in Baltimore].
</p><p>
<strong>And then there were a lot of things that had to work.</strong>
</p><p>
<strong>Acton:</strong> Yes, right. But there are some things that that are interesting. They have these things called nonexplosive actuators [used to secure the spacecraft during launch]. There are about 130 of them. And you actually can’t test them. You build them and they get used, basically, once. If you do reuse one, well, it’s now a different actuator because you have to solder it back together. So you can’t qualify the part, but what you can do is qualify the process.
</p><p>
	We could have still had a mission if some didn’t fire, but most of them were absolutely necessary for the success of the mission. So just ask yourself, let’s suppose you want to have a 95 percent chance of success. What number raised to the 130th power is equal to 0.95? That number is basically one. These things had to be perfect.
</p><p class="pull-quote">
	I remember walking home one night, talking on the phone to my wife, Heidi, and saying, “If I’m wrong about this I’ve just completely screwed up the telescope.” She said, “Scott, that’s why you’re there.” That was her way of telling me to cowboy up. The responsibility had to come down to somebody and in that moment, it was me.
</p><p>
<strong>I think the public perception was that the Webb was in very good shape and the in-flight setup all went very well. Would you say that’s accurate?</strong>
</p><p>
<strong>Acton: </strong>Early on in the mission there were hiccups, but other than that, I’d say things just went beyond our wildest expectations. Part of that comes down to the fact that my team and I had commissioned the telescope 100 times in simulations. And we always made it a little harder. I think that served us well because when we got to the real telescope, it was quite robust. It just worked.
</p><p>
<strong>Take us through the process of aligning the telescope.</strong>
</p><p>
<strong>Acton: </strong>The first image we got back from the telescope was 2 February, in the middle of the night. Most people had gone home, but I was there, and a lot of other people were too. We just pointed the telescope at the Large Magellanic Cloud, which has lots and lots of stars in it, and took images on the near-infrared cameras. People were really happy to see these images because they were looking basically to make sure that the science instruments worked.
</p><p>
	But some of us were really concerned with that image, because you could see some very significant astigmatism—stronger than we were expecting to see from our simulations. Later we would learn that the telescope’s secondary mirror was off in translation—about 1.5 millimeters along the deployment axis and about a millimeter in the other axis. And the primary mirror segments were clocked a bit from the perfectly aligned state.
</p><p>
<a href="https://jwst.nasa.gov/content/meetTheTeam/people/feinberg.html" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Lee Feinberg</a>, the telescope lead at NASA Goddard, texted me and said, “Scott, why can’t you just simulate this to see if you can get some images that bad?” So that morning I ran a simulation and was able to reproduce almost exactly what we were seeing in these images. We realized that we were not going to have any major problems with the wavefront.
</p><p><strong>Describe the cadence of your work during commissioning. What would a day be like?</strong>
</p><p>
<strong>Acton:</strong> One of the rules we set up very early on was that in terms of wavefront sensing and control, we would always have two people sitting in front of the computers at any given time. Anytime anything significant happened, I always wanted to make sure that I was there, so I got an apartment [near the institute in Baltimore]. From my door to the door of the of the Mission Operations Center was a 7-minute walk.
</p><p class="shortcode-media shortcode-media-rebelmouse-image">
<img alt="sky with bright star in middle with gases" class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="9e7e4d9499e9901a9c1bd852b8b57d33" data-rm-shortcode-name="rebelmouse-image" id="a9903" loading="lazy" src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/sky-with-bright-star-in-middle-with-gases.jpg?id=31638681&width=980"/>
<small class="image-media media-caption" placeholder="Add Photo Caption...">In this mosaic image stretching 340 light-years across, Webb’s Near-Infrared Camera (NIRCam) displays the Tarantula Nebula star-forming region in a new light, including tens of thousands of never-before-seen young stars that were previously shrouded in cosmic dust.</small><small class="image-media media-photo-credit" placeholder="Add Photo Credit...">NASA/ESA/CSA/STScI/Webb ERO Production Team</small>
</p><p>
	There were certainly times during the process where it had a very large pucker factor, if you will. We couldn’t point the telescope reliably at the very beginning. And a lot of our software, for the early steps of commissioning, depended on the immutability of telescope pointing. We wanted to have the telescope repeatedly pointed to within a couple of arc-seconds and it was closer to 20 or 30. Because of that, some of the initial moves to align the telescope had to be calculated, if you will, by hand.
</p><p>
	I remember walking home one night, talking on the phone to my wife, Heidi, and saying, “If I’m wrong about this I’ve just completely screwed up the telescope.” She said, “Scott, that’s why you’re there.” That was her way of telling me to cowboy up. The responsibility had to come down to somebody and in that moment, it was me.
</p><p>
	But when the result came back, we could see the images. We pointed the telescope at a bright isolated star and then we could see, one at a time, 18 spots appearing in the middle of our main science detector. I remember a colleague saying, “I now believe we’re going to completely align the telescope.” He felt in his mind that if we could get past that step, that everything else was downhill.
</p><p>
	You’re trying to piece together the universe. It’s hard to get it right, and very easy to make mistakes. But we did it.
</p><p>
<strong>Building the Webb was, of course, a big, complicated project. Do you think there are any particular lessons to be drawn from it that people in the future might find useful?</strong>
</p><p>
<strong>Acton:</strong> Here are a couple of really big ones that apply to wavefront sensing and control. One is that there are multiple institutions involved—Northrop Grumman, Ball Aerospace, the Goddard Space Flight Center, the Space Telescope Science Institute—and the complication of having all these institutional lines. It could have been very, very difficult to navigate. So very early on we decided not to have any lines. We were a completely badgeless team. Anybody could talk to anybody. If someone said, “No, I think this is wrong, you should do it this way,” even if they didn’t necessarily have contractual responsibility, everybody listened.
</p><p>
	Another big lesson we learned was about the importance of the interplay between experimentation and simulation. We built a one-sixth scale model, a fully functional optical model of the telescope, and it’s still working. It allowed us, very early on, to know what was going to be difficult. Then we could address those issues in simulation. That understanding, the interplay between experimentation and modeling and simulations, was absolutely essential.
</p><p>
<strong>Recognizing of course, that it’s very early, do you yet have a favorite image?</strong>
</p><p>
<strong>Acton:</strong> My favorite image, so far, was one that was taken during the last real wavefront activity that we did as part of commissioning. It was called a thermal slew test. The telescope has a large <a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/james-webb-telescope-sunshield" target="_self">sunshield</a>, but the sunshield can be at different angles with respect to the sun. So to make sure it was stable, we aimed it at a bright star we used as a guide star, put it in one orientation, and stayed there for five or six days. And then we switched to a different orientation for five or six days. It turned out to be quite stable. But how do you know that the telescope wasn’t rolling about the guide star? To check this, we took a series of test images with the redundant fine-guidance sensor. As you can imagine, when you have a 6-1/2 meter telescope at L2 away from any competing light sources that is cooled to 50 kelvins, yes, it is sensitive. Even just one 20-minute exposure is going to just have unbelievable detail regarding the deep universe. Imagine what happens if you take 100 of those images and average them together. We came up with an image of just some random part of the sky.
</p><p class="shortcode-media shortcode-media-rebelmouse-image">
<img alt="james webb telescope image of bright lights against a dark background" class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="d6e5ebd7d02699554f88c146434fd49c" data-rm-shortcode-name="rebelmouse-image" id="5a840" loading="lazy" src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/james-webb-telescope-image-of-bright-lights-against-a-dark-background.jpg?id=31638422&width=980"/>
<small class="image-media media-caption" placeholder="Add Photo Caption...">Scott Acton’s favorite Webb image: A test image of a random part of the sky, shot with the Webb’s fine-guidance sensor. The points with six-pointed diffraction patterns are stars; all other points are galaxies. </small><small class="image-media media-photo-credit" placeholder="Add Photo Credit...">NASA/CSA/FGS</small>
</p><p>
	I sent this image to <a href="https://www.astro.ucla.edu/~larkin/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">James Larkin</a> at UCLA, and he looked at it and estimated that that single image had 15,000 galaxies in it. Every one of those galaxies probably has between 100 [billion] and 200 billion stars.
</p><p>
	I don’t talk about religion too much when it comes to this, but I must have had in my mind a Biblical reference to the stars singing. I pictured all of those galaxies as singing, as if this was a way for the universe to express joy that after all these years, we could finally see them. It was quite an emotional experience for me and for many people.
</p><p>
<strong>You realized that there was so much out there, and you weren’t even really looking for it yet? You were still phasing the telescope?</strong>
</p><p>
<strong>Acton:</strong> That’s right. I guess I I’m not sure what I expected. I figured you’d just see dark sky. Well, there <em>is</em> no dark sky. Dark sky is a myth. Galaxies are everywhere.
</p><p>
	Finally, we got to our first diffraction-limited image [with the telescope calibrated for science observations for the first time]. And that’s the way the telescope is operating now.
</p><p>
	Several days later, about 70 of us got together—astronomers, engineers, and other team members. A member of the team—his name is Anthony Galyer—and I had gone halves several years earlier and purchased a bottle of cognac from 1906, the year that James Webb was born. We toasted James Webb and the telescope that bears his name.
</p>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2022 17:39:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spectrum.ieee.org/james-webb-space-telescope-mirror</guid><category>Jwst</category><category>Telescopes</category><category>Wavefront sensing</category><category>Simulations</category><category>Control systems</category><category>Optics</category><dc:creator>Ned Potter</dc:creator><media:content medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/a-person-on-a-cherry-picker-next-to-the-james-webb-space-telescope.jpg?id=31637785&amp;width=980"></media:content></item><item><title>How We Celebrate Engineers</title><link>https://spectrum.ieee.org/how-we-celebrate-engineers</link><description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/a-collage-of-5-people-on-a-blue-background.png?id=31356180&width=2068&height=1798&coordinates=0%2C0%2C0%2C0"/><br/><br/><p><em>The Institute</em> has appeared, off and on, in the pages of <em>IEEE</em> <em>Spectrum </em>since debuting as a four-page insert in the December 1976 issue. At various times during the ensuing decades, <em>The Institute</em>—or, as we call it in <em>Spectrum</em>’s offices, “<em>TI</em>”—has been published as a stand-alone monthly and then quarterly broadsheet. It even had its own website for a few years, before being integrated into <em>Spectrum</em>’s site in 2019 and appearing in the print magazine as a section on a quarterly basis. </p><p>While <em>Spectrum</em> dives deep into emerging technologies and delivers expert voices from the bleeding edge, <em>The Institute</em> has focused on IEEE members, featuring their stories, celebrating their accomplishments, and telling them about IEEE products, services, elections, and volunteer opportunities. <em>The Institute</em> also brings members all the news relevant to the functioning of the association, such as the reconfiguration of its geographic regions to ensure there is equitable representation across its global membership. </p><hr/><p><em>The Institute</em> staff—Editor in Chief Kathy Pretz and Assistant Editor Joanna Goodrich—say they are most excited about showcasing the diversity of IEEE’s membership and highlighting those who have made IEEE their professional home. Pretz says there’s a misconception that most of IEEE’s members work in academia. That’s why <em>The Institute</em> has put more emphasis on profiling the careers of those working in industry, such as <a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/tsmc-exec-on-chip-shortage" target="_self">Taiwan Semiconductor Manufacturing Co.’s senior vice president of R&D, Yuh-Jier Mii</a>. </p><p>“I’m always amazed how accessible top leaders at high-tech companies are when I tell them I would like to interview them for an article in IEEE’s member publication,” Pretz remarked recently. “And all of them are so humble about their accomplishments. TSMC’s Yuh-Jier Mii was no different.”</p><p>Pretz and Goodrich also write about the careers of young professionals who are the future of the organization. In this month’s issue, they <a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/legacy-of-eddie-custovic" target="_self">spotlight Eddie Custovic</a>, the recipient of the IEEE Theodore W. Hissey Outstanding Young Professionals Award. </p><p class="pull-quote">“It’s very rewarding to be able to interview members who have developed technology that I use every day.”</p><p><strong></strong>In addition to putting a spotlight on the accomplishments of individual engineers,<em> The Institute </em>also covers the history of technology. “It’s very rewarding to be able to interview members who have developed technology that I use every day, as well as members who are developing the next breakthrough tech that will impact society,” Goodrich says. “For example, Steven Sasson invented the <a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/first-digital-camera-history" target="_self">first digital camera</a>, which we use every day in some shape or form. Eddie Custovic, on the other hand, is working to develop an AI platform that will help solve food shortages that have been predicted for 2050.”</p><p>Indeed, IEEE members have for decades been turning their ideas into successful businesses. That’s why <em>TI</em> features entrepreneurial members who have launched their own ventures, like IEEE Fellow <a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/ai-to-increase-ivf-success" target="_self">Alex Bronstein of Embryonics</a>. And, of course, <em>TI</em> celebrates major anniversaries and milestones, like the 25th anniversary of <a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/ieee-wie-25-year-anniversary" target="_self">IEEE Women in Engineering</a>.</p><p>In future issues, readers can look forward to a profile of computer pioneer IEEE Fellow <a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/erol-gelenbe-profile" target="_blank">Erol Gelenbe</a>, whose invention of the packet-voice telephone switch made Zoom possible. In December, look for a piece on IEEE executive director Stephen Welby, who is leaving the organization at the end of the year. Kathy, Joanna, and I invite you to celebrate these engineers and their extraordinary accomplishments with us in the coming months. </p>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2022 16:17:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spectrum.ieee.org/how-we-celebrate-engineers</guid><category>The institute</category><category>Engineers</category><category>Engineering careers</category><category>Tech history</category><category>Type:ti</category><dc:creator>Harry Goldstein</dc:creator><media:content medium="image" type="image/png" url="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/a-collage-of-5-people-on-a-blue-background.png?id=31356180&amp;width=980"></media:content></item><item><title>Steradian’s 4D Imaging Radar Aims to Make Self-Driving Cars Smarter</title><link>https://spectrum.ieee.org/steradians-4d-imaging-radar</link><description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/hand-holding-small-computer-chip-between-the-thumb-and-forefinger.jpg?id=31300451&width=1245&height=700&coordinates=0%2C99%2C0%2C100"/><br/><br/><p>The founders of<a href="https://steradiansemi.com/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"> Steradian Semiconductors</a> saw a technology gap in the marketplace and used their know-how to fill it. Before launching the fabless semiconductor startup in 2016, the founders were working at well-known technology companies designing chipsets for mass-market radio technologies including Bluetooth, GPS, LTE cellular, and wireless LAN. They discovered that radars could be built with modern techniques, such as semiconductors and processing advances, so that they could extract shapes, sizes, and types of objects.</p><p>The sophisticated radar chips and processors working together could be used in autonomous cars to extract the same information if not more, the founders theorized.</p><hr/><p>“We did market studies and literature surveys—including IEEE publications—and found that radar has unlimited potential in the automotive industry,” says IEEE Senior Member<a href="https://steradiansemi.com/about/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"> Apu Sivadas</a>, the company’s CTO and a cofounder. “The radar echoes contain a wealth of hidden information, which we felt the existing technology used in autonomous vehicles could not fully harness.”</p><p>Headquartered in Bangalore, India, Steradian developed a “4D” millimeter-wave imaging radar system and the small MIMO (multiple input, multiple output) transceiver chipsets that go with it. The system is called 4D because it tracks distance, speed, elevation angles, and the azimuth, the horizontal angle or direction of a compass bearing.</p><p>At the moment, lidar has superior angular resolution, but Sivadas says he believes radar eventually can bridge the gap once modern radar chipsets and AI are combined.</p><h3>Using IEEE Xplore to its fullest</h3><br/><p>IEEE is “pretty close to my heart,” Sivadas says. “At the universities where I studied [the National Institute of Technology Calicut and the Indian Institute of Technology Kanpur], there was a history of faculty publishing in IEEE transactions or journals and referring to them to let us know what was new and trending. For example, our research topics were picked from the journals the professors wrote for.</p><p>“Even after so many years, IEEE is still very much baked into the education of Indian engineers.”</p><p>A subscription to the<a href="https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/Xplore/home.jsp" target="_blank"> IEEE Xplore Digital Library</a> is his most important member benefit, he says.</p><p>When he needs to solve a technical issue, he says, he searches the digital library to find relevant papers. And he has collaborated with some authors of those papers and hired graduate students who have coauthored the articles.</p><p>“Automotive sensing is fast emerging. We hope to achieve a lot more with radar, Sivadas says. “We should exploit radar to the maximum.”</p><p>The company was named <em>Steradian, </em>he says, because “it is the 3D version of radian, which is the International System of Units [measure] of angle on a plane.” Steradian is the SI unit for a solid angle and has “connotations of having very sharp antenna beams,” he says.</p><p>The startup, which has four dozen employees, submitted 26 U.S. patent applications for its technology, and it has been granted nine patents so far.</p><p>“We are an end-to-end product company,” he says. “The advanced technology that goes into radar—such as antennas, radar semiconductor chipsets, signal processors, and software—are all done under one roof. We take care of the entire product architecture.”</p><h2>4D imaging</h2><p>An imaging radar system consists of two main parts: a transceiver that sends and receives signals and an imaging/processing chip that turns the signals into images.</p><p>Steradian offers a state-of-the-art 28-nanometer CMOS chip that powers its 4D sensors. The radar chip is an integrated 16-channel MIMO that acts as a building block for high-resolution radars. In a market comparison, Sivadas says, Steradian’s transceiver had the highest output power and the lowest noise with the least amount of distortion.</p><p>The radar system, which operates in the 76- to 81-gigahertz frequency band, can be used in intelligent transportation infrastructure in addition to self-driving cars, he says.</p><p class="pull-quote">“The advanced technology that goes into radar—such as antennas, radar semiconductor chipsets, signal processors, and software—are all done under one roof.”</p><p><span></span>“The unit can be installed on highways or intersections to monitor traffic,” he says, “such as counting the number of vehicles in a lane, automating traffic lights, or monitoring a vehicle’s speed.”</p><p>The automotive industry is evaluating the use of 4D radar sensors in autonomous vehicles, he says, adding that the price of mass-produced imaging units is comparable to today’s conventional radar.</p><p>Steradian’s prototypes for intelligent transportation systems are being tested by about 20 companies. Sivadas says the company has revenue coming in from the sale of its system thanks to several partnerships it recently formed. In February the startup signed an<a href="https://roboticsandautomationnews.com/2022/02/14/visteon-partners-with-steradian-semiconductors-to-build-enhanced-advanced-driver-assistance-systems/49231/" target="_blank"> agreement</a> to work with mobility company<a href="https://www.visteon.com/" target="_blank"> Visteon</a> to produce enhanced advanced driver-assistance systems. Steradian also signed a<a href="https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/tech/technology/steradian-semiconductors-joins-hands-with-astra-microwave-products-for-traffic-monitoring-4d-imaging-radar/articleshow/89951722.cms?utm_source=contentofinterest&utm_medium=text&utm_campaign=cppst" target="_blank"> partnership deal</a> in March with <a href="https://www.astramwp.com/" target="_blank">Astra Microwave Products</a> to produce radar modules for traffic management systems.</p><h2>Former Qualcomm and Texas Instruments employee</h2><p>Sivadas has 25 years of experience in engineering R&D and management working for<a href="http://qualcomm.com" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"> Qualcomm</a> and<a href="http://ti.com" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"> Texas Instruments</a>. He holds more than 20 patents for RF technologies and integrated circuits.</p><p>He says it was an easy transition for Steradian’s founders to go from working for large tech companies to forming their own.</p><p>“We had done many of the same functions required in a large company, such as defining products and architectures, executing them, adding features ahead of the market, and hiring people and building up their capabilities,” he says. What was new for the founders, he says, was having to set up their early office themselves.</p><p>Finding qualified engineers to hire wasn’t difficult, he says, because India has many companies involved in chip design: “The talent pipeline already existed.”</p><p>As with other startups, another challenge has been raising capital. For the first three years, the company was self-funded. Steradian now has several investors, having received funding from venture capitalists and some tech companies with an interest in automotive sensing technology.</p><p>“The biggest challenge,” he says, “was getting the first set of investors to believe in us.”</p><p>On 31 August, <a href="https://www.renesas.com/us/en" target="_blank">Renesas Electronics Corp.</a>, a supplier of advanced semiconductor solutions headquartered in Tokyo, <a href="https://www.renesas.com/us/en/about/press-room/renesas-acquire-steradian-expand-its-reach-radar-market" target="_blank">announced</a> that it had entered into an agreement to acquire Steradian Semiconductors. </p><p><em>This article has been updated from an earlier version. </em></p>]]></description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Aug 2022 18:00:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spectrum.ieee.org/steradians-4d-imaging-radar</guid><category>Ieee member news</category><category>Self-driving cars</category><category>Autonomous vehicles</category><category>Intelligent transportation systems</category><category>Radar</category><category>Careers</category><category>Computer chip</category><category>Transportation</category><category>Type:ti</category><dc:creator>Kathy Pretz</dc:creator><media:content medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/hand-holding-small-computer-chip-between-the-thumb-and-forefinger.jpg?id=31300451&amp;width=980"></media:content></item><item><title>Nvidia’s CTO on the Future of High-Performance Computing</title><link>https://spectrum.ieee.org/nvidia-cto-michael-kagan-profile</link><description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/portrait-of-nvidias-cto-michael-kagan-on-a-gray-background.jpg?id=31044752&width=1245&height=700&coordinates=0%2C0%2C0%2C384"/><br/><br/><p>
	In 2019 Michael Kagan was leading the development of accelerated networking technologies as chief technology officer at 
	<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mellanox_Technologies#:~:text=Mellanox%20was%20founded%20in%20May,Udi%20Katz%20and%20Alon%20Webman." rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Mellanox Technologies</a>, which he and eight colleagues had founded two decades earlier. Then in April 2020 <a href="https://www.nvidia.com/en-us/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Nvidia</a> acquired the company for US $7 billion, and Kagan took over as CTO of that tech goliath—his dream job.
</p><p>
	Nvidia is headquartered in Santa Clara, Calif., but Kagan works out of the company’s office in Israel.
</p><hr/><p>
	At Mellanox, based in Yokneam Illit, Israel, Kagan had overseen the development of high-performance networking for computing and storage in cloud data centers. The company made networking equipment such as adapters, cables, and high-performance switches, as well as a new type of processor, the DPU. The company’s high-speed 
	<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/InfiniBand" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">InfiniBand</a> products can be found in most of the world’s fastest supercomputers, and its high-speed Ethernet products are in most cloud data centers, Kagan says.
</p><p>
	The IEEE senior member’s work is now focused on integrating a wealth of Nvidia technologies to build accelerated computing platforms, whose foundation are three chips: the GPU, the CPU, and the DPU, or data-processing unit. The DPU can support the ability to offload, accelerate, and isolate data center workloads, reducing CPU and GPU workloads.
</p><p>
	“At Mellanox we worked on the data center interconnect, but at Nvidia we are connecting state-of-the-art computing to become a single unit of computing: the data center,” Kagan says. Interconnects are used to link multiple servers and combine the entire data center into one, giant computing unit.
</p><p>
	“I have access and an open door to Nvidia technologies,” he says. “That’s what makes my life exciting and interesting. We are building the computing of the future.”
</p><h2>From Intel to Mellanox</h2><p>
	Kagan was born in St. Petersburg, Russia—then known as Leningrad. After he graduated high school in 1975, his family moved to Israel. As with many budding engineers, his curiosity led him to disassemble and reassemble things to figure out how they worked. And, with many engineers in the family, he says, pursuing an engineering career was an easy decision.
</p><p>
	He attended the 
	<a href="https://www.technion.ac.il/en/home-2/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Technion</a>, Israel’s Institute of Technology, because “it was one of the best engineering universities in the world,” he says. “The reason I picked electrical engineering is because it was considered to be the best faculty in the Technion.”
</p><p>
	Kagan graduated in 1980 with a bachelor’s degree in electrical engineering. He joined 
	<a href="https://www.intel.com/content/www/us/en/corporate-responsibility/intel-in-israel.html" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Intel</a> in Haifa, Israel, in 1983 as a design engineer and eventually relocated to the company’s offices in Hillsboro, Ore., where he worked on the 80387 floating-point coprocessor. A year later, after returning to Israel, Kagan served as an architect of the i8060XP vector processor and then led and managed design of the Pentium MMX microprocessor.
</p><p>
	During his 16 years at Intel, he worked his way up to chief architect. In 1999 he was preparing to move his family to California, where he would lead a high-profile project for the company. Then a former coworker at Intel, Eyal Waldman, asked Kagan to join him and five other acquaintances to form Mellanox.
</p><h3>About Michael Kagan</h3><br/><p>
<strong></strong><strong>Employer:</strong> Nvidia, Tel Aviv
</p><p>
<strong>Title:</strong> CTO
</p><p>
<strong>Member grade:</strong> Senior member
</p><p>
<strong>Alma mater:</strong> Technion, Israel’s Institute of Technology, Haifa</p><p>
	Kagan had been turning down offers to join startups nearly every week, he recalls, but Mellanox, with its team of cofounders and vision, drew him in. He says he saw it as a “compelling adventure, an opportunity to build a company with a culture based on the core values I grew up on: excellence, teamwork, and commitment.”
</p><p>
	During his more than 21 years there, he said, he had no regrets.
</p><p>
	“It was one of the greatest decisions I’ve ever made,” he says. “It ended up benefiting all aspects of my life: professionally, financially—everything.”
</p><p>
	InfiniBand, the startup’s breakout product, was designed for what today is known as cloud computing, Kagan says.
</p><p>
	“We took the goodies of InfiniBand and bolted them on top of the standard Ethernet,” he says. “As a result, we became the vendor of the most advanced network for high-performance computing. More than half the machines at the top 500 computer companies use the Mellanox interconnect, now the Nvidia interconnect.
</p><p>
	“Most of the cloud providers, such as 
	<a href="http://facebook.com" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Facebook</a>, <a href="https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Azure</a>, and <a href="https://www.alibaba.com/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Alibaba</a>, use Nvidia’s networking and compute technologies. No matter what you do on the Internet, you’re most likely running through the chip that we designed.”
</p><p>
	Kagan says the partnership between Mellanox and Nvidia was “natural,” as the two companies had been doing business together for nearly a decade.
</p><p>
	“We delivered quite a few innovative solutions as independent companies,” he says.
</p><p class="shortcode-media shortcode-media-rebelmouse-image">
<img alt="Nvidia\u2019s CTO Michael Kagan is an IEEE senior member." class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="140e8a20d3e09d9a3ae800a07d6d33e9" data-rm-shortcode-name="rebelmouse-image" id="0d91e" loading="lazy" src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/nvidia-u2019s-cto-michael-kagan-is-an-ieee-senior-member.jpg?id=31044758&width=980"/>
<small class="image-media media-caption" placeholder="Add Photo Caption...">One of Kagan's key priorities is Nvidia’s Bluefield DPU. The data center infrastructure on a chip offloads, accelerates, and isolates a variety of networking, storage, and security services.</small><small class="image-media media-photo-credit" placeholder="Add Photo Credit...">Nvidia</small>
</p><h2>BlueField and Omniverse supercomputers</h2><p>
	As CTO of Nvidia for the past two years, Kagan has shifted his focus from pure networking to the integration of multiple Nvidia technologies including building 
	<a href="https://www.nvidia.com/en-us/networking/products/data-processing-unit/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">BlueField</a> data-processing units and the <a href="https://www.nvidia.com/en-us/omniverse/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Omniverse</a> real-time graphics collaboration platform.
</p><p>
	He says Nvidia’s vision for the data center of the future is based on its three chips: CPU, DPU, and GPU.
</p><p>
	“These three pillars are connected with a very efficient and high-performance network that was originally developed at Mellanox and is being further developed at Nvidia,” he says.
</p><p>
	Development of the BlueField DPUs is now a key priority for Nvidia. It is a data center infrastructure on a chip, optimized for high-performance computing. It also offloads, accelerates, and isolates a variety of networking, storage, and security services.
</p><p>
	“In the data center, you have no control over who your clients are,” Kagan says. “It may very well happen that a client is a bad guy who wants to penetrate his neighbors’ or your infrastructure. You’re better off isolating yourself and other customers from each other by having a segregated or different computing platform run the operating system, which is basically the infrastructure management, the resource management, and the provisioning.”
</p><p>
	Kagan is particularly excited about the Omniverse, a new Nvidia product that uses 
	<a href="https://developer.nvidia.com/usd" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Pixar’s Universal Scene Description</a> software for creating virtual worlds—what has become known as the <a href="https://about.fb.com/news/2021/10/founders-letter/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">metaverse</a>. Kagan describes the 3D platform as “creating a world by collecting data and making a physically accurate simulation of the world.”
</p><p>
	Car manufacturers are using the Omniverse to test-drive autonomous vehicles. Instead of physically driving a car on different types of roads under various conditions, data about the virtual world can be generated to train the AI models.
</p><p>
	“You can create situations that the car has to handle in the real world but that you don’t want it to meet in the real world, like a car crash,” Kagan says. “You don’t want to crash the car to train the model, but you do need to have the model be able to handle hazardous conditions on the road.”
</p><div class="ieee-sidebar-small">
<h3>Access to IEEE Information</h3>
<p>
	Kagan joined IEEE in 1997. He says membership gives him access to information about technical topics that would otherwise be challenging to obtain.
	</p>
<p>
	“I enjoy this type of federated learning and being exposed to new things,” he says.
	</p>
<p>
	He adds that he likes connecting with members who are working on similar projects, because he always learns something new.
	</p>
<p>
	“Being connected to these people from more diverse communities helps a lot,” he says. “It inspires you to do your job in a different way.”
	</p>
</div><p>
	The Omniverse platform can generate millions of kilometers of synthetic driving data in orders of magnitude faster than actually driving the car.
</p><p>
	Nvidia is investing heavily in technology for self-driving cars, Kagan says.
</p><p>
	The company is also building what it calls the most powerful AI supercomputer for climate science: 
	<a href="https://blogs.nvidia.com/blog/2021/11/12/earth-2-supercomputer/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Earth-2</a>, a digital twin of the planet. Earth-2 is designed to continuously run models to predict climate and weather events at both the regional and global levels.
</p><p>
	Kagan says the climate modeling technology will enable people to try mitigation techniques for global warming and see what their impact is likely to be in 50 years.
</p><p>
	The company is also working closely with the health care industry to develop AI-based technologies. Its supercomputers are helping to identify cancer by generating synthetic data to enable researchers to train their models to better identify tumors. Its AI and accelerated computing products also assist with drug discovery and genome research, Kagan says.
</p><p>
	“We are actually moving forward at a fairly nice pace,” he says. “But the thing is that you always need to reinvent yourself and do the new thing faster and better, and basically win with what you have and not look for infinite resources. This is what commitment means.”
</p><p><em>This article has been updated from an earlier version.</em></p>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Aug 2022 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spectrum.ieee.org/nvidia-cto-michael-kagan-profile</guid><category>Ieee member news</category><category>Nvidia</category><category>Telecommunications</category><category>Mellanox</category><category>Intel</category><category>Gpu</category><category>Cpu</category><category>Dpu</category><category>Bluefield</category><category>Omniverse</category><category>Metaverse</category><category>Type:ti</category><dc:creator>Kathy Pretz</dc:creator><media:content medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/portrait-of-nvidias-cto-michael-kagan-on-a-gray-background.jpg?id=31044752&amp;width=980"></media:content></item><item><title>Building a Fleet of Personal EVs in Kenya</title><link>https://spectrum.ieee.org/building-a-fleet-of-personal-evs-in-kenya</link><description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/a-woman-dressed-in-a-black-t-shirt-and-blue-jeans-standing-inside-a-building-in-front-of-a-row-of-electric-bicycles.png?id=30836226&width=1245&height=700&coordinates=0%2C258%2C0%2C258"/><br/><br/><p><strong>Electric vehicles are</strong> gaining in popularity around the world, especially with the high cost of fuel. But some of the current EV models aren’t a good fit for owners who can’t wait around for hours for their batteries to charge, such as taxi drivers, delivery people, and ride-hailing services.</p><p>One startup trying to solve this problem is <a href="https://arcrideglobal.com/#/home" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">ARC Ride</a>, in Nairobi, Kenya.</p><hr/><p>Founded in 2020, the company sells a variety of EVs, including e-bikes, scooters, motorcycles, and <em>tuktuks</em>. ARC Ride is also installing battery-swapping stations around the city. The company’s app lets EV owners locate the battery-swap stations.</p><p>A key person involved in the critical tasks of assembling, servicing, and testing the company’s vehicles and related products is<a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/magdalene-maluta-8a901114b/?originalSubdomain=ke" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"> Magdalene Maluta</a>. The EV enthusiast came to the 20-employee company through the confluence of motivation, the right mix of skills, and fate.</p><p>“Before I came to ARC Ride, I had been looking into EVs [as a career choice],” Maluta says. “I would read about <a href="https://www.tesla.com/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Tesla</a> and wish I was one of the people in their videos making the vehicles.”</p><p>In March 2020, an IT firm where she was about to start a new job was shuttered because of the COVID-19 pandemic. After struggling to find a job, Maluta got a call in January 2021 from ARC Ride, offering her a position after someone had recommended her. She started with assembly and maintenance, where she learned about EVs from the ground up.</p><p>Working with electric vehicles requires mechanical and engineering expertise. Maluta has diplomas in mechanical engineering from the <a href="https://www.nita.go.ke/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">National Industrial Training Authority</a> and the <a href="http://kinyanjuitechnical.ac.ke/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">PC Kinyanjui Technical Training Institute</a>, both in Nairobi.</p><p>“My electrical engineering courses included basic electronics, programming, automation, robots, and robotics,” she says. “Applying what I learned in them has helped me solve problems in mechanical engineering and made my work easier."</p><p> As an inventory and maintenance manager, Maluta is involved in many facets of the company, including supervising the assembly of EVs, overseeing the maintenance and support teams, tracking inventory, and helping test new features on the mobile app. She is also helping to design and develop the company’s next generation of vehicles, batteries, and swap stations.</p><p> ARC Ride offers four types of EVs. The E1 is an electric bicycle with a battery range of 60 kilometers and up to 65 km with pedal assist. With the throttle, the top speed is 60 km/h, and with pedaling added, it can get up to 65 km/h. The E2 is a two-wheel scooter with a battery range of 85 km and a top speed of 60 km/h. The E2+ all-electric motorcycle—called a <em>boda-boda—</em>can accommodate two batteries and gets a range of 85 km with one battery and 160 km with two. Its top speed is 75 km/h. The E3, a three-wheeled <em>tuktuk</em> motorized rickshaw, can carry up to 500 kilograms of goods and has a range of 80 km. </p><p class="pull-quote">“You have to have the drive and passion for this kind of work, and you need to show it. Do not doubt yourself.”</p><p>Each vehicle includes a charger. Recharging a depleted battery takes less than 4 hours, Maluta says. As an alternative, owners can exchange their nearly discharged battery at the company’s battery-swap stations for a fully charged one. It takes about 2 minutes to complete a battery swap, Maluta says.</p><p>The startup has aggressive plans to add more models and increase production and sales to about 500 vehicles per month, along with adding more swap stations, she says. ARC Ride recently received an order for parts to assemble 120 E2+ motorcycles. It also has plans to expand to other cities in Kenya as well as neighboring countries in East Africa.</p><p> “We are looking into having a single battery that can be used in all four of our current EVs, which will make our swap stations even more useful,” she says. “Also, we are looking into increasing our vehicles’ range and speed. We want to add regenerative braking, which converts braking energy into electricity that goes back into the battery. And—like all EV makers—we want faster battery charging.” </p><p> Part of her job is testing scooters and e-bikes around the city, for performance, top speed, braking, and range. “When we do maintenance or service on one, I test each vehicle’s performance personally,” she says.</p><p>Maluta also has a hand in hiring people and looks for specific skills. “To design and develop EV products, you have to be able to use tools like AutoCAD, Autodesk, and SolidWorks. And you can’t do that without an engineering background.” </p><p>ARC Ride is committed to diversity in its hiring, and Maluta works hard to hire more women for her team. But, she emphasizes, “You have to have the drive and passion for this kind of work, and you need to show it. Do not doubt yourself. Your identity should be the last thing that is going to limit you.”</p><p><em>This article appears in the September 2022 print issue as “Magdalene Maluta.”</em></p>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Aug 2022 15:14:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spectrum.ieee.org/building-a-fleet-of-personal-evs-in-kenya</guid><category>Electric vehicles</category><category>Ev</category><category>Ev batteries</category><category>Profile</category><category>Startups</category><category>Transportation</category><category>Type:departments</category><category>Careers</category><dc:creator>Daniel P. Dern</dc:creator><media:content medium="image" type="image/png" url="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/a-woman-dressed-in-a-black-t-shirt-and-blue-jeans-standing-inside-a-building-in-front-of-a-row-of-electric-bicycles.png?id=30836226&amp;width=980"></media:content></item><item><title>Emmy Award Winner’s Algorithms Bring High-Quality Video to Your TV</title><link>https://spectrum.ieee.org/alan-bovik-profile</link><description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/portrait-of-alan-bovik.jpg?id=30849849&width=1245&height=700&coordinates=0%2C0%2C0%2C469"/><br/><br/><p><a href="https://ethw.org/Alan_Conrad_Bovik" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Alan Conrad Bovik</a>’s passion for science fiction inspired him to pursue a career in engineering. His favorite sci-fi authors when he was young were <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Arthur_C._Clarke" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Arthur C. Clarke</a>, who penned <em>2001: A Space Odyssey,</em> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Isaac_Asimov" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Isaac Asimov</a>, author of the Foundation series. Bovik says they wrote from a “very scientific point of view”—which made him want to help develop aerospace technology that would send humans “to other worlds.”</p><p>But he decided to study nuclear engineering in school—which then seemed like the future of energy. He discovered, however, that he didn't like the subject because it “required too much chemistry and memorization,” he says with a laugh. When he took a course in computer programming, he fell in love with it and ended up changing his major to computer engineering.</p><hr/><p>While pursuing a Ph.D. at the <a href="https://illinois.edu/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">University of Illinois Urbana-Champaign,</a> Bovik found his calling: digital image processing. It is a technology, he says, that back then didn’t have many applications and seemed like something out of a sci-fi novel. </p><p>The IEEE Fellow has since done groundbreaking work in the field.</p><p>He created theoretical models of how people will perceive the quality of an image or video after it has been compressed. He has used the models to develop algorithms that automatically measure picture quality.</p><h3>ABOUT ALAN BOVIK</h3><br/><p>
<strong>Employer:</strong> University of Texas
</p><p>
<strong>Title:</strong> Professor of engineering
</p><p>
<strong>Member grade: </strong>Fellow
</p><p>
<strong>Alma mater: </strong>University of Illinois
</p><p>
<strong>What TV shows or movies have you watched and enjoyed recently?</strong> “The Vikings” and “The Last Kingdom”
</p><p>
<strong>What book would you recommend to others?</strong> <em>The Fifth Season</em> by N.K. Jemisin
</p><p><strong>If you weren’t an engineer, what would be your job?</strong> Neuroscientist or cinematographer</p><p>Programs he helped develop include the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Structural_similarity" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Structural SIMilarity</a> (SSIM) index, the MOtion-tuned Video Integrity Evaluation (<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/MOVIE_Index" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">MOVIE</a>) index, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Visual_Information_Fidelity" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">visual information fidelity</a> algorithms, and the Video Multimethod Assessment Fusion (<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/VMAF" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">VMAF</a>) metric. His video quality prediction technology is used by streaming services, broadcasting companies, movie studios, and technology companies worldwide. </p><p>Bovik has received several awards for his work. The <a href="https://www.emmys.com/academy" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Academy of Television Arts and Sciences</a> honored him in 2015 with a <a href="http://live.ece.utexas.edu/emmy_award.php#:~:text=Professor%20Al%20Bovik%20and%20two,Development%20from%20the%20Television%20Academy." rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Primetime Emmy for Outstanding Achievement in Engineering Development</a> and with a 2020 <a href="https://theemmys.tv/tech/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Technology and Engineering Emmy</a>. IEEE recognized Bovik with this year’s <a href="https://corporate-awards.ieee.org/award/ieee-edison-medal/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Edison Medal</a> “for pioneering high-impact scientific and engineering contributions leading to the perceptually optimized global streaming and sharing of visual media.” The award is sponsored by <a href="https://www.samsung.com/us/aboutsamsung/home/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Samsung Electronics Co.</a></p><p>“The IEEE Edison Medal is the most important award I’ve received,” he says, “because of its history, the amazing past recipients, and because it’s from my peers.”</p><p>For nearly 40 years, he has been a professor of electrical and computer engineering at the <a href="https://www.utexas.edu/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">University of Texas</a> <a href="https://cockrell.utexas.edu/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Cockrell School of Engineering</a>, in Austin. He serves as director of Cockrell’s <a href="https://live.ece.utexas.edu/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Laboratory for Image and Video Engineering</a>, where graduate students and faculty members develop psychometric databases, theories, and algorithms to advance modern perceptual video processing technologies.</p><p>Bovik says he plans to remain at the university for another 40 years because “being an educator and video research is the best.”</p><p>“I didn't really know how much I would enjoy the academic experience until I started teaching,” he says. </p><h2>Developing the SSIM index</h2><p>At the University of Illinois, Bovik took a class on digital image processing taught by <a href="https://ethw.org/Oral-History:Thomas_Huang" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Thomas Huang</a>, a professor of electrical and computer engineering. The IEEE Life Fellow was a pioneer in computer vision, image processing, and image compression. </p><p>Bovik enjoyed the course so much that he joined Huang’s <a href="http://ifp-uiuc.github.io/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Image Formation and Processing Group</a>, part of the university’s <a href="https://beckman.illinois.edu/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Beckman Institute for Advanced Science and Technology</a>. The group conducted research in image and video coding, computer vision, pattern recognition, and machine learning. The professor became one of Bovik’s doctoral advisors. Bovik’s research focused on nonlinear statistical methods for image analysis and enhancement.</p><p>Huang suggested that Bovik consider applying for a job at the University of Texas after he graduated because he thought “it had a great future.” Bovik took his mentor’s advice and moved to Texas in 1984 to work for the Austin school as an assistant professor.</p><p>Bovik soon became interested in visual neuroscience and how it could be applied to video engineering. He spoke with several visual neuroscientists and visual psychologists to gain a better understanding of the brain’s visual cortex, which receives, integrates, and processes visual information. Bovik and his team of researchers created mathematical models of the visual cortex as well as the retina, which converts light into neural signals and sends them to the brain.</p><p class="pull-quote">“The IEEE Edison Medal is the most significant award I’ve received because it’s an award from my peers.”</p><p>In the early 2000s, he began studying how people perceive distortions—such as blurring, resizing, and noise—in pictures and videos, as video compression was becoming important because of digital television.</p><p>Video images take up a lot of space, and because bandwidth is limited, videos generally need to be compressed before being distributed. But the process can distort the images, causing people to perceive them as blurry or jagged. At the time, there was no program that could accurately predict how badly the images would be distorted before they were distributed, Bovik says, because the algorithms in use didn’t account for how people perceive the images. </p><p>Using the mathematical models he and his team previously developed, they created computational algorithms that accurately gauged the way humans would see distortions in compressed images. </p><p class="shortcode-media shortcode-media-rebelmouse-image">
<img alt="portrait of 3 people on a step and repeat background with edison medal" class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="66428339401d6aee0202e054597ead70" data-rm-shortcode-name="rebelmouse-image" id="32558" loading="lazy" src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/portrait-of-3-people-on-a-step-and-repeat-background-with-edison-medal.jpg?id=30849889&width=980"/>
<small class="image-media media-caption" placeholder="Add Photo Caption...">Bovik with IEEE President Ray Liu [left] and President-Elect Saifur Rahman at the IEEE Honors Ceremony held in San Diego in May.</small><small class="image-media media-photo-credit" placeholder="Add Photo Credit...">Alan Bovik</small></p><p>Bovik says the key to creating the algorithms was understanding how people process visual information when they first see an image.</p><p>“If an image is blurry, you don't have to think about it,” he says. “You sense that it’s blurry instantly.”</p><p>In 2001 he and his team developed SSIM. The program predicts how people will perceive a compressed image on a screen by measuring three factors: luminance masking (distortion visibility depending on an image’s brightness), contrast masking (distortion visibility depending on an image’s texture), and structural similarity.</p><p>If SSIM predicts an image will appear distorted, the errors can be fixed before the image is shared.</p><p>The algorithm has since become part of the <a href="https://www.itu.int/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">International Telecommunication Union</a>’s<a href="https://nisp.nw3.dk/standard/itu-t-h.264.html" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"> H.264 video coding reference software standard</a>. The standard allows streaming services, broadcasting companies, and technology companies to include the program in their products and services.</p><h2>Preparing for the metaverse</h2><p>Bovik continues to develop algorithms for image processing and video quality assessment. He and his team are working with<a href="https://about.facebook.com/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"> Meta</a>’s<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Reality_Labs" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"> Reality Labs</a> to develop an algorithm to be used in the metaverse, a <a href="https://about.fb.com/news/2021/10/founders-letter/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">simulated “embodied internet”</a> experienced in 3D, as defined by Meta founder <a href="https://www.forbes.com/profile/mark-zuckerberg/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Mark Zuckerberg</a>. Virtual and augmented reality will let users feel as if they can move through space at will and pick up objects with ease, Zuckerberg says.</p><p class="pull-quote">“Back in 1991, when we formed <em>Transactions</em>, not many people understood image processing. It seemed like something out of a science-fiction novel. But things have changed, and now it’s everywhere.”</p><p>“Nobody can predict how quickly the metaverse will be upon us,” Bovik says, “but it introduces all kinds of new challenges that are related to visual neuroscience.” The metaverse will require high-resolution images, he says, because the viewer’s eyes are centimeters away from the augmented-reality technology displays.</p><p>By developing perception-based algorithms, Bovik says, he hopes to “perceptually optimize the way videos are transmitted, compressed, and displayed in VR and AR.” </p><h2>Image processing at IEEE</h2><p>Bovik says he joined IEEE as a student member so he could access the organization’s journals. Maintaining that access is why he continues to be a member, he says.</p><p>He frequently attends IEEE conferences, where he has met engineers who have become his lifelong friends and mentors, he says. He often brings his students along. “I used to call the opportunity to go to a conference with me the <em>Alan Bovik Motivational System</em>,” he says, laughing.</p><p>Because he believed that image processing was going to have “a great feature,” he says, he helped launch the <a href="https://2022.ieeeicip.org/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">IEEE International Conference on Image Processing</a> and the <a href="https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/RecentIssue.jsp?punumber=83" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"><em>IEEE Transactions on Image Processing</em></a>. He is the publication’s longest-serving editor-in-chief.</p><p>“When I helped form <em>Transactions </em>in 1991, not many people understood the future applications of image processing,” Bovik says. “The technology seemed like something out of a science-fiction novel, but now it’s everywhere.”</p>]]></description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Aug 2022 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spectrum.ieee.org/alan-bovik-profile</guid><category>Ieee member news</category><category>Profiles</category><category>Image processing</category><category>Video compression</category><category>Type:ti</category><dc:creator>Joanna Goodrich</dc:creator><media:content medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/portrait-of-alan-bovik.jpg?id=30849849&amp;width=980"></media:content></item><item><title>Navigating the Great Resignation and Changing Client Demands</title><link>https://discover.clarivate.com/staffingwebinar?campaignname=Great_Resignation_LeadGen_Webinar_Aug09_IPG_Global_2022&amp;campaignid=7014N000002CcBu&amp;utm_campaign=Great_Resignation_LeadGen_Webinar_Aug09_IPG_Global_2022_IEEE&amp;utm_</link><description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/image.png?id=27150766&width=980"/><br/><br/><p>With IP law firms under increasing pressure to meet client expectations faster and more efficiently, many practices are turning to creative workflow solutions and new staffing models. <a href="https://discover.clarivate.com/staffingwebinar?campaignname=Great_Resignation_LeadGen_Webinar_Aug09_IPG_Global_2022&campaignid=7014N000002CcBu&utm_campaign=Great_Resignation_LeadGen_Webinar_Aug09_IPG_Global_2022_IEEE&utm_" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Register now for this free webinar.</a></p><hr/><p>Join us for the upcoming webinar, <a href="https://discover.clarivate.com/staffingwebinar?campaignname=Great_Resignation_LeadGen_Webinar_Aug09_IPG_Global_2022&campaignid=7014N000002CcBu&utm_campaign=Great_Resignation_LeadGen_Webinar_Aug09_IPG_Global_2022_IEEE&utm_" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Driving IP Law firm growth amidst staffing and market challenges</a>, as our in-house experts, with combined 40+ years of industry knowledge, share key learnings from the experiences of our IP law firm customers, including the considerations for getting it right and ensuring quality outcomes.</p><p>Topics that will be covered:</p><ul><li>Finding a right-fit resourcing balance: when to outsource vs. keeping in-house</li><li>Common pitfalls to avoid</li><li>Key learnings and strategies for firms to manage resourcing successfully</li></ul><div></div><div><a href="https://discover.clarivate.com/staffingwebinar?campaignname=Great_Resignation_LeadGen_Webinar_Aug09_IPG_Global_2022&campaignid=7014N000002CcBu&utm_campaign=Great_Resignation_LeadGen_Webinar_Aug09_IPG_Global_2022_IEEE&utm_" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Register now for this free webinar.</a></div>]]></description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2022 14:47:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://discover.clarivate.com/staffingwebinar?campaignname=Great_Resignation_LeadGen_Webinar_Aug09_IPG_Global_2022&amp;campaignid=7014N000002CcBu&amp;utm_campaign=Great_Resignation_LeadGen_Webinar_Aug09_IPG_Global_2022_IEEE&amp;utm_</guid><category>Intellectual property</category><category>Clarivate</category><category>Type:webinar</category><dc:creator>Clarivate</dc:creator><media:content medium="image" type="image/png" url="https://assets.rbl.ms/27150766/origin.png"></media:content></item><item><title>Turing Award Winner On His Pioneering Algorithms</title><link>https://spectrum.ieee.org/2021-turing-award-winner</link><description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/man-in-blue-sweater-posing-in-front-of-a-white-board.jpg?id=30298777&width=1245&height=700&coordinates=0%2C0%2C0%2C205"/><br/><br/><p>
<a href="https://netlib3.cs.utk.edu/utk/people/JackDongarra/index.html" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Jack Dongarra</a>’s dream job growing up was to teach science at a public high school in Chicago.
</p><p>
	“I was pretty good in math and science, but I wasn’t a particularly good student,” Dongarra says, laughing.
</p><p>
	After he graduated high school, there was only one university he wanted to attend:<a href="https://www.csu.edu/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"> Chicago State</a>. That’s because, he says, it was known for “churning out teachers.” Chicago State accepted his application, and he decided to major in mathematics.
</p><hr/><p>
	His physics professor suggested that Dongarra apply for an internship at the<a href="https://www.anl.gov/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"> Argonne National Laboratory</a>, in Lemont, Ill., a nearby U.S. <a href="https://www.energy.gov/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Department of Energy</a> science and engineering research center. For 16 weeks he worked with a group of researchers designing and developing<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/EISPACK" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"> EISPACK</a>, a package of Fortran routines that compute the eigenvalues and eigenvectors of matrices—calculations common in scientific computing.
</p><p>
	Dongarra acknowledges he didn’t have a background in or knowledge of eigenvalues and eigenvectors—or of linear algebra—but he loved what he was doing. The experience at Argonne, he says, was transformative. He had found his passion.
</p><p>
	“I thought it was a cool thing to do,” he says, “so I kept pursuing it.”
</p><h3>About Jack Dongarra</h3><br/><p><strong></strong><strong>Employer: </strong>University of Tennessee, Knoxville</p><p><strong>Title: </strong>Professor emeritus, computer science</p><p><strong>Member grade: </strong>Life Fellow</p><p><strong>Alma mater: </strong>Chicago State University</p><p>
	The IEEE Life Fellow has since made pioneering contributions to numerical algorithms and libraries for linear algebra, which allowed software to make good use of high-performance hardware. His open-source software libraries are used in just about every computer, from laptops to the world’s fastest supercomputers.
</p><p>
	The libraries include basic linear algebra subprograms (<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Basic_Linear_Algebra_Subprograms" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">BLAS</a>), the linear-algebra package <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/LAPACK" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">LAPACK</a>, parallel virtual machines (<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Parallel_Virtual_Machine" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">PVMs</a>), automatically tuned linear algebra software (<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Automatically_Tuned_Linear_Algebra_Software" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">ATLAS</a>), and the high-performance conjugate gradient <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/HPCG_benchmark" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">(HPCG)</a> benchmark.
</p><p>
	For his work, he was honored this year with the 2021<a href="https://amturing.acm.org/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"> A.M. Turing Award</a> from the<a href="https://www.acm.org/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"> Association for Computing Machinery</a>. He received US $1 million as part of the award, which is known as the Nobel Prize of computing.
</p><p>
			“When I think about previous Turing Award recipients, I’m humbled to think about what I’ve learned from their books and papers,” Dongarra says. “Their programming languages, theorems, techniques, and standards have helped me develop my algorithms.
		</p><p>
			“It’s a tremendous honor to be this year’s recipient. The award is a recognition by the computer-science community that the contributions we are making in high-performance computing are important and have an impact in the broader computer-science community and science in general.”
		</p><p>
			Dongarra didn’t end up teaching science to high school students. Instead, he became a professor of electrical engineering and computer science at the<a href="https://www.utk.edu/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"> University of Tennessee</a> in Knoxville, where he taught for 33 years. The university recently named him professor emeritus.
		</p><h2>Entrepreneurial Spirit</h2><p>
	After graduating from Chicago State in 1972 with a bachelor’s degree in mathematics, Dongarra went on to pursue a master’s degree in computer science at the<a href="https://www.iit.edu/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"> Illinois Institute of Technology</a>, also in Chicago. While there he worked one day a week for Argonne with the same team of researchers. After he got his degree in 1973, the lab hired him full time as a researcher.
</p><p>
	With encouragement from his colleagues to pursue a Ph.D., he left the lab to study applied mathematics at the<a href="https://www.unm.edu/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"> University of New Mexico</a> in Albuquerque. He honed his knowledge of linear algebra there and began working out algorithms and writing software.
</p><p>
	He returned to Argonne after getting his doctorate in 1980 and worked there as a senior scientist until 1989, when he got the opportunity to fulfill his dream of teaching.
</p><p>
	He was offered a joint position teaching computer science at the University of Tennessee and conducting research at the nearby<a href="https://www.ornl.gov/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"> Oak Ridge National Laboratory</a> which, like Argonne, is a Department of Energy facility.
</p><p>
	“It was time for me to try out some new things,” he says. “I was ready to try my hand at academia.”
</p><p>
	He says Oak Ridge operated in a similar way to Argonne, and the culture there was more or less the same.
</p><p>
	“The challenge,” he says, “was becoming a university professor.”
</p><p class="pull-quote">"The Turing Award is a recognition by the computer science community that the contributions we are making in high-performance computing are important, and have an impact in the broader computer science community and science in general.”</p><p>University culture is very different from that at a government laboratory, he says, but he quickly fell into the rhythm of the academic setting.
</p><p>
	Although he loved teaching, he says, he also was attracted to the opportunity the university gave its instructors to work on technology they are passionate about.
</p><p>
	“You follow your own path and course of research,” he says. “I’ve prospered in that environment. I interact with smart people, I have the ability to travel around the world, and I have collaborations going on with people in many countries.
</p><p>
	“Academia gives you this freedom to do things and not be constrained by a company’s drive or its motivation. Rather, I get to work on what motivates me. That’s why I’ve stayed in academia for so many years.”
</p><p class="shortcode-media shortcode-media-rebelmouse-image">
<img alt="Man with glasses and checkered shirt sitting in front of a Tektronix computer." class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="f75ef322062e4ffb0960422014ccfa71" data-rm-shortcode-name="rebelmouse-image" id="cb1e5" loading="lazy" src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/man-with-glasses-and-checkered-shirt-sitting-in-front-of-a-tektronix-computer.jpg?id=30298837&width=980"/>
<small class="image-media media-caption" placeholder="Add Photo Caption...">In 1980, Dongarra worked as a senior scientist at Argonne National Laboratory, in Lemont, Ill.</small><small class="image-media media-photo-credit" placeholder="Add Photo Credit...">Jack Dongarra</small></p><p>
	Dongarra founded the university’s<a href="https://www.icl.utk.edu/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"> Innovative Computing Laboratory</a>, whose mission is to provide tools for high-performance computing to the scientific community. He also directs the school’s <a href="https://citr.utk.edu/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Center for Information Technology Research</a>.
</p><p>
	He is now a distinguished researcher at Oak Ridge, which he calls “a wonderful place, with its state-of-the-art equipment and the latest computers.”
</p><h2>Software for Supercomputers</h2><p>
	It was working in creative environments that led Dongarra to come up with what many describe as world-changing software libraries, which have contributed to the growth of high-performance computing in many areas including artificial intelligence, data analytics, genomics, and health care.
</p><p>
	“The libraries we designed have basic components that are needed in many areas of science so that users can draw on those components to help them solve their computational problems,” he says. “That software is portable and efficient. It has all the attributes that we want in terms of being understandable and providing reliable results.”
</p><p>
	He’s currently working on creating a software library for the world’s fastest supercomputer, <a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/frontier-exascale-supercomputer" target="_self">Frontier</a>, which recently was installed at the Oak Ridge lab. It is the first computer that can process more than 1 quintillion operations per second.
</p><h2>Computer-Science Recognition</h2><p>
	Dongarra has been an IEEE member for more than 30 years.
</p><p>
	“I enjoy interacting with the community,” he says in explaining why he continues to belong. “Also I enjoy reading <em>IEEE Spectrum</em> and journals that are relevant to my specific field.”
</p><p>
	He has served as an editor for several IEEE journals including <a href="https://proceedingsoftheieee.ieee.org/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"><em>Proceedings of the IEEE</em></a>, <a href="https://www.computer.org/csdl/journal/ca" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"><em>IEEE Computer Architecture Letters</em></a>, and <a href="https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/RecentIssue.jsp?punumber=71" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"><em>IEEE Transactions on Parallel and Distributed Systems</em></a>.
</p><p>
	Dongarra says he’s a big promoter of IEEE meetings and workshops, especially the<a href="https://sc22.supercomputing.org/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"> International Conference for High Performance Computing, Networking, Storage, and Analysis</a>, sponsored by ACM and the<a href="http://computer.org" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"> IEEE Computer Society</a>, of which he is a member. He’s been attending the event every year since 1988. He has won many awards at the conference for his papers.
</p><p>
	“That conference is really a homecoming for the high-performance computing community,” he says, “and IEEE plays a major role.”
</p><p>
	IEEE is proud of Dongarra’s contributions to computing and has honored him over the years. In 2008 he received the first<a href="http://www.ieee-tcsc.org/achievement.php" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"> IEEE Medal of Excellence in Scalable Computing</a>. He also received the 2020 <a href="https://www.eecs.utk.edu/jack-dongarra-selected-to-receive-the-2020-ieee-computer-societys-computer-pioneer-award/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Computer Pioneer Award</a>, the 2013<a href="https://awards.acm.org/kennedy/award-winners" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"> ACM/IEEE Ken Kennedy Award</a>, the 2011<a href="https://www.computer.org/volunteering/awards/babbage" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"> IEEE Charles Babbage Award</a> and the 2003<a href="https://www.sighpc.org/celebrate/sid-fernbach-award" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"> Sidney Fernbach Award</a>.
</p><p>
	“I’m very happy and proud to be a member of IEEE,” he says. “I think it provides a valuable service to the community.”
</p>]]></description><pubDate>Wed, 27 Jul 2022 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spectrum.ieee.org/2021-turing-award-winner</guid><category>Ieee member news</category><category>Supercomputers</category><category>Careers</category><category>Ieee computer society</category><category>Awards</category><category>High-performance computing</category><category>Computing</category><category>Computers</category><category>Software</category><category>Software libraries</category><category>Type:ti</category><dc:creator>Kathy Pretz</dc:creator><media:content medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/man-in-blue-sweater-posing-in-front-of-a-white-board.jpg?id=30298777&amp;width=980"></media:content></item><item><title>Sustainable Weather Balloon Wins Student a $10,000 Scholarship</title><link>https://spectrum.ieee.org/2022-ieee-presidents-scholarship-recipients</link><description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/four-females-and-one-male-holding-certificates-are-pictured-in-front-of-a-banner-that-says-isef.jpg?id=30155006&width=1245&height=700&coordinates=0%2C0%2C0%2C312"/><br/><br/><p>Every day thousands of weather balloons are released all over the world, using radiosondes to measure pressure, relative humidity, and temperature. The balloons aren’t environmentally friendly, though, in part because they’re made out of nonrecyclable materials such as latex. Also, there’s a lot of waste.</p><p>After a few hours in the air, a weather balloon bursts and its radiosonde falls to the ground via a parachute. Out of the 75,000 radiosondes launched every year in the United States, only 20 percent are found and returned, according to the <a href="https://www.weather.gov/bmx/kidscorner_weatherballoons#:~:text=About%2020%25%20of%20the%2075%2C000,of%20data%20above%20the%20ground" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">National Weather Service</a>. The cost of replacing them adds up. </p><hr/><p>Amon Schumann, a senior at the <a href="https://www.robert-havemann-gymnasium.de/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Robert-Havemann-Gymnasium</a> school, in Berlin, has invented eco-friendly, cost-effective solutions.</p><p class="shortcode-media shortcode-media-rebelmouse-image rm-resized-container rm-resized-container-25 rm-float-left" data-rm-resized-container="25%" style="float: left;">
<img alt="A young man holding a device called a radiosonde" class="rm-shortcode rm-resized-image" data-rm-shortcode-id="90b7fd0ff78d3965413f226539feef5e" data-rm-shortcode-name="rebelmouse-image" id="863e5" loading="lazy" src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/a-young-man-holding-a-device-called-a-radiosonde.jpg?id=30155174&width=980" style="max-width: 100%"/>
<small class="image-media media-caption" placeholder="Add Photo Caption...">Amon Schumann’s radiosonde for weather balloons is equipped with a solar-powered battery and GPS.</small><small class="image-media media-photo-credit" placeholder="Add Photo Credit...">Lynn Bowlby</small></p><p>Schumann built a coin-size, solar-powered radiosonde that weighs 4.8 grams—far more compact than current models, which weigh about 96 g. The weather balloon he designed can stay in the air longer than traditional models as well. </p><p>His <a href="https://projectboard.world/isef/finalist-booth/etsd005---small-radiosondes-on-a-great-mission" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Small Radiosondes on a Great Mission</a> project was showcased in May at the <a href="https://www.societyforscience.org/isef/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Regeneron International Science and Engineering Fair</a> held in Atlanta.</p><p>At a special awards ceremony, Schumann was caught by surprise when it was announced that his project received the <a href="https://www.ieee.org/education/preuniversity/scholarship.html" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">IEEE Presidents’ Scholarship</a>. The award was established by the <a href="https://www.ieeefoundation.org/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">IEEE Foundation</a> to acknowledge a deserving student for a project that demonstrates an understanding of electrical or electronics engineering, computer science, or other IEEE field of interest. The scholarship is administered on behalf of <a href="https://www.ieee.org/education/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">IEEE Educational Activities</a> and is payable over four years of undergraduate university study. Schumann also received a complimentary IEEE student membership. <a href="https://susankathyland.com/" target="_blank">Susan K. “Kathy” Land</a>, the 2021 IEEE president, presented Schumann with this year’s scholarship.</p><p class="pull-quote">“In comparison to launching 2,000 to 5,000 balloons that stay up for just two to three hours, my balloon can stay up in the air for 52 days.” </p><p>Schumann was motivated to improve radiosondes and weather balloons during a visit to a local meteorology museum. There he learned that radiosondes have not significantly changed in the past 100 years.</p><p><strong>Environmentally Friendly</strong></p><p>Because of the increase in air pressure at high altitudes, weather balloons burst at around 35 kilometers. To address the problem, Schumann used layers of foil welded together, plus a heated Teflon wheel, to create a balloon that is able to withstand higher altitudes.</p><p>“In comparison to launching 2,000 to 5,000 balloons that stay up for just two to three hours, my balloon can stay up in the air for 52 days, so fewer balloons have to be launched,” he says. </p><p>His radiosonde provides several times more measurement data per day compared with traditional ones launched every two weeks. The radiosondes are equipped with a solar-powered battery, which is about 20 grams lighter than a lithium battery.</p><p>Schumann also developed an extension module with a camera to record additional data such as cloud formation.</p><p>“The camera can take aerial images of the clouds,” he says, “which allows for a more accurate view of their formation and connections in comparison to a traditional radar system.” </p><p>He added GPS to track his radiosonde in real time. The radiosonde’s location is uploaded to his <a href="https://do4as.github.io/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">balloon flight tracker</a>, which he hopes will be of use to those needing weather data.</p><p>The software he designed allows for the radio weather data packets to be transmitted in real time from his radiosonde to an analysis unit in his home. The data is then sent to the <a href="https://www.weather.gov/cle/CWOP" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Citizen Weather Observer Program</a>, a volunteer-based network. From there it’s forwarded to the <a href="https://www.noaa.gov/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration</a> for possible use in general weather forecasting.</p><p>Schumann says he plans to study electrical engineering at a technical university in Berlin.</p><p><strong>Brain-Computer Interface</strong></p><p>This year’s second-place recipient was Navya Ramakrishnan, a senior at<a href="https://www.pisd.edu/pshs" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"> Plano Senior High School</a>, in Texas. Her <a href="https://projectboard.world/isef/finalist-booth/soft016---bci-based-home-automation-system" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">interface</a> uses brain signals to complete household tasks such as turning on a television. </p><p>Ramakrishnan’s brain-computer interface was designed for people with paralysis and neuromuscular disorders including amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. She says her inspiration came from the machine Steven Hawking built that used his eye movements to communicate.</p><p>“That was definitely the starting point, when I thought about a way to have a universal communication-aid machine for ALS patients,” Ramakrishnan says. Instead of using eye movements, she used brain waves measured by an EEG headset to gauge activity.</p><p class="shortcode-media shortcode-media-rebelmouse-image rm-resized-container rm-resized-container-25 rm-float-left" data-rm-resized-container="25%" style="float: left;">
<img alt="A female student wearing a lanyard identifying her as a finalist at ISEF." class="rm-shortcode rm-resized-image" data-rm-shortcode-id="71a2aa8f8dc8c13d2d1bde612376f193" data-rm-shortcode-name="rebelmouse-image" id="c034a" loading="lazy" src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/a-female-student-wearing-a-lanyard-identifying-her-as-a-finalist-at-isef.jpg?id=30155203&width=980" style="max-width: 100%"/>
<small class="image-media media-caption" placeholder="Add Photo Caption...">Second-place recipient Navya Ramakrishnan designed a brain-computer interface to help those with paralysis and neuromuscular disorders do household tasks such as turning on a television. </small><small class="image-media media-photo-credit" placeholder="Add Photo Credit...">Lynn Bowlby</small></p><p>She discovered that a spike in the EEG data, a P300 signal, occurs in reaction to an event. Using a computer monitor, she created a visual display of commonly used home-automation command phrases. The BCI system is connected with the home’s circuit, which controls lights, appliances, and more. The command is performed via wireless transmission to the part of the circuit in control of that task.<br/></p><p>When users see their desired command flash on the monitor, they count in their head until it stops—which triggers a reaction and creates a P300 signal. The BCI system pinpoints which command lit up at the time the signal occurred. </p><p>“Let’s say the user wants to turn on a light. Every time that ‘Light on’ command flashes on the screen I ask them to count in their head,” she explains. “The counting will generate that ‘Oh, there’s the <em>light on</em> command,’ reaction, and it will generate that spike in the EEG data. </p><p>“Essentially what my system does,” she says, “is ask, ‘Where did those P300 signals occur?’ Because where they occur means the user just reacted to the command that flashed on the screen.”</p><p>Ramakrishnan said she will be attending <a href="https://www.harvard.edu/" target="_blank">Harvard </a>this year to pursue a degree in computer science with a concentration in mind, brain, and behavior. </p><p><strong>Detecting Leukemia</strong></p><p>Adelle Jia Xin Yong, a junior at <a href="https://whs.eanesisd.net/" target="_blank">Westlake High School</a> in Austin, Texas, was awarded third place for her <a href="https://projectboard.world/isef/finalist-booth/enbm023---smart-leukemia-labs" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Smart Leukemia Labs</a> project. Her portable microscope and diagnostic tool accurately and quickly detects acute lymphoblastic leukemia.</p><p class="shortcode-media shortcode-media-rebelmouse-image rm-resized-container rm-resized-container-25 rm-float-left" data-rm-resized-container="25%" style="float: left;">
<img alt="A female student holding a black portable microscope and diagnostic tool." class="rm-shortcode rm-resized-image" data-rm-shortcode-id="d2a66b88b00c595353c9453906a5ff21" data-rm-shortcode-name="rebelmouse-image" id="fe205" loading="lazy" src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/a-female-student-holding-a-black-portable-microscope-and-diagnostic-tool.jpg?id=30155240&width=980" style="max-width: 100%"/>
<small class="image-media media-caption" placeholder="Add Photo Caption...">Adelle Jia Xin Yong was awarded third place for her portable microscope and diagnostic tool that accurately and quickly detects acute lymphoblastic leukemia from a drop of blood.</small><small class="image-media media-photo-credit" placeholder="Add Photo Credit...">Lynn Bowlby</small></p><p>The invention is compatible with smartphones. An attachment magnifies a drop of blood on a 0.5-millimeter glass slide up to 1,000 times. An app that uses object detection, image recognition, and semantic segmentation identifies abnormal blood cells to diagnose leukemia.</p><p>Yong says her invention combines her passion for helping the community and improving access to health care.</p><p>“In seventh grade I had a friend who unfortunately had leukemia,” she says. “As I saw her go through the treatments, I wondered how people who didn’t have access to the technology she had were able to obtain treatments or even a diagnosis.” </p><p>Yong’s diagnostic tool is targeted at those living in underserved regions. It costs about US $28 to make and uses low-cost materials, most of which can be found around the home, such as a metal pin and a tiny plastic tube. </p><p>When Yong heard her name called at the fair, she was shocked, she says.</p><p>“ISEF is a really big thing,” she says. “I was happy with my invention, but I didn’t know I would win something. I am just absolutely thrilled.” </p><p>Yong’s father introduced her to engineering. In 2020 she taught herself how to code by watching <a href="https://www.youtube.com/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">YouTube</a> videos.</p><p>She founded GStar, a club at her high school that is focused on empowering women in science, technology, engineering, and math fields.</p><p>She says she hopes to attend medical school and become a doctor. Her goal is to turn her patented prototype into a viable product with the help of manufacturers and labs.</p>]]></description><pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2022 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spectrum.ieee.org/2022-ieee-presidents-scholarship-recipients</guid><category>Ieee news</category><category>Stem</category><category>Ieee presidents’ scholarship</category><category>Ieee educational activities</category><category>Ieee foundation</category><category>Education</category><category>Students</category><category>Weather balloon</category><category>Brain computer interface</category><category>Bci diagnostic tool</category><category>Type:ti</category><dc:creator>Amanda Weissman</dc:creator><media:content medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/four-females-and-one-male-holding-certificates-are-pictured-in-front-of-a-banner-that-says-isef.jpg?id=30155006&amp;width=980"></media:content></item><item><title>This Startup Builds USVs That Collect Data About Oceans</title><link>https://spectrum.ieee.org/julie-angus-profile</link><description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/a-woman-standing-on-a-vessel-in-front-of-a-red-circular-object-with-instruments-on-the-bottom-of-it.png?id=30091129&width=1245&height=700&coordinates=0%2C110%2C0%2C110"/><br/><br/><p>Because most of the ocean’s vast area is far from land, it can be dangerous and expensive for crewed vessels to conduct research expeditions. This spurred Julie Angus to cofound the startup <a href="https://openoceanrobotics.com" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Open Ocean Robotics</a> to design, build, and operate oceangoing uncrewed surface vehicle (USV) drones. She is the company’s CEO.</p><p>“Our planet’s oceans are full of information that can help us protect at-risk marine life, allow ships to select more fuel-efficient routes, crack down on illegal fishing, better understand the impacts of climate change, and more,” Angus says. The IEEE member also belongs to the <a href="https://ieeeoes.org" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">IEEE Oceanic Engineering Society</a>.</p><hr/><p>The startup offers marine data as a service using its solar-powered<a href="https://openoceanrobotics.com/dataxplorer" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"> Data Xplorer</a> ocean drones, which eliminate the need for traditional crewed vessels. They can travel for months at a time collecting ocean and environmental data. </p><p>“Our team will help you plan the mission and execute it from start to finish,” she says.</p><p>The company designs and builds the drone’s hull, deck, and circuit boards. There is a patent pending on the self-righting roll-bar system. The drone is equipped with electro-optical and infrared cameras. Its <a href="https://www.newventuresbc.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/DataXplorer.png" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">sensors</a> include hydrophones that can listen to marine life, as well as environmental sensors to measure water temperature, salinity, turbidity, and weather conditions. The USV weighs just over 100 kilograms, and its motor propels it at up to 33.3 kilometers per hour.</p><p>“We have 360-degree video streaming, so the operator can use a joystick to remotely drive the boat,” Angus says. “Otherwise, our command-and-control portal can program a vehicle for autonomous activity, such as uploading a route [for] doing a grid survey.” Thanks to the combination of solar cells and lithium batteries, she says, “our boats can operate and travel nonstop for months, without needing refueling or external recharging.”</p><p>Open Ocean Robotics has received several awards and recognitions, including being named a 2019 <a href="https://entrepreneurship.ieee.org/entrepreneurship-stars-2019/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">IEEE N3XT Star</a>. The N3XT program showcases engineering-driven founders and entrepreneurial topics. </p><p>The company began in the Anguses’ garage on Vancouver Island, B.C., Canada, in 2018. The following year, the company moved to the <a href="https://vitp.ca/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Vancouver Island Technology Park</a> research and tech center. Today, Open Ocean has more than two dozen full-time employees, plus contractors and part-time staff, bringing the total to just over 30. The company has received more than US $5 million in funding.</p><p>Angus knows firsthand about how challenging the ocean can be. Her water expeditions throughout the world include five months during 2005 and 2006, when she and her husband rowed from Portugal to Costa Rica. It was the first time a woman had rowed across the Atlantic Ocean from mainland to mainland. In 2009, the couple cofounded <a href="http://www.angusrowboats.com" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Angus Rowboats</a>, which manufactures rowboats and creates sailboat kits and plans for the recreational market.</p><p class="pull-quote">“Our boats can operate and travel nonstop for months, without needing refueling or external recharging.”</p><p>Angus also brings an academic perspective to her ponderings of the deep. She has a bachelor’s degree in biology and psychology from <a href="https://www.mcmaster.ca/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">McMaster University</a>, in Hamilton, Ont., Canada, and a master’s degree in molecular biology from the <a href="https://www.uvic.ca/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">University of Victoria</a>, in British Columbia. </p><p> As of June, Open Ocean Robotics had three Data Xplorers in service, and two more nearly completed. It plans to start manufacturing another 10 later this year. </p><p>“We are still primarily doing pilot projects in both Canada and the United States, but we are transitioning into more recurring-revenue contracts,” Angus says.</p><p>The startup is eager for new technology such as smaller base stations for low Earth orbit communication satellites when its USV can’t get cellular service. The company also plans to invest in continued advancements in photovoltaic cells and in power storage—and smaller, more energy-efficient sensors.</p><p>Although Open Ocean is committed to its maritime focus, “we are not necessarily limiting ourselves to surface vehicles,” Angus says. “I can also imagine having aerial drones or underwater vehicles as part of our data-collection services. For us, the goal is data collection, helping to build an Internet of Things for the sea.”</p><p class="shortcode-media shortcode-media-youtube">
<span class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="d888d493d28b8edc048bbc2e91496bf0" style="display:block;position:relative;padding-top:56.25%;"><iframe frameborder="0" height="auto" lazy-loadable="true" scrolling="no" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/eKUQoOPSzFY?rel=0" style="position:absolute;top:0;left:0;width:100%;height:100%;" width="100%"></iframe></span>
<small class="image-media media-caption" placeholder="Add Photo Caption...">Data Xplorer</small>
<small class="image-media media-photo-credit" placeholder="Add Photo Credit...">
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=eKUQoOPSzFY" target="_blank">www.youtube.com</a>
</small>
</p><p><em>This article appears in the August 2022 print issue as “Julie Angus.”</em></p>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2022 18:06:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spectrum.ieee.org/julie-angus-profile</guid><category>Careers</category><category>Drone</category><category>Profiles</category><category>Robotics</category><category>Startups</category><category>Type:departments</category><category>Uncrewed surface vehicle</category><dc:creator>Daniel P. Dern</dc:creator><media:content medium="image" type="image/png" url="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/a-woman-standing-on-a-vessel-in-front-of-a-red-circular-object-with-instruments-on-the-bottom-of-it.png?id=30091129&amp;width=980"></media:content></item><item><title>What’s the Tech Background of an Autonomous-Vehicle Engineer?</title><link>https://spectrum.ieee.org/av-engineer-jobs</link><description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/a-smiling-man-in-a-black-shirt-and-jeans-in-the-foreground-behind-him-is-an-autonomous-car-that-says-cruise-on-the-side.jpg?id=30068063&width=1245&height=700&coordinates=0%2C0%2C0%2C410"/><br/><br/><p><a href="https://www.getcruise.com/careers" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Cruise</a>, the San-Francisco–based designer and operator of all-electric self-driving cars, employs nearly 2,000 engineers, including somewhere between 300 and 900 engineers with Ph.D. degrees. They work in hardware and software. They specialize in AI, security, and safety. And though, indeed, some have robotics, automation, or automotive backgrounds, many don’t. Instead, they come from an incredibly long list of different technical fields—e-commerce, finance, game development, animation, cameras, semiconductors, and app development.</p><p>Here’s what <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/mohamedelshenawy" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Mohamed Elshenawy</a>, Cruise’s executive vice president of engineering, told <em>IEEE Spectrum</em> about the company’s workforce. (Elshenawy himself came to Cruise from stints as chief technology officer at a financial services startup and leader of a technology team at Amazon.)</p><p><em>I<strong>EEE Spectrum:</strong></em> <strong>Let’s start with the big picture of your engineering team.</strong></p><p><strong>Mohamed Elshenawy: </strong>In AI, we have machine-learning (ML) engineers that build the on-the-road decision-making modules. We also have the engineers that help build the tools for our continuous-learning machine. We have data engineers and data scientists, and even UI folks that help with the tools that the main core ML engineers use.</p><p>In robotics, we have AV foundations engineers, who build and maintain our robotics operating systems, and embedded systems developers.</p><p>In our security and safety operations, we have engineers working on threat modeling, app security engineering, IT enterprise security, and the security of the vehicle itself, along with all the systems engineers responsible for test validation, generating test-case scenarios, and tracking it all.</p><p>Our hardware engineers build our own EVs from the ground up, in partnership with <a href="https://www.gm.com/" target="_blank">GM</a> and <a href="http://www.honda.com/" target="_blank">Honda</a>. They handle the definition, design, development, and production of sensors, compute modules, and related hardware and include about 50 engineering disciplines, including acoustic engineers, power engineers, system-on-chips people, and so on.</p><p>Finally, we have the product engineering team—that covers both user-facing and internal apps—and the infrastructure team which builds the technical foundations (cloud infrastructure, internal tools, etc.) that the rest of our engineers rely on every day to get work done.</p><h3></h3><br/><div class="flourish-embed flourish-chart" data-src="visualisation/10499631?594662"><script src="https://public.flourish.studio/resources/embed.js"></script></div><p><strong>Where do these engineers generally come from?</strong></p><p><strong>Elshenawy:</strong> Many of our AI engineers come from academia, consumer tech, and finance. Our simulation group is part of this team. They include several engineers that helped build <em>The Sims</em> and others that worked for gaming and animation studios like <a href="https://www.pixar.com/" target="_blank">Pixar</a>, <a href="https://www.lucasfilm.com/what-we-do/games/" target="_blank">LucasArts</a>, and <a href="https://www.ubisoft.com/en-us/" target="_blank">Ubisoft</a>. Our hardware engineers include people who came from <a href="https://www.kodak.com/en" target="_blank">Kodak</a>, <a href="https://www.jpl.nasa.gov/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">JPL</a>, and chipmakers, as well as academia. For robotics, we generally look to robotics, other automotive, and aerospace companies for hiring. On the security side, we hire a mix of researchers and practitioners—and even literal hackers, including the team that infamously <a href="https://www.wired.com/2015/07/hackers-remotely-kill-jeep-highway/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">hacked a Jeep</a>. Our product and infrastructure engineers come from a variety of traditional engineering companies as well as startups; they’ve previously built videoconferencing software, cloud computing platforms, and even a meditation app.</p><p><strong>How has the mix shifted over the years?</strong></p><p><strong>Elshenawy:</strong> We’re solving for a problem that is mainly rooted in general AI, so we’ve always been heavy on the AI side of things. Because we are cloud native, we are able to leverage a lot of the existing technology that is provided by cloud providers, such as <a href="https://cloud.google.com/" target="_blank">Google Cloud Platform</a> and <a href="https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/" target="_blank">Azure</a>; we don’t need to reinvent that. So we’re leaning more heavily towards AI, robotics, and hardware over time.</p><p>Also, we’re ramping up product engineering now that we have started charging members of the public to ride in fully driverless cars. We expect that to continue to grow there as we solve for the technology and expand to multiple cities in the United States and internationally.</p><p><strong>You mean people working on the customer-facing app?</strong></p><p><strong>Elshenawy:</strong> That and a lot more. This includes the customer-facing app that lets you order a ride, the in-car experience, and all the fleet operation on the back end, where we control our fleet, placing our fleet ahead of demand and determining pricing, and all the services that keep these lights on.</p><h3></h3><br/><div class="flourish-embed flourish-chart" data-src="visualisation/10520927?594662"><script src="https://public.flourish.studio/resources/embed.js"></script></div><p><strong>What do your engineers have in common?</strong><br/></p><p><strong>Elshenawy:</strong> The self-driving cars problem is a great AI problem, and some people think about it as essentially a research problem, because you’re pushing the state of the art. But when you think about how you are actually going to pragmatically ship something continuously, it’s all rooted in experimentation.</p><p>So one common factor that we find in the engineers who are successful here, regardless of where in our organization that they land, is having the experimentation mind-set, the humble, resilient mind-set of someone who’s continuously curious and very agile in nature. There are certain types of engineers that don’t deal well with uncertainty and experimentation, and there are other engineers who thrive under an environment of continuous learning.</p><p>So the common trait among all these engineers is that learning, curiosity, and experimentation mind-set, and having the agility to deal with an unknown problem like this one.</p><p><strong>What are the hardest roles to fill right now?</strong></p><p><strong>Elshenawy:</strong> Software, in general, has a shortage and will always have less supply than demand in the coming years, particularly in AI, applied machine learning, and deep learning, and we will continue to need these engineers in many different areas as we grow. Robotics specializations, and in general, control theory, will be very important as we go forward and those areas will continually face high demand.</p>]]></description><pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2022 17:45:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spectrum.ieee.org/av-engineer-jobs</guid><category>Ai</category><category>Artificial intelligence</category><category>Autonomous vehicles</category><category>Engineering jobs</category><category>Software engineering jobs</category><category>Cruise</category><category>Careers</category><dc:creator>Tekla S. Perry</dc:creator><media:content medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/a-smiling-man-in-a-black-shirt-and-jeans-in-the-foreground-behind-him-is-an-autonomous-car-that-says-cruise-on-the-side.jpg?id=30068063&amp;width=980"></media:content></item><item><title>Leading the Way for More LGBTQ Inclusivity in STEM</title><link>https://spectrum.ieee.org/arti-agrawal-profile</link><description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/photo-of-a-woman-in-front-of-a-bookshelf.jpg?id=30071633&width=1245&height=700&coordinates=0%2C0%2C0%2C206"/><br/><br/><p>
<a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/artiagrawal/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Arti Agrawal</a>, who is gay, didn’t have access to LGBTQ+ support groups when growing up in India, where homosexuality was a crime until 2018.
</p><p>
	“The society itself was very homophobic,” she says. “I had to live under the radar, and it was very difficult and quite traumatizing to live that way.”
</p><hr/><p>
	Agrawal found solace in advocacy and support organizations in London after moving there in 2005. She went on to form her own groups and lead diversity, equity, and inclusion efforts at the universities she worked for in London and Sydney.
</p><p>
	 This year she started a consulting firm, where she helps businesses around the world improve their DEI programs. She also has spearheaded DEI campaigns for the<a href="https://www.photonicssociety.org/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"> IEEE Photonics Society</a>.
</p><p>
	For her efforts, the senior member received the society’s 2020<a href="https://www.photonicssociety.org/awards/distinguished-service-award#:~:text=The%20IEEE%20Photonics%20Society%20Distinguished,Photonics%20Society%20as%20a%20whole." rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"> Distinguished Service Award</a>.
</p><p><strong>Fighting for Diversity and Inclusivity in STEM</strong></p><p>
	After graduating in 2005 from the<a href="https://home.iitd.ac.in/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"> Indian Institute of Technology Delhi</a>, with a doctorate in physics, Agrawal decided to move to the United Kingdom. “I didn’t think I could be my true self at home,” she says, “and I thought I could live more openly.” She joined<a href="https://www.city.ac.uk/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"> City, University of London</a>, as a research fellow working on computational photonics.</p><p>
	 But she discovered there were fewer women in science, technology, engineering, and math at the university than at her alma mater. And, she says, the workplace atmosphere wasn’t welcoming.</p><h3></h3><br/><p><strong>About Arti Agrawal</strong></p><p><strong></strong><strong>Employer: </strong>Vividhataa in Sydney</p><p><strong>Title: </strong>Founder and CEO</p><p><strong>Member grade: </strong>Senior member</p><p><strong>Alma mater: </strong>City, University of London</p><p>
	 “I never felt like I was treated the same as my male peers or was given the same opportunities,” she says.</p><p>
	 She also faced homophobia, Agrawal says.</p><p>
	 “Even though the public opinion on gay rights in the U.K. was shifting, it wasn’t like that within STEM,” she says. “It was quite a closed space. You didn’t talk about sexual orientation. And it was okay for people to make homophobic jokes.”</p><p>
	 Because of such attitudes, Agrawal got more involved in support groups for members of the LGBTQ+ community as well as women in STEM. She joined <a href="https://www.gwn.org.uk/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">The London Gay Women’s Network</a>, which offers professional development and networking opportunities to community members who are pursuing a college degree.</p><p>
	 But, Agrawal says, she still felt isolated because the groups had few members from underrepresented ethnicities and cultures. So she created her own subgroup in 2009: the<a href="https://www.gwn.org.uk/gwnm/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"> Gay Women’s Network Multicultural</a>. It provides women of color a safe space to connect with each other. </p><p>
	 In 2011 she took a position at the university as a lecturer and started her own LGBTQ+ network there so she could help create a better environment. The group got school officials to install gender-neutral bathrooms, and it won the right for students and faculty members to use their preferred pronouns on human resource forms and in email.</p><p>
	 In 2018 she left to join the<a href="https://www.uts.edu.au/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"> University of Technology</a> in Sydney as director of<a href="https://www.uts.edu.au/about/faculty-engineering-and-information-technology/women-engineering-and-it" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"> its Women in Engineering and IT</a> program. It works to increase the enrollment of women in the school’s engineering program and to support them throughout their academic career by offering mentoring, scholarships, and professional development workshops.</p><p>
	 While there, she shook up the engineering school’s admissions process and helped increase cultural awareness. The percentage of women in the undergraduate program at the university “had been stuck at around 16 percent for more than 40 years,” she says. “No number of mentoring programs, scholarships, or industry outreach had changed this statistic.”</p><p>
	 To help more female candidates qualify for the engineering school, Agrawal pushed to change the admissions policy. Prospective students are ranked based on their Higher Secondary Certificate scores. HSC is a subject-based qualification whereby students take three or four courses of their choice in their last year of secondary school. The top-ranking 100 students, no matter their gender, were admitted to the engineering program. Agrawal recommended adding 10 points to every female applicant’s rank.</p><p>
	 “It doesn’t change their actual marks,” she says. “It just changes their rank.”</p><p class="pull-quote">
	 “If you want to make a change in a very difficult and unchanging environment, you must be disruptive. You have to do something bold and brave and have the courage to stand up to the backlash that will come eventually.”</p><p>The policy change was reviewed and approved by several university committees as well as by the<a href="https://antidiscrimination.nsw.gov.au/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"> New South Wales Anti-Discrimination</a> board, which handles citizen complaints. The board approved the change for 10 years.</p><p>
	 Since the policy change, implemented in 2019, the number of women in the program has increased by 10 percent, Agrawal says.</p><p>
	 The change created a huge backlash, though, Agrawal says, as people said “unqualified women would receive degrees.” Many women were against the change, saying it was doing them a disservice.</p><p>
	 “But there were people who understood that the administration wasn’t changing anyone’s scores,” Agrawal says. Every student who was admitted met the minimum criteria, she says; the change just bumped up the ranking of some qualified women.</p><p>
	 “If you want to make a change in a very difficult and unchanging environment, you must be disruptive,” she says. “You have to do something bold and brave and have the courage to stand up to the backlash that will come eventually.”</p><p>
	 Agrawal also worked to create stronger interpersonal relationships among the faculty and staff at the engineering school. She created social events, held every two weeks, at which faculty and staff meet over coffee and learn about cultural customs—such as Diwali, Eid al-Fitr, and Chinese New Year—from one another.</p><p>
	 “In a very informal sort of way, faculty and staff members raised their cultural awareness,” she says. “The overall environment also became more positive and welcoming.”
</p><p><strong>Launching a DEI Startup</strong></p><p>
	Agrawal left the university last year, and this year she started her own diversity, equity, and inclusion consulting business, Vividhataa, in Sydney.</p><p>
	 Vividhataa aims to help companies set goals and create strategies to achieve them. It also is educating managers and employees on gender identity, cultural sensitivity, disability inclusion, and related topics, Agrawal says.
</p><p><strong>Creating a Safe Space at IEEE</strong></p><p>
	Agrawal has been involved in similar efforts at IEEE. She joined the organization as a doctoral student at the Indian Institute of Technology so she could become a member of the<a href="https://www.photonicssociety.org/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"> IEEE Photonics Society</a> chapter there.</p><p>
	 She first became involved in the<a href="https://www.photonicssociety.org/chapters-communities/women-in-photonics" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"> IEEE Women in Photonics</a> group as its associate vice president. She spearheaded a campaign to increase the number of local chapters. The society also held events worldwide that addressed the needs of established chapters. The campaign grew to include hosting panels on DEI policies at conferences and holding leadership training.</p><p>
	 Agrawal founded the society’s diversity oversight committee in 2017 and became associate vice president. She explored how to attract more members from underrepresented groups. She says she also wanted to create a more welcoming environment for members regardless of their age, sexual orientation, or disability. She focused on increasing cultural, racial, and religious diversity.</p><p>
	 In 2018 she helped organize the society’s first<a href="https://www.photonicssociety.org/who-we-are/commitment-to-diversity/pride-in-photonics" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"> Pride in Photonics</a> symposium. During the event, LGBTQ+ engineers trained attendees on how to be a good ally to members of the community. Speakers also presented on their optics research and shared their personal journeys.</p><p>
	 “It brought the community together and helped reduce the sense of isolation that people can feel,” she says.</p><p>
	 The committee collaborated with the<a href="https://nsbp.org/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"> U.S. National Society of Black Physicists</a>, the<a href="https://hispanicphysicists.org/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"> National Society of Hispanic Physicists</a>, and other groups on joint conferences at Historically Black Colleges and Universities. The groups are also working to increase representation on IEEE’s committees and councils.</p><p>
	 The Photonics Society’s diversity oversight committee helped run a marketing campaign in 2020 to increase the number of nominations of qualified women and those from IEEE’s underrepresented regions for the organization’s 2021 medals, recognitions, and technical field awards. It also made a pledge to diversify its panels, meetings, conferences, and events, Agrawal says.</p><p>
	 “I thought the Photonics Society was, and still is, a marvelous society,” she says. “It has embraced diversity and inclusion and made a lot of headway in that area.”
</p>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spectrum.ieee.org/arti-agrawal-profile</guid><category>Ieee member news</category><category>Lgbt</category><category>Diversity and inclusion</category><category>Type:ti</category><dc:creator>Joanna Goodrich</dc:creator><media:content medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/photo-of-a-woman-in-front-of-a-bookshelf.jpg?id=30071633&amp;width=980"></media:content></item><item><title>IEEE STEM Activity Kits Are In Demand at 150 U.S. Public Libraries</title><link>https://spectrum.ieee.org/ieee-stem-activity-kits</link><description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/two-boys-and-one-girl-standing-in-front-of-a-computer-monitor-on-the-left-side-of-the-monitor-is-a-backpack-containing-a-scienc.jpg?id=30049260&width=1245&height=700&coordinates=0%2C0%2C0%2C552"/><br/><br/><p>More than 150 public libraries throughout the central United States now lend out activity kits that let children explore just about any aspect of science, technology, engineering, and mathematics. The kids can check them out just like they would a book. The kits teach youngsters what engineers do, as well as how to code, build robots, design video games, and create animations. </p><p>The collections have been made possible by the<a href="https://r4.ieee.org/skpl/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"> IEEE Region 4 Science Kits for Public Libraries</a> program with funding from Region 4 members and corporate sponsors. The SKPL program is the brainchild of IEEE Life Senior Member <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/john-zulaski-b4445243/" target="_blank">John A. Zulaski</a>, the chair of the SKPL committee.</p><p>Activity kits aren’t new to libraries, but STEM kits didn’t exist 10 years ago. Nowadays large, well-funded libraries might have them, but that’s not the case for many small and midsize ones, Zulaski says.</p><p>He says he is on a mission to encourage other IEEE entities to make the kits available at local libraries. Only public libraries in IEEE Region 4 currently are eligible for an SKPL grant. </p><p>“This is the perfect project for IEEE life members or young professionals to undertake,” Zulaski says. “The kits get kids interested in pursuing a technical career—which, by the way, helps increase IEEE membership down the road.”</p><p>Currently all 80 branches of the<a href="https://chipublib.bibliocommons.com/v2/search?query=science%20kits&searchType=smart&_ga=2.48539494.1160701079.1654617414-274951698.1654617414" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"> Chicago Public Library</a> have the kits, as do libraries in Illinois, Indiana, Iowa, Minnesota, Michigan, Nebraska, North Dakota, Ohio, and Wisconsin.</p><p><strong>STEM in Libraries </strong></p><p>After Zulaski retired as director of electronic products at<a href="https://www.sandc.com/en/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"> S&C Electric</a>, in Chicago, he became a trustee for his <a href="https://mtpros.ent.sirsi.net/client/en_US/default/search/results/?qu=science+kits" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">local library, in Mount Prospect, Ill</a>. During his visits there, he noticed cloth bags filled with puzzles and other activities, but none were specific to STEM. He recalled the wonderful experiences he had as a child playing with Erector sets, Lincoln Logs, and other activity kits, and he realized many children today are not so fortunate. In 2009 he talked to the library’s executive director, <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/marilyn-genther-108566a/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Marilyn Genther</a>, about creating science kits that could be circulated. She was interested but said she didn’t have the US $2,000 in her budget she estimated it would take to create such a collection.</p><p>Zulaski ran the idea past the <a href="https://ieeechicago.org/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">IEEE Chicago Section</a>, which agreed to provide funding. Assembled by youth librarians and IEEE volunteers, 12 kits were created for children in Grades 1 through 5. They included hands-on off-the-shelf STEM projects, instructions written by the librarians, and a recommended list of books, DVDs, videos, and other reference material from the library, Genther says. All the items were stowed in backpacks.</p><p>Genther says having libraries offer the kits makes a lot of sense. There is no curriculum for students to follow, so they can learn at their own pace and pick topics they find interesting. </p><p>“The kits get into the hands of children who may not have an opportunity to learn about STEM otherwise,” she says. Genther has since retired and is now a member of the IEEE SKPL committee.</p><p>Zulaski says the prototype kits were flying off the shelves—which persuaded the IEEE Chicago Section to launch the SKPL project in 2010. Through the generosity of the section’s members and a few corporate donors, more than 25 libraries in the Chicago area began circulating the science kits.</p><p>The kits get into the hands of children who may not have an opportunity to learn about STEM otherwise.</p><p><span></span>Kids aren’t the only ones checking out the collections. Teachers, Boy Scout leaders, parents who homeschool their children, and libraries that have in-house STEM programs do as well.</p><p>The kits are tailored to the needs of the local children, Zulaski says.</p><p>“We decided early on that we did not want to dictate to the libraries what should be in their kits,” he says. “They are in a better position to make that determination because they can look at their records on STEM-related books that have been checked out and see what subjects seem to be most popular.”</p><p><strong>Generous Donors </strong></p><p>In 2011 the project received funding from the IEEE Foundation and the IEEE<a href="https://mga.ieee.org/board-committees/committees/216-ieee-life-members-committee" target="_blank"> Life Members Committee</a> to enable 26 libraries in the Midwest to build science kit collections.</p><p>The SKPL committee set up a <a href="https://r4.ieee.org/skpl/apply-for-a-grant/" target="_blank">formal application process</a> for granting money to libraries. The number of libraries applying for SKPL grants has grown. This year the committee has received 79 applications, up from 40 last year. It awarded 15 grants of up to $2,000.</p><p>In a testimonial about the SKPL grant received by the <a href="https://bataviapubliclibrary.org/discovery-kits-youth/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Batavia Public Library</a>, in Illinois, its youth services librarian, Amanda Vanderwerf, said, “The deeper understanding that comes from sustained engagement with these kits is something we are proud to offer to our patrons, and we thank you for this opportunity. The Batavia community, the library staff, and especially the youth services department thanks IEEE for allowing us to be part of this fantastic opportunity to create circulating science kits.”</p><p>S&C Electric made a substantial donation to provide SKPL collections to the entire Chicago Public Library system. The company also makes an annual donation to maintain the existing kits and add new ones to the collection. Other corporate donors include <a href="https://www.atcllc.com/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">American Transmission</a>, <a href="https://www.eaton.com/us/en-us.html" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Eaton</a>, <a href="https://www.elite-electronics.com.au/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Elite Electronics</a>,<a href="https://www.emerson.com/en-us" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"> Emerson Electric</a>, and <a href="https://www.milwaukeetool.com/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Milwaukee Tool</a>. <a href="https://ieeeusa.org/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">IEEE-USA</a>, the <a href="https://www.ewh.ieee.org/reg/4/pace.php" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">IEEE Professional Activities Committee</a>, and the <a href="https://www.emcs.org/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">IEEE Electromagnetic Compatibility Society</a>’s Chicago chapter also have donated money. </p><p>With cash Zulaski received in 2015 from the <a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/ieee-new-initiatives-program-is-looking-to-bring-your-bright-ideas-into-the-light" target="_self">IEEE New Initiatives Committee </a>, the SKPL committee created a marketing campaign to promote the project, developed fundraising initiatives, and built its <a href="https://r4.ieee.org/skpl/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">website</a>. </p><p>The 2023 submission period for SKPL <a href="https://r4.ieee.org/skpl/apply-for-a-grant/#1586393847832-70d8c1af-b04d" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">grant</a> applications period begins 1 November 2022 and closes 15 January.</p><p>Zulaski says Region 4 members are making their libraries aware of the opportunity. He says he hopes that by this time next year, other IEEE groups will be offering grants. To help make that happen, funding is being sought to create a toolkit to train other IEEE entities how to implement their own SKPL program. </p><p>“Hopefully this can be accomplished by the end of this year, assuming major donors step forward,” Zulaski says. “There are around 10,000 public libraries in the United States alone and hundreds of thousands around the world. Much remains to be accomplished.”</p><p>If your IEEE entity is interested in offering the SKPL program, complete <a href="https://r4.ieee.org/skpl/contact-us/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">this form</a>.</p><p><a href="https://give.ieeefoundation.org/give/246578/#!/donation/checkout" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Donations</a> to the program are welcome.</p>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2022 18:00:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spectrum.ieee.org/ieee-stem-activity-kits</guid><category>Stem</category><category>Education</category><category>Ieee products services</category><category>Students</category><category>Ieee region 4</category><category>Ieee chicago section</category><category>Ieee science kits for local libraries</category><category>Type:ti</category><dc:creator>Kathy Pretz</dc:creator><media:content medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/two-boys-and-one-girl-standing-in-front-of-a-computer-monitor-on-the-left-side-of-the-monitor-is-a-backpack-containing-a-scienc.jpg?id=30049260&amp;width=980"></media:content></item><item><title>New AI-Powered Platform Aids Telecom Product Designers</title><link>https://spectrum.ieee.org/ieee-discoverypoint-launches</link><description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/a-man-and-woman-in-a-data-center-he-holds-a-laptop-while-they-confer.jpg?id=30007453&width=1245&height=700&coordinates=0%2C0%2C0%2C810"/><br/><br/><p>Engineers designing communications products need access to information—the latest research, lists of parts and components, and technical standards to help ensure that their design will work seamlessly with others. But tracking down resources across multiple websites can be time-consuming, and the material might not be relevant or the sources could be questionable. </p>
<p>The new <a href="https://discoverypoint.ieee.org/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">IEEE DiscoveryPoint for Communications</a> platform aims to solve those problems by providing one-stop access to searchable, curated content from trusted sources on just about any telecommunications topic. Its library contains more than 1 million full-text research documents; 10,000 technical standards; 8,000 online courses; 400 ebook titles; 18 million parts and various solutions from manufacturers and distributors; and 1,100 industry and product news bulletins, blogs, and white papers. </p><hr/>
<p>The documents come from reputable organizations including <a href="https://www.att.com/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">AT&T</a>, <a href="https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/Xplore/home.jsp" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">the IEEE Xplore Digital Library</a>, <a href="https://www.f5.com/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">F5 Networks</a>, <a href="https://www.itu.int/en/ITU-T/Pages/default.aspx" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">the International Telecommunication Union</a>, <a href="https://www.riverpublishers.com/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">River Publishers</a>, <a href="http://qualcomm.com/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Qualcomm</a>, <a href="https://www.verizon.com/about" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Verizon</a>, and <a href="https://www.smpte.org/?hsLang=en" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">SMPTE</a>.</p>
<p>“There’s nothing on the market right now that fully supports the workflow of the design engineer and that delivers all the information needed in one place,” says <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/markbarragry/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Mark Barragry</a>, senior product manager for corporate markets at IEEE Global Products and Marketing.</p>
<p>In designing IEEE DiscoveryPoint, Barragry says, “We reconstructed the work process of a product design engineer and put together a set of resources that meet all the information needs they would have during a standard product-development cycle.”</p>
<p><strong>Significant Resources</strong></p><p>IEEE has a wealth of content for telecom designers, Barragry says. IEEE publishes nine of the 10 most-cited journals in telecommunications. More than 40 percent of U.S. patents related to telecommunications cite an IEEE publication. The organization also sponsors more than 7,000 conferences that focus on communications, networking, and broadcast technologies. And the <a href="http://standards.ieee.org/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">IEEE Standards Association</a> has developed more than 900 standards related to communications, including the popular <a href="https://standards.ieee.org/search/?q=IEEE%20802.11" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">IEEE 802.11</a> WiFi standard.</p>
<p>Barragry adds that design engineers who tested the platform before launch said they liked that it came from IEEE, a trusted source.</p>
<p><strong>Search Algorithm</strong></p><p>The subscription-based product’s intuitive search engine saves users time because it zeroes in on key concepts related to the topic they’re searching for. To get started, the user types a word, phrase, concept, the name of an author or company, or another term into the search bar. The search engine’s ranking algorithm analyzes the full text and the metadata of the documents to find relevant material. </p>
<p>The results are organized into channels and categorized by type of material, such as research papers, standards, books, or industry news. For each search result, a machine-learning feature examines the document and generates a short summary of key points, which get highlighted in the document.</p>
<p>Search results can be sorted by relevance or by time period, starting with the previous 90 days and going as far back as 10 years for journals and five years for conferences. The results also can be grouped, for example, by a publication’s name. Searches can be saved, and users can bookmark documents.</p>
<p>IEEE DiscoveryPoint also recommends content based on an automated analysis of the user’s reading activity during the previous 30 days. Users can set up email alerts for new content that fits their search criteria.  </p>
<p>In one testimonial about IEEE DiscoveryPoint, a director of technology development said, “I really appreciated the thought that went into this product. It’s an unmet need for people like me.”</p>
<p>The subscription price is based on the size of the organization and how many engineers and technical professionals will be using it. To request a demo, complete <a href="https://discoverypoint.ieee.org/request-a-demo/?LT=LG_ENL_2022_RFD_IDPC_IEEE_Institute" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">this form</a>. </p>]]></description><pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2022 18:00:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spectrum.ieee.org/ieee-discoverypoint-launches</guid><category>Ieee xplore digital library</category><category>Education</category><category>Ieee discoverypoint</category><category>Ieee products services</category><category>Publications</category><category>Research</category><category>Standards</category><category>Telecommunications</category><category>Type:ti</category><dc:creator>Kathy Pretz</dc:creator><media:content medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/a-man-and-woman-in-a-data-center-he-holds-a-laptop-while-they-confer.jpg?id=30007453&amp;width=980"></media:content></item><item><title>IEEE Education Week Offered Hundreds of Learning Opportunities</title><link>https://spectrum.ieee.org/ieee-education-week-2022-overview</link><description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/five-women-standing-in-front-of-a-sign-that-says-ieee-education-week.jpg?id=29975910&width=1245&height=700&coordinates=0%2C0%2C0%2C566"/><br/><br/><p>
<strong>IEEE members across</strong> the globe came together to celebrate the first-ever <a href="http://educationweek.ieee.org" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">IEEE Education Week</a> from 4 to 8 April. The weeklong celebration highlighted educational opportunities provided by IEEE and its many organizational units. More than 60 IEEE operating units, regions, sections, and technical societies offered live events, virtual resources, special offers, and a daily online quiz that awarded a digital badge for participants who answered correctly.
</p><p>
	“Education Week was a chance to show the collective impact IEEE has on lifelong learning and education at every level,” says <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/jamie-moesch-7502b31/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Jamie Moesch</a>, managing director, Educational Activities. “From preuniversity STEM programs and university offerings to continuing professional education courses and tutorials, there are so many ways to engage with education from IEEE. This week was about bringing all those resources together in one place and making sure our members know about all of the amazing educational opportunities available to them.”
</p><hr/><p>
	The celebration highlighted resources for:
</p><ul>
<li>Engineers and professionals working in technical fields.</li>
<li>University students and faculty members.</li>
<li>Anyone looking for preuniversity STEM education resources and experiences to encourage the next generation of engineers and technologists.</li>
</ul><p>
	Events included:
</p><ul>
<li><a href="https://event.on24.com/wcc/r/3643947/9FE428F681BC0DF727B1AC2601F3C246" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">A webinar</a> featuring IEEE President <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/k-j-ray-liu-55791a103/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">K.J. Ray Liu</a> that illustrated how lifelong learning opportunities are among the reasons IEEE is the professional home for hundreds of thousands of members across the globe.</li>
<li><a href="https://ieee-edusociety.org/ieee-education-week-2022" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">A series of live virtual events</a> offered by the <a href="https://ieee-edusociety.org/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">IEEE Education Society</a> that covered topics of importance to academic faculty, such as online learning solutions, insight into the requirements of publishing educational research work in journals, and a step-by-step road map for instructors who want to move their traditional curricula to the online learning management environment required by their institution.</li>
<li>An <a href="https://tryengineering.org/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">IEEE TryEngineering</a> Tuesday <a href="https://event.on24.com/wcc/r/3654392/80244534587CE562F8C05B0A0915E08E" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">webinar</a>—a collaboration between the <a href="https://www.comsoc.org/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">IEEE Communications Society</a> and <a href="https://www.ieee.org/education/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">IEEE Educational Activities</a>—that featured <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/lola-awoniyi-oteri-phd-0ab9223/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Lola Awoniyi-Oteri</a>, principal systems research and development engineer with <a href="https://www.qualcomm.com/research" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Qualcomm</a>, who discussed her research in extended reality and 5G. </li>
<li>The <a href="https://romania.ieeer8.org/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">IEEE Romania Section</a> offered a <a href="https://events.vtools.ieee.org/m/310694" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">webinar</a> that focused on the sustainability of engineering education and the role IEEE plays in supporting student training. It included a discussion on online and offline education, how to train future engineers, and ways to attract young people to study engineering. </li>
<li>The <a href="https://cmte.ieee.org/futuredirections/projects/leo-satellites-systems/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">IEEE Low Earth Orbit Satellites & Systems project</a> held a panel discussion to address the importance of space education for high school students.</li>
<li>The IEEE <a href="https://www.dkte.ac.in/about-us/about-dkte-society" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">DKTE (Dattajirao Kadam Technical Education Society)</a> <a href="https://www.facebook.com/dktestei/photos/our-institute-has-established-ieee-dkte-student-branch-dkte-ieee-ieeestudents/1536897169827746/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">student branch</a> offered a live event led by the <a href="https://www.facebook.com/IEEEMadrasSSIT/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">IEEE Society on Social Implications of Technology Madras Section</a> that discussed IEEE learning resources available to engineering students.</li>
<li>The <a href="https://www.ieeefoundation.org/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">IEEE Foundation</a> hosted an <a href="https://vimeo.com/698257097" target="_blank">online panel</a> that addressed where and how the philanthropic organization supports educational programs across the globe.</li>
</ul><p>
	“For both young technical professionals and those who are more established in their fields, taking the time to learn new skills in this age of hybrid and remote working can help their careers flourish,” says <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/stephen-phillips-1034169/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Stephen Phillips</a>, vice president, IEEE Educational Activities.
</p><p class="shortcode-media shortcode-media-rebelmouse-image">
<img alt="A group of students hold up signs that spell IEEE Edu Week 2022 along with a banner." class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="73ce91a8310ada5d7585c27d89cb70e3" data-rm-shortcode-name="rebelmouse-image" id="e0906" loading="lazy" src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/a-group-of-students-hold-up-signs-that-spell-ieee-edu-week-2022-along-with-a-banner.jpg?id=29975914&width=980"/>
<small class="image-media media-caption" placeholder="Add Photo Caption...">The IEEE Antennas, Propagation, Microwave Theory, and Techniques student branch chapter at the Indian Institute of Technology, in Kharagpur, celebrated IEEE Education Week at Hijli College, in West Bengal, India. On 9 April, they led a hands-on session on how to use basic electronic components like resistors, switches, buzzers, wires, breadboards, and DC battery sources. </small><small class="image-media media-photo-credit" placeholder="Add Photo Credit...">Pallab Kumar Gogoi</small>
</p><p>
	“IEEE Education Week highlighted all of the preuniversity STEM, university, and continuing professional education resources for students, engineers, and technical professionals,” says <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/babak-beheshti-5807161/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Babak Beheshti</a>, chair of the IEEE Educational Activities continuing education committee. “As the private sector ramps up hiring, many are looking for candidates who have skills in emerging technologies. IEEE’s educational offerings directly address this increasing need.”
</p><p>
	Save the date for next year’s IEEE Education Week, to be held from 2 to 8 April. Follow updates on social media via #EducationAtIEEE and sign up for email updates at <a href="http://educationweek.ieee.org/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">educationweek.ieee.org</a>.
</p><h3>​The inaugural event also boasts some impressive stats:</h3><br/><p>• 225 events.<br/>• 102 resources provided.<br/>• 90 volunteer ambassadors from 23 countries.<br/>• Participation by 65 operating units, regions, sections, and technical society partners.<br/>• 434 quiz submissions.<br/>• 80 digital badges issued.<br/>• Visitors from 99 countries.<br/>• US $5,975 donated to the IEEE Foundation to support educational programs.</p>]]></description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2022 18:00:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spectrum.ieee.org/ieee-education-week-2022-overview</guid><category>Ieee products services</category><category>Ieee educational activities</category><category>Education</category><category>Careers</category><category>Stem</category><category>Students</category><category>Type:ti</category><dc:creator>Angelique Parashis</dc:creator><media:content medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/five-women-standing-in-front-of-a-sign-that-says-ieee-education-week.jpg?id=29975910&amp;width=980"></media:content></item><item><title>This VC Is Betting Big on Flying Taxis and Scooters</title><link>https://spectrum.ieee.org/adam-grosser-profile</link><description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/man-sitting-in-front-of-a-disassembled-car-in-a-garage-with-tools-behind-him.png?id=29963584&width=1245&height=700&coordinates=0%2C234%2C0%2C235"/><br/><br/><p><strong>Adam Grosser wants</strong> to improve transportationof people, goods, and energy. That’s why the chairman and managing partner of the early-stage venture capital fund <a href="https://up.partners" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">UP Partners</a> is investing in several mobility projects. They include <a href="https://www.beta.team/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Beta Technologies</a>’<a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/evtol-air-taxi-industry" target="_self"> electric vertical-takeoff-and-landing</a> aircraft, <a href="https://www.quincus.com" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Quincus</a>’s operating system for supply-chain and logistics providers, and <a href="http://www.teleo.ai" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Teleo</a>’s teleoperation platform for mining, construction, and other heavy equipment.</p><p>“Transportation is the underlying fabric of society,” Grosser says. “At UP, we invest in key enabling technologies that help move people and goods faster, safer, more efficiently, and sustainably. This can include anything from new kinds of ground, sea-born, air, or space vehicles to production lines, packages, and units of automation.”<br/></p><hr/><p>The mobility sector is ripe for improvement, he says. “Arguably just about everything on a car, except for a few safety systems, was invented by 1920—although not necessarily put into widespread practice. But mobility hasn’t previously been an investable category.” </p><p>He credits several factors for this. Faster, smaller, and cheaper additive manufacturing is now available. Also, rapid shifts in battery capacity and electric motor torque have dramatically changed how mobility vehicles and methods are built and work. </p><p>The question, he says, is how to pull all these together into something that is safe and more environmentally friendly than what we do today—and which has a viable financial model. </p><p>One company that ticks all these boxes for Grosser is <a href="https://kolors.com.mx/" target="_blank">Kolors</a>, in Acapulco, Mexico, which aims to transform the bus industry across Latin America by offering a website for riders to reserve a seat on an intercity bus. The company does not own the buses. Instead, it partners with small and medium-size bus lines that own their vehicles to provide a consistent customer experience and offer a single ticketing framework. He describes Kolors as an “asset-light bus company” and compares it to <a href="https://www.uber.com/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Uber</a>, the ride-hailing service, which also doesn’t own the vehicles customers use. </p><p class="pull-quote">At UP Partners, we invest in key enabling technologies that help move people and goods faster, safer, more efficiently, and sustainably.</p><p>Grosser decided to get into the investment business after two decades in senior positions at <a href="https://www.apple.com/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Apple</a>, <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/gamesblog/2013/apr/04/lucasarts-closed-by-disney" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">LucasArts</a>, <a href="https://www.sonypictures.com/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Sony Pictures Entertainment</a>, and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/@Home_Network" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">@Home Network</a>. He spent more than a decade at <a href="https://foundationcapital.com/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Foundation Capital</a>, primarily in early-stage ventures. He then moved to large-cap private equity firms, including <a href="https://www.silverlake.com/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Silver Lake</a>. He’s been with UP Partners since May 2020. </p><p>“Most people who go into tech investing today do that with a fairly clear intention of being an investor,” Grosser says. “[By contrast], I would consider myself an inadvertent investor. I’ve spent decades working to solve meaningful challenges, first as an engineer, then as an entrepreneur, and for the past 21 years as an investor.” </p><p>What helped him succeed at his investing goals? Mentors. </p><p>“I have been lucky enough to have amazing mentors and partners, from my college days through to the present," Grosser says. One was the late <a href="https://foundationcapital.com/in-memory-of-kathryn-gould/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Kathryn Gould</a>, who founded Foundation Capital. In addition to being one of the first female venture capitalists, she was also a physicist and concert violinist. </p><p>“She pulled me in and said, ‘I think you will be a good investor. Let me teach you.’”</p><p>Grosser also credits his diverse engineering experiences with helping him talk knowledgeably about potential new technologies and companies to invest in as well as conduct due diligence. </p><p>Grosser uses some of what he learned through his hands-on experience with a variety of vehicles. He has built airplanes, boats, hydrofoils, and motorcycles. He even <a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/cycle-by-wire-recumbent-trike" target="_self">built a cycle-by-wire electric trike</a> for a close friend who had been an avid cyclist but was essentially paralyzed by ALS. He also builds and restores classic cars and vintage military aircraft. He recently finished building a 1963 Porsche 356 B for his daughter. He also is converting the drivetrain of a 1974 Jaguar E-Type to an electric one.</p><p>Grosser has been a pilot for more than 40 years and has flown everything from gliders and biplanes to helicopters and seaplanes. He currently holds an Airline Transport Pilot rating certificate, which is the highest achievement of pilot certification.</p><p>His advice for would-be investors is to use the knowledge they already have. </p><p>“Courses like robotics or thermodynamics that may not have been part of your major can be integrated with whatever you’ve learned and done in software, hardware, and product design,” he says. “Any of this knowledge and experience can help you establish rapport and make more-informed selections.”</p><p><em>This article appears in the July 2022 print issue as “Adam Grosser.”</em></p>]]></description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2022 15:15:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spectrum.ieee.org/adam-grosser-profile</guid><category>Type:departments</category><category>Careers</category><category>Venture capital</category><category>Transportation</category><category>Vtol</category><category>Evtol</category><category>Flying taxi</category><dc:creator>Daniel P. Dern</dc:creator><media:content medium="image" type="image/png" url="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/man-sitting-in-front-of-a-disassembled-car-in-a-garage-with-tools-behind-him.png?id=29963584&amp;width=980"></media:content></item><item><title>From Fixing Farm Equipment to Becoming a Director at 3M</title><link>https://spectrum.ieee.org/gus-gaynor-profile</link><description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/a-photo-of-an-older-smiling-man-in-glasses.jpg?id=29959300&width=1245&height=700&coordinates=0%2C311%2C0%2C521"/><br/><br/><p><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/gus-gaynor-5652715" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Gerard “Gus” Gaynor</a> says he knew he would become an engineer when he was 7 years old, inspired by his father’s monthly <a href="https://www.popularmechanics.com/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"><em>Popular Mechanics</em></a> magazines. As his fascination with different engineering fields grew, he set out to explore them. He visited <a href="https://www.ford.com/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">a Ford</a> auto manufacturing plant in his home state of Michigan, watched the printing presses roll at the <a href="https://www.freep.com/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"><em>Detroit Free Press</em></a> plant, and listened on his crystal radio receiver to the broadcast of <a href="https://www.biography.com/historical-figure/charles-lindbergh" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Charles Lindbergh</a>’s transatlantic flight in 1927.</p><p>His enthusiasm for understanding how things work continued when, during the Great Depression, his family moved from his hometown of Detroit to a small farm in Livonia, Mich., about 32 kilometers away. He and his older brother repaired farm equipment and cars there, and they built their own chicken-plucking machine to automate the process.</p><hr/><p>“We couldn’t afford to pay [US] $350 to buy a machine at that time, so we had to build our own,” he says.</p><p>Gaynor’s hands-on experience and love of engineering led to a successful career with <a href="https://www.3m.com/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">3M</a> in St. Paul, Minn. The IEEE Life Fellow and <a href="https://cies.org/us-scholar-awards" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Fulbright</a> scholar held a variety of positions during his 25 years with the company, working his way up from instrumentation specialist to director.</p><p>Gaynor, who recently celebrated his 100th birthday, has been an active IEEE volunteer for more than three decades.</p><p>“I worked with Gus Gaynor in multiple capacities for over 30 years,” says IEEE Life Senior Member <a href="https://www.ieee.org/content/dam/ieee-org/ieee/web/org/voluntr/tab/hall-of-honor/tab-hall-of-honor-celia-desmond.pdf" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Celia Desmond</a>, a former president of the <a href="https://www.ieee-tems.org/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">IEEE Technology and Engineering Management Society</a>. “He has been consistently active through this entire time, always offering his vast knowledge of management techniques, problems, and solutions. He has been active at the board level in all the iterations of what is now [the] Technology and Engineering Management [Society], guiding many volunteers over the years. He has also been active in Technical Activities, where his influence was felt by a much wider audience. His contributions have brought incredible value to IEEE.”</p><p><strong>THE TRAVELING ENGINEER</strong></p><p>Like many people who lived through the Great Depression, Gaynor faced economic challenges that made a college degree seem unattainable. But he was determined to be an engineer. During the day he installed telecommunication equipment for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Michigan_Bell" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Michigan Bell</a>, a subsidiary of AT&T, and at night he attended the Lawrence Institute of Technology (now <a href="https://www.ltu.edu/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Lawrence Technological University</a>), in Southfield, outside of Detroit.</p><p>During that time, he joined the U.S. <a href="https://www.usar.army.mil/Portals/98/Documents/ARCD/DA%20PAM%20600-3s/SC%20DA%20PAM%20600-3.pdf?ver=2018-07-10-193039-390" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Army Signal Corps Reserve</a> and spent six months training in basic electronics. When World War II began, he was drafted to serve in Europe, where he was stationed for three years. After he was discharged, he continued his education at the <a href="https://umich.edu/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">University of Michigan</a> in Ann Arbor.</p><p>While pursuing his bachelor’s degree, he worked part time as a technician at a university research lab that had a contract with the U.S. government. He designed equipment that could measure the upper atmosphere’s temperature and pressure.</p><p>“I worked there for two years until I graduated” in 1950, he says. “I was guaranteed a job at the research lab, so I didn’t bother looking for a different one.” But just a few days before graduation, the lab’s contract with the government was terminated and Gaynor was laid off.</p><p class="pull-quote">Gaynor says the best part about being an IEEE volunteer is the camaraderie.</p><p>He found work as a technician for telephone equipment supplier <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Automatic_Electric" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Automatic Electric</a>, in Chicago. The company required incoming employees to go through a training program that taught them to install its telephone switch. Gaynor already knew how to do that. When the company wouldn’t let him skip the training, he quit.</p><p>He soon found a job at <a href="http://www.johnsonfarebox.com/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Johnson Farebox</a>, which made coin-collection systems for streetcars and buses. He was put in charge of establishing an electronics lab at the company. Its first project was to develop a device—now known as an electromagnetic flow meter—that could measure fluid movement without any interruptions in the pipe. Gaynor’s group also developed equipment for testing a streetcar’s exhaust and battery levels.</p><p>Throughout the nearly 10 years Gaynor spent there, the company moved its offices twice. First it merged with the U.S. <a href="https://www.energy.gov/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Department of Energy</a>’s <a href="https://www.energy.gov/science/history" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Office of Science</a>, and Gaynor moved his family to Washington, D.C. Two years later the company relocated to Fort Wayne, Ind.</p><p>Gaynor says the work was satisfying, and he enjoyed giving presentations to technology companies and publishing research papers. But eventually, he felt his work was becoming stagnant. In 1959 he asked to be transferred to another division, in California. His supervisor refused the request, so Gaynor resigned.</p><p>He “tried his hand at being an entrepreneur,” he says, and founded a startup in Chicago. The company developed instrumentation and process control systems for Ford, <a href="https://www.hotpoint.com/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Hotpoint</a>, <a href="https://www.nasa.gov/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">NASA</a>, the U.S. <a href="https://www.airforce.com/mission/history/overview" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Air Force</a>, and several small companies. But after three years, Gaynor took a job as an instrumentation specialist with 3M, where he worked for 25 years.</p><p>He says “3M was a very progressive company. Engineers and scientists could spend 15 percent of their time working on whatever projects they wanted.”</p><p>In 1964 3M bought an Italian company, <a href="https://www.filmferrania.com/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Ferrania Photographic Operations</a>, which made several types of film as well as inexpensive cameras. Gaynor was promoted to chief engineer there and relocated his family to Italy, where they lived for seven years. He’s most proud, he says, of turning the company’s 50-year-old plant into a successful modern photographic facility that produced triacetate film, which is the base material for photographic emulsions.</p><p>“The technologies that [the] engineers were using were backward compared to what Kodak and Fuji were using,” Gaynor says, “so we redesigned the entire operation.” It was a big investment, he remembers: “We managed to get $20 million of initial funding from 3M, but in the three years it took to complete the redesign, the company put in well over $150 million.”</p><p>He eventually became director of engineering for 3M Europe and then director of worldwide engineering for its graphic technologies sector. The sector generated approximately 25 percent of 3M’s revenue, Gaynor says.</p><p>He also chaired task forces on performance improvement in research and engineering, future trends in technology, and project management processes.</p><p>After retiring in 1987, he did consulting work for 3M and became more active in IEEE.</p><p><strong>ENTHUSIASTIC VOLUNTEER </strong></p><p>Gaynor joined the <a href="https://ethw.org/IRE_History_1912-1963#History_of_the_Institute_of_Radio_Engineers_1912-1963" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Institute of Radio Engineers</a>, one of IEEE’s predecessor societies, as a student member in 1942. He wanted to get involved with the organization then, he says, but between going to night school and working full time, he couldn’t find the extra time to do so. </p><p>It wasn’t until he was asked to attend a meeting of the <a href="https://tc-ieee.org/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">IEEE Twin Cities (Minn.) Section</a> in 1962 that he became more involved. At the talk, he met <a href="https://ethw.org/Oral-History:Joel_Snyder" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Joel Snyder</a>, who was 2001 IEEE president and “built up a very personal relationship with him,” Gaynor says. Snyder introduced him to other IEEE leaders and inspired him to become a member of the <a href="https://www.ieee.org/about/volunteers/tab.html" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">IEEE Technical Activities</a>’ finance committee, which jump-started his volunteerism.</p><p>During the past three decades, he has served on more than 10 IEEE boards and committees including the <a href="https://www.ieee.org/documents/opsmanual.pdf" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Publications Services and Products Board</a>, the <a href="https://www.ieee.org/education/eab.html" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Educational Activities Board</a>’s lifelong learning committee, and the <a href="https://www.ieee.org/about/corporate/initiatives/initiatives-committee.html" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">New Initiatives Committee</a>.</p><p>He was the founding editor of <a href="https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/search/searchresult.jsp?newsearch=true&queryText=Today%27s%20Engineer" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"><em>Today’s Engineer</em></a>, which was published by <a href="https://ieeeusa.org/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">IEEE-USA</a> to report on government legislation and issues affecting U.S. members’ careers. The 48-page magazine was discontinued after three years, but it is now available as the e-newsletter, <a href="https://insight.ieeeusa.org/about/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"><em>IEEE-USA InSight</em></a>. </p><p>Gaynor remains active. He’s currently a member of the IEEE Technology and Engineering Management Society (TEMS) and vice president of its publications.</p><p>“At the tender age of 100, Gus is a living legend in the field of technology and engineering management,” says IEEE Member <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/cws/share?url=https%3A%2F%2Fentrepreneurship.ieee.org%2Fspeaker%2F6494%2F" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Andy Chen</a>, 2021 president of IEEE TEMS. “Being the founding editor of <em>Today's Engineer</em> magazine, Gus’s contribution in the field of engineering management is well respected by scholars, researchers, and industry experts around the globe.”</p><p>Gaynor says the best part about being an IEEE volunteer is the camaraderie. He says he relishes the relationships he’s built.</p>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2022 18:00:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spectrum.ieee.org/gus-gaynor-profile</guid><category>3m</category><category>Ieee member news</category><category>Ieee technology and engineering management society</category><category>Member profile</category><category>Photography</category><category>Volunteer profile</category><category>Type:ti</category><dc:creator>Joanna Goodrich</dc:creator><media:content medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/a-photo-of-an-older-smiling-man-in-glasses.jpg?id=29959300&amp;width=980"></media:content></item><item><title>This Computer Pioneer’s Invention Made Zoom Possible</title><link>https://spectrum.ieee.org/erol-gelenbe-profile</link><description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/peter-weiner.jpg?id=29946417&width=1245&height=700&coordinates=0%2C59%2C0%2C976"/><br/><br/><p>Many IEEE members credit a parent or a teacher for encouraging them to pursue an engineering career, but for <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/erol-gelenbe-1025ba/?originalSubdomain=uk" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Erol Gelenbe</a> it was his next-door neighbor in his hometown of Ankara, Turkey.</p><p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Egbert_Adriaan_Kreiken" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Egbert Adriaan Kreiken</a>, a professor of astronomy at <a href="https://www.ankara.edu.tr/en/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Ankara University</a>, convinced the teenager that electronics engineering was going to be the “next big thing.” That was in the late 1950s.</p><p>“Kreiken told me studying anything else was absolutely crazy,” Gelenbe recalls. “He started selling the idea to me and even bribed me by promising an internship at <a href="https://www.philips.com/a-w/about.html" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Philips</a>, where he had connections. He had emigrated from the Netherlands. He kind of twisted my arm.” Philips was the largest electronics company in the world.</p><p>Because electrical engineering uses a lot of mathematics, a subject Gelenbe liked, he figured he wouldn’t be wasting his time by studying EE. He ended up loving the subject and went on to earn a bachelor’s, a master’s, and a doctoral degree, all in EE. And Kreiken did keep his promise about that internship at Philips, where Gelenbe conducted measurements on some early transistor circuits.</p><p>Riding the wave of that “next big thing” has paid off for the IEEE Fellow. He is recognized as a pioneer in the field of modeling and performance evaluation of computer systems and networks. He is best known for creating <a href="https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/BF02033314" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">G-networks</a> and random neural networks, probabilistic models inspired by the spiking behavior of neurons. An RNN can offer efficient learning algorithms for recurrent networks such as those used for cybersecurity applications and video compression.</p><p>Other technologies he invented can be found in production lines and in the first packet-based video-conferencing systems.</p><p>“For my Ph.D., I was interested in computers, but not computers in the sense of practical things,” Gelenbe says. “I was interested in computation—how computers can calculate and also by how the languages that the computers are able to process are transformed by random events that can occur for a variety of reasons. Then I became interested in the foundations of the design of computer systems and networks, and how design choices impact their performance.”</p><p>Gelenbe has spent his entire career in academia, and he has established a computer research lab at just about every university where he taught. Currently he is a professor at the <a href="https://www.iitis.pl/en" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Polish Academy of Sciences’ Institute of Theoretical and Applied Informatics</a>, in Gliwice, where he conducts research and supervises Ph.D. students.</p><p>To recognize his many contributions, this year the <a href="https://iasworld.org/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Islamic World Academy of Sciences</a> made Gelenbe an honorary Fellow. </p><p><strong>BUILDING A FIELD</strong></p><p>Gelenbe graduated in 1966 with a bachelor’s degree in engineering from <a href="https://www.metu.edu.tr/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Middle East Technical University</a>, in Ankara. He was awarded a <a href="https://us.fulbrightonline.org/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Fulbright</a> fellowship to pursue a master’s degree at Polytechnic Institute of Brooklyn (now part of <a href="https://engineering.nyu.edu/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">New York University</a>) which, in the 1960s, was considered one of the leading engineering schools. With financial support from a <a href="https://www.ndc.nato.int/research/research.php?icode=4" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">NATO</a> science fellowship, he stayed on at the school to earn a doctorate in electrical engineering in 1970.</p><p>His doctoral thesis was on stochastic automata theory, “which was an esoteric subject at that time for the foundation of computers, with impacts on digital systems and formal languages,” he says. “The results in my thesis were about how randomness can actually enhance the power of computation.”</p><p>His first teaching job was as an assistant professor of computer, information, and control engineering at the <a href="https://umich.edu/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">University of Michigan</a> in Ann Arbor. The university had one of the first computer science departments in the United States. One of the two courses he was assigned to teach each semester was on computer systems. </p><p>But Gelenbe had a problem. “I knew nothing about computer systems,” he now acknowledges with a laugh. At that time there wasn’t much literature on the field, so he says he devised explanations based on conducting research and writing research papers.</p><p>“I barely kept one step ahead of the students, researching and learning at night and teaching in the morning,” he says. “To develop a rational and systematic understanding of the subject so that I could explain it in a sensible way to the students, I was doing research about aspects that I did not understand.</p><p>“If you have something which is not really built on theory but just built on practice, you must extract or invent the theoretical elements. Through theoretical methods and math-based methods I became interested in explaining how computer systems and networks work.”</p><p>He found out that a few other professors at the time were in the same boat.</p><p>“It turned out that I was not the only poor chap or poor woman trying to do that, because some colleagues also had this problem,” he says. “The field was essentially built through the work of a few people like me who were at other universities such as Princeton and Harvard.”</p><p>He began contributing groundbreaking research himself while at Michigan. He developed queueing network models of computer systems and networks, through which he was able to establish optimum design choices for diverse issues such as computer communication protocols, optimum checkpointing in databases, and page-replacement problems in virtual memory systems.</p><p>He invented G-networks, generalized queueing networks that model both data networks and neural networks. A G-network, also known as a Gelenbe network, is used for queueing systems with specific control functions, such as data packets waiting to be transmitted to devices, like those used for network telephony. </p><p>In addition, he worked on improving the performance of multiprogramming computer systems, virtual memory management, and database reliability. He designed and built the first random-access LAN that uses fiber-optic connections, long before Ethernet became the standard.</p><p>Gelenbe says he had the most fun inventing the cognitive packet network for real-time adaptive routing in packet networks without routing tables, for which he holds a <a href="https://patents.google.com/patent/US6804201B1/en" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">patent</a>. He holds two patents for the first packet-voice telephone switch, which he designed in the 1990s. The switch is used in <a href="https://www.skype.com/en/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Skype</a> and<a href="https://zoom.us/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"> Zoom</a> video-conferencing services. He also created the <a href="https://econpapers.repec.org/article/eeeejores/v_3a53_3ay_3a1991_3ai_3a2_3ap_3a149-165.htm" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">FlexSim</a>, a computer-based model of a production system used for inventory, assembly, and transportation systems. </p><p>Not only was he inventing, he also was busy setting up computer science research labs around the world. They include the<a href="https://www.inria.fr/en/research-and-innovation" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"> Modeling and Performance Evaluation of Computer Systems research group</a> at<a href="https://www.inria.fr/en" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"> Inria</a>, the French national research institute for digital science and technology, in Paris. There is also the<a href="https://www.lri.fr/presentation_en.php" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"> Laboratory for Computer Science</a> at <a href="https://www.universite-paris-saclay.fr/en/about/universite-paris-saclay" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Université Paris-Saclay</a>; <a href="https://www.hesias.fr/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">L’école d’Informatique Hesias</a> at <a href="https://u-paris.fr/en/universite-de-paris/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Université Paris Cité</a>; and the<a href="https://www.ucf.edu/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"> </a><a href="https://www.ucf.edu/" target="_blank">University of Central Florida</a>’s <a href="https://www.ucf.edu/college/engineering-computer-science/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">college of electrical engineering and computer science</a>, in Orlando.</p><p>After retiring in 2019 from <a href="https://www.imperial.ac.uk/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Imperial College London</a>, Gelenbe joined the Polish Academy of Sciences. There he is researching energy-efficient computer systems, self-aware networks, network security, and networked auctions. He also consults for several companies. </p><p>He enjoys academia, he says, because “you’re always surrounded by young people, so you’re constantly in contact with people who are asking questions and don’t take things for granted.”</p><p><strong>ACCOLADES APLENTY</strong></p><p>Gelenbe has been elected Fellow of the French <a href="https://www.academie-technologies.fr/en/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">National Academy of Technologies</a>, the Belgian <a href="https://council.science/member/belgium-royal-academies-for-science-and-the-arts-of-belgium-rasab/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Royal Academy of Sciences, Arts, and Letters</a>, and the science academies of <a href="https://mta.hu/english/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Hungary</a>, <a href="https://pasific.pan.pl/polish-academy-of-sciences/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Poland</a>, and <a href="https://en.bilimakademisi.org/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Turkey</a>. In 2008 <a href="https://www.acm.org/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">ACM</a> awarded him its annual <a href="https://www.sigmetrics.org/awards.shtml#achievementaward" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Sigmetrics Achievement Award</a>. ACM said he was “the single individual who, over a span of 30 years, has made the greatest overall contribution to the field of computer system and network performance evaluation.” </p><p>France bestowed on him its <a href="https://www.legiondhonneur.fr/en/node/37" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Order of the Legion of Honor</a>’s chevalier award, and named him a commander of the National Order of Merit for his service to higher education and research in the country. While serving as a science and technology advisor to the French minister for universities from 1984 to 1986, he introduced computer science education to all undergraduate programs.</p><p>Italy honored him with a Commander of Merit award and named him a grand officer of the Order of the Star.</p><p><strong>UNFAIR TREATMENT</strong></p><p>Despite Gelenbe’s storied career, he has faced racism along the way.</p><p>“I’ve experienced forms of discrimination in every country I’ve been to,” he says. “Sometimes it’s blatant.”</p><p>In his first academic job in France, he says, one day he found a note written in French and posted on his office door. It said: “Immigrant worker in his Sunday best.” </p><p>“The implication was that I was an immigrant, which is true, and a worker, which is also true. I like to work hard,” he says. “All that is fine but, the ‘Sunday best<em>’</em> reference was that I was trying to look better than I should.”</p><p>Another example was an article about him that said: “Someone like that should not be a professor here, because most people who come from that same country are working in the coal mines.”</p><p>He says he hasn’t overcome the pain such comments have caused him; he’s just developed a thick skin: “I have accepted that it’s ‘normal’ that I will not get equal treatment in certain circumstances. I’ve compensated for this by the fact that I am quite gregarious and have developed connections with people.”</p><p><strong>THE VALUE OF VOLUNTEERISM</strong></p><p>Gelenbe joined IEEE as a student member because, he says, it gave him easy access to its publications—which is harder today because a subscription is needed to the <a href="https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">IEEE Xplore Digital Library</a>.</p><p>An active volunteer, he was the faculty advisor to Imperial College’s IEEE student branch. From 1979 to 1986 he chaired the <a href="http://computer.org/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">IEEE Computer Society</a>’s <a href="https://ewh.ieee.org/r8/france/cs/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">France Section</a>. He also helped found the society’s <a href="https://mascots.iitis.pl/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">International Symposium on Modeling, Analysis, and Simulation of Computer and Telecommunication Systems Conference</a>. Today he is a <a href="https://www.computer.org/profiles/erol-gelenbe" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Distinguished Visitor</a> for the society.</p><p>He says IEEE gives people in engineering professions the possibility of a career path.</p><p>“It is a way of viewing themselves not just in terms of who is employing them but also in terms of their professional standing and their professional activities, which are going to be outside of their strict job requirements. I would certainly recommend membership to anyone with a career in our fields, whether the person is an academic or not.”</p>]]></description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2022 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spectrum.ieee.org/erol-gelenbe-profile</guid><category>Ieee member news</category><category>Careers</category><category>Random neural networks</category><category>Skype</category><category>Zoom</category><category>Videoconferencing</category><category>Type:ti</category><dc:creator>Kathy Pretz</dc:creator><media:content medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/peter-weiner.jpg?id=29946417&amp;width=980"></media:content></item><item><title>Get the Coursera Campus Skills Report 2022</title><link>https://www.coursera.org/skills-reports/campus/get-report/?utm_medium=publisherplacement&amp;utm_source=ieee&amp;utm_campaign=csr-22&amp;utm_content=ieee-website-2022-05-19&amp;utm_term=</link><description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/image.png?id=29863524&width=980"/><br/><br/><p>Get comprehensive insights into higher education skill trends based on data from 3.8M registered learners on Coursera, and learn clear steps you can take to ensure your institution's engineering curriculum is aligned with the needs of the current and future job market. <a href="https://www.coursera.org/skills-reports/campus/get-report/?utm_medium=publisherplacement&utm_source=ieee&utm_campaign=csr-22&utm_content=ieee-website-2022-05-19&utm_term=" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Download the report now!</a></p>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2022 16:39:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.coursera.org/skills-reports/campus/get-report/?utm_medium=publisherplacement&amp;utm_source=ieee&amp;utm_campaign=csr-22&amp;utm_content=ieee-website-2022-05-19&amp;utm_term=</guid><category>Coursera</category><category>Careers</category><category>Education</category><category>Engineering jobs</category><category>Type:whitepaper</category><dc:creator>Coursera</dc:creator><media:content medium="image" type="image/png" url="https://assets.rbl.ms/29863524/origin.png"></media:content></item><item><title>Startup Makes It Easier to Detect Fires With IoT and Flir Cameras</title><link>https://spectrum.ieee.org/startup-fire-detection-system</link><description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/a-tablet-computer-shows-blueprints-overlaid-with-thermal-imagery.jpg?id=29844523&width=1245&height=700&coordinates=0%2C345%2C0%2C346"/><br/><br/><p>Fires at recycling sorting facilities, ignited by combustible materials in the waste stream, can cause millions of dollars in damage, injuring workers and first responders and contaminating the air.</p><p>Detecting the blazes early is key to preventing them from getting out of control.</p><hr/><p>Startup <a href="https://movitherm.com/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">MoviTHERM</a> aims to do that. The company sells cloud-based fire-detection monitoring systems to recycling facilities. Using thermal imaging and heat and smoke sensors, the system alerts users—on and off the site—when a fire is about to break out.</p><p>To date, MoviTHERM’s system operates in five recycling facilities. The company’s founder, IEEE Member <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/movimed/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Markus Tarin</a><em>,</em> says the product also can be used in coal stockpiling operations, industrial laundries, scrapyards, and warehouses.</p><p>In 1999 Tarin launched a consulting business in Irvine, Calif., to do product design and testing, mostly for medical clients. Then thermal-camera manufacturer Flir hired him to write software to automate non-contact temperature measurement processes to give Flir’s customers the ability to act quickly on temperature changes spotted by their camera.</p><p>“That was the beginning of me going into the thermal-imaging world and applying my knowledge,” he says. “I saw a lot of need out there because there weren’t very many companies doing this sort of thing.”</p><p>Tarin started MoviTHERM in 2008 to be a distributor and systems integrator for <a href="https://www.flir.com/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Flir</a> thermal imagers. The company, now with 11 employees and Tarin at the helm, is still in that business. However, Tarin became frustrated by the fact that the software he developed was not scalable; rather, it was tailored to each customer’s specific needs. And he began to discover around 2015 that interest in such custom software had fallen off.</p><p>“I could no longer easily sell a customized solution,” he says, “because it was perceived as too risky and too expensive.”</p><p class="pull-quote">“We are trying to prevent catastrophic losses and environmental damage.”</p><p><strong>INTELLIGENT MODULE</strong></p><p>In 2016 he began developing the MoviTHERM Series Intelligent I/O module (MIO). He targeted it at fire detection in recycling facilities, he says, because “we had a lot of customers reaching out for solutions in that field.”<br/></p><p>The Ethernet-connected programmable device includes eight digital alarm switches and eight channels of 4- to 20-milliampere outputs that can be used with up to seven Flir cameras. Once the module is connected to a camera, it starts monitoring. MIO can be expanded by adding more modules, Tarin says.</p><p>MoviTHERM sells the MIOs for Flirs in several versions for different camera models. Each variant supports from one to seven cameras, and they range in price from US $895 to $5,995.</p><p>MIO allows customers to “just click and connect multiple Flir cameras and set up the alarms without programming any software,” Tarin says. “The intelligent module sits on the network along with the cameras and sounds an alarm if a camera detects a hot spot,” he says. MIO won the <a href="https://www.vision-systems.com/home/article/16742105/movitherm-receives-2016-innovators-award-from-vision-systems-design" target="_blank">2016 Innovators Award</a> for industry-best product from <em>Vision Systems Design</em> magazine.</p><p>Tarin says Flir was “so fascinated by MIO that it began distributing the module worldwide.”</p><p>“It’s the only product the company is distributing that’s not a Flir product,” he says.</p><p>But, he says, that MIO series lacks the ability to send alerts to customers via voice, text, or email. It can use its built-in digital alarm outputs only to announce an alarm via a connected tool such as a siren or a flashing light.</p><p><strong>SMARTER FEATURES</strong></p><p>To add those features and more, Tarin late last year introduced MoviTHERM’s subscription-based iEFD early fire detection system, which can monitor and record a facility’s temperatures throughout the day. The system uses interconnected sensors, instruments, and other tools connected to cloud-based industrial software applications. It can check its own cameras and sensors to make sure they are working. Users can monitor and analyze data via an online dashboard.</p><p>If a camera detects a hot spot that could potentially develop into a fire, the system can send an alert to the phones of workers near the area to warn them, potentially giving them time to remove an item before it ignites, Tarin says.</p><p>The system also includes an interactive real-time map view of the facility that can be emailed to firefighters and first responders. The map can include information about the best way to access a facility and the location of utilities at the site, such as water, gas, and electricity.</p><p>“Firefighters often aren’t familiar with the facility, so they lose valuable time by driving around, figuring out how to enter the facility, and where to go,” Tarin says. “The map shows the best entry point to the facility and where the fire hydrants, water valves, electrical cabinets, gas lines, and so on are located. It also shows them where the fire is.</p><p>“We recently demonstrated this map to a fire marshal for a recycling facility, and he was blown away by it.”</p><p>By stopping fires, Tarin says, his system helps prevent toxic emissions from entering the atmosphere.</p><p>“Once you put the fire out, you have more or less an environmental disaster on your hands because you’re flushing all the hazardous stuff with fire suppressant, which itself might also be hazardous to the environment,” he says. “We are trying to prevent catastrophic losses and environmental damage.”</p>]]></description><pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2022 18:00:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spectrum.ieee.org/startup-fire-detection-system</guid><category>Ieee member news</category><category>Startups</category><category>Internet of things</category><category>Iot</category><category>Fire detection</category><category>Remote sensing</category><category>Flir</category><category>Thermal cameras</category><category>Predictive analytics</category><category>Ai</category><category>Artificial intelligence</category><category>Careers</category><category>Type:ti</category><dc:creator>Kathy Pretz</dc:creator><media:content medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/a-tablet-computer-shows-blueprints-overlaid-with-thermal-imagery.jpg?id=29844523&amp;width=980"></media:content></item></channel></rss>