<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"><channel><title>Translate</title><link>https://blog.google/products/translate/</link><description>Translate</description><atom:link href="https://blog.google/products/translate/rss/" rel="self"></atom:link><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2022 08:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/Translate_logo.max-100x100.png</url><title>Translate</title><link>https://blog.google/products/translate/</link></image><item><title>Delivering on our $1 billion commitment in Africa</title><link>https://blog.google/around-the-globe/google-africa/delivering-on-our-1b-commitment-in-africa/</link><description>&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;div class="block-paragraph"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="314zi"&gt;Last year our CEO, Sundar Pichai, announced that Google would invest $1 billion in Africa over the next five years to support a range of initiatives, from improved connectivity to investment in startups, to help boost Africa’s digital transformation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="afer1"&gt;Africa’s internet economy has the potential to grow to &lt;a href="https://www.ifc.org/wps/wcm/connect/publications_ext_content/ifc_external_publication_site/publications_listing_page/google-e-conomy"&gt;$180 billion by 2025&lt;/a&gt; – 5.2% of the continent’s GDP. To support this growth, over the last year we’ve made progress on helping to enable affordable access and on building products for every African user – helping businesses build their online presence, supporting entrepreneurs spur next-generation technologies, and helping nonprofits to improve lives across the continent.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="cuqbr"&gt;We’d like to share how we’re delivering on our commitment and partnering with others – policymakers, non-profits, businesses and creators – to make the internet more useful to more people in Africa.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 data-block-key="ann09"&gt;Introducing the first Google Cloud region in Africa&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="9b5q3"&gt;Today we’re announcing our intent to establish a Google Cloud region in South Africa – our first on the continent. South Africa will be joining Google Cloud’s &lt;a href="https://cloud.google.com/about/locations"&gt;global network&lt;/a&gt; of &lt;a href="https://cloud.google.com/about/locations"&gt;35 cloud regions and 106 zone&lt;/a&gt;s worldwide.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="1lnu0"&gt;The future cloud region in South Africa will bring Google Cloud services closer to our local customers, enabling them to innovate and securely deliver faster, more reliable experiences to their own customers, helping to accelerate their growth. According to research by AlphaBeta Economics for Google Cloud, the South Africa cloud region will contribute more than a cumulative USD 2.1 billion to the country’s GDP, and will support the creation of more than 40,000 jobs by 2030.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-image_full_width"&gt;&lt;div class="h-c-page"&gt;&lt;div class="article-image__is-caption h-c-grid__col--10 h-c-grid__col--offset-1 h-c-grid__col-l--offset-2 h-c-grid__col-l--8"&gt;&lt;a class="article-image--link"&gt;&lt;img alt="Image shows Director for Cloud in Africa, Niral Patel, next to a heading that announces Google's intent to establish its first Cloud region in Africa" class="article-image--full" data-loading='{
                "mobile": "https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/Niral_Screengrab_gB7aWHZ.max-500x500.png",
                "desktop": "https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/Niral_Screengrab_gB7aWHZ.max-1000x1000.png"
              }' loading="lazy" src=" https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/Niral_Screengrab_gB7aWHZ.max-100x100.png " tabindex="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption class="article-image__caption article-image__is-caption-image h-c-grid__col--8 h-c-grid__col--offset-2 h-c-grid__col-l--6 h-c-grid__col-l--offset-3"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="67cm8"&gt;Niral Patel, Director for Cloud in Africa announces Google's intention to establish Google's first Cloud region in Africa&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-paragraph"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="vw9iq"&gt;Along with the cloud region, we are expanding our network through the Equiano subsea cable and building Dedicated Cloud Interconnect sites in Johannesburg, Cape Town, Lagos and Nairobi. In doing so, we are building full scale Cloud capability for Africa.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 data-block-key="72vp7"&gt;Supporting African entrepreneurs&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="3s6s3"&gt;We continue to support African entrepreneurs in growing their businesses and developing their talent. Our recently announced second cohort of the &lt;a href="https://www.campus.co/africa/black-founders-fund/"&gt;Black Founders Fund&lt;/a&gt; builds on the success of last year’s cohort, who raised $97 million in follow-on funding and have employed more than 500 additional staff since they were selected. We’re also continuing our support of African small businesses through the &lt;a href="http://g.co/hustleacademy"&gt;Hustle Academy&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.google.com/business/"&gt;Google Business Profiles&lt;/a&gt;, and helping job seekers learn skills through Developer Scholarships and &lt;a href="https://grow.google/intl/ssa/google-certificates"&gt;Career Certifications&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="50p9u"&gt;We’ve also continued to support nonprofits working to improve lives in Africa, with a $40 million cash and in-kind commitment so far. Over the last year this has included:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li data-block-key="ef3pp"&gt;$1.5M investment in Career Certifications this year bringing our total Google.org funding to more than $3M since 2021&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li data-block-key="6lakd"&gt;A $3 million grant to support &lt;a href="https://www.airqo.net/"&gt;AirQo&lt;/a&gt; in expanding their work monitoring air quality from Kampala to ten cities in five countries on the continent;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li data-block-key="50sa9"&gt;A team of Googlers who have joined the &lt;a href="https://africa.googleblog.com/2022/03/helping-africans-create-their-own.html"&gt;Tony Elumelu Foundation&lt;/a&gt; for 6 months, full-time and pro-bono. The team helped build a new training web and app interface to support the next million African entrepreneurs to grow and fund their businesses.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="4d004"&gt;Across all our initiatives, we continue to work closely with our partners – most recently with the UN to launch the Global Africa Business Initiative (GABI), aimed at accelerating Africa’s economic growth and sustainable development.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 data-block-key="24d1a"&gt;Building more helpful products for Africa&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="3bjmo"&gt;We recently announced plans to open the first African product development centre in Nairobi. The centre will develop and build better products for Africans and the world.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="7v344"&gt;Today, we’re launching voice typing support for nine more African languages (isiNdebele, isiXhosa, Kinyarwanda, Northern Sotho, Swati, Sesotho, Tswana, Tshivenda and Xitsonga) in Gboard, the Google keyboard – while &lt;a href="https://blog.google/products/translate/24-new-languages/"&gt;24 new languages&lt;/a&gt; are now supported on Google Translate, including Lingala, which is spoken by more than 45 million people across Central Africa.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="fp6m3"&gt;To make Maps more useful, Street View imagery in Kenya, South Africa, Senegal and Nigeria has had a refresh with nearly 300,000 more kilometres of imagery now helping people virtually explore and navigate neighbourhoods. We’re also extending the service to Rwanda, meaning that Street View is now available in 11 African countries.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="7ar0g"&gt;In addition to &lt;a href="https://africa.googleblog.com/2022/05/google-research-enhances-its-ai-growth.html"&gt;expanding the AI Accra Research Center&lt;/a&gt; earlier this year, the&lt;a href="https://sites.research.google/open-buildings"&gt;Open Buildings&lt;/a&gt; Project, which mapped buildings across the African continent using machine learning and satellite imagery, is expanding to South and Southeast Asia and is a great example of the AI centre creating solutions for Africa that are useful across the world.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 data-block-key="5cnk2"&gt;Delivering on our promise&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="1f0kk"&gt;We remain committed to working with our partners in building for Africa together, and helping to unlock the benefits of the digital economy for more people by providing useful products, programmes and investments. We’re doing this by partnering with African organisations, businesses and entrepreneurs. It’s the talent and drive of the individuals in the countries, communities and businesses of Africa that will power Africa’s economic growth.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2022 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.google/around-the-globe/google-africa/delivering-on-our-1b-commitment-in-africa/</guid><category>Google in Africa</category><category>Google Cloud</category><category>Translate</category><category>Next Billion Users</category><media:content height="540" url="https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/Google_for_Africa_2022_logo.max-600x600.jpg" width="540"></media:content><og xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#"><type>article</type><title>Delivering on our $1 billion commitment in Africa</title><description>How we're partnering with policymakers, non-profits, businesses and creators to make the internet more useful to more people in Africa.</description><image>https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/Google_for_Africa_2022_logo.max-600x600.jpg</image><site_name>Google</site_name><url>https://blog.google/around-the-globe/google-africa/delivering-on-our-1b-commitment-in-africa/</url></og><author xmlns:author="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><name>Nitin Gajria</name><title>Managing Director, Google Sub-Saharan Africa</title><department></department><company></company></author></item><item><title>5 of our favorite Android widget features</title><link>https://blog.google/products/android/5-of-our-favorite-android-widget-features/</link><description>&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;div class="block-paragraph"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="n99eo"&gt;Widgets are a simple way to personalize any Home screen, putting the information that’s most important to you — your inbox, the weather, your to-do list or even a photo of your dog — front and center.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="fqush"&gt;With the upcoming launch of the nearby traffic widget for Google Maps (more on that soon), 35 Google widgets will be available on Android. To celebrate, we’re spotlighting five of our favorite widget features to help everyone better organize and personalize their Home screens.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 data-block-key="cn452"&gt;Check local traffic with a tap&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="jfej"&gt;Whether you’re commuting or heading out to meet friends, Google Maps’ &lt;a href="https://blog.google/products/maps/google-maps-101-how-ai-helps-predict-traffic-and-determine-routes/"&gt;real-time traffic predictions&lt;/a&gt; can help you easily plan your route. And with the new nearby traffic widget, launching in the coming weeks, you’ll see this information for your current location right from your Android Home screen. So if you're about to leave home, work, school or anywhere else, you’ll know at a glance exactly what local traffic might be like. And because Android widgets are tappable, you can zoom in and out without opening the Maps app.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-image_full_width"&gt;&lt;div class="h-c-page"&gt;&lt;div class="article-image h-c-grid__col-l--6 h-c-grid__col--8 h-c-grid__col-l--offset-3 h-c-grid__col--offset-2"&gt;&lt;a class="article-image--link"&gt;&lt;img alt="Dark green Android wallpaper showing a bamboo palm with the Google nearby traffic widget laid over the top. The widget shows a local map of traffic levels and zooms in and out." class="article-image--large" src=" https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/original_images/Maps-Zoom.gif " tabindex="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-paragraph"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;h3 data-block-key="n99eo"&gt;Tap to instantly archive emails&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="28dst"&gt;The Gmail widget is a simple way to keep your inbox organized. Just tap to archive an email when it hits your inbox, without having to open the Gmail app.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-image_full_width"&gt;&lt;div class="h-c-page"&gt;&lt;div class="article-image h-c-grid__col-l--6 h-c-grid__col--8 h-c-grid__col-l--offset-3 h-c-grid__col--offset-2"&gt;&lt;a class="article-image--link"&gt;&lt;img alt="An Android background with light purple orchids. In the foreground, the Gmail widget animates through the archive feature. An email arrives in the inbox, the archive button is tapped and the email disappears." class="article-image--large" src=" https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/original_images/Gmail-Archive_1.gif " tabindex="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-paragraph"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;h3 data-block-key="n99eo"&gt;Scroll through your to-do list&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="3epvb"&gt;Lots of you love the scrollable to-do list in the Keep widget. It’s an easy way to keep track of your tasks for the day, and there’s nothing quite as satisfying as crossing them off when you’re done — except maybe scrolling back up to see everything you accomplished.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-image_full_width"&gt;&lt;div class="h-c-page"&gt;&lt;div class="article-image h-c-grid__col-l--6 h-c-grid__col--8 h-c-grid__col-l--offset-3 h-c-grid__col--offset-2"&gt;&lt;a class="article-image--link"&gt;&lt;img alt="A light peach-colored pastel background, with the Google Keep widget in the foreground. The widget scrolls through a list of items to pack for vacation." class="article-image--large" src=" https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/original_images/Keep-Scroll.gif " tabindex="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-paragraph"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;h3 data-block-key="n99eo"&gt;Skim through your favorite translations&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="bu1fq"&gt;The Google Translate widget’s scrolling feature can help you stay organized, too. If you need to keep certain phrases handy while you’re traveling or speaking with friends and family, you can set them up to always appear on your Home Screen. Just star your favorite translations in the app and you’ll see them right on the widget.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-image_full_width"&gt;&lt;div class="h-c-page"&gt;&lt;div class="article-image h-c-grid__col-l--6 h-c-grid__col--8 h-c-grid__col-l--offset-3 h-c-grid__col--offset-2"&gt;&lt;a class="article-image--link"&gt;&lt;img alt="Light orange Android wallpaper of a flower stamen. In the foreground a user scrolls through the Google translate widget, with selected saved translations to use." class="article-image--large" src=" https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/original_images/Translate-Scroll.gif " tabindex="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-paragraph"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;h3 data-block-key="c7yjb"&gt;Resize widgets to fit your needs&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="9k0be"&gt;Android widgets are easy to resize and even change shape to help you declutter your Home screen — while keeping helpful features intact. For example, if you make the Drive widget smaller, it’ll turn into a toolbar so you can still quickly search for your files.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-image_full_width"&gt;&lt;div class="h-c-page"&gt;&lt;div class="article-image h-c-grid__col-l--6 h-c-grid__col--8 h-c-grid__col-l--offset-3 h-c-grid__col--offset-2"&gt;&lt;a class="article-image--link"&gt;&lt;img alt="Light green Android wallpaper showing a green flower. In the foreground, an animation of different Google Drive widgets resizes." class="article-image--large" src=" https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/original_images/Drive-Resize_7zNQlXU.gif " tabindex="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2022 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.google/products/android/5-of-our-favorite-android-widget-features/</guid><category>Google Workspace</category><category>Android</category><category>Maps</category><category>Translate</category><media:content height="540" url="https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/Hero_2aWpH4B.max-600x600.png" width="540"></media:content><og xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#"><type>article</type><title>5 of our favorite Android widget features</title><description>Android widgets are an easy way to personalize your Home screen, putting the actions and information that’s most important to you, front and center.</description><image>https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/Hero_2aWpH4B.max-600x600.png</image><site_name>Google</site_name><url>https://blog.google/products/android/5-of-our-favorite-android-widget-features/</url></og><author xmlns:author="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><name>Luke Wroblewski</name><title>Product Director</title><department></department><company></company></author></item><item><title>Google Translate learns 24 new languages</title><link>https://blog.google/products/translate/24-new-languages/</link><description>&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;div class="block-paragraph"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="4uazy"&gt;For years, Google Translate has helped break down language barriers and connect communities all over the world. And we want to make this possible for even more people — especially those whose languages aren’t represented in most technology. So today we’ve added 24 languages to Translate, now supporting a total of 133 used around the globe.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="adr67"&gt;Over 300 million people speak these newly added languages — like Mizo, used by around 800,000 people in the far northeast of India, and Lingala, used by over 45 million people across Central Africa. As part of this update, Indigenous languages of the Americas (Quechua, Guarani and Aymara) and an English dialect (Sierra Leonean Krio) have also been added to Translate for the first time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-image_full_width"&gt;&lt;div class="h-c-page"&gt;&lt;div class="article-image__is-caption h-c-grid__col--10 h-c-grid__col--offset-1 h-c-grid__col-l--offset-2 h-c-grid__col-l--8"&gt;&lt;a class="article-image--link"&gt;&lt;img alt='The Google Translate bar translates the phrase "Our mission: to enable everyone, everywhere to understand the world and express themselves across languages" into different languages.' class="article-image--full" src=" https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/original_images/Translate_New-Languages.gif " tabindex="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption class="article-image__caption article-image__is-caption-image h-c-grid__col--8 h-c-grid__col--offset-2 h-c-grid__col-l--6 h-c-grid__col-l--offset-3"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="d1el0"&gt;Translate's mission translated into some of our newly added languages&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-paragraph"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="4uazy"&gt;Here’s a complete list of the new languages now available in Google Translate:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li data-block-key="f6knl"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Assamese&lt;/b&gt;, used by about 25 million people in Northeast India&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li data-block-key="dau5c"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Aymara&lt;/b&gt;, used by about two million people in Bolivia, Chile and Peru&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li data-block-key="64os2"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Bambara&lt;/b&gt;, used by about 14 million people in Mali&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li data-block-key="c3iis"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Bhojpuri&lt;/b&gt;, used by about 50 million people in northern India, Nepal and Fiji&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li data-block-key="2dfs5"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Dhivehi&lt;/b&gt;, used by about 300,000 people in the Maldives&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li data-block-key="fb4fc"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Dogri&lt;/b&gt;, used by about three million people in northern India&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li data-block-key="9tr4g"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Ewe&lt;/b&gt;, used by about seven million people in Ghana and Togo&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li data-block-key="2pcs4"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Guarani&lt;/b&gt;, used by about seven million people in Paraguay and Bolivia, Argentina and Brazil&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li data-block-key="anklc"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Ilocano&lt;/b&gt;, used by about 10 million people in northern Philippines&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li data-block-key="5kv0r"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Konkani&lt;/b&gt;, used by about two million people in Central India&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li data-block-key="3lquf"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Krio&lt;/b&gt;, used by about four million people in Sierra Leone&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li data-block-key="b6k5n"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Kurdish (Sorani)&lt;/b&gt;, used by about 15 million people in Iraq and Iran&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li data-block-key="14aq9"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Lingala&lt;/b&gt;, used by about 45 million people in the Democratic Republic of the Congo, Republic of the Congo, Central African Republic, Angola and the Republic of South Sudan&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li data-block-key="83bb"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Luganda&lt;/b&gt;, used by about 20 million people in Uganda and Rwanda&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li data-block-key="a831f"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Maithili&lt;/b&gt;, used by about 34 million people in northern India&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li data-block-key="f1cj"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Meiteilon (Manipuri)&lt;/b&gt;, used by about two million people in Northeast India&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li data-block-key="hld5"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Mizo&lt;/b&gt;, used by about 830,000 people in Northeast India&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li data-block-key="g5d6"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Oromo&lt;/b&gt;, used by about 37 million people in Ethiopia and Kenya&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li data-block-key="3ia76"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Quechua&lt;/b&gt;, used by about 10 million people in Peru, Bolivia, Ecuador and surrounding countries&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li data-block-key="eqcsd"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Sanskrit&lt;/b&gt;, used by about 20,000 people in India&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li data-block-key="5udlv"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Sepedi&lt;/b&gt;, used by about 14 million people in South Africa&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li data-block-key="2clhp"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Tigrinya&lt;/b&gt;, used by about eight million people in Eritrea and Ethiopia&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li data-block-key="75crg"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Tsonga&lt;/b&gt;, used by about seven million people in Eswatini, Mozambique, South Africa and Zimbabwe&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li data-block-key="2nn1f"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Twi&lt;/b&gt;, used by about 11 million people in Ghana&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="ftfro"&gt;This is also a technical milestone for Google Translate. These are the first languages we’ve added using Zero-Shot Machine Translation, where a machine learning model only sees monolingual text — meaning, it learns to translate into another language without ever seeing an example. While this technology is impressive, it isn't perfect. And we’ll keep improving these models to deliver the same experience you’re used to with a Spanish or German translation, for example. If you want to dig into the technical details, check out our &lt;a href="http://ai.googleblog.com/2022/05/24-new-languages-google-translate.html"&gt;Google AI blog post&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/2205.03983.pdf"&gt;research paper&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p data-block-key="elebt"&gt;We’re grateful to the many native speakers, professors and linguists who worked with us on this latest update and kept us inspired with their passion and enthusiasm. If you want to help us support your language in a future update, contribute evaluations or translations through &lt;a href="https://support.google.com/translate/answer/2534530?hl=en"&gt;Translate Contribute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2022 17:16:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.google/products/translate/24-new-languages/</guid><category>Translate</category><category>Next Billion Users</category><category>Diversity and Inclusion</category><category>AI</category><media:content height="540" url="https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/io_2022_heroes_translate-11.max-600x600.jpg" width="540"></media:content><og xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#"><type>article</type><title>Google Translate learns 24 new languages</title><description>Google Translate adds 24 new languages, including Indigenous languages of the Americas and languages from around Africa and India.</description><image>https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/io_2022_heroes_translate-11.max-600x600.jpg</image><site_name>Google</site_name><url>https://blog.google/products/translate/24-new-languages/</url></og><author xmlns:author="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><name>Isaac Caswell</name><title>Senior Software Engineer, Google Translate</title><department></department><company></company></author></item><item><title>Google Translate: One billion installs, one billion stories</title><link>https://blog.google/products/translate/one-billion-installs/</link><description>&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;div class="block-paragraph"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;p&gt;When my wife and I were flying home from a trip to France a few years ago, our seatmate had just spent a few months exploring the French countryside and staying in small inns. When he learned that I worked on Google Translate, he got excited. He told me Translate’s conversation mode helped him chat with his hosts about family, politics, culture and more. Thanks to Translate, he said, he connected more deeply with people around him while in France.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The passenger I met isn't alone. Google Translate on Android hit one billion installs from the &lt;a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.google.android.apps.translate"&gt;Google Play Store&lt;/a&gt; this March, and each one represents a story of people being able to better connect with one another. By understanding 109 languages (and counting!), Translate enables conversation and communication between millions of people which otherwise would have been impossible. And Translate itself has gone through countless changes on the path to one billion installs. Here’s how it has evolved so far.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-paragraph_with_image"&gt;&lt;div class="article-module h-c-page"&gt;&lt;div class="h-c-grid uni-paragraph-wrap"&gt;&lt;div class="uni-paragraph h-c-grid__col h-c-grid__col--8 h-c-grid__col-m--6 h-c-grid__col-l--6 h-c-grid__col--offset-2 h-c-grid__col-m--offset-3 h-c-grid__col-l--offset-3" data-component="uni-article-paragraph"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-image_full_width"&gt;&lt;div class="h-c-page"&gt;&lt;div class="article-image h-c-grid__col-l--6 h-c-grid__col--8 h-c-grid__col-l--offset-3 h-c-grid__col--offset-2"&gt;&lt;a class="article-image--link"&gt;&lt;img alt="An animation showing a person using Google Lens on a smartphone, taking a picture of a sign in Russian that is translated to “Access to City.”" class="article-image--large" src=" https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/original_images/Google-Word-Lens_4vHEvUA.gif " tabindex="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-paragraph"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;November 2015: 300+ million&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;As it approached 300 million installs, Translate improved in two major ways. First, revamping Translate's conversation mode enabled two people to converse with each other despite speaking different languages, helping people in their everyday lives, as featured in the video &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2RB4yWmzG-4"&gt;From Syria to Canada&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-video"&gt;&lt;div class="h-c-page h-c-page--mobile-full-bleed"&gt;&lt;div class="h-c-grid"&gt;&lt;div class="h-c-grid__col h-c-grid__col-l--10 h-c-grid__col-l--offset-1"&gt;&lt;div class="article-module uni-article-video uni-article-video--body" data-component="uni-article-yt-player" data-page-title="" data-video-id="2RB4yWmzG-4"&gt;&lt;div class="uni-article-video__embed-container hidden"&gt;&lt;div id="uni-article-yt-player-2RB4yWmzG-4"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;a class="h-c-video h-c-video--marquee uni-article-video__custom-wrapper" role="link" tabindex="0"&gt;&lt;div class="uni-article-video__aspect-image"&gt;&lt;img alt="A mother looking at a tablet and reading aloud to two children." data-loading='{
                        "mobile": "https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/From_Syria_to_Canada_video_thumbnail.max-500x500.png",
                        "desktop": "https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/From_Syria_to_Canada_video_thumbnail.max-1000x1000.png"
                      }' loading="lazy" src="https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/From_Syria_to_Canada_video_thumbnail.max-100x100.png"/&gt;&lt;div class="uni-article-video__dimmer"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;svg class="uni-article-video__play-button--active" role="img"&gt;&lt;use xlink:href="#yt_video_play_button_no_hole"&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;svg class="uni-article-video__play-button" role="img"&gt;&lt;use xlink:href="#yt_video_play_button"&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;div class="uni-article-video__duration loading"&gt;&lt;svg class="uni-article-video__duration-icon" role="img"&gt;&lt;use xlink:href="#yt_video_duration"&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;span class="uni-article-video__duration-time"&gt;10:25&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-paragraph_with_image"&gt;&lt;div class="article-module h-c-page"&gt;&lt;div class="h-c-grid uni-paragraph-wrap"&gt;&lt;div class="uni-paragraph h-c-grid__col h-c-grid__col--8 h-c-grid__col-m--6 h-c-grid__col-l--6 h-c-grid__col--offset-2 h-c-grid__col-m--offset-3 h-c-grid__col-l--offset-3" data-component="uni-article-paragraph"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-paragraph_with_image"&gt;&lt;div class="article-module h-c-page"&gt;&lt;div class="h-c-grid uni-paragraph-wrap"&gt;&lt;div class="uni-paragraph h-c-grid__col h-c-grid__col--8 h-c-grid__col-m--6 h-c-grid__col-l--6 h-c-grid__col--offset-2 h-c-grid__col-m--offset-3 h-c-grid__col-l--offset-3" data-component="uni-article-paragraph"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-perspective_qa"&gt;&lt;div class="uni-related-article-tout h-c-page" data-component="uni-related-article-tout"&gt;&lt;section class="h-c-grid"&gt;&lt;div class="uni-related-article-tout__wrapper h-c-grid__col h-c-grid__col--8 h-c-grid__col-m--6 h-c-grid__col-l--6 h-c-grid__col--offset-2 h-c-grid__col-m--offset-3 h-c-grid__col-l--offset-3"&gt;&lt;div class="uni-related-article-tout__inner-wrapper uni-related-article-tout__inner-wrapper--top-16"&gt;&lt;p class="uni-related-article-tout__eyebrow uni-related-article-tout__eyebrow--light"&gt;Latest stories&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="uni-related-article-tout__content-wrapper"&gt;&lt;div class="uni-related-article-tout__content uni-related-article-tout__content--text-only"&gt;&lt;a class="uni-related-article-tout__link uni-click-tracker" data-analytics='{
                       "event": "page interaction",
                       "category": "article lead",
                       "action": "related article - inline text",
                       "label": "article: ten-years-of-google-translate"
                     }' href="https://blog.google/products/translate/ten-years-of-google-translate/"&gt;&lt;p class="uni-related-article-tout__text"&gt;Ten years of Google Translate&lt;/p&gt;&lt;svg class="uni-related-article-tout__arrow" data-target="arrow" role="img"&gt;&lt;use xlink:href="#mi-arrow-forward-no-bg"&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/section&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Apr 2021 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.google/products/translate/one-billion-installs/</guid><category>Translate</category><media:content height="540" url="https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/Translate-hero-image.max-600x600.png" width="540"></media:content><og xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#"><type>article</type><title>Google Translate: One billion installs, one billion stories</title><description>Here’s how Google Translate has changed over the years as it grew to more than one billion installs.</description><image>https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/Translate-hero-image.max-600x600.png</image><site_name>Google</site_name><url>https://blog.google/products/translate/one-billion-installs/</url></og><author xmlns:author="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><name>Jeff Pitman</name><title>Engineering Manager</title><department>Google Translate</department><company></company></author></item><item><title>Now you can transcribe speech with Google Translate</title><link>https://blog.google/products/translate/transcribe-speech/</link><description>&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;div class="block-paragraph"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Recently, I was at my friend’s family gathering, where her grandmother told a story from her childhood. I could see that she was excited to share it with everyone but there was a problem—she told the story in Spanish, a language that I don’t understand. I pulled out Google Translate to transcribe the speech as it was happening. As she was telling the story, the English translation appeared on my phone so that I could follow along—it fostered a moment of understanding that would have otherwise been lost. And now anyone can do this—starting today, you can use the Google Translate Android app to transcribe foreign language speech as it’s happening.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Transcribe will be rolling out in the next few days with support for any combination of the following eight languages: English, French, German, Hindi, Portuguese, Russian, Spanish and Thai. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-image_full_width"&gt;&lt;div class="h-c-page"&gt;&lt;div class="article-image__is-caption h-c-grid__col-l--2 h-c-grid__col--4 h-c-grid__col-l--offset-5 h-c-grid__col--offset-4"&gt;&lt;a class="article-image--link"&gt;&lt;img alt="Ongoing translated transcript" class="article-image--small" src=" https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/original_images/transcribe_v1_gif_-_for_blogpost.gif " tabindex="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption class="article-image__caption article-image__is-caption-image h-c-grid__col--8 h-c-grid__col--offset-2 h-c-grid__col-l--6 h-c-grid__col-l--offset-3"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-paragraph"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;p&gt;To try the transcribe feature, go to your &lt;a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.google.android.apps.translate"&gt;Translate app on Android&lt;/a&gt;, and make sure you have the latest updates from the Play store. Tap on the “Transcribe” icon from the home screen and select the source and target languages from the language dropdown at the top. You can pause or restart transcription by tapping on the mic icon. You also can see the original transcript, change the text size or choose a dark theme in the settings menu. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-image_full_width"&gt;&lt;div class="h-c-page"&gt;&lt;div class="article-image__is-caption h-c-grid__col-l--6 h-c-grid__col--8 h-c-grid__col-l--offset-3 h-c-grid__col--offset-2"&gt;&lt;a class="article-image--link"&gt;&lt;img alt="On the left: redesigned home screen, On the right:  change settings for a comfortable read" class="article-image--large" data-loading='{
                "mobile": "https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/pasted_image_0_6_mXkbb74.max-500x500.png",
                "desktop": "https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/pasted_image_0_6_mXkbb74.max-1000x1000.png"
              }' loading="lazy" src=" https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/pasted_image_0_6_mXkbb74.max-100x100.png " tabindex="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption class="article-image__caption article-image__is-caption-image h-c-grid__col--8 h-c-grid__col--offset-2 h-c-grid__col-l--6 h-c-grid__col-l--offset-3"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;p&gt;On the left: redesigned home screen. On the right: how to change the settings for a comfortable read.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-paragraph"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;p&gt;We’ll continue to make speech translations available in a variety of situations. Right now, the transcribe feature will work best in a quiet environment with one person speaking at a time. In other situations, the app will still do its best to provide the gist of what's being said. &lt;a href="https://support.google.com/translate/answer/6142474?co=GENIE.Platform%3DAndroid&amp;amp;hl=en"&gt;Conversation mode&lt;/a&gt; in the app will continue to help you to have a back and forth translated conversation with someone.  &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Try it out and give us &lt;a href="https://support.google.com/translate/community"&gt;feedback&lt;/a&gt; on how we can be better. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Mar 2020 16:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.google/products/translate/transcribe-speech/</guid><category>Android</category><category>Translate</category><og xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#"><type>article</type><title>Now you can transcribe speech with Google Translate</title><description>With the Transcribe feature in the Google Translate Android app you can transcribe a speech in a foreign language as it is happening.</description><site_name>Google</site_name><url>https://blog.google/products/translate/transcribe-speech/</url></og><author xmlns:author="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><name>Sami Iqram</name><title>Product Manager, Google Translate</title><department></department><company></company></author></item><item><title>Google Translate adds five languages</title><link>https://blog.google/products/translate/five-new-languages/</link><description>&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;div class="block-paragraph"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Millions of people around the world use Google Translate, whether in a verbal conversation, or while navigating a menu or reading a webpage online. Translate learns from existing translations, which are most often found on the web. Languages without a lot of web content have traditionally been challenging to translate, but through advancements in our machine learning technology, coupled with active involvement of the &lt;a href="https://translate.google.com/community"&gt;Google Translate Community&lt;/a&gt;, we’ve added support for five languages: Kinyarwanda, Odia (Oriya), Tatar, Turkmen and Uyghur. These languages, spoken by more than 75 million people worldwide, are the first languages we’ve added to Google Translate in four years, and expand the capabilities of Google Translate to 108 languages.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Translate supports both text translation and website translation for each of these languages. In addition, Translate supports &lt;a href="https://www.google.com/inputtools/services/features/virtual-keyboard.html"&gt;virtual keyboard input&lt;/a&gt; for Kinyarwanda, Tatar and Uyghur. Below you can see our team motto, “Enable everyone, everywhere to understand the world and express themselves across languages,” translated into the five new languages. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-image_full_width"&gt;&lt;div class="h-c-page"&gt;&lt;div class="article-image h-c-grid__col--10 h-c-grid__col--offset-1 h-c-grid__col-l--offset-2 h-c-grid__col-l--8"&gt;&lt;a class="article-image--link"&gt;&lt;img alt="Translate Mission.gif" class="article-image--full" src=" https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/original_images/V2.gif " tabindex="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-paragraph"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you speak any of these languages and are interested in helping, please join the &lt;a href="https://translate.google.com/community"&gt;Google Translate Community&lt;/a&gt; and improve our translations.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2020 17:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.google/products/translate/five-new-languages/</guid><category>Translate</category><category>Next Billion Users</category><og xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#"><type>article</type><title>Google Translate adds five languages</title><description>Google Translate added five new languages: Kinyarwanda, Odia (Oriya), Tatar, Turkmen, and Uyghur.</description><site_name>Google</site_name><url>https://blog.google/products/translate/five-new-languages/</url></og><author xmlns:author="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><name>Isaac Caswell</name><title>Senior Software Engineer, Google Translate</title><department></department><company></company></author></item><item><title>Google Translate improves offline translation</title><link>https://blog.google/products/translate/offline-translation/</link><description>&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;div class="block-paragraph"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;p&gt;When you’re traveling somewhere without access to the internet or don’t want to use your data plan, you can still use the Google Translate app on Android and iOS when your phone is offline. Offline translation is getting better: now, in 59 languages, offline translation is 12 percent more accurate, with improved word choice, grammar and sentence structure. In some languages like Japanese, Korean, Thai, Polish, and Hindi the quality gain is more than 20 percent. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-image_full_width"&gt;&lt;div class="h-c-page"&gt;&lt;div class="article-image h-c-grid__col-l--6 h-c-grid__col--8 h-c-grid__col-l--offset-3 h-c-grid__col--offset-2"&gt;&lt;a class="article-image--link"&gt;&lt;img alt="translation.png" class="article-image--large" data-loading='{
                "mobile": "https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/translation_0Woh7mF.max-500x500.png",
                "desktop": "https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/translation_0Woh7mF.max-1000x1000.png"
              }' loading="lazy" src=" https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/translation_0Woh7mF.max-100x100.png " tabindex="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-paragraph"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;p&gt;It can be particularly hard to pronounce and spell words in languages that are written in a script you're not familiar with. To help you in these cases, Translate offers transliteration, which gives an equivalent spelling in the alphabet you're used to. For example, when you translate “hello” to Hindi, you will see “नमस्ते” and “namaste” in the translation card where “namaste” is the transliteration of “नमस्ते.” This is a great tool for learning how to communicate in a different language, and Translate has offline transliteration support for 10 new languages: Arabic, Bengali, Gujarati, Kannada, Marathi, Tamil, Telugu and Urdu.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-image_full_width"&gt;&lt;div class="h-c-page"&gt;&lt;div class="article-image h-c-grid__col-l--4 h-c-grid__col--6 h-c-grid__col-l--offset-4 h-c-grid__col--offset-3"&gt;&lt;a class="article-image--link"&gt;&lt;img alt="Transliteration" class="article-image--medium" data-loading='{
                "mobile": "https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/transliteration_-_phone_frame_-_zoom_in.max-500x500.png",
                "desktop": "https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/transliteration_-_phone_frame_-_zoom_in.max-1000x1000.png"
              }' loading="lazy" src=" https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/transliteration_-_phone_frame_-_zoom_in.max-100x100.png " tabindex="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-paragraph"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;To try our improved offline translation and transliteration, go to your Translate app on Android or iOS. If you do not have the app, you can &lt;a href="https://translate.google.com/about/index.html"&gt;download it.&lt;/a&gt; Make sure you have the latest updates from the Play or App store. If you’ve used offline translation before, you’ll see a banner on your home screen that will take you to the right place to update your offline files. If not, go to your offline translation settings and tap the arrow next to the language name to download that language. Now you’ll be ready to translate text whether you’re online or not.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2019 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.google/products/translate/offline-translation/</guid><category>Translate</category><og xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#"><type>article</type><title>Google Translate improves offline translation</title><description>In 59 languages, offline translation is 12 percent more accurate.</description><site_name>Google</site_name><url>https://blog.google/products/translate/offline-translation/</url></og><author xmlns:author="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><name>Sami Iqram</name><title>Product Manager, Google Translate</title><department></department><company></company></author></item><item><title>Speak easy while traveling with Google Maps</title><link>https://blog.google/products/maps/speak-easy-while-traveling/</link><description>&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;div class="block-paragraph"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Google Maps has made travel easier than ever before. You can scout out a neighborhood before booking a hotel, get directions on the go and even see what nearby restaurants the locals recommend thanks to auto-translated reviews.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But when you're in a foreign country where you don't speak or read the language, getting around can still be difficult -- especially when you need to speak with someone. Think about that anxiety-inducing time you tried to talk to a taxi driver, or that moment you tried to casually ask a passerby for directions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;To help, we're bringing Google Maps and Google Translate closer together. This month, we’re adding a new translator feature that enables your phone to speak out a place's name and address in the local lingo. Simply tap the new speaker button next to the place name or address, and Google Maps will say it out loud, making your next trip that much simpler. And when you want to have a deeper conversation, Google Maps will quickly link you to the Google Translate app.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-image_full_width"&gt;&lt;div class="h-c-page"&gt;&lt;div class="article-image h-c-grid__col-l--6 h-c-grid__col--8 h-c-grid__col-l--offset-3 h-c-grid__col--offset-2"&gt;&lt;a class="article-image--link"&gt;&lt;img alt="Google_SpeakEasy_GIF_191018.gif" class="article-image--large" src=" https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/original_images/Google_SpeakEasy_GIF_191018.gif " tabindex="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-paragraph"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;p&gt;This text-to-speech technology automatically detects what language your phone is using to determine which places you might need help translating. For instance, if your phone is set to English and you’re looking at a place of interest in Tokyo, you’ll see the new speaker icon next to the place’s name and address so you can get a real-time translation. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The new feature will be rolling out this month on Android and iOS with support for 50 languages and more on the way. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2019 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.google/products/maps/speak-easy-while-traveling/</guid><category>Translate</category><category>Maps</category><media:content height="540" url="https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/original_images/Keyword_post_hero.gif" width="540"></media:content><og xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#"><type>article</type><title>Speak easy while traveling with Google Maps</title><description>Google Maps now translates and speaks names and addresses of places for you when you don’t know the local language.</description><image>https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/original_images/Keyword_post_hero.gif</image><site_name>Google</site_name><url>https://blog.google/products/maps/speak-easy-while-traveling/</url></og><author xmlns:author="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><name>Laszlo de Brissac</name><title>Product Manager, Google Maps</title><department></department><company></company></author></item><item><title>Google Translate’s instant camera translation gets an upgrade</title><link>https://blog.google/products/translate/google-translates-instant-camera-translation-gets-upgrade/</link><description>&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;div class="block-paragraph"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Google Translate allows you to explore unfamiliar lands, communicate in different languages, and make connections that would be otherwise impossible. One of my favorite features on the &lt;a href="https://translate.google.com/about"&gt;Google Translate mobile app&lt;/a&gt; is instant camera translation, which allows you to see the world in your language by just pointing your camera lens at the foreign text. Similar to the real-time translation feature we recently launched in &lt;a href="https://www.blog.google/products/search/helpful-new-visual-features-search-lens-io/"&gt;Google Lens&lt;/a&gt;, this is an intuitive way to understand your surroundings, and it’s especially helpful when you’re traveling abroad as it works even when you’re not connected to Wi-Fi or using cellular data. Today, we’re launching new upgrades to this feature, so that it’s even more useful.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-image_full_width"&gt;&lt;div class="h-c-page"&gt;&lt;div class="article-image h-c-grid__col-l--4 h-c-grid__col--6 h-c-grid__col-l--offset-4 h-c-grid__col--offset-3"&gt;&lt;a class="article-image--link"&gt;&lt;img alt="Instant camera translation.gif" class="article-image--medium" src=" https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/original_images/optics.gif " tabindex="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-paragraph"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Translate from 88 languages into 100+ languages&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;The instant camera translation adds support for 60 more languages, such as Arabic, Hindi, Malay, Thai and Vietnamese. &lt;a href="https://support.google.com/translate/answer/6142483?ref_topic=7011659"&gt;Here’s a full list&lt;/a&gt; of all 88 supported languages.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;What’s more exciting is that, previously you could only translate between English and other languages, but now you can translate into any of the 100+ languages supported on Google Translate. This means you can now translate from Arabic to French, or from Japanese to Chinese, etc. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Automatically detect the language&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;When traveling abroad, especially in a region with multiple languages, it can be challenging for people to determine the language of the text that they need to translate. We took care of that—in the new version of the app, you can just select “Detect language” as the source language, and the Translate app will automatically detect the language and translate. Say you’re traveling through South America, where both Portuguese and Spanish are spoken, and you encounter a sign. Translate app can now determine what language the sign is in, and then translate it for you into your language of choice.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Better translations powered by Neural Machine Translation&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;For the first time, Neural Machine Translation (NMT) technology is built into instant camera translations. This produces &lt;a href="https://ai.googleblog.com/2016/09/a-neural-network-for-machine.html"&gt;more accurate&lt;/a&gt; and natural translations, reducing errors by 55-85 percent in certain language pairs. And most of the languages can be downloaded onto your device, so that you can use the feature without an internet connection. However, when your device is connected to the internet, the feature uses that connection to produce higher quality translations.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;A new look&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Last but not least, the feature has a new look and is more intuitive to use. In the past, you might have noticed the translated text would flicker when viewed on your phone, making it difficult to read. We’ve reduced that flickering, making the text more stable and easier to understand. The new look has all three camera translation features conveniently located on the bottom of the app: “Instant” translates foreign text when you point your camera at it. "Scan" lets you take a photo and use your finger to highlight text you want translated. And “Import” lets you translate text from photos on your camera roll. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;To try out the the instant camera translation feature, &lt;a href="https://translate.google.com/about/index.html"&gt;download the Google Translate app&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2019 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.google/products/translate/google-translates-instant-camera-translation-gets-upgrade/</guid><category>Translate</category><category>AI</category><og xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#"><type>article</type><title>Google Translate’s instant camera translation gets an upgrade</title><description>Google Translate adds new languages, source language auto-detect, and increased accuracy to its instant camera translations feature.</description><site_name>Google</site_name><url>https://blog.google/products/translate/google-translates-instant-camera-translation-gets-upgrade/</url></og><author xmlns:author="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><name>Xinxing Gu</name><title>Product Manager</title><department>Google Translate</department><company></company></author></item><item><title>Reducing gender bias in Google Translate</title><link>https://blog.google/products/translate/reducing-gender-bias-google-translate/</link><description>&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;div class="block-paragraph"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Over the course of this year, there’s been an effort across Google to &lt;a href="https://ai.google/education/responsible-ai-practices?category=fairness"&gt;promote fairness and reduce bias&lt;/a&gt; in machine learning. Our latest development in this effort addresses gender bias by providing feminine and masculine translations for some gender-neutral words on the &lt;a href="https://translate.google.com/"&gt;Google Translate website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Google Translate learns from hundreds of millions of already-translated examples from the web. Historically, it has provided only one translation for a query, even if the translation could have either a feminine or masculine form. So when the model produced one translation, it inadvertently replicated gender biases that already existed. For example: it would skew masculine for words like “strong” or “doctor,” and feminine for other words, like “nurse” or “beautiful.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now you’ll get both a feminine and masculine translation for a single word—like “surgeon”—when translating from English into French, Italian, Portuguese or Spanish. You’ll also get both translations when translating phrases and sentences from Turkish to English. For example, if you type “o bir doktor” in Turkish, you’ll now get “she is a doctor” and “he is a doctor” as the gender-specific translations.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-image_full_width"&gt;&lt;div class="h-c-page"&gt;&lt;div class="article-image__is-caption h-c-grid__col-l--6 h-c-grid__col--8 h-c-grid__col-l--offset-3 h-c-grid__col--offset-2"&gt;&lt;a class="article-image--link"&gt;&lt;img alt="gender specific translation" class="article-image--large" data-loading='{
                "mobile": "https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/gender-before-after.max-500x500.jpg",
                "desktop": "https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/gender-before-after.max-1000x1000.jpg"
              }' loading="lazy" src=" https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/gender-before-after.max-100x100.jpg " tabindex="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption class="article-image__caption article-image__is-caption-image h-c-grid__col--8 h-c-grid__col--offset-2 h-c-grid__col-l--6 h-c-grid__col-l--offset-3"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Gender-specific translations on the Google Translate website.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-paragraph"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the future, we plan to extend gender-specific translations to more languages, launch on other Translate surfaces like our iOS and Android apps, and address gender bias in features like query auto-complete. And we're already thinking about how to address non-binary gender in translations, though it’s not part of this initial launch.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;To check out gender-specific translations, visit the &lt;a href="https://translate.google.com/"&gt;Google Translate website&lt;/a&gt;, and you can get more information on our &lt;a href="https://support.google.com/translate/answer/9179237"&gt;Google Translate Help Center page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Dec 2018 16:42:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.google/products/translate/reducing-gender-bias-google-translate/</guid><category>Translate</category><og xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#"><type>article</type><title>Reducing gender bias in Google Translate</title><description>Google Translate is launching gender-specific translations: masculine and feminine results for a gender-neutral query.</description><site_name>Google</site_name><url>https://blog.google/products/translate/reducing-gender-bias-google-translate/</url></og><author xmlns:author="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><name>James Kuczmarski</name><title>Product Manager, Google Translate</title><department></department><company></company></author></item><item><title>A new look for Google Translate on the web</title><link>https://blog.google/products/translate/new-look-google-translate-web/</link><description>&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;div class="block-paragraph"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;p&gt;It’s been twelve years since the launch of Google Translate, and since then Translate has evolved to keep up with the ways people use it. Initially translating between English and Arabic only, we now translate 30 trillion sentences per year across 103 languages.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Google Translate has become an essential tool for communicating across languages, and we recently redesigned the &lt;a href="https://translate.google.com/"&gt;Translate website&lt;/a&gt; to make it easier to use. Here’s what you need to know:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;The site’s new look is now consistent with other Google products, and updated labeling and typography make it easier to navigate. For instance, you’ve always been able to upload documents for translation, but now that feature is easier to find. &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Now it’s even more convenient to save and organize important translations you regularly utilize or search for. We’ve added labels to each saved translation, so if you speak multiple languages, you can sort and group your translations with a single click.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;We've made the website responsive so it can adjust dynamically for your screen size. So when we launch new features, you get a great web experience across all your devices: mobile, tablet, or desktop. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-image_full_width"&gt;&lt;div class="h-c-page"&gt;&lt;div class="article-image__is-caption h-c-grid__col-l--6 h-c-grid__col--8 h-c-grid__col-l--offset-3 h-c-grid__col--offset-2"&gt;&lt;a class="article-image--link"&gt;&lt;img alt="translate web redesign gif" class="article-image--large" src=" https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/original_images/blog-gif.gif " tabindex="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption class="article-image__caption article-image__is-caption-image h-c-grid__col--8 h-c-grid__col--offset-2 h-c-grid__col-l--6 h-c-grid__col-l--offset-3"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;p&gt;The new responsive website adjusts dynamically to your screen size.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-paragraph"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;p&gt;To check out the new site, visit &lt;a href="http://translate.google.com"&gt;translate.google.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2018 23:59:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.google/products/translate/new-look-google-translate-web/</guid><category>Translate</category><og xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#"><type>article</type><title>A new look for Google Translate on the web</title><description>The redesigned Google Translate website with enhanced feature discoverability, updates for Material Design, and improved usability.</description><site_name>Google</site_name><url>https://blog.google/products/translate/new-look-google-translate-web/</url></og><author xmlns:author="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><name>James Kuczmarski</name><title>Product Manager, Google Translate</title><department></department><company></company></author></item><item><title>Bringing hope to a refugee family, using Google Translate</title><link>https://blog.google/products/translate/refugee-family-translate/</link><description>&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;div class="block-paragraph"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;p&gt;In 2015, I joined Google to be a part of a company using technology to help others. I’m proud that Google’s commitment to its mission—to organize the world’s information and make it universally accessible and useful—remains &lt;a href="https://www.blog.google/inside-google/company-announcements/marking-20ish-years-google/"&gt;strong&lt;/a&gt; 20 years in. I knew I wanted to be a part of it all, but had no idea that I would experience the power of our mission firsthand, and that it would help me to forge a friendship when I least expected it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For the past three years, my wife and I have been working with organizations involved with refugee resettlement efforts. We both have immigrant parents, so we’ve heard stories about resettling in a country to make a better life for your children, but being forced to leave a country is very different. These refugees are often fleeing from life threatening situations. Aside from dealing with their past trauma and being in an unfamiliar place without a support system, they often can’t speak the local language.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;My wife and I learned of a family of four—Nour, Mariam, three-year old Sanah and six-month-old Yousuf—who settled in Rialto, 45 minutes from where my wife and I grew up in Southern California. Through the assistance of organizations such as &lt;a href="https://www.heartsofmercy.org/"&gt;Hearts of Mercy&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://miryslist.org/"&gt;Miry’s List&lt;/a&gt;, they settled into an apartment shortly before giving birth to Yousuf. Still recovering from injuries sustained in Syria, Nour was unable to work, and had to rely on the help of others to get by. Without a car, their options were further limited. Then, in April of this year, they faced their hardest challenge yet: their daughter Sanah was diagnosed with Stage 4 &lt;a href="https://www.cancer.org/cancer/neuroblastoma/about/what-is-neuroblastoma.html"&gt;Neuroblastoma&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We wanted to help, but didn’t know where to start—and as new parents ourselves, we could relate on a personal level. We fundraised for the family and collected toys for Yousuf and Sanah in hopes that they could feel supported. Moreso, we wanted to help them get through Sanah’s treatments with as little to worry about as possible.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A few weeks after we first heard of their story, we went to their home to meet in person. Nour was waiting outside for us, and we quickly realized there was a challenge that we had overlooked: the family only spoke Arabic. There I was, face to face with Nour, wanting to hear his story and reassure him that he’s surrounded by a supportive community, but couldn't convey those thoughts or give Nour the ability to convey his. The only option I could think of was Google Translate, which I had used in previous international trips, and hoped would bridge this gap.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I opened the app to translate a few words, but we couldn’t get far by manually typing sentences. Instead, I tried "conversation" mode, which allows for real-time audio translations and makes the interaction feel more natural. We talked about his family’s story and what they were up against. I learned that back in Syria, Nour was shot twice in the back, and endured the deaths of his brothers. Now, Nour and Mariam are giving up everything to take care of Sanah and spend up to two hours commuting on a bus to and from her hospital treatments. Through all of this, they continue to be optimistic and hopeful, and are grateful for being able to make it to America.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-image_full_width"&gt;&lt;div class="h-c-page"&gt;&lt;div class="article-image__is-caption h-c-grid__col-l--6 h-c-grid__col--8 h-c-grid__col-l--offset-3 h-c-grid__col--offset-2"&gt;&lt;a class="article-image--link"&gt;&lt;img alt="image (2).png" class="article-image--large" data-loading='{
                "mobile": "https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/image_2_4AMNXMU.max-500x500.png",
                "desktop": "https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/image_2_4AMNXMU.max-1000x1000.png"
              }' loading="lazy" src=" https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/image_2_4AMNXMU.max-100x100.png " tabindex="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption class="article-image__caption article-image__is-caption-image h-c-grid__col--8 h-c-grid__col--offset-2 h-c-grid__col-l--6 h-c-grid__col-l--offset-3"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;p&gt;A snapshot of my visit with Nour.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-paragraph"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;p&gt;I never imagined that we could sustain a 90-minute conversation in two languages, and that it would bring us closer together, inspiring me in a way I didn’t expect. Without Translate, we would have exchanged a few pleasantries, shared poorly communicated words and parted ways. Instead, we walked away with a bond built on an understanding of one another—we were just two fathers, talking about our fears and hopes for our family’s future. To this day, we stay connected on how the family is doing, and I’m looking forward to keeping this relationship going for a long time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Refugee families often find themselves in situations that may seem normal to you and me—like at the DMV trying to get a driver’s license—or worse, in a dire situation like a hospital, with no way of communicating. We generally think of technology as an enabler of change, driving efficiency or making the impossible happen. But in this case, technology allowed me to make a life-changing connection, and brought me closer to family who was very far away from home.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Sep 2018 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.google/products/translate/refugee-family-translate/</guid><category>Translate</category><category>Googlers</category><og xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#"><type>article</type><title>Bringing hope to a refugee family, using Google Translate</title><description>How one Googler used Google Translate to help a refugee family.</description><site_name>Google</site_name><url>https://blog.google/products/translate/refugee-family-translate/</url></og><author xmlns:author="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><name>Abid Kapadya</name><title>Retail Innovation &amp; Partnerships</title><department></department><company></company></author></item><item><title>Offline translations are now a lot better thanks to on-device AI</title><link>https://blog.google/products/translate/offline-translations-are-now-lot-better-thanks-device-ai/</link><description>&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;div class="block-paragraph"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Just about two years ago we &lt;a href="https://www.blog.google/products/translate/found-translation-more-accurate-fluent-sentences-google-translate/"&gt;introduced&lt;/a&gt; neural machine translation (NMT) to Google Translate, significantly improving accuracy of our online translations. Today, we’re bringing NMT technology offline—on device. This means that the technology will run in the Google Translate apps directly on your Android or iOS device, so that you can get high-quality translations even when you don't have access to an internet connection.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The neural system translates whole sentences at a time, rather than piece by piece. It uses broader context to help determine the most relevant translation, which it then rearranges and adjusts to sound more like a real person speaking with proper grammar. This makes translated paragraphs and articles a lot smoother and easier to read.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Offline translations can be useful when traveling to other countries without a local data plan, if you don’t have access to internet, or if you just don’t want to use cellular data. And since each language set is just 35-45MB, they won’t take too much storage space on your phone when you download them.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-image_full_width"&gt;&lt;div class="h-c-page"&gt;&lt;div class="article-image__is-caption h-c-grid__col--10 h-c-grid__col--offset-1 h-c-grid__col-l--offset-2 h-c-grid__col-l--8"&gt;&lt;a class="article-image--link"&gt;&lt;img alt="Comparison between phrase based translation and online/offline NMT" class="article-image--full" data-loading='{
                "mobile": "https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/original_images/offline-comparison.png",
                "desktop": "https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/offline-comparison.max-1000x1000.png"
              }' loading="lazy" src=" https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/original_images/offline-comparison.png " tabindex="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption class="article-image__caption article-image__is-caption-image h-c-grid__col--8 h-c-grid__col--offset-2 h-c-grid__col-l--6 h-c-grid__col-l--offset-3"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;p&gt;A comparison between our current phrase-based machine translation (PBMT), new offline neural machine translation (on-device), and online neural machine translation&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-paragraph"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;p&gt;To try NMT offline translations, go to your Translate app on Android or iOS. If you’ve used offline translations before, you’ll see a banner on your home screen which will take you to the right place to update your offline files. If not, go to your offline translation settings and tap the arrow next to the language name to download the package for that language. Now you’ll be ready to translate text whether you’re online or not. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-image_full_width"&gt;&lt;div class="h-c-page"&gt;&lt;div class="article-image h-c-grid__col-l--4 h-c-grid__col--6 h-c-grid__col-l--offset-4 h-c-grid__col--offset-3"&gt;&lt;a class="article-image--link"&gt;&lt;img alt="Google Translate offline NMT" class="article-image--medium" data-loading='{
                "mobile": "https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/original_images/Screenshot_20180612-110738.png",
                "desktop": "https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/Screenshot_20180612-110738.max-1000x1000.png"
              }' loading="lazy" src=" https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/original_images/Screenshot_20180612-110738.png " tabindex="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-paragraph"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;p&gt;We're rolling out this update in 59 languages over the next few days, so get out there and connect to the world around you!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2018 17:43:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.google/products/translate/offline-translations-are-now-lot-better-thanks-device-ai/</guid><category>Translate</category><category>Next Billion Users</category><category>AI</category><og xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#"><type>article</type><title>Offline translations are now a lot better thanks to on-device AI</title><description>We’re bringing neural machine translation technology on device, so you can get high-quality translations even when you're offline.</description><site_name>Google</site_name><url>https://blog.google/products/translate/offline-translations-are-now-lot-better-thanks-device-ai/</url></og><author xmlns:author="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><name>Julie Cattiau</name><title>Product Manager</title><department>Translate apps</department><company></company></author></item><item><title>Tune in for the world’s first Google Translate music tour</title><link>https://blog.google/products/translate/tune-worlds-first-google-translate-music-tour/</link><description>&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;div class="block-paragraph"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Eleven years ago, Google Translate was created to break down language barriers. Since then, it has enabled billions of people and businesses all over the world to talk, connect and understand each other in new ways.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And we’re still re-imagining how it can be used—most recently, with music. The music industry in Sweden is one of the world's most successful exporters of hit music in English—with artists such Abba, The Cardigans and Avicii originating from the country. But there are still many talented Swedish artists who may not get the recognition or success they deserve except for in a small country up in the north.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This sparked an idea: might it be possible to use Google Translate with the sole purpose of breaking a Swedish band internationally?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Today, we’re presenting Translate Tour, in which up and coming Swedish indie pop group &lt;a href="http://www.vitabergen.se/"&gt;Vita Bergen&lt;/a&gt; will be using Google Translate to perform their new single “Tänd Ljusen” in three different languages—English, Spanish and French—on the streets of three different European cities. In just a couple of days, the band will set off to London, Paris and Madrid to sing their locally adapted songs in front of the eyes of the public—with the aim of spreading Swedish music culture and inviting people all over the world to tune into the band’s cross-European indie pop music.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-image_full_width"&gt;&lt;div class="h-c-page"&gt;&lt;div class="article-image__is-caption h-c-grid__col-l--6 h-c-grid__col--8 h-c-grid__col-l--offset-3 h-c-grid__col--offset-2"&gt;&lt;a class="article-image--link"&gt;&lt;img alt="Translate Tour 2_Credit Anton Olin.jpg" class="article-image--large" data-loading='{
                "mobile": "https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/Translate_Tour_2_Credit_Anton_Olin.max-500x500.jpg",
                "desktop": "https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/Translate_Tour_2_Credit_Anton_Olin.max-1000x1000.jpg"
              }' loading="lazy" src=" https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/Translate_Tour_2_Credit_Anton_Olin.max-100x100.jpg " tabindex="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption class="article-image__caption article-image__is-caption-image h-c-grid__col--8 h-c-grid__col--offset-2 h-c-grid__col-l--6 h-c-grid__col-l--offset-3"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;p&gt;William Hellström from Vita Bergen will be performing his song in English, Spanish and French.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-paragraph"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Last year Google Translate switched from phrase-based translation to &lt;a href="https://www.blog.google/products/translate/found-translation-more-accurate-fluent-sentences-google-translate/"&gt;Google Neural Machine Translation&lt;/a&gt;, which means that the tool now translates whole sentences at a time, rather than just piece by piece. It uses this broader context to figure out the most relevant translation, which it then rearranges and adjusts to be more like a human speaking with proper grammar.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Using this updated version of Google Translate, the English, Spanish and French translations of the song were close to flawless. The translations will also continue to improve, as the system learns from the more people using it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-paragraph"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tune in to Vita Bergen’s release event, &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCntvm4EIiWvPjbLdfxxPbWg"&gt;live streamed on YouTube&lt;/a&gt; today at 5:00 p.m. CEST, or listen to the songs in Swedish (“&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Lft6-XtF-LU&amp;amp;feature=youtu.be"&gt;Tänd Ljusen&lt;/a&gt;”), English (“&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=sMGW4NVm3jY&amp;amp;feature=youtu.be"&gt;Light the Lights&lt;/a&gt;”), Spanish (&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/HPk7wdRdV_8"&gt;“Enciende las Luces&lt;/a&gt;”) and French (“&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/Q6PgyiRxMbs"&gt;Allumez les Lumières&lt;/a&gt;”).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2017 07:55:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.google/products/translate/tune-worlds-first-google-translate-music-tour/</guid><category>Translate</category><category>YouTube</category><media:content height="540" url="https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/Translate_Tour_1_Credit_Anton_Olin.max-600x600.jpg" width="540"></media:content><og xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#"><type>article</type><title>Tune in for the world’s first Google Translate music tour</title><description>Introducing the world’s first Google Translate music launch and tour—three gigs, three cities and three languages.</description><image>https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/Translate_Tour_1_Credit_Anton_Olin.max-600x600.jpg</image><site_name>Google</site_name><url>https://blog.google/products/translate/tune-worlds-first-google-translate-music-tour/</url></og><author xmlns:author="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><name>Farshad Shadloo</name><title>Google Sweden</title><department></department><company></company></author></item><item><title>Making the internet more inclusive in India</title><link>https://blog.google/products/translate/making-internet-more-inclusive-india/</link><description>&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;div class="block-paragraph"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;p&gt;More than 400 million people in India use the internet, and more are coming online every day. But the vast majority of India’s online content is in English, which only 20 percent of the country’s population speaks—meaning most Indians have a hard time finding content and services in their language.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Building for everyone means first and foremost making things work in the languages people speak. That’s why we’ve now brought our new &lt;a href="https://research.googleblog.com/2016/09/a-neural-network-for-machine.html"&gt;neural machine translation&lt;/a&gt; technology to translations between English and nine widely used Indian languages—Hindi, Bengali, Marathi, Gujarati, Punjabi, Tamil, Telugu, Malayalam and Kannada.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Neural machine translation translates full sentences at a time, instead of pieces of a sentence, using this broader context to help it figure out the most relevant translation. The result is higher-quality, more human sounding translations.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Just like it’s easier to learn a language when you already know a related language, our neural technology speaks each language better when it learns several at a time. For example, we have a whole lot more sample data for Hindi than its relatives Marathi and Bengali, but when we train them all together, the translations for all improve more than if we’d trained each individually.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-image_full_width"&gt;&lt;div class="h-c-page"&gt;&lt;div class="article-image__is-caption h-c-grid__col--10 h-c-grid__col--offset-1 h-c-grid__col-l--offset-2 h-c-grid__col-l--8"&gt;&lt;a class="article-image--link"&gt;&lt;img alt="NMT Translation India.jpg" class="article-image--full" data-loading='{
                "mobile": "https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/NMT_Translation_India.max-500x500.jpg",
                "desktop": "https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/NMT_Translation_India.max-1000x1000.jpg"
              }' loading="lazy" src=" https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/NMT_Translation_India.max-100x100.jpg " tabindex="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption class="article-image__caption article-image__is-caption-image h-c-grid__col--8 h-c-grid__col--offset-2 h-c-grid__col-l--6 h-c-grid__col-l--offset-3"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;Left: Phrase-based translation; right: neural machine translation&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-paragraph"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;p&gt;These improvements to Google Translate in India join several other updates we announced at an event in New Delhi today, including neutral machine translation in Chrome and bringing the Rajpal &amp;amp; Sons Hindi dictionary online so it’s easier for Hindi speakers to find word meanings right in search results. All these improvements help make the web more useful for hundreds of millions of Indians, and bring them closer to benefiting from the full value of the internet.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Apr 2017 19:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.google/products/translate/making-internet-more-inclusive-india/</guid><category>India</category><category>Translate</category><category>Google in Asia</category><media:content height="540" url="https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/about_fallback_B_3_nuZyZBl.max-600x600.png" width="540"></media:content><og xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#"><type>article</type><title>Making the internet more inclusive in India</title><description>We’re bringing our neural machine translation technology to nine Indian languages—Hindi, Bengali, Marathi, Tamil, Telugu, Gujarati, Punjabi, Malayalam and Kannada.</description><image>https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/about_fallback_B_3_nuZyZBl.max-600x600.png</image><site_name>Google</site_name><url>https://blog.google/products/translate/making-internet-more-inclusive-india/</url></og><author xmlns:author="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><name>Barak Turovsky</name><title>Group Product Manager</title><department>Google Translate</department><company></company></author></item><item><title>Even better translations in Chrome, with one tap</title><link>https://blog.google/products/chrome/even-better-translations-chrome-one-tap/</link><description>&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;div class="block-paragraph"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Half the world’s webpages are in English, but &lt;a href="https://www.ethnologue.com/language/eng "&gt;less than 15 percent&lt;/a&gt; of the global population speaks it as a primary or secondary language. It’s no surprise that Chrome’s built-in Translate functionality is one of the most beloved Chrome features. Every day Chrome users translate more than 150 million webpages with just one click or tap.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Last year, Google Translate introduced &lt;a href="https://blog.google/products/translate/found-translation-more-accurate-fluent-sentences-google-translate/"&gt;neural machine translation&lt;/a&gt;, which uses deep neural networks to translate entire sentences, rather than just phrases, to figure out the most relevant translation. Since then we’ve been gradually making these improvements available for Chrome’s built-in translation for select language pairs. The result is higher-quality, full-page translations that are more accurate and easier to read.&lt;/p&gt;Today, neural machine translation improvement is coming to Translate in Chrome for nine more language pairs. Neural machine translation will be used for most pages to and from English for Indonesian and eight Indian languages: Bengali, Gujarati, Kannada, Malayalam, Marathi, Punjabi, Tamil and Telugu. This means higher quality translations on pages containing everything from &lt;a href="http://www.azlyrics.com/lyrics/shakira/wakawakathistimeforafrica.html"&gt;song lyrics&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href="http://indianexpress.com/article/sports/cricket/ipl-2017-10/zaheer-khan-announces-engagement-with-actress-sagarika-ghatge-4626646/"&gt;news articles&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href="http://www.indiancricketfans.com/forums/forum/6-cricket-talk/"&gt;cricket discussions&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-image_full_width"&gt;&lt;div class="h-c-page"&gt;&lt;div class="article-image__is-caption h-c-grid__col--10 h-c-grid__col--offset-1 h-c-grid__col-l--offset-2 h-c-grid__col-l--8"&gt;&lt;a class="article-image--link"&gt;&lt;img alt="translation.png" class="article-image--full" data-loading='{
                "mobile": "https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/translation.max-500x500.png",
                "desktop": "https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/translation.max-1000x1000.png"
              }' loading="lazy" src=" https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/translation.max-100x100.png " tabindex="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption class="article-image__caption article-image__is-caption-image h-c-grid__col--8 h-c-grid__col--offset-2 h-c-grid__col-l--6 h-c-grid__col-l--offset-3"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;From left: A webpage in Indonesian; the page translated into English without neural machine translation; the page translated into English with neural machine translation. As you can see, the translations after neural machine translation are more fluid and natural.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-paragraph"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;p&gt;The addition of these nine languages brings the total number of languages enabled with neural machine translations in Chrome to more than 20. You can already translate to and from English for Chinese, French, German, Hebrew, Hindi, Japanese, Korean, Portuguese, Thai, Turkish, Vietnamese, and one-way from Spanish to English.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We’ll bring neural machine translation to even more languages in the future. Until then, learn more about enabling Translate in Chrome &lt;a href="https://support.google.com/chrome/answer/173424?co=GENIE.Platform%3DDesktop&amp;amp;hl=en"&gt;in our help center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Apr 2017 18:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.google/products/chrome/even-better-translations-chrome-one-tap/</guid><category>Translate</category><category>Chrome</category><media:content height="540" url="https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/about_fallback_A_2_1.max-600x600.png" width="540"></media:content><og xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#"><type>article</type><title>Even better translations in Chrome, with one tap</title><description>We're adding neural machine translations to Chrome for nine more languages, for a total of more than 20. The result is higher-quality, full-page translations that are more accurate and easier to read.</description><image>https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/about_fallback_A_2_1.max-600x600.png</image><site_name>Google</site_name><url>https://blog.google/products/chrome/even-better-translations-chrome-one-tap/</url></og><author xmlns:author="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><name>Yana Yushkina</name><title>Chrome Product Manager</title><department>Polyglot</department><company></company></author></item><item><title>The Arrival of our 32nd Word Lens Language, Heptapod B</title><link>https://blog.google/products/translate/arrival-our-32nd-word-lens-language-heptapod-b/</link><description>&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;div class="block-paragraph"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;p&gt;We’re honored to have partnered with Dr. Louise Banks, esteemed linguistics professor, to develop instant camera translation for our 32nd language, Heptapod B. Following our experience with logograms in &lt;a href="https://blog.google/products/translate/translate-where-you-need-it-in-any-app/"&gt;Chinese&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://blog.google/topics/google-asia/lost-translation-no-more-word-lens-japanese/"&gt;Japanese&lt;/a&gt;, as well as the many characters containing circles in &lt;a href="http://korea.googleblog.com/2017/03/kr-wordlens.html"&gt;Korean&lt;/a&gt;, we were ready to blend our expertise in low-memory-footprint convolutional modeling and Dr. Banks’ linguistic background to the deciphering of circular logograms in the Word Lens feature in the Google Translate app.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-image_full_width"&gt;&lt;div class="h-c-page"&gt;&lt;div class="article-image h-c-grid__col--10 h-c-grid__col--offset-1 h-c-grid__col-l--offset-2 h-c-grid__col-l--8"&gt;&lt;a class="article-image--link"&gt;&lt;img alt="Translate_Arrival_1.png" class="article-image--full" data-loading='{
                "mobile": "https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/Translate_Arrival_1.max-500x500.png",
                "desktop": "https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/Translate_Arrival_1.max-1000x1000.png"
              }' loading="lazy" src=" https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/Translate_Arrival_1.max-100x100.png " tabindex="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-paragraph"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;p&gt;The challenge with understanding Heptapod B is its nonlinear orthography. Fortunately, Google's &lt;a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/1609.08144"&gt;neural machine translation system&lt;/a&gt; employs an encoder/decoder system that internally represents sentences as high-dimensional vectors. These vectors map well to the non-linear orthography of the Heptapod language and they are really the enabling technical factor in translating Heptapod B.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We interpret Heptapod B into English, Chinese, Danish, Japanese, Urdu, Russian, French, Spanish and Arabic. As with our other Word Lens languages, it works offline, which is really handy if you happen to need to read a circular logogram in an isolated location. Dr. Banks assures us that the app will continue to work for at least 3,000 years.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-image_full_width"&gt;&lt;div class="h-c-page"&gt;&lt;div class="article-image h-c-grid__col--10 h-c-grid__col--offset-1 h-c-grid__col-l--offset-2 h-c-grid__col-l--8"&gt;&lt;a class="article-image--link"&gt;&lt;img alt="Translate_Arrival_2.png" class="article-image--full" data-loading='{
                "mobile": "https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/Translate_Arrival_2.max-500x500.png",
                "desktop": "https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/Translate_Arrival_2.max-1000x1000.png"
              }' loading="lazy" src=" https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/Translate_Arrival_2.max-100x100.png " tabindex="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-paragraph"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Communicating across language (and glass) barriers can be a rather alienating experience. While learning a new writing system can be quite rewarding and even a mind-altering experience, not everyone has time for that. So whether the world’s fate hangs in the balance, or if you’re simply trying to discern whether your coffee stain ring means something, we wish you success as you integrate this tool into the story of your life.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;sub&gt;(Okay, if you haven’t guessed already... we’re just having some fun here. But we really are eager to bring Word Lens and Neural translation to more languages, &lt;br/&gt;so stay tuned.)&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.google/products/translate/arrival-our-32nd-word-lens-language-heptapod-b/</guid><category>Translate</category><media:content height="540" url="https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/Translate_Arrival_hero.max-600x600.png" width="540"></media:content><og xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#"><type>article</type><title>The Arrival of our 32nd Word Lens Language, Heptapod B</title><description>We’ve combined convolutional neural networks with transtemporal non-linear logogram discernment to launch our most ambitious instant camera translation yet.</description><image>https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/Translate_Arrival_hero.max-600x600.png</image><site_name>Google</site_name><url>https://blog.google/products/translate/arrival-our-32nd-word-lens-language-heptapod-b/</url></og><author xmlns:author="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><name>Jesse Friedman</name><title>sociolinguist and intrahuman communications specialist</title><department>Google Translate</department><company></company></author></item><item><title>How Google Translate is making learning English fun in Israel</title><link>https://blog.google/products/translate/how-google-translate-making-learning-english-fun-israel/</link><description>&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;div class="block-paragraph"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Using &lt;a href="https://blog.google/products/translate/higher-quality-neural-translations-bunch-more-languages/"&gt;neural machine translation&lt;/a&gt;, we’ve just updated Hebrew and Arabic languages on Google Translate. But what you can’t see on the surface is that these translations also improved thanks to students across Israel. As English as a Foreign Language (EFL) students used the &lt;a href="https://translate.google.com/about/intl/en_ALL/contribute.html"&gt;Google Translate Community platform&lt;/a&gt; to learn and practice their English, they actually improved translations for everyone in the process.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Adele Raemer is an Israeli English teacher, a trainer for English as a Foreign Language (EFL) and digital pedagogy at the Israel Ministry of Education; she’s also a &lt;a href="https://edutrainingcenter.withgoogle.com/certification_innovator"&gt;Google Certified Innovator&lt;/a&gt;, a &lt;a href="https://www.google.com/landing/geg/"&gt;Google Educator Group&lt;/a&gt; leader, and &lt;a href="http://adeleefl.blogspot.co.il/2017/02/and-winners-are-everyone.html"&gt;blogger&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-image_half_width"&gt;&lt;div class="h-c-page"&gt;&lt;div class="article-image__is-caption h-c-grid__col-l--4 h-c-grid__col--6 h-c-grid__col-l--offset-4 h-c-grid__col--offset-3"&gt;&lt;a class="article-image--link"&gt;&lt;img alt="Adele Raemer.png" class="article-image--medium" data-loading='{
                "mobile": "https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/Adele_Raemer.max-500x500.png",
                "desktop": "https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/Adele_Raemer.max-1000x1000.png"
              }' loading="lazy" src=" https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/Adele_Raemer.max-100x100.png " tabindex="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption class="article-image__caption article-image__is-caption-image h-c-grid__col--8 h-c-grid__col--offset-2 h-c-grid__col-l--6 h-c-grid__col-l--offset-3"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;Adele Raemer, English as a Foreign Language teacher and trainer at Israel’s Ministry of Education&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-paragraph"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;p&gt;When Adele first used the Translate Community as tool to teach English, she was impressed by how eager and motivated her students became. She wanted other students to share in the experience, so with the support of the Ministry of Education EFL superintendent and &lt;a href="http://google.com/edu"&gt;our education team&lt;/a&gt;, she turned this into a challenge for classrooms across Israel. The goal was to help students work on their vocabulary, develop critical thinking and translating skills and enhanced their engagement with English studies.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Last spring, 51 classes from across the country joined our Google Translate Community pilot competition. A month later, the class with the highest number of collective contributions joined us for a visit to our Google Israel office. The teachers used the challenge as a fun activity on top of their regular curriculum. As Mazi, an English teacher at “Hodayot” high school, said: “The experience of participating in the competition was very positive and enriched my teaching. Any time that a student finished a task early or had a bit of time at the end of the lesson, they could be productive by going into the site and translating!”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-image_full_width"&gt;&lt;div class="h-c-page"&gt;&lt;div class="article-image__is-caption h-c-grid__col--10 h-c-grid__col--offset-1 h-c-grid__col-l--offset-2 h-c-grid__col-l--8"&gt;&lt;a class="article-image--link"&gt;&lt;img alt="Translate_Israel_Group.png" class="article-image--full" data-loading='{
                "mobile": "https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/Translate_Israel_Group.max-500x500.png",
                "desktop": "https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/Translate_Israel_Group.max-1000x1000.png"
              }' loading="lazy" src=" https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/Translate_Israel_Group.max-100x100.png " tabindex="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption class="article-image__caption article-image__is-caption-image h-c-grid__col--8 h-c-grid__col--offset-2 h-c-grid__col-l--6 h-c-grid__col-l--offset-3"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;Winning class from Jadeidi-Makr science school who won a visit to the Google Israel office&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-paragraph"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Inspired by the success of Adele's pilot program, the Translate Community team then built new tools that allowed group contributions and measured results more accurately. With new supporting &lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/drive/folders/0BwN5aO9LpakgOXNwbnlpMkdGWWc?usp=sharing"&gt;lesson plans&lt;/a&gt;, more than 150 classes participated in a three month competition for Hebrew-English and Arabic-English. From these two competitions, 3,500 students translated and verified more than 4 million words and phrases.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-image_half_width"&gt;&lt;div class="h-c-page"&gt;&lt;div class="article-image__is-caption h-c-grid__col-l--4 h-c-grid__col--6 h-c-grid__col-l--offset-4 h-c-grid__col--offset-3"&gt;&lt;a class="article-image--link"&gt;&lt;img alt="Translate_Israel_1.png" class="article-image--medium" data-loading='{
                "mobile": "https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/Translate_Israel_1.max-500x500.png",
                "desktop": "https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/Translate_Israel_1.max-1000x1000.png"
              }' loading="lazy" src=" https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/Translate_Israel_1.max-100x100.png " tabindex="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption class="article-image__caption article-image__is-caption-image h-c-grid__col--8 h-c-grid__col--offset-2 h-c-grid__col-l--6 h-c-grid__col-l--offset-3"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;English teacher from the winning school, “Nitzanim” school, with a student translating during a lesson&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-paragraph"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;p&gt;We’ve incorporated this multi-lingual knowledge into the training for our &lt;a href="https://blog.google/products/translate/found-translation-more-accurate-fluent-sentences-google-translate/"&gt;cutting-edge neural technology&lt;/a&gt;, which we’ve just launched today for Hebrew and Arabic. That means every one of these contributions helped improve translations for millions of people doing translations to or from these related languages.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We were thrilled to see the great impact that these students had on Translate itself. It’s so cool to see how the next generation of students is working hand in hand with the next generation of machine translation technology!&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Mar 2017 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.google/products/translate/how-google-translate-making-learning-english-fun-israel/</guid><category>Education</category><category>Translate</category><category>AI</category><media:content height="540" url="https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/Translate_Israel_header.max-600x600.png" width="540"></media:content><og xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#"><type>article</type><title>How Google Translate is making learning English fun in Israel</title><description>Thousands of Israeli students improve their English with the Google Translate community, and millions get cutting-edge Neural translation for Hebrew and Arabic.</description><image>https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/Translate_Israel_header.max-600x600.png</image><site_name>Google</site_name><url>https://blog.google/products/translate/how-google-translate-making-learning-english-fun-israel/</url></og><author xmlns:author="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><name>Lee Reshef</name><title></title><department>Consumer and Brand team, Israel</department><company></company></author></item><item><title>Higher quality neural translations for a bunch more languages</title><link>https://blog.google/products/translate/higher-quality-neural-translations-bunch-more-languages/</link><description>&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;div class="block-paragraph"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Last November, people from Brazil to Turkey to Japan discovered that Google Translate for their language was suddenly more accurate and easier to understand. That’s because we introduced &lt;a href="https://blog.google/products/translate/found-translation-more-accurate-fluent-sentences-google-translate/"&gt;neural machine translation&lt;/a&gt;—using deep neural networks to translate entire sentences, rather than just phrases—for eight languages overall. Over the next couple of weeks, these improvements are coming to Google Translate in many more languages, starting right now with Hindi, Russian and Vietnamese.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Neural translation is a lot better than our previous technology, because we translate whole sentences at a time, instead of pieces of a sentence. (Of course there’s lots of machine learning magic powering this under the hood, which you can read about on the &lt;a href="https://research.googleblog.com/2016/09/a-neural-network-for-machine.html"&gt;Research blog&lt;/a&gt;.) This makes for translations that are usually more accurate and sound closer to the way people speak the language. Here’s one example to show how much it’s improved:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-image_full_width"&gt;&lt;div class="h-c-page"&gt;&lt;div class="article-image h-c-grid__col--10 h-c-grid__col--offset-1 h-c-grid__col-l--offset-2 h-c-grid__col-l--8"&gt;&lt;a class="article-image--link"&gt;&lt;img alt="Hindi_GoogleTranslate_v4_Blog.gif" class="article-image--full" src=" https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/original_images/Hindi_GoogleTranslate_v4_Blog.gif " tabindex="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-paragraph"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;p&gt;You’ll get these new translations automatically in most places Google Translate is available: in the iOS and Android apps, at translate.google.com, and through Google Search and the Google app. We’ll be introducing neural machine translation to even more languages over the next few weeks, so keep an eye out for smoother, more fluent translations.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Finally, please keep contributing to &lt;a href="https://translate.google.com/community_s"&gt;Translate Community&lt;/a&gt;! Our translations are still far from perfect, and it helps everyone using Google Translate when you suggest improvements.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2017 21:15:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.google/products/translate/higher-quality-neural-translations-bunch-more-languages/</guid><category>Translate</category><media:content height="540" url="https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/13_about_fallback_D_1.max-600x600.png" width="540"></media:content><og xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#"><type>article</type><title>Higher quality neural translations for a bunch more languages</title><description>With neural translation, Google Translate is more accurate and sounds more human. We’re upgrading more languages starting today with Russian, Vietnamese and Hindi.</description><image>https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/13_about_fallback_D_1.max-600x600.png</image><site_name>Google</site_name><url>https://blog.google/products/translate/higher-quality-neural-translations-bunch-more-languages/</url></og><author xmlns:author="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><name>Barak Turovsky</name><title>Product Lead (and proud Russian speaker!)</title><department>Google Translate</department><company></company></author></item><item><title>Lost in Translation no more with Word Lens in Japanese</title><link>https://blog.google/around-the-globe/google-asia/lost-translation-no-more-word-lens-japanese/</link><description>&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;div class="block-paragraph"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you don’t speak Japanese, Tokyo can be a confusing and sometimes daunting place to visit. Even if you make it through the complex subway system, you’ll be faced by street signs, menus or products on supermarket shelves that are only in Japanese. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-paragraph"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;p&gt;With Word Lens now available in Japanese, you’ll never have to worry about taking a wrong turn on a busy Shibuya street or ordering something you wouldn't normally eat. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Google Translate app already lets you snap a photo of Japanese text and get a translation for it in English. But it’s a whole lot more convenient if you can just point your camera and instantly translate text on the go. With Word Lens, you just need to fire up the Translate app, point your camera at the Japanese text, and the English translations will appear overlaid on your screen—even if you don't have an Internet or data connection. It’s every savvy traveller’s dream! &lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-image_full_width"&gt;&lt;div class="h-c-page"&gt;&lt;div class="article-image h-c-grid__col--10 h-c-grid__col--offset-1 h-c-grid__col-l--offset-2 h-c-grid__col-l--8"&gt;&lt;a class="article-image--link"&gt;&lt;img alt="Google Translate: Cash only" class="article-image--full" data-loading='{
                "mobile": "https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/Translate_-_Cash_only.max-500x500.png",
                "desktop": "https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/Translate_-_Cash_only.max-1000x1000.png"
              }' loading="lazy" src=" https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/Translate_-_Cash_only.max-100x100.png " tabindex="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="block-paragraph"&gt;&lt;div class="rich-text"&gt;&lt;p&gt;To turn your smartphone into a powerful instant translation tool for English to Japanese (and vice versa), all you need to do is download the Google Translate app, either on &lt;a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.google.android.apps.translate"&gt;Android&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/google-translate/id414706506?mt=8&amp;amp;ign-mpt=uo%3D2"&gt;iOS&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2017 05:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.google/around-the-globe/google-asia/lost-translation-no-more-word-lens-japanese/</guid><category>Japan</category><category>Translate</category><category>Google in Asia</category><media:content height="540" url="https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/Okamoto_Lagoon_with_Google_Translate.max-600x600.png" width="540"></media:content><og xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#"><type>article</type><title>Lost in Translation no more with Word Lens in Japanese</title><description>Let Google Translate help you find your way through Japan, now with instant translation</description><image>https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-uniblog-publish-prod/images/Okamoto_Lagoon_with_Google_Translate.max-600x600.png</image><site_name>Google</site_name><url>https://blog.google/around-the-globe/google-asia/lost-translation-no-more-word-lens-japanese/</url></og><author xmlns:author="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><name>Masakazu Seno</name><title>Software Engineer, Google Translate</title><department></department><company></company></author></item></channel></rss>