<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:itunesu="http://www.itunesu.com/feed" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
  <title>Economics - Audio</title>
    <link>https://www.csis.org/topics/economics</link>
<atom:link href="https://www.csis.org/topics/economics/itunes-audio" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
<language>en-us</language>
<copyright>All content &#169; 2022 Center for Strategic and International Studies</copyright>
<itunes:author>Center for Strategic and International Studies</itunes:author>
<itunes:subtitle>Exploring the nexus between economics and national security at a time when international relations are increasingly defined by the pursuit of economic and commercial power.</itunes:subtitle>
<description><![CDATA[ With experts on economic policy and finance, business and trade, development, energy, and technology, CSIS offers a 360-degree perspective on economic trends in an interconnected world. Our research and programs examine the role of economics as an influence on foreign policy and the use of diplomacy as a means to improve economic outcomes. CSIS’s work in this realm is spearheaded by:

	Economics Program 
	Scholl Chair in International Business&nbsp;

Find the latest research from our scholars and CSIS events on this topic below. ]]></description>
<itunes:owner>
  <itunes:name>Center for Strategic and International Studies</itunes:name>
  <itunes:email>webmaster@csis.org</itunes:email>
</itunes:owner>
<itunes:image href="https://csis-website-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/s3fs-public/itunes_u/economics_collection.jpg" />
<itunesu:category itunesu:code="100100" />
<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>  
    <item>  
          <title>Some Good News and Some Bad News</title>    
          <description><![CDATA[ <p>In this episode, the Trade Guys and Andrew discuss some silver linings coming out of the COVID-19 crisis. They also break some bad news about the economy coming out of the World Trade Organization and the International Monetary Fund.</p>
 ]]></description>    
            <itunes:author>Scott Miller, William Alan Reinsch, H. Andrew Schwartz</itunes:author>
    
          <pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2020 16:30:00 -0400</pubDate>    
          <enclosure  url="https://csis-website-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/s3fs-public/field_soundcloud_audio/TGE90.mp3" type="audio/mpeg" length="44831274" />
<itunes:duration>29:03</itunes:duration>
<guid>https://csis-website-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/s3fs-public/field_soundcloud_audio/TGE90.mp3</guid>
  </item>
<item>  
          <title>The Present and Future Promise of Synthetic Biology</title>    
          <description><![CDATA[ The Center for Strategic and International Studies (CSIS) invites you to attend the inaugural event in our <i>Synthetic Biology: The Ongoing Technology Revolution</i> Series. This initial event will introduce the science of synthetic biology, as well as the opportunities and risks it presents to both national security and the global economy. This event will serve as the first of four events, which will convene a diverse set of experts to discuss the security and economic policy implications of this critical emerging technology.<br />
 <br />
<i>Synthetic Biology: The Ongoing Technology Revolution </i>Series<br />
 <br />
Emerging technologies—such as artificial intelligence, quantum computing, 5G, and synthetic biology—drive security and economic competition and are increasingly shaping national strategies. To develop an effective strategy for synthetic biology, policy makers and the general public need a better understanding of synthetic biology’s underlying capabilities, state of development, and diverse applications. Through a series of four symposia, CSIS will explore synthetic biology’s wide-ranging applications—from advanced microelectronics and materials to nutrition and cosmetics —and opportunities to shape its future development in support of U.S. security and economic interests. This series will include targeted discussions on synthetic biology’s:
<ul>
	<li>Present and future potential as a critical emerging technology;</li>
	<li>Economic, societal, and international implications;</li>
	<li>National security opportunities and risks; and</li>
	<li>Implications for emerging technology policy.</li>
</ul>
CSIS hopes you will join us for our inaugural event on February 6and will continue the discussion in the events that follow.<br />
 <br />
<i>This series of events is sponsored by Ginkgo Bioworks, Inc.</i> ]]></description>    
            <itunes:author>CSIS</itunes:author>
    
          <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2020 14:00:00 -0500</pubDate>    
          <enclosure  url="https://csis-website-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/s3fs-public/field_soundcloud_audio/The%20Present%20and%20Future%20Promise%20of%20Synthetic%20Biology.mp3" type="audio/mpeg" length="85238473" />
<guid>https://csis-website-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/s3fs-public/field_soundcloud_audio/The%20Present%20and%20Future%20Promise%20of%20Synthetic%20Biology.mp3</guid>
  </item>
<item>  
          <title>Cities of Tomorrow: Safety, Smarts, and Surveillance </title>    
          <description><![CDATA[ <p>As the world becomes increasingly urban and digital, smart cities are emerging as ground-zero for new approaches to development and governance. On Thursday, January 23rd, CSIS will convene a diverse panel of experts to distinguish between leading smart city models and discuss how their technologies, including in the areas of public safety and surveillance, are impacting the power of citizens, governments, and corporations, both within and between countries. </p>
<p> <i><b>Featuring keynote remarks by:</b></i><br /> Dr. Sokwoo Rhee, <i>Associate Director for Cyber-Physical Systems Innovation, National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST)</i></p>
<p> <b>A presentation by</b>:<br /> Jonathan E. Hillman<i>, Director of the Reconnecting Asia Project and Senior Fellow of the Simon Chair in Political Economy, CSIS</i></p>
<p> <i><b>And a panel discussion with</b></i>: <br /> Dr. Sheena Chestnut Greitens, <i>Assistant Professor, University of Missouri</i><br /> Michelle Holland, <i>Director of Consulting &amp; Deals, PwC Canada and former Chief Advocate for the Innovation Economy, City of Toronto</i><br /> Abha<i> </i>Joshi-Ghani<i>, Senior Adviser, World Bank</i><br /> Michael Sherwood, <i>Director of Technology and Innovation, City of Las Vegas</i></p>
<p> <i><b>Moderated by</b></i>: <br /> Peter Raymond, <i>Senior Associate, CSIS</i></p>
 ]]></description>    
            <itunes:author>Peter Raymond , Matthew P. Goodman</itunes:author>
    
          <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2020 13:45:00 -0500</pubDate>    
          <enclosure  url="https://csis-website-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/s3fs-public/field_soundcloud_audio/Cities%20of%20Tomorrow-%20Safety%2C%20Smarts%2C%20and%20Surveillance.mp3" type="audio/mpeg" length="101693406" />
<itunes:duration>1:41:37</itunes:duration>
<guid>https://csis-website-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/s3fs-public/field_soundcloud_audio/Cities%20of%20Tomorrow-%20Safety%2C%20Smarts%2C%20and%20Surveillance.mp3</guid>
  </item>
<item>  
          <title>Refreshing Transatlantic Trade Relations</title>    
          <description><![CDATA[ <p>The CSIS Scholl Chair is honored to be hosting Mr. Phil Hogan, European Commissioner for Trade, on his first official visit to Washington, DC in his new role. In her Mission Letter to him, European Commission President Ursula von der Leyen tasked Mr. Hogan with creating a level playing field for all, strengthening Europe's global trade leadership, building sustainable trade in light of climate change, and making trade more transparent. Join the Scholl Chair as we discuss with Mr. Hogan this mandate, refreshing the Transatlantic trading relationship with the new European Commission, and looking to 2020 and beyond in the world of trade. Commissioner for Trade since December 2019, Mr. Hogan of Ireland was previously European Commissioner for Agriculture and Rural Development from 2014-2019.</p>

<p><i>This event is made possible through general support to CSIS.</i></p>
 ]]></description>    
            <itunes:author>William Alan Reinsch</itunes:author>
    
          <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2020 08:30:00 -0500</pubDate>    
          <enclosure  url="https://csis-website-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/s3fs-public/field_soundcloud_audio/Refreshing%20the%20Transatlantic%20Trading%20Relationship.mp3" type="audio/mpeg" length="72697099" />
<itunes:duration>1:20:58</itunes:duration>
<guid>https://csis-website-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/s3fs-public/field_soundcloud_audio/Refreshing%20the%20Transatlantic%20Trading%20Relationship.mp3</guid>
  </item>
<item>  
          <title>Applying Lessons from Global Entrepreneurship</title>    
          <description><![CDATA[ <p><b>Please join us for a public event that will explore how the U.S. can lead the world in meeting the global demand for entrepreneurship and innovation.</b><br />  <br /> To remain competitive in a 21st-century workforce, youth must have strong backgrounds in STEM (Science, Technology, Engineering, and Math) and leadership skills. Developing economies will stagnate without qualified workforces, and there will be a mismatch between the skills that are needed for open jobs and those being taught in schools. Creating environments that foster entrepreneurship will bolster economic development and provide jobs for people around the world. There are many stories such as that of the Indonesian <a href="https://fortune.com/2019/10/21/gojek-ceo-nadiem-makarim-resigns-indonesia-ride-hailing/">“unicorn,”</a> Go-Jek, that went from having 20 bikes to be valued at <a href="https://www.scmp.com/week-asia/business/article/2116287/how-indonesian-unicorn-go-jek-went-20-bikes-us25-billion-and-e">$2.5 billion</a> in just 10 years. <a href="https://blogs.worldbank.org/opendata/chart-how-worlds-youth-population-changing">42%</a> of the world’s population is under 25 years old, therefore finding jobs for the growing number of youth entering the workforce each year will one of the most pressing global development challenges.<br />  <br /> Small and medium-sized enterprises (SMEs) are valuable sources of economic growth and help economies harness and utilize new technologies. Under the right circumstances, SMEs can play a disruptive effect on the market and pushing the incumbent players to be more efficient with the pricing of their products and services. For example, they were responsible for over <a href="https://www.oecd-ilibrary.org/sites/34907e9c-en/1/1/6/index.html?itemId=/content/publication/34907e9c-en&amp;mimeType=text/html&amp;_csp_=97b1ca7ff34abaf04c3b6ec7089258c9&amp;itemIGO=oecd&amp;itemContentType=book">60 percent</a> of employment in many OECD regions and cities. Startups, in particular, have massive potential for growth with the average startup in the United States hiring <a href="https://indicators.kauffman.org/">5.2 employees</a> in its first year. Startups also have greater agility in charting growth and market expansion. Over <a href="https://indicators.kauffman.org/">86 percent</a> of entrepreneurs who create and scale startups do so out of choice and not as a necessity.<br />  <br /> As the world prepares to confront the job creation challenge to respond to an expanding youth bulge, the global economy must be driven by entrepreneurship, while governments must enable innovation in creating favorable conditions that sustain SME growth.<br />  <br /> <i>This event is made possible with general support from Chevron. </i></p>
 ]]></description>    
            <itunes:author>Daniel F. Runde</itunes:author>
    
          <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2020 10:00:00 -0500</pubDate>    
          <enclosure  url="https://csis-website-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/s3fs-public/field_soundcloud_audio/Applying%20Lessons%20from%20Global%20Entrepreneurship.mp3" type="audio/mpeg" length="84688954" />
<itunes:duration>1:14:26</itunes:duration>
<guid>https://csis-website-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/s3fs-public/field_soundcloud_audio/Applying%20Lessons%20from%20Global%20Entrepreneurship.mp3</guid>
  </item>
<item>  
          <title>China and the NBA Call a Timeout: A Conversation with Victor Cha</title>    
          <description><![CDATA[ <p>By: Bonnie S. Glaser</p>
<p> This episode explores China's retaliatory actions against the NBA after a recent incident, as well as the larger questions surrounding the Chinese government’s treatment of foreign private companies. Our guest, Dr. Victor Cha, discusses how both US and Chinese audiences have reacted to the NBA controversy and weighs in on whether Chinese public opinion might sway Beijing’s handling of the incident. Dr. Cha also addresses the struggles that other foreign companies have faced in China and how Beijing uses “predatory liberalism” to serve its political interests.</p>
<p> Dr. Victor Cha is a senior adviser and holds the Korea Chair at CSIS. He is also a Professor of Government and the holder of the D.S. Song-KF Chair in the Department of Government and the School of Foreign Service (SFS) at Georgetown University. In July 2019, he was appointed Vice Dean for Faculty and Graduate Affairs in the SFS. His article, “Flagrant Foul: China’s Predatory Liberalism and the NBA,” will appear in the December issue of the <i>Washington Quarterly</i>.</p>
 ]]></description>    
            <itunes:author>Victor Cha</itunes:author>
    
          <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2019 09:45:00 -0500</pubDate>    
          <enclosure  url="https://csis-website-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/s3fs-public/field_soundcloud_audio/CP_Victor_Cha_Version2.mp3" type="audio/mpeg" length="36094257" />
<itunes:duration>25:04</itunes:duration>
<guid>https://csis-website-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/s3fs-public/field_soundcloud_audio/CP_Victor_Cha_Version2.mp3</guid>
  </item>
<item>  
          <title>The Future of Work in Argentina</title>    
          <description><![CDATA[ <p>With the fourth industrial revolution set to disrupt labor markets, global stability is contingent on developing countries' ability to transform their economies and create jobs to meet the economic aspirations of their people. Argentina, during its presidency of the G20 in 2018, has made the future of work one of the main priorities throughout the year and created a T20 Task Force to develop recommendations on the future of work and education for the digital age.</p>
<p> Join us for a discussion on the future of work in Argentina with the Argentine Minister for Labor and Production Dante Sica.</p>
<p> <i>This event is made possible by general support to CSIS.</i></p>
 ]]></description>    
            <itunes:author>Romina Bandura</itunes:author>
    
          <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2019 10:00:00 -0500</pubDate>    
          <enclosure  url="https://csis-website-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/s3fs-public/field_soundcloud_audio/The%20Future%20of%20Work%20in%20Argentina.mp3" type="audio/mpeg" length="72377485" />
<itunes:duration>1:12:54</itunes:duration>
<guid>https://csis-website-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/s3fs-public/field_soundcloud_audio/The%20Future%20of%20Work%20in%20Argentina.mp3</guid>
  </item>
<item>  
          <title>How the U.S. Should Respond to China&#039;s Strength</title>    
          <description><![CDATA[ <p>In this episode, Dan is joined by Dr. Jonathan Ward, author of <i>China’s Vision of Victory</i>, to discuss China’s ambitions for the world and how the United States should respond. Jonathan explains that in order to continue leading a free world, the United States must focus on the source of China’s strength: its economic might. His recommendations include the United States more effectively trading with its allies, integrating its allies in Europe and in Japan, and ramping up funding for research and development.</p>
 ]]></description>    
            <itunes:author>Daniel F. Runde</itunes:author>
    
          <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2019 09:30:00 -0500</pubDate>    
          <enclosure  url="https://csis-website-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/s3fs-public/field_soundcloud_audio/PPD_Jonathan_Ward_FINAL.mp3" type="audio/mpeg" length="30876710" />
<itunes:duration>21:26</itunes:duration>
<guid>https://csis-website-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/s3fs-public/field_soundcloud_audio/PPD_Jonathan_Ward_FINAL.mp3</guid>
  </item>
<item>  
          <title>Politics of You-Smacka</title>    
          <description><![CDATA[ <p>Andrew and the Trade Guys discuss the USMCA on the campaign trail, China's play at the WTO, and more. </p>
<p> Download the full transcript <a href="https://www.csis.org/analysis/politics-you-smacka">here</a>.</p>
 ]]></description>    
            <itunes:author>Scott Miller, William Alan Reinsch, H. Andrew Schwartz</itunes:author>
    
          <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2019 18:45:00 -0400</pubDate>    
          <enclosure  url="https://csis-website-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/s3fs-public/field_soundcloud_audio/TG_E66_191023.mp3" type="audio/mpeg" length="39597625" />
<itunes:duration>25:36</itunes:duration>
<guid>https://csis-website-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/s3fs-public/field_soundcloud_audio/TG_E66_191023.mp3</guid>
  </item>
<item>  
          <title>The World Trading System is Not Dying</title>    
          <description><![CDATA[ <p>The World Trade Organization (WTO) is at a pivotal moment. Once indispensable, the WTO finds itself struggling to settle disputes, negotiate new rules, and grapple with disruptive technologies and the re-emergence of mercantilism. While some predict the demise of the WTO, others see today’s uncertainty as an opportunity to reinvigorate the global trading system. Join CSIS on October 21 for a conversation on the future of the global trading system with Ambassador Alan Wm. Wolff, Deputy Director-General WTO and CSIS Senior Adviser and Scholl Chair holder Bill Reinsch.”<br />
<br />
The Scholl Chair will also be highlighting its <a href="https://www.csis.org/analysis/wto-crossroad">report</a>, <i>The WTO at a Crossroad.</i><br />
<br />
<i>This event is made possible by general support to CSIS. </i></p>
 ]]></description>    
            <itunes:author>CSIS</itunes:author>
    
          <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2019 09:00:00 -0400</pubDate>    
          <enclosure  url="https://csis-website-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/s3fs-public/field_soundcloud_audio/The%20World%20Trading%20System%20is%20Not%20Dying.mp3" type="audio/mpeg" length="75872797" />
<itunes:duration>1:17:01</itunes:duration>
<guid>https://csis-website-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/s3fs-public/field_soundcloud_audio/The%20World%20Trading%20System%20is%20Not%20Dying.mp3</guid>
  </item>
<item>  
          <title>Infrastructure Development in &quot;God&#039;s Own Country&quot; Kerala</title>    
          <description><![CDATA[ <p>In this episode, Dan is joined by Rick Rossow, CSIS Wadhwani Chair in U.S.-India Policy Studies, as they host two senior bureaucrats from the Indian state of Kerala, Tom Jose and Sanjeev Kaushik. They all discuss how Kerala is becoming a force to be reckoned with and how infrastructure development can take them to the next level. Additionally, they explain why transportation, water, and solid waste management are of high priority for the state; and the role of various development partners in financing Kerala's infrastructure plans.</p>
 ]]></description>    
            <itunes:author>Daniel F. Runde, Richard M. Rossow</itunes:author>
    
          <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2019 11:30:00 -0400</pubDate>    
          <enclosure  url="https://csis-website-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/s3fs-public/field_soundcloud_audio/PPD_Rossow_mixdown.mp3" type="audio/mpeg" length="35688495" />
<itunes:duration>24:47</itunes:duration>
<guid>https://csis-website-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/s3fs-public/field_soundcloud_audio/PPD_Rossow_mixdown.mp3</guid>
  </item>
<item>  
          <title>Asian Architecture Conference</title>    
          <description><![CDATA[ <p>Please join CSIS as we preview key issues that will be on the agenda for leaders participating in November’s Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation (APEC) forum and East Asia Summit (EAS), as well as broader trends in multilateral structures in the Asia-Pacific.</p>
<p> <b>9:20 a.m. - Welcoming Remarks</b><br />  <br /> <b>Dr.</b> <b>Amy Searight</b><br /> Senior Adviser and Director, Southeast Asia Program<br /> Center for Strategic and International Studies<br />  <br /> <b>Opening Keynote</b><br />  <br /> <b>Rep. Ami Bera (D-CA)</b><br /> Chair, Subcommittee on Oversight and Investigations, Committee on Foreign Affairs<br /> U.S. House of Representatives<br />  <br /> <i>Introduction:</i> <br /> <b>Monica Hardy Whaley</b><br /> President<br /> National Center for APEC<br />  <br /> <b>10:00 a.m. - Beyond the Bogor Goals: APEC’s Role in a Turbulent Economic Atmosphere</b><br />  <br /> <b>Sandra Oudkirk</b><br /> U.S. Senior Official for APEC and Deputy Assistant Secretary for Australia, New Zealand, and the Pacific Islands, Bureau of East Asian and Pacific Affairs<br /> U.S. Department of State<br />  <br /> <b>H.E. Rosemary Banks</b><br /> Ambassador<br /> Embassy of New Zealand</p>
<p> <b>Richard Cantor</b><br /> Chief of Credit Risk<br /> Moody’s Corporation<br />  <br /> <b>Ito Sadanori</b><br /> Special Advisor to the Ministry of Economy, Trade and Industry (METI), Japan and Director, Japan External Trade Organization (JETRO) New York</p>
<p> <i>Moderator:</i> <br /> <b>William Reinsch</b><br /> Senior Adviser and Scholl Chair in International Business<br /> Center for Strategic and International Studies<br />  <br /> <b>Coffee Break</b>- <b>11:15 a.m. </b><br />  <br /> <b>11:30 a.m. - Strategic Priorities for the East Asia Summit</b><br />  <br /> <b>Boosara Kanchanalai</b><br /> Minister<br /> Royal Thai Embassy<br />  <br /> <b>David Nakamura</b><br /> White House Reporter<br /> The Washington Post<br />                                    <br /> <b>Malcolm Cook</b><br /> Senior Fellow<br /> ISEAS Yusof Ishak Institute<br />  <br /> <b>Dhruva Jaishankar</b><br /> Director of the US Initiative<br /> Observer Research Foundation<br />  <br /> <i>Moderator:</i><br /> <b>Dr. Amy E. Searight</b><br /> Senior Adviser and Director, Southeast Asia Program<br /> Center for Strategic and International Studies<br />  <br /> <b>12:45 p.m. - Lunch Served</b><br />  <br /> <b>2:00 p.m. - Armchair Discussion</b><br />  <br /> <b>Takehiko Nakao</b><br /> President<br /> Asian Development Bank<br />  <br /> <i>Moderator:</i><br /> <b>Matthew P. Goodman</b><br /> Senior Vice President and Simon Chair in Political Economy<br /> Center for Strategic and International Studies</p>
<p> <i>The conference is made possible with support from the Government of Japan, the National Center for APEC, and the Asian Development Bank.</i></p>
 ]]></description>    
            <itunes:author>William Alan Reinsch, Matthew P. Goodman</itunes:author>
    
          <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2019 09:00:00 -0400</pubDate>    
          <enclosure  url="https://csis-website-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/s3fs-public/field_soundcloud_audio/Asian%20Architecture%20Conference.mp3" type="audio/mpeg" length="226707313" />
<itunes:duration>4:17:05</itunes:duration>
<guid>https://csis-website-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/s3fs-public/field_soundcloud_audio/Asian%20Architecture%20Conference.mp3</guid>
  </item>
<item>  
          <title>Kirchner 3.0</title>    
          <description><![CDATA[ By: Richard Miles<br />
<br />
Argentines go to the polls on October 27th, and the results may spell the end of Mauricio Macri’s presidency. What went wrong? Michael Matera, Argentine expert and Director of the Americas Program at CSIS, explains how inflation never went away and growth never returned. He also makes predictions on the polices of a likely Alberto Fernández - Cristina Fernández de Kirchner government, and whether the two can even govern together. ]]></description>    
            <itunes:author>CSIS</itunes:author>
    
          <pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 14:00:00 -0400</pubDate>    
          <enclosure  url="https://csis-website-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/s3fs-public/field_soundcloud_audio/35West_Matera_FINAL1.mp3" type="audio/mpeg" length="30017861" />
<itunes:duration>20:51</itunes:duration>
<guid>https://csis-website-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/s3fs-public/field_soundcloud_audio/35West_Matera_FINAL1.mp3</guid>
  </item>
<item>  
          <title>Trade Guys on the Road: CIBE Edition</title>    
          <description><![CDATA[ <p>In this episode, the Trade Guys and Andrew hit the road to record in front of the Centers for International Business Education and Research directors at The George Washington University. The event was organized by the University of Maryland’s Robert H. Smith School of Business. On the agenda was the USMCA amid the impeachment inquiry, and the US-Japan deal.</p>
 ]]></description>    
            <itunes:author>Scott Miller, William Alan Reinsch, H. Andrew Schwartz</itunes:author>
    
          <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 14:45:00 -0400</pubDate>    
          <enclosure  url="https://csis-website-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/s3fs-public/field_soundcloud_audio/Final_191027_GW%20Live_Edit%203.mp3" type="audio/mpeg" length="39356960" />
<itunes:duration>27:20</itunes:duration>
<guid>https://csis-website-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/s3fs-public/field_soundcloud_audio/Final_191027_GW%20Live_Edit%203.mp3</guid>
  </item>
<item>  
          <title>Beyond the Brink: Escalation and Conflict in U.S.-China Economic Relations</title>    
          <description><![CDATA[ <div>

</div>
The U.S.-China trade war is unprecedented in size, scope, and importance. The potential economic costs of the conflict—and any decoupling it prompts—are enormous, not only to the United States and China but to the global economy. Nearly 18 months since escalation began, the path to resolution is still unclear.<br />
<br />
In this event, senior experts will discuss the state of U.S.-China trade relations today and roll out a major CSIS report on escalation dynamics in economic conflict. The event will draw on game theory as well as observations of real-world escalation to help policymakers manage economic conflict with China.<br />
<br />
<b>Agenda:</b><br />
<i>Welcome and Presentation of Findings</i><br />
<a href="https://www.csis.org/people/matthew-p-goodman">Matthew P. Goodman</a> <br />
Senior Vice President and Simon Chair in Political Economy, CSIS <br />
<br />
<i>Expert Panel Discussion</i><br />
<a href="https://www.csis.org/people/scott-kennedy">Scott Kennedy</a><br />
Senior Adviser and Trustee Chair in Chinese Business and Economics, CSIS<br />
<br />
<a href="https://www.csis.org/people/william-alan-reinsch">William Reinsch</a> <br />
Senior Adviser and Scholl Chair in International Business, CSIS<br />
<br />
<a href="https://www.arnoldporter.com/en/people/r/reade-claire">Claire Reade</a> <br />
Senior Counsel, Arnold &amp; Porter<br />
<br />
<a href="https://www.csis.org/people/stephanie-segal">Stephanie Segal</a><br />
Senior Fellow, Simon Chair in Political Economy, CSIS<br />
<br />
<i>This event was made possible by support from Smith Richardson Foundation and Alcoa Foundation.</i><br />
  ]]></description>    
            <itunes:author>Matthew P. Goodman, William Alan Reinsch, Scott Kennedy, Stephanie Segal</itunes:author>
    
          <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2019 14:30:00 -0400</pubDate>    
          <enclosure  url="https://csis-website-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/s3fs-public/field_soundcloud_audio/Beyond%20the%20Brink-%20Escalation%20Dominance%20in%20the%20U.S.-China%20Trade%20War.mp3" type="audio/mpeg" length="88210633" />
<itunes:duration>1:34:40</itunes:duration>
<guid>https://csis-website-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/s3fs-public/field_soundcloud_audio/Beyond%20the%20Brink-%20Escalation%20Dominance%20in%20the%20U.S.-China%20Trade%20War.mp3</guid>
  </item>
<item>  
          <title>Global Imbalances: The Role of Exchange Rates and Other Policies in External Adjustments</title>    
          <description><![CDATA[ Concern over external imbalances – specifically “excessive” trade deficits and surpluses – is nothing new. But the current environment of escalating trade tensions between the world’s two largest economies underscores the importance of understanding the actual drivers of trade outcomes. Exchange rates are part of the story, but only a part.<br />
<br />
In the wake of the Global Financial Crisis, and at the direction of the world’s largest economies, the IMF began publishing an annual report to identify the key sources and drivers of external imbalances. The IMF’s latest ESR estimates that about 35 to 45 percent of overall current account surpluses and deficits were “excessive” in 2018, are increasingly concentrated in advanced economies, and are now driven mainly by fiscal policies and structural factors.<br />
<br />
On September 13, Dr. Gita Gopinath, Economic Counsellor and Director of the Research Department at the IMF, will speak to the findings of the latest ESR in a keynote address at CSIS. She will then be joined by an expert panel to discuss global imbalances and the dynamics of external adjustment.<br />
<br />
<b>Keynote address</b><b>:</b><br />
<a href="https://blogs.imf.org/bloggers/gita-gopinath/">Gita Gopinath</a>, Economic Counsellor and Director of the Research Department at the International Monetary Fund (IMF)<br />
<br />
<i>Introduced by</i><br />
<a href="https://www.csis.org/people/matthew-p-goodman">Matthew P. Goodman</a>, Senior Vice President and Simon Chair in Political Economy, CSIS<br />
<br />
<b>Expert panel featuring:</b><br />
<a href="https://www.iif.com/About-Us/Our-Leadership">Robin Brooks</a>, Managing Director and Chief Economist, Institute of International Finance<br />
<a href="https://www.omfif.org/about/team/mark-sobel/">Mark Sobel</a>, US Chairman, OMFIF; former Deputy Assistant Secretary, US Treasury; and former US representative at the IMF<br />
<br />
<i>Moderated by</i><br />
<a href="https://www.csis.org/people/stephanie-segal">Stephanie Segal</a>, Simon Chair Senior Fellow, CSIS<br />
<br />
<i>This event was made possible by general support to CSIS.</i> ]]></description>    
            <itunes:author>Matthew P. Goodman, Stephanie Segal, Mark Sobel</itunes:author>
    
          <pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2019 09:00:00 -0400</pubDate>    
          <enclosure  url="https://csis-website-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/s3fs-public/field_soundcloud_audio/Global%20Imbalances-%20The%20Role%20of%20Exchange%20Rates%20and%20Other%20Policies%20in%20External%20Adjustments.mp3" type="audio/mpeg" length="217402651" />
<itunes:duration>1:30:36</itunes:duration>
<guid>https://csis-website-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/s3fs-public/field_soundcloud_audio/Global%20Imbalances-%20The%20Role%20of%20Exchange%20Rates%20and%20Other%20Policies%20in%20External%20Adjustments.mp3</guid>
  </item>
<item>  
          <title>Incentivizing Reform: the MCC&#039;s Approach to Reducing Poverty</title>    
          <description><![CDATA[ <p>In this episode, Dan sits down with Sean Cairncross, Chief Executive Officer of the Millennium Challenge Corporation (MCC). As CEO, Mr. Cairncross leads the agency and provides strategic direction and vision as MCC fulfills its mission of reducing poverty through economic growth and advancing America’s interests around the globe. Dan and Mr. Cairncross discuss the recent MCC-Cote D’Ivoire compact, the addition of regional compacts, the MCC model, and beyond. They also analyze how the MCC integrates accountability and sustainability mechanisms into their agenda and how its threshold programs lead to successful country compacts.</p>
 ]]></description>    
            <itunes:author>Daniel F. Runde</itunes:author>
    
          <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2019 12:30:00 -0400</pubDate>    
          <enclosure  url="https://csis-website-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/s3fs-public/field_soundcloud_audio/PPD_190814_Sean_Cairncross_mixdown.mp3" type="audio/mpeg" length="29421710" />
<itunes:duration>20:26</itunes:duration>
<guid>https://csis-website-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/s3fs-public/field_soundcloud_audio/PPD_190814_Sean_Cairncross_mixdown.mp3</guid>
  </item>
<item>  
          <title>Failing Faster to Succeed</title>    
          <description><![CDATA[ <p> Liz Smith, Executive Chairman of the Board and former CEO of Bloomin’ Brands and deputy chair of the Atlanta Fed, joined Beverly Kirk to talk about the importance of embracing your failures in the workplace, learning the lessons, and moving on quickly. They also discussed her mission of creating gender parity on corporate boards.</p>
 ]]></description>    
            <itunes:author>Beverly Kirk</itunes:author>
    
          <pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2019 11:00:00 -0400</pubDate>    
          <enclosure  url="https://csis-website-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/s3fs-public/field_soundcloud_audio/190815_Liz_Edit%203.mp3" type="audio/mpeg" length="41569376" />
<itunes:duration>28:53</itunes:duration>
<guid>https://csis-website-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/s3fs-public/field_soundcloud_audio/190815_Liz_Edit%203.mp3</guid>
  </item>
<item>  
          <title>Chinese Interests and Policies in the Middle East: A Conversation with Jon Alterman</title>    
          <description><![CDATA[ <p>By: Bonnie S. Glaser</p>
<p> This episode examines China’s increasing engagement with countries in the Middle East and North Africa (MENA). Our guest, Dr. Jon Alterman, evaluates the main drivers of China’s growing involvement in the region, including its crude oil imports and investment in ports and infrastructure. Dr. Alterman also explains China’s non-interference policy in the region’s disputes, and why China’s relationship with MENA countries has not suffered since China’s mass detention of Uighur populations in Xinjiang.</p>
<p> Dr. Jon Alterman is a senior vice president, holds the Zbigniew Brzezinski Chair in Global Security and Geostrategy, and is director of the Middle East Program at CSIS. He previously served as a member of the Policy Planning Staff at the U.S. Department of State and as a special assistant to the assistant secretary of state for Near Eastern affairs. In addition to his policy work, he often teaches Middle Eastern studies at the Johns Hopkins School of Advanced International Studies and the George Washington University.</p>
 ]]></description>    
            <itunes:author>Jon B. Alterman</itunes:author>
    
          <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2019 10:30:00 -0400</pubDate>    
          <enclosure  url="https://csis-website-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/s3fs-public/field_soundcloud_audio/CP_190731_Jon_Alterman_mixdown.mp3" type="audio/mpeg" length="36261285" />
<itunes:duration>25:11</itunes:duration>
<guid>https://csis-website-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/s3fs-public/field_soundcloud_audio/CP_190731_Jon_Alterman_mixdown.mp3</guid>
  </item>
<item>  
          <title>Currency Manipulation and the Belt &amp; Road</title>    
          <description><![CDATA[ <p>In this episode, the Trade Guys and Andrew discuss the Trump administration's designation of China as a currency manipulator. They also welcome a special in-house guest, Jonathan Hillman, who is a senior fellow with the CSIS Simon Chair in Political Economy and directs the <a href="https://reconnectingasia.csis.org/">Reconnecting Asia Project</a>. Reconnecting Asia tracks new roads, railways, ports, and other infrastructure projects across Eurasia--and most notably, China's Belt &amp; Road initiative.</p>
<p> Download the full transcript <a href="https://www.csis.org/analysis/currency-manipulation-and-belt-road">here</a>.</p>
 ]]></description>    
            <itunes:author>Scott Miller, William Alan Reinsch, H. Andrew Schwartz</itunes:author>
    
          <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2019 11:30:00 -0400</pubDate>    
          <enclosure  url="https://csis-website-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/s3fs-public/field_soundcloud_audio/TGE61_Hillman.mp3" type="audio/mpeg" length="44586352" />
<itunes:duration>29:09</itunes:duration>
<guid>https://csis-website-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/s3fs-public/field_soundcloud_audio/TGE61_Hillman.mp3</guid>
  </item>
<item>  
          <title>Not So Easy Money</title>    
          <description><![CDATA[ <p>By: Richard Miles</p>
<p> Latin America has had a love-hate relationship with foreign investment. China is the latest suitor to test the region’s readiness to join the global economy. Stephen Kaplan, professor of international affairs and political science at George Washington University, dissects China’s role in the region, as well as the prospects for Venezuela to eventually rebuild its economy.</p>
 ]]></description>    
            <itunes:author>CSIS</itunes:author>
    
          <pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2019 15:15:00 -0400</pubDate>    
          <enclosure  url="https://csis-website-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/s3fs-public/field_soundcloud_audio/35_Stephen_Kaplan_FINAL_mixdown.mp3" type="audio/mpeg" length="36093517" />
<itunes:duration>25:04</itunes:duration>
<guid>https://csis-website-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/s3fs-public/field_soundcloud_audio/35_Stephen_Kaplan_FINAL_mixdown.mp3</guid>
  </item>
<item>  
          <title>5G Innovation and Security</title>    
          <description><![CDATA[ <p>The development of 5G technologies is a focus of intense competition. This event will focus on how the United States can best work to develop a common approach to 5G security while remaining at the forefront of 5G innovation. Please join us for interactive discussions with senior leaders in industry and government. </p>
<p><b>Agenda</b></p>
<p> <i>2:30 pm </i>— Opening Remarks by <b>Director Christopher Krebs</b>, Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency, U.S. Department of Homeland Security</p>
<p> <i>2:40 pm </i>— Industry Panel<b> – “Security in 5G</b>”<br />
</p><div>Moderator<br /> <b>Kim Hart</b>, Managing Editor, Axios
<p> Panelists<br /> <b>Jason Boswell</b>, Head of Security, Network Product Solutions, North America, Ericsson<br /> <b>John Godfrey</b>, Senior Vice President, Public Policy, Samsung<br /> <b>Susie Armstrong, </b>Senior Vice President, Engineering, Qualcomm<br /> <b>Peter Lord, </b>Vice President, Strategic Initiatives, Oracle</p></div>
<p> <i>3:25 pm</i> — Conversation on the International Landscape of 5G with <b>Ambassador Robert Strayer</b>, Deputy Assistant Secretary for Cyber and International Communications and Information Policy, U.S. Department of State</p>
<p> <i>3:55 pm</i> — Industry Panel<b> – “Innovation in 5G</b>”</p>
<div>Moderator<br /> <b>Denise Zheng</b>, Vice President, Business Roundtable
<p> Panelists<br /> <b>Eric Wenger</b>, Director, Cybersecurity and Privacy Policy,  Cisco<br /> <b>Kevin Linehan</b>, Vice President, Office of Chief Technology Officer, CommScope<br /> <b>Chris Boyer</b>, Assistant Vice President, Global Public Policy, AT&amp;T<br /> <b>Valerie J. Parker</b>, Director, PE Network and Edge Compute Business and Technical Strategy, Intel  <br />  </p></div>
<p> <i>4:40 pm</i> — Panel <b>- "U.S. Government Approach to 5G Innovation and Security" </b><br />
</p><div>Moderator</div>
<div><b>Clete Johnson</b>, Senior Fellow, CSIS &amp; Partner, Wilkinson Barker Knauer LLP</div>
<div> </div>
<div>Panelists</div>
<div><b>Commissioner Geoffrey Starks</b>, U.S. Federal Communications Commission<br /> <b>Director Christopher Krebs</b>, Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency, U.S. Department of Homeland Security<br /> <b>Jennifer Lane,</b> Senior Counsel, Office of the General Counsel, U.S. Department of Commerce<br />  </div>
<p> <i>This event is made possible with support from Business Roundtable.</i></p>
 ]]></description>    
            <itunes:author>James Andrew Lewis, Clete Johnson</itunes:author>
    
          <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2019 14:30:00 -0400</pubDate>    
          <enclosure  url="https://csis-website-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/s3fs-public/field_soundcloud_audio/5G%20Innovation%20and%20Security.mp3" type="audio/mpeg" length="155742368" />
<itunes:duration>2:57:40</itunes:duration>
<guid>https://csis-website-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/s3fs-public/field_soundcloud_audio/5G%20Innovation%20and%20Security.mp3</guid>
  </item>
<item>  
          <title>Are Sanctions Working?</title>    
          <description><![CDATA[ <a href="https://home.treasury.gov/news/press-releases/sm748">Click here for Under Secretary Mandelker’s complete remarks.</a><br />
<br />
The CSIS Energy &amp; National Security Program is pleased to invite you to <i>Are Sanctions Working?</i>, a conference examining the state of U.S. sanctions―what is different, what is and is not working, and implications for U.S. foreign policy, the global economy, and the energy sector.<br />
<br />
The United States has employed sanctions as a foreign policy mechanism for decades.  In recent years, the United States has developed a new generation of more targeted, more agile economic sanctions.  It has become increasingly reliant on these new tools, and its ambitions for their impact have increased.<br />
<br />
Whether more robust sanctions regimes have won any clear victories is a matter of debate.   In the last three years, U.S.-imposed unilateral and secondary sanctions regimes have sought to influence North Korea, Russia, Iran, and Venezuela.  But countries that have been subject to sanctions for years have found ways to adjust to U.S. moves.<br />
<br />
This conference will review the efficacy of the new style of U.S. sanctions, understand what is contributing to their success or failure, and gauge their future.  Speakers will also explore how sustained use of sanctions is impacting one universally important sector: the energy sector.<br />
 


<p><b>Welcome &amp; Opening Remarks</b><br />
<i>Dr. John Hamre, President and CEO, CSIS</i><br />
<br />
<b>Keynote </b><br />
<i>Sigal Mandelker, Under Secretary for Terrorism and Financial Intelligence, U.S. Department of the Treasury</i><br />
<br />
<b>Sanctions and Foreign Policy</b><br />
<i>Heather Conley, Jon Alterman, Jeffrey Mankoff, Moises Rendon, Matthew Goodman</i><br />
<br />
<b>Sanctions and the Energy Sector</b><br />
<i>Peter Flanagan, Sarah Ladislaw, Kevin Book, Stephanie Segal</i></p>
<br />
<i>This event is made possible by general funding to CSIS and the CSIS Energy &amp; National Security Program.</i>


 ]]></description>    
            <itunes:author>John J. Hamre, Sarah Ladislaw, Matthew P. Goodman, Jon B. Alterman, Stephanie Segal, Kevin Book, Jeffrey Mankoff, Moises Rendon</itunes:author>
    
          <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2019 09:00:00 -0400</pubDate>    
          <enclosure  url="https://csis-website-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/s3fs-public/field_soundcloud_audio/Are%20Sanctions%20Working_0.mp3" type="audio/mpeg" length="147725111" />
<itunes:duration>2:47:32</itunes:duration>
<guid>https://csis-website-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/s3fs-public/field_soundcloud_audio/Are%20Sanctions%20Working_0.mp3</guid>
  </item>
<item>  
          <title>The China Tweets and Liz Warren&#039;s Trade Plan</title>    
          <description><![CDATA[ <p>In this episode, Andrew and the Trade Guys break down President Trump's China tweets from this morning as negotiators from both sides resume talks this week in Shanghai. What is the president's next move? Plus, Senator Elizabeth Warren unveils her trade policy. How might trade play out on the Democratic debate stage?</p>
<p> Download the full transcript <a href="/analysis/china-tweets-and-liz-warrens-trade-plan">here</a>.</p>
 ]]></description>    
            <itunes:author>Scott Miller, William Alan Reinsch, H. Andrew Schwartz</itunes:author>
    
          <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2019 15:45:00 -0400</pubDate>    
          <enclosure  url="https://csis-website-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/s3fs-public/field_soundcloud_audio/TG_E60.mp3" type="audio/mpeg" length="49136457" />
<itunes:duration>32:20</itunes:duration>
<guid>https://csis-website-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/s3fs-public/field_soundcloud_audio/TG_E60.mp3</guid>
  </item>
<item>  
          <title>Transatlantic Choices: Cooperation or Conflict?</title>    
          <description><![CDATA[ The CSIS Scholl Chair is honored to be hosting Dr. Sabine Weyand, the new Director General of Trade for the European Commission on her first official trip to Washington, DC in her new role. The trading relationship between the United States and the European Union forms a key part of the backbone of the transatlantic alliance. Join us as we discuss with Dr. Weyand this relationship, her vision of trade in the 21st century, and the role of the U.S. and the EU in constructing and maintaining a multilateral global trading system. <br />
<br />
<i>This event is made possible by general support to CSIS.</i> ]]></description>    
            <itunes:author>William Alan Reinsch</itunes:author>
    
          <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2019 09:15:00 -0400</pubDate>    
          <enclosure  url="https://csis-website-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/s3fs-public/field_soundcloud_audio/Transatlantic%20Choices-%20Cooperation%20or%20Conflict_0.mp3" type="audio/mpeg" length="64581965" />
<itunes:duration>1:11:30</itunes:duration>
<guid>https://csis-website-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/s3fs-public/field_soundcloud_audio/Transatlantic%20Choices-%20Cooperation%20or%20Conflict_0.mp3</guid>
  </item>
<item>  
          <title>World Peace Through World Trade</title>    
          <description><![CDATA[ In this episode, Andrew and the Trade Guys talk with Chris Padilla, vice president for government and regulatory affairs at IBM, about why trade matters to IBM and how the company has navigated the global economy for over 100 years.<br />
<br />
Download the full transcript <a href="https://www.csis.org/analysis/world-peace-through-world-trade">here</a>. ]]></description>    
            <itunes:author>Scott Miller, William Alan Reinsch, H. Andrew Schwartz</itunes:author>
    
          <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2019 16:00:00 -0400</pubDate>    
          <enclosure  url="https://csis-website-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/s3fs-public/field_soundcloud_audio/EP%2058_190716_Chris_edit%201.mp3" type="audio/mpeg" length="51369440" />
<itunes:duration>35:41</itunes:duration>
<guid>https://csis-website-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/s3fs-public/field_soundcloud_audio/EP%2058_190716_Chris_edit%201.mp3</guid>
  </item>
<item>  
          <title>China and the World Trade Organization: A Conversation with Tu Xinquan</title>    
          <description><![CDATA[ <p>By: Bonnie S. Glaser</p>
<p> This episode examines China’s role in the World Trade Organization (WTO), including the economic and political effects of membership since its accession process. Our guest, Dr. Tu Xinquan, discusses the ways in which Beijing has utilized the WTO dispute settlement mechanism and assesses how well it has complied with WTO rulings. He also explains China’s proposed WTO reforms and the overall influence of the WTO as an organization amid anti-globalization sentiments.</p>
<p> Dr. Tu Xinquan is Executive Dean and Professor at the China Institute for WTO Studies at the University of International Business and Economics, Beijing (UIBE). Dr. Tu’s research focuses on the WTO, Chinese trade policy, agreements on government procurement, and US-China trade relations.</p>
 ]]></description>    
            <itunes:author>CSIS</itunes:author>
    
          <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2019 15:15:00 -0400</pubDate>    
          <enclosure  url="https://csis-website-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/s3fs-public/field_soundcloud_audio/FINAL_190619_Tu_Xinquan_mixdown.mp3" type="audio/mpeg" length="32751297" />
<itunes:duration>22:45</itunes:duration>
<guid>https://csis-website-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/s3fs-public/field_soundcloud_audio/FINAL_190619_Tu_Xinquan_mixdown.mp3</guid>
  </item>
<item>  
          <title>ROK-U.S. Strategic Forum 2019</title>    
          <description><![CDATA[ <p>Please join us for our annual ROK-U.S. Strategic Forum 2019. A timely discussion with current and former government officials, scholars, experts, and opinion leaders from the United States and Korea who will participate in a series of panel discussions to address the state of the U.S.-ROK alliance, the prospects for the peace building process on the Korean Peninsula, and the changing regional dynamics in East Asia and beyond.<br />
<br />
This event will be co-hosted with the Korea Foundation, a leading organization of Korea's international exchange and public policy initiative.<br />
<br />
You are also invited to join us after the ROK-U.S. Strategic Forum 2019 for a special 10 anniversary celebration of the CSIS Korea Chair, starting at 5:00 PM. For more information and to register for the celebration, please visit this page: <a href="https://www.csis.org/events/csis-korea-chair-10-year-anniversary-celebration">https://www.csis.org/events/csis-korea-chair-10-year-anniversary-celebration</a> </p>

<p><b>10:30 – 10:45 AM WELCOMING REMARKS</b></p>

<p><b>Ambassador Richard Armitage</b><br />
<i>President, Armitage International; Trustee, CSIS</i></p>

<p><b>Ambassador Lee Sihyung, </b><i>President, The Korea Foundation</i></p>

<p><b>10:45 – 11:30 AM KEYNOTE ADDRESS &amp; CONVERSATION</b></p>

<p><b>Congressman Ami Bera</b> (D-CA), <i>Chairman, Subcommittee on Oversight and<br />
Investigations, House Foreign Affairs Committee;<br />
Co-Chair of Congressional Study Group on Korea </i></p>

<p><i>Moderated by</i>:</p>

<p><b>Ambassador Mark Lippert</b>, <i>Senior Advisor, CSIS Korea Chair; Former U.S. Ambassador</i> <i>to the Republic of Korea</i></p>

<p><b>11:30 – 12:30 PM LUNCHEON</b></p>

<p><b>12:30 – 1:45 PM <i>The ROK-U.S. Alliance for Peace and Denuclearization</i>SESSION I: </b></p>

<p><i>Moderator</i>:</p>

<p><b>Mr. David Nakamura, </b><i>White House Correspondent, The Washington Post </i></p>

<p><i>Panelists</i>:</p>

<p><b>Ms. Joy Yamamoto,</b><i> Director, Office of Korean Affairs, U.S. Department of State</i></p>

<p><b>Dr. Victor Cha,</b><i> Senior Adviser and Korea Chair, CSIS; D.S. Song-KF Professor of<br />
Government, Georgetown University;<br />
Former National Security Council</i></p>

<p><b>Dr. Joon Hyung Kim, </b><i>Professor, Handong Global University </i></p>

<p><b>Dr. Sang Hyun Lee, </b><i>Senior Research Fellow, Sejong Institute</i></p>

<p><b>Ambassador Joseph Yun, </b><i>Senior Advisor to the Asia Center,<br />
United States Institute of Peace; Former Special Representative<br />
for North Korea Policy and Deputy Assistant Secretary for<br />
Korea and Japan, U.S. Department of State </i></p>

<p><b>1:45 – 2:00 PM COFFEE BREAK</b></p>

<p><b>2:00 – 3:15 PM</b> <b><i>Recasting and Forecasting of the Peace Building Process on the Korean Peninsula</i>SESSION II: </b></p>

<p><i>Moderator</i>:</p>

<p><b>Ambassador Byungjae Cho, </b><i>Former Chancellor, Korea National<br />
Diplomatic Academy, Former ROK Ambassador to Myanmar and<br />
Malaysia</i></p>

<p><i>Panelists</i>:</p>

<p><b>Dr. Haksoon Paik, </b><i>President, Sejong Institute</i></p>

<p><b>Dr. Ramon Pacheco Pardo</b>, <i>KF-VUB Korea Chair, Institute for European Studies<br />
(IES-VUB); Reader (Associate Professor) in International Relations,<br />
King's College London</i></p>

<p><b>Dr. Jiyoung Park, </b><i>Director and Senior Fellow, Center for<br />
Science and Technology Policy, the Asan Institute for Policy Studies</i></p>

<p><b>Dr. Sue Mi Terry</b>, <i>Senior Fellow, CSIS Korea Chair; Former Senior Analyst,<br />
Central Intelligence Agency; Former National Security Council </i></p>

<p><b>3:15 – 3:30 PM COFFEE BREAK</b></p>

<p><b>3:30 – 4:45 PM</b> <b><i>The Regional Dynamics: East-Asia and Beyond</i>SESSION III: </b></p>

<p><i>Moderator</i>:</p>

<p><b>Dr. Sue Mi Terry</b>, <i>Senior Fellow, CSIS Korea Chair; Former Senior Analyst,<br />
Central Intelligence Agency; Former National Security Council </i></p>

<p><i>...</i></p> ]]></description>    
            <itunes:author>Victor Cha, Mark Lippert, Ramon Pacheco Pardo</itunes:author>
    
          <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2019 10:30:00 -0400</pubDate>    
          <enclosure  url="https://csis-website-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/s3fs-public/field_soundcloud_audio/ROK-U.S.%20Strategic%20Forum%202019%20-%20Morning%20Session.mp3" type="audio/mpeg" length="123193606" />
<itunes:duration>51:20</itunes:duration>
<guid>https://csis-website-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/s3fs-public/field_soundcloud_audio/ROK-U.S.%20Strategic%20Forum%202019%20-%20Morning%20Session.mp3</guid>
  </item>
<item>  
          <title>ROK-U.S. Strategic Forum 2019</title>    
          <description><![CDATA[ <p>Please join us for our annual ROK-U.S. Strategic Forum 2019. A timely discussion with current and former government officials, scholars, experts, and opinion leaders from the United States and Korea who will participate in a series of panel discussions to address the state of the U.S.-ROK alliance, the prospects for the peace building process on the Korean Peninsula, and the changing regional dynamics in East Asia and beyond.<br />
<br />
This event will be co-hosted with the Korea Foundation, a leading organization of Korea's international exchange and public policy initiative.<br />
<br />
You are also invited to join us after the ROK-U.S. Strategic Forum 2019 for a special 10 anniversary celebration of the CSIS Korea Chair, starting at 5:00 PM. For more information and to register for the celebration, please visit this page: <a href="https://www.csis.org/events/csis-korea-chair-10-year-anniversary-celebration">https://www.csis.org/events/csis-korea-chair-10-year-anniversary-celebration</a> </p>

<p><b>10:30 – 10:45 AM WELCOMING REMARKS</b></p>

<p><b>Ambassador Richard Armitage</b><br />
<i>President, Armitage International; Trustee, CSIS</i></p>

<p><b>Ambassador Lee Sihyung, </b><i>President, The Korea Foundation</i></p>

<p><b>10:45 – 11:30 AM KEYNOTE ADDRESS &amp; CONVERSATION</b></p>

<p><b>Congressman Ami Bera</b> (D-CA), <i>Chairman, Subcommittee on Oversight and<br />
Investigations, House Foreign Affairs Committee;<br />
Co-Chair of Congressional Study Group on Korea </i></p>

<p><i>Moderated by</i>:</p>

<p><b>Ambassador Mark Lippert</b>, <i>Senior Advisor, CSIS Korea Chair; Former U.S. Ambassador</i> <i>to the Republic of Korea</i></p>

<p><b>11:30 – 12:30 PM LUNCHEON</b></p>

<p><b>12:30 – 1:45 PM <i>The ROK-U.S. Alliance for Peace and Denuclearization</i>SESSION I: </b></p>

<p><i>Moderator</i>:</p>

<p><b>Mr. David Nakamura, </b><i>White House Correspondent, The Washington Post </i></p>

<p><i>Panelists</i>:</p>

<p><b>Ms. Joy Yamamoto,</b><i> Director, Office of Korean Affairs, U.S. Department of State</i></p>

<p><b>Dr. Victor Cha,</b><i> Senior Adviser and Korea Chair, CSIS; D.S. Song-KF Professor of<br />
Government, Georgetown University;<br />
Former National Security Council</i></p>

<p><b>Dr. Joon Hyung Kim, </b><i>Professor, Handong Global University </i></p>

<p><b>Dr. Sang Hyun Lee, </b><i>Senior Research Fellow, Sejong Institute</i></p>

<p><b>Ambassador Joseph Yun, </b><i>Senior Advisor to the Asia Center,<br />
United States Institute of Peace; Former Special Representative<br />
for North Korea Policy and Deputy Assistant Secretary for<br />
Korea and Japan, U.S. Department of State </i></p>

<p><b>1:45 – 2:00 PM COFFEE BREAK</b></p>

<p><b>2:00 – 3:15 PM</b> <b><i>Recasting and Forecasting of the Peace Building Process on the Korean Peninsula</i>SESSION II: </b></p>

<p><i>Moderator</i>:</p>

<p><b>Ambassador Byungjae Cho, </b><i>Former Chancellor, Korea National<br />
Diplomatic Academy, Former ROK Ambassador to Myanmar and<br />
Malaysia</i></p>

<p><i>Panelists</i>:</p>

<p><b>Dr. Haksoon Paik, </b><i>President, Sejong Institute</i></p>

<p><b>Dr. Ramon Pacheco Pardo</b>, <i>KF-VUB Korea Chair, Institute for European Studies<br />
(IES-VUB); Reader (Associate Professor) in International Relations,<br />
King's College London</i></p>

<p><b>Dr. Jiyoung Park, </b><i>Director and Senior Fellow, Center for<br />
Science and Technology Policy, the Asan Institute for Policy Studies</i></p>

<p><b>Dr. Sue Mi Terry</b>, <i>Senior Fellow, CSIS Korea Chair; Former Senior Analyst,<br />
Central Intelligence Agency; Former National Security Council </i></p>

<p><b>3:15 – 3:30 PM COFFEE BREAK</b></p>

<p><b>3:30 – 4:45 PM</b> <b><i>The Regional Dynamics: East-Asia and Beyond</i>SESSION III: </b></p>

<p><i>Moderator</i>:</p>

<p><b>Dr. Sue Mi Terry</b>, <i>Senior Fellow, CSIS Korea Chair; Former Senior Analyst,<br />
Central Intelligence Agency; Former National Security Council </i></p>

<p><i>...</i></p> ]]></description>    
            <itunes:author>Victor Cha, Mark Lippert, Ramon Pacheco Pardo</itunes:author>
    
          <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2019 10:30:00 -0400</pubDate>    
          <enclosure  url="https://csis-website-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/s3fs-public/field_soundcloud_audio/ROK-U.S.%20Strategic%20Forum%202019%20-%20Afternoon%20Session.mp3" type="audio/mpeg" length="182877799" />
<itunes:duration>3:38:00</itunes:duration>
<guid>https://csis-website-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/s3fs-public/field_soundcloud_audio/ROK-U.S.%20Strategic%20Forum%202019%20-%20Afternoon%20Session.mp3</guid>
  </item>
<item>  
          <title>China-U.S. Trade: The British View</title>    
          <description><![CDATA[ <p> Dame Barbara Woodward, the United Kingdom’s Ambassador to China discusses the current Washington-Beijing trade spat and its implications for the U.K. and the rest of the world. She also talks about 21st century diplomatic challenges and how most are related to China.</p>
 ]]></description>    
            <itunes:author>Beverly Kirk</itunes:author>
    
          <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2019 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>    
          <enclosure  url="https://csis-website-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/s3fs-public/field_soundcloud_audio/woodward_02.mp3" type="audio/mpeg" length="32430918" />
<itunes:duration>22:28</itunes:duration>
<guid>https://csis-website-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/s3fs-public/field_soundcloud_audio/woodward_02.mp3</guid>
  </item>
<item>  
          <title>Calling It War</title>    
          <description><![CDATA[ On this episode, the Trade Guys try to make sense of the latest escalation in the U.S.-China trade spat and predict that the trade war may just be getting starting.<br />
<br />
Download the full transcript <a href="https://www.csis.org/analysis/calling-it-war">here</a>. ]]></description>    
            <itunes:author>William Alan Reinsch, Scott Miller, H. Andrew Schwartz</itunes:author>
    
          <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2019 09:30:00 -0400</pubDate>    
          <enclosure  url="https://csis-website-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/s3fs-public/field_soundcloud_audio/TG_E48_01.mp3" type="audio/mpeg" length="33841075" />
<itunes:duration>22:00</itunes:duration>
<guid>https://csis-website-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/s3fs-public/field_soundcloud_audio/TG_E48_01.mp3</guid>
  </item>
<item>  
          <title>Iran One Year Later: The Trump Administration’s Policy, Looking Back and Looking Forward</title>    
          <description><![CDATA[ Please join the Center for Strategic and International Studies for a discussion with Brian Hook, U.S. special representative for Iran, on President Trump's Iran policy, the impact of the U.S. withdrawal from the JCPOA, and the future of U.S.-Iran relations.<br />
<br />
<b>Brian Hook</b> is the U.S. Special Representative for Iran and Senior Policy Advisor to the Secretary of State. Prior to this appointment, he served as Director of the Policy Planning Staff from 2017-2018. From 2009-2017, he managed an international strategic consulting firm based in Washington, DC. He held a number of senior positions in the Bush Administration, including Assistant Secretary of State for International Organizations; Senior Advisor to the U.S. Ambassador to the United Nations; Special Assistant to the President for Policy in the White House Chief of Staff’s office; and Counsel, Office of Legal Policy, at the Justice Department. He practiced corporate law at Hogan &amp; Hartson in Washington from 1999-2003. Before practicing law, he served as an advisor to Iowa Governor Terry Branstad and to U.S. Congressman James Leach.<br />
<br />
<i>This event is made possible by general support to CSIS. </i> ]]></description>    
            <itunes:author>Jon B. Alterman</itunes:author>
    
          <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2019 13:30:00 -0400</pubDate>    
          <enclosure  url="https://csis-website-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/s3fs-public/field_soundcloud_audio/Iran%20One%20Year%20Later%20The%20Trump%20Administration%E2%80%99s%20Policy%2C%20Looking%20Back%20and%20Looking%20Forward.mp3" type="audio/mpeg" length="143277590" />
<itunes:duration>59:42</itunes:duration>
<guid>https://csis-website-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/s3fs-public/field_soundcloud_audio/Iran%20One%20Year%20Later%20The%20Trump%20Administration%E2%80%99s%20Policy%2C%20Looking%20Back%20and%20Looking%20Forward.mp3</guid>
  </item>
<item>  
          <title>Zimbabwe&#039;s Burgeoning Food Crisis</title>    
          <description><![CDATA[ <p>The CSIS Global Food Security Project and the CSIS Africa Program invite you to join a discussion on the economic decline and food insecurity crisis in Zimbabwe. According to the <a href="https://reliefweb.int/report/zimbabwe/zimbabwe-vulnerability-assessment-committee-results-2018"><i>Zimbabwe Vulnerability Assessment Committee’s 2018 Rural Livelihoods Assessment</i></a>, nearly 2.4 million people in rural Zimbabwe were projected to be severely food insecure by March 2019. In the wake of Cyclone Idai, Zimbabwe's dire condition seems poised to worsen. If the current trends continue, Zimbabwe could be facing a severe humanitarian crises that rivals some of the worst in the world.<br />  <br /> Is Zimbabwe prepared to reform its economy, address its food security challenges, and develop a sustainable strategy to response to natural disasters? How can the international community and the U.S. government support peace and prosperity in the wake of this disaster? Panelists Ashok Chakravarti, Jason Taylor, and Peter Thomas will tackle these questions and shine a light on the escalating situation in Zimbabwe to the Washington policy community.</p>
<p> <i>This event is made possible through the generous support of the Bill &amp; Melinda Gates Foundation.</i></p>
 ]]></description>    
            <itunes:author>Kimberly Flowers</itunes:author>
    
          <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 09:00:00 -0400</pubDate>    
          <enclosure  url="https://csis-website-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/s3fs-public/field_soundcloud_audio/Zimbabwe%27s%20Burgeoning%20Food%20Crisis.mp3" type="audio/mpeg" length="207128169" />
<itunes:duration>1:26:19</itunes:duration>
<guid>https://csis-website-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/s3fs-public/field_soundcloud_audio/Zimbabwe%27s%20Burgeoning%20Food%20Crisis.mp3</guid>
  </item>
<item>  
          <title>Women and Market Mechanisms in North Korea</title>    
          <description><![CDATA[ <p>The growth of markets is one of the most significant socioeconomic developments to occur in North Korea over the past two decades. While many understand that North Korea now has a thriving market system, the important role that the women of North Korea play is not as well known or appreciated.</p>
<p> The CSIS Korea Chair and the North Korea Freedom Coalition invite you to join us for a special event featuring expert discussions on markets and civil society in North Korea as well as a presentation of <a href="https://beyondparallel.csis.org/markets-private-economy-capitalism-north-korea/"><b>Beyond Parallel's mapping of 436 officially sanctioned markets across North Korea</b></a>. The panel discussion will be followed by testimonies from North Korean escapees on the importance of women's roles and experiences in North Korea's markets.</p>
<p> <b>2:00 PM | WELCOMING REMARKS</b><br /> <b>Mr. H. Andrew Schwartz</b>, <i>Chief Communications Officer, CSIS</i><br /> <b>Dr. Suzanne Scholte</b>, <i>Chair, North Korea Freedom Coalition</i></p>
<p> <b>2:05 PM | SESSION I: </b><b>Markets and Civil Society in North Korea</b><br /> <b>Ms. Amy Lehr</b>, <i>Director, Human Rights Initiative, CSIS </i><br /> <b>Dr. Victor Cha</b>, <i>Senior Adviser and Korea Chair, CSIS; D.S. Song-KF Professor of Government, Georgetown University</i><br /> <b>Dr. Andrew Yeo</b>, <i>Associate Professor and Director of Asian Studies, The Catholic University of America</i><br /> <b>Ms. Olivia Enos</b>, <i>Policy Analyst, Asian Studies Center, The Heritage Foundation</i></p>
<p> <b>2:55 PM | SESSION II: Women in the Markets<br /> Dr. Suzanne Scholte</b>, <i>North Korea Freedom Coalition</i><br /> <b>Ms. Lee, Hyo-joo</b>, <i>North Korean Escapee with Experience as Wholesale Market Vendor and Diesel Oil Trader</i><br /> <b>Ms. Park, Ji-hye</b>, <i>North Korean Escapee with Experience as Rice and Corn Trader</i><br /> <b>Ms. Heo, Cho-hee</b>, <i>North Korean Escapee with Experience as Small Consumer Goods Trader</i><br /> <b>Ms. Kim, Ji-young</b>, <i>North Korean Escapee</i></p>
<p> <b>4:00 PM | ADJOURNMENT</b></p>
<p> <i>This event is made possible by the general support to CSIS.</i></p>
 ]]></description>    
            <itunes:author>Victor Cha, Amy K. Lehr</itunes:author>
    
          <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2019 14:00:00 -0400</pubDate>    
          <enclosure  url="https://csis-website-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/s3fs-public/field_soundcloud_audio/Women%20and%20Market%20Mechanisms%20in%20North%20Korea_0.mp3" type="audio/mpeg" length="89160411" />
<itunes:duration>1:48:12</itunes:duration>
<guid>https://csis-website-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/s3fs-public/field_soundcloud_audio/Women%20and%20Market%20Mechanisms%20in%20North%20Korea_0.mp3</guid>
  </item>
<item>  
          <title>The Higher Road: Forging a U.S. Strategy for the Global Infrastructure Challenge</title>    
          <description><![CDATA[ <div><a href="https://www.csis.org/higherroad">Download the Report</a></div>

<div><a href="https://www.csis.org/analysis/higher-road-forging-us-strategy-global-infrastructure-challenge">Download the Brief</a></div>
Over the next 15 years, it is projected that more infrastructure will be built globally than currently exists. Please join the CSIS Reconnecting Asia Project and the Project on Prosperity and Development for the rollout of a new report discussing how the United States can strategically shape the global infrastructure buildout. <br />
 
<p>Opening remarks by:<br />
<b>Matthew P. Goodman</b><br />
Senior Vice President, Simon Chair in Political Economy and Senior Adviser for Asian Economics, CSIS  </p>
Featuring a Panel Discussion with:<br />
<br />
<b>Ambassador Charlene Barshefsky</b><br />
<i>Senior International Partner, WilmerHale</i><br />
<i>Former </i><i>U.S. Trade Representative</i><br />
 <br />
<b>Stephen J. Hadley</b><br />
<i>Principal, RiceHadleyGates LLC</i><br />
<i>Former National Security Advisor</i><br />
<br />
<b>Peter Raymond</b><br />
<i>Senior Associate, Reconnecting Asia Project and Simon Chair, CSIS</i><br />
<i>Former Global Advisory Leader, Capital Projects &amp; Infrastructure Practice, PwC</i><br />
<br />
Moderated by: <br />
<b>Daniel F. Runde</b><br />
<i>Senior Vice President, William A. Schreyer Chair and Director, Project on Prosperity and Development, CSIS</i>

<div> </div>

<div>
<div>
<div><i>This event is made possible by generous support from Bechtel Group, IBM, and the Inter-American Development Bank. </i></div>
</div>
</div>
 ]]></description>    
            <itunes:author>Matthew P. Goodman, Daniel F. Runde, Peter Raymond </itunes:author>
    
          <pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2019 13:00:00 -0400</pubDate>    
          <enclosure  url="https://csis-website-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/s3fs-public/field_soundcloud_audio/The%20Higher%20Road%20Forging%20a%20U.S.%20Strategy%20for%20the%20Global%20Infrastructure%20Challenge.mp3" type="audio/mpeg" length="79210990" />
<itunes:duration>1:20:15</itunes:duration>
<guid>https://csis-website-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/s3fs-public/field_soundcloud_audio/The%20Higher%20Road%20Forging%20a%20U.S.%20Strategy%20for%20the%20Global%20Infrastructure%20Challenge.mp3</guid>
  </item>
<item>  
          <title>Winning at the WTO</title>    
          <description><![CDATA[ <p>Andrew and the Trade Guys catch up on the latest WTO dispute settlement news, review the latest economic analysis of the USMCA, and somehow manage to weave in a Game of Thrones update.</p>
 ]]></description>    
            <itunes:author>William Alan Reinsch, Scott Miller, H. Andrew Schwartz</itunes:author>
    
          <pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2019 11:15:00 -0400</pubDate>    
          <enclosure  url="https://csis-website-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/s3fs-public/field_soundcloud_audio/TG_E46_final.mp3" type="audio/mpeg" length="41984299" />
<itunes:duration>27:41</itunes:duration>
<guid>https://csis-website-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/s3fs-public/field_soundcloud_audio/TG_E46_final.mp3</guid>
  </item>
<item>  
          <title>The Famished Road</title>    
          <description><![CDATA[ <p>How do we build roads to the future? Former Liberian Minister of Public Works Gyude Moore (Center for Global Development) explains how cutting-edge technology can revolutionize Africa’s basic infrastructure challenges. Judd Devermont (CSIS), Diane McMahon (Bechtel Corporation), and Joel Wiegert (Nexant) weigh in on Moore’s vision, Uganda-Rwanda tensions, and the African Continental Free Trade Agreement (AfCFTA).</p>
 ]]></description>    
            <itunes:author>CSIS</itunes:author>
    
          <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2019 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>    
          <enclosure  url="https://csis-website-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/s3fs-public/field_soundcloud_audio/IA_E11_final.mp3" type="audio/mpeg" length="36300028" />
<itunes:duration>25:01</itunes:duration>
<guid>https://csis-website-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/s3fs-public/field_soundcloud_audio/IA_E11_final.mp3</guid>
  </item>
<item>  
          <title>Delivering Prosperity in the Indo-Pacific </title>    
          <description><![CDATA[ 




Please join us on April 18 for a lively discussion of U.S.-Australia economic partnership. Participants will receive the CSIS Simon Chair in Political Economy’s latest brief, “Delivering Prosperity in the Indo-Pacific,” a wide-ranging look at opportunities for U.S.-Australia coordination in the Indo-Pacific across five sectors (infrastructure, investment facilitation, energy, digital economy, and financial systems).<br />
<br />
PANELISTS:

<p><b>Bill Costello</b><br />
Minister-Counsellor of Development, Embassy of Australia</p>

<p><b><a href="https://csis.us11.list-manage.com/track/click?u=833ec271d60c6750d9c3baaac&amp;id=87c2b8448e&amp;e=01632b0a25">Mark Sobel</a></b><br />
U.S. Chairman, OMFIF; Former Deputy Assistant Secretary, U.S. Department of the Treasury</p>

<p><b><a href="https://csis.us11.list-manage.com/track/click?u=833ec271d60c6750d9c3baaac&amp;id=393c82a37c&amp;e=01632b0a25">Nikos Tsafos</a></b><br />
Senior Fellow, Energy and National Security Program, CSIS</p>

<p><b><a href="https://csis.us11.list-manage.com/track/click?u=833ec271d60c6750d9c3baaac&amp;id=24c00c4d81&amp;e=01632b0a25">Matthew P. Goodman</a></b><br />
Senior Vice President and Simon Chair, CSIS</p>
<i>MODERATED BY</i>

<p><b><a href="https://csis.us11.list-manage.com/track/click?u=833ec271d60c6750d9c3baaac&amp;id=05dd3380d3&amp;e=01632b0a25">Amy Searight</a></b><br />
Senior Adviser and Director, Southeast Asia Program, CSIS</p>
<i>This event is made possible through general support to CSIS.</i>  ]]></description>    
            <itunes:author>Matthew P. Goodman</itunes:author>
    
          <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2019 14:30:00 -0400</pubDate>    
          <enclosure  url="https://csis-website-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/s3fs-public/field_soundcloud_audio/Delivering%20Prosperity%20in%20the%20Indo-Pacific.mp3" type="audio/mpeg" length="172730129" />
<itunes:duration>1:11:59</itunes:duration>
<guid>https://csis-website-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/s3fs-public/field_soundcloud_audio/Delivering%20Prosperity%20in%20the%20Indo-Pacific.mp3</guid>
  </item>
<item>  
          <title>Digital Trade with Victoria Espinel of BSA | The Software Alliance</title>    
          <description><![CDATA[ <p>Andrew and the Trade Guys take on the world of digital trade with Victoria Espinel, president and CEO of BSA | The Software Alliance. Victoria shares her thoughts on USMCA, the evolving intersection of privacy and digital trade, and much more.</p>
<p> Download full transcript <a href="https://www.csis.org/analysis/digital-trade-victoria-espinel-bsa-software-alliance">here</a>.</p>
 ]]></description>    
            <itunes:author>William Alan Reinsch, Scott Miller, H. Andrew Schwartz</itunes:author>
    
          <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2019 14:00:00 -0400</pubDate>    
          <enclosure  url="https://csis-website-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/s3fs-public/field_soundcloud_audio/TG_E45_mixdown_03.mp3" type="audio/mpeg" length="56557328" />
<itunes:duration>37:50</itunes:duration>
<guid>https://csis-website-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/s3fs-public/field_soundcloud_audio/TG_E45_mixdown_03.mp3</guid>
  </item>
<item>  
          <title>Collateral Trade Damage</title>    
          <description><![CDATA[ <p>A trade war has escalated between the U.S. and China, and African economies are caught in the crossfire. On this episode, Bill Reinsch (CSIS), Catherine Chiang (CSIS), and Julius Agbor (Vanguard University of Southern California) join <a href="https://twitter.com/JDevermont?utm_source=CSIS+All&amp;utm_campaign=5249312b18-EMAIL_CAMPAIGN_2018_10_29_08_49_COPY_01&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_term=0_f326fc46b6-5249312b18-">Judd Devermont </a>(CSIS) to unpack how tariff tensions are impacting African economic growth and what it means for U.S.-Africa relations. The experts also assess the international response to Cameroon’s protracted conflict and the China-Kenya tiff over tilapia.</p>
 ]]></description>    
            <itunes:author>William Alan Reinsch</itunes:author>
    
          <pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2019 17:30:00 -0400</pubDate>    
          <enclosure  url="https://csis-website-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/s3fs-public/field_soundcloud_audio/IA_E10_03.mp3" type="audio/mpeg" length="35692903" />
<itunes:duration>24:17</itunes:duration>
<guid>https://csis-website-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/s3fs-public/field_soundcloud_audio/IA_E10_03.mp3</guid>
  </item>
<item>  
          <title>Rewriting the Rules of the Game: the USMCA and Shifting Auto Rules of Origin</title>    
          <description><![CDATA[ 

<p>
In recent decades, supply chains have become more global while bilateral and regional free trade agreements (FTA) have continued to grow in popularity. For free trade agreements to operate as intended— that is, to provide benefits to the member countries—it must be possible for goods to be identified as products of an FTA member and therefore be eligible for preferential treatment. Free trade agreements also are expected to encourage manufacturers outside the agreement’s boundaries to locate production facilities within the countries party to the agreement to take advantage of the preferential treatment for goods produced there. Rules of origin codified in trade agreements play a crucial role in shaping global supply chains by setting out rules to ascertain the origin of a good.</p>

<p>The newly negotiated U.S.-Mexico-Canada Agreement (USMCA) demonstrates the power of rules of origin to force the many businesses that depend on the current trade agreement to alter their supply chains and business models. Join the Scholl Chair as we deliver our newest report, examining the importance of rules of origin using the new USMCA rules for the North American auto industry as a case study.</p>


<i>This event is made possible through the support provided by the Alcoa Foundation. </i> ]]></description>    
            <itunes:author>William Alan Reinsch</itunes:author>
    
          <pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2019 14:00:00 -0400</pubDate>    
          <enclosure  url="https://csis-website-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/s3fs-public/field_soundcloud_audio/Rewriting%20the%20Rules%20of%20the%20Game%20the%20USMCA%20and%20Shifting%20Auto%20Rules%20of%20Origin.mp3" type="audio/mpeg" length="103361606" />
<itunes:duration>1:21:36</itunes:duration>
<guid>https://csis-website-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/s3fs-public/field_soundcloud_audio/Rewriting%20the%20Rules%20of%20the%20Game%20the%20USMCA%20and%20Shifting%20Auto%20Rules%20of%20Origin.mp3</guid>
  </item>
<item>  
          <title>Trade Guys on the Road: Georgetown University Edition</title>    
          <description><![CDATA[ <p>In this episode, the Trade Guys and Andrew hit the road to record in front of a live audience at Georgetown University. On the agenda was the status of the US-China talks and what the president means by a US-Japan deal. Students of CSIS Korea Chair Victor Cha’s Modern Asia class asked questions that the Trade Guys answered throughout the show. Hosted by H. Andrew Schwartz and produced by Yumi Araki and Jack Caporal at the Center for Strategic and International Studies in Washington.</p>
<p> Download full transcript<a href="https://www.csis.org/analysis/josh-bolten-joins-trade-guys-part-i"> </a><a href="https://www.csis.org/analysis/trade-guys-road-georgetown-university-edition">here</a>.</p>
 ]]></description>    
            <itunes:author>Scott Miller, William Alan Reinsch, H. Andrew Schwartz</itunes:author>
    
          <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2019 16:45:00 -0400</pubDate>    
          <enclosure  url="https://csis-website-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/s3fs-public/field_soundcloud_audio/TG_190402.mp3" type="audio/mpeg" length="75758552" />
<itunes:duration>51:04</itunes:duration>
<guid>https://csis-website-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/s3fs-public/field_soundcloud_audio/TG_190402.mp3</guid>
  </item>
<item>  
          <title>Trade Guys on the Road: The State International Trade Development Organization Edition</title>    
          <description><![CDATA[ <p>In this episode, Andrew and the Trade Guys head to the Hill for a live recording in front of audiences attending the State International Trade Development Organization (SIDO)'s 2019 Washington Forum. Joining the Trade Guys were Gabrielle Gerbaud, the executive director of the Minnesota Trade Office, and Wade Merritt, the president of Maine's International Trade Center and a former SIDO president. They discuss the USMCA, the US-China deal, and Section 232 tariffs.</p>
<p> Download full transcript <a href="https://www.csis.org/analysis/trade-guys-road-state-international-trade-development-organization-edition">here</a>.</p>
 ]]></description>    
            <itunes:author>Scott Miller, William Alan Reinsch, H. Andrew Schwartz</itunes:author>
    
          <pubDate>Wed, 27 Feb 2019 16:00:00 -0500</pubDate>    
          <enclosure  url="https://csis-website-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/s3fs-public/field_soundcloud_audio/E40_190227_SIDO.mp3" type="audio/mpeg" length="56209707" />
<itunes:duration>37:18</itunes:duration>
<guid>https://csis-website-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/s3fs-public/field_soundcloud_audio/E40_190227_SIDO.mp3</guid>
  </item>
<item>  
          <title>A Positive Trade Agenda</title>    
          <description><![CDATA[ 

<p>In the space of just a few years, the public discourse on trade has undergone a significant shift. Where trade was once commonly agreed upon as a net benefit to the U.S. economy and the global good, it is now used as a scapegoat across the political spectrum for systemic issues. As we approach the 75th anniversary of the Bretton Woods Conference, deep questions are emerging about the post-War economy it reconstructed, the multilateral system it created, and the liberal values it codified. The international trading system and its norms have unleashed an unprecedented wave of globalization but how the world understands free and open trade and its value is undergoing a generational shift. Join the Scholl Chair in International Business and CSIS to launch a major initiative to investigate and reshape the conversation on trade for the 21st century.</p>


<p><i>Introductory Remarks by:</i><br />
F​rederick W. Smith<br />
Chairman and CEO of FedEx Corp.</p>

<p><i>Keynote Address by:</i><br />
Henry M. Paulson<br />
​Secretary of the Treasury (2006-2009)<br />
Chairman of the Paulson Institute</p>



<p><b>Envisioning a World of "Three Zeroes": Zero Tariffs, Zero Subsidies, and Zero Non-tariff Barriers to Trade</b><br />
<i>Moderated by Scott Miller</i></p>
<b>Daniel J. Ikenson</b><br />
<i>Director, Herbert A. Stiefel Center for Trade Policy Studies</i><br />
<br />
<b>Ambassador Susan C. Schwab</b><br />
<i>Former United States Trade Representative (2005-2009)</i><br />
 
<p><b>Out With the Old, In With the New: Developing New International Frameworks or Reforming the Old?</b><br />
<i>Moderated by Matthew P. Goodman</i></p>
<b>Catherine A. Novelli</b> <br />
<i>President, Listening for America</i><br />
<br />
<b>Dr. Derek M. Scissors</b><br />
<i>Resident Scholar, AEI</i><br />
 
<p><b>Meeting the China Challenge: Engagement or Decoupling?</b><br />
<i>Moderated by Dr. Scott Kennedy</i></p>
<b>Dr. David Dollar</b><br />
<i>Senior Fellow, John L. Thorton China Center, The Brookings Institution</i><br />
<br />
<b>Ambassador Jorge Guajardo</b><br />
<i>Ambassador of Mexico to the People's Republic of China (2007-2013) </i><br />
<br />
<i>This event is made possible through general support to CSIS.</i> ]]></description>    
            <itunes:author>John J. Hamre, William Alan Reinsch, Matthew P. Goodman, Scott Miller, Scott Kennedy</itunes:author>
    
          <pubDate>Wed, 27 Feb 2019 09:30:00 -0500</pubDate>    
          <enclosure  url="https://csis-website-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/s3fs-public/field_soundcloud_audio/A%20Positive%20Trade%20Agenda%20Part%202%20-%20Envisioning%20a%20World%20of%20Three%20Zeroes.mp3" type="audio/mpeg" length="60060871" />
<itunes:duration>1:02:34</itunes:duration>
<guid>https://csis-website-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/s3fs-public/field_soundcloud_audio/A%20Positive%20Trade%20Agenda%20Part%202%20-%20Envisioning%20a%20World%20of%20Three%20Zeroes.mp3</guid>
  </item>
<item>  
          <title>A Positive Trade Agenda</title>    
          <description><![CDATA[ 

<p>In the space of just a few years, the public discourse on trade has undergone a significant shift. Where trade was once commonly agreed upon as a net benefit to the U.S. economy and the global good, it is now used as a scapegoat across the political spectrum for systemic issues. As we approach the 75th anniversary of the Bretton Woods Conference, deep questions are emerging about the post-War economy it reconstructed, the multilateral system it created, and the liberal values it codified. The international trading system and its norms have unleashed an unprecedented wave of globalization but how the world understands free and open trade and its value is undergoing a generational shift. Join the Scholl Chair in International Business and CSIS to launch a major initiative to investigate and reshape the conversation on trade for the 21st century.</p>


<p><i>Introductory Remarks by:</i><br />
F​rederick W. Smith<br />
Chairman and CEO of FedEx Corp.</p>

<p><i>Keynote Address by:</i><br />
Henry M. Paulson<br />
​Secretary of the Treasury (2006-2009)<br />
Chairman of the Paulson Institute</p>



<p><b>Envisioning a World of "Three Zeroes": Zero Tariffs, Zero Subsidies, and Zero Non-tariff Barriers to Trade</b><br />
<i>Moderated by Scott Miller</i></p>
<b>Daniel J. Ikenson</b><br />
<i>Director, Herbert A. Stiefel Center for Trade Policy Studies</i><br />
<br />
<b>Ambassador Susan C. Schwab</b><br />
<i>Former United States Trade Representative (2005-2009)</i><br />
 
<p><b>Out With the Old, In With the New: Developing New International Frameworks or Reforming the Old?</b><br />
<i>Moderated by Matthew P. Goodman</i></p>
<b>Catherine A. Novelli</b> <br />
<i>President, Listening for America</i><br />
<br />
<b>Dr. Derek M. Scissors</b><br />
<i>Resident Scholar, AEI</i><br />
 
<p><b>Meeting the China Challenge: Engagement or Decoupling?</b><br />
<i>Moderated by Dr. Scott Kennedy</i></p>
<b>Dr. David Dollar</b><br />
<i>Senior Fellow, John L. Thorton China Center, The Brookings Institution</i><br />
<br />
<b>Ambassador Jorge Guajardo</b><br />
<i>Ambassador of Mexico to the People's Republic of China (2007-2013) </i><br />
<br />
<i>This event is made possible through general support to CSIS.</i> ]]></description>    
            <itunes:author>John J. Hamre, William Alan Reinsch, Matthew P. Goodman, Scott Miller, Scott Kennedy</itunes:author>
    
          <pubDate>Wed, 27 Feb 2019 09:30:00 -0500</pubDate>    
          <enclosure  url="https://csis-website-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/s3fs-public/field_soundcloud_audio/A%20Positive%20Trade%20Agenda%20Part%205%20-%20Afternoon%20Discussion.mp3" type="audio/mpeg" length="48931872" />
<itunes:duration>50:59</itunes:duration>
<guid>https://csis-website-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/s3fs-public/field_soundcloud_audio/A%20Positive%20Trade%20Agenda%20Part%205%20-%20Afternoon%20Discussion.mp3</guid>
  </item>
<item>  
          <title>A Positive Trade Agenda</title>    
          <description><![CDATA[ 

<p>In the space of just a few years, the public discourse on trade has undergone a significant shift. Where trade was once commonly agreed upon as a net benefit to the U.S. economy and the global good, it is now used as a scapegoat across the political spectrum for systemic issues. As we approach the 75th anniversary of the Bretton Woods Conference, deep questions are emerging about the post-War economy it reconstructed, the multilateral system it created, and the liberal values it codified. The international trading system and its norms have unleashed an unprecedented wave of globalization but how the world understands free and open trade and its value is undergoing a generational shift. Join the Scholl Chair in International Business and CSIS to launch a major initiative to investigate and reshape the conversation on trade for the 21st century.</p>


<p><i>Introductory Remarks by:</i><br />
F​rederick W. Smith<br />
Chairman and CEO of FedEx Corp.</p>

<p><i>Keynote Address by:</i><br />
Henry M. Paulson<br />
​Secretary of the Treasury (2006-2009)<br />
Chairman of the Paulson Institute</p>



<p><b>Envisioning a World of "Three Zeroes": Zero Tariffs, Zero Subsidies, and Zero Non-tariff Barriers to Trade</b><br />
<i>Moderated by Scott Miller</i></p>
<b>Daniel J. Ikenson</b><br />
<i>Director, Herbert A. Stiefel Center for Trade Policy Studies</i><br />
<br />
<b>Ambassador Susan C. Schwab</b><br />
<i>Former United States Trade Representative (2005-2009)</i><br />
 
<p><b>Out With the Old, In With the New: Developing New International Frameworks or Reforming the Old?</b><br />
<i>Moderated by Matthew P. Goodman</i></p>
<b>Catherine A. Novelli</b> <br />
<i>President, Listening for America</i><br />
<br />
<b>Dr. Derek M. Scissors</b><br />
<i>Resident Scholar, AEI</i><br />
 
<p><b>Meeting the China Challenge: Engagement or Decoupling?</b><br />
<i>Moderated by Dr. Scott Kennedy</i></p>
<b>Dr. David Dollar</b><br />
<i>Senior Fellow, John L. Thorton China Center, The Brookings Institution</i><br />
<br />
<b>Ambassador Jorge Guajardo</b><br />
<i>Ambassador of Mexico to the People's Republic of China (2007-2013) </i><br />
<br />
<i>This event is made possible through general support to CSIS.</i> ]]></description>    
            <itunes:author>John J. Hamre, William Alan Reinsch, Matthew P. Goodman, Scott Miller, Scott Kennedy</itunes:author>
    
          <pubDate>Wed, 27 Feb 2019 09:30:00 -0500</pubDate>    
          <enclosure  url="https://csis-website-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/s3fs-public/field_soundcloud_audio/A%20Positive%20Trade%20Agenda%20Part%201%20-%20Opening%20Keynote%20with%20Hank%20Paulson.mp3" type="audio/mpeg" length="58392378" />
<itunes:duration>1:00:50</itunes:duration>
<guid>https://csis-website-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/s3fs-public/field_soundcloud_audio/A%20Positive%20Trade%20Agenda%20Part%201%20-%20Opening%20Keynote%20with%20Hank%20Paulson.mp3</guid>
  </item>
<item>  
          <title>A Positive Trade Agenda</title>    
          <description><![CDATA[ 

<p>In the space of just a few years, the public discourse on trade has undergone a significant shift. Where trade was once commonly agreed upon as a net benefit to the U.S. economy and the global good, it is now used as a scapegoat across the political spectrum for systemic issues. As we approach the 75th anniversary of the Bretton Woods Conference, deep questions are emerging about the post-War economy it reconstructed, the multilateral system it created, and the liberal values it codified. The international trading system and its norms have unleashed an unprecedented wave of globalization but how the world understands free and open trade and its value is undergoing a generational shift. Join the Scholl Chair in International Business and CSIS to launch a major initiative to investigate and reshape the conversation on trade for the 21st century.</p>


<p><i>Introductory Remarks by:</i><br />
F​rederick W. Smith<br />
Chairman and CEO of FedEx Corp.</p>

<p><i>Keynote Address by:</i><br />
Henry M. Paulson<br />
​Secretary of the Treasury (2006-2009)<br />
Chairman of the Paulson Institute</p>



<p><b>Envisioning a World of "Three Zeroes": Zero Tariffs, Zero Subsidies, and Zero Non-tariff Barriers to Trade</b><br />
<i>Moderated by Scott Miller</i></p>
<b>Daniel J. Ikenson</b><br />
<i>Director, Herbert A. Stiefel Center for Trade Policy Studies</i><br />
<br />
<b>Ambassador Susan C. Schwab</b><br />
<i>Former United States Trade Representative (2005-2009)</i><br />
 
<p><b>Out With the Old, In With the New: Developing New International Frameworks or Reforming the Old?</b><br />
<i>Moderated by Matthew P. Goodman</i></p>
<b>Catherine A. Novelli</b> <br />
<i>President, Listening for America</i><br />
<br />
<b>Dr. Derek M. Scissors</b><br />
<i>Resident Scholar, AEI</i><br />
 
<p><b>Meeting the China Challenge: Engagement or Decoupling?</b><br />
<i>Moderated by Dr. Scott Kennedy</i></p>
<b>Dr. David Dollar</b><br />
<i>Senior Fellow, John L. Thorton China Center, The Brookings Institution</i><br />
<br />
<b>Ambassador Jorge Guajardo</b><br />
<i>Ambassador of Mexico to the People's Republic of China (2007-2013) </i><br />
<br />
<i>This event is made possible through general support to CSIS.</i> ]]></description>    
            <itunes:author>John J. Hamre, William Alan Reinsch, Matthew P. Goodman, Scott Miller, Scott Kennedy</itunes:author>
    
          <pubDate>Wed, 27 Feb 2019 09:30:00 -0500</pubDate>    
          <enclosure  url="https://csis-website-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/s3fs-public/field_soundcloud_audio/A%20Positive%20Trade%20Agenda%20Part%204%20-%20Meeting%20the%20China%20Challenge.mp3" type="audio/mpeg" length="65720457" />
<itunes:duration>1:08:28</itunes:duration>
<guid>https://csis-website-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/s3fs-public/field_soundcloud_audio/A%20Positive%20Trade%20Agenda%20Part%204%20-%20Meeting%20the%20China%20Challenge.mp3</guid>
  </item>
<item>  
          <title>A Positive Trade Agenda</title>    
          <description><![CDATA[ 

<p>In the space of just a few years, the public discourse on trade has undergone a significant shift. Where trade was once commonly agreed upon as a net benefit to the U.S. economy and the global good, it is now used as a scapegoat across the political spectrum for systemic issues. As we approach the 75th anniversary of the Bretton Woods Conference, deep questions are emerging about the post-War economy it reconstructed, the multilateral system it created, and the liberal values it codified. The international trading system and its norms have unleashed an unprecedented wave of globalization but how the world understands free and open trade and its value is undergoing a generational shift. Join the Scholl Chair in International Business and CSIS to launch a major initiative to investigate and reshape the conversation on trade for the 21st century.</p>


<p><i>Introductory Remarks by:</i><br />
F​rederick W. Smith<br />
Chairman and CEO of FedEx Corp.</p>

<p><i>Keynote Address by:</i><br />
Henry M. Paulson<br />
​Secretary of the Treasury (2006-2009)<br />
Chairman of the Paulson Institute</p>



<p><b>Envisioning a World of "Three Zeroes": Zero Tariffs, Zero Subsidies, and Zero Non-tariff Barriers to Trade</b><br />
<i>Moderated by Scott Miller</i></p>
<b>Daniel J. Ikenson</b><br />
<i>Director, Herbert A. Stiefel Center for Trade Policy Studies</i><br />
<br />
<b>Ambassador Susan C. Schwab</b><br />
<i>Former United States Trade Representative (2005-2009)</i><br />
 
<p><b>Out With the Old, In With the New: Developing New International Frameworks or Reforming the Old?</b><br />
<i>Moderated by Matthew P. Goodman</i></p>
<b>Catherine A. Novelli</b> <br />
<i>President, Listening for America</i><br />
<br />
<b>Dr. Derek M. Scissors</b><br />
<i>Resident Scholar, AEI</i><br />
 
<p><b>Meeting the China Challenge: Engagement or Decoupling?</b><br />
<i>Moderated by Dr. Scott Kennedy</i></p>
<b>Dr. David Dollar</b><br />
<i>Senior Fellow, John L. Thorton China Center, The Brookings Institution</i><br />
<br />
<b>Ambassador Jorge Guajardo</b><br />
<i>Ambassador of Mexico to the People's Republic of China (2007-2013) </i><br />
<br />
<i>This event is made possible through general support to CSIS.</i> ]]></description>    
            <itunes:author>John J. Hamre, William Alan Reinsch, Matthew P. Goodman, Scott Miller, Scott Kennedy</itunes:author>
    
          <pubDate>Wed, 27 Feb 2019 09:30:00 -0500</pubDate>    
          <enclosure  url="https://csis-website-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/s3fs-public/field_soundcloud_audio/A%20Positive%20Trade%20Agenda%20Part%203%20-%20Out%20With%20the%20Old%2C%20In%20With%20the%20New.mp3" type="audio/mpeg" length="65297064" />
<itunes:duration>1:08:02</itunes:duration>
<guid>https://csis-website-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/s3fs-public/field_soundcloud_audio/A%20Positive%20Trade%20Agenda%20Part%203%20-%20Out%20With%20the%20Old%2C%20In%20With%20the%20New.mp3</guid>
  </item>
<item>  
          <title>State of the Trading Union</title>    
          <description><![CDATA[ <p>In this episode of The Trade Guys, the State of the Union is front and center. After the address was pushed back a week because of the government shutdown, the president is expected to call on Congress to pass the USMCA. All this goes on as Congress drafts legislation to curb the president's current national security tariff powers. Will the president deliver a bipartisan message? What will he say about the US-China trade war? Hosted by H. Andrew Schwartz and produced by Yumi Araki and Jack Caporal at the Center for Strategic and International Studies in Washington.</p>
<p> Download full transcript<a href="https://www.csis.org/analysis/josh-bolten-joins-trade-guys-part-i"> </a><a href="https://www.csis.org/analysis/state-trading-union">here</a>.</p>
 ]]></description>    
            <itunes:author>Scott Miller, William Alan Reinsch, H. Andrew Schwartz</itunes:author>
    
          <pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2019 16:15:00 -0500</pubDate>    
          <enclosure  url="https://csis-website-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/s3fs-public/field_soundcloud_audio/TG_E35_190205_1.mp3" type="audio/mpeg" length="45987857" />
<itunes:duration>30:30</itunes:duration>
<guid>https://csis-website-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/s3fs-public/field_soundcloud_audio/TG_E35_190205_1.mp3</guid>
  </item>
<item>  
          <title>APEC: 2019 and Beyond</title>    
          <description><![CDATA[ <p>Join us as we discuss the upcoming 2019 APEC summit in Chile and APEC's place in defining the ecosystem for emerging core technologies. As the fourth industrial revolution takes off with automation, artificial intelligence, quantum computing, the Internet of Things, and 5G, the need for multilateral coordination is all the more important.</p>
<p> Opening statements will be made by Monica Hardy Whaley, President of the National Center of APEC, followed by a keynote address by Ambassador Matt Matthews.</p>
<p> Afterward we will host a panel discussion with Ambassador Ashok Mirpuri of Singapore, Wendy Culter of the Asia Society, David Weller of Google, and Monica Hardy Whaley of NCAPEC, moderated by Bill Reinsch, Scholl Chair in International Business.</p>
<p> <i>Agenda:</i></p>
<p> Keynote by Ambassador Matthews: 9:30 a.m. - 10:00 a.m.<br /> Panel Discussion: 10:00 a.m. - 11:30 a.m.</p>
<p> <i>This event is made possible through the generous support of the National Center for APEC.</i></p>
 ]]></description>    
            <itunes:author>William Alan Reinsch</itunes:author>
    
          <pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2019 09:30:00 -0500</pubDate>    
          <enclosure  url="https://csis-website-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/s3fs-public/field_soundcloud_audio/APEC%202019%20and%20Beyond.mp3" type="audio/mpeg" length="106962579" />
<itunes:duration>1:51:26</itunes:duration>
<guid>https://csis-website-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/s3fs-public/field_soundcloud_audio/APEC%202019%20and%20Beyond.mp3</guid>
  </item>
  </channel>  </rss>
