<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<rdf:RDF
 xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
 xmlns="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/"
 xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
 xmlns:taxo="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/taxonomy/"
 xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
 xmlns:syn="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
 xmlns:admin="http://webns.net/mvcb/"
>

<channel rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/">
<title>q-bio.CB updates on arXiv.org</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">Quantitative Biology -- Cell Behavior (q-bio.CB) updates on the arXiv.org e-print archive</description>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:date>2022-11-03T20:30:00-05:00</dc:date>
<dc:publisher>help@arxiv.org</dc:publisher>
<dc:subject>Quantitative Biology -- Cell Behavior</dc:subject>
<syn:updateBase>1901-01-01T00:00+00:00</syn:updateBase>
<syn:updateFrequency>1</syn:updateFrequency>
<syn:updatePeriod>daily</syn:updatePeriod>
<items>
 <rdf:Seq>
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01867" />
 </rdf:Seq>
</items>
<image rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif" />
</channel>
<image rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif">
<title>arXiv.org</title>
<url>http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif</url>
<link>http://arxiv.org/</link>
</image>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01867">
<title>Macrophage anti-inflammatory behaviour in a multiphase model of atherosclerotic plaque development. (arXiv:2211.01867v1 [q-bio.CB])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01867</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Atherosclerosis is an inflammatory disease characterised by the formation of
plaques, which are deposits of lipids and cholesterol-laden macrophages that
form in the artery wall. The inflammation is often non-resolving, due in large
part to changes in normal macrophage anti-inflammatory behaviour that are
induced by the toxic plaque microenvironment. These changes include higher
death rates, defective efferocytic uptake of dead cells, and reduced rates of
emigration. We develop a free boundary multiphase model for early
atherosclerotic plaques, and we use it to investigate the effects of impaired
macrophage anti-inflammatory behaviour on plaque structure and growth. We find
that high rates of cell death relative to efferocytic uptake results in a
plaque populated mostly by dead cells. We also find that emigration can
potentially slow or halt plaque growth by allowing material to exit the plaque,
but this is contingent on the availability of live macrophage foam cells in the
deep plaque. Finally, we introduce an additional bead species to model
macrophage tagging via microspheres, and we use the extended model to explore
how high rates of cell death and low rates of efferocytosis and emigration
prevent the clearance of macrophages from the plaque.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/q-bio/1/au:+Ahmed_I/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ishraq U. Ahmed&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/q-bio/1/au:+Byrne_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Helen M. Byrne&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/q-bio/1/au:+Myerscough_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Mary R. Myerscough&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
</rdf:RDF>