<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<rdf:RDF
 xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
 xmlns="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/"
 xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
 xmlns:taxo="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/taxonomy/"
 xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
 xmlns:syn="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
 xmlns:admin="http://webns.net/mvcb/"
>

<channel rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/">
<title>econ.TH updates on arXiv.org</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">Economics -- Theoretical Economics (econ.TH) updates on the arXiv.org e-print archive</description>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:date>2022-11-03T20:30:00-05:00</dc:date>
<dc:publisher>help@arxiv.org</dc:publisher>
<dc:subject>Economics -- Theoretical Economics</dc:subject>
<syn:updateBase>1901-01-01T00:00+00:00</syn:updateBase>
<syn:updateFrequency>1</syn:updateFrequency>
<syn:updatePeriod>daily</syn:updatePeriod>
<items>
 <rdf:Seq>
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2203.17232" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.00520" />
 </rdf:Seq>
</items>
<image rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif" />
</channel>
<image rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif">
<title>arXiv.org</title>
<url>http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif</url>
<link>http://arxiv.org/</link>
</image>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2203.17232">
<title>Performative Power. (arXiv:2203.17232v2 [cs.LG] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2203.17232</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We introduce the notion of performative power, which measures the ability of
a firm operating an algorithmic system, such as a digital content
recommendation platform, to cause change in a population of participants. We
relate performative power to the economic study of competition in digital
economies. Traditional economic concepts struggle with identifying
anti-competitive patterns in digital platforms not least due to the complexity
of market definition. In contrast, performative power is a causal notion that
is identifiable with minimal knowledge of the market, its internals,
participants, products, or prices.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Low performative power implies that a firm can do no better than to optimize
their objective on current data. In contrast, firms of high performative power
stand to benefit from steering the population towards more profitable behavior.
We confirm in a simple theoretical model that monopolies maximize performative
power. A firm&apos;s ability to personalize increases performative power, while
competition and outside options decrease performative power. On the empirical
side, we propose an observational causal design to identify performative power
from discontinuities in how digital platforms display content. This allows to
repurpose causal effects from various studies about digital platforms as lower
bounds on performative power. Finally, we speculate about the role that
performative power might play in competition policy and antitrust enforcement
in digital marketplaces.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Hardt_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Moritz Hardt&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Jagadeesan_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Meena Jagadeesan&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Mendler_Dunner_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Celestine Mendler-D&amp;#xfc;nner&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.00520">
<title>Distortion risk measures in random environments: construction and axiomatic characterization. (arXiv:2211.00520v2 [econ.TH] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.00520</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The risk of a financial position shines through by means of the fluctuation
of its market price. The factors affecting the price of a financial position
include not only market internal factors, but also other various market
external factors. The latter can be understood as sorts of environments to
which financial positions have to expose. Motivated by this observation, this
paper aims to design a novel axiomatic approach to risk measures in random
environments. We construct a new distortion-type risk measure, which can
appropriately evaluate the risk of financial positions in the presence of
environments. After having studied its fundamental properties, we also
axiomatically characterize it. Furthermore, its coherence and dual
representation are investigated. The new class of risk measures in random
environments is large enough, for example, it not only can recover some known
risk measures such as the common weighted value at risk and range value at
risk, but also can induce other new specific risk measures such as risk
measures in the presence of background risk. Examples are given to illustrate
the new framework of risk measures. This paper gives some theoretical results
about risk measures in random environments, helping one to have an insight look
at the potential impact of environments on risk measures of positions.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/econ/1/au:+Gong_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Shuo Gong&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/econ/1/au:+Hu_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yijun Hu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/econ/1/au:+Wei_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Linxiao Wei&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
</rdf:RDF>