<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Rocket-Powered Data Science</title>
	<atom:link href="http://rocketdatascience.org/?feed=rss2" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://rocketdatascience.org</link>
	<description>Data Reflections by Dr. Kirk Borne @KirkDBorne</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 24 Sep 2022 21:18:12 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.0.3</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Editorial Review of “Building Industrial Digital Twins”</title>
		<link>http://rocketdatascience.org/?p=1714</link>
					<comments>http://rocketdatascience.org/?p=1714#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kirk Borne]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 24 Sep 2022 21:18:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Analytics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Data Science]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://rocketdatascience.org/?p=1714</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I was asked by the publisher to provide an editorial review of the book “Building Industrial Digital Twins: Design, develop, and deploy digital twin solutions for real-world industries using Azure Digital Twins“, by Shyam Varan Nath and Pieter van Schalkwyk. For this, I received a complimentary copy of the book and no other compensation. Let [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large"><a href="https://amzn.to/3fl195P" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><img width="833" height="1024" src="http://rocketdatascience.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/387B0CD6-491A-4065-963B-CF79109FD2E2-833x1024.jpeg" alt="" class="wp-image-1715" srcset="http://rocketdatascience.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/387B0CD6-491A-4065-963B-CF79109FD2E2-833x1024.jpeg 833w, http://rocketdatascience.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/387B0CD6-491A-4065-963B-CF79109FD2E2-244x300.jpeg 244w, http://rocketdatascience.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/387B0CD6-491A-4065-963B-CF79109FD2E2-768x945.jpeg 768w, http://rocketdatascience.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/387B0CD6-491A-4065-963B-CF79109FD2E2-624x767.jpeg 624w, http://rocketdatascience.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/387B0CD6-491A-4065-963B-CF79109FD2E2.jpeg 1170w" sizes="(max-width: 833px) 100vw, 833px" /></a><figcaption><a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://amzn.to/3fl195P" target="_blank">https://amzn.to/3fl195P</a></figcaption></figure></div>


<p>I was asked by the publisher to provide an editorial review of the book “Building Industrial Digital Twins: Design, develop, and deploy digital twin solutions for real-world industries using Azure Digital Twins“, by Shyam Varan Nath and Pieter van Schalkwyk. For this, I received a complimentary copy of the book and no other compensation.</p>



<p>Let us begin…</p>



<p>This book is a very timely contribution to the world of industrial digital transformation. The digital twin is more than a data collector. It is an insight engine, providing not only data for descriptive and diagnostic analytics applications, but also providing essential data for predictive and prescriptive analytics applications. This is all fueled and facilitated by data flows across processes, products, and people&#8217;s activities, used in synergy with computational models and simulations of the system being digitally twinned. In order to help an organization get started with a DT (digital twin), this book outlines the process of building the MVT (Minimum Viable Twin). All phases of the MVT process are discussed: strategy, designs, pilot, implementation, test, validation, operations, and monitoring.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This book knows and forcefully proves what is the enabler and value producer of digital anything (especially and most emphatically the DT)&nbsp;—&nbsp;it is all about the data and the simulation&nbsp;—&nbsp;that’s business modeling at its finest, incorporating the best of technology (physical assets, sensors, and cloud), techniques (analytics, algorithms, and modeling), and talent (culture, people, and strategic plans).</p>



<p>There were many themes and topics (both broad and specific) that fascinated me and kept me engaged in discovering serendipitous knowledge nuggets throughout this book. Here are a few:&nbsp;</p>



<p>1) Azure DT, whose cloud-based PaaS (Platform-as-a-Service) provides a viable, scalable, and accessible launchpad for DTaaS in any organization.</p>



<p>2) Streaming sensor data from the IoT (Internet of Things) and IIoT (Industrial IoT) become the source for an IoC (Internet of Context), ultimately delivering Insights-aaS, Context-aaS, and Forecasting-aaS.</p>



<p>3) The consistent emphasis on and elaboration of key DT value propositions, requirements, and KPI tracking.</p>



<p>4) The DT Canvas (chapter 4)!</p>



<p>5) Helpful discussions of phased DT deployments, prototypes, pilots, feedback, and validation.</p>



<p>6) Specific Industry 4.0 examples, with constant reminders that’s it all about the data plus analytics!</p>



<p>7) Forward-looking DTs in the industrial enterprise.</p>



<p>Beyond being a technical how-to manual (though it is definitely that), this book delivers so much more! It is truly a business digital transformation manual.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>http://rocketdatascience.org/?feed=rss2&#038;p=1714</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>My top learning and pondering moments at Splunk .conf22</title>
		<link>http://rocketdatascience.org/?p=1670</link>
					<comments>http://rocketdatascience.org/?p=1670#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kirk Borne]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2022 19:45:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Analytics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Big Data]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Internet of Things]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Products]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Data Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Machine Learning]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://rocketdatascience.org/?p=1670</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I recently attended the Splunk .conf22 conference. While the event was live in-person in Las Vegas, I attended virtually from my home office. Consequently I missed the incredible in-person experience of the brilliant speakers on the main stage, the technodazzle of 100&#8217;s of exhibitors&#8217; offerings in the exhibit arena, and the smooth hip hop sounds [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>I recently attended the <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://conf.splunk.com/" target="_blank">Splunk .conf22</a> conference. While the event was live in-person in Las Vegas, I attended virtually from my home office. Consequently I missed the incredible in-person experience of the brilliant speakers on the main stage, the technodazzle of 100&#8217;s of exhibitors&#8217; offerings in the exhibit arena, and the smooth hip hop sounds from the special guest entertainer — <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://conf.splunk.com/connect.html#evening-events" target="_blank">guess who</a>?</p>



<p>What I missed in-person was more than compensated for by the incredible online presentations by <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://www.splunk.com/" target="_blank">Splunk </a>leaders, developers, and customers. If you have ever attended a major expo at one of the major Vegas hotels, you know that there is a lot of walking between different sessions &#8212; literally, miles of walking per day. That&#8217;s good for you, but it often means that you don&#8217;t attend all of the sessions that you would like because of the requisite rushing from venue to venue. None of that was necessary on the Splunk .conf22 virtual conference platform. I was able to see a lot, learn a lot, be impressed a lot, and ponder a lot about all of the wonderful features, functionalities, and future plans for the Splunk platform.</p>



<p>One of the first major attractions for me to attend this event is found in the primary descriptor of the Splunk Platform — it is appropriately called the Splunk Observability Cloud, which includes an impressive suite of <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://www.splunk.com/en_us/products/observability.html" target="_blank">Observability and Monitoring products and services</a>. I have written and spoken frequently and passionately about Observability in the past couple of years. For example, I wrote this in 2021: </p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote has-small-font-size"><p><em>&#8220;Observability emerged as one of the hottest and (for me) most exciting developments of the year. Do not confuse observability with monitoring (specifically, with IT monitoring). The key difference is this: monitoring is what you do, and observability is why you do it. Observability is a business strategy: what you monitor, why you monitor it, what you intend to learn from it, how it will be used, and how it will contribute to business objectives and mission success. But the power, value, and imperative of observability does not stop there. Observability meets AI – it is part of the complete AIOps package: &#8216;keeping an eye on the AI.&#8217; Observability delivers actionable insights, context-enriched data sets, early warning alert generation, root cause visibility, active performance monitoring, predictive and prescriptive incident management, real-time operational deviation detection (6-Sigma never had it so good!), tight coupling of cyber-physical systems, digital twinning of almost anything in the enterprise, and more. And the goodness doesn’t stop there.&#8221;</em></p><cite>Continue reading my thoughts on Observability at <a href="http://rocketdatascience.org/?p=1589" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">http://rocketdatascience.org/?p=1589</a></cite></blockquote>



<p>The dominant references everywhere to <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://conf.splunk.com/sessions-virtual-amer.html?search=Observability" target="_blank">Observability</a> was just the start of awesome brain food offered at Splunk&#8217;s .conf22 event. Here is a list of my top moments, learnings, and musings from this year&#8217;s <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://conf.splunk.com/" target="_blank">Splunk .conf</a>: </p>



<ol><li>Observability for Unified Security with AI (Artificial Intelligence) and Machine Learning on the Splunk platform empowers enterprises to operationalize data for use-case-specific functionality across shared datasets. (<a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://splunk.com/en_us/blog/conf-splunklive/-conf22-bringing-the-power-of-unified-security-observability-to-customers.html" target="_blank">Reference</a>)</li><li>The latest updates to the Splunk platform address the complexities of multi-cloud and hybrid environments, enabling cybersecurity and network big data functions (e.g., log analytics and anomaly detection) across distributed data sources and diverse enterprise IT infrastructure resources. (<a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://helpnetsecurity.com/2022/06/15/splunk-platform/" target="_blank">Reference</a>) </li><li>Splunk Enterprise 9.0 is here, now! Explore and test-drive it (with a free trial) <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://splunk.com/en_us/products/platform.html" target="_blank">here</a>.</li><li>The new Splunk Enterprise 9.0 release enables DevSecOps users to gain more insights from Observability data with Federated Search, with the ability to correlate ops with security alerts, and with Edge Management, all in one platform. (<a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://techtarget.com/searchitoperations/news/252521589/Splunk-Enterprise-users-push-more-data-into-DevSecOps" target="_blank">Reference</a>) </li><li>Security information and event management (SIEM) on the Splunk platform is enhanced with end-to-end visibility and platform extensibility, with machine learning and automation (AIOps), with risk-based alerting, and with Federated Search (i.e., Observability on-demand). (<a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://splunk.com/en_us/blog/security/risk-based-alerting-the-new-frontier-for-siem.html" target="_blank">Reference</a>) </li><li>Customer success story: As a customer-obsessed bank with ultra-rapid growth, <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://nubank.com.br/" target="_blank">Nubank</a> turned to Splunk to optimize data flows, analytics applications, customer support functions, and insights-obsessed IT monitoring. (<a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://iqstock.news/n/splunk-helps-nubank-deliver-digital-banking-millions-4041041/" target="_blank">Reference</a>) </li><li>The key characteristics of the Splunk Observability Cloud are Resilience, Security, Scalability, and EXTENSIBILITY. The latter specifically refers to the ease in which developers can extend Splunk&#8217;s capabilities to other apps, applying their AIOps and DevSecOps best practices and principles! Developers can start <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://dev.splunk.com" target="_blank">here</a>.</li><li>The Splunk Observability Cloud has many functions for data-intensive IT, Security, and Network operations, including Anomaly Detection Service, Federated Search, Synthetic Monitoring, Incident Intelligence, and much more. Synthetic monitoring is essentially digital twinning of your network and IT environment, providing insights through simulated risks, attacks, and anomalies via predictive and prescriptive modeling. [<a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://docs.splunk.com/Observability/get-started/welcome.html" target="_blank">Reference</a>] </li><li>Splunk Observability Cloud&#8217;s Federated Search capability activates search and analytics regardless of where your data lives — on-site, in the cloud, or from a third party. (<a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://splunk.com/en_us/products/platform-federated-search-and-analytics.html" target="_blank">Reference</a>) </li><li>The new release of the Splunk Data Manager provides a simple, modern, automated experience of data ingest for Splunk Cloud admins, which reduces the time it takes to configure data collection (from hours/days to minutes). (<a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://splunk.com/en_us/blog/platform/announcing-the-general-availability-of-data-manager.html" target="_blank">Reference</a>) </li><li>Splunk works on data, data, data, but the focus is always on customer, customer, customer — because delivering best outcomes for customers is job #1. Explore Splunk&#8217;s amazing Partner ecosystem (Partnerverse) and the impressive catalog of partners&#8217; solutions <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://partners.splunk.com/solutionscatalog/" target="_blank">here</a>. </li><li><a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://www.splunk.com/en_us/newsroom/press-releases/2022/splunk-conf22-invites-organizations-to-unlock-innovation-with-data.html" target="_blank">Splunk .conf22 Invites Organizations to Unlock Innovation With Data</a>.</li></ol>



<p>In summary, here is my list of key words and topics that illustrate the diverse capabilities and value-packed features of the Splunk Observability Cloud Platform that I learned about at the .conf22 event:</p>



<p>&#8211; Anomaly Detection Assistant<br>&#8211; Risk-based Alerting (powered by AI and Machine Learning scoring algorithms)<br>&#8211; Federated Search (Observability on-demand)<br>&#8211; End-to-End Visibility<br>&#8211; Platform Extensibility<br>&#8211; Massive(!) Scalability of the Splunk Observability Cloud (to billions of transactions per day)<br>&#8211; Insights-obsessed Monitoring (&#8220;We don&#8217;t need more information. We need more insights.&#8221;)<br>&#8211; APIs in Action (to Turn Data into Doing<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/14.0.0/72x72/2122.png" alt="™" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" />)<br>&#8211; Splunk Incident Intelligence<br>&#8211; Synthetic Monitoring (Digital Twin of Network/IT infrastructure)<br>&#8211; Splunk Data Manager<br>&#8211; The Splunk Partner Universe (Partnerverse)</p>



<p>My closing thought — Cybersecurity is basically Data Analytics: detection, prediction, prescription, and optimizing for unpredictability. This is what Splunk lives for!</p>



<p>Follow me on LinkedIn <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/kirkdborne/" target="_blank">here</a> and on Twitter at <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://twitter.com/kirkdborne" target="_blank">@KirkDBorne</a>.</p>



<p>Disclaimer: I was compensated as an independent freelance media influencer for my participation at the conference and for this article. The opinions expressed here are entirely my own and do not represent those of Splunk or of any Splunk partners. Any misrepresentations of the products and services mentioned in my statements are entirely my own responsibility. Nothing here should be construed as an offer to sell or as financial advice of any kind. My comments are entirely of a technical nature, focused on the technical capabilities of the items mentioned in the article.<a href=""></a></p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full"><a href="http://rocketdatascience.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/Splunk-dashboard2.webp"><img loading="lazy" width="2048" height="1153" src="http://rocketdatascience.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/Splunk-dashboard2.webp" alt="" class="wp-image-1695"/></a><figcaption>Splunk Cloud Platform Dashboard. <br>Source: <a href="https://www.splunk.com/en_us/products/splunk-cloud-platform.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">https://www.splunk.com/en_us/products/splunk-cloud-platform.html</a></figcaption></figure></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>http://rocketdatascience.org/?feed=rss2&#038;p=1670</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Data Insights for Everyone — The Semantic Layer to the Rescue</title>
		<link>http://rocketdatascience.org/?p=1649</link>
					<comments>http://rocketdatascience.org/?p=1649#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kirk Borne]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 20 Sep 2021 19:43:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Analytics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Big Data]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Data Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Strategy]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://rocketdatascience.org/?p=1649</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[What is a semantic layer? That’s a good question, but let’s first explain semantics. The way that I&#160;explained it to my data science students years ago was like this. In the early days of web search engines, those engines were primarily keyword search engines. If you knew the right keywords to search and if the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>What is a semantic layer? That’s a good question, but let’s first explain semantics. The way that I&nbsp;explained it to my data science students years ago was like this. In the early days of web search engines, those engines were primarily keyword search engines. If you knew the right keywords to search and if the content providers also used the same keywords on their website, then you could type the words into your favorite search engine and find the content you needed. So, I asked my students what results they would expect from such a search engine if I typed the following words into the search box: “How many cows are there in Texas?” My students were smart. They realized that the search results would probably not provide an answer to my question, but the results would simply list websites that included my words on the page or in the metadata tags: “Texas”, “Cows”, “How”, etc. Then, I explained to my students that a semantic-enabled search engine (with a semantic meta-layer, including ontologies and similar semantic tools) would be able to interpret my question’s meaning and then map that meaning to websites that can answer the question.</p>



<p>This was a good opening for my students to the wonderful world of semantics. I brought them deeper into the world by pointing out how much more effective and efficient the data professionals’ life would be if our data repositories had a similar semantic meta-layer. We would be able to go far beyond searching for correctly spelled column headings in databases or specific keywords in data documentation, to find the data we needed (assuming we even knew the correct labels, metatags, and keywords used by the dataset creators). We could search for data with common business terminology, regardless of the specific choice or spelling of the data descriptors in the dataset. Even more than that, we could easily start discovering and integrating, on-the-fly, data from totally different datasets that used different descriptors. For example, if I am searching for customer sales numbers, different datasets may label that “<strong>sales</strong>”, or “<strong>revenue</strong>”, or “<strong>customer_sales</strong>”, or “<strong>Cust_sales</strong>”, or any number of other such unique identifiers. What a nightmare that would be! But what a dream the semantic layer becomes!</p>



<p>When I was teaching those students so many years ago, the semantic layer itself was just a dream. Now it is a reality. We can now achieve the benefits, efficiencies, and data superhero powers that we previously could only imagine. But wait! There’s more.</p>



<p>Perhaps the greatest achievement of the semantic layer is to provide <strong><em>different </em></strong>data professionals with easy access to the data needed for their specific roles and tasks. The semantic layer is the representation of data that helps different business end-users discover and access the right data efficiently, effectively, and effortlessly using common business terms. The data scientists need to find the right data as inputs for their models — they also need a place to write-back the outputs of their models to the data repository for other users to access. The BI (business intelligence) analysts need to find the right data for their visualization packages, business questions, and decision support tools — they also need the outputs from the data scientists’ models, such as forecasts, alerts, classifications, and more. The semantic layer achieves this by mapping heterogeneously labeled data into familiar business terms, providing a unified, consolidated view of data across the enterprise.</p>



<p>The semantic layer delivers data insights discovery and usability across the whole enterprise, with each business user empowered to use the terminology and tools that are specific to their role. How data are stored, labeled, and meta-tagged in the data cloud is no longer a bottleneck to discovery and access. The decision-makers and data science modelers can fluidly share inputs and outputs with one another, to inform their role-specific tasks and improve their effectiveness. The semantic layer takes the user-specific results out of being a “one-off” solution on that user’s laptop to becoming an enterprise analytics accelerant, enabling business answer discovery at the speed of business questions.</p>



<p>Insights discovery for everyone is achieved. The semantic layer becomes the arbiter (multi-lingual data translator) for insights discovery between and among all business users of data, within the tools that they are already using. The data science team may be focused on feature importance metrics, feature engineering, predictive modeling, model explainability, and model monitoring. The BI team may be focused on KPIs, forecasts, trends, and decision-support insights. The data science team needs to know and to use that data which the BI team considers to be most important. The BI team needs to know and to use which trends, patterns, segments, and anomalies are being found in those data by the data science team. Sharing and integrating such important data streams has never been such a dream.</p>



<p>The semantic layer bridges the gaps between the data cloud, the decision-makers, and the data science modelers. The key results from the data science modelers can be written back to the semantic layer, to be sent directly to consumers of those results in the executive suite and on the BI team. Data scientists can focus on their tools; the BI users and executives can focus on their tools; and the data engineers can focus on their tools. The enterprise data science, analytics, and BI functions have never been so enterprisey. (Is “enterprisey” a word? I don’t know, but I’m sure you get my semantic meaning.)</p>



<p>That’s empowering. That’s data democratization. That’s insights democratization. That’s data fluency/literacy-building across the enterprise. That’s enterprise-wide agile curiosity, question-asking, hypothesizing, testing/experimenting, and continuous learning. That’s data insights for everyone.</p>



<p>Are you ready to learn more how you can bring these advantages to your organization? Be sure to watch the&nbsp;<a href="https://www.atscale.com/single-source-of-truth/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">AtScale&nbsp;</a>webinar “<a href="https://bit.ly/3ySVIiu" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">How to Bridge Data Science and Business Intelligence</a>” where I join a panel in a multi-industry discussion on how a&nbsp;<a href="https://www.atscale.com/universal-semantic-layer/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">semantic layer</a>&nbsp;can help organizations make smarter data-driven decisions at scale. There will be several speakers, including me. I will be speaking about&nbsp;<em>“Model Monitoring in the Enterprise — Filling the Gaps&#8221;,&nbsp;</em>specifically focused on&nbsp;<em>&#8220;Filling the Communication Gaps Between BI and Data Science Teams With a Semantic Data Layer.”</em></p>



<p>Register to attend and view the webinar at&nbsp;<a href="https://bit.ly/3ySVIiu">https://bit.ly/3ySVIiu</a>.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full is-resized"><a href="http://rocketdatascience.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/AtScale-Webinar-Panelists-2021sept30.jpg"><img loading="lazy" src="http://rocketdatascience.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/AtScale-Webinar-Panelists-2021sept30.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1650" width="840" height="420" srcset="http://rocketdatascience.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/AtScale-Webinar-Panelists-2021sept30.jpg 1024w, http://rocketdatascience.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/AtScale-Webinar-Panelists-2021sept30-300x150.jpg 300w, http://rocketdatascience.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/AtScale-Webinar-Panelists-2021sept30-768x384.jpg 768w, http://rocketdatascience.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/AtScale-Webinar-Panelists-2021sept30-624x312.jpg 624w" sizes="(max-width: 840px) 100vw, 840px" /></a><figcaption><a href="https://bit.ly/3ySVIiu" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">https://bit.ly/3ySVIiu</a></figcaption></figure>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>http://rocketdatascience.org/?feed=rss2&#038;p=1649</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>EX is the New CX</title>
		<link>http://rocketdatascience.org/?p=1628</link>
					<comments>http://rocketdatascience.org/?p=1628#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kirk Borne]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 03 Sep 2021 00:43:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Analytics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Products]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Customer Experience]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://rocketdatascience.org/?p=1628</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[(This article is a continuation of my earlier article “When the Voice of the Customer Actually Talks.”) I recently attended (virtually)&#160;CX Summit 2021, presented by&#160;Five9, which focused on “CX Reimagined.” At first this title for the event seemed a bit grandiose to me – Reimagined! After attending the event, I now think the title was [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>(This article is a continuation of my earlier article “<a href="http://rocketdatascience.org/?p=1622" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">When the Voice of the Customer Actually Talks</a>.”)</p>



<p>I recently attended (virtually)&nbsp;<a href="https://five9cxsummit.com/insix" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">CX Summit 2021</a>, presented by&nbsp;<a href="https://www.five9.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Five9</a>, which focused on “CX Reimagined.” At first this title for the event seemed a bit grandiose to me – Reimagined! After attending the event, I now think the title was perfect, and it could have gone even further. I saw how the “art of the possible” in CX (Customer Experience) and EX (Employee Experience) in the Contact Center is already being realized and is being taken to new realms of possibility through AI and Cloud empowerments.</p>



<p>The evolved (reimagined) Contact Center now comes with more options for digital channels to accommodate the customer, more voice data-powered services that serve both the customer and the contact center representative, and more seamless actions on both ends of the call line, even for complex inquiries. This is all enabled by the 3 A’s: AI, Automation, and voice Analytics. We have heard it before: “happy employee, happy customer!” That now looks like this: “EX is the new CX.” Boom!</p>



<p>In an information-packed talk from Gartner Analyst Drew Kraus on “Getting Past the Hype in Customer Service”, where he reviewed just how much hype there is in the customer service and support technologies market, it became clear to me that <a href="https://www.five9.com/solutions" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Five9</a> delivers on the needs, not the hype.</p>



<p>Another informative and data-packed presentation was by Five9 SVP Scott Kolman and COMMfusion analyst Blair Pleasant, where they presented and did a deep dive into the Five9 survey “<a href="https://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20210901005157/en/Five9-Survey-Finds-30-of-Customers-Ditched-Brands-They-had-Previously-Been-Loyal-to-Last-Year" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">2021 Customer Service Index</a> &#8211; Learn how customers have reimagined the customer service experience.” I won’t go too deep here (you should watch the whole session on-demand). Some interesting highlights include:</p>



<ol type="1"><li>Five9 surveyed 2048 consumers, with participants from 7 countries, representing ages 19 to early 70’s. They also completed a similar survey in 2020. Side-by-side comparisons of the survey results (by age, by year of survey, and by country) for the different survey questions were quite informative and potentially quite useful for any contact center operation. If that’s what you or your business does, then you should investigate these “Voice of the Customer” results.</li><li>Across all demographics, only 25% of respondents felt that their contact center experience got worse (either “much worse” or “slightly worse”) from 2020 to 2021. We might have expected a different result with the pandemic raging. Everyone else (75%) felt that their experience got better, much better, or had no opinion.</li><li>Some very surprising results appeared (with significant differences between countries) when people were asked to rate the keys to “Good Service Experience”. Highly rated categories were “Rep gets right answer, even if it takes more time” (33%); “Rep can answer my question quickly’’ (26%); and “Don’t have to wait long to reach rep” (20%).</li><li>Similarly, there were some significant differences by country when people were asked to rate the keys to “Bad Service Experience”. Top responses included: “Get passed from one rep to another” (34%); “Have to wait long to reach rep” (26%); and a tie for third place (at 13%) for “Cue/on hold system not helpful” and “Rep cannot answer my question quickly”. (Remember, that despite these seriously bad experiences, only 25% of respondents generally saw a drop in customer service experience in the past year.)</li><li>One of the more enlightening survey results appeared when asked, “How likely are you to do business with a company if you have a Poor Service Experience?” The USA responses were significantly different than responses from the other 6 countries in the survey in one category: over 11% of USA respondents were “very likely” to continue doing business, versus 3-6% of non-USA respondents being “very likely”. However, in the “somewhat likely” category, all countries were in the range 10-16%, with the USA respondents close to the midpoint, near 14%. In my opinion (not expressed by the session presenters), a reason for these seemingly incompatible responses is that there are two sentiments being conflated in this one question. On the one hand, you have the bad experience on “this” call. On the other hand, you have perhaps the much worse (time-consuming) future experience of switching providers and dealing with the corresponding onboarding (for whatever service this is about). I might be “somewhat likely” to switch providers after one bad call experience, but I would not be “very likely” to go through the pain of switching providers and all that entails.</li></ol>



<p>There were many interesting and powerful sessions in addition to this one, which I focused on here because it presented lots of survey data, and I love data! Another great session was the presentation by former astronaut (now Professor) <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mike_Massimino" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Michael Massimino</a> – brilliant and inspiring, with numerous words of wisdom, leadership advice, and life’s lessons learned. Of course, I admit that I was drawn into his NASA space stories, including the Hubble Telescope repair mission that almost went wrong, because I worked with the Hubble Space Telescope project for 10 years and I worked an additional 10 years at NASA’s Goddard Space Flight Center where many of the telescope’s instruments were tested.</p>



<p>My big takeaway from the Five9 CX Summit is how cloud, AI, automation, and voice analytics are rapidly driving change in the positive direction for contact center representatives and for customers who call in. Maybe that’s why the customer experience didn’t change much from 2020 to 2021, because a lot of those technologies have already been deployed in the past couple of years, particularly for Five9’s clients. </p>



<p>Chatbots and conversational AI are just part of the story – there’s so much more. Five9’s new cloud-enabled, AI-powered, voice data-driven <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://www.five9.com/solutions" target="_blank">solutions</a> and <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://www.five9.com/contact-center-services" target="_blank">services</a> described at the summit are definitely worth exploring and investigating for your contact center: IVA (Intelligent Virtual Agents), VoiceStream, Agent Assist, Studio7, Practical AI, WFO (Work Flow Optimization), Conversation Architect, and UC (unified communications) integration into the contact center VX (Voice Experience) workflow.</p>



<p>Learn more about CX Reimagined and the roles of AI, Automation, Cloud, Voice Analytics, and Omnichannel Customer Engagement in the modern contact center at&nbsp;<a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://five9cxsummit.com/insix" target="_blank"><strong>CX Summit 2021</strong></a>, presented by&nbsp;<a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://www.five9.com/" target="_blank"><strong>Five9</strong></a>. (Even if you missed the live event, the sessions are recorded, so you can watch them on-demand at any time you wish.)&nbsp;See for yourself where the Reimagined becomes the Realized in CX. And learn why EX is the new CX.</p>



<p>Note: This article was sponsored. The opinions expressed here are my own and do not represent the opinions of any other person, company, or entity.</p>



<p>#Five9CXSummit #CXNation </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>http://rocketdatascience.org/?feed=rss2&#038;p=1628</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>When the Voice of the Customer Actually Talks</title>
		<link>http://rocketdatascience.org/?p=1622</link>
					<comments>http://rocketdatascience.org/?p=1622#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kirk Borne]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 22 Aug 2021 23:18:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Analytics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Products]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Customer Experience]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://rocketdatascience.org/?p=1622</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[For many years, organizations (mostly consumer-facing) have placed the &#8220;voice of the customer&#8221; (VoC) high on their priority list of top sources for customer intelligence. The goals of such activities are to improve customer service, customer interactions, customer&#160;engagement, and customer&#160;experience (CX) through just-in-time customer assistance, personalization, and loyalty-building activities. In recent years, even government agencies [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>For many years, organizations (mostly consumer-facing) have placed the &#8220;voice of the customer&#8221; (VoC) high on their priority list of top sources for customer intelligence. The goals of such activities are to improve customer service, customer interactions, customer&nbsp;engagement, and customer&nbsp;experience (CX) through just-in-time customer assistance, personalization, and loyalty-building activities. In recent years, even government agencies have increased their attention on Citizen Experience (CX) and Voice of the Citizen (VoC), to inform and guide their citizen services.</p>



<p>CX has become increasingly data-informed and data-driven, with VoC data being one of the key data sources. Other data sources include purchase patterns, online reviews, online shopping behavior analytics, and call center analytics. As good as these data analytics have been, collecting data and then performing pattern-detection and pattern-recognition analytics can be taken so much further now with AI-enabled customer interactions.&nbsp;</p>



<p>AI is great for pattern recognition, product and service recommendations, anomaly detection, next-best action and next-best decision recommendations, and providing an insights power-boost to all of those. AI can be considered as Accelerated, Actionable, Amplified, Assisted, Augmented, even Awesome Intelligence, both for the customer and for the call center staff.</p>



<p>Consequently, VoC and AI have wonderfully come together in conversational AI applications, including chatbots. Chatbots can be deployed to answer FAQs, to direct calls to the right service representative, to detect customer sentiment, to monitor call center employee performance, to recall and recognize patterns in the customer&#8217;s prior history with the business, to confirm customer identity, to identify up-sell and cross-sell opportunities, to streamline data entry by automatically capturing intricate details of a customer&#8217;s preferences, concerns, requests, critical information, and callback expectations, and to detect when it&#8217;s time to direct the call to a human agent (the right human agent).</p>



<p>In short, the VoC reaches its peak value when it captures the full depth and breadth of what the customer is talking about and what they are trying to communicate. AI-enabled chatbots are thus bringing great value and effectiveness in consumers&#8217; call center experiences.&nbsp;</p>



<p>From the call center representative perspective, AI-enabled chatbots are a tremendous efficiency and effectiveness boost for these persons also. Many details of the initial customer interaction can be&nbsp;automatically&nbsp;captured, recorded, indexed, and made searchable even before the call is directed to the representative, increasing the likelihood that it is the right representative for that customer&#8217;s specific needs. Not only is the CX amplified, but so is the EX (Employee Experience). Surveys and reports have documented that the strong improvement in call center staff EX is a source of significant value to the entire organization.&nbsp;</p>



<p>One dimension of this EX amplification that should not be overlooked is when advanced case management is required from a human call center agent. In cases like that, the agent is engaged in their best (most satisfying) capacity as the expert and most knowledgeable source to help the customer, in sharp contrast to other calls where they are engaged in answering the standard FAQs, or in quoting customer account information from a database that a chatbot could easily have retrieved, or in asking the customer to repeat the same information that the customer gave to a previous agent. Everybody wins when all those latter activities are handled swiftly, accurately, and non-redundantly prior to the person-to-person engagement that can then provide&nbsp;the best human touch in the entire caller experience.</p>



<p>Chatbots employ a suite of data-driven technologies, including: machine learning (for pattern detection and recognition, sentiment and emotion detection), natural language processing (covering natural language understanding NLU and natural language generation NLG), voice assistants (for voice search and autonomous action-enablement), cloud computing (to activate actions, services, document creation and document processing), AI (for&nbsp;auto-transcribing conversations, creating real-time action lists, and adding information to appropriate fields automatically), and more.</p>



<p>When the Voice of the Customer talks, the modern AI-powered Call Center listens and responds.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Learn more about the modern Call Center and CX Reimagined at&nbsp;<a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://five9cxsummit.com/insix" target="_blank">CX Summit 2021</a>, presented by&nbsp;<a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://www.five9.com/" target="_blank">Five9</a>. The Summit&#8217;s 5 tracks and multiple sessions will focus on the transformation of the contact center through the evolution of digital channels, AI, Automation and Analytics. By applying the power of data and the cloud we can reimagine CX and realize results in a rapidly changing marketplace. At the Summit, you can connect and network with contact center professionals, ecosystem partners and peers, you can learn to optimize your&nbsp;<a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://www.five9.com/" target="_blank">Five9&nbsp;</a>implementation to superpower your contact center, you can hear customer stories and product updates, and you can learn how Five9 can help you deliver a whole new level of customer service. Register here for&nbsp;<a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://five9cxsummit.com/insix" target="_blank">CX Summit 2021</a>&nbsp;and see for yourself where the Reimagined becomes the Realized in CX:&nbsp;<a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://five9cxsummit.com/insix" target="_blank">https://five9cxsummit.com/insix</a> </p>



<p>Learn more about the Summit, some highlights and key takeaways, in my follow-up article &#8220;<a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="http://rocketdatascience.org/?p=1628" target="_blank">EX is the New CX</a>.&#8221;</p>



<p>Note: This article was sponsored. The opinions expressed here are my own and do not represent the opinions of any other person, company, or entity.</p>



<p>#Five9CXSummit #CXNation</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>http://rocketdatascience.org/?feed=rss2&#038;p=1622</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Are You Content with Your Organization’s Content Strategy?</title>
		<link>http://rocketdatascience.org/?p=1593</link>
					<comments>http://rocketdatascience.org/?p=1593#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kirk Borne]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 06 Jul 2021 18:01:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Analytics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Big Data]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Internet of Things]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Machine Learning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Products]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Strategy]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://rocketdatascience.org/?p=1593</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In this post, we will examine ways that your organization can separate useful content into separate categories that amplify your own staff’s performance. Before we start, I have a few questions for you. What attributes of your organization’s strategies can you attribute to successful outcomes? How long do you deliberate before taking specific deliberate actions? [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>In this post, we will examine ways that your organization can separate useful content into separate categories that amplify your own staff’s performance. Before we start, I have a few questions for you.</p>



<p>What
attributes of your organization’s strategies can you attribute to successful
outcomes? How long do you deliberate before taking specific deliberate actions?
Do you converse with your employees about decisions that might be the converse
of what they would expect? Is a process modification that saves a minute in
someone’s workday considered too minute for consideration? Do you present your
employees with a present for their innovative ideas? Do you perfect your plans
in anticipation of perfect outcomes? Or do you project foregone conclusions on
a project before it is completed? </p>



<p>If
you have good answers to these questions, that is awesome! I would not contest
any of your answers since this is not a contest. In fact, this is actually
something quite different. Before you combine all these questions in a heap and
thresh them in a combine, and before you buffet me with a buffet of skeptical
remarks, stick with me and let me explain. Do not close the door on me when I
am so close to giving you an explanation. </p>



<p>What
you have just experienced is a plethora of heteronyms. Heteronyms are words
that are spelled identically but have different meanings when pronounced
differently. If you include the title of this blog, you were just presented
with 13 examples of heteronyms in the preceding paragraphs. Can you find them
all?</p>



<p>Seriously
now, what do these word games have to do with content strategy? I would say
that they have a great deal to do with it. Specifically, in the modern era of
massive data collections and exploding content repositories, we can no longer
simply rely on keyword searches to be sufficient. In the case of a heteronym, a
keyword search would return both uses of the word, even though their meanings
are quite different. In “information retrieval” language, we would say that we
have high RECALL, but low PRECISION. In other words, we can find most occurrences
of the word (recall), but not all the results correspond to the meaning of our
search (precision). That is no longer good enough when the volume is so high.</p>



<p>The
key to success is to start enhancing and augmenting content management systems
(CMS) with additional features: semantic content and context. This is
accomplished through tags, annotations, and metadata (TAM). TAM management,
like content management, begins with business strategy.</p>



<p>Strategic content management focusses on business outcomes, business process improvement, efficiency (precision – i.e., &#8220;did I find only the content that I need without a lot of noise?&#8221;), and effectiveness (recall – i.e., &#8220;did I find all the content that I need?&#8221;). Just because people can request a needle in the haystack, it is not a good thing to deliver the whole haystack that contains that needle. Clearly, such a content delivery system is not good for business productivity. So, there must be a strategy regarding who, what, when, where, why, and how is the organization’s content to be indexed, stored, accessed, delivered, used, and documented. The content strategy should emulate a digital library strategy. Labeling, indexing, ease of discovery, and ease of access are essential if end-users are to find and benefit from the collection.</p>



<p>My favorite approach to TAM creation and to modern data management in general is AI and machine learning (ML). That is, use AI and machine learning techniques on digital content (databases, documents, images, videos, press releases, forms, web content, social network posts, etc.) to infer topics, trends, sentiment, context, content, named entity identification, numerical content extraction (including the units on those numbers), and negations. Do not forget the negations. A document that states “this form should not be used for XYZ” is exactly the opposite of a document that states “this form must be used for XYZ”. Similarly, a social media post that states “Yes. I believe that this product is good” is quite different from a post that states “Yeah, sure. I believe that this product is good. LOL.”</p>



<p>Contextual TAM enhances a CMS with knowledge-driven search and retrieval, not just keyword-driven. Contextual TAM includes semantic TAM, taxonomic indexing, and even usage-based tags (digital breadcrumbs of the users of specific pieces of content, including the key words and phrases that people used to describe the content in their own reports). Adding these to your organization’s content makes the CMS semantically searchable and usable. That’s far more laser-focused (high-precision) than keyword search.</p>



<p>One
type of implementation of a content strategy that is specific to data
collections are data catalogs. Data catalogs are very useful and important.
They become even more useful and valuable if they include granular search
capabilities. For example, the end-user may only need the piece of the dataset
that has the content that their task requires, versus being delivered the full
dataset. Tagging and annotating those subcomponents and subsets (i.e.,
granules) of the data collection for fast search, access, and retrieval is also
important for efficient orchestration and delivery of the data that fuels AI,
automation, and machine learning operations. </p>



<p>One
way to describe this is “smart content” for intelligent digital business
operations. Smart content includes labeled (tagged, annotated) metadata (TAM).
These labels include content, context, uses, sources, and characterizations
(patterns, features) associated with the whole content and with individual
content granules. Labels can be learned through machine learning, or applied by
human experts, or proposed by non-experts when those labels represent cognitive
human-discovered patterns and features in the data. Labels can be learned and
applied in existing CMS, in massive streaming data, and in sensor data
(collected in devices at the “edge”). </p>



<p>Some specific tools and techniques that can be applied to CMS to generate smart content include these:</p>



<ul><li>Natural language understanding and natural language generation</li><li>Topic modeling (including topic drift and topic emergence detection)</li><li>Sentiment detection (including emotion detection)</li><li>AI-generated and ML-inferred content and context</li><li>Entity identification and extraction</li><li>Numerical quantity extraction</li><li>Automated structured (searchable) database generation from textual (unstructured) document collections (for example: <a rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label="Textual ETL (opens in a new tab)" href="https://www.forestrimtech.com/" target="_blank">Textual ETL</a>).</li></ul>



<p>Consequently, smart content thrives at the convergence of AI and content. Labels are curated and stored with the content, thus enabling curation, cataloguing (indexing), search, delivery, orchestration, and use of content and data in AI applications, including knowledge-driven decision-making and autonomous operations. Techniques that both enable (contribute to) and benefit from smart content are content discovery, machine learning, knowledge graphs, semantic linked data, semantic data integration, knowledge discovery, and knowledge management. Smart content thus meets the needs for digital business operations and autonomous (AI and intelligent automation) activities, which must devour streams of content and data – not just any content, but smart content – the right (semantically identified) content delivered at the right time in the right context.</p>



<p>The
four tactical steps in a smart content strategy include:</p>



<ol><li>Characterize and contextualize the patterns, events, and entities in the content collection with semantic (contextual) tags, annotation, and metadata (TAM).</li><li>Collect, curate, and catalog (i.e., index) each TAM component to make it searchable, accessible, and reusable.</li><li>Deliver the right content at the right time in the right context to the decision agent.</li><li>Decide and act on the delivered insights and knowledge.</li></ol>



<p>Remember,
do not be content with your current content management strategy. But discover
and deliver the perfect smart content that perfects your digital business outcomes.
Smart content strategy can save end-users countless minutes in a typical
workday, and that type of business process improvement certainly is not too
minute for consideration.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>http://rocketdatascience.org/?feed=rss2&#038;p=1593</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Top 10 Data Innovation Trends During 2020</title>
		<link>http://rocketdatascience.org/?p=1589</link>
					<comments>http://rocketdatascience.org/?p=1589#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kirk Borne]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 06 Jul 2021 17:42:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Analytics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Big Data]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Internet of Things]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Machine Learning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Strategy]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://rocketdatascience.org/?p=1589</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The year 2020 was remarkably different in many ways from previous years. In at least one way, it was not different, and that was in the continued development of innovations that are inspired by data. This steady march of data-driven innovation has been a consistent characteristic of each year for at least the past decade. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The year 2020 was remarkably different in many
ways from previous years. In at least one way, it was not different, and that was
in the continued development of innovations that are inspired by data. This
steady march of data-driven innovation has been a consistent characteristic of
each year for at least the past decade. These data-fueled innovations come in
the form of new algorithms, new technologies, new applications, new concepts,
and even some “old things made new again”.</p>



<p>I provide below my perspective on what was
interesting, innovative, and influential in my watch list of the Top 10 data
innovation trends during 2020. </p>



<p>1)&nbsp;Automated Narrative Text Generation
tools became incredibly good in 2020, being able to create scary good “deep
fake” articles. The GPT-3 (Generative Pretrained Transformer, 3rd generation
text autocomplete) algorithm made headlines since it demonstrated that it can
start with a very thin amount of input (a short topic description, or a question),
from which it can then generate several paragraphs of narrative that are very
hard (perhaps impossible) to distinguish from human-generated text. However, it
is far from perfect, since it certainly does not have reasoning skills, and it
also loses its “train of thought” after several paragraphs (e.g., by making
contradictory statements at different places in the narrative, even though the
statements are nicely formed sentences).</p>



<p>2) MLOps became the expected norm
in&nbsp;machine&nbsp;learning&nbsp;and data science projects. MLOps takes the
modeling, algorithms, and data wrangling out of the experimental “one off”
phase and moves the best models into deployment and sustained operational&nbsp;phase.
MLOps &#8220;done right&#8221; addresses sustainable model operations, explainability,
trust, versioning, reproducibility, training updates, and governance (i.e., the
monitoring of very important operational ML characteristics: data drift,
concept drift, and model security).</p>



<p>3) Concept drift by COVID – as mentioned above, concept drift is being addressed in machine learning and data science projects by MLOps, but concept drift is so much bigger than MLOps. Specifically, it feels to many of us like a decade of business transformation was compressed into the one year 2020. How and why businesses make decisions, customers make decisions, and anybody else makes decisions became conceptually and contextually different in 2020. Customer purchase patterns, supply chain, inventory, and logistics represent just a few domains where we saw new and emergent behaviors, responses, and outcomes represented in our data and in our predictive models. The old models were not able to predict very well based on the previous year’s data since the previous year seemed like 100 years ago in “data years”. Another example was in new data-driven cybersecurity practices introduced by the COVID pandemic, including behavior biometrics (or biometric analytics), which were driven strongly by the global “work from home” transition, where many insecurities in networks, data-sharing, and collaboration / communication tools were exposed. Behavior biometrics may possibly become the essential cyber requirement for unique user identification, finally putting weak passwords out of commission. Data and network access controls have similar user-based permissions when working from home as when working behind the firewall at your place of business, but the security checks and usage tracking can be more verifiable and certified with biometric analytics. This is critical in our massively data-sharing world and enterprises.</p>



<p>4) AIOps increasingly became a focus in AI
strategy conversations. While it is similar to MLOps, AIOps is less focused on
the ML algorithms and more focused on automation and AI applications in the
enterprise IT environment – i.e., focused on operationalizing AI, including
data orchestration, the AI platform, AI outcomes monitoring, and cybersecurity
requirements. AIOps appears in discussions related to ITIM (IT infrastructure
monitoring), SIEM (security information and event management), APM (application
performance monitoring), UEBA (user and entity behavior analytics), DevSecOps,
Anomaly Detection, Rout Cause Analysis, Alert Generation, and related
enterprise IT applications.</p>



<p>5) The emergence of Edge-to-Cloud
architectures clearly began pushing Industry 4.0 forward (with some folks now starting
to envision what Industry 5.0 will look like). The Edge-to-Cloud architectures are
responding to the growth of IoT sensors and devices everywhere, whose
deployments are boosted by 5G capabilities that are now helping to
significantly reduce data-to-action latency. In some cases, the analytics and
intelligence must be computed and acted upon at the edge (Edge Computing, at
the point of data collection), as in autonomous vehicles. In other cases, the
analytics and insights may have more significant computation requirements and
less strict latency requirements, thus allowing the data to be moved to larger
computational resources in the cloud. The almost forgotten &#8220;orphan&#8221;
in these architectures, Fog Computing (living between edge and cloud), is now moving
to a more significant status in data and analytics architecture design. </p>



<p>6)&nbsp;Federated&nbsp;Machine&nbsp;Learning&nbsp;(FML)
is another &#8220;orphan&#8221; concept (formerly called Distributed Data Mining
a decade ago) that found new life in modeling requirements, algorithms, and
applications in 2020. To some extent, the pandemic contributed to this
because&nbsp;FML&nbsp;enforces data privacy by essentially removing
data-sharing as a requirement for model-building across multiple datasets,
multiple organizations, and multiple applications. FML model training is done incrementally
and locally on the local dataset, with the meta-parameters of the local models
then being shared with a centralized model-inference engine (which does not see
any of the private data). The centralized ML engine then builds a global model,
which is communicated back to the local nodes. Multiple iterations in
parameter-updating and hyperparameter-tuning can occur between local nodes and
the central inference engine, until satisfactory model performance is achieved.
All through these training stages, data privacy is preserved, while allowing
for the generation of globally useful, distributable, and accurate models.</p>



<p>7) Deep learning (DL) may not be “the one
algorithm to dominate all others” after all. There was some research published
earlier in 2020 that found that traditional, less complex algorithms can be
nearly as good or better than deep learning on some tasks. This could be yet
another demonstration of the “no free lunch theorem”, which basically states
that there is no single universal algorithm that is the best for all problems.
Consequently, the results of the new DL research may not be so surprising, but
they certainly prompt us with necessary reminders that sometimes simple is
better than complexity, and that the old saying is often still true: <em>“perfect
is the enemy of good enough.”</em></p>



<p>8) RPA (Robotic Process Automation) and
intelligent automation&nbsp;were not new in 2020, but the surge in their use
and in the number of providers was remarkable. While RPA is more rule-based
(informed by business process mining, to automate work tasks that have very
little variation), intelligent automation is more data-driven, adaptable, and
self-learning in real-time. RPA mimics human actions, by repetition of routine
tasks based on a set of rules. Intelligent automation simulates human
intelligence, which responds and adapts to emergent patterns in new data, and
which is capable of learning to automate non-routine tasks. Keep an eye on the
intelligent automation space for new and exciting developments to come in the
near future around hyperautomation and enterprise intelligence, such as the
emergence of learning business systems that learn and adapt their processes
based on signals in enterprise data across numerous business functions:
finance, marketing, HR, customer service, production, operations, sales, and
management.</p>



<p>9) The Rise of Data Literacy initiatives,
imperatives, instructional programs, and institutional awareness in 2020 was
one of the two most exciting things that I witnessed during the year. (The
other one of the two is next on my list.) I have said for nearly 20 years that
data literacy must become a key component of education at all levels and an
aptitude of nearly all employees in all organizations. The world is data,
revolves around data, produces and consumes massive quantities of data, and
drives innovative emerging technologies that are inspired by, informed by, and
fueled by data: augmented reality (AR), virtual reality (VR), autonomous
vehicles, computer vision, digital twins, drones, robotics, AI, IoT, hyperautomation,
virtual assistants, conversational AI, chatbots, natural language understanding
and generation (NLU, NLG), automatic language translation, 4D-printing, cyber
resilience, and more. Data literacy is essential for future of work, future
innovation, work from home, and everyone that touches digital information.
Studies have shown that organizations that are not adopting data literacy
programs are not only falling behind, but they may stay behind, their
competition. Get on board with data literacy! Now!</p>



<p>10) Observability emerged as one of the hottest and (for me) most exciting developments of the year. Do not confuse observability with monitoring (specifically, with IT monitoring). The key difference is this: monitoring is what you do, and observability is why you do it. Observability is a business strategy: what you monitor, why you monitor it, what you intend to learn from it, how it will be used, and how it will contribute to business objectives and mission success. But the power, value, and imperative of observability does not stop there. Observability meets AI – it is part of the complete AIOps package: “keeping an eye on the AI.” Observability delivers actionable insights, context-enriched data sets, early warning alert generation, root cause visibility, active performance monitoring, predictive and prescriptive incident management, real-time operational deviation detection (6-Sigma never had it so good!), tight coupling of cyber-physical systems, digital twinning of almost anything in the enterprise, and more. And the goodness doesn’t stop there. The emergence of standards, like OpenTelemetry, can unify all aspects of your enterprise observability strategy: process instrumentation, sensing, metrics specification, context generation, data collection, data export, and data analysis of business process performance and behavior monitoring in the cloud. This plethora of benefits is a real game-changer for open-source self-service intelligent data-driven business process monitoring (BPM) and application performance monitoring (APM), feedback, and improvement. As mentioned above, monitoring is “what you are doing”, and observability is “why you are doing it.” If your organization is not having “the talk” about observability, now is the time to start – to understand why and how to produce business value through observability into the multitude of data-rich digital business applications and processes all across the modern enterprise. Don&#8217;t drown in those deep seas of data. Instead, develop an Observability Strategy to help your organization ride the waves of data, to help your business innovation and transformation practices move at the speed of data.</p>



<p>In summary, my top 10 data innovation trends from 2020 are:</p>



<ul><li>GPT-3</li><li>MLOps</li><li>Concept Drift by COVID</li><li>AIOps</li><li>Edge-to-Cloud and Fog
Computing</li><li>Federated Machine
Learning</li><li>Deep Learning meets
the “no free lunch theorem”</li><li>RPA and Intelligent
Automation</li><li>Rise of Data Literacy</li><li>Observability</li></ul>



<p>If
I were to choose what was hottest trend in 2020, it would not be a single item in
this top 10 list. The hottest trend would be a hybrid (convergence) of several of
these items. That hybrid would include: Observability, coupled with Edge and
the ever-rising ubiquitous IoT (sensors on everything), boosted by 5G and cloud
technologies, fueling ever-improving ML and DL algorithms, all of which are
enabling “just-in-time” intelligence and intelligent automation (for
data-driven decisions and action, at the point of data collection), deployed with
a data-literate workforce, in a sustainable and trusted MLOps environment,
where algorithms, data, and applications work harmoniously and are governed and
secured by AIOps. </p>



<p>If we
learned anything from the year 2020, it should be that trendy technologies do not
comprise a menu of digital transformation solutions to choose from, but there really
is only one combined solution, which is the hybrid convergence of data
innovation technologies. From my perspective, that was the single most
significant data innovation trend of the year 2020. </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>http://rocketdatascience.org/?feed=rss2&#038;p=1589</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Analytics Insights and Careers at the Speed of Data</title>
		<link>http://rocketdatascience.org/?p=1574</link>
					<comments>http://rocketdatascience.org/?p=1574#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kirk Borne]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2021 21:54:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Analytics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Big Data]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Data Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Internet of Things]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Machine Learning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Strategy]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://rocketdatascience.org/?p=1574</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The determination of winners and losers in the data analytics space is a much more dynamic proposition than it ever has been. One CIO said it this way, “If CIOs invested in machine learning three years ago, they would have wasted their money. But if they wait another three years, they will never catch up.” [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-image"><img loading="lazy" width="744" height="400" src="http://rocketdatascience.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/LinkedIn-Article-Graphic.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1575" srcset="http://rocketdatascience.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/LinkedIn-Article-Graphic.jpg 744w, http://rocketdatascience.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/LinkedIn-Article-Graphic-300x161.jpg 300w, http://rocketdatascience.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/LinkedIn-Article-Graphic-624x335.jpg 624w" sizes="(max-width: 744px) 100vw, 744px" /><figcaption> <em>How to make smarter data-driven decisions at scale</em>: <a href="http://bit.ly/3rS3ZQW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label=" (opens in a new tab)">http://bit.ly/3rS3ZQW</a> </figcaption></figure>



<p>The determination of winners and losers in the data analytics space is a much more dynamic proposition than it ever has been. One<a> </a><a rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label="CIO said it this way (opens in a new tab)" href="https://www.cio.com/article/3061713/why-its-time-for-cios-to-invest-in-machine-learning.html" target="_blank">CIO said it this way</a>, <em>“If CIOs invested in machine learning three years ago, they would have wasted their money. But if they wait another three years, they will never catch up.” </em>&nbsp;Well, that statement was made five years ago! A lot has changed in those five years, and so has the data landscape. </p>



<p>The dynamic changes of the business requirements and
value propositions around data analytics have been increasingly intense in
depth (in the number of applications in each business unit) and in breadth (in
the enterprise-wide scope of applications in all business units in all
sectors). But more significant has been the acceleration in the number of dynamic,
real-time data sources and corresponding dynamic, real-time analytics
applications. </p>



<p>We no longer should worry about “managing data at the
speed of business,” but worry more about “managing business at the speed of
data.”</p>



<p>One of the primary drivers for the phenomenal growth in dynamic real-time data analytics today and in the coming decade is the&nbsp;Internet of Things (IoT) and its sibling the Industrial IoT (IIoT). With its vast assortment of sensors and streams of data that yield digital insights in situ in almost any situation, the IoT / IIoT market has a <a href="https://www.iot-now.com/2020/05/20/102937-global-iot-market-to-grow-to-1-5trn-annual-revenue-by-2030/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label="projected market valuation of $1.5 trillion by 2030 (opens in a new tab)">projected market valuation of $1.5 trillion by 2030</a>. The accompanying technology Edge Computing, through which those streaming digital insights are extracted and then served to end-users, has a <a rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label="projected valuation of $800 billion by 2028 (opens in a new tab)" href="https://venturebeat.com/2021/03/11/state-of-the-edge-report-projects-edge-computing-will-reach-800b-by-2028/" target="_blank">projected valuation of $800 billion by 2028</a>. </p>



<p>With dynamic real-time insights, this “Internet
of Everything” can then become the “Internet of Intelligent Things”, or as I
like to say, <em>“The Internet used to be a thing. Now things are the Internet.”</em>
The vast scope of this digital transformation in dynamic business insights
discovery from entities, events, and behaviors is on a scale that is almost
incomprehensible. Traditional business analytics approaches (on laptops, in the
cloud, or with static datasets) will not keep up with this growing tidal wave
of dynamic data.</p>



<p>Another dimension to this story, of course, is the Future of Work discussion, including creation of new job titles and roles, and the demise of older job titles and roles. <a href="https://www.androidauthority.com/internet-of-things-companies-1023404/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label="One group has declared (opens in a new tab)">One group has declared</a>, <em>“IoT companies will dominate the 2020s: Prepare your resume!”</em> This article quotes an older <a rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label=" (opens in a new tab)" href="https://www.crn.com/slide-shows/internet-of-things/10-hot-iot-companies-to-watch-in-2019" target="_blank">market projection (from 2019)</a>, which estimated <em>“the global industrial IoT market could reach $14.2 trillion by 2030.”</em></p>



<p>In
dynamic data-driven applications, automation of the essential processes (in
this case, data triage, insights discovery, and analytics delivery) can give a
power boost to ride that tidal wave of fast-moving data streams. One can
prepare for and improve skill readiness for these new business and career
opportunities in several ways:</p>



<ul><li>Focus on the automation of business processes: <em>e.g.,</em> artificial intelligence, robotics, robotic process automation, intelligent process automation, chatbots. </li><li>Focus on the technologies and engineering components: <em>e.g.,</em> sensors, monitoring, cloud-to-edge, microservices, serverless, insights-as-a-service APIs, IFTTT (IF-This-Then-That) architectures. </li><li>Focus on the data science: <em>e.g.,</em> machine learning, statistics, computer vision, natural language understanding, coding, forecasting, predictive analytics, prescriptive analytics, anomaly detection, emergent behavior discovery, model explainability, trust, ethics, model monitoring (for data drift and concept drift) in dynamic environments (MLOps, ModelOps, AIOps).</li><li>Focus on specific data types: <em>e.g.,</em> time series, video, audio, images, streaming text (such as social media or online chat channels), network logs, supply chain tracking (e.g., RFID), inventory monitoring (SKU / UPC tracking).</li><li>Focus on the strategies that aim these tools, talents, and technologies at reaching business mission and goals: <em>e.g.,</em> data strategy, analytics strategy, observability strategy (<em>i.e.,</em> why and where are we deploying the data-streaming sensors, and what outcomes should they achieve?).</li></ul>



<p>Insights
discovery from ubiquitous data collection (via the tens of billions of
connected devices that will be measuring, monitoring, and tracking nearly
everything internally in our business environment and contextually in the
broader market and global community) is ultimately about value creation and business
outcomes. Embedding real-time dynamic analytics at the edge, at the point of
data collection, or at the moment of need will dynamically (and positively) change
the slope of your business or career trajectory. Dynamic sense-making, insights
discovery, next-best-action response, and value creation is essential when data
is being acquired at an enormous rate. Only then can one hope to realize the
promised trillion-dollar market value of the Internet of Everything.</p>



<p>For more advice, check out this upcoming webinar panel discussion, sponsored by <a rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label="AtScale (opens in a new tab)" href="https://www.linkedin.com/company/atscale-inc-/" target="_blank">AtScale</a>,  with data and analytics leaders from Wayfair, Cardinal Health, <a rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label=" (opens in a new tab)" href="http://bol.com/" target="_blank">bol.com</a>, and Slickdeals: <em>“How to make smarter data-driven decisions at scale.”</em> Each panelist will share an overview of their data &amp; analytics journey, and how they are building a self-service, data-driven culture that scales. Join us on Wednesday, March 31, 2021 (11:00am PT | 2:00pm ET). Save your spot here: <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="http://bit.ly/3rS3ZQW" target="_blank">http://bit.ly/3rS3ZQW</a>. I hope that you find this event useful. And I hope to see you there! </p>



<p> Please follow me on <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/kirkdborne/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label="LinkedIn (opens in a new tab)">LinkedIn</a>&nbsp;and follow me on Twitter at&nbsp;<a rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label="@KirkDBorne.  (opens in a new tab)" href="https://twitter.com/KirkDBorne" target="_blank">@KirkDBorne. </a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>http://rocketdatascience.org/?feed=rss2&#038;p=1574</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>RPA and IPA – Their Similarities are Different, but Their Rapid Growth Trajectories are the Same</title>
		<link>http://rocketdatascience.org/?p=1558</link>
					<comments>http://rocketdatascience.org/?p=1558#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kirk Borne]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 13 Feb 2021 02:30:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Machine Learning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Strategy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Robotic Process Automation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[RPA]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://rocketdatascience.org/?p=1558</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[When I was growing up, friends at school would occasionally ask me if my older brother and I were twins. We were not, though we looked twin-like! As I grew tired of answering that question, one day I decided to give a more thoughtful answer to the question (beyond a simple “No”). I replied: “Yes, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>When I was growing up, friends at school would occasionally
ask me if my older brother and I were twins. We were not, though we looked
twin-like! As I grew tired of answering that question, one day I decided to
give a more thoughtful answer to the question (beyond a simple “No”). I
replied: “Yes, we are twins. We were born 20 months apart!” My response caused
the questioner to pause and think about what I said, and perhaps reframe their
own thinking. </p>



<p>This story reminds me that two things may appear very much
the same, but they may be found to be not so similar after deeper inspection
and reflection. RPA and IPA are like that. Their similarities are different!</p>



<p>What are RPA and IPA? RPA is Robotic Process Automation, and
IPA is Intelligent Process Automation. Sound similar? Yes, in fact, their
differences are similar! </p>



<p>In the rest of this article, we will refer to IPA as
intelligent automation (IA), which is simply short-hand for intelligent process
automation.</p>



<p>Process automation is relatively clear – it refers to an
automatic implementation of a process, specifically a business process in our
case. One can automate a very complicated and time-consuming process, even for
a one-time bespoke application – the ROI must be worth it, to justify doing this
only once. Robotic Process Automation is for “more than once” automation. RPA then
refers specifically to the robotic repetition of a business process. Repetition
implies that the same steps are repeated many times, for example claims
processing or business form completion or invoice processing or invoice
submission or more data-specific activities, such as data extraction from
documents (such as PDFs), data entry, data validation, and report preparation. </p>



<p>The benefits of RPA accrue from its robotic repetition of a
well-defined process (specifically some sort of digital process with defined instructions,
inputs, rules, and outputs), which is to be repeated without error, thus
removing potential missteps in the process, or accidental omission of steps, or
employee fatigue. The process must be simple, stable, repetitive, and routine, and
it must be carried out the same way hundreds or thousands (or more) times. This
robotic repetition of the process assures that the steps are replicated identically,
correctly, and rapidly from one application to the next, thus yielding higher
business productivity. Consequently, as organizations everywhere are undergoing
significant digital transformation, we have been witnessing increases both in
the use of RPA in organizations and in the number of RPA products in the
market. </p>



<p>So, what about Intelligent Automation? IA refers to the
addition of “intelligence” to the RPA – transforming it into “smart RPA” or
even “cognitive RPA”. This is accomplished by adding more data-driven, machine
learning, and AI (artificial intelligence) components to the process discovery,
process mining, and process learning stages. IA incorporates feedback,
learning, improvement, and optimization in the automation loop. The market and
business appetite for IA is growing rapidly, particularly as more organizations
are seeking to add AI to their enterprise functions and to step up the value
derived from their process automation activities. </p>



<p>The pivot from RPA to IA right now has spurred <a href="https://www.automationanywhere.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label="Automation Anywhere, Inc. (opens in a new tab)">Automation Anywhere, Inc.</a> (AAI) to conduct a survey of businesses and organizations in numerous sectors and industries, to assess the current and future (Now and Next) state of RPA in the enterprise. AAI’s recently published “<a rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label="Now and Next State of RPA” report (opens in a new tab)" href="https://bit.ly/3p0IZpJ" target="_blank">Now and Next State of RPA” report</a> presents detailed results of that survey. </p>



<p>The AAI report covers these industries: energy/utilities,
financial/insurance, government, healthcare, industrial/manufacturing, life
sciences, retail/consumer, services/consulting, technology, telecom, and
transportation/airlines. </p>



<p>The first part of the report addresses the “Now” – the
present-day impact of RPA and IA – how organizations are deploying process
automation, what their priorities are, how much are they investing in it, and
what are the benefits being achieved. The “Next” part of the report probes
organizations’ forward-looking strategies and goals over the next one to two
years. Of course, both the “now” and “next” sections are affected and informed
by the COVID-19 pandemic.</p>



<p>Some top trends from the report include: </p>



<ul><li>Cloud is becoming the platform of choice for RPA
deployments. Cloud is top of mind for leaders everywhere, and that includes
cloud migration and cloud security.</li><li>Organizations are thinking big about RPA, with
millions of bots already implemented by AAI customers. Some AAI customers have
individually deployed tens of thousands of bots.</li><li>The pandemic has rapidly increased demand for
RPA, especially in customer-facing functions, such as call centers.</li><li>Most organizations (63%) are deploying or
scaling their efforts, while 27% are still evaluating RPA solutions, and 10%
have no plans at this time.</li><li>Spending on RPA is increasing, with an estimated
doubling of the number of bots deployed in the next 12 months in most
organizations who are already actively using RPA bots.</li><li>Productivity improvement is the single most
important driver for adopting RPA, IA, and AI.</li><li>The average ROI from RPA/IA deployments is 250%.</li><li>Interest in AI is high and growing, specifically
in the areas of smart analytics, customer-centricity, chatbots, and predictive
modeling. Many organizations are seeing a strong alignment of their AI and RPA
(hence, IA) projects.</li><li>The top barriers to adoption are (in order of
significance): lack of expertise, insufficient budget, lack of resources, lack
of use cases, limited ROI, organizational resistance, scalability concerns, and
security concerns.</li><li>Top use cases in the back office include finance
(general ledger data reconciliation), accounts payable (invoice processing and
payment), and HR (new employee onboarding).</li><li>Top use cases in the front office include
customer records management (including account updates), customer service
(request handling and call center support), and sales order processing.</li><li>RPA education and training are on the rise
(specifically online training). This reflects the corresponding increase in
interest among many organizations in data literacy, analytics skills, AI
literacy, and AI skills training. Education initiatives address the change
management, employee reskilling, and worker upskilling that organizations are
now prioritizing.</li><li>Organizations report an increased excitement for
RPA/IA, an awareness of significant new opportunities for adoption, and a
desire for more mature RPA – that is, intelligent automation!</li></ul>



<p>There are many more details, including specific insights for different sectors, in the 21-page “Now and Next State of RPA” report from <a href="https://www.automationanywhere.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label="Automation Anywhere, Inc (opens in a new tab)">Automation Anywhere, Inc</a>. You can download the full report here: <a rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label="https://bit.ly/3p0IZpJ (opens in a new tab)" href="https://t.co/BDpqR63Tcw?amp=1" target="_blank">https://bit.ly/3p0IZpJ</a>. Download it for free and learn more how the robotic twinning and repetition of business processes is the most intelligent step in accelerating digital transformation and boosting business productivity.</p>



<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter"><a href="https://bit.ly/3p0IZpJ" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><img loading="lazy" width="902" height="810" src="http://rocketdatascience.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EsRkqH5XMAA_D1b.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1560" srcset="http://rocketdatascience.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EsRkqH5XMAA_D1b.jpg 902w, http://rocketdatascience.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EsRkqH5XMAA_D1b-300x269.jpg 300w, http://rocketdatascience.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EsRkqH5XMAA_D1b-768x690.jpg 768w, http://rocketdatascience.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EsRkqH5XMAA_D1b-624x560.jpg 624w" sizes="(max-width: 902px) 100vw, 902px" /></a><figcaption><a href="https://bit.ly/3p0IZpJ" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label=" (opens in a new tab)">https://bit.ly/3p0IZpJ</a></figcaption></figure></div>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img loading="lazy" width="854" height="878" src="http://rocketdatascience.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EsDCSUPXYAAmCDP.png" alt="" class="wp-image-1567" srcset="http://rocketdatascience.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EsDCSUPXYAAmCDP.png 854w, http://rocketdatascience.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EsDCSUPXYAAmCDP-292x300.png 292w, http://rocketdatascience.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EsDCSUPXYAAmCDP-768x790.png 768w, http://rocketdatascience.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EsDCSUPXYAAmCDP-624x642.png 624w" sizes="(max-width: 854px) 100vw, 854px" /><figcaption>Productivity is the top driver of RPA and AI.</figcaption></figure>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img loading="lazy" width="928" height="842" src="http://rocketdatascience.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EsDGiVfXIAEnatY.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1568" srcset="http://rocketdatascience.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EsDGiVfXIAEnatY.jpg 928w, http://rocketdatascience.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EsDGiVfXIAEnatY-300x272.jpg 300w, http://rocketdatascience.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EsDGiVfXIAEnatY-768x697.jpg 768w, http://rocketdatascience.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EsDGiVfXIAEnatY-624x566.jpg 624w" sizes="(max-width: 928px) 100vw, 928px" /><figcaption>Open-ended survey questions gave insights into organizations&#8217; planned AI projects.</figcaption></figure>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img loading="lazy" width="1024" height="507" src="http://rocketdatascience.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EsDGiVhXUAErsmh-1024x507.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1569" srcset="http://rocketdatascience.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EsDGiVhXUAErsmh-1024x507.jpg 1024w, http://rocketdatascience.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EsDGiVhXUAErsmh-300x149.jpg 300w, http://rocketdatascience.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EsDGiVhXUAErsmh-768x380.jpg 768w, http://rocketdatascience.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EsDGiVhXUAErsmh-624x309.jpg 624w, http://rocketdatascience.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EsDGiVhXUAErsmh.jpg 1199w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><figcaption>Training initiatives are a high priority for increasing ROI from RPA and AI projects.<br></figcaption></figure>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>http://rocketdatascience.org/?feed=rss2&#038;p=1558</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How We Teach The Leaders of Tomorrow To Be Curious, Ask Questions and Not Be Afraid To Fail Fast To Learn Fast</title>
		<link>http://rocketdatascience.org/?p=1524</link>
					<comments>http://rocketdatascience.org/?p=1524#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kirk Borne]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2020 21:25:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Big Data]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Data Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Machine Learning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Strategy]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://rocketdatascience.org/?p=1524</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I recently enjoyed recording a podcast with Joe DosSantos (Chief Data Officer at Qlik). This was one in a series of #DataBrilliant podcasts by Qlik, which you can also access here (Apple Podcasts) and here (Spotify). I summarize below some of the topics that Joe and I discussed in the podcast. Be sure to listen [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>I recently enjoyed recording a podcast with <a rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label="Joe DosSantos (opens in a new tab)" href="https://blog.qlik.com/joe-dossantos/" target="_blank">Joe DosSantos</a> (Chief Data Officer at <a rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label="Qlik (opens in a new tab)" href="https://www.qlik.com/" target="_blank">Qlik</a>). This was one in a series of <a rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label="#DataBrilliant podcasts by Qlik (opens in a new tab)" href="https://www.listennotes.com/podcasts/data-brilliant-qlik-oWOh2H5Y97U/" target="_blank">#DataBrilliant podcasts by Qlik</a>, which you can also access <a rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label="here (opens in a new tab)" href="https://podcasts.apple.com/us/podcast/data-brilliant/id1510000879" target="_blank">here</a> (Apple Podcasts) and <a rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label="here (opens in a new tab)" href="https://open.spotify.com/show/6s4HW4jvJ5x7xZaYz1TVrb" target="_blank">here</a> (Spotify). I summarize below some of the topics that Joe and I discussed in the podcast. Be sure to listen to the full recording of our lively conversation, which covered Data Literacy, Data Strategy, Data Leadership, and more.</p>



<p><strong>The Age of Hype Cycles</strong></p>



<p>The data age has been marked by numerous “hype cycles.” First, we heard how Big Data, Data Science, Machine Learning (ML) and Advanced Analytics would have the honor to be the technologies that would cure cancer, end world hunger and solve the world’s biggest challenges. Then came third-generation Artificial Intelligence (AI), Blockchain and soon Quantum Computing, with each one seeking that honor.</p>



<p>From all this hope and hype, one constant has always been there: a focus on value creation from data. As a scientist, I have always recommended a scientific approach: State your problem first, be curious (ask questions), collect facts to address those questions (acquire data), investigate, analyze, ask more questions, include a sensible serving of skepticism, and (above all else) aim to fail fast in order to learn fast. As I discussed with Joe DosSantos when I spoke with him for the latest episode of Data Brilliant, you don’t need to be a data scientist to follow these principles. These apply to everyone, in all organizations and walks of life, in every sector.</p>



<p>One characteristic of science that is especially true in data science and implicit in ML is the concept of continuous learning and refining our understanding. We build models to test our understanding, but these models are not “one and done.” They are part of a cycle of learning. In ML, the learning cycle is sometimes called backpropagation, where the errors (inaccurate predictions) of our models are fed back into adjusting the model’s input parameters in a way that aims to improve the output accuracy. A more colloquial expression for this is: good judgment comes from experience, and experience comes from bad judgment.</p>



<p><strong>Data Literacy For All</strong></p>



<p>I know that for some, the term data and some of the other terminology I’ve mentioned already can be scary. But they shouldn’t be. We are all surrounded by – and creating – masses of data every single day. As Joe and I talked about, one of the first hurdles in data literacy is getting people to recognize that everything is data. What you see with your eyes? That’s data. What you hear with your ears? Data. The words that come out of your mouth that other people hear? That’s all data. Images, text, documents, audio, video and all the apps on your phone, all the things you search for on the internet? Yet again, that’s data.</p>



<p>Every single day, everyone around the world is using data and the principles I mention above, many without realizing it. So, now we need to bring this value to our businesses.</p>



<p><strong>How To Build A Successful Enterprise Data Strategy</strong></p>



<p>In my chat with Joe, we talked about many data concepts in the context of enterprise digital transformation. As always, but especially during the race toward digital transformation that has been accelerated by the 2020 pandemic, a successful enterprise data strategy that leads to business value creation can benefit from first addressing these six key questions:</p>



<p>(1) What mission objective and outcomes are you aiming to achieve?</p>



<p>(2) What is the business problem, expressed in data terminology? Specifically, is it a detection problem (fraud or emergent behavior), a discovery problem (new customers or new opportunities), a prediction problem (what will happen) or an optimization problem (how to improve outcomes)?</p>



<p>(3) Do you have the talent (key people representing diverse perspectives), tools (data technologies) and techniques (AI and ML knowledge) to make it happen?</p>



<p>(4) What data do you have to fuel the algorithms, the training and the modeling processes?</p>



<p>(5) Is your organizational culture ready for this (for data-informed decisions; an experimentation mindset; continuous learning; fail fast to learn fast; with principled AI and data governance)?</p>



<p>(6) What operational technology environment do you have to deploy the implementation (cloud or on-premise platform)?</p>



<p><strong>Data Leadership</strong></p>



<p>As Joe and I discussed, your ultimate business goal is to build a data-fueled enterprise that delivers business value from data. Therefore, ask questions, be purposeful (goal-oriented and mission-focused), be reasonable in your expectations and remain reasonably skeptical – because as famous statistician, George Box, once said “all models are wrong, but some are useful.”</p>



<p>Now, listen to the full podcast <a href="https://blog.qlik.com/how-we-teach-the-leaders-of-tomorrow-to-be-curious-ask-questions-and-not-be-afraid-to-fail-fast-to-learn-fast" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label="here (opens in a new tab)">here</a>.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img loading="lazy" width="1024" height="536" src="http://rocketdatascience.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/episode-6-blog-asset-1200x628-1024x536.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1534" srcset="http://rocketdatascience.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/episode-6-blog-asset-1200x628-1024x536.jpg 1024w, http://rocketdatascience.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/episode-6-blog-asset-1200x628-300x157.jpg 300w, http://rocketdatascience.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/episode-6-blog-asset-1200x628-768x402.jpg 768w, http://rocketdatascience.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/episode-6-blog-asset-1200x628-624x327.jpg 624w, http://rocketdatascience.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/episode-6-blog-asset-1200x628.jpg 1200w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>http://rocketdatascience.org/?feed=rss2&#038;p=1524</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
