<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<rdf:RDF
 xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
 xmlns="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/"
 xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
 xmlns:taxo="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/taxonomy/"
 xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
 xmlns:syn="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
 xmlns:admin="http://webns.net/mvcb/"
>

<channel rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/">
<title>physics.comp-ph updates on arXiv.org</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">Physics -- Computational Physics (physics.comp-ph) updates on the arXiv.org e-print archive</description>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:date>2022-11-03T20:30:00-05:00</dc:date>
<dc:publisher>help@arxiv.org</dc:publisher>
<dc:subject>Physics -- Computational Physics</dc:subject>
<syn:updateBase>1901-01-01T00:00+00:00</syn:updateBase>
<syn:updateFrequency>1</syn:updateFrequency>
<syn:updatePeriod>daily</syn:updatePeriod>
<items>
 <rdf:Seq>
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01375" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01531" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01929" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01995" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2107.09984" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2112.09280" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2208.13772" />
 </rdf:Seq>
</items>
<image rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif" />
</channel>
<image rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif">
<title>arXiv.org</title>
<url>http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif</url>
<link>http://arxiv.org/</link>
</image>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01375">
<title>High-speed processing of X-ray wavefront marking data with the Unified Modulated Pattern Analysis (UMPA) model. (arXiv:2211.01375v1 [physics.med-ph])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01375</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Wavefront-marking X-ray imaging techniques use e.g., sandpaper or a grating
to generate intensity fluctuations, and analyze their distortion by the sample
in order to retrieve attenuation, phase-contrast, and dark-field information.
Phase contrast yields an improved visibility of soft-tissue specimens, while
dark-field reveals small-angle scatter from sub-resolution structures. Both
have found many biomedical and engineering applications. The previously
developed Unified Modulated Pattern Analysis (UMPA) model extracts these
modalities from wavefront-marking data. We here present a new UMPA
implementation, capable of rapidly processing large datasets and featuring
capabilities to greatly extend the field of view. We also discuss possible
artifacts and additional new features.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Marco_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Fabio De Marco&lt;/a&gt; (1,2), &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Savatovic_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Sara Savatovi&amp;#x107;&lt;/a&gt; (1,2), &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Smith_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ronan Smith&lt;/a&gt; (3), &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Trapani_V/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Vittorio Di Trapani&lt;/a&gt; (1,2), &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Margini_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Marco Margini&lt;/a&gt; (1,2), &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Lautizi_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ginevra Lautizi&lt;/a&gt; (1,2), &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Thibault_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Pierre Thibault&lt;/a&gt; (1,2) ((1) Department of Physics, University of Trieste, (2) Elettra-Sincrotrone Trieste, (3) Department of Physics, University of Southampton)</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01531">
<title>Adaptive sparse grid discontinuous Galerkin method: review and software implementation. (arXiv:2211.01531v1 [math.NA])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01531</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;This paper reviews the adaptive sparse grid discontinuous Galerkin (aSG-DG)
method for computing high dimensional partial differential equations (PDEs) and
its software implementation. The C\texttt{++} software package called AdaM-DG,
implementing the aSG-DG method, is available on Github at
\url{https://github.com/JuntaoHuang/adaptive-multiresolution-DG}. The package
is capable of treating a large class of high dimensional linear and nonlinear
PDEs. We review the essential components of the algorithm and the functionality
of the software, including the multiwavelets used, assembling of bilinear
operators, fast matrix-vector product for data with hierarchical structures. We
further demonstrate the performance of the package by reporting numerical error
and CPU cost for several benchmark test, including linear transport equations,
wave equations and Hamilton-Jacobi equations.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Huang_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Juntao Huang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Guo_W/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Wei Guo&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Cheng_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yingda Cheng&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01929">
<title>Attractors and bifurcation diagrams in complex climate models. (arXiv:2211.01929v1 [physics.ao-ph])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01929</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The climate is a complex non-equilibrium dynamical system that relaxes toward
a steady state under the continuous input of solar radiation and dissipative
mechanisms. The steady state is not necessarily unique. A useful tool to
describe the possible steady states under different forcing is the bifurcation
diagram, that reveals the regions of multi-stability, the position of tipping
points, and the range of stability of each steady state. However, its
construction is highly time consuming in climate models with a dynamical deep
ocean, interactive ice sheets or carbon cycle, where the relaxation time
becomes larger than thousand years. Using a coupled setup of MITgcm, we test
two techniques with complementary advantages. The first is based on the
introduction of random fluctuations in the forcing and permits to explore a
wide part of phase space. The second reconstructs the stable branches and is
more precise in finding the position of tipping points.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Brunetti_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Maura Brunetti&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Ragon_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Charline Ragon&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01995">
<title>Computing zero-group-velocity points in anisotropic elastic waveguides: globally and locally convergent methods. (arXiv:2211.01995v1 [physics.class-ph])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01995</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Dispersion curves of elastic waveguides exhibit points where the group
velocity vanishes while the wavenumber remains finite. These are the so-called
zero-group-velocity (ZGV) points. As the elastodynamic energy at these points
remains confined close to the source, they are of practical interest for
nondestructive testing and quantitative characterization of structures. These
applications rely on the correct prediction of the ZGV points. In this
contribution, we first model the ZGV resonances in anisotropic plates based on
the appearance of an exceptional mode. The resulting governing equation is
interpreted as a two-parameter eigenvalue problem. We then present three
complementary numerical procedures capable of computing ZGV points in arbitrary
nondissipative elastic waveguides. The first method is globally convergent and
guarantees to find all ZGV points but can only be used for small problems. The
second procedure is a very fast, generally-applicable, Newton-type iteration
that is locally convergent and requires initial guesses. The third method
combines both kind of approaches and yields a procedure that is applicable to
large problems, does not require initial guesses and is likely to find all ZGV
points.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Kiefer_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Daniel A. Kiefer&lt;/a&gt; (1), &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Plestenjak_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Bor Plestenjak&lt;/a&gt; (2), &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Gravenkamp_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Hauke Gravenkamp&lt;/a&gt; (3), &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Prada_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Claire Prada&lt;/a&gt; (1) ((1) Institut Langevin, ESPCI Paris, Universit&amp;#xe9; PSL, CNRS, Paris, France, (2) Faculty of Mathematics and Physics, University of Ljubljana, Ljubljana, Slovenia, (3) International Centre for Numerical Methods in Engineering (CIMNE), Barcelona, Spain)</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2107.09984">
<title>Chiral Dirac-like fermion in spin-orbit-free antiferromagnetic semimetals. (arXiv:2107.09984v3 [cond-mat.mtrl-sci] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2107.09984</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Dirac semimetal is a phase of matter, whose elementary excitation is
described by the relativistic Dirac equation. In the limit of zero mass, its
parity-time symmetry enforces the Dirac fermion in the momentum space, which is
composed of two Weyl fermions with opposite chirality, to be non-chiral.
Inspired by the flavor symmetry in particle physics, we theoretically propose a
massless Dirac-like equation yet linking two Weyl fields with the identical
chirality by assuming SU(2) isospin symmetry, independent of the space-time
rotation exchanging the two fields. Dramatically, such symmetry is hidden in
certain solid-state spin-1/2 systems with negligible spin-orbit coupling, where
the spin degree of freedom is decoupled with the lattice. Therefore, the
existence of the corresponding quasiparticle, dubbed as flavor Weyl fermion,
cannot be explained by the conventional (magnetic) space group framework. The
four-fold degenerate flavor Weyl fermion manifests linear dispersion and a
Chern number of 2, leading to a robust network of topologically protected Fermi
arcs throughout the Brillouin zone. For material realization, we show that the
transition-metal chalcogenide CoNb3S6 with experimentally confirmed collinear
antiferromagnetic order is ideal for flavor Weyl semimetal under the
approximation of vanishing spin-orbit coupling. Our work reveals a counterpart
of the flavor symmetry in magnetic electronic systems, leading to further
possibilities of emergent phenomena in quantum materials.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Liu_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Pengfei Liu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Zhang_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ao Zhang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Han_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jingzhi Han&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Liu_Q/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Qihang Liu&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2112.09280">
<title>Scaling dynamics of the ultra-cold Bose gas. (arXiv:2112.09280v2 [cond-mat.quant-gas] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2112.09280</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The large-scale expansion dynamics of quantum gases is a central tool for
ultra-cold gas experiments and poses a significant challenge for theory.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this work we provide an exact reformulation of the Gross-Pitaevskii
equation for the ultra-cold Bose gas in a coordinate frame that adaptively
scales with the system size during evolution, enabling simulations of long
evolution times during expansion or similar large-scale manipulation. Our
approach makes no hydrodynamic approximations, is not restricted to a scaling
ansatz, harmonic potentials, or energy eigenstates, and can be generalized
readily to non-contact interactions via the appropriate stress tensor of the
quantum fluid. As applications, we simulate the expansion of the ideal gas, a
cigar-shaped condensate in the Thomas-Fermi regime, and a linear superposition
of counter propagating Gaussian wavepackets. We recover known scaling for the
ideal gas and Thomas-Fermi regimes, and identify a linear regime of
aspect-ratio preserving free expansion; analysis of the scaling dynamics
equations shows that an exact, aspect-ratio invariant, free expansion does not
exist for nonlinear evolution. Our treatment enables exploration of nonlinear
effects in matter-wave dynamics over large scale-changing evolution.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Bradley_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ashton S. Bradley&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Clarke_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jordan Clarke&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Neely_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Tyler W. Neely&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Anderson_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Brian P Anderson&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2208.13772">
<title>Computing committors via Mahalanobis diffusion maps with enhanced sampling data. (arXiv:2208.13772v2 [physics.comp-ph] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2208.13772</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The study of phenomena such as protein folding and conformational changes in
molecules is a central theme in chemical physics. Molecular dynamics (MD)
simulation is the primary tool for the study of transition processes in
biomolecules, but it is hampered by a huge timescale gap between the processes
of interest and atomic vibrations which dictate the time step size. Therefore,
it is imperative to combine MD simulations with other techniques in order to
quantify the transition processes taking place on large timescales. In this
work, the diffusion map with Mahalanobis kernel, a meshless approach for
approximating the Backward Kolmogorov Operator (BKO) in collective variables,
is upgraded to incorporate standard enhanced sampling techniques such as
metadynamics. The resulting algorithm, which we call the &quot;target measure
Mahalanobis diffusion map&quot; (tm-mmap), is suitable for a moderate number of
collective variables in which one can approximate the diffusion tensor and free
energy. Imposing appropriate boundary conditions allows use of the approximated
BKO to solve for the committor function and utilization of transition path
theory to find the reactive current delineating the transition channels and the
transition rate. The proposed algorithm, tm-mmap, is tested on the
two-dimensional Moro-Cardin two-well system with position-dependent diffusion
coefficient and on alanine dipeptide in two collective variables where the
committor, the reactive current, and the transition rate are compared to those
computed by the finite element method (FEM). Finally, tm-mmap is applied to
alanine dipeptide in four collective variables where the use of finite elements
is infeasible.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Evans_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Luke Evans&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Cameron_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Maria K. Cameron&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Tiwary_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Pratyush Tiwary&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
</rdf:RDF>