<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>DIMENSIONLESS TECHNOLOGIES PVT.LTD.</title>
	<atom:link href="https://dimensionless.in/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://dimensionless.in</link>
	<description>Online Data Science Courses</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Jul 2020 11:46:41 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.8.5</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://dimensionless.in/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/Dimensionless-Data-Science-Training.png</url>
	<title>DIMENSIONLESS TECHNOLOGIES PVT.LTD.</title>
	<link>https://dimensionless.in</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>My Journey: From Business Analyst to Data Scientist</title>
		<link>https://dimensionless.in/career-transition-my-journey-from-business-analysis-to-data-science/</link>
					<comments>https://dimensionless.in/career-transition-my-journey-from-business-analysis-to-data-science/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Pooja Sahatiya]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2020 02:30:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Career Transitions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Data Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Career Switch Data Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Career Transition]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data science careers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data science job]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data science professional]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data science skillset]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Data Science Success Story]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[future ready careers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hardware Engineer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Learn Data Science and Business Analytics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Machine Learning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Network Engineer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Research Associate]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://dimensionless.in/?p=225333</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Good course structure and in-depth teaching were 2 key factors that impressed me at Dimensionless.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<h2>Success Story: An upgrade from Analysis to Data Science</h2>
<p>Akash Lamba was a successful Business Analyst who wanted to take the next step in advancing his career. He joined Dimensionless to switch from Business Analysis to Data Science.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">When you set out to learn a new skill, the biggest hurdle is finding the relevant content. After finding it, a bigger hurdle is learning it thoroughly.</span></i></p>
<cite>&#8211; <span style="font-weight: 400;">Akash Lamba</span></cite></blockquote>



<h3>Background</h3>



<p><strong>Education:</strong> <span style="font-weight: 400;">B.Tech. in Electronics and Telecommunications</span></p>



<table class="wp-block-table is-style-stripes">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td><strong>Previous Profile  &gt;&gt;&gt;</strong></td>
<td><strong>Current Profile</strong></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>
<p><strong>Profile: </strong><span style="font-weight: 400;">Banking Domain</span></p>
<p><strong>Designation: </strong><span style="font-weight: 400;">Senior Business Analyst </span></p>
<strong>Experience: </strong><span style="font-weight: 400;">2 years and 3 months</span></td>
<td>
<p><strong>Profile: </strong><span style="font-weight: 400;">Data Scientist</span></p>
<p><strong>Designation: </strong><span style="font-weight: 400;">Tableau Consultant</span></p>
<p><strong>Domain:</strong> <span style="font-weight: 400;"> Manufacturing</span></p>
</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>



<div class="wp-block-spacer" style="height: 32px;" aria-hidden="true"> </div>



<h3>My journey into Data Science<br /><br /></h3>



<h4>Why Data Science?</h4>



<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Being a Business Analyst, I was aware that many companies have centred their businesses on data. The demand for Data professionals was going to only increase. The future is bright in data-related profiles and I can see a secure future for myself. After some experience as a Business Analyst, Data Science would be the perfect next step for a career-upgrade. So, I was sure of getting into Data Science.</span></p>



<h4>Why Dimensionless?</h4>



<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">When you set out to learn a new skill, the biggest hurdle is finding the relevant content. After finding it, a bigger hurdle is learning it thoroughly.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I did my own research over a couple of days. I came across many courses and after going through many data science courses online I landed on Dimensionless website. When I had a word with a Dimensionless mentor, who reserved a seat for me at their Demo Class. Coming from a similar background, I could judge their knowledge and course curriculum. At the time, Dimensionless was the only class offering the flexibility of time (post-work and weekend classes), a holistic curriculum and mentor-led classes. I decided to sign-up for the ‘Data Science Specialization Course with Python and R’ at Dimensionless. </span></p>



<h4>Experience with Dimensionless?</h4>



<p>My experience with Dimensionless was excellent. All the topics were very well-taught and in-depth concepts are covered. The best thing is that I could resolve doubts instantly during the live sessions. The mentors were very friendly and made sure everyone&#8217;s doubts were cleared. In fact, they have always happily helped me with my issues even after the course was completed.<br /><br />Dimensionless makes learning interesting by explaining the concepts well with practical implementation simultaneously. They allow you to attend different classes if you want to expedite your learning or missed any class. HR is very supportive in giving placement assistance and also gives personal attention to build up the resume as well. I definitely recommend Dimensionless to everyone and anyone who is serious about Data Science.</p>



<h3>Career Transition to Data Science</h3>



<p>During the last 1 month of the course, with the help of project mentoring and resume-building activities at Dimensionless, I updated my profile. After my resume-building was completed, I started searching for internships in Data Science and finally ended up in a start-up as a Data Science Intern. After completing my internship for 5 months I again started applying for jobs.</p>
<p>With the help of Dimensionless network and placement assistance, I was able to apply to many companies for Data Science. After circulating my resume and interviewing in my companies I finally got my first job in the Data Science field as a Tableau Consultant. I always loved visualizing data with business domain knowledge and really got lucky to get into my field of interest. </p>



<figure class="wp-block-pullquote">
<blockquote>
<p>Thanks to Dimensionless for supporting me from a time with no job in hand to a time where I finally got my job.</p>
</blockquote>
</figure>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>There are many more like Akash who have switched to Data Science from different domains. Read their <a href="https://dimensionless.in/category/career-transitions/">success stories here</a>.</p>
<p>Want to know whether such a Career Transition is possible for you?<br /><strong>Follow this </strong><a href="http://dimensionless.in/"><strong>link</strong></a>, and make it possible with <a href="http://dimensionless.in">Dimensionless Techademy</a>!</p>



<p>Furthermore, if you want to read more about data science, you can <strong>read our blogs </strong><a href="http://dimensionless.in/blog"><strong>here</strong></a><strong>.</strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>


]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://dimensionless.in/career-transition-my-journey-from-business-analysis-to-data-science/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Test Engineer to Data Science: Career Switch</title>
		<link>https://dimensionless.in/test-engineer-data-science/</link>
					<comments>https://dimensionless.in/test-engineer-data-science/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Pooja Sahatiya]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2020 07:10:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Career Transitions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Data Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Career Switch Data Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Career Transition]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data science careers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data science job]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data science professional]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data science skillset]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Data Science Success Story]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[future ready careers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hardware Engineer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Learn Data Science and Business Analytics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Machine Learning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Network Engineer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Research Associate]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://dimensionless.in/?p=219134</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[My actual Data Science journey began the day I decided to switch careers and enrolled with Dimensionless.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<h2>My Journey: From Test Engineer to Data Science</h2>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p>Correct Guidance is the key to a successful Career Switch. That&#8217;s how I was able to cover the journey of Test Engineer to Data Science.</p>
<cite>&#8211; <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/megha-kansal-711700115/">Megha Kansal</a></cite></blockquote>



<h3>Background</h3>



<p><strong>Education:</strong> B Tech IT</p>



<table class="wp-block-table is-style-stripes" style="height: 139px;" width="478">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td><strong>Previous Profile  &gt;&gt;&gt;</strong></td>
<td><strong>Current Profile</strong></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>
<p>Profile: <strong>Test Engineer</strong><br />Designation: Test Lead<br />Experience: 3 years</p>
</td>
<td>
<p>Profile: <strong>Data Scientist<br /></strong>Designation: Manager &#8211; Data Science</p>
</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>



<div class="wp-block-spacer" style="height: 32px;" aria-hidden="true"> </div>



<h3>My journey into Data Science</h3>



<h4>Why Data Science?</h4>



<p>Frankly, I started finding my job a bit monotonous. Testing was a lucrative career a few years back, but with new technologies coming in, I wanted to explore the possibility of upskilling and switching careers. I spoke to friends and researched a bit about Data Science. Since I was not from a coding background, I really worried whether I could learn to code efficiently. I tried to understand R and Python on my own. There were 2 things I found out: the languages are basically plain English, easy to understand, and I will definitely need guidance because Data Science is much more than just learning a language.</p>



<h4>Why Dimensionless?</h4>



<p>I had enquired in a lot of institutes. While the curriculum and other offerings were perfect, there was one particular detail for which I was convinced to join Dimensionless. I did not want to learn with 40-50 other people in a class, where the teacher hardly has any time to interact or resolve doubts. There was one institute which said that they have around 120 people in one batch! Dimensionless promised to not have more than 20 people in one batch! </p>
<p>Also, when I spoke to one of the mentors, he carefully studied my background and made me understand my career transition path in the first call itself. It gave me the confidence to finally pursue Data Science. I enrolled with Dimensionless for their next batch.</p>



<h4>Experience with Dimensionless?</h4>



<p>Really good. The classes were very interactive. Teachers ensured that everyone participated in the class. They would ask us to answer in individually and explain patiently whenever we were wrong or were confused. It hardly felt like a virtual classroom. Mentors were always available to have a word or discuss any doubts we had.</p>



<h3>Career Transition to Data Science</h3>



<p>For cracking interviews in Data Science, or any Tech, it is essential you have hands-on knowledge. To practice on real-time projects, I started practising Data Science techniques I had learnt in Dimensionless in my then-current project. Another thing that helped was the Resume Upgrading sessions and Case Studies given by Dimensionless.</p>
<p>I got a lot of exposure and confidence for interviews. Almost 5-6 job openings were shared every day by the Dimensionless Team. It took me some time but I finally started hearing back from good companies. I got offers from SpectraMedix, Genpact and Excel. My current company wanted to retain me and they offered me an internal transfer. That&#8217;s where my Data Science journey began.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-pullquote">
<blockquote>
<p>My actual Data Science journey began the day I decided to switch careers and enrolled with Dimensionless.</p>
</blockquote>
</figure>
<p>There are many more like Megha who switched to Data Science from different domains. Read their <a href="https://dimensionless.in/category/career-transitions/">success stories here</a>.</p>
<p>Want to know whether such a Career Transition is possible for you?<br /><strong>Follow this </strong><a href="http://dimensionless.in/"><strong>link</strong></a>, and make it possible with <a href="http://dimensionless.in">Dimensionless Techademy</a>!</p>



<p>Furthermore, if you want to read more about data science, you can <strong>read our blogs </strong><a href="http://dimensionless.in/blog"><strong>here</strong></a><strong>.</strong></p>


]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://dimensionless.in/test-engineer-data-science/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Data Engineer to Data Scientist : Career Switch</title>
		<link>https://dimensionless.in/career-transition-data-engineer-data-scientist/</link>
					<comments>https://dimensionless.in/career-transition-data-engineer-data-scientist/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Pooja Sahatiya]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2020 10:00:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Career Transitions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Data Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Career Switch Data Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Career Transition]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data science careers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data science job]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data science professional]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data science skillset]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Data Science Success Story]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[future ready careers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hardware Engineer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Learn Data Science and Business Analytics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Machine Learning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Network Engineer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Research Associate]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://dimensionless.in/?p=218662</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Good course structure and in-depth teaching were 2 key factors that impressed me at Dimensionless.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<h2>Success Story: Switching from Data Engineer to Data Scientist</h2>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p>I believe anyone with patience, passion and guidance can learn Data Science.</p>
<cite>&#8211; Kranthi Bandi</cite></blockquote>



<h3>Background</h3>



<p><strong>Education:</strong> M. Tech Mobile and Satellite Communications</p>



<table class="wp-block-table is-style-stripes">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td><strong>Previous Profile  &gt;&gt;&gt;</strong></td>
<td><strong>Current Profile</strong></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Designation: <br />Profile: Data Engineer<br />Domain: Enterprise Software<br />Experience: 3 years</td>
<td>
<p>Designation: <br />Profile: <strong>Data Scientist</strong><br />Domain: Enterprise Software<br /><br /></p>
</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>



<div class="wp-block-spacer" style="height: 32px;" aria-hidden="true"> </div>



<h3>My journey into Data Science<br /><br /></h3>



<h4>Why Data Science?</h4>



<p>Being a Data Engineer, I always felt like I belonged to the field of Data. I could see how the tech was moving. All the businesses are becoming Data-oriented and automation is the need of the hour. Once Cloud Technology is stable, Artificial Intelligence is going to dominate the trend. During my Masters, I had Statistics as a subject and used it heavily in a project. My Masters’ thesis was with MATLAB, using concepts and fundamentals of Data Science.</p>
<p>So, I was sure of getting into Data Science. </p>



<h4>Why Dimensionless?</h4>



<p>While looking for a program, the only challenge was finding a class with a well-balanced curriculum. I tried understanding the curriculum of a lot of classes, some of them had a very high-level curriculum while others were not covering any relevant knowledge. Also, I did not want to go to any well-known classes because teachers aren’t able to give personalized attention.</p>
<p>Since this is a serious subject, the only way I could be sure about any course would be if a credible source vouched for it. A friend (an ex-student of Dimensionless) strongly recommended the Data Science course from Dimensionless. Their curriculum was balanced for anyone who wanted to start in Data Science. In fact, the first demo I attended was on Statistics. It is essential to start with Statistics and Mathematics to grasp Data Science fully.</p>
<p>If you see the progression, going from being a Data Engineer to being Data Scientist was an obvious step forward.</p>



<h4>Experience with Dimensionless?</h4>



<p>Good course structure and in-depth teaching were 2 key factors that impressed me at Dimensionless. Learning Data Science takes time and effort from both the teacher and the students. We got that at Dimensionless. </p>
<p>Also, people coming from a Data background are usually weak at programming. The teachers made it easy for us to understand and learn Python. </p>
<p>The teachers covered a lot of ground for all the subjects and they were always available for clearing our doubts. I was satisfied with the course structure and the teaching method.</p>



<h3>Career Transition to Data Science</h3>



<p>Luckily, in my previous company, they were building an AI team and testing various projects. At the end of the course, I got support from Dimensionless to prepare with Mock Interviews.</p>
<p>I applied to be a part of the AI Team at my company and got selected through a written test and interview. The exposure was immense. I got to work on multiple projects from scratch. We discussed Use Cases and projects in-depth, covering even the business aspects of it. </p>
<p>After that, I knew I could comfortably face any Data Science or AI interview. </p>



<figure class="wp-block-pullquote">
<blockquote>
<p>Now, if anyone asks me how much time it takes to become a Data Scientist, I first ask them “How dedicated are you?”.</p>
</blockquote>
</figure>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>There are many more like Kranthi who have switched to Data Science from different domains. Read their <a href="https://dimensionless.in/category/career-transitions/">success stories here</a>.</p>
<p>Want to know whether such a Career Transition is possible for you?<br /><strong>Follow this </strong><a href="http://dimensionless.in/"><strong>link</strong></a>, and make it possible with <a href="http://dimensionless.in">Dimensionless Techademy</a>!</p>



<p>Furthermore, if you want to read more about data science, you can <strong>read our blogs </strong><a href="http://dimensionless.in/blog"><strong>here</strong></a><strong>.</strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>


]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://dimensionless.in/career-transition-data-engineer-data-scientist/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Data Science Trend Forecast: 2020</title>
		<link>https://dimensionless.in/2020-trends-data-science/</link>
					<comments>https://dimensionless.in/2020-trends-data-science/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Samadrita Ghosh]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2019 23:50:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Data Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trending]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[2019]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[2019 trends]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Big Data]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BlockChain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cloud Computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data science careers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Data Science Trends]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://dimensionless.in/?p=218409</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Taking into consideration the positive trends of Data Science from previous years, there lies an immense well of possibilities that awaits us in the future, that is, the upcoming year 2020. Some of these Data Science Trend Forecast for 2020 can be foreseen as follows: Augmented Analysis Complicated code and extensions will no longer be [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Taking into consideration the positive trends of <a href="https://dimensionless.in/2019-trends-data-science/">Data Science from previous years</a>, there lies an immense well of possibilities that awaits us in the future, that is, the upcoming year 2020. Some of these Data Science Trend Forecast for 2020 can be foreseen as follows:</p>
<ul>
<li>
<h4>Augmented Analysis</h4>
</li>
</ul>
<p>Complicated code and extensions will no longer be required to get deep insights from data. The augmented analysis helps layman users/analysts (in machine learning/data science) to make use of AI to analyze data. This will change the way data is consumed, created and shared across all data-intensive fields. Already several BI and analytics tools are trying to implement AI assistance full force in their platforms.</p>
<ul>
<li>
<h4>Continuous/ Real-time Intelligence</h4>
</li>
</ul>
<p>There is intensive activity ongoing every second in real-time platforms. If through some method, one can plug into this data, real-time user experience can be enhanced manifold. Continuous or real-time intelligence aims to do just that by analyzing data in real-time so that instant results can be provided to the user while he is still surfing the platform. It can also help increase profit margins by re-aligning the platform as per the observed interaction of the user.</p>
<ul>
<li>
<h4>NLP</h4>
</li>
</ul>
<p>Natural Language Processing is a very important segment of Artificial Intelligence since most real-world data are in text or voice format. To process such data, advanced NLP techniques are required which are being innovated with each passing data. Today, we can read, understand, classify and even create unique text documents with the help of machines. Further developments like intelligent summarization, entity recognition and task management using text input and much more are expected to happen, owing to the intense research and increasing data-science experts choosing NLP specialisation.</p>
<ul>
<li>
<h4>Conversational technology</h4>
</li>
</ul>
<p>There has already been a visible surge in the performance of voice assistants in 2019. In 2020, it is expected to further improve such that the conversational systems become more sensitive to the human language and also more humane in their response. By more humane, it will mean that the systems can keep track of previous responses and questions (which is not a very developed feature in any voice assistant in the market to this day). Also, most client interactions are expected to be taken over by conversational technology, thus, increasing response rate and efficiency.</p>
<ul>
<li>
<h4>Explainable AI</h4>
</li>
</ul>
<p>The last decade has seen massive growth in AI aided decisions for sure, but it has been a persistent problem to be able to explain these decisions or why the AI wants to go a certain way instead of another. Recently, however, a lot of research has increased the scope of explainable AI. 2020 can further be invested in understanding problems like say, how and why a certain neural network arrived at a certain decision. This will indefinitely increase the faith of clients on adolescent technology.</p>
<ul>
<li>
<h4>Persistent memory/ In-memory computation</h4>
</li>
</ul>
<p>In-memory computing or IMC can deliver extremely high-performance tasks due to optimized memory architecture. It also has become more feasible due to the decreasing expense of memory which owes credit to constantly emerging innovations.</p>
<ul>
<li>
<h4>Data Fabric</h4>
</li>
</ul>
<p>Data Fabric helps in the smooth access and sharing of data in distributed environments. It is usually custom made and helps in the transfer and store of data, data pipelines, APIs and previously used data services that have a chance of being re-invoked. Trusted and efficient data fabric can help to catalyze data science pipelines and reduce delays in customer-client interaction/iterations.</p>
<ul>
<li>
<h4>Advances in Quantum Computing</h4>
</li>
</ul>
<p>The research in Quantum Computing has a very high momentum at the moment. Even though the whole architecture of Quantum computing is at a very basic stage, increased investments and research are helping the field to grow by inches every passing day. A quantum computer is said to perform calculations which will take general computers a few years, in just a few seconds! As remarkable as it sounds, it can bestow superpowers to mankind! Imagine munching on years and years of historical data to arrive at conclusions about the future in just a few seconds. A whole lot of astonishing things await us, and we must be blessed to be a part of this century.</p>
<p>It is expected that India’s job openings in the analytics sector will double to about 200000 or two lakh jobs in 2020. Here is what 2020 for job seekers in data science will look like:</p>
<ul>
<li>Fields like finance, IT, professional services and insurance will see a boom in demand for data science and analytics.</li>
<li>Having analytics skills like MapReduce, Apache Pig, Machine learning and Hadoop can provide an edge over other competitors in the field. The most fundamental in-demand skills will be Python and Machine Learning. Statistics is an added advantage.</li>
<li>Vacancies for roles like data developers, data engineers and data scientists will go over 700,000 by 2020.</li>
<li>The most promising sectors that will tend to create increasing opportunities include Aviation, Agriculture, Security, Healthcare and Automation.</li>
<li>The average salaries in India in development roles like Data Scientist or Data Engineer will range from 5 to 8 Lakh per annum.</li>
<li>The average salaries in India in management/strategizing roles like data architect or business intelligence manager will range from 10 to 20 Lakh per annum.</li>
</ul>
<p>As exciting as all of it sounds, there is always a bag of unforeseen advancements that are bound to take us all by surprise, as has always happened with Data Science and AI in the past. So, hold tight for yet another mind-boggling ride through the lanes of technology this 2020!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://dimensionless.in/2020-trends-data-science/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Best of 2019 Trends in Data Science</title>
		<link>https://dimensionless.in/2019-trends-data-science/</link>
					<comments>https://dimensionless.in/2019-trends-data-science/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Samadrita Ghosh]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2019 14:45:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Data Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trending]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[2019]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[2019 trends]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Big Data]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BlockChain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cloud Computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data science careers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Data Science Trends]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://dimensionless.in/?p=218402</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Data Science has seen a massive boom in the past few years. It has also been claimed that it is indefinitely one of the fastest-growing fields in the IT/academic sector. One of the most hyped Trends in Data Science this year was that the sector saw a major hike in jobs as compared to the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Data Science has seen a massive boom in the past few years. It has also been claimed that it is indefinitely one of the fastest-growing fields in the IT/academic sector. One of the most hyped Trends in Data Science this year was that the sector saw a major hike in jobs as compared to the past years!</p>
<p>Such an unprecedented growth owes all its dues to the unimaginable benefits that artificial intelligence has brought to the plate of mankind for the very first time. It was never before imagined that external machines could aid us with such sophistication as is present today. Owing to this, it is imperative that an individual, irrespective of his/her calling, must have at least a superficial knowledge about the past advances and future possibilities of this field of study. Even if it is the job of scientists and engineers to figure out solutions using machine learning and data science, the solutions, undoubtedly is bound to affect all our lives in the upcoming years. Moreover, if you are planning to plug into the huge well of job openings in data science, exploring the past and upcoming trends in this field will surely take you a step ahead.</p>
<p>Looking back on the achievements of the year 2019, there is much which has happened. Here is a brief glimpse of what Trends in Data Science of 2019 looked like:</p>
<ul>
<li>
<h4>Accessible AI</h4>
</li>
</ul>
<p>The once-popular belief that AI technology was only meant for high-scale and high-tech industries, is now an old wives’ tale. AI has spread so rapidly across every phase of our lives, that sometimes we do not even realize that we are being aided by AI. For instance, recommendations that we get on online forums are something we have become very used to in recent times. However, very few have the conscious knowledge that the recommendations are regulated by AI technology. There are also several instances where a layman can use AI to get optimized outputs, like in automated machine learning pipelines. We even have improvised AI-aided security systems, music systems and voice assistants in our very homes! Overall, the impact of AI in everyday lives saw a massive boost in 2019, and it is only bound to increase.</p>
<ul>
<li>
<h4>The rapid growth of IoT products</h4>
</li>
</ul>
<p>As was already forecasted, the number of machines/devices which came online in 2019 was immense. Billions were invested in research to back the uprising IoT industry. Today it is nothing out of the ordinary to control home appliances like television and air conditioners with our smartphones or lock our and unlock our cars from even the opposite end of the globe. Bringing devices online not only makes the user experience far smoother but also generates crucial data for analysis. With such data, several unopened gates can be explored across several domains. The investments and count of IoT devices are expected to go up at an increasing rate in the upcoming years.</p>
<ul>
<li>
<h4>Evolution of Predictive Analysis</h4>
</li>
</ul>
<p>The concept of predictive analysis is to use past data to learn recurring patterns, such that it can predict outcomes of future events based on the patterns learnt. Today, with increasing data it becomes extensively important to make use of optimized predictive solutions. Big data comes into picture here and significant advancements have been made in 2019 about it. Tools like PySpark and MLLib have helped scale simple predictive solutions to extensive data.</p>
<ul>
<li>
<h4>Migration of Dark Data</h4>
</li>
</ul>
<p>Dark data is very old data which has probably been sitting in obsolete archives like old systems or even files in storage rooms! There is a general understanding that such unexplored data can show us the way to crucial insights about past trends which can help grab useful opportunities and even avoid unwanted loopholes. Therefore, there has been visible initiatives to make dark data more available to present-day systems with the help of efficient storage and migration tools.</p>
<ul>
<li>
<h4>Implementation of Regulations</h4>
</li>
</ul>
<p>In 2018, General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) brought in a few data governance rules to emphasize the importance of data governance. The rules were laid down so fast that even at the year-end, several companies dealing with data are still trying to comply wholly with all the principles laid down. These principles have not only created a standard for data consumption and data handling domains but are also bound to shape the future of data handling with great impact.</p>
<ul>
<li>
<h4>DataOps</h4>
</li>
</ul>
<p>DataOps is an initiative to bring in some order in the way the data science pipeline functions. It is essentially a reflection of agile and DevOps methods in the field of data science. In 2019, it has been one of the major concerns of management in data science to integrate DataOps into their respective teams. Previously, such integration was not possible since the generic pipeline was still in making or under research. However, now, with a more robust structure, integrating DataOps can mean wonders for data science teams.</p>
<ul>
<li>
<h4>Edge Computing</h4>
</li>
</ul>
<p>As stated by Gartner, Inc. cloud computing and edge computing has evolved to become a complementary model in 2019. Edge computing goes by the concept of “more the proximity (or closeness to the source of computation), better is the efficiency”. Edge computing allows workloads to be located closer to the consumers and thus, reduces latency several-fold.</p>
<p>There is, however, a huge recurring gap when it comes to the need and availability of skilled people who can launch and contribute to these developments significantly. India contributed to 6% of job openings worldwide in 2019, which scales to around 97000 jobs!</p>
<p>The job trends of 2019 looked as follows:</p>
<ul>
<li>BFSI sector had a massive demand for analytics professionals, followed by the e-commerce and telecom sectors. The banking and financial sectors continued to have high demand throughout.</li>
<li>Python served as a great skill to attract employers to skilled job seekers</li>
<li>A 2% increase in jobs offering over 15 Lakh per annum was observed</li>
<li>Also, 21% of jobs demanded young talent in data science, a great contrast to all previous years. 70% of job openings were for professionals with less than 5 years of experience.</li>
<li>The top in-demand designations were Analytics Manager, Business Analyst, Research Analyst, Data Analyst, SAS Analyst, Analytics Consultants, Statistical Analyst and Hadoop Developer</li>
<li>Big data skills like Hadoop and Spark were extremely in demand due to the growing rate of data.</li>
<li>Telecom industry saw a fall in demand for data science professionals.</li>
<li>The median salary of analytics jobs was just over 11 Lakh per annum.</li>
</ul>
<p>On to <a href="https://dimensionless.in/2020-trends-data-science/">2020 now</a>!</p>
<p>Read more of our blogs <a href="http://dimensionless.in/blog/">here</a>!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://dimensionless.in/2019-trends-data-science/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>MBA to Data Science: Career Transition</title>
		<link>https://dimensionless.in/career-transition-data-science-mba/</link>
					<comments>https://dimensionless.in/career-transition-data-science-mba/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Pooja Sahatiya]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2019 15:23:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Career Transitions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Data Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Career Switch Data Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Career Transition]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data science careers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data science job]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data science professional]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data science skillset]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Data Science Success Story]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[future ready careers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hardware Engineer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Learn Data Science and Business Analytics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Machine Learning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Network Engineer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Research Associate]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://dimensionless.in/?p=216526</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Dimensionless ensured that my journey from MBA to Data Science was a succcessful one.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<h2>Career Jump from MBA to Data Science Success Story</h2>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p>Knowledge is what matters the most in the industry. </p>
<cite><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/karthik-sripati-686370129/">&#8211; Karthik Sripati</a></cite></blockquote>



<h3>Background</h3>



<p><strong>Education:</strong> Masters in Business Administration</p>



<table class="wp-block-table is-style-stripes">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td><strong>Previous Profile  &gt;&gt;&gt;</strong></td>
<td><strong>Current Profile</strong></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Company: Amazon State Street Syntel<br />Profile: <strong>Operations </strong><br />Designation: Deputy Manager<br />Domain: BFSI<br />Experience: 2.2 years</td>
<td>Company: Google<br />Profile: Data Analysis<br />Designation: <strong>Deputy Manager</strong><br />Domain: KPO (IT) Software</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>



<div class="wp-block-spacer" style="height: 32px" aria-hidden="true"> </div>



<h3>My journey into Data Science<br /><br /></h3>



<h4>Why Data Science?</h4>



<p>During my MBA days, or even when I was working at Amazon State Street Syntel, I kept hearing about AI &amp; Data Science and the new projects that were coming up. Everyone always got excited when they spoke about Data Science. I was always good at Maths. Coming from a background of Business Studies, data crunching and data analysis always fascinated me. I wanted to have a holistic point of view of the business trends and future forecasting.</p>



<p>I understood that Data Science focuses on Problem Solving, Analytical Skills and Domain Knowledge. In my job also, I was working on Reporting and business analysis. So, that’s where my liking to Data Science began.</p>



<h4>Why Dimensionless?</h4>



<p>I did a lot of research to find the perfect classes. I checked their reviews and contacted a couple of students who had done their course to be doubly sure and they all verified that the teachers would deep dive into the subjects and give individual attention to all students.</p>



<p>After a discussion based on my profile with the mentors, I was able to get beyond my fears of programming.</p>



<p>In the Demo sessions, I liked their teaching method and the teacher’s knowledge. And, that’s what mattered the most for me.</p>



<h4>Experience with Dimensionless?</h4>



<p>I was never into any technical role, never even had any technical subjects. Really, I didn’t know how I was going to cope with the coding bit. It was difficult at the start. The classes progressed and I found it easier to understand Python and Machine Learning. By the end of the course, I got quite good at coding. I asked a lot of doubts in the classes and the teachers were always ready to help.</p>



<h3>Career Transition to Data Science</h3>



<p>With the help of project mentoring and resume-building activities at Dimensionless, I updated my profile. They suggested the apt projects and skills for adding to my profile, which made it a bit relevant to my domain knowledge too. <br />Frankly, I thought I will have to give a lot of interviews before I crack one. After a walk-in interview, I got the idea about the kind of questions asked in Data Science interviews. I nailed it in the next interview and got placed to a position similar to my previous one.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-pullquote">
<blockquote>
<p>I’ve learnt from my personal experience that most businesses look for capable people and not certifications.</p>
</blockquote>
</figure>



<p>Do you also want a career transition like Karthik? <br /><strong>Follow this </strong><a href="http://dimensionless.in/"><strong>link</strong></a>, and make it possible with Dimensionless Techademy!</p>



<p>Furthermore, if you want to read more about data science, you can <strong>read our blogs </strong><a href="http://dimensionless.in/blog"><strong>here</strong></a><strong>.</strong></p>



<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://dimensionless.in/career-transition-data-science-mba/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Database Management to Data Science: Career Switch</title>
		<link>https://dimensionless.in/career-switch-data-science-database-management/</link>
					<comments>https://dimensionless.in/career-switch-data-science-database-management/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Pooja Sahatiya]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2019 05:08:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Career Transitions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Data Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Career Switch Data Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Career Transition]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data science careers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data science job]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data science professional]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data science skillset]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Data Science Success Story]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[future ready careers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hardware Engineer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Learn Data Science and Business Analytics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Machine Learning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Network Engineer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Research Associate]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://dimensionless.in/?p=216495</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Dimensionless gave me the confidence to move to Data Science even after 8 years in Database Management. My career transition to Data Science went smoothly.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<h2>Career Transition from Team Lead, Database Management to Data Scientist</h2>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p>I believe it’s never too late to learn and move to a better technology. </p>
<cite><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/ruchi-saboo-5126287a/">&#8211; </a><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/vikash-kumar-prakash-03850179/">Vikash Kumar Prakash</a></cite></blockquote>



<h3>Background</h3>



<p><strong>Education:</strong> B. Tech in Computer Science</p>



<table class="wp-block-table is-style-stripes">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td><strong>Previous Profile  &gt;&gt;&gt;</strong></td>
<td><strong>Current Profile</strong></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Company: BNY Melon<br />Profile: <strong>Oracle, PL/SQL Developer</strong><br />Designation: Team Lead, Database Management<br />Domain: Finance<br />Experience: 8 years</td>
<td>Company: Barclays<br />Profile: <strong>Data Analyst</strong><br />Designation: Team Lead<br />Domain: Finance</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>



<div class="wp-block-spacer" style="height: 32px" aria-hidden="true"> </div>



<h3>My journey into Data Science<br /><br /></h3>



<h4>Why Data Science?</h4>



<p>There wasn’t much growth in PL/SQL and Database Management after a certain level. After reaching that level and giving about 8 years to one technology, and it was scary to move to newer technology. So I started looking at how I could build on stuff I already knew. I knew how to use and store the data. Now, I was more interested in the business side of it. I was interested in predictive analytics to help businesses apply this data and get insights from it. Data Science would help me do that. Because of this interest, Machine Learning and Data Science was an obvious choice.</p>



<h4>Why Dimensionless?</h4>



<p>One of my trusted friends did his course from Dimensionless and recommended it to me. He too was able to transition from Database Management to Data Science.</p>



<p>After checking out the course myself, I found it to be good in every aspect. My main issue was timings, but they provided the flexibility of attending classes in the morning or evening. Plus, there were weekend classes which covered the most syllabus. The faculty looked promising since they were all from Machine Learning background, they had worked in this technology. After the Demo, I was convinced completely.</p>



<h4>Experience with Dimensionless?</h4>



<p>I had a very good experience with Dimensionless. One thing I really liked was that the faculty gave equal attention to all the students. Even the doubts were resolved quickly by the teachers. Any issues we had were discussed either in the lecture itself or personally too.<br />We got assignments and case studies that helped us get hands-on experience in the applications of Data Science, which was the most interesting part for me.</p>



<h3>Career Transition to Data Science</h3>



<p>After the course was done, I started giving interviews. The Placement Assistance really helped me here. Right from resume preparation to mock interviews, Dimensionless prepared us for everything. We were given a set of questions to prepare from and then mock interview would be held. I think these activities boosted my confidence more than anything else.</p>



<p>Within 2 months after the course, I got placed in Barclays as a Data Analyst with R and Python.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-pullquote">
<blockquote>
<p>Dedicating time to learning new tech is the best way out of an outdated job, no matter how much experience you have. In Data Science, as well as every other advanced technology, the main thing that matters is practical knowledge.</p>
</blockquote>
</figure>



<p>Do you also want career transition like <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/vikash-kumar-prakash-03850179/"><strong>Vikash</strong></a>? <br /><strong>Follow this </strong><a href="http://dimensionless.in/"><strong>link</strong></a>, and make it possible with Dimensionless Techademy!</p>



<p>Furthermore, if you want to read more about data science, you can <strong>read our blogs </strong><a href="http://dimensionless.in/blog"><strong>here</strong></a><strong>.</strong></p>



<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://dimensionless.in/career-switch-data-science-database-management/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>System Engineer to Data Science: Growth Journey</title>
		<link>https://dimensionless.in/career-transition-data-science-system-engineer/</link>
					<comments>https://dimensionless.in/career-transition-data-science-system-engineer/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Pooja Sahatiya]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2019 06:59:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Career Transitions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Data Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Career Switch Data Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Career Transition]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data science careers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data science job]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data science professional]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data science skillset]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Data Science Success Story]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[future ready careers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hardware Engineer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Learn Data Science and Business Analytics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Machine Learning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Network Engineer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Research Associate]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://dimensionless.in/?p=216489</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Dimensionless ensured that my journey from being a System Engineer to Data Science was a succcessful one.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<h2>Career Transition from <br />System Engineer to Data Science Success Story</h2>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p>You are judged based on practical knowledge, regardless of past experience. </p>
<cite><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/ruchi-saboo-5126287a/">&#8211; Ruchi Saboo</a></cite></blockquote>



<h3>Background</h3>



<p><strong>Education:</strong> B. Engineering in Computer Science</p>



<table class="wp-block-table is-style-stripes">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td><strong>Previous Profile  &gt;&gt;&gt;</strong></td>
<td><strong>Current Profile</strong></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Company: Amdocs<br />Profile: <strong>SQL, UNIX Developer</strong><br /><strong>(Ordering and Billing)</strong><br />Designation: System Engineer<br />Domain: Telecom<br />Experience: 2 years</td>
<td>Company: TSystems <br />Designation: <strong>Consultant</strong><br />Profile: <strong>Data Science</strong><br />Designation: Data Scientist<br />Domain: Telecom</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>



<div class="wp-block-spacer" style="height: 32px" aria-hidden="true"> </div>



<h3>My journey into Data Science<br /><br /></h3>



<h4>Why Data Science?</h4>



<p>Day by day, the technology is evolving. I didn’t see myself getting the career growth I wanted with the technology I was working on before (SQL/UNIX). As anyone in IT would know, having a job as a System Engineer in SQL/UNIX these days is very mundane. I thought I wouldn’t survive for long. That was the main motivation to keep myself updated with the latest tech.</p>



<p>When it came to choosing the new tech, I found myself being more keen towards Data Science. It’s very interesting and insightful. It called to my intellectual side. It’s like you’re creatively playing with data and getting business results.</p>



<h4>Why Dimensionless?</h4>



<p>It’s a funny story. When I decided to go with Data Science, I enrolled in a classroom course mainly because I was never comfortable with Online Classes. It was mostly theory and my experience was neutral. <br />Since I was already working as a System Engineer using SQL, I had the database part covered at my end.</p>



<p>It was only when I started giving interviews, that I realized that their course curriculum and faculty was sub-par. A lot of the interview questions asked were not even covered in the lectures. When I went back to them with these doubts, they said it was out of syllabus.<br />Then I tried to learn by myself. I checked out some free courses.</p>



<p>In one of my interviews, I met this guy. He was a fellow candidate and he seemed pretty confident. We got to talking and he told me that he did a Data Science specialization course from Dimensionless. He was so satisfied with the course that I could feel his genuineness. Obviously, I got very excited to know more about Dimensionless.</p>



<p>Next thing I did was I spoke to their counsellors and joined in the next batch itself.</p>



<h4>Experience with Dimensionless?</h4>



<p>TBH, before taking up this course with Dimensionless, I was convinced that I can only learn properly in a physical classroom. I thought physical classrooms provide more support and are more accessible. Now I am much more comfortable in online training. Online or offline, if the teachers are good and doubts are handled, it doesn’t matter. It was so comfortable to attend classes from anywhere.</p>



<p>I knew why that guy in the interview was so happy with Dimensionless. The doubt-solving was quick. Teachers were available on call too. The sessions had a lot of communication and they were interactive overall. The course content was practical and easy to follow too.</p>



<h3>Career Transition to Data Science</h3>



<p>After completing the course in 5 months, I did some more self-study because I thought why someone would select me over an experienced Data Science professional.  I delayed applying for jobs. Finally, after some moral support from their mentors and mock interviews with Dimensionless HR, I built up the courage to apply for jobs and give interviews. Among other companies, I applied at TSystems, Wipro and Capegemini, and I got selected in all three!!! Imagine my excitement.</p>



<p>When I started giving interviews I realized that interviewers judge you based on knowledge and not past experience.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-pullquote">
<blockquote>
<p>In Data Science, as well as every other advanced technology, the main thing that matters is practical knowledge.</p>
</blockquote>
</figure>



<p>Do you also want career transition like <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/ruchi-saboo-5126287a/">Ruchi</a>? <br /><strong>Follow this </strong><a href="http://dimensionless.in/"><strong>link</strong></a>, and make it possible with Dimensionless Techademy!</p>



<p>Furthermore, if you want to read more about data science, you can <strong>read our blogs </strong><a href="http://dimensionless.in/blog"><strong>here</strong></a><strong>.</strong></p>



<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://dimensionless.in/career-transition-data-science-system-engineer/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Network Engineer to Machine Learning Engineer</title>
		<link>https://dimensionless.in/career-transition-data-science-network-engineer/</link>
					<comments>https://dimensionless.in/career-transition-data-science-network-engineer/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Pooja Sahatiya]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2019 09:46:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Career Transitions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Data Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Career Switch Data Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Career Transition]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data science careers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data science job]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data science professional]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data science skillset]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Data Science Success Story]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[future ready careers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hardware Engineer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Learn Data Science and Business Analytics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Machine Learning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Network Engineer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Research Associate]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://dimensionless.in/?p=216460</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I got shortlisted for multiple companies for Data Science job roles, one of them was through Dimensionless. I joined Affine Analytics with almost 70% hike from my previous job. I am thankful to Dimensionless for all of this.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<h2>Career Transition to Data Science Success Story</h2>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p>Hands-on practice is the key to a good start in Data Science! </p>
<cite><br /><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/ashish-anand-bb6582bb/">-Ashish Anand</a></cite></blockquote>



<h3>Background</h3>



<p><strong>Education:</strong> BE Electronics &amp; Communications</p>



<table class="wp-block-table is-style-stripes">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td><strong>Previous Profile &gt;&gt;&gt;</strong></td>
<td><strong>Transition Profile &gt;&gt;&gt;</strong></td>
<td><strong>Current Profile</strong></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Company: Ericsson<br />Profile: <strong>Network Engineer </strong><br />Domain: Telecom</td>
<td>Company: Ericsson <br />Profile: <strong>Data Science Analyst</strong><br />Domain: Telecom</td>
<td>Company: Affine Analytics <br />Designation: <strong>Data Science Associate</strong><br />Profile: <strong>Sr. Business Analyst</strong><br />Domain: Retail</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>



<div class="wp-block-spacer" style="height: 32px" aria-hidden="true"> </div>



<h3>My journey into Data Science<br /><br /></h3>



<h4>Why Data Science?</h4>



<p>In my previous profile, the work was very manual and monotonous, doing the same thing time and again. I was not satisfied with my work. I knew I had to change something. At that time, I was considering Data Science as well as Big Data since these two have the maximum scope and good pay as well. Maths and Stats were always my strong points and I am technically strong too. Considering this, Data Science looked like an exciting journey.</p>



<h4>Why Dimensionless?</h4>



<p>I tried to learn by myself through other online learning classes. I also took a course through Udemy. The pre-recorded videos were a drag. It was not interactive and I had a lot of doubts. That is when I came across Dimensionless.</p>



<p>Compared to other courses, this one had a detailed syllabus with 200 hours Live and Interactive training. I was sure about joining this course as soon as I attended the Demo. I took a lot of other courses but there was something or the other missing in them. With Dimensionless, I found all of it in one place.</p>



<h4>Experience with Dimensionless?</h4>



<p>It was exactly as I wanted it, a good mix of theory and practical. The classes were very interactive and teachers were always available for doubt-solving. They also helped me with my additional self-studies. I went to them with topics that were not in the syllabus and still got support. There was ample pre-recorded content as well, that we could refer to after the live classes.</p>



<h3>Career Transition to Data Science</h3>



<p>I’ll be honest, I didn’t get through any interviews at first. With mentors at Dimensionless, I got feedback on my performance at the interviews. The career mentoring facility helped me understand what I was interested in and which jobs I should be applying to accordingly. The HR guided me about which companies and jobs I need to apply to, weigh the advantages and disadvantages of the profiles.</p>



<p>This started giving me confidence. Finally, I got shortlisted for multiple companies, one of them was through Dimensionless. I joined Affine Analytics with almost 70% hike from my previous job. I am thankful to Dimensionless for all of this.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-pullquote">
<blockquote>
<p>I like my work, I can work for 10 hours straight and not feel stressed.</p>
</blockquote>
</figure>



<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://dimensionless.in/career-transition-data-science-network-engineer/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Electronics Engineer to Machine Learning Engineer</title>
		<link>https://dimensionless.in/career-transition-data-science-electronics-engineer/</link>
					<comments>https://dimensionless.in/career-transition-data-science-electronics-engineer/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Pooja Sahatiya]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2019 11:18:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Career Transitions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Data Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Career Switch Data Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Career Transition]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data science careers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data science job]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data science professional]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data science skillset]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Data Science Success Story]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[future ready careers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hardware Engineer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Learn Data Science and Business Analytics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Machine Learning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Research Associate]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://dimensionless.in/?p=216380</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I went from and Aerospace Hardware Engineer to machine learning Engineer, within just 4 months into the course. With sincere efforts, you too can become a Data Scientist.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<div class="et_pb_section et_pb_section_0 et_section_regular">
				
				
				
				
					<div class="et_pb_row et_pb_row_0">
				<div class="et_pb_column et_pb_column_4_4 et_pb_column_0  et_pb_css_mix_blend_mode_passthrough et-last-child">
				
				
				<div class="et_pb_module et_pb_text et_pb_text_0 et_pb_bg_layout_light  et_pb_text_align_left">
				
				
				<div class="et_pb_text_inner"><!-- divi:heading -->
<h2>Career Transition to Data Science Success Story</h2>
<!-- /divi:heading -->

<!-- divi:quote -->
<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>Data Science and AI are career choices for everyone who want to be excited about their jobs and learn new things!<br></p><cite><br> &#8211;<a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/jagrati-valecha-6a868895/"> Jagrati Valecha</a></cite></blockquote>
<!-- /divi:quote -->

<!-- divi:heading {"level":3} -->
<h3>Background﻿<br></h3>
<!-- /divi:heading -->

<!-- divi:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Education:</strong>  B. Tech Electronics &amp; Communications  </p>
<!-- /divi:paragraph -->

<!-- divi:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Previous Profile</strong><br></p>
<!-- /divi:paragraph -->

<!-- divi:paragraph -->
<p>Company: Honeywell Aerospace<br>Profile: Electronics Engineer<br>Domain: Aerospace<br>Experience: 3.4 years</p>
<!-- /divi:paragraph -->

<!-- divi:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Current Profile</strong><br></p>
<!-- /divi:paragraph -->

<!-- divi:paragraph -->
<p>Company: Honeywell Aerospace <br>Profile: Machine Learning Engineer<br>Domain: Aerospace<br></p>
<!-- /divi:paragraph -->

<!-- divi:heading {"level":4} -->
<h4>My journey into Data Science</h4>
<!-- /divi:heading -->

<!-- divi:heading {"level":4} -->
<h4>Why Data Science?</h4>
<!-- /divi:heading -->

<!-- divi:paragraph -->
<p>I was an Electronics Engineer in Aerospace and I couldn&#8217;t see any growth in my domain. The opportunities to learn new things were limited, which lead to no growth and it became less and less exciting to me every day.</p>
<!-- /divi:paragraph -->

<!-- divi:paragraph -->
<p>I realized I had to switch to software and upgrade my skills as per the demand to stay relevant throughout my career. I spoke with many of my peers, did some research, and found a few career choices viable as per the market right now. <a href="https://dimensionless.in">Data Science</a> looked like an interesting career choice but I still remember having so many doubts!</p>
<!-- /divi:paragraph -->

<!-- divi:heading {"level":4} -->
<h4>Why Dimensionless?</h4>
<!-- /divi:heading -->

<!-- divi:paragraph -->
<p>As I was researching, I came across Dimensionless on Google and enrolled for a Demo session. I asked them all the questions and doubts I had about taking up Data Science. I literally bombarded them with questions like…<br>How difficult is it going to be without having much of programming knowledge?<br>Is having no previous work-experience okay? And does it count?<br>How does <a href="https://dimensionless.in/data-science-using-r-python/">Data Science</a> fit in my domain (Aerospace)?</p>
<!-- /divi:paragraph -->

<!-- divi:paragraph -->
<p>They answered all of it with patience and logic. I also had a one-on-one career counselling session with their counsellor.</p>
<!-- /divi:paragraph -->

<!-- divi:paragraph -->
<p>Then there were other things to consider, like if I can attend the classes regularly, if the fee is viable, if I can get back to studies after such a long break, etc.</p>
<!-- /divi:paragraph -->

<!-- divi:paragraph -->
<p>So, I went for the <strong>Experience and Pay</strong> option. Attended the classes for 2 weeks, I liked their methodology, and since I could understand what I was learning, I found myself attending lectures regularly along with my work and without being too stressed. And then, I continued and completed the entire course.</p>
<!-- /divi:paragraph -->

<!-- divi:heading {"level":4} -->
<h4>Experience with Dimensionless?</h4>
<!-- /divi:heading -->

<!-- divi:paragraph -->
<p>The course structure and methodology is not too stressing. The teaching pace wasn’t too stressing. Doubt-solving was immediate. I could get my doubts solved during the class, in the doubt-solving sessions or even one-on-one with the respective teacher. And trust me, coming from a non-programming background, I had a lot of doubts. Mentors and teachers were always available answering doubts.</p>
<!-- /divi:paragraph -->

<!-- divi:heading {"level":3} -->
<h3>Career Transition to Data Science</h3>
<!-- /divi:heading -->

<!-- divi:paragraph -->
<p>Resume-building sessions made me understand how to steer my career towards Data Science in Aerospace. When mentors started giving us projects, I got to choose projects from my domain so I could build upon my experience. This helped me get ready for interviews more than anything. Knowing theory is one thing, but the interviewers ask very technical and practical questions. <br></p>
<!-- /divi:paragraph -->

<!-- divi:paragraph -->
<p>About only 70% of the course was done when I applied for an internal-switch at my company and got accepted. In fact, I even got a promotion and didn’t have to apply anywhere else.</p>
<!-- /divi:paragraph -->

<!-- divi:pullquote -->
<figure class="wp-block-pullquote"><blockquote><p>I went from an Electronics Engineer to Machine Learning Engineer, within just 4 months into the course. With sincere efforts, you too can become a Data Scientist.</p><p>Go beyond doubts, ask questions and keep learning.</p></blockquote></figure>
<!-- /divi:pullquote -->

<!-- divi:paragraph -->
<p><br></p>
<!-- /divi:paragraph --></div>
			</div> <!-- .et_pb_text -->
			</div> <!-- .et_pb_column -->
				
				
			</div> <!-- .et_pb_row -->
				
				
			</div> <!-- .et_pb_section -->
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://dimensionless.in/career-transition-data-science-electronics-engineer/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
