<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<rdf:RDF
 xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
 xmlns="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/"
 xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
 xmlns:taxo="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/taxonomy/"
 xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
 xmlns:syn="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
 xmlns:admin="http://webns.net/mvcb/"
>

<channel rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/">
<title>cond-mat.supr-con updates on arXiv.org</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">Condensed Matter -- Superconductivity (cond-mat.supr-con) updates on the arXiv.org e-print archive</description>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:date>2022-11-03T20:30:00-05:00</dc:date>
<dc:publisher>help@arxiv.org</dc:publisher>
<dc:subject>Condensed Matter -- Superconductivity</dc:subject>
<syn:updateBase>1901-01-01T00:00+00:00</syn:updateBase>
<syn:updateFrequency>1</syn:updateFrequency>
<syn:updatePeriod>daily</syn:updatePeriod>
<items>
 <rdf:Seq>
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01376" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01388" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01400" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01609" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01707" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01733" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.02002" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.02031" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2203.06586" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2205.14993" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2206.09922" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2208.05712" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.00679" />
 </rdf:Seq>
</items>
<image rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif" />
</channel>
<image rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif">
<title>arXiv.org</title>
<url>http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif</url>
<link>http://arxiv.org/</link>
</image>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01376">
<title>Higgs Condensates are Symmetry-Protected Topological Phases: I. Discrete Symmetries. (arXiv:2211.01376v1 [cond-mat.str-el])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01376</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Where in the landscape of many-body phases of matter do we place the Higgs
condensate of a gauge theory? On the one hand, the Higgs phase is gapped, has
no local order parameter, and for fundamental Higgs fields is adiabatically
connected to the confined phase. On the other hand, Higgs phases such as
superconductors display rich phenomenology. In this work, we propose a minimal
description of the Higgs phase as a symmetry-protected topological (SPT) phase,
utilizing conventional and higher-form symmetries. In this first part, we focus
on 2+1D $\mathbb Z_2$ gauge theory and find that the Higgs phase is protected
by a higher-form magnetic symmetry and a matter symmetry, whose meaning depends
on the physical context. While this proposal captures known properties of Higgs
phases, it also predicts that the Higgs phase of the Fradkin-Shenker model has
SPT edge modes in the symmetric part of the phase diagram, which we confirm
analytically. In addition, we argue that this SPT property is remarkably robust
upon explicitly breaking the magnetic symmetry. Although the Higgs and confined
phases are then connected without a bulk transition, they are separated by a
boundary phase transition, which we confirm with tensor network simulations.
More generally, the boundary anomaly of the Higgs SPT phase coincides with the
emergent anomaly of symmetry-breaking phases, making precise the relation
between Higgs phases and symmetry breaking. The SPT nature of the Higgs phase
can also manifest in the bulk, e.g., at transitions between distinct Higgs
condensates. Finally, we extract insights which are applicable to general SPT
phases, such as a &apos;bulk-defect correspondence&apos; generalizing discrete gauge
group analogs of Superconductor-Insulator-Superconductor (SIS) junctions. The
sequel to this work will generalize &apos;Higgs=SPT&apos; to continuous symmetries,
interpreting superconductivity as an SPT property.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Verresen_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ruben Verresen&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Borla_U/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Umberto Borla&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Vishwanath_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ashvin Vishwanath&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Moroz_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Sergej Moroz&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Thorngren_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ryan Thorngren&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01388">
<title>Sublattice Interference promotes Pair Density Wave order in Kagome Metals. (arXiv:2211.01388v1 [cond-mat.str-el])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01388</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Motivated by the observation of a pair density wave (PDW) in the kagome metal
CsV${}_3$Sb${}_5$, we consider the fate of electrons near a p-type van Hove
singularity (vHS) in the presence of local repulsive interactions. We study the
effect of such interactions on Fermi surface &quot;patches&quot; at the vHS. We show how
a feature unique to the Kagome lattice known as sublattice interference
crucially affects the form of the interactions among the patches. The RG flow
of such interactions results in a regime where nearest neighbor interactions
exceed onsite repulsion. We identify this condition as being favorable for the
formation of CDW and PDW orders. We conclude that in the weak-coupling limit,
CDW order is the dominant order, whereas PDW order sets in at intermediate
coupling.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Wu_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yi-Ming Wu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Thomale_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ronny Thomale&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Raghu_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;S. Raghu&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01400">
<title>Improved effective vertices in the multi-orbital Two-Particle Self-Consistent method from Dynamical Mean-Field Theory. (arXiv:2211.01400v1 [cond-mat.str-el])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01400</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;In this work we present a multi-orbital form of the Two-Particle
Self-Consistent approach (TPSC), here the effective local and static
irreducible interaction vertices are determined by means of the Dynamical
Mean-Field Theory (DMFT). This approach replaces the approximate ansatz
equations for the double occupations $\langle
n^{}_{\alpha,\sigma}n^{}_{\beta,\sigma&apos;}\rangle$ by sampling them directly for
the same model using DMFT. Compared to the usual Hartree-Fock like ansatz, this
leads to more accurate local vertices in the weakly correlated regime, and
provides access to stronger correlated systems that were previously out of
reach. This approach is extended by replacing the local component of the TPSC
self-energy by the DMFT impurity self-energy, which results in an improved
self-energy that incorporates strong local correlations but retains a
non-trivial momentum-dependence. We find that this combination of TPSC and DMFT
provides a significant improvement over the multi-orbital formulation of
multi-orbital TPSC, as it allows to determine the components of the spin vertex
without artificial symmetry assumptions, and opens the possibility to include
the transversal particle-hole channel. The new approach is also able to remove
unphysical divergences in the charge vertices in TPSC. We find a general trend
that lower temperatures can be accessed in the calculation. Benchmarking
single-particle quantities such as the local spectral function with other
many-body methods we find significant improvement in the more strongly
correlated regime.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Zantout_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Karim Zantout&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Backes_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Steffen Backes&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Razpopov_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Aleksandar Razpopov&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Lessnich_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Dominik Lessnich&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Valenti_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Roser Valenti&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01609">
<title>Josephson Effect in NbS$_{2}$ van der Waals Junctions. (arXiv:2211.01609v1 [cond-mat.supr-con])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01609</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Van der Waals (vdW) Josephson junctions can possibly accelerate the
development of advanced superconducting device that utilizes the unique
properties of two-dimensional (2D) transition metal dichalcogenide (TMD)
superconductors such as spin-orbit coupling, spin-valley locking. Here, we
fabricate vertically stacked NbS$_{2}$/NbS$_{2}$ Josephson junctions using a
modified all-dry transfer technique and characterize the device performance via
systematic low-temperature transport measurements. The experimental results
show that the superconducting transition temperature of the NbS$_{2}$/NbS$_{2}$
Josephson junction is 5.84 K, and the critical current density reaches 3975
A/cm$^{2}$ at 2K. Moreover, we extract a superconducting energy gap
$\Delta=0.58$ meV, which is considerably smaller than that expected from the
single band s-wave Bardeen-Cooper-Schrieffer (BCS) model ($\Delta=0.89$ meV).
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Zhao_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Chuanwen Zhao&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Yi_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xin Yi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Chen_Q/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Qiao Chen&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Yan_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Chengyu Yan&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Wang_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Shun Wang&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01707">
<title>Electrostatic effects of the MnBi2Te4-superconductor hetero-structures in chiral Majorana search. (arXiv:2211.01707v1 [cond-mat.supr-con])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01707</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The realization of chiral Majorana modes is a challenging task. We aim to
comprehend the phase diagrams and parameter control capabilities of the actual
devices used in the chiral Majorana search. Beyond the well-known minimal
models, we develop a numerical simulation scheme using a self-consistent
Schrodinger-Poisson approach to study, as an example, the MnBi2Te4 thin film
coupled to an s-wave superconductor. We show that both the superconducting
proximity effect and the tunability of the chemical potential for the
topological surface states are significantly influenced by the gate-induced
electrostatic potential. This complicates the implementation in experiments,
and the actual topological region will be narrowed in stark contrast to those
predicted in the previous minimal models. Nevertheless, we demonstrate that the
chiral Majorana mode still exists in a wide range of experimental parameters
with practical tunability.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Chen_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Li Chen&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Cao_Z/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Zhan Cao&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+He_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ke He&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Liu_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xin Liu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Liu_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Dong E. Liu&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01733">
<title>Gradual emergence of superconductivity in underdoped LSCO. (arXiv:2211.01733v1 [cond-mat.supr-con])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01733</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We present triple-axis neutron scattering studies of low-energy magnetic
fluctuations in strongly underdoped La$_{2-x}$Sr$_{x}$CuO$_{4}$ with $x=0.05$,
$0.06$ and $0.07$, providing quantitative evidence for a direct competition
between these fluctuations and superconductivity. At dopings $x=0.06$ and
$x=0.07$, three-dimensional superconductivity is found, while only a very weak
signature of two-dimensional superconductivity residing in the CuO$_2$ planes
is detectable for $x=0.05$. We find a surprising suppression of the low-energy
fluctuations by an external magnetic field at all three dopings. This implies
that the response of two-dimensional superconductivity to a magnetic field is
similar to that of a bulk superconductor. Our results provide direct evidence
of a very gradual onset of superconductivity in cuprates.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Tutueanu_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ana-Elena Tutueanu&lt;/a&gt; (1 and 2), &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Kamminga_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Machteld E. Kamminga&lt;/a&gt; (1), &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Tejsner_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Tim B. Tejsner&lt;/a&gt; (1 and 2), &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Jacobsen_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Henrik Jacobsen&lt;/a&gt; (1 and 3), &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Hansen_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Henriette W. Hansen&lt;/a&gt; (1), &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Lacatusu_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Monica-Elisabeta Lacatusu&lt;/a&gt; (1 and 3), &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Baas_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jacob Baas&lt;/a&gt; (4), &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Eliasen_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Kira L. Eliasen&lt;/a&gt; (1 and 5), &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Grivel_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jean-Claude Grivel&lt;/a&gt; (6), &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Sassa_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yasmine Sassa&lt;/a&gt; (7), &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Christensen_N/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Niels Bech Christensen&lt;/a&gt; (8), &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Steffens_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Paul Steffens&lt;/a&gt; (2), &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Boehm_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Martin Boehm&lt;/a&gt; (2), &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Piovano_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Andrea Piovano&lt;/a&gt; (2), &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Lefmann_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Kim Lefmann&lt;/a&gt; (1), &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Romer_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Astrid T. R&amp;#xf8;mer&lt;/a&gt; (1 and 9) ((1) Nanoscience Center, Niels Bohr Institute, University of Copenhagen, Denmark, (2) Institut Laue-Langevin, Grenoble, France, (3) Paul Scherrer Institute, Laboratory for Neutron Scattering and Imaging, Villigen, Switzerland, (4) Zernike Institute for Advanced Materials, University of Groningen, The Netherlands, (5) Glass and Time, IMFUFA, Department of Science and Environment, Roskilde University, Denmark, (6) Department of Energy Conversion and Storage, Technical University of Denmark, Kgs. Lyngby, Denmark, (7) Department of Physics, Chalmers University of Technology, G&amp;#xf6;teborg, Sweden, (8) Department of Physics, Technical University of Denmark, Kgs. Lyngby, Denmark, (9) Danish Fundamental Metrology, H&amp;#xf8;rsholm, Denmark)</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.02002">
<title>Emergence of Competing Orders and Possible Quantum Spin Liquid in SU(N) Fermions. (arXiv:2211.02002v1 [cond-mat.str-el])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.02002</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;In the past decades, tremendous efforts have been made towards understanding
the exotic physics emerging from competition between various ordering
tendencies in strongly correlated systems. Employing state-of-the-art quantum
Monte-Carlo simulation, we investigate an interacting SU($N$) fermionic model
with varying interaction strength and value of $N$, and unveil the ground-state
phase diagram of the model exhibiting a plethora of exotic phases. For small
value of $N$, namely $N=2,3$, the ground state is antiferromagnetic (AFM)
phase, whereas in the large-$N$ limit, valence bound solid (VBS) order is
dominant. For the intermediate value of $N$ such as $N=4$, remarkably, our
study reveals distinct VBS orders appear in the weak and strong coupling
regimes. More fantastically, the competition between staggered and columnar VBS
ordering tendencies gives rise to a Mott insulating phase without spontaneously
symmetry breaking (SSB), existing in a large interacting parameter regime,
which is consistent with a gapped quantum spin liquid. Our study not only
provides a platform to investigate the fundamental physics of quantum many-body
systems, but also offers a novel route towards searching for exotic states of
matter such as quantum spin liquid in realistic quantum materials.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Yu_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xue-Jia Yu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Shi_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Shao-Hang Shi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Xu_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Limei Xu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Li_Z/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Zi-Xiang Li&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.02031">
<title>Spectral properties of 1D extended Hubbard model from bosonization and time-dependent variational principle: applications to 1D cuprate. (arXiv:2211.02031v1 [cond-mat.str-el])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.02031</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Recent ARPES experiments on doped 1D cuprates revealed the importance of
effective near-neighbor (NN) attractions in explaining certain features in
spectral functions. Here we investigate spectral properties of the extended
Hubbard model with the on-site repulsion $U$ and NN interaction $V$, by
employing bosonization analysis and the high-precision time-dependent
variational principle (TDVP) calculations of the model on 1D chain with up to
300 sites. From state-of-the-art TDVP calculations, we find that the spectral
weights of the holon-folding and $3k_F$ branches evolve oppositely as a
function of $V$. This peculiar dichotomy may be explained in bosonization
analysis from the opposite dependence of exponent that determines the spectral
weights on Luttinger parameter $K_{\rho}$. Moreover, our TDVP calculations of
models with fixed $U=8t$ and different $V$ show that $V\approx -1.7t$ may fit
the experimental results best, indicating a moderate effective NN attraction in
1D cuprates that might provide some hints towards understanding
superconductivity in 2D cuprates.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Wang_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Hao-Xin Wang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Wu_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yi-Ming Wu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Jiang_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yi-Fan Jiang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Yao_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Hong Yao&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2203.06586">
<title>Phonon downconversion to suppress correlated errors in superconducting qubits. (arXiv:2203.06586v2 [quant-ph] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2203.06586</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Quantum error correction can preserve quantum information in the presence of
local errors, but correlated errors are fatal. For superconducting qubits,
high-energy particle impacts from background radioactivity produce energetic
phonons that travel throughout the substrate and create excitations above the
superconducting ground state, known as quasiparticles, which can poison all
qubits on the chip. We use normal metal reservoirs on the chip back side to
downconvert phonons to low energies where they can no longer poison qubits. We
introduce a pump-probe scheme involving controlled injection of pair-breaking
phonons into the qubit chips. We examine quasiparticle poisoning on chips with
and without back-side metallization and demonstrate a reduction in the flux of
pair-breaking phonons by over a factor of 20. We use a Ramsey interferometer
scheme to simultaneously monitor quasiparticle parity on three qubits for each
chip and observe a two-order of magnitude reduction in correlated poisoning due
to background radiation.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Iaia_V/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;V. Iaia&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Ku_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;J. Ku&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Ballard_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;A. Ballard&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Larson_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;C. P. Larson&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Yelton_E/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;E. Yelton&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Liu_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;C. H. Liu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Patel_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;S. Patel&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+McDermott_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;R. McDermott&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Plourde_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;B. L. T. Plourde&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2205.14993">
<title>Josephson junctions of 2D time-reversal invariant superconductors: signatures of the topological phase. (arXiv:2205.14993v3 [cond-mat.supr-con] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2205.14993</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We determine the current-phase relation (CPR) of two-terminal configurations
of Josephson junctions containing two-dimensional (2D) time-reversal invariant
topological superconductors (TRITOPS), including TRITOPS-TRITOPS, as well as
junctions between topological and non-topological superconductors (TRITOPS-S).
We focus on long junctions for which several channels intervene in the
tunneling coupling through the junction. We present a description of the
topological edge modes for different TRITOPS models including $p$-wave pairing
and the combination of $s$-wave pairing with spin-orbit coupling. We derive
effective low-energy Hamiltonians to describe the Josephson junction, which can
be solved analytically to explain the contribution of the edge states to the
Josephson current as a function of the phase bias. We find that edge-modes
yield singular corrections to the CPR for both junction types. The primary
effects occur for the response of the Majorana zero-modes at half-flux quantum
phase $\phi\approx \pi$ in TRITOPS-TRITOPS junctions and for integer flux
quantum phase $\phi \approx 0$ for TRITOPS-S junctions, respectively. The
former effect is particularly strong two-component nematic superconductors. The
latter effect leads to a spontaneously broken time-reversal symmetry in the
TRITOPS-S junction and to a breakdown of the bulk-boundary correspondence.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Ruiz_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Gabriel F. Rodr&amp;#xed;guez Ruiz&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Rampp_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Michael A. Rampp&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Aligia_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;A. A. Aligia&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Schmalian_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Joerg Schmalian&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Arrachea_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Liliana Arrachea&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2206.09922">
<title>Enhanced superconductivity through virtual tunneling in Bernal bilayer graphene coupled to WSe$_2$. (arXiv:2206.09922v3 [cond-mat.supr-con] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2206.09922</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Motivated by a recent experiment [&lt;a href=&quot;/abs/2205.05087&quot;&gt;arXiv:2205.05087&lt;/a&gt;], we investigate a
possible mechanism that enhances superconductivity in hole-doped Bernal bilayer
graphene due to a proximate WSe$_2$ monolayer. We show that the virtual
tunneling between WSe$_2$ and Bernal bilayer graphene, which is known to induce
Ising spin-orbit coupling, can generate an additional attraction between two
holes, providing a potential explanation for enhancing superconductivity in
Bernal bilayer graphene. Using microscopic interlayer tunneling, we derive the
Ising spin-orbit coupling and the effective attraction as functions of the
twist angle between Bernal bilayer graphene and the WSe$_2$ monolayer. Our
theory provides an intuitive and physical explanation for the intertwined
relation between Ising spin-orbit coupling and superconductivity enhancement,
which should motivate future studies.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Chou_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yang-Zhi Chou&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Wu_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Fengcheng Wu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Sarma_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Sankar Das Sarma&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2208.05712">
<title>Superconductivity in epitaxially grown LaVO3/KTaO3(111) heterostructures. (arXiv:2208.05712v3 [cond-mat.supr-con] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2208.05712</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Complex oxide heterointerfaces can host a rich of emergent phenomena, and
epitaxial growth is usually at the heart of forming these interfaces. Recently,
a strong crystalline-orientation-dependent two-dimensional superconductivity
was discovered at interfaces between KTaO3 single-crystal substrates and films
of other oxides. Unexpectedly, rare of these oxide films was epitaxially grown.
Here, we report the existence of superconductivity in epitaxially grown
LaVO3/KTaO3(111) heterostructures, with a superconducting transition
temperature of ~0.5 K. Meanwhile, no superconductivity was detected in the
(001)- and (110)-orientated LaVO3/KTaO3 heterostructures down to 50 mK.
Moreover, we find that for the LaVO3/KTaO3(111) interfaces to be conducting, an
oxygen-deficient growth environment and a minimum LaVO3 thickness of ~0.8 nm (~
2 unit cells) are needed.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Liu_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yuan Liu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Liu_Z/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Zhongran Liu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Zhang_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Meng Zhang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Sun_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yanqiu Sun&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Tian_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;He Tian&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Xie_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yanwu Xie&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.00679">
<title>Quantum phase transitions in non-Hermitian $\mathcal{P}\mathcal{T}$-symmetric transverse-field Ising spin chains. (arXiv:2211.00679v1 [quant-ph] CROSS LISTED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.00679</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We present a theoretical study of quantum phases and quantum phase
transitions occurring in non-Hermitian $\mathcal{P}\mathcal{T}$-symmetric
superconducting qubits chains described by a transverse-field Ising spin model.
A non-Hermitian part of the Hamiltonian is implemented via imaginary staggered
\textit{longitudinal } magnetic field, which corresponds to a local staggered
gain and loss terms. By making use of a direct numerical diagonalization of the
Hamiltonian for spin chains of a finite size $N$, we explore the dependencies
of the energy spectrum, including the energy difference between the first
excited and the ground states, the spatial correlation function of local
polarization ($z$-component of local magnetization) on the adjacent spins
interaction strength $J$ and the local gain (loss) parameter $\gamma$. A
scaling procedure for the coherence length $\xi$ allows us to establish a
complete quantum phase diagram of the system. We obtain two quantum phases for
$J&amp;lt;0$, namely, $\mathcal{P}\mathcal{T}$-symmetry broken antiferromagnetic state
and $\mathcal{P}\mathcal{T}$-symmetry preserved paramagnetic state, and the
quantum phase transition line between them is the line of exception points. For
$J&amp;gt;0$ the $\mathcal{P}\mathcal{T}$-symmetry of the ground state is retained in
a whole region of parameter space of $J$ and $\gamma$, and a system shows
\textit{two} intriguing quantum phase transitions between ferromagnetic and
paramagnetic states for a fixed parameter $\gamma &amp;gt; 1$. We also provide the
qualitative quantum phase diagram $\gamma-J$ derived in the framework of the
Bethe-Peierls approximation that is in a good accord with numerically obtained
results.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Starkov_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Grigory A. Starkov&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Fistoul_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Mikhail V. Fistoul&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Eremin_I/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ilya M. Eremin&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
</rdf:RDF>