<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<rdf:RDF
 xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
 xmlns="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/"
 xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
 xmlns:taxo="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/taxonomy/"
 xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
 xmlns:syn="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
 xmlns:admin="http://webns.net/mvcb/"
>

<channel rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/">
<title>physics.data-an updates on arXiv.org</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">Physics -- Data Analysis, Statistics and Probability (physics.data-an) updates on the arXiv.org e-print archive</description>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:date>2022-11-03T20:30:00-05:00</dc:date>
<dc:publisher>help@arxiv.org</dc:publisher>
<dc:subject>Physics -- Data Analysis, Statistics and Probability</dc:subject>
<syn:updateBase>1901-01-01T00:00+00:00</syn:updateBase>
<syn:updateFrequency>1</syn:updateFrequency>
<syn:updatePeriod>daily</syn:updatePeriod>
<items>
 <rdf:Seq>
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01481" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01936" />
 </rdf:Seq>
</items>
<image rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif" />
</channel>
<image rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif">
<title>arXiv.org</title>
<url>http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif</url>
<link>http://arxiv.org/</link>
</image>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01481">
<title>Physics-inspired machine learning for power grid frequency modelling. (arXiv:2211.01481v1 [eess.SY])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01481</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The operation of power systems is affected by diverse technical, economic and
social factors. Social behaviour determines load patterns, electricity markets
regulate the generation and weather-dependent renewables introduce power
fluctuations. Thus, power system dynamics must be regarded as a non-autonomous
system whose parameters vary strongly with time. However, the external driving
factors are usually only available on coarse scales and the actual dependencies
of the dynamic system parameters are generally unknown. Here, we propose a
physics-inspired machine learning model that bridges the gap between
large-scale drivers and short-term dynamics of the power system. Integrating
stochastic differential equations and artificial neural networks, we construct
a probabilistic model of the power grid frequency dynamics in Continental
Europe. Its probabilistic prediction outperforms the daily average profile,
which is an important benchmark. Using the integrated model, we identify and
explain the parameters of the dynamical system from the data, which reveals
their strong time-dependence and their relation to external drivers such as
wind power feed-in and fast generation ramps. Finally, we generate synthetic
time series from the model, which successfully reproduce central
characteristics of the grid frequency such as their heavy-tailed distribution.
All in all, our work emphasises the importance of modelling power system
dynamics as a stochastic non-autonomous system with both intrinsic dynamics and
external drivers.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/eess/1/au:+Kruse_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Johannes Kruse&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/eess/1/au:+Cramer_E/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Eike Cramer&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/eess/1/au:+Schafer_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Benjamin Sch&amp;#xe4;fer&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/eess/1/au:+Witthaut_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Dirk Witthaut&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01936">
<title>Differences in collaboration structures and impact among prominent researchers in Europe and North America. (arXiv:2211.01936v1 [physics.soc-ph])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01936</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Scientists collaborate through intricate networks, which impact the quality
and scope of their research. At the same time, funding and institutional
arrangements, as well as scientific and political cultures, affect the
structure of collaboration networks. Since such arrangements and cultures
differ across regions in the world in systematic ways, we surmise that
collaboration networks and impact should also differ systematically across
regions. To test this, we compare the structure of collaboration networks among
prominent researchers in North America and Europe. We find that prominent
researchers in Europe establish denser collaboration networks, whereas those in
North-America establish more decentralized networks. We also find that the
impact of the publications of prominent researchers in North America is
significantly higher than for those in Europe, both when they collaborate with
other prominent researchers and when they do not. Although Europeans
collaborate with other prominent researchers more often, which increases their
impact, we also find that repeated collaboration among prominent researchers
decreases the synergistic effect of collaborating.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Danus_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Lluis Danus&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Muntaner_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Carles Muntaner&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Krauss_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Alexander Krauss&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Sales_Pardo_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Marta Sales-Pardo&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Guimera_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Roger Guimera&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
</rdf:RDF>