<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<rdf:RDF
 xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
 xmlns="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/"
 xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
 xmlns:taxo="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/taxonomy/"
 xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
 xmlns:syn="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
 xmlns:admin="http://webns.net/mvcb/"
>

<channel rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/">
<title>nlin.PS updates on arXiv.org</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">Nonlinear Sciences -- Pattern Formation and Solitons (nlin.PS) updates on the arXiv.org e-print archive</description>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:date>2022-11-03T20:30:00-05:00</dc:date>
<dc:publisher>help@arxiv.org</dc:publisher>
<dc:subject>Nonlinear Sciences -- Pattern Formation and Solitons</dc:subject>
<syn:updateBase>1901-01-01T00:00+00:00</syn:updateBase>
<syn:updateFrequency>1</syn:updateFrequency>
<syn:updatePeriod>daily</syn:updatePeriod>
<items>
 <rdf:Seq>
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2205.14511" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.00324" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01075" />
 </rdf:Seq>
</items>
<image rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif" />
</channel>
<image rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif">
<title>arXiv.org</title>
<url>http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif</url>
<link>http://arxiv.org/</link>
</image>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2205.14511">
<title>Multiphase nonlinear electron plasma waves. (arXiv:2205.14511v2 [physics.plasm-ph] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2205.14511</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We present a method for constructing multiphase excitations in the generally
non-integrable system of warm fluid equations describing plasma oscillations.
It is based on autoresonant excitation of nonlinear electron plasma waves by
phase locking with small amplitude chirped-frequency ponderomotive drives. We
demonstrate the excitation of these multiphase waves by performing fully
nonlinear numerical simulations of the fluid equations. We develop a simplified
model based on a weakly nonlinear analytical theory by applying Whitham&apos;s
averaged Lagrangian procedure. The simplified model predictions are in good
agreement with the results from the warm fluid simulations. Such autoresonantly
excited multiphase waves form coherent quasicrystalline structures, which can
potentially be used as plasma photonic or accelerating devices. Finally, we
discuss the laser parameters required for the autoresonant excitation of
nonlinear waves in a plasma.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Munirov_V/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Vadim R. Munirov&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Friedland_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Lazar Friedland&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Wurtele_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jonathan S. Wurtele&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.00324">
<title>$N$-soliton solutions of the Fokas-Lenells equation for the plasma ion-cyclotron waves: Inverse scattering transform approach. (arXiv:2211.00324v2 [nlin.PS] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.00324</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We present a simple and constructive method to find $N$-soliton solutions of
the equation suggested by Davydova and Lashkin to describe the dynamics of
nonlinear ion-cyclotron waves in a plasma and subsequently known (in a more
general form and as applied to nonlinear optics) as the Fokas-Lenells equation.
Using the classical inverse scattering transform approach, we find bright
$N$-soliton solutions, rational $N$-soliton solutions, and $N$-soliton
solutions in the form of a mixture of exponential and rational functions.
Explicit breather solutions are presented as examples. Unlike purely algebraic
constructions of the Hirota or Darboux type, we also give a general expression
for arbitrary initial data decaying at infinity, which contains the
contribution of the continuous spectrum (radiation).
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/nlin/1/au:+Lashkin_V/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;V. M. Lashkin&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01075">
<title>Electromagnetic wave propagation in a nonlinear hyperbolic medium. (arXiv:2211.01075v2 [nlin.PS] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01075</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The propagation of a quasi-harmonic electromagnetic wave in a bulk hyperbolic
dielectric metamaterial is considered. If the group velocities dispersion is
not taken into account, then wave propagation can be described either by the
hyperbolic nonlinear Schrodinger equation or by the hyperbolic Manakov
equations. It is shown that the region in the space of wave vectors in which
the modulation instability of a spatially homogeneous wave is possible is not
limited, in contrast to the case of ordinary media.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/nlin/1/au:+Maimistov_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;A.I. Maimistov&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
</rdf:RDF>