<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:rdau="http://rdaregistry.info/Elements/u/#" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:swpo="http://sw-portal.deri.org/ontologies/swportal#" xmlns:identifiers="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/identifiers/" xmlns:ebucore="http://www.ebu.ch/metadata/ontologies/ebucore/ebucore#">
<channel>
<title>Federal Reserve Bank of Boston publications</title>
<description>Economic research and commentary from Federal Reserve Bank of Boston</description>
<link>https://fedinprint.org/search?facets[]=provider_literal_array:Federal+Reserve+Bank+of+Boston</link>
<atom:link href="https://fedinprint.org/search?facets[]=provider_literal_array:Federal+Reserve+Bank+of+Boston" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2022 15:47:32 +0000</pubDate>
<item>
<title>Did High Leverage Render Small Businesses Vulnerable to the COVID-19 Shock?</title>
<link>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedbwp/94908/original</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[Using supervisory data on small and mid-sized nonfinancial enterprises (SMEs), we find that those SMEs with higher leverage faced tighter constraints in accessing bank credit after the COVID-19 outbreak in spring 2020. Specifically, SMEs with higher pre-COVID leverage obtained a smaller volume of new loans and had to pay a higher spread on them during the pandemic period. Consistent with an inward shift in loan supply, these effects were concentrated in loans originated by banks with below-median capital buffers. Highly levered SMEs that relied on low-capital large banks for funding before the pandemic were not able to substitute to other sources of debt financing and thus experienced more of a reduction in total debt as well as a decline in investment and employment. On the other hand, the unprecedented public support, especially the Paycheck Protection Program (PPP), mitigated the adverse real effect stemming from bank credit constraints.]]>
</description>
<guid>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedbwp/94908/original</guid>
<dc:creator>Bräuning, Falk; Fillat, José; Wang, J. Christina</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2022-07-01</dc:date>
<rdau:hasExtent>67</rdau:hasExtent>
<dc:subject>leverage; small business; credit supply; bank capital; COVID-19</dc:subject>
<swpo:hasNumber>22-13</swpo:hasNumber>
<identifiers:doi>10.29412/res.wp.2022.13</identifiers:doi>
<bibo:series>Working Papers</bibo:series>
</item>
<item>
<title>How to Increase Housing Affordability: Understanding Local Deterrents to Building Multifamily Housing</title>
<link>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedbwp/94892/original</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[This paper studies how local land-use regulations and community opposition affect the trade-offs to building single-family, multifamily, and affordable housing and how their effects on rents differ from their effects on house prices. Using lot-level zoning regulations and a boundary discontinuity design at regulation boundaries in Greater Boston, we obtain causal estimates for the effects of zoning regulations on the supply of different types of housing, single-family-house prices, multifamily rents, and households’ willingness to pay for higher density. We find that relaxing density restrictions (minimum lot size and maximum number of dwelling units)—either alone or in combination with relaxing maximum-height restrictions or allowing multifamily housing—is the most fruitful policy reform for increasing the housing supply and reducing multifamily rents and single-family-house prices. However, adopting multifamily zoning or relaxing height regulations alone has little effect on the number of units built or on rents. Moreover, in each land-use relaxation scenario where rents fall, house prices also fall, complicating the political economy of land-use reform. We also find that mature suburbs that are closer to a city center and have a representative town meeting structure of local governance are the most restrictive with respect to adding multi-unit housing. Furthermore, inclusionary zoning policies such as Massachusetts’s Chapter 40B rarely substitute for relaxing zoning regulations, particularly restrictions on building multifamily housing.]]>
</description>
<guid>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedbwp/94892/original</guid>
<dc:creator>Sood, Aradhya; Chiumenti, Nicholas; Kulka, Amrita</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2022-06-01</dc:date>
<rdau:hasExtent>89</rdau:hasExtent>
<dc:subject>multifamily zoning; height restrictions; density; house prices; rents</dc:subject>
<swpo:hasNumber>22-10</swpo:hasNumber>
<identifiers:doi>10.29412/res.wp.2022.10</identifiers:doi>
<bibo:series>Working Papers</bibo:series>
</item>
<item>
<title>Finding Needles in Haystacks: Multiple-Imputation Record  Linkage Using Machine Learning</title>
<link>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedbwp/94891/original</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[This paper considers the problem of record linkage between a household-level survey and an establishment-level frame in the absence of unique identifiers. Linkage between frames in this setting is challenging because the distribution of employment across establishments is highly skewed. To address these difficulties, this paper develops a probabilistic record linkage methodology that combines machine learning (ML) with multiple imputation (MI). This ML-MI methodology is applied to link survey respondents in the Health and Retirement Study to their workplaces in the Census Business Register. The linked data reveal new evidence that non-sampling errors in household survey data are correlated with respondents’ workplace characteristics.]]>
</description>
<guid>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedbwp/94891/original</guid>
<dc:creator>Raghunathan, Trivellore; Rodgers, Ann Michelle; McCue, Kristin; Patki, Dhiren; Abramowitz, Joelle Hillary; Shapiro, Matthew D.; Zinsser, Dawn; Levenstein, Margaret Catherine; Wasi, Nada; Abowd, John M.</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2021-10-01</dc:date>
<rdau:hasExtent>36</rdau:hasExtent>
<dc:subject>administrative data; machine learning; multiple imputation; probabilistic record linkage; survey data</dc:subject>
<swpo:hasNumber>22-11</swpo:hasNumber>
<identifiers:doi>10.29412/res.wp.2022.11</identifiers:doi>
<bibo:series>Working Papers</bibo:series>
</item>
<item>
<title>Bad Times, Bad Jobs? How Recessions Affect Early Career Trajectories</title>
<link>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedbwp/94884/original</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[Workers who enter the labor market during recessions experience lasting earnings losses, but the role of non-pay amenities in either exacerbating or counteracting these losses remains unknown. Using population-scale data from Germany, we find that labor market entry during recessions generates a 6 percent reduction in earnings cumulated over the first 15 years of experience. Implementing a revealed-preference estimator of employer quality that aggregates information from the universe of worker moves across employers, we find that one-quarter of recession-induced earnings losses are compensated for by non-pay amenities. Purely pecuniary estimates can therefore overstate the welfare costs of labor market entry during recessions.]]>
</description>
<guid>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedbwp/94884/original</guid>
<dc:creator>Stüber, Heiko; Patki, Dhiren; Mahajan, Parag</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2022-10-01</dc:date>
<rdau:hasExtent>58</rdau:hasExtent>
<dc:subject>earnings inequality; recessions; non-pay amenities</dc:subject>
<swpo:hasNumber>22-12</swpo:hasNumber>
<identifiers:doi>10.29412/res.wp.2022.12</identifiers:doi>
<bibo:series>Working Papers</bibo:series>
</item>
<item>
<title>Local Zoning Laws and the Supply of Multifamily  Housing in Greater Boston</title>
<link>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedbcr/94865</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[Housing affordability is a significant issue in many U.S. metropolitan areas, including Greater Boston. Affordability has always been a major challenge for low-income renters; however, even middle-income families now face considerable affordability hurdles, particularly in metro areas with strong labor markets. Where people live has important implications for their health, schooling, and economic mobility. Researchers and policymakers have devoted attention to the role of land-use practices, such as regulating residential zoning, in creating housing affordability problems, particularly in the context of single-family houses. This paper studies how zoning regulations influence affordability in the context of multifamily housing, focusing on Greater Boston. It finds that reforms such as relaxing housing-density restrictions could lead to meaningful increases in the supply of multifamily housing and reductions in rents.]]>
</description>
<guid>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedbcr/94865</guid>
<dc:creator>Sood, Aradhya; Chiumenti, Nicholas</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2022-10-01</dc:date>
<rdau:hasExtent>33</rdau:hasExtent>
<dc:subject>multifamily zoning; height restrictions; density; house prices; rents</dc:subject>
<swpo:hasNumber>22-1</swpo:hasNumber>
<bibo:series>New England Public Policy Center Research Report</bibo:series>
</item>
<item>
<title>Perspectives on the Economy, and on the Opportunities Ahead</title>
<link>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedbsp/94851</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[Speech to the Greater Boston Chamber of Commerce.  In her first speech as president of the Boston Fed, Susan Collins touched on a broad range of topics, including monetary policy, her vision as leader of the Boston Reserve Bank, and the work being done at the Bank to support a vibrant regional and national economy.]]>
</description>
<guid>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedbsp/94851</guid>
<dc:creator>Collins, Susan M.</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2022-09-26</dc:date>
<rdau:hasExtent>10</rdau:hasExtent>
<dc:subject>inflation; inflationary trends; price stability; maximum employment; labor market; inclusive economy; economic outlook; FedNow; Working Places</dc:subject>
<bibo:series>Speech</bibo:series>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Role of Industrial Composition in Driving the Frequency of Price Change</title>
<link>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedbwp/94618/original</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[We analyze the impact of shifts in the industrial composition of the economy on the distribution of the frequency of price change and its consequences for the slope of the Phillips curve for the United States. By combining product-level microdata on the frequency of price change with data on industry shares from 1947 through 2019, we document that shifts in industrial composition led to a gradual reduction in the median monthly frequency of price change from 9.2 percent in 1947 to 6.9 percent in 2019. Other percentiles of the distribution of the frequency of price change show similar reductions. These declines were broadly driven by a shift in the industrial composition of the economy from primary and secondary industries toward service industries. In a calibrated multisector general equilibrium menu cost model, we find that this effect flattened the Phillips curve by 28.5 percent from 1947 to 2019. However, despite a flatter Phillips curve, persistent shocks to aggregate demand still can cause significant inflation.]]>
</description>
<guid>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedbwp/94618/original</guid>
<dc:creator>Garga, Vaishali; Cotton, Christopher D.</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2022-06-01</dc:date>
<rdau:hasExtent>63</rdau:hasExtent>
<dc:subject>industrial composition; inflation; services; price rigidity; Phillips curve</dc:subject>
<swpo:hasNumber>22-9</swpo:hasNumber>
<identifiers:doi>10.29412/res.wp.2022.09</identifiers:doi>
<bibo:series>Working Papers</bibo:series>
</item>
<item>
<title>Credit Card Debt Puzzle: Liquid Assets to Pay Bills</title>
<link>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedbwp/94585/original</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[Using transaction data from a US consumer payments diary, we revisit the credit card debt puzzle—a scenario in which consumers revolve credit card debt while also keeping liquid assets as bank account deposits. This scenario is very common: 42 percent of consumers in our sample were borrower-savers in 2019 (those who carry $100 or more in credit card debt and $100 or more in liquid assets). We explain the puzzle by showing that consumers need their liquid assets to pay monthly bills and other necessary expenses, including mortgage or rent. More than 80 percent of bills by value were paid out of bank accounts and could not be charged to credit cards, so bank account balances were needed to cover those basic expenses. On average, borrower-savers’ credit card debt exceeded their liquid assets. The average borrower-saver carried almost $6,400 in unpaid credit card debt and had $5,400 in liquid assets, including checking and savings accounts, cash, and general-purpose prepaid cards. Only 40 percent of borrower-savers had liquid assets greater than their unpaid credit card balance. In addition, borrower-savers’ monthly expenses (bills and purchases) averaged 77 percent of their liquid assets, not leaving enough to repay their credit card debt. On average, the value of their liquid assets could cover only about 60 percent of their unpaid debt plus monthly bills. In almost every category of assets or debts, both housing and non-housing related, borrower-savers were significantly worse off financially than savers. Thus, the differences between borrower-savers and savers are much broader than just their credit card debt and bank account balances; they extend to mortgage debt and home equity. Even when we control for income and demographics in a regression, we find that carrying a mortgage or other debt (such as auto or educational loans) is associated with a higher probability of revolving on a credit card, suggesting that various types of household debt are complements rather than substitutes. During the COVID-19 pandemic in 2020, consumers’ unpaid credit card debt decreased and their liquid assets increased, so the fraction of borrower-savers dropped to 35 percent of the sample.]]>
</description>
<guid>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedbwp/94585/original</guid>
<dc:creator>Stavins, Joanna; Greene, Claire</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2022-06-01</dc:date>
<rdau:hasExtent>38</rdau:hasExtent>
<dc:subject>credit card debt; consumer payments; liquid assets; COVID-19</dc:subject>
<swpo:hasNumber>22-8</swpo:hasNumber>
<identifiers:doi>10.29412/res.wp.2022.08</identifiers:doi>
<bibo:series>Working Papers</bibo:series>
</item>
<item>
<title>Lessons Learned from Mortgage Borrower Policies and Outcomes during the COVID-19 Pandemic</title>
<link>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedbcq/94444</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[This article reviews the aid offered to the roughly 50 million homeowners with mortgages included in a forbearance program, and the Federal Reserve’s actions that pushed down mortgage rates, allowing many mortgage holders to reduce their monthly payments by refinancing. We deem these policies to be quite effective in relieving financial distress and allowing homeowners to stay in their homes, especially in contrast with the policies pursued during the Great Recession. We emphasize that these policies in part worked because of rising housing prices and home equity, before and during the pandemic, and note that such conditions might not hold in future downturns. We observe that minority mortgage borrowers were much more likely to miss mortgage payments, so forbearance was 
particularly important to them. Black and Hispanic borrowers, however, were less likely than white or Asian borrowers to refinance.]]>
</description>
<guid>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedbcq/94444</guid>
<dc:creator>Gerardi, Kristopher S.; Willen, Paul S.; Lambie-Hanson, Lauren</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2022-07-07</dc:date>
<rdau:hasExtent>30</rdau:hasExtent>
<dc:subject>mortgage refinancing; mortgage repayment; home equity; racial inequality</dc:subject>
<bibo:series>Current Policy Perspectives</bibo:series>
</item>
<item>
<title>Impact of Occupational Unemployment Risk on Household Spending</title>
<link>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedbwp/94277/original</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[The life-cycle consumption and permanent income hypotheses predict that if workers face greater likelihood of unemployment in the future that lowers expected future income, they will save more today. In this paper, we test this hypothesis by looking at the expenditure response of workers to the change in unemployment risk measured at the occupational level. We find that occupational unemployment risk does not have a large impact on consumption expenditure. However, despite investigating multiple forms of occupational unemployment risk for multiple expenditure categories in two expenditure surveys (PSID, CEX), we do not obtain narrow confidence intervals for our estimates, so there remains a possibility of a limited impact.]]>
</description>
<guid>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedbwp/94277/original</guid>
<dc:creator>Rohan, Justin; Cotton, Christopher D.; Garga, Vaishali</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2021-11-01</dc:date>
<rdau:hasExtent>33</rdau:hasExtent>
<dc:subject>unemployment risk; expenditures; life-cycle consumption; permanent income</dc:subject>
<swpo:hasNumber>22-7</swpo:hasNumber>
<identifiers:doi>10.29412/res.wp.2022.07</identifiers:doi>
<bibo:series>Working Papers</bibo:series>
</item>
<item>
<title>Cost-Price Relationships in a  Concentrated Economy</title>
<link>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedbcq/94265</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[The US economy is at least 50 percent more concentrated today than it was in 2005. In this paper, we estimate the effect of this increase on the pass-through of cost shocks into prices. Our estimates imply that the pass-through becomes about 25 percentage points greater when there is an increase in concentration similar to the one observed since the beginning of this century. The resulting above-trend price growth lasts for about four quarters. Our findings suggest that the increase in industry concentration over the past two decades could be amplifying the inflationary pressure from current supply-chain disruptions and a tight labor market.]]>
</description>
<guid>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedbcq/94265</guid>
<dc:creator>Bräuning, Falk; Joaquim, Gustavo; Fillat, José</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2022-05-23</dc:date>
<rdau:hasExtent>9</rdau:hasExtent>
<dc:subject>inflation; supply shock identification; cost-price pass-through; industry concentration</dc:subject>
<bibo:series>Current Policy Perspectives</bibo:series>
</item>
<item>
<title>Payments Evolution from Paper to Electronic Payments  by Merchant Type</title>
<link>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedbwp/94224/original</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[The use of paper instruments—cash and checks—has been declining in the United States, and consumers have been gradually replacing paper with cards and electronic payments. Stavins (2021) examines the evolution of payments from paper to cards and electronic payments, while Shy (2020) shows the payments landscape across merchant types. This paper combines the cross-sectional analysis across merchants with the aggregate time series study to analyze the evolution of consumer payments by merchant type. Using data from a representative diary survey of US consumers collected annually over the past several years, we examine changes for each merchant type to assess which transactions shifted from paper to electronic payments and from in-person to remote transactions. We find that cash use declined faster than check use, in large part because transactions shifted from in person to remote. While the cash-use share of transactions dropped for almost all merchant types, changes in check use were much more heterogenous across merchants. COVID-19 accelerated the payments evolution away from cash for some merchant types, as their drop in cash payments was much larger during the pandemic than prior to it. Merchants whose transactions are typically conducted in person experienced the largest decline in cash payments during the pandemic. Regression results show that the probability of using either cash or checks declined significantly in 2019 and 2020, even after controlling for merchant types, the dollar value of transactions, and consumers’ socio-demographic attributes.]]>
</description>
<guid>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedbwp/94224/original</guid>
<dc:creator>Shy, Oz; Stavins, Joanna; Cohen, Ruth</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2022-02-01</dc:date>
<rdau:hasExtent>39</rdau:hasExtent>
<dc:subject>consumer payments; merchant category; cash; check; cards; electronic payments; COVID-19</dc:subject>
<swpo:hasNumber>22-6</swpo:hasNumber>
<identifiers:doi>10.29412/res.wp.2022.06</identifiers:doi>
<bibo:series>Working Papers</bibo:series>
</item>
<item>
<title>Did the Medicaid Expansion Crowd Out Other Payment Sources for Medications for Opioid Use Disorder?  Evidence from Rhode Island</title>
<link>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedbcq/93991</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[Using information from the all-payer claims database for Rhode Island covering more than three-quarters of health insurance enrollees in the state from April 2011 through May 2019, this paper offers new measures of the association between the Medicaid expansion and the rate of receipt of buprenorphine and methadone for opioid use disorder (OUD). These robust measures adjust for the extent to which new Medicaid payments for these medications that started in 2014 crowded out payments from either non-Medicaid insurance or from non-insurance subsidies for the treatment of opioid abuse. We find that crowding out was nontrivial but incomplete for either buprenorphine or methadone, such that the Medicaid expansion in Rhode Island appears to have enabled many patients to access medications for OUD for the first time. These findings offer support for the expansion of Medicaid in states that have not already done so.]]>
</description>
<guid>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedbcq/93991</guid>
<dc:creator>Sullivan, Riley; Burke, Mary A.</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2022-04-14</dc:date>
<rdau:hasExtent>38</rdau:hasExtent>
<dc:subject>opiod use disorder; Medicaid expansion; buprenorphine; methadone; crowding out; Rhode Island; all-payer claims database</dc:subject>
<bibo:series>Current Policy Perspectives</bibo:series>
</item>
<item>
<title>High-Yield Debt Covenants and  Their Real Effects</title>
<link>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedbwp/93873/original</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[High-yield debt, including leveraged loans, is characterized by incurrence financial covenants, or “cov-lite” provisions. Unlike, traditional, maintenance covenants, incurrence covenants preserve equity control rights but trigger pre-specified restrictions on the borrower’s actions once the covenant threshold is crossed. We show that restricted actions impose significant constraints on investments: Similar to the effects of the shift of control rights to creditors in traditional loans, the drop in investment under incurrence covenants is large and sudden. This evidence suggests a new shock amplification mechanism through contractual restrictions that are at play for a highly levered corporate sector long before default or bankruptcy.]]>
</description>
<guid>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedbwp/93873/original</guid>
<dc:creator>Ivashina, Victoria; Ozdagli, Ali; Bräuning, Falk</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2022-03-01</dc:date>
<rdau:hasExtent>49</rdau:hasExtent>
<dc:subject>high-yield debt; corporate debt; covenants; incurrence covenants; cov-lite; amplification mechanisms; contracts; contingent contracting</dc:subject>
<swpo:hasNumber>22-5</swpo:hasNumber>
<identifiers:doi>10.29412/res.wp.2022.05</identifiers:doi>
<bibo:series>Working Papers</bibo:series>
</item>
<item>
<title>Inflation Levels and (In)Attention</title>
<link>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedbwp/93857/original</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[Inflation expectations are key determinants of economic activity and are central to the current policy debate about whether inflation expectations will remain anchored in the face of recent pandemic-related increases in inflation. This paper explores evidence of inattention by constructing two different measures of consumers’ inattention and documents greater inattention when inflation is low. This suggests that there is indeed a risk of an acceleration in the increases in inflation expectations if actual inflation remains high.]]>
</description>
<guid>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedbwp/93857/original</guid>
<dc:creator>Bracha, Anat; Tang, Jenny</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2022-01-01</dc:date>
<rdau:hasExtent>45</rdau:hasExtent>
<dc:subject>inattention; inflation expectations; expectation anchoring</dc:subject>
<swpo:hasNumber>22-4</swpo:hasNumber>
<identifiers:doi>10.29412/res.wp.2022.04</identifiers:doi>
<bibo:series>Working Papers</bibo:series>
</item>
<item>
<title>Racial Wealth Disparities: Reconsidering the Roles of  Human Capital and Inheritance</title>
<link>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedbwp/93709/original</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[In this paper, we present updated measures of racial disparities in wealth using the most recent data from the Survey of Consumer Finances (SCF), augmented by household-level estimates of defined benefit (DB) pension wealth developed by Sabelhaus and Volz (2020). Including this important asset, we find that racial wealth disparities are smaller than the numbers typically discussed in other research or in the media, but the disparities remain substantial. The paper proceeds by exploring two specific factors that have long been identified as playing potentially important roles in generating disparities in wealth by race, namely differences in earnings (education/human capital) and intergenerational transfers in the form of inheritances and inter vivos gifts. We contribute to the existing literature by introducing several data innovations in the exploration of these factors using the SCF. We augment the SCF data with individual-level lifetime earnings histories (developed by Jacobs et al. 2020, 2021) and enhanced measures of intergenerational transfers (developed by Feiveson and Sabelhaus 2018, 2019). We also create an expanded set of variables that reflect the range of pension coverage and generosity across workers. With all three of these new data components, we use non-parametric decomposition techniques to estimate their contributions to racial wealth gaps between white and non-white families. Differences in lifetime earnings, pension generosity, and a handful of other human capital and work-related variables explain three-quarters of the white/Black wealth gap and 80 to 90 percent of the white/Hispanic gap. Reweighting white family wealth to match the distribution of human capital traits of families of “other” races (including Asian, Native American and other groups) raises counterfactual white wealth to the level of “other” family wealth, nearly closing the white/“other” gap. Differences in intergenerational transfers are found to account for 13 to 16 percent of white/non-white private wealth gaps, although much of the influence of these transfers likely works through the human capital channel. Policies that successfully increase skills, employment, earnings, and pension coverage among low-wealth Black and Hispanic families will make important contributions to closing wealth gaps.]]>
</description>
<guid>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedbwp/93709/original</guid>
<dc:creator>Sabelhaus, John Edward; Thompson, Jeffrey P.</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2021-09-01</dc:date>
<rdau:hasExtent>104</rdau:hasExtent>
<dc:subject>racial wealth gap; inequality; human capital; lifetime earnings; retirement plans; pensions; inheritance</dc:subject>
<swpo:hasNumber>22-3</swpo:hasNumber>
<identifiers:doi>10.29412/res.wp.2022.03</identifiers:doi>
<bibo:series>Working Papers</bibo:series>
</item>
<item>
<title>Interest Rate Surprises: A Tale of Two Shocks</title>
<link>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedbwp/93691/original</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[Interest rate surprises around FOMC announcements reveal both the surprise in the monetary policy stance (the pure policy shock) and interest rate movements driven by exogenous information about the economy from the central bank (the information shock). In order to disentangle the effects of these two shocks, we use interest rate changes on days of macroeconomic data releases. On these release dates, there are no pure policy shocks, which allows us to identify the impact of information shocks and thereby distill pure policy shocks from interest rate surprises around FOMC announcements. Our results show that there is a prominent central bank information component in the widely used high-frequency policy rate surprise measure that needs to be parsed out. When we remove this central bank information component, the estimated effects of monetary policy shocks are more pronounced relative to those estimated using the entire policy rate surprise.]]>
</description>
<guid>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedbwp/93691/original</guid>
<dc:creator>Nunes, Ricardo; Ozdagli, Ali; Tang, Jenny</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2022-01-01</dc:date>
<rdau:hasExtent>39</rdau:hasExtent>
<dc:subject>monetary policy; central bank information; high-frequency identification; proxy structural VAR; external instruments</dc:subject>
<swpo:hasNumber>22-2</swpo:hasNumber>
<identifiers:doi>10.29412/res.wp.2022.02</identifiers:doi>
<bibo:series>Working Papers</bibo:series>
</item>
<item>
<title>Should the ECB Adjust Its Strategy in the  Face of a Lower r*?</title>
<link>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedbwp/93688/original</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[We address the question in this paper’s title using an estimated New Keynesian DSGE model of the euro area with trend inflation, imperfect indexation, and a lower bound on the nominal interest rate. In this setup, a decrease in the steady-state real interest rate, r*, increases the probability of hitting the lower bound constraint, which entails significant welfare costs and warrants an adjustment of the monetary policy strategy. Under an unchanged monetary policy rule, an increase in the inflation target of eight-tenths the size of the drop in the real natural rate of interest is warranted. Absent an increase in the inflation target, and assuming the effective lower bound prevents the European Central Bank from implementing more aggressive negative interest rate policies, adjusting the monetary strategy requires considering alternative instruments or policy rules, such as a commitment to make up for recent, below-target inflation realizations.]]>
</description>
<guid>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedbwp/93688/original</guid>
<dc:creator>Matheron, Julien; Le Bihan, Hervé; Gali, Jordi; Andrade, Philippe</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2021-04-01</dc:date>
<rdau:hasExtent>38</rdau:hasExtent>
<dc:subject>inflation target; effective lower bound; monetary policy strategy; euro area</dc:subject>
<swpo:hasNumber>22-1</swpo:hasNumber>
<identifiers:doi>10.29412/res.wp.2022.01</identifiers:doi>
<bibo:series>Working Papers</bibo:series>
</item>
<item>
<title>Optimal Allocation of Relief Funds: The Case of the Paycheck Protection Program</title>
<link>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedbwp/93557/original</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[The Paycheck Protection Program (PPP) was a large and unprecedented small-business support program that allocated $800 billion in loans and grants to small businesses following the onset of the COVID-19 crisis. This paper explores the optimal allocation of funds across firms and the distortions caused by allocating these funds through banks. We show that it can be optimal to allocate funds to the least or most affected firms depending on the underlying distribution of the shock that firms face, the firms’ financial position, and the total budget available for the program. In the model, as in the data, banks distort the allocation toward firms with more pre-pandemic debt and those less affected by the COVID-19 crisis. We characterize how this misallocation depends on the degree of asymmetric information between banks and the government. In an empirical application of our model, we estimate the PPP’s effectiveness and compare it with alternative policies. A policy targeted at the smallest firms could have increased the program’s effectiveness significantly.]]>
</description>
<guid>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedbwp/93557/original</guid>
<dc:creator>Joaquim, Gustavo; Netto, Felipe</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2021-10-01</dc:date>
<rdau:hasExtent>44</rdau:hasExtent>
<dc:subject>Paycheck Protection Program; COVID-19; small business lending; financial frictions</dc:subject>
<swpo:hasNumber>21-16</swpo:hasNumber>
<identifiers:doi>10.29412/res.wp.2021.16</identifiers:doi>
<bibo:series>Working Papers</bibo:series>
</item>
<item>
<title>Bank Incentives and the Effect of the Paycheck Protection Program</title>
<link>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedbwp/93556/original</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[We assess the role of banks in the Paycheck Protection Program (PPP), a large and unprecedented small-business support program instituted as a response to the COVID-19 crisis in the United States. In 2020, the PPP administered more than $525 billion in loans and grants to small businesses through the banking system. First, we provide empirical evidence of heterogeneity in the allocation of PPP loans. Firms that were larger and less affected by the COVID-19 crisis received loans earlier, even in a within-bank analysis. Second, we develop a model of PPP allocation through banks that is consistent with the data. We show that research designs based on bank or regional shocks in PPP disbursement, common in the empirical literature, cannot directly identify the overall effect of the program. Bank targeting implies that these designs can, at best, recover the effect of the PPP on a set of firms that is endogenous, changes over time, and is systematically different from the overall set of firms that ultimately receive PPP loans. We propose and implement a model-based method to estimate the overall effect of the program and find that the PPP saved 7.5 million jobs.]]>
</description>
<guid>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedbwp/93556/original</guid>
<dc:creator>Netto, Felipe; Joaquim, Gustavo</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2021-10-01</dc:date>
<rdau:hasExtent>74</rdau:hasExtent>
<dc:subject>COVID-19; Paycheck Protection Program; small business lending; financial frictions</dc:subject>
<swpo:hasNumber>21-15</swpo:hasNumber>
<identifiers:doi>10.29412/res.wp.2021.15</identifiers:doi>
<bibo:series>Working Papers</bibo:series>
</item>
<item>
<title>On the Origins of the Multinational Premium</title>
<link>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedbwp/93555/original</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[How do foreign direct investment (FDI) dynamics relate to the risk premium of a firm? To answer this question, we compare the stock returns of US firms with different FDI and mergers and acquisitions (M&A) exposure to study the evolution of stock returns as firms expand into foreign markets. We document three empirical regularities. First, there are cross-sectional risk premia associated with both multinational activity and mergers and acquisitions. Second, firm-level stock returns decline when a firm undertakes M&A activity and with merger deepening. Third, future multinational acquirers already have higher stock returns compared with domestic non-acquirers prior to entering foreign markets, indicating that cross-sectional returns differentials are driven by selection based on common unobserved firm characteristics. We find that CEOs play a role in explaining the relationship between firms’ risk premia and foreign expansion. To rationalize these facts, we develop a dynamic model in which management attitudes shape the relationship between firm characteristics, selection into FDI, and risk premia.]]>
</description>
<guid>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedbwp/93555/original</guid>
<dc:creator>Fillat, José; Garetto, Stefania</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2021-10-01</dc:date>
<rdau:hasExtent>46</rdau:hasExtent>
<dc:subject>multinational firms; mergers and acquisitions; stock returns; management</dc:subject>
<swpo:hasNumber>21-20</swpo:hasNumber>
<identifiers:doi>10.29412/res.wp.2021.20</identifiers:doi>
<bibo:series>Working Papers</bibo:series>
</item>
<item>
<title>Job Displacement and Sectoral Mobility</title>
<link>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedbwp/93554/original</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[This paper combines two components of the US Current Population Survey to characterize the relationship between job displacement and sectoral mobility for long-tenured workers over the 1996–2019 period: (1) the cross-sectional Displaced Worker Survey and (2) the 16-month longitudinal design of the Basic Monthly Survey. While displacement negatively correlates with mobility over time, such job loss has a positive causal impact on mobility for displaced workers compared with similar non-displaced workers. Education and industry structure facilitate post-displacement industry switching, and several factors, including business cycles, affect whether the alternative to sectoral mobility is likely to be same-industry employment or nonemployment.]]>
</description>
<guid>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedbwp/93554/original</guid>
<dc:creator>Jackson, Osborne</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2021-10-01</dc:date>
<rdau:hasExtent>35</rdau:hasExtent>
<dc:subject>Displaced Worker Survey; job displacement; sectoral mobility; Current Population Survey</dc:subject>
<swpo:hasNumber>21-19</swpo:hasNumber>
<identifiers:doi>10.29412/res.wp.2021.19</identifiers:doi>
<bibo:series>Working Papers</bibo:series>
</item>
<item>
<title>Corporate Finance and the Transmission of Shocks to the Real Economy</title>
<link>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedbwp/93553/original</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[Credit availability from different sources varies greatly across firms and has firm-level effects on investment decisions and aggregate effects on output. We develop a theoretical framework in which firms decide endogenously at the extensive and intensive margins of different funding sources to study the role of firm choices on the transmission of credit supply shocks to the real economy. As in the data, firms can borrow from different banks, issue bonds, or raise equity through retained earnings to fund productive investment. Our model is calibrated to detailed firm- and loan-level data and reproduces stylized empirical facts: Larger, more productive firms rely on more banks and more sources of funding; smaller firms mostly rely on a small number of banks and internal funding. Our quantitative analysis shows that bank credit supply shocks lead to a sizable reduction in aggregate output, with substantial heterogeneity across firms, due to the lack of substitutability among alternative credit sources. Finally, we show that our insights have important implications for the validity of standard empirical methods used to identify credit supply effects (Khwaja and Mian 2008).]]>
</description>
<guid>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedbwp/93553/original</guid>
<dc:creator>Joaquim, Gustavo; Fillat, José; Bräuning, Falk</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2021-11-01</dc:date>
<rdau:hasExtent>52</rdau:hasExtent>
<dc:subject>shocks transmission; bank-firm matching; firm financing; credit supply shocks</dc:subject>
<swpo:hasNumber>21-18</swpo:hasNumber>
<identifiers:doi>10.29412/res.wp.2021.18</identifiers:doi>
<bibo:series>Working Papers</bibo:series>
</item>
<item>
<title>Did the Affordable Care Act Affect Access to Medications for Opioid Use Disorder among the Already Insured? Evidence from the Rhode Island All-payer Claims Database</title>
<link>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedbwp/93552/original</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[Previous research suggests that state Medicaid expansions implemented under the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (ACA) helped large numbers of patients suffering from opioid use disorder (OUD) gain access to life-saving medications, including buprenorphine. However, Medicaid expansions could have impeded access to care among individuals already enrolled in Medicaid, as new enrollees would have placed added demands on a limited supply of buprenorphine providers. Using a panel data set of medical claims from Rhode Island, we estimate the causal effects of the state’s January 2014 ACA implementation on buprenorphine receipt among incumbent (pre-ACA) Medicaid enrollees by leveraging geographic variation within Rhode Island in the intensity of treatment under the ACA. Using a difference-in-differences identification strategy, multivariate regression analysis yields no evidence that incumbent Medicaid enrollees experienced added 
difficulties in accessing buprenorphine as a result of the ACA, despite the fact that both Medicaid and non-Medicaid enrollment increased substantially under the policy. Supply-side factors may have helped to blunt any negative fallout, as we find that the number of buprenorphine prescribers in the state increased fairly steadily during the two years leading up to January 2014 and for at least 15 months after that date. Also, the average number of buprenorphine recipients per prescriber increased rapidly after January 2014, suggesting that providers had unused treatment capacity before the policy went into effect.]]>
</description>
<guid>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedbwp/93552/original</guid>
<dc:creator>Sullivan, Riley; Yu, Hao; Wharam, James Frank; Burke, Mary A.; Carman, Katherine Grace; Wen, Hefei</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2021-10-01</dc:date>
<rdau:hasExtent>56</rdau:hasExtent>
<dc:subject>Medicaid expansion; opioid use disorder; methadone; buprenorphine; Rhode Island; all-payer claims database</dc:subject>
<swpo:hasNumber>21-17</swpo:hasNumber>
<identifiers:doi>10.29412/res.wp.2021.17</identifiers:doi>
<bibo:series>Working Papers</bibo:series>
</item>
<item>
<title>Opting in with the Joneses: What Affects the Timing of Municipal Adoption of a Local-option Meals Tax?</title>
<link>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedbwp/93550/original</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[States use local-option taxes to promote local revenue diversification and improve local fiscal health. However, many sub-state governments wait a long time before adopting local-option taxes or do not adopt them at all, which seems puzzling or even irrational upon first glance. This paper uses the local-option meals tax in Massachusetts as a case study to examine the factors that affect the timing of local adoptions. It finds significant positive results for adoption by neighboring municipalities, which are robust to a variety of specifications, neighbor definitions, and weighting matrices. The adoption hazard also increases if a municipality faces greater fiscal stress, such as being more constrained by a property tax limitation or receiving a larger cut in state aid. In addition, the form of local government, size of the meals tax base, and ability to export the tax to non-residents are important factors.]]>
</description>
<guid>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedbwp/93550/original</guid>
<dc:creator>Zhao, Bo</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2021-10-01</dc:date>
<rdau:hasExtent>29</rdau:hasExtent>
<dc:subject>hazard models; fiscal stress; policy diffusion; local-option tax; yardstick competition</dc:subject>
<swpo:hasNumber>21-14</swpo:hasNumber>
<identifiers:doi>10.29412/res.wp.2021.14</identifiers:doi>
<bibo:series>Working Papers</bibo:series>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>