<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<rdf:RDF
 xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
 xmlns="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/"
 xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
 xmlns:taxo="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/taxonomy/"
 xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
 xmlns:syn="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
 xmlns:admin="http://webns.net/mvcb/"
>

<channel rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/">
<title>stat.AP updates on arXiv.org</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">Statistics -- Applications (stat.AP) updates on the arXiv.org e-print archive</description>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:date>2022-11-03T20:30:00-05:00</dc:date>
<dc:publisher>help@arxiv.org</dc:publisher>
<dc:subject>Statistics -- Applications</dc:subject>
<syn:updateBase>1901-01-01T00:00+00:00</syn:updateBase>
<syn:updateFrequency>1</syn:updateFrequency>
<syn:updatePeriod>daily</syn:updatePeriod>
<items>
 <rdf:Seq>
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01457" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01955" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.02020" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.02023" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2010.13599" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2105.08013" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2202.10085" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2205.04539" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2207.04805" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2208.06727" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.01757" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.13133" />
 </rdf:Seq>
</items>
<image rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif" />
</channel>
<image rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif">
<title>arXiv.org</title>
<url>http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif</url>
<link>http://arxiv.org/</link>
</image>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01457">
<title>Small area estimation using multiple imputation in three-parameter logistic models. (arXiv:2211.01457v1 [stat.AP])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01457</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We propose a novel methodology relating item response theory methods with
small area estimation strategies in the presence of missing data. Specifically,
we propose an unbiased estimator for the average ability parameter of
three-parameter logistic models. Thus, we carry out an extensive simulation
study in order to compare our estimator with the well-known Horvitz-Thompson
estimator. According to our experiments with synthetic data, our proposal has
substantial lower standard errors than its competitor. In addition, we perform
an actual application by considering the Mathematics results of the 2015
Program for International Student Assessment (PISA), and also, compare our
results with previous analyses. Our findings strongly suggest that our
methodology is a high competitive alternative for generating compelling
official statistics.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/stat/1/au:+Tellez_Pinerez_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Cristian Tellez-Pi&amp;#xf1;erez&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/stat/1/au:+Trujillo_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Leonardo Trujillo&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/stat/1/au:+Gutierrez_Rojas_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Andr&amp;#xe9;s Guti&amp;#xe9;rrez-Rojas&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/stat/1/au:+Sosa_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Juan Sosa&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01955">
<title>Quantifying the `end of history&apos; through a Bayesian Markov-chain approach. (arXiv:2211.01955v1 [physics.soc-ph])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01955</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Political regimes have been changing throughout human history. After the
apparent triumph of liberal democracies at the end of the twentieth century,
Francis Fukuyama and others have been arguing that humankind is approaching an
`end of history&apos; (EoH) in the form of a universality of liberal democracies.
This view has been challenged by recent developments that seem to indicate the
rise of defective democracies across the globe. There has been no attempt to
quantify the expected EoH with a statistical approach. In this study, we model
the transition between political regimes as a Markov process and -- using a
Bayesian inference approach -- we estimate the transition probabilities between
political regimes from time-series data describing the evolution of political
regimes from 1800--2018. We then compute the steady state for this Markov
process which represents a mathematical abstraction of the EoH and predicts
that approximately 46 % of countries will be full democracies. Furthermore, we
find that, under our model, the fraction of autocracies in the world is
expected to increase for the next half-century before it declines. Using
random-walk theory, we then estimate survival curves of different types of
regimes and estimate characteristic lifetimes of democracies and autocracies of
244 years and 69 years, respectively. Quantifying the expected EoH allows us to
challenge common beliefs about the nature of political equilibria.
Specifically, we find no statistical evidence that the EoH constitutes a fixed,
complete omnipresence of democratic regimes.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Klimm_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Florian Klimm&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.02020">
<title>Sensitivity of Bayesian Casual Forests to Modeling Choices: A Re-analysis of the 2022 ACIC Data Challenge. (arXiv:2211.02020v1 [stat.AP])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.02020</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We demonstrate how Hahn et al.&apos;s Bayesian Causal Forests model (BCF) can be
used to estimate conditional average treatment effects for the longitudinal
dataset in the 2022 American Causal Inference Conference Data Challenge.
Unfortunately, existing implementations of BCF do not scale to the size of the
challenge data. Therefore, we developed flexBCF -- a more scalable and flexible
implementation of BCF -- and used it in our challenge submission. We
investigate the sensitivity of our results to two ad hoc modeling choices we
made during our initial submission: (i) the choice of propensity score
estimation method and (ii) the use of sparsity-inducing regression tree priors.
While we found that our overall point predictions were not especially sensitive
to these modeling choices, we did observe that running BCF with flexibly
estimated propensity scores often yielded better-calibrated uncertainty
intervals.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/stat/1/au:+Kokandakar_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ajinkya H. Kokandakar&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/stat/1/au:+Kang_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Hyunseung Kang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/stat/1/au:+Deshpande_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Sameer K. Deshpande&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.02023">
<title>Research on the impact of asteroid mining on global equity. (arXiv:2211.02023v1 [physics.soc-ph])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.02023</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;In the future situation, aiming to seek more resources, human beings decided
to march towards the mysterious and bright starry sky, which opened the era of
great interstellar exploration. According to the Outer Space Treaty, any
exploration of celestial bodies should be aimed at promoting global equality
and for the benefit of all nations. Firstly, we defined global equity and set a
Unified Equity Index (UEI) model to measure it. We merge the factors with
greater correlation, and finally, get 6 elements, and then use the entropy
method (TEM) to find the dispersion of these elements in different countries.
Then use principal component analysis (PCA) to reduce the dimensionality of the
dispersion, and then use the scandalized index to obtain the global equity.
Secondly, we simulated a future with asteroid mining and evaluated its impact
on Unified Equity Index (UEI). Then, we divided the mineable asteroids into
three classes with different mining difficulties and values, identified 28
mining entities including private companies, national and international
organizations. We considered changes in the asteroid classes, mining
capabilities and mining scales to determine the changes in the value of
minerals mined between 2025 and 2085. We convert mining output value into
mineral transaction value through allocation matrix. Based on grey relational
analysis (GRA). Finally, we presented three possible versions of the future of
asteroid mining by changing the conditions. We propose two sets of
corresponding policies for changes in future trends in global fairness with
asteroid mining. We test the separate and combined effects of these policies
and find that they are positive, strongly supporting the effectiveness of our
model.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Sun_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;He Sun&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Zhu_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Junfeng Zhu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Xu_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yipeng Xu&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2010.13599">
<title>Design-Based Inference for Spatial Experiments with Interference. (arXiv:2010.13599v3 [stat.ME] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2010.13599</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We consider design-based causal inference in settings where randomized
treatments have effects that bleed out into space in complex ways that overlap
and in violation of the standard &quot;no interference&quot; assumption for many causal
inference methods. We define a spatial &quot;average marginalized response,&quot; which
characterizes how, in expectation, units of observation that are a specified
distance from an intervention point are affected by treatments at that point,
averaging over effects emanating from other intervention points. We establish
conditions for non-parametric identification, asymptotic distributions of
estimators, and recovery of structural effects. We propose methods for both
sample-theoretic and permutation-based inference. We provide illustrations
using randomized field experiments on forest conservation and health.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/stat/1/au:+Wang_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ye Wang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/stat/1/au:+Samii_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Cyrus Samii&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/stat/1/au:+Chang_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Haoge Chang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/stat/1/au:+Aronow_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;P.M. Aronow&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2105.08013">
<title>What makes you unique?. (arXiv:2105.08013v3 [stat.AP] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2105.08013</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;This paper proposes a uniqueness Shapley measure to compare the extent to
which different variables are able to identify a subject. Revealing the value
of a variable on subject $t$ shrinks the set of possible subjects that $t$
could be. The extent of the shrinkage depends on which other variables have
also been revealed. We use Shapley value to combine all of the reductions in
log cardinality due to revealing a variable after some subset of the other
variables has been revealed. This uniqueness Shapley measure can be aggregated
over subjects where it becomes a weighted sum of conditional entropies.
Aggregation over subsets of subjects can address questions like how identifying
is age for people of a given zip code. Such aggregates have a corresponding
expression in terms of cross entropies. We use uniqueness Shapley to
investigate the differential effects of revealing variables from the North
Carolina voter registration rolls and in identifying anomalous solar flares. An
enormous speedup (approaching 2000 fold in one example) is obtained by using
the all dimension trees of Moore and Lee (1998) to store the cardinalities we
need.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/stat/1/au:+Seiler_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Benjamin B. Seiler&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/stat/1/au:+Mase_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Masayoshi Mase&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/stat/1/au:+Owen_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Art B. Owen&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2202.10085">
<title>Bettors&apos; reaction to match dynamics -- Evidence from in-game betting. (arXiv:2202.10085v2 [stat.AP] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2202.10085</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;It is still largely unclear to what extent bettors update their prior
assumptions about the strength and form of competing teams considering the
dynamics during the match. This is of interest not only from the psychological
perspective, but also as the pricing of live odds ideally should be driven both
by the (objective) outcome probabilities and also the bettors&apos; behaviour. Using
state-space models (SSMs) to account for the dynamically evolving latent
sentiment of the betting market, we analyse a unique high-frequency data set on
stakes placed during the match. We find that stakes in the live-betting market
are driven both by perceived pre-game strength and by in-game strength, the
latter as measured by the Valuing Actions by Estimating Probabilities (VAEP)
approach. Both effects vary over the course of the match.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/stat/1/au:+Michels_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Rouven Michels&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/stat/1/au:+Otting_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Marius &amp;#xd6;tting&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/stat/1/au:+Langrock_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Roland Langrock&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2205.04539">
<title>Efficient algorithms for building representative matched pairs with enhanced generalizability. (arXiv:2205.04539v2 [stat.ME] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2205.04539</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Many recent efforts center on assessing the ability of real-world evidence
(RWE) generated from non-randomized, observational data to produce results
compatible with those from randomized controlled trials (RCTs). One noticeable
endeavor is the RCT DUPLICATE initiative (Franklin et al., 2020, 2021). To
better reconcile findings from an observational study and an RCT, or two
observational studies based on different databases, it is desirable to
eliminate differences between study populations. We outline an efficient,
network-flow-based statistical matching algorithm that designs well-matched
pairs from observational data that resemble the covariate distributions of a
target population, for instance, the target-RCT-eligible population in the RCT
DUPLICATE initiative studies or a generic population of scientific interest. We
demonstrate the usefulness of the method by revisiting the inconsistency
regarding a cardioprotective effect of the hormone replacement therapy (HRT) in
the Women&apos;s Health Initiative (WHI) clinical trial and corresponding
observational study. We found that the discrepancy between the trial and
observational study persisted in a design that adjusted for study populations&apos;
cardiovascular risk profile, but seemed to disappear in a study design that
further adjusted for the HRT initiation age and previous
estrogen-plus-progestin use. The proposed method is integrated into the R
package match2C.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/stat/1/au:+Zhang_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Bo Zhang&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2207.04805">
<title>Monitoring pollution pathways in river water by predictive path modelling using untargeted GC-MS measurements. (arXiv:2207.04805v3 [stat.AP] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2207.04805</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;A comprehensive approach to protect river water quality is needed within the
European Water Framework Directive. Non-target screening of a complete chemical
fingerprint of the aquatic ecosystem is essential, to identify chemicals of
emerging concern and to reveal their suspicious dynamic patterns in river
water. This requires a new combination of two measurement paradigms: the path
of potential pollution should be traced through the river network, while there
may be many compounds that make up this chemical composition - both known and
unknown. Dedicated data processing of ongoing GC-MS measurements at 9 sites
along the Rhine using PARAFAC2 for non-target screening, combined with
spatiotemporal modelling of these sites within the river network using path
modelling (Process PLS), provided a new integrated approach to track chemicals
through the Rhine catchment, and tentatively identify known and as-yet unknown
potential pollutants based on non-target screening and spatiotemporal
behaviour.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/stat/1/au:+Cairoli_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Maria Cairoli&lt;/a&gt; (1), &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/stat/1/au:+Doel_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Andr&amp;#xe9; van den Doel&lt;/a&gt; (1), &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/stat/1/au:+Postma_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Berber Postma&lt;/a&gt; (1), &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/stat/1/au:+Offermans_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Tim Offermans&lt;/a&gt; (1), &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/stat/1/au:+Zemmelink_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Henk Zemmelink&lt;/a&gt; (2), &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/stat/1/au:+Stroomberg_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Gerard Stroomberg&lt;/a&gt; (1 and 3), &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/stat/1/au:+Buydens_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Lutgarde Buydens&lt;/a&gt; (1), &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/stat/1/au:+Kollenburg_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Geert van Kollenburg&lt;/a&gt; (1 and 4), &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/stat/1/au:+Jansen_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jeroen Jansen&lt;/a&gt; (1) ((1) Radboud University, Department of Analytical Chemistry &amp;amp; Chemometrics, Nijmegen, The Netherlands (2) Rijkswaterstaat, Lelystad, The Netherlands (3) RIWA Rijn, Nieuwegein, The Netherlands (4) Eindhoven University of Technology, Interconnected Resource-aware Intelligent Systems, Eindhoven, The Netherlands)</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2208.06727">
<title>Reliable emulation of complex functionals by active learning with error control. (arXiv:2208.06727v2 [physics.chem-ph] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2208.06727</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;A statistical emulator can be used as a surrogate of complex physics-based
calculations to drastically reduce the computational cost. Its successful
implementation hinges on an accurate representation of the nonlinear response
surface with a high-dimensional input space. Conventional ``space-filling&apos;&apos;
designs, including random sampling and Latin hypercube sampling, become
inefficient as the dimensionality of the input variables increases, and the
predictive accuracy of the emulator can degrade substantially for a test input
distant from the training input set. To address this fundamental challenge, we
develop a reliable emulator for predicting complex functionals by active
learning with error control (ALEC). The algorithm is applicable to
infinite-dimensional mapping with high-fidelity predictions and a controlled
predictive error. The computational efficiency has been demonstrated by
emulating the classical density functional theory (cDFT) calculations, a
statistical-mechanical method widely used in modeling the equilibrium
properties of complex molecular systems. We show that ALEC is much more
accurate than conventional emulators based on the Gaussian processes with
``space-filling&apos;&apos; designs and alternative active learning methods. Besides, it
is computationally more efficient than direct cDFT calculations. ALEC can be a
reliable building block for emulating expensive functionals owing to its
minimal computational cost, controllable predictive error, and fully automatic
features.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Fang_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xinyi Fang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Gu_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Mengyang Gu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Wu_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jianzhong Wu&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.01757">
<title>Purely prognostic variables may modify marginal treatment effects for non-collapsible effect measures. (arXiv:2210.01757v3 [stat.ME] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.01757</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;In evidence synthesis, effect measure modifiers are typically described as
variables that induce treatment effect heterogeneity at the individual level,
through treatment-covariate interactions in an outcome model parametrized at
such level. As such, effect modification is defined with respect to a
conditional measure. However, marginal effect estimates are required for
population-level decisions in health technology assessment. For non-collapsible
effect measures, purely prognostic variables that do not predict response to
treatment at the individual level may modify marginal treatment effects at the
population level. This has important implications for recommended practices for
evidence synthesis. Firstly, unadjusted indirect comparisons of marginal
effects may be biased in the absence of individual-level treatment effect
heterogeneity. Secondly, covariate adjustment may be necessary to account for
cross-study imbalances in purely prognostic variables. Popular summary measures
in meta-analysis such as odds ratios and hazard ratios are non-collapsible.
Collapsible measures would facilitate the transportability of marginal effects
between studies by: (1) removing dependence on model-based covariate adjustment
when there is treatment effect homogeneity at the individual level; and (2)
facilitating the selection of baseline characteristics for covariate adjustment
when there is heterogeneity.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/stat/1/au:+Remiro_Azocar_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Antonio Remiro-Az&amp;#xf3;car&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.13133">
<title>Markov-modulated marked Poisson processes for modelling disease dynamics based on medical claims data. (arXiv:2210.13133v2 [stat.AP] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.13133</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We explore Markov-modulated marked Poisson processes (MMMPPs) as a natural
framework for modelling patients&apos; disease dynamics over time based on medical
claims data. In claims data, observations do not only occur at random points in
time but are also informative, i.e. driven by unobserved disease levels, as
poor health conditions usually lead to more frequent interactions with the
healthcare system. Therefore, we model the observation process as a
Markov-modulated Poisson process, where the rate of healthcare interactions is
governed by a continuous-time Markov chain. Its states serve as proxies for the
patients&apos; latent disease levels and further determine the distribution of
additional data collected at each observation time, the so-called marks.
Overall, MMMPPs jointly model observations and their informative time points by
comprising two state-dependent processes: the observation process
(corresponding to the event times) and the mark process (corresponding to
event-specific information), which both depend on the underlying states. The
approach is illustrated using claims data from patients diagnosed with chronic
obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD) by modelling their drug use and the
interval lengths between consecutive physician consultations. The results
indicate that MMMPPs are able to detect distinct patterns of healthcare
utilisation related to disease processes and reveal inter-individual
differences in the state-switching dynamics.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/stat/1/au:+Mews_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Sina Mews&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/stat/1/au:+Surmann_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Bastian Surmann&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/stat/1/au:+Hasemann_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Lena Hasemann&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/stat/1/au:+Elkenkamp_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Svenja Elkenkamp&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
</rdf:RDF>