<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<rdf:RDF
 xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
 xmlns="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/"
 xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
 xmlns:taxo="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/taxonomy/"
 xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
 xmlns:syn="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
 xmlns:admin="http://webns.net/mvcb/"
>

<channel rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/">
<title>astro-ph.IM updates on arXiv.org</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">Astrophysics -- Instrumentation and Methods for Astrophysics (astro-ph.IM) updates on the arXiv.org e-print archive</description>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:date>2022-11-03T20:30:00-05:00</dc:date>
<dc:publisher>help@arxiv.org</dc:publisher>
<dc:subject>Astrophysics -- Instrumentation and Methods for Astrophysics</dc:subject>
<syn:updateBase>1901-01-01T00:00+00:00</syn:updateBase>
<syn:updateFrequency>1</syn:updateFrequency>
<syn:updatePeriod>daily</syn:updatePeriod>
<items>
 <rdf:Seq>
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01393" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01401" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01449" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01459" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01502" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01532" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01567" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01682" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01718" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01767" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01880" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01891" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01901" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01927" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01935" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.02041" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.02045" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2009.10813" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.14890" />
 </rdf:Seq>
</items>
<image rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif" />
</channel>
<image rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif">
<title>arXiv.org</title>
<url>http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif</url>
<link>http://arxiv.org/</link>
</image>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01393">
<title>Exploring diffuse radio emission in galaxy clusters and groups with the uGMRT and the SKA. (arXiv:2211.01393v1 [astro-ph.CO])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01393</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Diffuse radio emission has been detected in a considerable number of galaxy
clusters and groups, revealing the presence of pervasive cosmic magnetic
fields, and of relativistic particles in the large-scale structure (LSS) of the
Universe. Since cluster radio emission is faint and steep spectrum, its
observations are largely limited by the instrument sensitivity and frequency of
observation, leading to a dearth of information, more so for lower-mass
systems. The unprecedented sensitivity of recently commissioned low-frequency
radio telescope arrays, aided by the development of advanced calibration and
imaging techniques, have helped in achieving unparalleled image quality. At the
same time, the development of sophisticated numerical simulations and the
availability of supercomputing facilities have paved the way for
high-resolution numerical modeling of radio emission, and the structure of the
cosmic magnetic fields in LSS, leading to predictions matching the capabilities
of observational facilities. In view of these rapidly-evolving scenerio in
modeling and observations, in this review, we summarise the role of the new
telescope arrays and the development of advanced imaging techniques and discuss
the detections of various kinds of cluster radio sources. In particular, we
discuss observations of the cosmic web in the form of supercluster filaments,
studies of emission in poor clusters and groups of galaxies, and of ultra-steep
spectrum sources. We also review the current theoretical understanding of
various diffuse cluster radio sources and the associated magnetic field and
polarization. As the statistics of detections improve along with our
theoretical understanding, we update the source classification schemes based on
their intrinsic properties. We conclude by summarising the role of the upgraded
GMRT and our expectations from the upcoming Square Kilometre Array (SKA)
observatories.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Paul_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Surajit Paul&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Kale_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ruta Kale&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Datta_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Abhirup Datta&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Basu_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Aritra Basu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Sur_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Sharanya Sur&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Parekh_V/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Viral Parekh&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Gupta_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Prateek Gupta&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Chatterjee_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Swarna Chatterjee&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Salunkhe_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Sameer Salunkhe&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Iqbal_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Asif Iqbal&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Pandey_Pommier_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Mamta Pandey-Pommier&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Raja_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ramij Raja&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Rahaman_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Majidul Rahaman&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Raychaudhury_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Somak Raychaudhury&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Nath_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Biman B. Nath&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Majumdar_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Subhabrata Majumdar&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01401">
<title>Efficient Gravitational Wave Searches with Pulsar Timing Arrays using Hamiltonian Monte Carlo. (arXiv:2211.01401v1 [astro-ph.IM])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01401</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Pulsar timing arrays (PTAs) detect low-frequency gravitational waves (GWs) by
looking for correlated deviations in pulse arrival times. Current Bayesian
searches use Markov Chain Monte Carlo (MCMC) methods, which struggle to sample
the large number of parameters needed to model the PTA and GW signals. As the
data span and number of pulsars increase, this problem will only worsen. An
alternative Monte Carlo sampling method, Hamiltonian Monte Carlo (HMC),
utilizes Hamiltonian dynamics to produce sample proposals informed by
first-order gradients of the model likelihood. This in turn allows it to
converge faster to high dimensional distributions. We implement HMC as an
alternative sampling method in our search for an isotropic stochastic GW
background, and show that this method produces equivalent statistical results
to similar analyses run with standard MCMC techniques, while requiring 100-200
times fewer samples. We show that the speed of HMC sample generation scales as
$\mathcal{O}(N_\mathrm{psr}^{5/4})$ where $N_\mathrm{psr}$ is the number of
pulsars, compared to $\mathcal{O}(N_\mathrm{psr}^2)$ for MCMC methods. These
factors offset the increased time required to generate a sample using HMC,
demonstrating the value of adopting HMC techniques for PTAs.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Freedman_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Gabriel E. Freedman&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Johnson_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Aaron D. Johnson&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Haasteren_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Rutger van Haasteren&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Vigeland_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Sarah J. Vigeland&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01449">
<title>The Fifth Catalogue of Nearby Stars (CNS5). (arXiv:2211.01449v1 [astro-ph.SR])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01449</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We present the compilation of the Fifth Catalogue of Nearby Stars (CNS5),
based on astrometric and photometric data from Gaia EDR3 and Hipparcos, and
supplemented with parallaxes from ground-based astrometric surveys carried out
in the infrared.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The aim of the CNS5 is to provide the most complete sample of objects in the
solar neighbourhood. For all known stars and brown dwarfs in the 25 pc sphere
around the Sun, basic astrometric and photometric parameters are given.
Furthermore, we provide the colour-magnitude diagram and various luminosity
functions of the stellar content in the solar neighbourhood, and characterise
the completeness of the CNS5 catalogue.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We compile a sample of stars and brown dwarfs which most likely are located
within 25 pc of the Sun, taking space-based parallaxes from Gaia EDR3 and
Hipparcos as well as ground-based parallaxes from Best et al. (2021),
Kirkpatrick et al. (2021), and from the CNS4 into account. We develop a set of
selection criteria to clean the sample from spurious sources. Furthermore, we
show that effects of blending in the Gaia photometry, which affect mainly the
faint and red sources in Gaia, can be mitigated, to reliably place those
objects in a colour-magnitude diagram. We also assess the completeness of the
CNS5 using a Kolmogorov-Smirnov test and derive observational optical and
mid-infrared luminosity functions for the main-sequence stars and white dwarfs
in the solar neighbourhood. The CNS5 contains 5931 objects, including 5230
stars (4946 main-sequence stars, 20 red giants and 264 white dwarfs) and 701
brown dwarfs.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We find that the CNS5 catalogue is statistically complete down to 19.7 mag in
G-band and 11.8 mag in W1-band absolute magnitudes, corresponding to a spectral
type of L8.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Golovin_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Alex Golovin&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Reffert_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Sabine Reffert&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Just_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Andreas Just&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Jordan_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Stefan Jordan&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Vani_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Akash Vani&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Jahreiss_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Hartmut Jahrei&amp;#xdf;&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01459">
<title>Spectroscopic Time-series Performance of JWST/NIRSpec from Commissioning Observations. (arXiv:2211.01459v1 [astro-ph.EP])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01459</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We report on JWST commissioning observations of the transiting exoplanet
HAT-P-14 b, obtained using the Bright Object Time Series (BOTS) mode of the
NIRSpec instrument with the G395H/F290LP grating/filter combination
($3-5\mu$m). While the data were used primarily to verify that the NIRSpec BOTS
mode is working as expected, and to enable it for general scientific use, they
yield a precise transmission spectrum which we find is featureless down to the
precision level of the instrument, consistent with expectations given
HAT-P-14~b&apos;s small scale-height and hence expected atmospheric features. The
exquisite quality and stability of the \emph{JWST/NIRSpec} transit spectrum --
almost devoid of any systematic effects -- allowed us to obtain median
uncertainties of 50-60 ppm in this wavelength range at a resolution of $R=100$
in a single exposure, which is in excellent agreement with pre-flight
expectations and close to the (or at the) photon-noise limit for a $J = 9.094$,
F-type star like HAT-P-14. These observations showcase the ability of
NIRSpec/BOTS to perform cutting-edge transiting exoplanet atmospheric science,
setting the stage for observations and discoveries to be made in Cycle 1 and
beyond.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Espinoza_N/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;N&amp;#xe9;stor Espinoza&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Ubeda_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Leonardo &amp;#xda;beda&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Birkmann_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Stephan M. Birkmann&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Ferruit_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Pierre Ferruit&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Valenti_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jeff A. Valenti&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Sing_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;David K. Sing&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Rustamkulov_Z/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Zafar Rustamkulov&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Regan_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Michael Regan&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Kendrew_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Sarah Kendrew&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Sabbi_E/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Elena Sabbi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Schlawin_E/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Everett Schlawin&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Beatty_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Thomas Beatty&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Albert_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Lo&amp;#xef;c Albert&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Greene_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Thomas P. Greene&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Nikolov_N/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Nikolay Nikolov&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Karakla_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Diane Karakla&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Keyes_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Charles Keyes&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Kumari_N/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Nimisha Kumari&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Oliveira_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Catarina Alves de Oliveira&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Boker_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Torsten B&amp;#xf6;ker&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Pena_Guerrero_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Maria Pe&amp;#xf1;a-Guerrero&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Giardino_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Giovanna Giardino&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Manjavacas_E/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Elena Manjavacas&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Proffitt_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Charles Proffitt&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Rawle_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Timothy Rawle&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01502">
<title>Detection and characterization of wind-blown charged sand grains on Titan with the DraGMet/EFIELD experiment on Dragonfly. (arXiv:2211.01502v1 [astro-ph.EP])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01502</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The EFIELD instrument is part of the geophysics and meteorology sensor
package DraGMet on the Dragonfly mission, which will explore the surface of
Titan in the mid-2030s. EFIELD consists of two electrodes designed to passively
record the AC electric field at each landing site.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The exploration zone of Dragonfly will mostly consist of dune fields, covered
with sand grains. Little is known on the properties of these grains, although
Cassini-Huygens observations suggest they are mostly made of organic material
produced by Titan&apos;s atmospheric photochemistry and evolved at the surface.
Little is known also about dune formation and in general about the transport of
sediments by winds. The latter much depends on inter-particle forces and
therefore on how grains are charged by friction. We demonstrate here that the
EFIELD experiment can bring new insights on these questions.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have developed a hydrodynamic-electrostatic model to simulate the
trajectory of a wind-blown charged sand grain in the vicinity of an idealized
EFIELD probe and to predict how such a grain flying close to the probe would
affect its potential. We show that, in some conditions, the resulting
perturbation will be strong enough to be detected by the EFIELD probe. More
specifically, we find that the detection of typical charged wind-blown grains
(200 microns) on Titan requires an instrument standard deviation noise inferior
to 1mV, though occasional larger grains flying close to one electrode could be
detected with a higher noise level.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, we propose a method to retrieve information on the charge and
velocity of wind-blown charged grains detected by the EFIELD experiment. This
method well applies for cases where the particle trajectory can be regarded as
quasi-linear. We validate our inversion approach on both synthetic and
experimental data obtained with a laboratory prototype of the EFIELD
experiment.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Chatain_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Audrey Chatain&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Gall_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Alice Le Gall&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Berthelier_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jean-Jacques Berthelier&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Lorenz_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ralph D. Lorenz&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Hassen_Khodja_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Rafik Hassen-Khodja&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Lebreton_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jean-Pierre Lebreton&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Joly_Jehenne_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Tom Joly-Jehenne&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Deprez_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Gr&amp;#xe9;goire D&amp;#xe9;prez&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01532">
<title>A 16 Hour Transit Observed by the Unistellar Network. (arXiv:2211.01532v1 [astro-ph.EP])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01532</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;More than 5,000 exoplanets have been confirmed and among them almost 4,000
were discovered by the transit method. However, few transiting exoplanets have
an orbital period greater than 100 days. Here we report a transit detection of
Kepler-167 e, a &quot;Jupiter analog&quot; exoplanet orbiting a K4 star with a period of
1,071 days, using the Unistellar ground-based telescope network. From 2021
November 18 to 20, citizen astronomers located in nine different countries
gathered 43 observations, covering the 16 hour long transit. Using a nested
sampling approach to combine and fit the observations, we detected the
mid-transit time to be UTC 2021 November 19 17:20:51 with a 1$\sigma$
uncertainty of 9.8 minutes, making it the longest-period planet to ever have
its transit detected from the ground. This is the fourth transit detection of
Kepler-167 e, but the first made from the ground. This timing measurement
refines the orbit and keeps the ephemeris up to date without requiring space
telescopes. Observations like this demonstrate the capabilities of coordinated
networks of small telescopes to identify and characterize planets with long
orbital periods.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Perrocheau_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Amaury Perrocheau&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Esposito_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Thomas M. Esposito&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Dalba_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Paul A. Dalba&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Marchis_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Franck Marchis&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Avsar_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Arin M. Avsar&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Carrera_E/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ero Carrera&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Douezy_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Michel Douezy&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Fukui_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Keiichi Fukui&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Gamurot_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ryan Gamurot&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Goto_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Tateki Goto&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Guillet_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Bruno Guillet&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Kuossari_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Petri Kuossari&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Laugier_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jean-Marie Laugier&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Lewin_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Pablo Lewin&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Loose_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Margaret A. Loose&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Manganese_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Laurent Manganese&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Mirwald_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Benjamin Mirwald&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Mountz_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Hubert Mountz&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Mountz_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Marti Mountz&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Ostrem_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Cory Ostrem&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Parker_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Bruce Parker&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Picard_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Patrick Picard&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Primm_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Michael Primm&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Randolph_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Justus Randolph&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Runge_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jay Runge&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Savonnet_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Robert Savonnet&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Sharon_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Chelsea E. Sharon&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Shih_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jenny Shih&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Shimizu_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Masao Shimizu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Silvis_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;George Silvis&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Simard_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Georges Simard&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Simpson_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Alan Simpson&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Sivayogan_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Thusheeta Sivayogan&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Stein_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Meyer Stein&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Trudel_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Denis Trudel&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Tsuchiyama_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Hiroaki Tsuchiyama&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Wagner_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Kevin Wagner&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Will_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Stefan Will&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01567">
<title>Galaxy Image Deconvolution for Weak Gravitational Lensing with Physics-informed Deep Learning. (arXiv:2211.01567v1 [astro-ph.IM])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01567</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Removing optical and atmospheric blur from galaxy images significantly
improves galaxy shape measurements for weak gravitational lensing and galaxy
evolution studies. This ill-posed linear inverse problem is usually solved with
deconvolution algorithms enhanced by regularisation priors or deep learning. We
introduce a so-called &quot;physics-based deep learning&quot; approach to the Point
Spread Function (PSF) deconvolution problem in galaxy surveys. We apply
algorithm unrolling and the Plug-and-Play technique to the Alternating
Direction Method of Multipliers (ADMM) with a Poisson noise model and use a
neural network to learn appropriate priors from simulated galaxy images. We
characterise the time-performance trade-off of several methods for galaxies of
differing brightness levels, showing an improvement of 26% (SNR=20)/48%
(SNR=100) compared to standard methods and 14% (SNR=20) compared to modern
methods.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Li_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Tianao Li&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Alexander_E/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Emma Alexander&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01682">
<title>First Lunar Occultation Results with the TIRCAM2 Near-Infrared Imager at the Devasthal 3.6-m Telescope. (arXiv:2211.01682v1 [astro-ph.SR])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01682</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;TIRCAM2 is the facility near-infrared Imager at the Devasthal 3.6-m telescope
in northern India, equipped with an Aladdin III InSb array detector. We have
pioneered the use of TIRCAM2 for very fast photometry, with the aim of
recording Lunar Occultations (LO). This mode is now operational and publicly
offered. In this paper we describe the relevant instrumental details, we
provide references to the LO method and the underlying data analysis
procedures, and we list the LO events recorded so far. Among the results, we
highlight a few which have led to the measurement of one small-separation
binary star and of two stellar angular diameters. We conclude with a brief
outlook on further possible instrumental developments and an estimate of the
scientific return. In particular, we find that the LO technique can detect
sources down to K~ 9 mag with SNR=1 on the DOT telescope. Angular diameters
larger than ~ 1 milliarcsecond (mas) could be measured with SNR above 10, or
K~6 mag. These numbers are only an indication and will depend strongly on
observing conditions such as lunar phase and rate of lunar limb motion. Based
on statistics alone, there are several thousands LO events observable in
principle with the given telescope and instrument every year.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Sharma_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Saurabh Sharma&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Richichi_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Andrea Richichi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Ojha_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Devendra K. Ojha&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Kumar_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Brajesh Kumar&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Naik_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Milind Naik&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Rawat_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jeewan Rawat&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Bora_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Darshan S. Bora&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Belwal_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Kuldeep Belwal&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Dhami_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Prakash Dhami&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Bisht_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Mohit Bisht&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01718">
<title>The SPHERE view of multiple star formation. (arXiv:2211.01718v1 [astro-ph.SR])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01718</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;While a large fraction of the stars are in multiple systems, our
understanding of the processes leading to the formation of these systems is
still inadequate. Given the large theoretical uncertainties, observation plays
a basic role. Here we discuss the contribution of high contrast imaging, and
more specifically of the SPHERE instrument at the ESO Very Large Telescope, in
this area. SPHERE nicely complements other techniques - in particular those
exploiting Gaia and ALMA - in detecting and characterising systems near the
peak of the distribution with separation and allows to capture snapshots of
binary formation within disks that are invaluable for the understanding of disk
fragmentation.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Gratton_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;R.Gratton&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Desidera_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;S. Desidera&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Marzari_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;F. Marzari&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Bonavita_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;M. Bonavita&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01767">
<title>Redefining Astronomy Summer Camps in the Age of the Pandemic: a Break from the IAYC&apos;s 50-Year History. (arXiv:2211.01767v1 [physics.ed-ph])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01767</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The International Astronomical Youth Camp (IAYC) is a 50-year old summer
camp, where participants work independently on astronomy projects. Due to the
ongoing COVID-19 pandemic, the 2020 and 2021 instalments of the IAYC were
cancelled, a first in the camp&apos;s history. An online format was established
dubbed the eIAYC, consisting of three types of activities: (1) an engagement
series with astronomical talks and workshops; (2) small independent research
projects; and (3) a non-astronomical program involving a range of social
activities. Here we present the experience of adapting an in-person camp into
an online alternative in order to further the IAYC&apos;s mission. We discuss
organisational challenges, experiences with online engagement, and how the 2020
eIAYC informed plans for this year&apos;s eIAYC.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Ahrer_E/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Eva-Maria Ahrer&lt;/a&gt; (1 and 2), &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Archipley_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Melanie Archipley&lt;/a&gt; (1 and 3), &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Dalgleish_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Hannah S. Dalgleish&lt;/a&gt; (1 and 4), &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Mortimer_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Daniel J. Mortimer&lt;/a&gt; (1 and 5) ((1) International Workshop for Astronomy e.V., (2) University of Warwick, (3) University of Illinois Urbana-Champaign, (4) University of Namibia, (5) University of Cambridge)</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01880">
<title>Performance of different correction maps in the extended phase-space method for spinning compact binaries. (arXiv:2211.01880v1 [gr-qc])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01880</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Since the first detection of gravitational waves by the LIGO/VIRGO team, the
related research field has attracted more attention. The spinning compact
binaries system, as one of the gravitational-wave sources for broadband laser
interferometers, has been widely studied by related researchers. In order to
analyze the gravitational wave signals using matched filtering techniques,
reliable numerical algorithms are needed. Spinning compact binaries systems in
Post-Newtonian (PN) celestial mechanics have an inseparable Hamiltonian. The
extended phase-space algorithm is an effective solution for the problem of this
system. We have developed correction maps for the extended phase-space method
in our previous work, which significantly improves the accuracy and stability
of the method with only a momentum scale factor. In this paper, we will add
more scale factors to modify the numerical solution in order to minimize the
errors in the constants of motion. However, we find that these correction maps
will result in a large energy bias in the subterms of the Hamiltonian in
chaotic orbits, whose potential and kinetic energy, etc. are calculated
inaccurately. We develop new correction maps to reduce the energy bias of the
subterms of the Hamiltonian, which can instead improve the accuracy of the
numerical solution and also provides a new idea for the application of the
manifold correction in other algorithms.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Luo_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Junjie Luo&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Feng_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jie Feng&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Zhang_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Hong-Hao Zhang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Lin_W/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Weipeng Lin&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01891">
<title>Protostellar collapse simulations in spherical geometry with dust coagulation and fragmentation. (arXiv:2211.01891v1 [astro-ph.GA])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01891</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We model the coagulation and fragmentation of dust grains during the
protostellar collapse with our newly developed shark code. It solves the
gas-dust hydrodynamics in a spherical geometry and the
coagulation/fragmentation equation. It also computes the ionization state of
the cloud and the Ohmic, ambipolar and Hall resistivities. We find that the
dust size distribution evolves significantly during the collapse, large grain
formation being controlled by the turbulent differential velocity. When
turbulence is included, only ambipolar diffusion remains efficient at removing
the small grains from the distribution, brownian motion is only efficient as a
standalone process. The macroscopic gas-dust drift is negligible for grain
growth and only dynamically significant near the first Larson core. At high
density, we find that the coagulated distribution is unaffected by the initial
choice of dust distribution. Strong magnetic fields are found to enhance the
small grains depletion, causing an important increase of the ambipolar
diffusion. This hints that the magnetic field strength could be regulated by
the small grain population during the protostellar collapse. Fragmentation
could be effective for bare silicates, but its modeling relies on the choice of
ill-constrained parameters. It is also found to be negligible for icy grains.
When fragmentation occurs, it strongly affects the magnetic resistivities
profiles. Dust coagulation is a critical process that needs to be fully taken
into account during the protostellar collapse. The onset and feedback of
fragmentation remains uncertain and its modeling should be further
investigated.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Lebreuilly_U/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ugo Lebreuilly&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Vallucci_Goy_V/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Valentin Vallucci-Goy&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Guillet_V/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Vincent Guillet&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Lombart_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Maxime Lombart&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Marchand_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Pierre Marchand&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01901">
<title>Augmenting photometric redshift estimates using spectroscopic nearest neighbours. (arXiv:2211.01901v1 [astro-ph.CO])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01901</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;As a consequence of galaxy clustering, close galaxies observed on the plane
of the sky should be spatially correlated with a probability inversely
proportional to their angular separation. In principle, this information can be
used to improve photometric redshift estimates when spectroscopic redshifts are
available for some of the neighbouring objects. Depending on the depth of the
survey, however, such angular correlation is reduced by chance projections. In
this work, we implement a deep learning model to distinguish between apparent
and real angular neighbours by solving a classification task. We adopt a graph
neural network architecture to tie together the photometry, the spectroscopy
and the spatial information between neighbouring galaxies. We train and
validate the algorithm on the data of the VIPERS galaxy survey, for which
SED-fitting based photometric redshifts are also available. The model yields a
confidence level for a pair of galaxies to be real angular neighbours, enabling
us to disentangle chance superpositions in a probabilistic way. When objects
for which no physical companion can be identified are excluded, all photometric
redshifts&apos; quality metrics improve significantly, confirming that their
estimates were of lower quality. For our typical test configuration, the
algorithm identifies a subset containing ~75% of high-quality photometric
redshifts, for which the dispersion is reduced by as much as 50% (from 0.08 to
0.04), while the fraction of outliers reduces from 3% to 0.8%. Moreover, we
show that the spectroscopic redshift of the angular neighbour with the highest
detection probability provides an excellent estimate of the redshift of the
target galaxy, comparable or even better than the corresponding template
fitting estimate.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Tosone_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;F. Tosone&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Cagliari_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;M.S. Cagliari&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Guzzo_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;L. Guzzo&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Granett_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;B.R. Granett&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Crespi_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;A. Crespi&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01927">
<title>Modeling Solids in Nuclear Astrophysics with Smoothed Particle Hydrodynamics. (arXiv:2211.01927v1 [astro-ph.IM])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01927</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Smoothed Particle Hydrodynamics (SPH) is a frequently applied tool in
computational astrophysics to solve the fluid dynamics equations governing the
systems under study. For some problems, for example when involving asteroids
and asteroid impacts, the additional inclusion of material strength is
necessary in order to accurately describe the dynamics. In compact stars, that
is white dwarfs and neutron stars, solid components are also present. Neutron
stars have a solid crust which is the strongest material known in nature.
However, their dynamical evolution, when modeled via SPH or other computational
fluid dynamics codes, is usually described as a purely fluid dynamics problem.
Here, we present the first 3D simulations of neutron-star crustal toroidal
oscillations including material strength with the Los Alamos National
Laboratory SPH code FleCSPH. In the first half of the paper, we present the
numerical implementation of solid material modeling together with standard
tests. The second half is on the simulation of crustal oscillations in the
fundamental toroidal mode. Here, we dedicate a large fraction of the paper to
approaches which can suppress numerical noise in the solid. If not minimized,
the latter can dominate the crustal motion in the simulations.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Sagert_I/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Irina Sagert&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Korobkin_O/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Oleg Korobkin&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Tews_I/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ingo Tews&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Tsao_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Bing-Jyun Tsao&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Lim_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Hyun Lim&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Falato_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Michael J. Falato&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Loiseau_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Julien Loiseau&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01935">
<title>Discovering a new well: Decaying dark matter with profile likelihoods. (arXiv:2211.01935v1 [astro-ph.CO])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01935</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;A large number of studies, all using Bayesian parameter inference from Markov
Chain Monte Carlo methods, have constrained the presence of a decaying dark
matter component. All such studies find a strong preference for either very
long-lived or very short-lived dark matter. However, in this letter, we
demonstrate that this preference is due to parameter volume effects that drive
the model towards the standard $\Lambda$CDM model, which is known to provide a
good fit to most observational data.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using profile likelihoods, which are free from volume effects, we instead
find that the best-fitting parameters are associated with an intermediate
regime where around $3 \%$ of cold dark matter decays just prior to
recombination. With two additional parameters, the model yields an overall
preference over the $\Lambda$CDM model of $\Delta \chi^2 \approx -2.8$ with
\textit{Planck} and BAO and $\Delta \chi^2 \approx -7.8$ with the SH0ES $H_0$
measurement, while only slightly alleviating the $H_0$ tension. Ultimately, our
results reveal that decaying dark matter is more viable than previously
assumed, and illustrate the dangers of relying exclusively on Bayesian
parameter inference when analysing extensions to the $\Lambda$CDM model.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Holm_E/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Emil Brinch Holm&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Herold_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Laura Herold&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Hannestad_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Steen Hannestad&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Nygaard_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Andreas Nygaard&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Tram_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Thomas Tram&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.02041">
<title>Detecting galaxies in a large H{\sc i}~spectral cube. (arXiv:2211.02041v1 [astro-ph.IM])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.02041</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The upcoming Square Kilometer Array (SKA) is expected to produce humongous
amount of data for undertaking H{\sc i}~science. We have developed an MPI-based
{\sc Python} pipeline to deal with the large data efficiently with the present
computational resources. Our pipeline divides such large H{\sc i}~21-cm
spectral cubes into several small cubelets, and then processes them in parallel
using publicly available H{\sc i}~source finder {\sc SoFiA-$2$}. The pipeline
also takes care of sources at the boundaries of the cubelets and also filters
out false and redundant detections. By comapring with the true source catalog,
we find that the detection efficiency depends on the {\sc SoFiA-$2$} parameters
such as the smoothing kernel size, linking length and threshold values. We find
the optimal kernel size for all flux bins to be between $3$ to $5$ pixels and
$7$ to $15$ pixels, respectively in the spatial and frequency directions.
Comparing the recovered source parameters with the original values, we find
that the output of {\sc SoFiA-$2$} is highly dependent on kernel sizes and a
single choice of kernel is not sufficient for all types of H{\sc i}~galaxies.
We also propose use of alternative methods to {\sc SoFiA-$2$} which can be used
in our pipeline to find sources more robustly.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Shaw_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Abinash Kumar Shaw&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Jagannath_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Manoj Jagannath&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Mazumder_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Aishrila Mazumder&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Chakraborty_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Arnab Chakraborty&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Patra_N/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Narendra Nath Patra&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Mondal_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Rajesh Mondal&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Choudhuri_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Samir Choudhuri&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.02045">
<title>Fast and robust Bayesian Inference using Gaussian Processes with GPry. (arXiv:2211.02045v1 [astro-ph.CO])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.02045</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We present the GPry algorithm for fast Bayesian inference of general
(non-Gaussian) posteriors with a moderate number of parameters. GPry does not
need any pre-training, special hardware such as GPUs, and is intended as a
drop-in replacement for traditional Monte Carlo methods for Bayesian inference.
Our algorithm is based on generating a Gaussian Process surrogate model of the
log-posterior, aided by a Support Vector Machine classifier that excludes
extreme or non-finite values. An active learning scheme allows us to reduce the
number of required posterior evaluations by two orders of magnitude compared to
traditional Monte Carlo inference. Our algorithm allows for parallel
evaluations of the posterior at optimal locations, further reducing wall-clock
times. We significantly improve performance using properties of the posterior
in our active learning scheme and for the definition of the GP prior. In
particular we account for the expected dynamical range of the posterior in
different dimensionalities. We test our model against a number of synthetic and
cosmological examples. GPry outperforms traditional Monte Carlo methods when
the evaluation time of the likelihood (or the calculation of theoretical
observables) is of the order of seconds; for evaluation times of over a minute
it can perform inference in days that would take months using traditional
methods. GPry is distributed as an open source Python package (pip install
gpry) and can also be found at https://github.com/jonaselgammal/GPry.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Gammal_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jonas El Gammal&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Schoneberg_N/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Nils Sch&amp;#xf6;neberg&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Torrado_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jes&amp;#xfa;s Torrado&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Fidler_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Christian Fidler&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2009.10813">
<title>Launching the VASCO citizen science project. (arXiv:2009.10813v2 [astro-ph.IM] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2009.10813</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The Vanishing \&amp;amp; Appearing Sources during a Century of Observations (VASCO)
project investigates astronomical surveys spanning a time interval of 70 years,
searching for unusual and exotic transients. We present herein the VASCO
Citizen Science Project, which can identify unusual candidates driven by three
different approaches: hypothesis, exploratory, and machine learning, which is
particularly useful for SETI searches. To address the big data challenge, VASCO
combines three methods: the Virtual Observatory, user-aided machine learning,
and visual inspection through citizen science. Here we demonstrate the citizen
science project and its improved candidate selection process, and we give a
progress report. We also present the VASCO citizen science network led by
amateur astronomy associations mainly located in Algeria, Cameroon, and
Nigeria. At the moment of writing, the citizen science project has carefully
examined 15,593 candidate image pairs in the data (ca. 10\% of the candidates),
and has so far identified 798 objects classified as ``vanished&apos;&apos;. The most
interesting candidates will be followed up with optical and infrared imaging,
together with the observations by the most potent radio telescopes.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Villarroel_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Beatriz Villarroel&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Pelckmans_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Kristiaan Pelckmans&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Solano_E/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Enrique Solano&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Laaksoharju_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Mikael Laaksoharju&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Souza_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Abel Souza&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Dom_O/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Onyeuwaoma Nnaemeka Dom&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Laggoune_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Khaoula Laggoune&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Mimouni_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jamal Mimouni&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Mattsson_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Lars Mattsson&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Soodla_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Johan Soodla&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Castillo_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Diego Castillo&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Shultz_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Matthew E. Shultz&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Aworka_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Rubby Aworka&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Comeron_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;S&amp;#xe9;bastien Comer&amp;#xf3;n&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Geier_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Stefan Geier&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Marcy_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Geoffrey Marcy&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Gupta_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Alok C. Gupta&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Bergstedt_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Josefine Bergstedt&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Bar_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Rudolf E. B&amp;#xe4;r&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Buelens_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Bart Buelens&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Enriquez_E/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Emilio Enriquez&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Mellon_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Christopher K. Mellon&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Prieto_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;M. Almudena Prieto&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Wamalwa_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Dismas Simiyu Wamalwa&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Ward_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Martin J. Ward&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.14890">
<title>The deconvolved distribution estimator: enhancing reionisation-era CO line-intensity mapping analyses with a cross-correlation analogue for one-point statistics. (arXiv:2210.14890v2 [astro-ph.CO] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.14890</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We present the deconvolved distribution estimator (DDE), an extension of the
voxel intensity distribution (VID), in the context of future observations
proposed as part of the CO Mapping Array Project (COMAP). The DDE exploits the
fact that the observed VID is a convolution of correlated signal intensity
distributions and uncorrelated noise or interloper intensity distributions. By
deconvolving the individual VID of two observables away from their joint VID in
a Fourier-space operation, the DDE suppresses sensitivity to interloper
emission while maintaining sensitivity to correlated components. The DDE thus
improves upon the VID by rejecting uncorrelated noise and interloper biases,
which is useful in the context of COMAP observations that observe different
rotational transitions of CO from the same comoving volume in different
observing frequency bands. Fisher forecasts suggest that the theoretical
sensitivity in the DDE allows significant improvements in constraining power
compared to either the cross power spectrum or the individual VID data, and
matches the constraining power of the combination of all other one- and
two-point summary statistics. Future work should further investigate the
covariance and model-dependent behaviour of this novel one-point
cross-correlation statistic.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Chung_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Dongwoo T. Chung&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Bangari_I/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ishika Bangari&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Breysse_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Patrick C. Breysse&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Ihle_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;H&amp;#xe5;vard T. Ihle&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Bond_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;J. Richard Bond&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Dunne_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Delaney A. Dunne&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Padmanabhan_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Hamsa Padmanabhan&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Philip_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Liju Philip&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Rennie_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Thomas J. Rennie&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Viero_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Marco P. Viero&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
</rdf:RDF>