<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"><channel><title>IEEE Spectrum</title><link>https://spectrum.ieee.org/</link><description>IEEE Spectrum</description><atom:link href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/feeds/topic/telecommunications.rss" rel="self"></atom:link><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2022 10:56:42 -0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/eyJ0eXAiOiJKV1QiLCJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJpbWFnZSI6Imh0dHBzOi8vYXNzZXRzLnJibC5tcy8yNjg4NDUyMC9vcmlnaW4ucG5nIiwiZXhwaXJlc19hdCI6MTY5OTk5OTQzOX0.aimbeagNFKGtififsLPFvztNYGr1_NMvLOOT1mPOjEU/image.png?width=210</url><link>https://spectrum.ieee.org/</link><title>IEEE Spectrum</title></image><item><title>Introduction to the 5 Pillars of Data Acquisition</title><link>https://go.teledynelecroy.com/ieee_five_pillars_webinar</link><description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/image.png?id=28133682&width=980"/><br/><br/><p>Join Teledyne SP Devices for a live webinar about the foundations of data acquisition. </p><p>Explore digitizer fundamentals and learn more about analog front-end (AFE), triggering, clocking, signal processing, and the use of general-purpose input/output (GPIO).</p><p><a href="https://go.teledynelecroy.com/ieee_five_pillars_webinar" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Register now for this free webinar!</a></p>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2022 19:04:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://go.teledynelecroy.com/ieee_five_pillars_webinar</guid><category>Analog</category><category>Data acquisition</category><category>Digitizer</category><category>Signal processing</category><category>Teledyne</category><category>Type:webinar</category><dc:creator>Teledyne</dc:creator><media:content medium="image" type="image/png" url="https://assets.rbl.ms/28133682/origin.png"></media:content></item><item><title>This Chip Could Replace a Thousand Lasers</title><link>https://spectrum.ieee.org/frequency-comb</link><description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/illustration-of-a-square-shape-with-a-yellow-ring-on-top-and-red-lines-in-a-pattern-rising-from-the-circle-in-small-then-large.jpg?id=32036445&width=1245&height=700&coordinates=0%2C102%2C0%2C103"/><br/><br/><p>A record-breaking optical chip can transmit 1.8 petabits—1.8 million gigabits—per second, roughly twice as much traffic as transmitted per second over the entire world's Internet, a new study finds.</p><p>Previous research transmitted up to <a href="https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/9083661" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">10.66 petabits per second</a> over <a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/chip-scale-photonic-amplifier" target="_self">fiber optics</a>. However, these experiments relied on bulky electronics. A compact microchip-based strategy could enable mass production and result in smaller footprints, lower costs, and lower energy consumption. Until now, the fastest single optical microchip supported data rates of 661 terabits—661,000 gigabits—per second.</p><p>The new chip uses the light from a single infrared laser to create a rainbow spectrum of many colors. All the resulting frequencies of light are a fixed specific frequency distance from one another, a bit like the teeth of the comb, which is why the device is called a <a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/micro-comb" target="_self">frequency comb</a>. Each frequency can be isolated and have such properties as its amplitude modulated to carry data. The frequencies can then be collected together and transmitted simultaneously over fiber optics.</p><p>“Several groups worldwide have shown that frequency combs can be used for data transmission instead of using individual lasers,” says study senior author Leif Katsuo Oxenløwe, an optical communications researcher at the Technical University of Denmark.</p><p>The new microchip emits light roughly 1,530 to 1,610 nanometers in wavelength. These fall into the C and L bands of telecommunications frequencies, two of <a href="https://www.fiberlabs.com/glossary/optical-communication-band/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">five wavelength bands</a> where optical fibers experience minimal signal loss.</p><p>In experiments, the scientists achieved 1.84 petabits per second over a 7.9-kilometer-long optical fiber using 223 wavelength channels. “This is the first time it is investigated just how much data a single frequency comb can carry,” Oxenløwe says.</p><p>Using conventional equipment, this data rate would require about 1,000 lasers, the researchers say. The new microchip could therefore help significantly reduce Internet power consumption. “You could save a thousand lasers out of your energy budget,” Oxenløwe says.</p><p>In addition, a computational model the scientists developed to examine the potential of frequency combs suggests that a single chip could achieve a data rate of up to 100 petabits per second if given a cable with thousands of fibers. “You can already today buy cables with thousands of fibers in them to transport large quantities of data around in data centers, so scaling to such numbers is actually realistic,” Oxenløwe says.</p><p>The researchers say they accomplish this staggering data rate by dividing one frequency comb into many copies and optically amplifying their signals. “The power and potential of frequency combs is thus far greater than I think most comb enthusiasts even dared to dream of,” Oxenløwe says.</p><p>Future research can integrate components such as the laser, data modulators, and amplifiers onto the optical chip, Oxenløwe says.</p><p>The scientists detailed <u><a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41566-022-01082-z" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">their findings</a></u> 20 October in the journal <em>Nature Photonics</em>.</p>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 18:09:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spectrum.ieee.org/frequency-comb</guid><category>Optoelectronics</category><category>Internet</category><category>Lasers</category><category>Frequency comb</category><dc:creator>Charles Q. Choi</dc:creator><media:content medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/illustration-of-a-square-shape-with-a-yellow-ring-on-top-and-red-lines-in-a-pattern-rising-from-the-circle-in-small-then-large.jpg?id=32036445&amp;width=980"></media:content></item><item><title>Accelerate the Future of Innovation</title><link>https://connectlp.keysight.com/Emerging_Technologies_White_Papers?elqCampaignId=22934&amp;cmpid=ASC-2106531&amp;utm_source=ADSC&amp;utm_medium=ASC&amp;utm_campaign=303</link><description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/image.png?id=27151193&width=980"/><br/><br/><p>Looking for help with technical challenges related to emerging technologies like 5G, 6G, and quantum computing?<u></u><u></u></p><p><a href="https://connectlp.keysight.com/Emerging_Technologies_White_Papers?elqCampaignId=22934&cmpid=ASC-2106531&utm_source=ADSC&utm_medium=ASC&utm_campaign=303" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Download these three whitepapers</a> to help inspire and accelerate your future innovations:<u></u><u></u></p><ul><li><strong>“5G Private Networks Enable Business Everywhere” <em>by MIT Technology Review Insights</em></strong> — Learn how 5G private networks will drive innovations in many industrial and enterprise sectors<u></u><u></u></li><li><strong>“How 6G Will Change the Way We Interact with Technology” </strong><em><strong>by MIT Technology Review Insights</strong></em> — Learn how Keysight and Nokia investigate the sub-terahertz spectrum to power the bandwidth needed to make 6G technology real<u></u><u></u></li><li><strong>“Quantum Computing: Infrastructure and Scaling Challenges”</strong> — Learn how researchers overcome challenges in this emerging computing ecosystem</li></ul>]]></description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 12:00:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://connectlp.keysight.com/Emerging_Technologies_White_Papers?elqCampaignId=22934&amp;cmpid=ASC-2106531&amp;utm_source=ADSC&amp;utm_medium=ASC&amp;utm_campaign=303</guid><category>5g</category><category>6g</category><category>Innovation</category><category>Keysight</category><category>Quantum computing</category><category>Type:whitepaper</category><dc:creator>Keysight</dc:creator><media:content medium="image" type="image/png" url="https://assets.rbl.ms/27151193/origin.png"></media:content></item><item><title>AI for Wireless</title><link>https://spectrum.ieee.org/ai-for-wireless</link><description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/graph-showing-three-communications-signal-levels-in-decibels.jpg?id=31893330&width=980"/><br/><br/><p>
<em>This is a sponsored article brought to you by <a href="https://www.mathworks.com/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">MathWorks</a>.</em>
</p><p>
	The evolution of mobile wireless technology, from 3G/4G to 5G, and introduction of Industry 4.0, have resulted in the ever-increasing complexity of wireless systems design. Wireless networks have also become more difficult to manage due to requirements necessitating optimal sharing of valuable resources to expanding sets of users. These challenges force engineers to think beyond traditional rules-based approaches with many are turning to artificial intelligence (AI) as the go-to solution to face the challenges introduced by modern systems.
</p><p>
	From managing communications between autonomous vehicles, to optimization of resource allocations in mobile calls, AI has brought the sophistication necessary for modern wireless applications. As the number and scope of devices connected to networks expands, so too will the role of AI in wireless. Engineers must be prepared to introduce it into increasingly complex systems. Knowing the benefits and current applications of AI in wireless systems, as well as the best practices necessary for optimal implementation, will be key for the future success of the technology.
</p><hr/><h2>The Primary Benefits of AI for Wireless </h2><p>
	The transition to 5G has brought about the optimization of speed and quality of mobile broadband networks, as well as the need for ultra-reliable low rates and massive machine-type communication for time-sensitive connections between Industry 4.0 devices – three distinct use-cases in a modern network and the contending forces driving engineers to the adoption of AI.
</p><p>
	As devices compete for the resources of the network, with the number of users and applications of a wireless system increasing all the time, formerly linear patterns of designs once understood by human-based rules, cease to be sufficient. AI techniques, however, can better solve non-linear problems by extracting any pattern automatically and efficiently, beyond the ability of human-based approaches.
</p><p>
	By AI in this context, we mean those machine learning and deep learning systems used to recognize patterns within communications channels that link devices and people. These systems then optimize the resources given to that link to improve performance. Simply put, running a network for those disparate use cases without exploiting AI methodologies becomes a near impossible task.
</p><p>
	Beyond bringing sophistication and optimization, AI also brings project management benefits. Incorporating simulated environments into an algorithmic model through estimating the behaviour of source environments can enable engineers to quickly study a system’s dominant effect using minimal computational resources. This leaves more time to explore design and carry out more iterations faster, reducing cost and development time.
</p><p>
<a href="https://engineeringresources.spectrum.ieee.org/free/w_math06/prgm.cgi?a=1" target="_blank"><img alt="Click to watch on-demand webinar: Apply AI Techniques to Solve Wireless Communications System Design Challenges" src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/ai-for-wireless-workflow-data-generation-ai-training-validation-and-testing-and-deployment-on-hardware-click-to-watch-on-demand-webinar-apply-ai-techniques-to-solve-wireless-communications-system-design-challenges.jpg?id=31897034&width=1694&quality=80"/></a>
<small alt="Click Watch on-demand webinar: Apply AI Techniques to Solve Wireless Communications System Design Challenges" class="image-media media-caption" placeholder="Add Photo Caption...">AI for Wireless workflow: Data generation, AI training, validation and testing and deployment on hardware. Click on the image to watch on-demand webinar: Apply AI Techniques to Solve Wireless Communications System Design Challenges.</small>
<small class="image-media media-photo-credit" placeholder="Add Photo Credit...">
	MathWorks
	</small>
</p><h2>Best Practices for the Application of AI in Wireless Systems<br/>
</h2><p>
	Data size and quality are vital for effective deployment of AI models, because they are only as effective as the data they are trained with. To deal with a range of real-world scenarios, these models need to be trained with a broad range of data. By synthesizing new data based on primitives or by extracting them from over-the-air signals, applications like MathWorks’ 
	<a href="https://www.mathworks.com/products/5g.html" target="_blank">5G Toolbox</a> provide the data variability necessary for 5G network designers to train AI robustly. Failure to explore a large training data set and iterate on different algorithms based on that data could result in a narrow local optimization instead of an overall global one.
</p><p>
	A robust approach to testing AI models in the field is similarly critical to success. Variability in signal needed for testing AI techniques is a problem, where signals captured in a narrow, localized geography may adversely impact how an engineer might optimize quality of their design. Without field iterations, the parameters of individual cases cannot be used to optimize AI for specific locations, negatively impacting call performance.
</p><h2>AI for a Wireless World – Primary Application Areas</h2><p>
	Digital transformation in areas like telecommunications and automotive necessitate the use of AI and is the primary driver for its application. Placing electronic communications in areas once mechanical orientated generates large amounts of data as applications like smart cities, telecommunication networks and autonomous vehicles (AV) connect. As they do so, the resources of the network joining them becomes stretched.
</p><p>
	In telecommunications, AI is deployed at two levels – at the physical layer (PHY) and above PHY. The application of AI for improving performance in a line connecting two users is referred to as operating at PHY. Applications of AI techniques to physical layers includes digital pre-distortion, channel estimation and channel resource optimization, as well as automatic adjustments to transceiver parameters during a call otherwise known as autoencoder design.
</p><p>
	Channel optimization is the enhancement of the connection between two devices, notably network infrastructure and user equipment. Often, this means using AI to overcome signal variability in localized environments through techniques such as fingerprinting and channel state information compression.
</p><p>
	With fingerprinting, AI is used to optimize positioning and localization for wireless networks by mapping disruptions to propagation patterns in indoor environments, caused by individuals entering them. AI then estimates based on these individualized 5G signal variations the position of the user. Meanwhile, channel state information compression is the use of AI to compress feedback data from user equipment to a base station, ensuring that the feedback loop informing the station’s attempt to improve call performance does not exceed the available bandwidth thus consequently causing a dropped call.
</p><p>
	Above-PHY uses are mainly in network management and resource allocation. Applications, such as scheduling, beam management and spectrum allocation, are functions that manage and optimize the resources of core systems for the competing users and use-cases of the network. As the number of users and use-cases on the network increase, network designers have turned to AI techniques in order to respond to allocation demands in real time.
</p><p>
	In the automotive industry, using AI for wireless connectivity is making safe autonomous driving possible. Autonomous vehicles (AV) rely on data from multiple sources, including LiDAR, radar, and wireless sensors, to interpret the environment in which they are situated. The hardware present in AVs must handle data from these many competing sources. AI enables sensor fusion, fusing competing signals to allow the vehicle’s software to make sense of its location and establish how it will interact with its environment.
</p><h2>The Future of AI for Wireless</h2><p>
	As the use cases for wireless technology expand, so too does the need to implement AI within those systems. Without it, systems such as 5G, autonomous vehicles and IoT applications would not have the sophistication necessary to function effectively. While AI’s place in engineering, particularly wireless system design, has been increasing in recent years, it can be expected for this to keep rising – and faster – as the use cases and the number of network users grow.
</p><p>
	To learn more about this topic, see the additional resource below or email at 
	<a href="mailto:hzarrink@mathworks.com" target="_blank">hzarrink@mathworks.com</a>:
</p><p>
	• 
	<a href="https://www.mathworks.com/campaigns/products/trials.html" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Free MATLAB Trial</a> (30-day free trial): Start your free 30-day trial to help evaluate MATLAB and Simulink as well as the other products while also getting unlimited online access.
</p>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2022 16:09:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spectrum.ieee.org/ai-for-wireless</guid><category>5g</category><category>Machine learning</category><category>Deep learning</category><category>Mathworks</category><category>Wireless</category><dc:creator>Houman Zarrinkoub</dc:creator><media:content medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://assets.rbl.ms/31893330/origin.jpg"></media:content></item><item><title>How 5G’s Rollout Rattled Hundreds of Pilots</title><link>https://spectrum.ieee.org/faa-5g</link><description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/an-airplane-just-before-landing-in-the-early-morning-runway-lights-can-be-seen-in-the-foreground.jpg?id=31913203&width=1245&height=700&coordinates=0%2C187%2C0%2C188"/><br/><br/><p>In January this year, at least three flights above Tennessee simultaneously experienced altimeter errors that made it “impossible to maintain assigned altitude,” according to one of the pilots. One jet lost its autopilot completely, and reportedly had fire trucks waiting for it on landing.</p><p>In February, a passenger plane on approach to the Louis Armstrong International Airport in New Orleans experienced erratic low-altitude warnings as it flew below 1,000 feet. “This sort of erroneous warning indications would be extremely distracting in a more challenging environment such as low visibility, icing conditions, etc,” the pilot wrote later.</p><p>In March, a commercial jet landing on autopilot at Los Angeles International Airport suddenly went into an aggressive descent just 100 feet above the ground. “I took control of the aircraft and raised the nose and landed,” its pilot reported. “It was a very alarming pushover by the autopilot. In [other] conditions, it could have caused a crash.”</p><hr/><p>All three incidents—and many more this year—were linked by pilots to problems with the aircrafts’ radio (radar) altimeters, which pilots rely on during takeoff and landing, and to help avoid crashing into mountains. These altimeters also feed into critical autopilot, auto-throttle, and instrument landing systems. According to an <em>IEEE Spectrum</em> analysis of reports made to NASA’s <a href="https://asrs.arc.nasa.gov/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Aviation Safety Reporting System</a> (ASRS), complaints of malfunctioning and failing altimeters soared after the rollout earlier this year of <a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/5g-faa" target="_self">high-speed 5G wireless networks</a>, which use similar frequencies.</p><p>ASRS is a public database maintained by NASA to encourage U.S.-based air and ground crew, and air traffic controllers, to anonymously share safety incidents and concerns. Between January and May, there were 93 reports of faulty or failing radar altimeters, where a normal year might see only a handful. January alone saw almost twice as many complaints of malfunctioning altimeters as the previous five years combined. In most, including the Tennessee and Los Angeles incidents above, the reporter referred to 5G interference.</p><p>The <a href="https://www.fcc.gov/" target="_blank">U.S. Federal Communications Commission</a> initially played down concerns that the new cell towers and devices might interfere with commercial jet radar altimeters, which operate a few hundred megahertz higher in the radio spectrum. In early 2020, <a href="https://docs.fcc.gov/public/attachments/DOC-362358A1.pdf" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">the agency wrote</a>: “The technical rules on power and emission limits we set for the 3.7 [gigahertz] service and the spectral separation of 220 megahertz offers significant protection of services in the 4.2–4.4 GHz band.”</p><p>The <a href="https://www.faa.gov/" target="_blank">U.S. Federal Aviation Administration</a> was not so certain. It commissioned an empirical study by <a href="https://www.rtca.org/" target="_blank">RTCA</a>, a nonprofit that studies aviation electronics, to assess the operational risks of 5G interference. <a href="https://www.rtca.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/SC-239-5G-Interference-Assessment-Report_274-20-PMC-2073_accepted_changes.pdf" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">That report concluded</a> that C-band 5G systems would cause harmful interference to radar altimeters on all types of civil aircraft, and that “this risk is widespread and has the potential for broad impacts to aviation operations in the United States, including the possibility of catastrophic failures leading to multiple fatalities.”</p><p>It found the risk would originate from intentional and spurious signals from terrestrial cell towers, as well as 5G cellphones inadvertently operated onboard aircraft, exacerbated by altimeter receivers with poor spectral selectivity. In what now seems a prescient observation, the RTCA report said: “[The] possibility of harmful interference…is particularly dangerous given that up to the present time, radar altimeter failures…have been extremely uncommon.”</p><p>Nevertheless, the spectrum auction went ahead, with wireless providers led by <a href="https://www.verizon.com/" target="_blank">Verizon</a> and <a href="https://www.att.com/" target="_blank">AT&T</a> paying over US $80 billion for the frequencies. 5G services were due to go live in 46 markets around the United States on 5 January this year. But as the deployment neared, the FAA issued an airworthiness directive that would have vastly restricted air travel into those areas. </p><p>Ultimately, wireless carriers agreed to delay the 5G rollout for two weeks, and the FAA banned certain aircraft—those with susceptible or untested altimeters—from low-visibility landings at airports with 5G wireless networks. The networks also agreed to set up “<a href="https://www.faa.gov/sites/faa.gov/files/2022-01/50%20Airports%20with%205G%20Buffer.pdf" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">buffer zones</a>” around 50 airports that would reduce 5G C-band signal levels by at least 10 times within a mile of takeoff and landing runways. The mitigations would remain in place for six months, while the FAA attempted to clear more aircraft for operation.</p><p>On 19 January, the 5G systems were switched on.</p><p>Almost immediately, complaints began rolling into NASA. On their first flight to San Francisco after 5G was switched on, one pilot was horrified when their plane’s speed brakes unexpectedly activated before touchdown. “With over 18,000 hours as Captain of Boeing airliners…I’ve never had the auto speedbrakes deploy uncommanded before ground contact,” they wrote. “While I operate in the 5G environment, I have no intention on being the first to make a 5G landing.”</p><p>“I was predisposed to think the implementation would be a non-event and was surprised to experience actual interference events,” reported another pilot, who suspected a malfunctioning altimeter had caused their plane’s auto-throttle to disengage.</p><p>ASRS contains at least 40 reports of possible 5G interference in the vicinity of the 50 airports with buffer zones. With six reports, Phoenix Sky Harbor International Airport had the most complaints.</p><p>“I've been flying an aircraft with a radar altimeter for years and never once have I seen a malfunction such as this until the 5G turn on,” wrote another pilot in Florida, whose altimeter fluctuated between -90 and 400 feet prior to takeoff. “Coincidence? Probably not.”</p><p>But could it be? <a href="https://people.ece.uw.edu/rudell_chris/" target="_blank">Chris Rudell</a> is an associate professor in the department of electrical and computer engineering at the University of Washington. “I’d sleep like a baby [on a plane] that flew over a 5G base station at full power output,” he told <em>Spectrum</em>. “Probably something happens that’s unusual and the pilots attribute it to 5G but maybe it’s not attributable to 5G. After everything in the news, they’re now submitting what they actually see, whereas before they perhaps weren't motivated to do that.”</p><p>It is true that the FAA does now have a specific online radio-altimeter anomaly reporting form, that it asks pilots and other aviation personnel to complete. The FAA would not share the full details of these reports, but it did provide high-level data that indicates it has received around 550 such submissions since January.</p><p>The agency has reviewed over half of the reports, and was unable to rule out 5G interference in around 80 incidents. Contrary to the ASRS reports, none of the interference events identified by the FAA had any safety-related system impacts, affecting direct aircraft control inputs such as auto-throttle or speed brakes. The FAA has concluded that the mitigations it had agreed with wireless providers “are working.” In June, it agreed with the carriers to extend those mitigations for <a href="https://www.faa.gov/newsroom/faa-statements-5g" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">another year</a>.</p><p>Although altimeter complaints on ASRS seem to be declining, many pilots still want tighter controls on 5G technology. <a href="https://www.aopa.org/" target="_blank">AOPA</a>, the world’s largest organization representing general aviation pilots and aircraft owners, told <em>Spectrum</em>: “We call for continued discussions between the public and private sectors to further mitigate the proven safety risks that 5G technology poses to radar altimeters. Further cooperation and coordination will bring about solutions that work for all.”</p><p>A few pilots were less diplomatic when sharing their views anonymously. “Shutdown [sic] 5G until carefully vetted,” suggested one. “Delay implementation of 5G service until all issues with radar altimeters and transport category aircraft have been dealt with,” wrote another. A third simply pleaded: “Turn off 5G cell service near airports.”<br/></p><p><em>This article was updated to clarify AOPA’s status as an aviation association.</em><br/></p>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2022 15:25:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spectrum.ieee.org/faa-5g</guid><category>5g</category><category>Cellular networks</category><category>Aviation</category><category>Faa</category><category>Fcc</category><category>Wireless</category><dc:creator>Mark Harris</dc:creator><media:content medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/an-airplane-just-before-landing-in-the-early-morning-runway-lights-can-be-seen-in-the-foreground.jpg?id=31913203&amp;width=980"></media:content></item><item><title>Why the Internet Needs the InterPlanetary File System</title><link>https://spectrum.ieee.org/peer-to-peer-network</link><description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/an-illustration-of-a-series.png?id=31861014&width=1245&height=700&coordinates=242%2C0%2C243%2C0"/><br/><br/><p>
<strong>When the COVID-19 </strong>pandemic erupted in early 2020, the world made an unprecedented shift to remote work. As a precaution, some Internet providers scaled back service levels temporarily, although that probably wasn’t necessary for countries in Asia, Europe, and North America, which were generally able to cope with the surge in demand caused by people teleworking (and binge-watching <a href="https://www.netflix.com/" target="_blank">Netflix</a>). That’s because most of their networks were overprovisioned, with more capacity than they usually need. But in countries without the same level of investment in network infrastructure, the picture was less rosy: Internet service providers (ISPs) in <a href="https://theeconreview.com/2020/06/17/the-pandemic-may-yet-break-south-africas-internet/" target="_blank">South Africa</a> and <a href="https://www.washingtonexaminer.com/opinion/coronavirus-might-break-venezuelas-internet" target="_blank">Venezuela</a>, for instance, reported significant strain.
</p><p>
	But is overprovisioning the only way to ensure resilience? We don’t think so. To understand the alternative approach we’re championing, though, you first need to recall how the Internet works.
</p><hr/><p>
	The core protocol of the Internet, aptly named the 
	<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Internet_Protocol" target="_blank">Internet Protocol</a> (IP), defines an addressing scheme that computers use to communicate with one another. This scheme assigns addresses to specific devices—people’s computers as well as servers—and uses those addresses to send data between them as needed.
</p><p>
	It’s a model that works well for sending unique information from one point to another, say, your bank statement or a letter from a loved one. This approach made sense when the Internet was used mainly to deliver different content to different people. But this design is not well suited for the mass consumption of static content, such as movies or TV shows.
</p><p>
	The reality today is that the Internet is more often used to send exactly the same thing to many people, and it’s doing a huge amount of that now, much of which is in the form of video. The demands grow even higher as our screens obtain ever-increasing resolutions, with 4K video already in widespread use and 8K on the horizon.
</p><p>
	The 
	<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Content_delivery_network" target="_blank">content delivery networks</a> (CDNs) used by streaming services such as Netflix help address the problem by temporarily storing content close to, or even inside, many ISPs. But this strategy relies on ISPs and CDNs being able to make deals and deploy the required infrastructure. And it can still leave the edges of the network having to handle more traffic than actually needs to flow.
</p><p>
	 The real problem is not so much the volume of content being passed around—it’s how it is being delivered, from a central source to many different far-away users, even when those users are located right next to one another.
</p><p class="shortcode-media shortcode-media-rebelmouse-image">
<img alt="This diagram depicts the information in a database table with two columns: Node and Content. The diagram also shows nodes in the network that query the database to find the location of files they are seeking." class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="1692d73a5f9fab048244139eea41aebd" data-rm-shortcode-name="rebelmouse-image" id="c54d9" loading="lazy" src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/this-diagram-depicts-the-information-in-a-database-table-with-two-columns-node-and-content-the-diagram-also-shows-nodes-in-the.png?id=31861102&width=980"/>
<small class="image-media media-caption" placeholder="Add Photo Caption...">One scheme used by peer-to-peer systems to determine the location of a file is to keep that information in a centralized database. <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Napster" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Napster</a>, the first large-scale peer-to-peer content-delivery system, used this approach.</small>
<small class="image-media media-photo-credit" placeholder="Add Photo Credit...">Carl De Torres</small>
</p><p>
	A more efficient distribution scheme in that case would be for the data to be served to your device from your neighbor’s device in a direct peer-to-peer manner. But how would your device even know whom to ask? Welcome to the InterPlanetary File System (IPFS).
</p><p>
	The InterPlanetary File System gets its name because, in theory, it could be extended to share data even between computers on different planets of the solar system. For now, though, we’re focused on rolling it out for just Earth!
</p><p>
	 The key to IPFS is what’s called content addressing. Instead of asking a particular provider, “Please send me this file,” your machine asks the network, “Who can send me this file?” It starts by querying peers: other computers in the user’s vicinity, others in the same house or office, others in the same neighborhood, others in the same city—expanding progressively outward to globally distant locations, if need be, until the system finds a copy of what you’re looking for.
</p><p>
	These queries are made using IPFS, an alternative to the 
	<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hypertext_Transfer_Protocol" target="_blank">Hypertext Transfer Protocol</a> (HTTP), which powers the World Wide Web. Building on the principles of peer-to-peer networking and content-based addressing, IPFS allows for a decentralized and distributed network for data storage and delivery.
</p><p>
	The benefits of IPFS include faster and more-efficient distribution of content. But they don’t stop there. IPFS can also improve security with content-integrity checking so that data cannot be tampered with by intermediary actors. And with IPFS, the network can continue operating even if the connection to the originating server is cut or if the service that initially provided the content is experiencing an outage—particularly important in places with networks that work only intermittently. IPFS also offers resistance to censorship.
</p><p>
	To understand more fully how IPFS differs from most of what takes place online today, let’s take a quick look at the Internet’s architecture and some earlier peer-to-peer approaches.
</p><p>
<strong>As mentioned above, </strong>with today’s Internet architecture, you request content based on a server’s address. This comes from the protocol that underlies the Internet and governs how data flows from point to point, a scheme first described by Vint Cerf and Bob Kahn in <a href="https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/1092259" target="_blank">a 1974 paper</a> in the <a href="https://www.comsoc.org/publications/journals/ieee-tcom" target="_blank"><em>IEEE Transactions on Communications</em></a> and now known as the Internet Protocol. The World Wide Web is built on top of the Internet Protocol. Browsing the Web consists of asking a specific machine, identified by an IP address, for a given piece of data.
</p><p class="pull-quote">
	Instead of asking a particular provider, “Please send me this file,” your machine asks the network, “Who can send me this file?”
</p><p>
	The process starts when a user types a URL into the address bar of the browser, which takes the hostname portion and sends it to a 
	<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Domain_Name_System" target="_blank">Domain Name System</a> (DNS) server. That DNS server returns a corresponding numerical IP address. The user’s browser will then connect to the IP address and ask for the Web page located at that URL.
</p><p>
	In other words, even if a computer in the same building has a copy of the desired data, it will neither see the request, nor would it be able to match it to the copy it holds because the content does not have an intrinsic identifier—it is not content-addressed.
</p><p>
	A content-addressing model for the Internet would give data, not devices, the leading role. Requesters would ask for the content explicitly, using a unique identifier (akin to the 
	<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Digital_object_identifier" target="_blank">DOI number</a> of a journal article or the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/ISBN" target="_blank">ISBN</a> of a book), and the Internet would handle forwarding the request to an available peer that has a copy.
</p><p>
	The major challenge in doing so is that it would require changes to the core Internet infrastructure, which is owned and operated by thousands of ISPs worldwide, with no central authority able to control what they all do. While this distributed architecture is one of the Internet’s greatest strengths, it makes it nearly impossible to make fundamental changes to the system, which would then break things for many of the people using it. It’s often very hard even to implement incremental improvements. A good example of the difficulty encountered when introducing change is 
	<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/IPv6" target="_blank">IPv6</a>, which expands the number of possible IP addresses. Today, almost 25 years after its introduction, it still hasn’t reached 50 percent adoption.
</p><p>
	A way around this inertia is to implement changes at a higher layer of abstraction, on top of existing Internet protocols, requiring no modification to the underlying networking software stacks or intermediate devices.
</p><p>
	Other peer-to-peer systems besides IPFS, such as 
	<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/BitTorrent" target="_blank">BitTorrent</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Freenet" target="_blank">Freenet</a>, have tried to do this by introducing systems that can operate in parallel with the World Wide Web, albeit often with Web interfaces. For example, you can click on a Web link for the BitTorrent tracker associated with a file, but this process typically requires that the tracker data be passed off to a separate application from your Web browser to handle the transfers. And if you can’t find a tracker link, you can’t find the data.
</p><p>
	Freenet also uses a distributed peer-to-peer system to store content, which can be requested via an identifier and can even be accessed using the Web’s HTTP protocol. But Freenet and IPFS have different aims: Freenet has a strong focus on anonymity and manages the replication of data in ways that serve that goal but lessen performance and user control. IPFS provides flexible, high-performance sharing and retrieval mechanisms but keeps control over data in the hands of the users.
</p><p class="shortcode-media shortcode-media-rebelmouse-image">
<img alt="This diagram shows schematically how query flooding works in a network of interconnected nodes for which the request must make several hops before the target file is located." class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="8dc8aad050ea20259e0844ae2edec141" data-rm-shortcode-name="rebelmouse-image" id="d63e0" loading="lazy" src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/this-diagram-shows-schematically-how-query-flooding-works-in-a-network-of-interconnected-nodes-for-which-the-request-must-make-s.png?id=31861180&width=980"/>
<small class="image-media media-caption" placeholder="Add Photo Caption...">Another approach to finding a file in a peer-to-peer network is called query flooding. The node seeking a file broadcasts a request for it to all nodes to which it is attached. If the node receiving the request does not have the file [red], it forwards the request to all the nodes to which it is attached until finally a node with the file passes a copy back to the requester [blue]. The <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gnutella" target="_blank">Gnutella</a> peer-to-peer network used this protocol.</small><small class="image-media media-photo-credit" placeholder="Add Photo Credit...">Carl De Torres</small>
</p><p>
	We designed IPFS as a protocol to upgrade the Web and not to create an alternative version. It is designed to make the Web better, to allow people to work offline, to make links permanent, to be faster and more secure, and to make it as easy as possible to use.
</p><p>
<strong>IPFS started in </strong>2013 as an open-source project supported by <a href="https://protocol.ai/" target="_blank">Protocol Labs</a>, where we work, and built by a vibrant community and ecosystem with hundreds of organizations and thousands of developers. IPFS is built on a strong foundation of previous work in peer-to-peer (P2P) networking and content-based addressing.
</p><p>
	The core tenet of all P2P systems is that users simultaneously participate as clients (which request and receive files from others) 
	<em>and</em> as servers (which store and send files to others). The combination of content addressing and P2P provides the right ingredients for fetching data from the closest peer that holds a copy of what’s desired—or more correctly, the closest one in terms of network topology, though not necessarily in physical distance.
</p><p>
	To make this happen, IPFS produces a fingerprint of the content it holds (called a 
	<a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/hans-peter-luhn-and-the-birth-of-the-hashing-algorithm" target="_self">hash</a>) that no other item can have. That hash can be thought of as a unique address for that piece of content. Changing a single bit in that content will yield an entirely different address. Computers wanting to fetch this piece of content broadcast a request for a file with this particular hash.
</p><p>
	Because identifiers are unique and never change, people often refer to IPFS as the “Permanent Web.” And with identifiers that never change, the network will be able to find a specific file as long as some computer on the network stores it.
</p><p>
	Name persistence and immutability inherently provide another significant property: verifiability. Having the content and its identifier, a user can verify that what was received is what was asked for and has not been tampered with, either in transit or by the provider. This not only improves security but also helps safeguard the public record and prevent history from being rewritten.
</p><p>
	You might wonder what would happen with content that needs to be updated to include fresh information, such as a Web page. This is a valid concern and IPFS does have a suite of mechanisms that would point users to the most up-to-date content.
</p><p class="pull-quote">
	Reducing the duplication of data moving through the network and procuring it from nearby sources will let ISPs provide faster service at lower cost.
</p><p>
	The world had a chance to observe how content addressing worked in April 2017 when the government of Turkey 
	<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Block_of_Wikipedia_in_Turkey#:~:text=From%2029%20April%202017%20to,imposed%20by%20Turkish%20Law%20No." target="_blank">blocked access to Wikipedia</a> because an article on the platform described Turkey as a state that sponsored terrorism. Within a week, a full copy of the Turkish version of Wikipedia was added to IPFS, and it remained accessible to people in the country for the nearly three years that the ban continued.
</p><p>
	A similar demonstration took place half a year later, when the Spanish government tried to suppress an independence referendum in Catalonia, ordering ISPs to block related websites. Once again, the information 
	<a href="https://www.wired.co.uk/article/catalan-government-independence-internet-spain" target="_blank">remained available via IPFS</a>.
</p><p>
	IPFS is an open, permissionless network: Any user can join and fetch or provide content. Despite numerous open-source success stories, the current Internet is heavily based on closed platforms, many of which adopt lock-in tactics but also offer users great convenience. While IPFS can provide improved efficiency, privacy, and security, giving this decentralized platform the level of usability that people are accustomed to remains a challenge.
</p><p>
	You see, the peer-to-peer, unstructured nature of IPFS is both a strength and a weakness. While CDNs have built sprawling infrastructure and advanced techniques to provide high-quality service, IPFS nodes are operated by end users. The network therefore relies on their behavior—how long their computers are online, how good their connectivity is, and what data they decide to cache. And often those things are not optimal.
</p><p>
	One of the key research questions for the folks working at Protocol Labs is how to keep the IPFS network resilient despite shortcomings in the nodes that make it up—or even when those nodes exhibit selfish or malicious behavior. We’ll need to overcome such issues if we’re to keep the performance of IPFS competitive with conventional distribution channels.
</p><p>
<strong>You may have </strong>noticed that we haven’t yet provided an example of an IPFS address. That’s because hash-based addressing results in URLs that aren’t easy to spell out or type.
</p><p>
	For instance, you can find the Wikipedia logo on IPFS by using the following address in a suitable browser: 
	<a href="https://ipfs.io/ipfs/QmRW3V9znzFW9M5FYbitSEvd5dQrPWGvPvgQD6LM22Tv8D" target="_blank">ipfs://QmRW3V9znzFW9M5FYbitSEvd5dQrPWGvPvgQD6LM22Tv8D</a>/. That long string can be thought of as a digital fingerprint for the file holding that logo.
</p><p class="shortcode-media shortcode-media-rebelmouse-image">
<img alt="This diagram shows schematically a file being stored in the network and also a file being retrieved. Where it is stored (and where to find it) is determined by the hashed value of the file." class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="b6834104d265f41f9e1dc46edb93317f" data-rm-shortcode-name="rebelmouse-image" id="da696" loading="lazy" src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/this-diagram-shows-schematically-a-file-being-stored-in-the-network-and-also-a-file-being-retrieved-where-it-is-stored-and-whe.png?id=31861212&width=980"/>
<small class="image-media media-caption" placeholder="Add Photo Caption...">To keep track of which nodes hold which files, the InterPlanetary File System uses what’s called a distributed hash table. In this simplified view, three nodes hold different parts of a table that has two columns: One column (Keys) contains hashes of the stored files; the other column (Records) contains the files themselves. Depending on what its hashed key is, a file gets stored in the appropriate place [left]—depicted here as though the system checked the first letter of hashes and stored different parts of the alphabet in different places. The actual algorithm for distributing files is more complex, but the concept is similar. Retrieving a file is efficient because it’s possible to locate the file according to what its hash is [right].</small>
<small class="image-media media-photo-credit" placeholder="Add Photo Credit...">Carl De Torres</small>
</p><p>
	There are other content-addressing schemes that use human-readable naming, or hierarchical, URL-style naming, but each comes with its own set of trade-offs. Finding practical ways to use human-readable names with IPFS would go a long way toward improving user-friendliness. It’s a goal, but we’re not there yet.
</p><p>
	Protocol Labs, has been tackling these and other technical, usability, and societal issues for most of the last decade. Over this time, we have been seeing rapidly increasing adoption of IPFS, with its network size doubling year over year. Scaling up at such speeds brings many challenges. But that’s par for the course when your intent is changing the Internet as we know it.
</p><p>
	Widespread adoption of content addressing and IPFS should help the whole Internet ecosystem. By empowering users to request exact content and verify that they received it unaltered, IPFS will improve trust and security. Reducing the duplication of data moving through the network and procuring it from nearby sources will let ISPs provide faster service at lower cost. Enabling the network to continue providing service even when it becomes partitioned will make our infrastructure more resilient to natural disasters and other large-scale disruptions.
</p><p>
	But is there a dark side to decentralization? We often hear concerns about how peer-to-peer networks may be used by bad actors to support illegal activity. These concerns are important but sometimes overstated.
</p><p>
	One area where IPFS improves on HTTP is in allowing comprehensive auditing of stored data. For example, thanks to its content-addressing functionality and, in particular, to the use of unique and permanent content identifiers, IPFS makes it easier to determine whether certain content is present on the network, and which nodes are storing it. Moreover, IPFS makes it trivial for users to decide what content they distribute and what content they stop distributing (by merely deleting it from their machines).
</p><p>
	At the same time, IPFS provides no mechanisms to allow for censorship, given that it operates as a distributed P2P file system with no central authority. So there is no actor with the technical means to prohibit the storage and propagation of a file or to delete a file from other peers’ storage. Consequently, censorship of unwanted content cannot be technically enforced, which represents a safeguard for users whose freedom of speech is under threat. Lawful requests to take down content are still possible, but they need to be addressed to the users actually storing it, avoiding commonplace abuses (like illegitimate 
	<a href="https://www.dmca.com/FAQ/What-is-a-DMCA-Takedown" target="_blank">DMCA takedown requests</a>) against which large platforms have difficulties defending.
</p><p>
	Ultimately, IPFS is an open network, governed by community rules, and open to everyone. And you can become a part of it today! The 
	<a href="https://brave.com/" target="_blank">Brave browser</a> ships with <a href="https://brave.com/ipfs-support/" target="_blank">built-in IPFS support</a>, as does <a href="https://press.opera.com/2020/03/30/opera-introduces-major-updates-to-its-blockchain-browser-on-android/" target="_blank">Opera for Android</a>. There are browser extensions available for Chrome and Firefox, and <a href="https://docs.ipfs.io/install/ipfs-desktop/" target="_blank">IPFS Desktop</a> makes it easy to run a local node. Several organizations provide IPFS-based hosting services, while others operate public gateways that allow you to fetch data from IPFS through the browser without any special software.
</p><p>
	These gateways act as entries to the P2P network and are important to bootstrap adoption. Through some simple DNS magic, a domain can be configured so that a user’s access request will result in the corresponding content being retrieved and served by a gateway, in a way that is completely transparent to the user.
</p><p>
	So far, IPFS has been used to build varied applications, including systems for 
	<a href="https://bitcoinmagazine.com/business/openbazaar-integrating-interplanetary-file-system-to-help-keep-stores-open-longer-1460660998" target="_blank">e-commerce</a>, <a href="https://envirodatagov.org/wp-content/uploads/2017/02/EDGI-Introduction-and-Accomplishments-Report.pdf" target="_blank">secure distribution of scientific data sets</a>, <a href="https://ipfs.io/blog/24-uncensorable-wikipedia/" target="_blank">mirroring Wikipedia</a>, <a href="https://akasha.world/" target="_blank">creating new social networks</a>, <a href="https://github.com/cancergenetrust/cgtd" target="_blank">sharing cancer data</a>, <a href="https://filecoin.io/" target="_blank"> blockchain</a> creation, <a href="https://peergos.org/" target="_blank"> secure and encrypted personal-file storage and sharing</a>, <a href="https://github.com/diasdavid/npm-on-ipfs" target="_blank">developer</a> <a href="https://hardbin.com/" target="_blank">tools</a>, and <a href="http://www.cse.unsw.edu.au/~hpaik/thesis/showcases/16s2/scott_brisbane.pdf" target="_blank">data analytics</a>.
</p><p>
	You may have used this network already: If you’ve ever visited the Protocol Labs site (
	<a href="http://protocol.ai/" target="_blank">Protocol.ai</a>), you’ve retrieved pages of a website from IPFS without even realizing it!
	<span class="ieee-end-mark"></span>
</p><p><em>This article appears in the November 2022 print issue as “To the InterPlanetary File System—and Beyond!”</em></p>]]></description><pubDate>Sun, 09 Oct 2022 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spectrum.ieee.org/peer-to-peer-network</guid><category>Internet</category><category>Peer-to-peer</category><dc:creator>David Dias</dc:creator><media:content medium="image" type="image/png" url="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/an-illustration-of-a-series.png?id=31861014&amp;width=980"></media:content></item><item><title>The Impact of Standard Essential Patents (SEPs)</title><link>https://clarivate.com/lp/dont-let-standards-slip-how-to-prioritize-your-efforts-when-everything-is-essential/?campaignname=Standards_Essential_Patents_LeadGen_IPG_Global_2022&amp;campaignid=7014N000001uvkS&amp;utm_campaign=Standards_Essential_Patents_LeadGen_IPG_Global_2022&amp;utm_source=third_party_email_IEEE&amp;utm_medium=paid</link><description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/image.png?id=27150766&width=980"/><br/><br/><p>As standard essential patents (SEPs) continue to accelerate and impact new industries beyond just telecommunications, it’s become increasingly challenging for stakeholders to wade through data sets, navigate data weaknesses and assess what’s truly essential in order to make the best commercial and licensing decisions.<u></u><u></u></p><p><a href="https://clarivate.com/lp/dont-let-standards-slip-how-to-prioritize-your-efforts-when-everything-is-essential/?campaignname=Standards_Essential_Patents_LeadGen_IPG_Global_2022&campaignid=7014N000001uvkS&utm_campaign=Standards_Essential_Patents_LeadGen_IPG_Global_2022&utm_source=third_party_email_IEEE&utm_medium=paid" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow" target="_blank">Download this free whitepaper now!</a></p><p>To help you navigate the complexities of SEPs, we’ve released a new standards essential patents paper covering:<u></u><u></u></p><ul><li>Challenges stemming from the significant growth in SEPs<u></u><u></u></li><li>Recent policy updates and long term needs to address systemic issues<u></u><u></u></li><li>What trends to expect in the SEP space going forward<u></u><u></u></li><li>Takeaways for SEP owners and implementers to tackle issues efficiently and effectively in the short term</li></ul>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Oct 2022 18:50:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://clarivate.com/lp/dont-let-standards-slip-how-to-prioritize-your-efforts-when-everything-is-essential/?campaignname=Standards_Essential_Patents_LeadGen_IPG_Global_2022&amp;campaignid=7014N000001uvkS&amp;utm_campaign=Standards_Essential_Patents_LeadGen_IPG_Global_2022&amp;utm_source=third_party_email_IEEE&amp;utm_medium=paid</guid><category>Clarivate</category><category>Innovation</category><category>Patents</category><category>Type:whitepaper</category><dc:creator>Clarivate</dc:creator><media:content medium="image" type="image/png" url="https://assets.rbl.ms/27150766/origin.png"></media:content></item><item><title>Entangled Photons Can Come Out in Webs Now</title><link>https://spectrum.ieee.org/metasurface-entangled-photons</link><description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/purple-toned-close-up-of-an-object-which-has-many-squares-on-it-covered-in-green-light.jpg?id=31842638&width=1245&height=700&coordinates=0%2C253%2C0%2C253"/><br/><br/><p>The equipment that generates <a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/what-is-quantum-entanglement" target="_blank">quantum entanglement</a> is often bulky and produces entangled photons only one pair at a time. Now scientists have created a device roughly one-third as thick as a penny that can yield complex webs of entangled photons—not just in pairs but several pairs all linked together. The invention may not only greatly simplify the setup needed for quantum technology but also help support more complex quantum applications.</p><p>A common way to generate entangled photons is by shining a beam of light at a special “<a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/quantum-holography-using-undetected-light" target="_self">nonlinear crysta</a>l.” These crystals each can split a photon into two lower-energy, longer-wavelength entangled photons.</p><p class="pull-quote">“The opportunities are vast, and we have just scratched the surface.”<br/>—Igal Brener, Sandia National Laboratories</p><p>The conventional techniques for producing entangled photons are not flexible—they generate pairs of photons only within specific ranges of wavelengths that are typically very narrow, says study cosenior author <a href="https://mpl.mpg.de/research-at-mpl/independent-research-groups/chekhova-research-group/" target="_blank">Maria Chekhova</a>, a physicist at the Max Planck Institute for the Science of Light in Erlangen, Germany. This narrow bandwidth can limit communication rates.</p><p>In addition, the standard methods for producing entangled photons end up dictating many of the properties of the entangled photons, such as their wavelength and polarization, Chekhova adds. More equipment is needed if one wants to further manipulate these features, she explains.</p><p>Moreover, nonlinear crystals are often bulky. This can prove cumbersome for applications that require many entangled photons. “A quantum computation source would require tens or hundreds of bulky crystals,” says study cosenior author <a href="https://www.lanl.gov/search-capabilities/profiles/igal-brener.shtml" target="_blank">Igal Brener</a>, a physicist at Sandia National Laboratories’ Center for Integrated Nanotechnologies in Albuquerque.</p><p>Instead of a lab full of crystals, lenses, mirrors, filters, and other equipment to generate entangled photons, scientists now find that devices only roughly a half-millimeter thick may suffice. The devices are <a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/metalens" target="_self">metasurfaces</a>, which are surfaces covered with forests of microscopic pillars.</p><p>“We just need to focus one or more lasers onto a flat sample, and the rest is done by the metasurface,” Brener says.</p><p>The metasurfaces each consist of a glass surface 500 micromillimeters thick covered with gallium arsenide structures that each resemble cubes roughly 300 nanometers wide with notches cut into them. The way in which the composition, structure, and placement of each metasurface’s nanostructures are tailored could help the scientists control many features of light falling onto the devices.</p><p class="shortcode-media shortcode-media-rebelmouse-image">
<img alt="A silver square with 110 pink rectangles in a grid. Blue waves come in the back and orange and red waves come out the front and are linked by white light." class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="bc4935a69e19bdaad3cd85e538c3e18a" data-rm-shortcode-name="rebelmouse-image" id="b9db1" loading="lazy" src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/a-silver-square-with-110-pink-rectangles-in-a-grid-blue-waves-come-in-the-back-and-orange-and-red-waves-come-out-the-front-and.jpg?id=31842653&width=980"/>
<small class="image-media media-caption" placeholder="Add Photo Caption...">In this artist rendering of a metasurface, light passes through tiny rectangular structures—the building blocks of the metasurface—and creates pairs of entangled photons at different wavelengths.</small><small class="image-media media-photo-credit" placeholder="Add Photo Credit...">Sandia National Laboratories</small></p><p>Shining a laser beam onto these metasurfaces can result in entangled photons emerging. “One single metasurface can, in principle, create several types of entangled photon pairs,” Brener says. “Creating more complex quantum states using multiple photon pairs can lead to new or more efficient ways to do quantum computation, <a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/superradiance-sensor" target="_self">sensing</a>, encryption, and so on.”</p><p>In addition, metasurfaces could manipulate a range of the entangled photons’ features, “but we haven’t explored that degree of freedom yet,” Brener says. “The opportunities are vast, and we have just scratched the surface.”</p><p>Currently the efficiency of these metasurfaces is low. “We had a rate of less than one pair per second, and standard crystals give hundreds of thousands pairs per second,” Chekhova says. However, she notes, further modifications of the devices may improve efficiency by at least a thousandfold.</p><p>The group’s research was detailed in a study <a href="https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.abq8684" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">online</a> 25 August in <em>Science. </em></p>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2022 15:02:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spectrum.ieee.org/metasurface-entangled-photons</guid><category>Gallium arsenide</category><category>Quantum computing</category><category>Quantum cryptography</category><category>Quantum sensor</category><category>Entanglement</category><category>Nonlinear</category><category>Metasurfaces</category><dc:creator>Charles Q. Choi</dc:creator><media:content medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/purple-toned-close-up-of-an-object-which-has-many-squares-on-it-covered-in-green-light.jpg?id=31842638&amp;width=980"></media:content></item><item><title>Strange Topological Physics Could Help Enable 6G Tech</title><link>https://spectrum.ieee.org/photonic-topological-insulators-2658324693</link><description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/a-pattern-of-red-triangles-with-some-that-are-yellow.jpg?id=31821727&width=1245&height=700&coordinates=0%2C100%2C0%2C101"/><br/><br/><p>The next generation of wireless communications, <a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/6g-geopolitics" target="_self">6G</a>, will likely rely on terahertz rays to help reach unprecedented speeds. Now research suggests that unusual topological physics may help control terahertz radiation on chips for 6G applications.</p><p><a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/terahertz-chip" target="_self">Terahertz waves</a> (also called <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Terahertz_radiation" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">submillimeter radiation or far-infrared light</a>) fall between optical waves and microwaves on the electromagnetic spectrum. Ranging in frequency from 0.1 to 10 terahertz, these waves could be key to <a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/memristor-6g-switches" target="_self">future 6G wireless networks</a>.</p><p>“Terahertz technologies are the critical enabler for developing 6G devices, products, services, and ubiquitous connectivity that will redefine how we create, consume, and deliver data,” says study senior author <a href="http://web.spms.ntu.edu.sg/~ranjans/prof.html" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Ranjan Singh</a>, a photonics researcher at <a href="https://www.ntu.edu.sg/" target="_blank">Nanyang Technological University</a>, in Singapore.</p><p>The vision for 6G includes blazingly fast speeds of <a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/terabit-second" target="_self">terabits</a> (trillions of bits) per second to support applications such as autonomous vehicles, augmented reality, and immersive telepresence. These goals require on-chip communication technologies providing data rates beyond 100 gigabits (billions of bits) per second.</p><p>However, existing terahertz on-chip communication devices suffer from signal scattering, crosstalk—signals leaking between channels—and the inability to actively tune across multiple channels. These problems have limited these devices to data-transmission speeds of a few dozen gigabits per second.</p><p>“A novel integrated-circuit architecture is required to compute, process, and transport a massive volume of data using terahertz carrier frequencies,” Singh says.</p><p>Singh and his colleagues now reveal that the growing field of topological photonics may help overcome these challenges. They detailed <a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-022-32909-6" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">their findings</a> online 15 September in the journal <em>Nature Communications</em>.</p><p><a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/a-beginners-guide-to-topological-materials" target="_self">Topology</a> is the branch of mathematics that investigates what features of shapes may survive deformation. For example, an object shaped like a doughnut can be pushed and pulled into the shape of a mug, so that the doughnut’s hole forms the hole in the cup’s handle. However, the object could not lose its hole without changing into a fundamentally different shape.</p><p>Using insights from topology, researchers developed the first electronic topological insulators in 2007. Electrons zipping along the edges or surfaces of these materials strongly resist any disturbances that might hamper their flow, much like how a doughnut-shaped object will retain the same basic topology no matter how much it gets deformed—so long as the hole remains intact. This breakthrough won <a href="https://www.nobelprize.org/prizes/physics/2016/press-release/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">the Nobel Prize in Physics in 2016</a>.</p><p>Recently, scientists have created <a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/photonic-topological-insulators" target="_self">photonic topological insulators</a> in which photons of light are similarly “topologically protected.” These materials usually possess regular variations in their structures that let specific wavelengths of light flow within them without scattering or losses, even around corners and imperfections. One possible application for such materials could be <a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/roomtemp-topolaser" target="_self">lasers that incorporate topological protection</a>, which may be more efficient and robust against defects than conventional devices. Another application might be helping <a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/terahertz-chip" target="_self">data flow through chips at a trillion bits per second</a>.</p><p>In the new study, researchers fabricated a silicon chip that was 200 micrometers thick and roughly 20 centimeters wide. They perforated it with rows of triangular holes. Each triangle alternated in width between 72.75 and 169.75 micrometers, with the smaller triangles pointing in the opposite direction of the larger ones. These rows of holes were arranged in clusters in which all the larger triangles either pointed up or down. Light entering this chip flowed, topologically protected, along the interface between the different sets of holes.</p><p>The new on-chip topological waveguide could support a single-channel broadband-communication link with data rates of up to 160 Gb/s. The researchers showed that they could use light to actively turn the chip on and off.</p><p>The scientists also coupled this device to an on-chip topological demultiplexer that enabled simultaneous multiple independent signals in the communications network. They found they could achieve two perfectly isolated data signals without any crosstalk. One channel permitted real-time uncompressed high-definition video streaming at 1.5 Gb/s, while the other supported data transmission at 40 Gb/s.</p><p>The new topological chip “will be a stepping stone for developing terahertz integrated circuits for emerging 6G devices,” Singh says.</p>]]></description><pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2022 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spectrum.ieee.org/photonic-topological-insulators-2658324693</guid><category>Photonics</category><category>Terahertz</category><category>Terabit</category><category>6g</category><category>Topological insulators</category><dc:creator>Charles Q. Choi</dc:creator><media:content medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/a-pattern-of-red-triangles-with-some-that-are-yellow.jpg?id=31821727&amp;width=980"></media:content></item><item><title>Government’s Role in Further Developing 5G Technologies and Future Networks</title><link>https://event.on24.com/wcc/r/3955427/412CCC2ABF3FDA6A2F3EC0135093DD67</link><description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/image.png?id=26851521&width=980"/><br/><br/><p>
	Similar to 5G, many key technology developments have been supported by government funding and institutions for years. Federally Funded Research and Development Centers (FFRDC) and University Affiliated Research Centers (UARC) have been foundational elements of this government support.
</p><p>
	This webinar will examine the impact this research has had on national security and the overall economy. It will also discuss how these institutions have made use of testing to attain these security and economic goals. Finally, it will look at how these resources can continue to be leveraged in the further development of 5G technologies and beyond for future networks.<u></u><u></u>
</p><p>
<a href="https://event.on24.com/wcc/r/3955427/412CCC2ABF3FDA6A2F3EC0135093DD67" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Register now for this webinar!</a></p><hr/><p><strong>
	Speaker:
</strong></p><p>
			MURAT TORLAK
		</p><p>		Program Director, Computer and Network Systems (CNS)</p><p>
			Murat Torlak received the M.S. and Ph.D. degrees in electrical engineering from The University of Texas at Austin, in 1995 and 1999, respectively. Since August 1999, he has been with the Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering, The University of Texas at Dallas, where he has been promoted to the rank of a Full Professor. He is on leave from UT Dallas to serve as a Rotating Program Director at the U.S. National Science Foundation (NSF) since mid 2020. His current research interests include experimental verification of wireless networking systems, cognitive radios, millimeter-wave automotive radars, millimeter-wave imaging systems, and interference mitigation in radio telescopes. He has served as an Associate Editor for the IEEE Transactions on Wireless Communications, from 2008 to 2013. He was a Guest co-Editor of IEEE JSTSP Special Issue on Recent Advances in Automotive Radar Signal Processing, 2021. He has also served in several IEEE committees and helped to organized IEEE conferences.
		</p>]]></description><pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2022 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://event.on24.com/wcc/r/3955427/412CCC2ABF3FDA6A2F3EC0135093DD67</guid><category>5g</category><category>Anritsu</category><category>Telecommunications</category><category>Type:webinar</category><dc:creator>Anritsu</dc:creator><media:content medium="image" type="image/png" url="https://assets.rbl.ms/26851521/origin.png"></media:content></item><item><title>Full-Wave EM Simulations: Electrically Large Antenna Placement and RCS Scenarios</title><link>https://wipl-d.com/electrically-large-scenarios/</link><description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/image.png?id=26851496&width=980"/><br/><br/><p>Handling various complex simulation scenarios with a single simulation method is a rather challenging task for any software suite. We will show you how our software, based on Method-of-Moments, can analyze several scenarios including complicated and electrically large models (for instance, antenna placement and RCS) using desktop workstations.<u></u><u></u></p><p><a href="https://wipl-d.com/electrically-large-scenarios/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Download this free whitepaper now!</a></p>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 23 Sep 2022 15:52:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wipl-d.com/electrically-large-scenarios/</guid><category>Antennas</category><category>Electromagnetic waves</category><category>Simulation</category><category>Type:whitepaper</category><category>Wipl-d</category><dc:creator>WIPL-D</dc:creator><media:content medium="image" type="image/png" url="https://assets.rbl.ms/26851496/origin.png"></media:content></item><item><title>Automated Cloud Driven Scheduling and Optimization of 5G Phased Antenna Arrays</title><link>https://www.ansys.com/resource-center/webinar/automated-cloud-driven-scheduling-optimization-5g-phased-antenna-array</link><description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/image.png?id=26851525&width=980"/><br/><br/><p>
	Nokia and Ansys Presents: Automated Cloud Driven Scheduling and Optimization of 5G Phased Antenna Arrays.
</p><p>
<a href="https://www.ansys.com/resource-center/webinar/automated-cloud-driven-scheduling-optimization-5g-phased-antenna-array" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow" target="_blank">Register now for this free webinar!</a>
</p><p>
	5G massive MIMO radio applications require more complex antenna systems. The phased antenna array design workflow for such systems is typically both comprehensive and complex, which many times requires a combined effort from different experts.
</p><hr/><p>
	Moreover, the traditional antenna design workflow involves extensive manual tweaking of design parameters to achieve optimum performance. Furthermore, the large 5G phase antenna array simulations are naturally computationally extensive but can mitigated with high-performance computing. However, the most efficient workflow would require a cloud driven workflow that is capable of embarrassingly parallel computation i.e., parallel computing of both the design variations from the optimizer, and the frequency sweep within each design variation.
</p><p>
	This presentation will show how a real 5G phased antenna array optimization workflow within the Ansys product family, where Ansys ModelCenter is the orchestrator that is scheduling the design variations for the optimizer. The state-of-the-art EM solvers in Ansys HFSS is automatically configured to execute and solve the design variations in parallel in the Ansys cloud environment. The automation of this workflow not only enables a far reduced complexity in the optimization process of 5G phased antenna array, but also considerable time savings due to the hardware availability and parallelism of Ansys Cloud.
</p><p>
<strong>What you will learn:</strong>
</p><ul>
<li>How to build real 5G phased antenna array optimization workflow</li>
<li>How to use ModelCenter to schedule the design variations for the optimizer</li>
<li>How to automatically configure, execute and solve the design variations in parallel</li>
<li>How to overcome hardware bottlenecks by employing Ansys Cloud</li>
<li>How to drive time savings in your project</li>
</ul><p>
<strong>Who should attend:</strong>
</p><p>
	This webinar will benefit engineers and designers working with phased antenna array applications. The attendees will learn how Ansys solutions can connect silos, reduce hardware and bottlenecks, and improve time to market.
</p><h2>CONTINUING EDUCATION CERTIFICATES</h2><p>
			Attendees of this IEEE Spectrum webinar have the opportunity to earn PDHs or Continuing Education Certificates!
		</p><p>
			To request your certificate you will need to get a code. You will be provided a code during the webinar (live or on-demand) which will enable you to <a href="http://innovationatwork.ieee.org/spectrum/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">complete the form</a> to request the certificate.
		</p>]]></description><pubDate>Tue, 13 Sep 2022 16:58:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.ansys.com/resource-center/webinar/automated-cloud-driven-scheduling-optimization-5g-phased-antenna-array</guid><category>5g</category><category>Angennas</category><category>Ansys</category><category>Mimo</category><category>Nokia</category><category>Type:webinar</category><dc:creator>Ansys</dc:creator><media:content medium="image" type="image/png" url="https://assets.rbl.ms/26851525/origin.png"></media:content></item><item><title>Apple Kicks Off the Cell-Calls-From-Space Race</title><link>https://spectrum.ieee.org/5g-from-space-apple-spacex</link><description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/man-talking-on-apple-smartphone.jpg?id=31529965&width=1245&height=700&coordinates=0%2C0%2C0%2C469"/><br/><br/><p>The race to deliver cellular calls from space passes two milestones this month and saw one major announcement last month. First, <a href="https://www.apple.com/iphone-14/" target="_blank">Apple will offer emergency satellite messaging on two of its latest iPhone models</a>, the company announced on Wednesday. Second, AST SpaceMobile plans a launch on Saturday, 10 September, of an experimental satellite to test full-fledged satellite 5G service. In addition, T-Mobile USA and SpaceX intend to offer their own messaging and limited data service via the second generation of SpaceX’s Starlink satellite constellation, as <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Qzli-Ww26Qs" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">the two companies announced on 25 August</a>. </p><p>Each contender is taking a different approach to space-based cellular service. The Apple offering <a href="https://www.lightreading.com/5g/globalstars-mystery-deepens/d/d-id/771369https://investors.globalstar.com/node/14431/html" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">uses the existing satellite bandwidth</a> Globalstar once used for messaging offerings, but without the need for a satellite-specific handset. The AST project and another company, <a href="https://lynk.global/" target="_blank">Lynk Global</a>, would use a dedicated network of satellites with larger-than-normal antennas to produce a 4G, 5G, and someday 6G cellular signal compatible with any existing 4G-compatible phone (as detailed in <a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/5g-satellite" target="_blank">other recent <em>IEEE</em> <em>Spectrum</em></a><a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/5g-satellite"> coverage</a> of space-based 5G offerings). Assuming regulatory approval is forthcoming, the technology would work first in equatorial regions and then across more of the planet as these providers expand their satellite constellations. T-Mobile and Starlink’s offering would work in the former PCS band in the United States. SpaceX, like AST and Lynk, would need to negotiate access to spectrum on a country-by-country basis.</p><p>Apple’s competitors are unlikely to see commercial operations before 2024.</p><p class="pull-quote">“Regulators have not decided on the power limits from space, what concerns there are about interference, especially across national borders. There’s a whole bunch of regulatory issues that simply haven’t been thought about to date.”<br/>—Tim Farrar, telecommunications consultant</p><p>The T-Mobile–Starlink announcement is “in some ways an endorsement” of AST and Lynk’s proposition, and “in other ways a great threat,” says telecommunications consultant Tim Farrar of <a href="http://www.tmfassociates.com/Principals.html" target="_blank">Tim Farrar Associates</a> in Menlo Park, Calif. AST and Lynk have so far told investors they expect their national mobile network operator partners to charge per use or per day, but T-Mobile announced that they plan to include satellite messaging in the 1,900-megahertz range in their existing services. Apple said their Emergency SOS via Satellite service would be free the first two years for U.S. and Canadian iPhone 14 buyers, but did not say what it would cost after that. For now, the Globalstar satellites it is using cannot offer the kind of broadband bandwidth AST has promised, but Globalstar has reported to investors orders for new satellites that might offer new capabilities, including new gateways.</p><p>Even under the best conditions—a clear view of the sky—users will need 15 seconds to send a message via Apple’s service. They will also have to follow onscreen guidance to keep the device pointed at the satellites they are using. Light foliage can cause the same message to take more than a minute to send. Ashley Williams, a satellite engineer at Apple who recorded the service’s announcement, also mentioned a data-compression algorithm and a series of rescue-related suggested auto-replies intended to minimize the amount of data that users would need to send during a rescue.</p><p>Meanwhile, AST SpaceMobile says it aims to launch an experimental satellite Saturday, 10 September, to test its cellular broadband offering.</p><p>Last month’s T-Mobile-SpaceX <a href="https://www.t-mobile.com/news/un-carrier/t-mobile-takes-coverage-above-and-beyond-with-spacex" target="_blank">announcement</a> “helped the world focus attention on the huge market opportunity for SpaceMobile, the only planned space-based cellular broadband network. BlueWalker 3, which has a 693 sq ft array, is scheduled for launch within weeks!” <a href="https://twitter.com/AbelAvellan/status/1562987060977614848?s=20&t=0CE866Ew1r_F2YjDQCR77Q" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">tweeted</a> AST SpaceMobile CEO Abel Avellan on 25 August. The size of the array matters because AST SpaceMobile has so far indicated in its applications for experimental satellite licenses that it intends to use lower radio frequencies (700–900 MHz) with less propagation loss but that require antennas much larger than conventional satellites carry.</p><p>The size of the array will also make it more reflective, which has raised concerns among astronomers. The size of Starlink’s planned constellation has already provoked complaints among astronomers because it will interfere with their ability to observe space. <em>Sky & Telescope</em> magazine <a href="https://skyandtelescope.org/astronomy-news/as-bluewalker-satellites-join-a-brightening-sky-heres-how-you-can-help/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">published on 1 September a call</a> for both professional and amateur astronomers to observe the growing constellations of satellites to document the interference. Professional astronomy societies have <a href="https://aas.org/posts/advocacy/2021/08/impacts-large-satellite-constellations-astronomy-live-updates" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">lobbied U.S. government agencies and Congress on the issue and met with SpaceX officials in May to discuss a recent change that brightened satellites by 0.5 visual magnitudes</a>. </p><p>So far government agencies have issued licenses for thousands of low-Earth-orbiting satellites, which have the biggest impact on astronomers. Even with the constellations starting to form, satellite-cellular telecommunications companies are still open to big regulatory risks. “Regulators have not decided on the power limits from space, what concerns there are about interference, especially across national borders. There’s a whole bunch of regulatory issues that simply haven’t been thought about to date,” Farrar says.</p><p>For a hiker with a twisted ankle, a messaging service that takes a while to connect and twinkles in and out of service as satellites fly by may be better than nothing, but early space-based cellular <a href="https://frankrayal.com/2022/08/29/t-mobile-spacex-direct-satellite-to-handset-service-lots-of-hype-and-little-reality/" target="_blank">will not be a seamless way to connect to video calls from out at sea</a>.</p><p>“User cooperation is in my view the single most critical aspect of whether this service will attract mass-market usage or people willing to pay a significant amount for this service,” Farrar says.</p>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Sep 2022 14:18:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spectrum.ieee.org/5g-from-space-apple-spacex</guid><category>5g</category><category>Satellite broadband</category><category>Apple</category><category>Spacex</category><dc:creator>Lucas Laursen</dc:creator><media:content medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/man-talking-on-apple-smartphone.jpg?id=31529965&amp;width=980"></media:content></item><item><title>A Four-Year Program to Tackle a Fundamental Antenna Challenge</title><link>https://spectrum.ieee.org/electrically-small-antenna</link><description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/differently-colored-lines-of-light-swirl-on-a-dark-background.jpg?id=31484242&width=1245&height=700&coordinates=0%2C234%2C0%2C235"/><br/><br/><p>For 80 years, a class of antenna called electrically small antennas has been stymied by a seemingly insurmountable barrier. These antennas, which can receive signals with wavelengths that are much longer than the antennas themselves, are seemingly stuck with designs in which there is a trade-off between high bandwidth and efficiency.</p><p>Now, a new program by the U.S. <a href="https://www.iarpa.gov/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Intelligence Advanced Research Projects Activity</a> (IARPA) agency seeks ways to finally circumvent or overcome these historical limitations for electrically small antennas. Over the next four years, the research teams participating in the <a href="https://www.iarpa.gov/research-programs/equal-p" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Effective Quantitative Antenna Limits for Performance</a> (EQuAL-P) program will work through three phases of progressively more ambitious benchmarks in order to prove their ideas can work.</p><p>The simplest form of antenna is a dipole antenna, which is essentially just two pieces of wire placed end to end with a feed point in the middle. The length of this antenna is typically half the wavelength of the signal that is being received or transmitted, so a shortwave radio dipole working in the 20-meter band would be 10 meters long. An “electrically small” antenna is one that is significantly shorter than the wavelength of the signals it is designed for. These antennas typically take the form of small loops or patches. </p><p>The benefit of electrically small antennas is clear—as the name implies, they confer an advantage when space is at a premium. Satellites, for example, can use them to reduce mass and free up more space for other components.</p><p>But the trade-off with electrically small antennas is that as they get shorter, their bandwidth and radiation efficiency also shrink, eventually hitting something named the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chu%E2%80%93Harrington_limit" target="_blank">Chu-Harrington limit</a>. This has meant that although such antennas have been in use for decades, they remain difficult to design and limited in their applicability. Historically, any attempts to widen the usable bandwidth have decreased these antennas' radiation efficiency even more, and vice versa. This is the problem the EQuAL-P program is aimed at.</p><p class="pull-quote">The teams have proposed different kinds of approaches, but Kolb says there are several common themes among them.</p><p>“Because it’s an 80-year problem, we want to give them a little more time to come up with solutions,” says <a href="https://www.iarpa.gov/who-we-are/program-managers/dr-paul-kolb" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Paul Kolb</a>, the program manager for EQuAL-P. The eight teams participating will work through three increasingly ambitious phases during the next four years to prove their ideas can pass muster.</p><p>At the end of 18 months, Kolb says, he hopes to see that the teams have made meaningful progress toward the ultimate goal of a 10-decibel gain in antenna performance in the HF and ultrahigh frequency (UHF) bands. But because of the difficulty of the challenge, teams won’t be required to produce a working demonstration of their technology at that point.</p><p>That changes at the end of the second phase, 15 months later, in which the teams will need to demonstrate an actual antenna that has a 6-dB gain in performance over existing electrically small antennas.</p><p>EQuAL-P, like other IARPA projects, will rely on an independent verification of the demonstrations with external labs. In this instance, Kolb says, verification will be provided by the <a href="https://www.niwcpacific.navy.mil/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Naval Information Warfare Center Pacific</a>—which specializes in HF measurements—the <a href="https://www.navair.navy.mil/organization/NAWCWD" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Naval Air Warfare Center Weapons Division</a>, and the <a href="https://www.afrl.af.mil/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Air Force Research Laboratory</a>.</p><p>According to Kolb, the rationale behind the multiple phases is that it gives the agency the ability to fund the teams’ progress in increments, monitor that progress, and end projects if they don’t seem to be panning out.</p><p>The final, 12-month phase will require the research teams to demonstrate a 10-dB gain in performance. Kolb admits the threshold will be difficult to reach. “That’s a huge improvement,” he says, “but it also gives any eventual users enough motivation to actually use the new technique.”</p><p>Kolb doesn’t expect to see commercially viable products four years from now, however. That would be too ambitious even here. Instead, he wants to see functioning demonstrations of the technology that will hopefully provide the participating teams a clearer path forward and a good springboard from which to launch.</p><p>The teams have proposed different kinds of approaches, but Kolb says there are several common themes among them. Almost all of them include, for example, time-varying components—whether that’s accomplished through diodes, voltage changes, switches, or some other mechanism. Many of the teams will also need to design and build their own validation techniques because existing methods for assessing antenna performance likely won’t be up to snuff. In such cases, the teams will also need to ensure that the independent labs can verify their validation techniques.</p><p>The eight teams include researchers from <a href="https://www.boeing.com/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Boeing</a>, <a href="https://www.ncsu.edu/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">North Carolina State University</a>, <a href="https://www.rtx.com/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Raytheon</a>, and the <a href="https://www.wisc.edu/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">University of Wisconsin-Madison</a>, to name a few. In order to keep the number of teams manageable, Kolb says, some groups with similar proposals were combined, such as two groups in the <a href="https://www.universityofcalifornia.edu/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">University of California</a> system that originally submitted individual proposals.</p><p>Ultimately, there’s no guarantee the program will pan out, but that’s the bread and butter for programs at IARPA, which—like <a href="https://www.darpa.mil/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">DARPA</a> and <a href="https://arpa-e.energy.gov/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">ARPA-E</a>—funds high-risk, high-reward research efforts. And even though the chance of failure is not insignificant, it’s the best chance for improvements to electrically small antennas we've seen in 80 years.</p>]]></description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2022 19:01:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spectrum.ieee.org/electrically-small-antenna</guid><category>Antennas</category><category>Iarpa</category><category>Wireless</category><dc:creator>Michael Koziol</dc:creator><media:content medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/differently-colored-lines-of-light-swirl-on-a-dark-background.jpg?id=31484242&amp;width=980"></media:content></item><item><title>Metamaterials Could Solve One of 6G’s Big Problems</title><link>https://spectrum.ieee.org/metamaterials-could-solve-one-of-6gs-big-problems</link><description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/an-illustration-depicting-cellphone-users-at-street-level-in-a-city-with-wireless-signals-reaching-them-via-reflecting-surfaces.jpg?id=31252545&width=1245&height=700&coordinates=0%2C466%2C0%2C0"/><br/><br/><p>
<strong>For all the tumultuous </strong>revolution in wireless technology over the past several decades, there have been a couple of constants. One is the overcrowding of radio bands, and the other is the move to escape that congestion by exploiting higher and higher frequencies. And today, as engineers roll out 5G and plan for 6G wireless, they find themselves at a crossroads: After years of designing superefficient transmitters and receivers, and of compensating for the signal losses at the end points of a radio channel, they’re beginning to realize that they are approaching the practical limits of transmitter and receiver efficiency. From now on, to get high performance as we go to higher frequencies, we will need to engineer the <em>wireless channel itself</em>. But how can we possibly engineer and control a wireless environment, which is determined by a host of factors, many of them random and therefore unpredictable?
</p><p>
	Perhaps the most promising solution, right now, is to use reconfigurable intelligent surfaces. These are planar structures typically ranging in size from about 100 square centimeters to about 5 square meters or more, depending on the frequency and other factors. These surfaces use advanced substances called 
	<a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/forbestechcouncil/2022/07/07/what-are-metamaterials-and-what-does-this-science-have-to-do-with-the-future-of-space/?sh=2986c4413487" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">metamaterials</a> to reflect and refract electromagnetic waves. Thin two-dimensional metamaterials, known as metasurfaces, can be designed to sense the local electromagnetic environment and tune the wave’s key properties, such as its <a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41377-021-00552-3" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">amplitude, phase, and polarization</a>, as the wave is reflected or refracted by the surface. So as the waves fall on such a surface, it can alter the incident waves’ direction so as to strengthen the channel.  In fact, these metasurfaces can be programmed to make these changes dynamically, reconfiguring the signal in real time in response to changes in the wireless channel. Think of reconfigurable intelligent surfaces as the next evolution of the repeater concept.
</p><p class="pull-quote">
	Reconfigurable intelligent surfaces could play a big role in the coming integration of wireless and satellite networks.
</p><p>
	That’s important, because as we move to higher frequencies, the propagation characteristics become more “hostile” to the signal. The wireless channel varies constantly depending on surrounding objects. At 5G and 6G frequencies, the wavelength is vanishingly small compared to the size of buildings, vehicles, hills, trees, and rain. Lower-frequency waves diffract around or through such obstacles, but higher-frequency signals are absorbed, reflected, or scattered. Basically, at these frequencies, the line-of-sight signal is about all you can count on.
</p><p>
	Such problems help explain why the topic of
	<a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S2352864821000912" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"> reconfigurable intelligent surfaces</a> (RIS) is one of the hottest in wireless research. The hype is justified. A landslide of R&D activity and results has gathered momentum over the last several years, set in motion by the development of the first digitally controlled metamaterials <a href="https://encyclopedia.pub/entry/history/show/32830" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">almost 10 years ago</a>.
</p><div class="ieee-sidebar-medium">
<p class="shortcode-media shortcode-media-rebelmouse-image">
		This article was jointly produced by 
		<em>IEEE Spectrum</em> and <em>Proceedings of the IEEE </em>with similar versions published in both publications. For more on reconfigurable intelligent surfaces, those with access to IEEE Xplore can download <a href="https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?isnumber=9896612" target="_blank">a complete special issue</a> on the topic.
	</p>
</div><p>
	RIS prototypes are showing great promise at scores of laboratories around the world. And yet one of the first major projects, the European-funded 
	<a href="https://www.visorsurf.eu/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Visorsurf</a>, began just five years ago and ran until 2020. The first public demonstrations of the technology occurred in late 2018, by <a href="https://www.docomo.ne.jp/english/corporate/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">NTT Docomo</a> in Japan and<a href="https://www.metawave.com/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"> Metawave</a>, of Carlsbad, Calif.
</p><p>
	Today, hundreds of researchers in Europe, Asia, and the United States are working on applying RIS to produce programmable and smart wireless environments. Vendors such as Huawei, Ericsson, NEC, Nokia, Samsung, and ZTE are working alone or in collaboration with universities. And major network operators, such as NTT Docomo, Orange, China Mobile, China Telecom, and BT are all carrying out substantial RIS trials or have plans to do so. This work has repeatedly demonstrated the ability of RIS to greatly strengthen signals in the most problematic bands of 5G and 6G.
</p><h2>How reconfigurable intelligent surfaces strengthen a wireless signal</h2><p>
	To understand how RIS improves a signal, consider the electromagnetic environment. 
	<a href="https://www.businesstechweekly.com/operational-efficiency/wireless-networks/cellular-networks/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Traditional cellular networks</a> consist of scattered base stations that are deployed on masts or towers, and on top of buildings and utility poles in urban areas. Objects in the path of a signal can block it, a problem that becomes especially bad at 5G’s higher frequencies, such as the <a href="https://www.techtarget.com/searchnetworking/definition/millimeter-wave-MM-wave#" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">millimeter-wave bands</a> between 24.25 and 52.6 gigahertz. And it will only get worse if communication companies go ahead with plans to exploit <a href="https://www.edn.com/sub-terahertz-research-in-6g-wireless-where-should-you-start/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">subterahertz bands</a>, between 90 and 300 GHz, in 6G networks. Here’s why. With 4G and similar lower-frequency bands, reflections from surfaces can actually strengthen the received signal, as reflected signals combine. However, as we move higher in frequencies, such <a href="https://www.electronics-notes.com/articles/antennas-propagation/propagation-overview/multipath-propagation.php#" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">multipath effects</a> become much weaker or disappear entirely. The reason is that surfaces that appear smooth to a longer-wavelength signal are relatively rough to a shorter-wavelength signal. So rather than reflecting off such a surface, the signal simply scatters.
</p><p>
	One solution is to use more powerful base stations or to install more of them throughout an area. But that strategy can double costs, or worse. Repeaters or relays can also improve coverage but here, too, the costs can be prohibitive. RIS, on the other hand, promises greatly improved coverage at just marginally higher cost
</p><div class="rm-embed embed-media"><div class="flourish-embed flourish-cards" data-src="visualisation/10941421?607871">
<script src="https://public.flourish.studio/resources/embed.js"> </script>
</div></div><p>
	The key feature of RIS that makes it attractive in comparison with these alternatives is its nearly passive nature. The absence of amplifiers to boost the signal means that an RIS node can be powered with just a battery and a small solar panel.
</p><p>
	RIS functions like a very sophisticated mirror, whose orientation and curvature can be adjusted in order to focus and redirect a signal in a specific direction. But rather than physically moving or reshaping the mirror, you electronically alter its surface so that it changes key properties of the incoming 
	<a href="http://electron9.phys.utk.edu/optics421/modules/m1/emwaves.htm" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">electromagnetic wave</a>, such as the phase.
</p><p>
	That’s what the metamaterials do. This emerging class of materials exhibits properties beyond (from the Greek 
	<em>meta</em>) those of natural materials, such as anomalous reflection or refraction. The materials are fabricated using ordinary metals and electrical insulators, or dielectrics. As an electromagnetic wave impinges on a metamaterial, a predetermined gradient in the material alters the phase and other characteristics  of the wave, making it possible to bend the wave front and redirect the beam as desired.
</p><p>
	An RIS node is made up of hundreds or thousands of metamaterial elements called unit cells. Each cell consists of metallic and dielectric layers along with one or more switches or other tunable components. A typical structure includes an upper metallic patch with switches, a biasing layer, and a metallic ground layer separated by dielectric substrates. By controlling the biasing—the voltage between the metallic patch and the ground layer—you can switch each unit cell on or off and thus control how each cell alters the phase and other characteristics of an incident wave.
</p><p>
	To control the direction of the larger wave reflecting off the entire RIS, you synchronize all the unit cells to create patterns of 
	<a href="https://www.phys.uconn.edu/~gibson/Notes/Section5_2/Sec5_2.htm" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">constructive and destructive interference</a> in the larger reflected waves [ see illustration below]. This interference pattern reforms the incident beam and sends it in a particular direction determined by the pattern. This basic operating principle, by the way, is the same as that of a phased-array radar.
</p><h3>Beamforming by constructive and destructive interference</h3><br/><img class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="28a6d2cedeefffce6750988a7c21767f" data-rm-shortcode-name="rebelmouse-image" id="84106" loading="lazy" src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/image.png?id=31258733&width=980"/><p>A reconfigurable intelligent surface comprises an array of unit cells. In each unit cell, a metamaterial alters the phase of an incoming radio wave, so that the resulting waves interfere with one another [above, top]. Precisely controlling the patterns of this constructive and destructive interference allows the reflected wave to be redirected [bottom], improving signal coverage.</p><h3></h3><br/><div class="rblad-ieee_in_content"></div><h3></h3><br/><p>An RIS has other useful features. Even without an amplifier, an RIS manages to provide substantial gain—about 30 to 40 decibels relative to isotropic (dBi)—depending on the size of the surface and the frequency. That’s because the gain of an antenna is <a href="https://www.phys.hawaii.edu/~anita/new/papers/militaryHandbook/antennas.pdf" target="_blank">proportional to the antenna’s aperture</a> area. An RIS has the equivalent of many antenna elements covering a large aperture area, so it has higher gain than a conventional antenna does.</p><p>All the many unit cells in an RIS are controlled by a logic chip, such as a <a href="https://www.xilinx.com/products/silicon-devices/fpga/what-is-an-fpga.html" target="_blank">field-programmable gate array</a> with a microcontroller, which also stores the many coding sequences needed to dynamically tune the RIS. The controller gives the appropriate instructions to the individual unit cells, setting their state. The most common coding scheme is simple binary coding, in which the controller toggles the switches of each unit cell on and off. The unit-cell switches are usually semiconductor devices, such as <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/PIN_diode" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">PIN diodes</a> or field-effect transistors.</p><p>The important factors here are power consumption, speed, and flexibility, with the control circuit usually being one of the most power-hungry parts of an RIS. Reasonably efficient RIS implementations today have a total power consumption of around a few watts to a dozen watts during the switching state of reconfiguration, and much less in the idle state.</p><h2>Engineers use simulations to decide where to deploy RIS nodes</h2><p>To deploy RIS nodes in a real-world network, researchers must first answer three questions: How many RIS nodes are needed? Where should they be placed? And how big should the surfaces be? As you might expect, there are complicated calculations and trade-offs.</p><p>Engineers can identify the best RIS positions by planning for them when the base station is designed. Or it can be done afterward by identifying, in the coverage map, the areas of poor signal strength. As for the size of the surfaces, that will depend on the frequencies (lower frequencies require larger surfaces) as well as the number of surfaces being deployed.</p><p>To optimize the network’s performance, researchers rely on simulations and measurements. At <a href="https://carrier.huawei.com/en/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Huawei Sweden</a>, where I work, we’ve had a lot of discussions about the best placement of RIS units in urban environments. We’re using a proprietary platform, called the Coffee Grinder Simulator, to <a href="https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/9852389" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">simulate an RIS installation</a> prior to its construction and deployment. We’re partnering with <a href="https://www.cnrs.fr/en/cnrs" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">CNRS Research</a> and <a href="https://www.centralesupelec.fr/en" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">CentraleSupélec</a>, both in France, among others.</p><p>In a recent project, we used simulations to quantify the performance improvement gained when multiple RIS were deployed in a typical urban 5G network. As far as we know, this was the first large-scale, system-level attempt to gauge RIS performance in that setting. We optimized the RIS-augmented wireless coverage through the use of efficient deployment algorithms that we developed. Given the locations of the base stations and the users, the algorithms were designed to help us select the optimal three-dimensional locations and sizes of the RIS nodes from among thousands of possible positions on walls, roofs, corners, and so on. The output of the software is an RIS deployment map that maximizes the number of users able to receive a target signal.</p><h3></h3><br/><div class="rblad-ieee_in_content"></div><h3></h3><br/><img alt="An array of electronic devices sits atop a supporting structure." class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="96ece9d103af560f5688ff5603c19b8a" data-rm-shortcode-name="rebelmouse-image" id="2a98c" loading="lazy" src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/an-array-of-electronic-devices-sits-atop-a-supporting-structure.jpg?id=31253227&width=980"/><h3></h3><br/><div class="rblad-ieee_in_content"></div><h3></h3><br/><p>Of course, the users of special interest are those at the edges of the cell-coverage area, who have the worst signal reception. Our results showed big improvements in coverage and data rates at the cell edges—and also for users with decent signal reception, especially in the millimeter band.</p><p>We also investigated how potential RIS hardware trade-offs affect performance. Simply put, every RIS design requires compromises—such as digitizing the responses of each unit cell into binary phases and amplitudes—in order to construct a less complex and cheaper RIS. But it’s important to know whether a design compromise will create additional beams to undesired directions or cause interference to other users. That’s why we studied the impact of network interference due to multiple base stations, reradiated waves by the RIS, and other factors.</p><p>Not surprisingly, our simulations confirmed that both larger RIS surfaces and larger numbers of them improved overall performance. But which is preferable? When we factored in the costs of the RIS nodes and the base stations, we found that in general a smaller number of larger RIS nodes, deployed further from a base station and its users to provide coverage to a larger area, was a particularly cost-effective solution.</p><p>The size and dimensions of the RIS depend on the operating frequency [see illustration below] . We found that a small number of rectangular RIS nodes, each around 4 meters wide for C-band frequencies (3.5 GHz) and around half a meter wide for millimeter-wave band (28 GHz), was a good compromise, and could boost performance significantly in both bands. This was a pleasant surprise: RIS improved signals not only in the millimeter-wave (5G high) band, where coverage problems can be especially acute, but also in the C band (5G mid).</p><h3></h3><br/><div class="flourish-embed flourish-table" data-src="visualisation/10950128?607871"><script src="https://public.flourish.studio/resources/embed.js"></script></div><h3></h3><br/><img class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="b293f526599e1135fcde3e046820f376" data-rm-shortcode-name="rebelmouse-image" id="ae6de" loading="lazy" src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/image.png?id=31301079&width=980"/><p>
<br/>
</p><p>
	To extend wireless coverage indoors, researchers in Asia are investigating a really intriguing possibility: covering room windows with transparent RIS nodes. Experiments at NTT Docomo and at Southeast and Nanjing universities, both in China, used smart films or smart glass. The films are fabricated from transparent conductive oxides (such as 
	<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Indium_tin_oxide#" target="_blank">indium tin oxide</a>), graphene, or silver nanowires and do not noticeably reduce light transmission. When the films are placed on windows, signals coming from outside can be refracted and boosted as they pass into a building, enhancing the coverage inside.
</p><h2>What will it take to make RIS nodes intelligent?</h2><p>
	Planning and installing the RIS nodes is only part of the challenge. For an RIS node to work optimally, it needs to have a configuration, moment by moment, that is appropriate for the state of the communication channel in the instant the node is being used. The best configuration requires an accurate and instantaneous estimate of the channel. Technicians can come up with such an estimate by measuring the “channel impulse response” between the base station, the RIS, and the users. This response is measured using pilots, which are reference signals known beforehand by both the transmitter and the receiver. It’s a standard technique in wireless communications. Based on this estimation of the channel, it’s possible to calculate the phase shifts for each unit cell in the RIS.
</p><p>
	The current approaches perform these calculations at the base station. However, that requires a huge number of pilots, because every unit cell needs its own phase configuration. There are various ideas for reducing this overhead, but so far none of them are really promising.
</p><p>
	The total calculated configuration for all of the unit cells is fed to each RIS node through a wireless control link. So each RIS node needs a wireless receiver to periodically collect the instructions. This of course consumes power, and it also means that the RIS nodes are fully dependent on the base station, with unavoidable—and unaffordable—overhead and the need for continuous control. As a result, the whole system requires a flawless and complex orchestration of base stations and multiple RIS nodes via the wireless-control channels.
</p><p>
	We need a better way. Recall that the “I” in RIS stands for intelligent. The word suggests real-time, dynamic control of the surface from within the node itself—the ability to learn, understand, and react to changes. We don’t have that now. Today’s RIS nodes cannot perceive, reason, or respond; they only execute remote orders from the base station. That’s why my colleagues and I at Huawei have started working on a project we call Autonomous RIS (AutoRIS). The goal is to enable the RIS nodes to autonomously control and configure the phase shifts of their unit cells. That will largely eliminate the base-station-based control and the massive signaling that either limit the data-rate gains from using RIS, or require synchronization and additional power consumption at the nodes. The success of AutoRIS might very well help determine whether RIS will ever be deployed commercially on a large scale.
</p><p>
	Of course, it’s a rather daunting challenge to integrate into an RIS node the necessary receiving and processing capabilities while keeping the node lightweight and low power. In fact, it will require a huge research effort. For RIS to be commercially competitive, it will have to preserve its low-power nature.
</p><p>
	With that in mind, we are now exploring the integration of an ultralow-power AI chip in an RIS, as well as the use of extremely efficient machine-learning models to provide the intelligence. These smart models will be able to produce the output RIS configuration based on the received data about the channel, while at the same time classifying users according to their contracted services and their network operator. Integrating AI into the RIS will also enable other functions, such as dynamically predicting upcoming RIS configurations and grouping users by location or other behavioral characteristics that affect the RIS operation.
</p><p>
	Intelligent, autonomous RIS won’t be necessary for all situations. For some areas, a static RIS, with occasional reconfiguration—perhaps a couple of times per day or less—will be entirely adequate. In fact, there will undoubtedly be a range of deployments from static to fully intelligent and autonomous. Success will depend on not just efficiency and high performance but also ease of integration into an existing network.
</p><p class="pull-quote">
	6G promises to unleash staggering amounts of bandwidth—but only if we can surmount a potentially ruinous range problem.
</p><p>
	The real test case for RIS will be 6G. The coming generation of wireless is expected to embrace autonomous networks and smart environments with real-time, flexible, software-defined, and adaptive control. Compared with 5G, 6G is expected to provide much higher data rates, greater coverage, lower latency, more intelligence, and sensing services of much higher accuracy. At the same time, a key driver for 6G is sustainability—we’ll need more energy-efficient solutions to achieve the “net zero” emission targets that many network operators are striving for. RIS fits all of those imperatives.
</p><p>
	Start with massive MIMO, which stands for 
	<a href="https://www.electronics-notes.com/articles/antennas-propagation/mimo/what-is-mimo-multiple-input-multiple-output-wireless-technology.php" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">multiple-input multiple-output</a>. This foundational 5G technique uses multiple antennas packed into an array at both the transmitting and receiving ends of wireless channels, to send and receive many signals at once and thus dramatically boost network capacity. However, the desire for higher data rates in 6G will demand even more massive MIMO, which will require many more radio-frequency chains to work and will be power-hungry and costly to operate. An energy-efficient and less costly alternative will be to place multiple low-power RIS nodes between massive MIMO base stations and users as we have described in this article.
</p><p>
	The millimeter-wave and subterahertz 6G bands promise to unleash staggering amounts of bandwidth, but only if we can surmount a potentially ruinous range problem without resorting to costly solutions, such as ultradense deployments of base stations or active repeaters. My opinion is that only RIS will be able to make these frequency bands commercially viable at a reasonable cost.
</p><p>
	The communications industry is already touting sensing—high-accuracy localization services as well as object detection and posture recognition—as an important possible feature for 6G. Sensing would also enhance performance. For example, highly accurate localization of users will help steer wireless beams efficiently. Sensing could also be offered as a new network service to vertical industries such as smart factories and autonomous driving, where detection of people or cars could be used for mapping an environment; the same capability could be used for surveillance in a home-security system. The large aperture of RIS nodes and their resulting high resolution mean that such applications will be not only possible but probably even cost effective.
</p><p>
	And the sky is not the limit. RIS could enable the integration of satellites into 6G networks. Typically, a satellite uses a lot of power and has large antennas to compensate for the long-distance propagation losses and for the modest capabilities of mobile devices on Earth. RIS could play a big role in minimizing those limitations and perhaps even allowing direct communication from satellite to 6G users. Such a scheme could lead to more efficient satellite-integrated 6G networks.
</p><p>
	As it transitions into new services and vast new frequency regimes, wireless communications will soon enter a period of great promise and sobering challenges. Many technologies will be needed to usher in this next exciting phase. None will be more essential than reconfigurable intelligent surfaces.
<span class="ieee-end-mark"></span>
</p><p>
<em>The author wishes to acknowledge the help of Ulrik Imberg in the writing of this article.<br/></em></p><p><em>This article appears in the November 2022 print issue as “6G’s Metamaterials Solution.”<br/></em></p>]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Sep 2022 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spectrum.ieee.org/metamaterials-could-solve-one-of-6gs-big-problems</guid><category>6g</category><category>Metamaterials</category><category>5g</category><category>Wireless communication</category><dc:creator>Marios Poulakis</dc:creator><media:content medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/an-illustration-depicting-cellphone-users-at-street-level-in-a-city-with-wireless-signals-reaching-them-via-reflecting-surfaces.jpg?id=31252545&amp;width=980"></media:content></item><item><title>Apply Al Techniques to Solve Wireless Communications System Design Challenges</title><link>https://engineeringresources.spectrum.ieee.org/free/w_math06/prgm.cgi</link><description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/apply-al-techniques-to-solve-wireless-communications-system-design-challenges.gif?id=31450905&width=1245&height=700&coordinates=75%2C0%2C76%2C0"/><br/><br/><p>The webinar explores the use of artificial intelligence (AI) to solve wireless communications problems. After brief introductions of machine learning, deep leaning and reinforcement learning methodologies, we will cover typical applications, including how standards bodies are incorporating AI techniques in wireless standards. Learn the AI-driven system design workflow, and how to streamline data generation process, AI networks training, and design validation and testing. And, how to simplify deployment of your AI networks on embedded devices, enterprise systems and easily leverage existing deep learning networks outside MATLAB.</p> <p>Highlights include:</p> <ul> <li>Generate training data in the form of synthetic and over-the-air signals</li> <li>Design and train AI models using interactive tools</li> <li>Perform large-scale simulation to test and validate trained networks</li> <li>Deploy validated models to enterprise or embedded systems</li> <li>How to easily interoperate with models developed in 3rd party environments such as python</li> </ul> <p><strong>Speakers</strong>:</p> <p><strong>Houman Zarrinkoub, PhD.</strong>, <em>Principal Wireless Communications Product Manager, MathWorks</em></p> <ul> <li>Dr. Houman Zarrinkoub is the principal product manager at MathWorks responsible for wireless communications products. During his 20-year tenure at MathWorks, he has also served as a development manager and has been responsible for multiple signal processing and communications software tools. Prior to MathWorks, he was a research scientist working on mobile and voice coding technologies in the Wireless Group at Nortel Networks. He has been awarded multiple patents on topics related to computer simulations of signal processing applications. Houman is the author of the book Understanding LTE with MATLAB: From Mathematical Modeling to Simulation and Prototyping. He holds a B.Sc. degree in electrical engineering from McGill University and M.Sc. and Ph.D. degrees in telecommunications from the University of Quebec, in Canada.</li> </ul>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 02 Sep 2022 15:41:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://engineeringresources.spectrum.ieee.org/free/w_math06/prgm.cgi</guid><category>Type:webinar</category><dc:creator>MathWorks</dc:creator><media:content medium="image" type="image/gif" url="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/apply-al-techniques-to-solve-wireless-communications-system-design-challenges.gif?id=31450905&amp;width=980"></media:content></item><item><title>The Metaverse Needs Standards, Too</title><link>https://spectrum.ieee.org/metaverse-standards-forum</link><description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/a-diverse-group-of-people-meeting-in-a-conference-room-in-the-metaverse.jpg?id=31247491&width=1245&height=700&coordinates=0%2C0%2C0%2C0"/><br/><br/><p>When Meta (formerly Facebook) announced in October 2021 that <a href="https://about.fb.com/news/2021/10/facebook-company-is-now-meta/" target="_blank">it would be developing metaverse technologies</a>, it prompted a flurry of speculation and attendant announcements from other companies. Beyond that, it triggered an avalanche of confusion around <a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/metaverse-second-life" target="_self">what exactly</a> <a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/meta-offers-nothing-new-to-the-metaverse" target="_self">the metaverse</a> <a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/silicon-valleys-metaverse-problem" target="_self">is supposed to be</a>.<br/></p><p>Nearly a year later, the concrete details of the metaverse are as opaque as ever. The <a href="https://metaverse-standards.org/" target="_blank">Metaverse Standards Forum</a>, which launched on 21 June 2022, isn’t trying to wrangle those details—not directly. But the forum sees an opportunity to get everyone to sit down at the same (probably virtual) table and hash out the basic technologies needed. With a more solid foundation, the forum believes, the metaverse can better develop and evolve.</p><p>Now, the forum has announced that after two months of hashing priorities, it has a list of initial priority topics that will steer metaverse standards development in its domain working groups. The topics include both straightforward technical problems like augmented and virtual reality standards, as well as concerns around privacy, ethics, and user safety.</p><p class="pull-quote">“I like the theory that there’s only one metaverse, and you go between different experiences within the metaverse. Because we need an analogy to the Web.”<br/>—Neil Trevett, Metaverse Standards Forum</p><p>To be clear: The metaverse does not exist yet, and probably won’t for some years to come. But there’s enough industry interest in beginning the process toward building it—whatever it may ultimately be. So <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/neil-trevett-748791" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Neil Trevett</a>, the chair of the Metaverse Standards Forum, says now is the time to start standardizing. “I think what we’re seeing, much to everyone’s surprise—including our own—is the level of interest in standards for the metaverse. I think there is a thirst, or hunger, for them.”</p><p>The Metaverse Standards Forum is being organized by the <a href="https://www.khronos.org/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Khronos Group</a>, a software consortium developing royalty-free standards around technologies like virtual reality, augmented reality, and vision processing. The forum began with just 35 founding members, but its roster has in two months already ballooned to 1,500.</p><h3>Standardizing the Standards</h3><p>The MSF isn’t a standards body, Trevett says, so much as it’s a liaison to improve coordination and trust between the big commercial metaverse interests to date—including Google, Meta, Microsoft, and others using the technologies required for the creation, care, and maintenance of virtual worlds—as well as the standards organizations that will define those technologies. </p><p>“What we’re doing is casting a wide net, because some of the companies and organizations in the forum know each other, but there are lots of people that don’t know each other at all,” says Trevett. Trevett is also president of the Khronos Group.</p><p>Although there are numerous competing visions of what the metaverse will be, many such visions have common points of connection. <a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/the-metaverse-could-help-us-better-understand-reality" target="_self">Virtual reality</a> (VR) and <a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/metaverse-niantic-augmented-reality" target="_self">augmented reality</a> (AR) tech will probably be involved. As will the drive toward shared experiences—whether that’s something exciting like <a href="https://www.hollywoodreporter.com/business/digital/iheartmedia-iheartland-fortnite-1235204209/" target="_blank">attending a concert</a> or more mundane like renewing your drivers license.</p><p>“I like the theory that there’s only one metaverse and you go between different experiences within the metaverse, because we need an analogy to the Web,” says Trevett.</p><p>“It’s going to be an evolution of the Internet as we know it today,” says <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/david-morin" target="_blank">David Morin</a>, the executive director of the <a href="https://www.aswf.io/" target="_blank">Academy Software Foundation</a>, an organization working to standardize the visual-effects technologies pioneered by the movie industry. Morin says one way to envision that evolution is as a collection of situations to experience—a virtual Amazon storefront in which to browse products, rather than a flat Webpage—with the option to move between one situation and another. The idea isn’t entirely novel, he adds: "Many of these thoughts and experiments already exist in some corner of an industry or another.”</p><p>“I think most people have in mind something like the web,” says <a href="https://fr.linkedin.com/in/dominiquehazaelmassieux/fr" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Dominque Hazael-Massieux</a>, part of the management team for the <a href="https://www.w3.org/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">World Wide Web Consortium</a> standards body. ”You go to one place and another, and it just works, and you can keep some of the data you have from one place to another.”</p><h3>Making the Virtual a Reality</h3><p>So how will the metaverse <a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/is-the-metaverse-even-feasible" target="_blank">feasibly be realized</a>?<br/></p><p>Some see it as a future iteration of (or replacement for) the Internet. But if so, the technologies that make it happen will need to be  more tightly integrated than they are now. Beyond standardizing just AR and VR come related technologies like 3D modeling, volumetric video, and geospatial data.</p><p>According to <strong></strong>Trevett, the Metaverse Standards Forum’s first meetings—held via Zoom—yielded a Google spreadsheet that spelled out the forum’s priority topics, enabling members to garner support for their own preferences.</p><p> “We’re seeing a number of domains emerging,” says Trevett. “At the highest level, there’s spatial computing—which is all the 3D stuff and 3D assets—avatars and apparel, geospatial, [extended reality], and user interface.”<strong> </strong>Trevett points to additional interest in user identity, privacy, ethics, openness, and accessibility concerns.</p><p><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/nadinealameh" target="_blank">Nadine Alameh</a>, the CEO of the <a href="https://www.ogc.org/" target="_blank">Open Geospatial Consortium</a>, which is developing geospatial and location data standards, says part of the forum’s appeal is that, beyond the nuts and bolts of technical standards, there simply hasn’t been a centralized place to talk about the vision and implications of the technology. “Because some of these conversations that are happening are not about standards at all,” she says. “But people don’t have another forum to talk about the vision of the metaverse.”</p><p>In all, members proposed more than 200 potential topics to prioritize for metaverse development. That list <a href="https://metaverse-standards.org/news/blog/setting-course-for-an-open-metaverse-part-1-updates-from-the-first-60-days-of-the-metaverse-standards-forum/" target="_blank">has been narrowed down to eight areas of interest</a>, which will form the first domain working groups for the forum’s members to join. The list includes more technical challenges, such as interoperable 3D assets, user identity, augmented and virtual reality, and user interfaces. Broader challenges are also highlighted, including metaverse ethics, privacy and governance, and education and certification. </p><p>Trevett calls the forum’s approach “Darwinian.” It’s focusing for now on foundational matters like technical standards. Then, how it functions and is used will remain up to member companies like Amazon, Google, Meta, Microsoft, and others. </p><p>Many of the forum members that <em>IEEE Spectrum</em> spoke with felt strongly about the problem of metaverse openness. Open standards—as opposed to proprietary ones—make a shared foundation with increased interoperability more likely. By analogy, think of the Worldwide Web’s <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hypertext_Transfer_Protocol" target="_blank">HTTP protocol</a>. Were it a closed or proprietary standard, multiple “webs” would likely have cropped up with varying user bases as well as technological standards. And whatever the proprietary “Web” would have ultimately become, it’d also likely have taken much longer to develop and blossom, if it ever would have blossomed at all.</p><p>As a second analogy, the wireless industry began working on 6G cellular standards in 2019. But 6G likely <a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/6g-geopolitics" target="_self">won’t come to fruition until 2030</a>. Building the metaverse will be a multiyear effort, if not a generational one. “We’re just doing the building blocks,” says Alameh. “It’s really our kids who will actually build whatever that is. We’re just enabling, and I think that’s why you need to inject the ethics and the responsibility, because you’re building something new.”</p>]]></description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Aug 2022 20:07:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spectrum.ieee.org/metaverse-standards-forum</guid><category>Metaverse</category><category>Standards</category><category>Internet</category><category>Virtual reality</category><category>Augmented reality</category><dc:creator>Michael Koziol</dc:creator><media:content medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/a-diverse-group-of-people-meeting-in-a-conference-room-in-the-metaverse.jpg?id=31247491&amp;width=980"></media:content></item><item><title>Streetlight Wi-Fi Hotspots: A Bright Idea</title><link>https://spectrum.ieee.org/wi-fi</link><description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/streetlights-seen-against-a-colorful-sky.jpg?id=31291888&width=1245&height=700&coordinates=0%2C177%2C0%2C177"/><br/><br/><p>Wi-Fi deployed via streetlights—the vision of an international consortium founded by Intel, Facebook, Nokia and others—may one day help augment wireless access throughout cities. However, much remains unknown about the most apt placement for these access points. Now a novel algorithm could help telecommunications companies discover how to best install this infrastructure, a new study finds.<br/></p><p>The international <a href="https://telecominfraproject.com/faq/" target="_blank">Telecom Infra Project</a> envisions making public Wi-Fi available via the 60-gigahertz frequency band (ranging from 57 to 73 GHz) by <a href="https://telecominfraproject.com/tip-playbook-for-smart-cities/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">installing access points on light poles</a>. This band is unlicensed, and the<a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/qualcomm-introduces-new-chipsets-for-60-ghz-wifi" target="_self"> IEEE 802.11ay</a> standard for 60-GHz Wi-Fi released in 2021 supports up to 8.64 GHz of bandwidth.</p><p>A challenge that comes along with using 60-GHz signals is that oxygen absorption exacerbates attenuation, thus limiting their range. If wireless links using these frequencies are relatively short—less than 100 meters—they may still prove useful in dense urban areas. However, much remains unknown about the best way to use such transmissions in cities, such as the ideal height for access points to avoid obstructions that might scatter these signals.</p><p>In the new study, researchers at the National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST) in Gaithersburg, Md., developed a model for tracking 60-GHz signals that accounted for wide variances in light poles’ height. It uses a new algorithm for analyzing transmission paths that goes beyond usual parameters such as signal angles and delays to include receiver locations.</p><p>The scientists detailed <u><a href="https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/9765658" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">their findings</a></u> in a paper published in the August issue of <em>IEEE Antennas and Wireless Propagation Letters</em>.</p><p>The scientists tested their model in downtown Boulder, Colo., with a stationary transmitter mounted on a mast and a mobile receiver on the roof of a van. They measured signals at 4-, 6-, and 9-meter antenna heights, reflecting the ways in which light-pole heights can vary within and between cities.</p><p>The researchers found that their model predicted real-world measurements very well, with an accuracy comparable to that of more complicated methods. In general, the scientists found that the optimal height for Wi-Fi signals depended on the transmission frequency and antenna design. Attaching equipment at lower heights (about 4 meters above street level) proved better for traditional wireless systems with omnidirectional antennas, whereas higher locations 6 or 9 meters up were better for the latest systems such as 5G that use higher, millimeter-wave frequencies and narrow-beam antennas.</p><p class="shortcode-media shortcode-media-rebelmouse-image">
<img alt="A person in a safety vest stands on a platform looking at a large mast in a parking lot." class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="28189c97d3b0925a5c9b4ead176588dc" data-rm-shortcode-name="rebelmouse-image" id="9258b" loading="lazy" src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/a-person-in-a-safety-vest-stands-on-a-platform-looking-at-a-large-mast-in-a-parking-lot.jpg?id=31291889&width=980"/>
<small class="image-media media-caption" placeholder="Add Photo Caption...">The NIST team works to verify their channel model for evaluating high-frequency wireless-network designs in Boulder, Colo. Researcher Sung Yun Jun checks the alignment of the transmitter, mounted 6 meters high on a mast, with the receiver antenna array on the roof of the blue van. </small><small class="image-media media-photo-credit" placeholder="Add Photo Credit...">NIST</small></p><p>The scientists focused on how transmitted power spread over space at different heights.<br/></p><p>“At lower heights, there are more random obstacles—trees, vehicles, and so on—which impede propagation. As a result, the power is less spread out,” says  Jelena Senic, an electrical engineer at NIST who was a coauthor of the paper detailing the study. “At higher heights, the power is less inhibited—it can bounce around off the buildings multiple times before losing strength, hence the power is more spread out.”</p><p>Senic notes that 5G and 6G wireless-communication systems “will employ antennas with very narrow beamwidths—on the order of a few degrees—and so are often referred to as pencil beams. (They have high <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gain_(antenna)" target="_blank">antenna gain</a> to compensate for the greater <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Path_loss" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">path loss</a> experienced at <a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/the-anatomy-of-mmwave-communications-prototype-for-5g-testing" target="_self">millimeter wave</a> frequencies.) Having the power spread out in space is good for these systems, because they can steer the pencil beams in multiple directions through spatial <a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/neural-network-multiplex?share_id=6966369" target="_self">multiplexing</a>, with each position providing a separate channel, to increase the combined bit rate over the channels. So higher heights are definitely more advantageous, making lampposts an adequate solution.”</p><p>The researchers also conducted these tests on the NIST campus with comparable results. This suggests this model may generalize to different environments, such as residential areas.</p><p>These findings suggest that cell providers can implement next-generation 5G and 6G systems at low cost, “since lampposts are present everywhere in urban environments,” Senic says. At the same time, customers can expect a variety of new applications such as ultrahigh-definition video streaming and virtual reality, which become possible with multigigabit-per-second data rates and low latency,  she says. “In addition, 60 GHz provides a 14-GHz superwide bandwidth in the unlicensed band,” she adds.</p><p>Jenic cautions that customers “shouldn’t expect Wi-Fi access from lampposts everywhere.” The first targets for this service are likely <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Urban_canyon" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">urban canyons</a>, “because there the wireless demand is high due to the density of the population.”</p>]]></description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Aug 2022 18:12:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spectrum.ieee.org/wi-fi</guid><category>Streetlights</category><category>Mmwave</category><category>6g</category><category>5g</category><category>Nist</category><category>Telecommunications</category><category>60 ghz</category><category>Multiplexing</category><category>Wi-fi</category><category>Journal watch</category><dc:creator>Charles Q. Choi</dc:creator><media:content medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/streetlights-seen-against-a-colorful-sky.jpg?id=31291888&amp;width=980"></media:content></item><item><title>Component-level Modeling of an Antenna onto a Satellite</title><link>https://www.ansys.com/resource-center/webinar/component-level-modeling-of-an-antenna-onto-a-satellite</link><description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/image.png?id=26851525&width=980"/><br/><br/><p>The relationship between component and system-level modeling is significant for customers working in space applications and urban environments. This webinar will demonstrate a complete simulation workflow from the component-level modeling of an antenna to the system-level integration of the antenna onto a satellite.<u></u><u></u></p><p><a href="https://upl.inc/4719919" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Register now for this free webinar!</a></p><p>Digital mission support for a satellite in orbit uses the installed array to transmit signals to a receiver on Earth. Furthermore, an additional radar analysis is performed with STK with actual RCS data from an aircraft model with HFSS. Using STK, systems engineers develop workflows that seamlessly integrate the higher fidelity component models from its existing market-leading physics-based simulation tools like Ansys HFSS.<u></u><u></u></p><p>What you will learn:<u></u><u></u></p><ul><li>Build and analyze a communication link<u></u><u></u></li><li>Apply external antenna gain patterns files from HFSS<u></u><u></u></li><li>Generate a link budget<u></u><u></u></li><li>Use HFSS generated RCS files from an aircraft in STK<u></u><u></u></li><li>See model radar with STK (e.g., probability of detection)</li></ul>]]></description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Aug 2022 18:03:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.ansys.com/resource-center/webinar/component-level-modeling-of-an-antenna-onto-a-satellite</guid><category>Ansys</category><category>Antennas</category><category>Satellites</category><category>Simulation</category><category>Type:webinar</category><dc:creator>Ansys</dc:creator><media:content medium="image" type="image/png" url="https://assets.rbl.ms/26851525/origin.png"></media:content></item><item><title>Cutting-edge Analysis of EDGE Compute Nodes &amp; 5G</title><link>https://www.ansys.com/resource-center/webinar/cutting-edge-analysis-of-edge-compute-nodes-5g</link><description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/image.png?id=26851525&width=980"/><br/><br/><p>NEDGE systems enable 5G/6G network providers to move cloud access, data processing, and storage closer to the consumer. This reduces the signal latency to levels that allow technologies such as autonomous vehicle control, AR/VR applications, eVTOL, emergency communications, smart factory operation, smart cities, large IoT systems, and more.</p><p><a href="https://www.ansys.com/resource-center/webinar/cutting-edge-analysis-of-edge-compute-nodes-5g" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Register now for this free webinar!</a></p><p>In today's 5G systems, EDGE compute nodes are constructed with 5G NR mmWave and sub6 wireless connection capabilities built-in, with WiFi, Bluetooth, and GPS combined with a complex microserver.</p><p>The need for proximity makes designing EDGE nodes complex. Since many nodes are outside and must be weather sealed, you can't use airflow cooling systems. This webinar will show how you can use digital mission engineering software to model EDGE nodes in an extensive system and assess them for signal integrity, power integrity, thermal integrity, structural integrity, antenna systems, and large system deployment.</p>]]></description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Aug 2022 17:54:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.ansys.com/resource-center/webinar/cutting-edge-analysis-of-edge-compute-nodes-5g</guid><category>5g</category><category>Edge computing</category><category>Iot</category><category>Telecommunications</category><category>Type:webinar</category><category>Ansys</category><dc:creator>Ansys</dc:creator><media:content medium="image" type="image/png" url="https://assets.rbl.ms/26851525/origin.png"></media:content></item><item><title>As China’s Quantum-Encrypting Satellites Shrink, Their Networking Abilities Grow</title><link>https://spectrum.ieee.org/satellite-qkd-china</link><description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/a-conceptual-image-showing-a-ground-based-station-connecting-with-satellites.jpg?id=31214800&width=1245&height=700&coordinates=0%2C150%2C0%2C150"/><br/><br/><p>The orbiting Tiangong-2 space lab has transmitted quantum-encryption keys to four ground stations, researchers <a href="https://opg.optica.org/optica/fulltext.cfm?uri=optica-9-8-933&id=492969" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">reported on 18 August</a>. The same network of ground stations is also able to receive quantum keys from the orbiting Micius satellite, which is in a much higher orbit, using the space station as a repeater. It comes just after the late July launch of Jinan 1, China’s second quantum-encrypting satellite, by the University of Science and Technology of China. USTC told the <a href="https://news.satnews.com/2022/07/31/china-launches-new-satellite-in-important-step-towards-global-quantum-communications-network/" target="_blank">Xinhua News Agency</a> that the new satellite is one-sixth the mass of its 2016 predecessor. </p><p>“The launch is significant,” says physicist <a href="https://physics.illinois.edu/people/directory/profile/kwiat" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Paul Kwiat</a> of the University of Illinois in Urbana-Champaign, because it means the team are starting to build, not just plan, a quantum network. USTC researchers did not reply to <em>IEEE Spectrum’s</em> request for comments. </p><p>In quantum-key distribution (QKD), the quantum states of a single photon, such as polarization, encode and distribute random information that can be used to encrypt a classical message. Because it is impossible to copy the quantum state without changing it, senders and recipients can verify that their transmission got through without tampering or reading by third parties. In some scenarios it involves sending just one well-described photon at a time, but single photons are difficult to produce, and in this case, researchers used an attenuated laser to send small pulses that might also come out a couple of photons at a time, or not at all.</p><p>The USTC research team, led by Jian-Wei Pan, had already <a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/nature23655" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">established quantum-key distribution from Micius to a single ground station</a> in 2017, not long after the 2016 launch of the satellite. The work that Pan and colleagues reported this month, but which took place in 2018 and 2019, is a necessary step for building a constellation of quantum-encryption-compatible satellites across a range of orbits, to ensure more secure long-distance communications.</p><p>Several other research groups have <a href="https://www.optica-opn.org/home/articles/volume_29/february_2018/features/satellite-based_qkd/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">transmitted quantum keys</a>, and others are now building microsatellites for the same purpose. However, the U.S. National Security Agency’s site about QKD lists several technical limitations, such as requiring an initial verification of the counterparty’s identity, the need for special equipment, the cost, and the risk of hardware-based security vulnerabilities. In the absence of fixes, <a href="https://www.nsa.gov/Cybersecurity/Quantum-Key-Distribution-QKD-and-Quantum-Cryptography-QC/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">the NSA does not anticipate approving QKD for national security</a> communications.</p><p>However, attenuated laser pulses are just one way of implementing QKD. Another is to use quantum entanglement, by which a pair of photons will behave the same way, even at a distance, when someone measures one of their quantum properties. In earlier experiments, Pan and colleagues also reported <a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-020-2401-y" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">using quantum entanglement for QKD</a> and mixing satellite and fiber-optic links to establish a <a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-020-03093-8.epdf?sharing_token=1CW5z-80KWF4rgRGti-ZLNRgN0jAjWel9jnR3ZoTv0MNVpe6EvGQLTY7KE8U5lpv1AcqqXD5K2i3SN7zSU9K-dIX_fTfOWh3AkcjO3lLZZQSom5J0UumeoZfz1ZIXNNoNUSoEMYhZmfqWAO_FJy0sAa0ur09z2pHIX00xbdt4Y22R3sPuCz9nadZZORyizjpkFYizVoGYKpYleWnrNiIIG-n2Q-KiOo9HdosHMD_WoM%3D&tracking_referrer=spectrum.ieee.org" target="_blank">mixed-modality QKD network spanning almost 5,000 kilometers</a>. </p><p>“A quantum network with entangled nodes is the thing that would be really interesting, enabling distributed quantum computing and sensing, but  that’s a hard thing to make. Being able to do QKD is a necessary but not sufficient first step,” Kwiat says. The USTC experiments are a chance to establish many technical abilities, such as the precise control of the pulse duration and direction of the lasers involved, or the ability to accurately transfer and measure the quantum signals to the standard necessary for a more complex quantum network. </p><p>That is a step ahead of the many other QKD efforts made so far on laboratory benchtops, over ground-to-ground cables, or aboard balloons or aircraft. “You have to do things very differently if you’re not allowed to fiddle with something once it’s launched into space,” Kwiat says.</p><p>The U.S. CHIPS and Science Act of 2022, signed on 9 August, <a href="https://www.quantum.gov/quantum-in-the-chips-and-science-act-of-2022/" target="_blank">allocated more than US $153 million a year for quantum computing and networks</a>. While that’s unlikely to drive more American work toward an end goal of QKD, Kwiat says, “maybe we do it on the way to these more interesting applications.”</p>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2022 18:37:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spectrum.ieee.org/satellite-qkd-china</guid><category>Qkd</category><category>Satellites</category><category>Networking</category><category>Qkd</category><dc:creator>Lucas Laursen</dc:creator><media:content medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/a-conceptual-image-showing-a-ground-based-station-connecting-with-satellites.jpg?id=31214800&amp;width=980"></media:content></item><item><title>5G Networks Are Worryingly Hackable</title><link>https://spectrum.ieee.org/5g-virtualization-increased-hackability</link><description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/illustration-of-network-with-locks-around-it.jpg?id=31141770&width=1245&height=700&coordinates=0%2C187%2C0%2C188"/><br/><br/><p>Prominent tech firms like <a href="https://www.lightreading.com/service-provider-cloud/with-hacks-on-rise-microsoft-looks-to-secure-open-ran/d/d-id/779743" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Microsoft</a> and <a href="https://www.fiercewireless.com/tech/nec-exec-open-ran-moving-pretty-fast-compared-prior-tech-shifts" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">NEC</a> have recently expressed concerns over the security and perhaps too-rapid adoption, respectively, of critical 5G technologies. Now German security researchers have given some substance to the industry’s fears and unease.</p><p>At a hacker conference held in the Netherlands last month, <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=LRQsFTmWa2w" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Karsten Nohl</a>, founder of Berlin-based <a href="https://www.srlabs.de/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Security Research Labs</a>, outlined how his team had breached live 5G networks in a series of “red teaming” exercises—where hackers are hired by a company to test their defenses. In most cases they were able to take control of the network, he says, potentially allowing them to steal customer data or disrupt operations.</p><p>The hacks, <a href="https://media.ccc.de/v/mch2022-273-openran-5g-hacking-just-got-a-lot-more-interesting" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">revealed at the May Contain Hackers 2022 event (a.k.a. MCH2022</a>), were made possible thanks to poorly configured cloud technology, which is playing an increasingly important role in 5G networks. Nohl says many telcos are inexperienced in how to protect such systems, and his team found that operators had failed to apply basic cloud security techniques that could help mitigate hacks.</p><p class="pull-quote">The push toward Open RAN, virtualization, and “cloudifcation” unlocks more choice and functionality for 5G operators. It has also thrust them into the unfamiliar role of system integrator, suddenly responsible for securing the entire supply chain.</p><p>“5G has swept over telcos with all its implications, and nobody seems well prepared,” says Nohl. “We are introducing new technology into mobile networks, and those technologies can greatly enhance the security of our mobile networks. Or they can basically destroy any hacking resistance we’ve built up over the years. People are not aware of those choices.”</p><p>Mobile operators have traditionally relied on proprietary hardware from vendors like Ericsson, Nokia, and Huawei to build their networks. But in recent years, there has been a major push to “virtualize” network functions, which involves replicating key components in software so they can run on generic hardware, or even in the cloud. And the advent of 5G has only heightened the demand for virtualization, in particular when it comes to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Radio_access_network" target="_blank">radio access networks (RANs)</a>—the part of the network involved in connecting end-user devices like cellphones to the network core.</p><p>Virtualization has a host of benefits, including the ability to deploy networks faster and more cheaply, to quickly upgrade networks, and even to dynamically reconfigure them in response to changing situations on the ground. The decoupling of hardware and software also prevents <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Vendor_lock-in" target="_blank">vendor lock-in</a> and allows network operators to mix and match components from different companies, something advocated for by the <a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/the-cellular-industrys-clash-over-the-movement-to-remake-networks" target="_self">Open RAN movement</a>.</p><p>But these new capabilities are also making 5G networks more complex, says Nohl, which in turn necessitates the increasing use of automation to manage networks. And the ability to mix and match software and services from different companies means far more people are involved in the development pipeline. “The more stuff you have and the more moving parts, the more opportunities for mistakes, little misconfigurations,” says Nohl.</p><p>This makes it much easier to break into such virtualized networks than was previously possible. Among the entry points the team discovered included a backdoor-revealing API that had been posted publicly to the Internet as well as an old development site that had accidentally been left online. But the increased ease with which attackers can penetrate the networks is not in and of itself the main problem. “The really critical question is how difficult it is to break through from your initial foothold to something actually valuable within the network,” says Nohl.</p><p>His team found it was worryingly easy to move deeper into the networks they tested, thanks primarily to poorly configured “containers.” These are self-contained packages of software that bundle up an application and everything needed to run it—code, software libraries, and configuration files—so that it can be run on any hardware. Containers are a critical part of the cloud, because they allow different applications from different companies or departments to run alongside one another on the same servers. Containers are supposed to be isolated from one another, but if they are poorly configured it’s possible to break out and gain access to other containers or even to take control of the host system. In multiple instances Nohl and his team found misconfigured containers that allowed them to do just this.</p><p class="pull-quote">“I saw it many times when security teams were invited to the party when all is done and almost finished. The security guys have a very short time slot in order to fine-tune it—if they are actually allowed to touch it.”<br/>—Dmitry Kurbatov, SecurityGen</p><p>Some of the above difficulties could be attributed to the fact that telcos are inexperienced when it comes to cloud security, says Nohl. But they also may be taking shortcuts. Often operators are “lifting and shifting” preexisting software components into containers, Nohl said, but many of the settings designed to isolate containers from one another prevent the software from working as it should. Rather than rewriting code, developers often simply remove these protections, says Nohl. “Those shortcuts we see everywhere now,” he says.</p><p>“Network operators are having to move into a new operating model that’s significantly different than what they’ve done in the past,” says <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/erichanselman/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Eric Hanselman</a>, chief analyst at 451 Research. “The reality is that telcos have never had to deal with these levels of software development or low-level infrastructure management before. They always rely on their suppliers for this.”</p><p>While the shift toward Open RAN and the growing virtualization and “cloudifcation” of networks is unlocking more choice and functionality for operators, says Hanselman, it has also thrust them into the unfamiliar role of system integrator, responsible for securing the entire supply chain.</p><p><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/xcosta/" target="_blank">Xavier Costa Pérez</a>, head of 5G networks R&D at <a href="https://www.neclab.eu/" target="_blank">NEC Laboratories Europe</a>, disputes that operators are behind the curve when it comes to 5G security. While he admits that the transition to more virtualized networks entails inevitable risks, he says major players are investing heavily in security and partnering with cloud providers to tap into their security expertise. “I think the telco industry is very much aware that this can be a big issue,” he says. “It’s critical for survival, so I don’t think it’s taken lightly at all.”</p><p>It’s also important to remember that these kinds of highly virtualized networks still represent only a small portion of the 5G infrastructure today, probably less than 10 percent, says Costa Pérez. And all operators have backup 4G networks that they can switch to in the event of any problems.</p><p>Network operators aren’t complacent, says Ian Smith, security operations director at the industry body <a href="https://www.gsma.com/" target="_blank">GSMA</a>. “We know that maintaining security, especially for new network technologies, is an ongoing and evolving effort, and one to which the mobile industry is wholeheartedly committed.”</p><p>However, that hasn’t been the experience of <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/dmitry-kurbatov/?originalSubdomain=uk" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Dmitry Kurbatov</a>, cofounder of telecom security startup SecurityGen. He has found that security often appears to be an afterthought, rather than being part of the development process from the start. “I saw it many times when security teams were invited to the party when all is done and almost finished.” he says. “The security guys have a very short time slot in order to fine-tune it—if they are actually allowed to touch it.”</p><p>Nonetheless, he’s optimistic about the shift to 5G. Previously, operators had little option but to trust vendors when it came to security, but now they will be able to take matters into their own hands. “You actually can have full visibility and control over [5G] systems and functions, which means now you have the chance as the network owner to be much more secure,” he says.</p><p>And even more important, the industry isn’t alone in going through the transition to the cloud, says John Carse, chief information security officer at the Japanese operator <a href="https://corp.mobile.rakuten.co.jp/english/" target="_blank">Rakuten Mobile</a>, which has been a champion of Open RAN principles. “This is a good thing because it means telecom doesn’t have a special problem to solve,” he says. “Telecom can benefit from adoption of techniques happening in all the industries surrounding it versus trying to overcome proprietary challenges.”</p>]]></description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2022 20:09:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spectrum.ieee.org/5g-virtualization-increased-hackability</guid><category>Cybersecurity</category><category>Telecommunications</category><category>Open ran</category><category>5g</category><dc:creator>Edd Gent</dc:creator><media:content medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/illustration-of-network-with-locks-around-it.jpg?id=31141770&amp;width=980"></media:content></item><item><title>The Math Proves It—Network Congestion Is Inevitable</title><link>https://spectrum.ieee.org/internet-congestion-control</link><description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/stop-lights-amongst-a-dark-colorful-background.jpg?id=31093971&width=1245&height=700&coordinates=0%2C104%2C0%2C104"/><br/><br/><p><span style="background-color: initial;">Just as highway networks may suffer from snarls of traffic, so too may computer networks face congestion. Now a new study finds that many key algorithms designed to control these delays on computer networks may prove deeply unfair, letting some users hog all the bandwidth while others get essentially nothing.</span><br/></p><p>Computers and other devices that send data over the internet break it down into smaller <a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/simulating-networks" target="_self">packets</a> and then use special algorithms to decide how fast to send these packets. These congestion-control algorithms aim to discover and exploit all the available network capacity while sharing it with other users on the same network.</p><p>Over the past decade, researchers have developed several congestion-control algorithms that seek to achieve high rates of data transmission while minimizing the delays resulting from data waiting in queues in the network. Some of these, such as Google’s <a href="https://cloud.google.com/blog/products/networking/tcp-bbr-congestion-control-comes-to-gcp-your-internet-just-got-faster" target="_blank">BBR algorithm</a>, are now widely used by many websites and applications.</p><p class="pull-quote">“Extreme unfairness happens even when everybody cooperates, and it is nobody’s fault.”<br/>—Venkat Arun, MIT</p><p>However, although hundreds of congestion-control algorithms have been proposed in the last roughly 40 years, “there is no clear winner,” says study lead author <a href="https://people.csail.mit.edu/venkatar/" target="_blank">Venkat Arun</a>, a computer scientist at MIT. “I was frustrated by how little we knew about where these algorithms would and would not work. This motivated me to create a mathematical model that could make more systematic predictions.”</p><p>Unexpectedly, Arun and his colleagues now find many congestion-control algorithms may prove highly unfair. Their new study finds that given the real-world complexity of network paths, there will always be a scenario where a problem known as “starvation” cannot be avoided—where at least one sender on a network receives almost no bandwidth compared to that of other users.</p><p>A user’s computer does not know how fast to send data packets because it lacks knowledge about the network, such as how many other senders are on it or the quality of the connection. Sending packets too slowly makes poor use of the available bandwidth. However, sending packets too quickly may overwhelm a network, resulting in packets getting dropped. These packets then need to be sent again, resulting in delays. Delays may also result from packets waiting in queues for a long time.</p><p>Congestion-control algorithms rely on packet losses and delays as details to infer congestion and decide how fast to send data. However, packets can get lost and delayed for reasons other than network congestion. For example, data may be held up and then released in a burst with other packets, or a receiver’s acknowledgement that it received packets might get delayed. The researchers called delays that do not result from congestion “jitter.”</p><p>Congestion-control algorithms cannot distinguish the difference between delays caused by congestion and jitter. This can lead to problems, as delays caused by jitter are unpredictable. This ambiguity confuses senders, which can make each of them estimate delay differently and send packets at unequal rates. The researchers found this eventually leads to situations where starvation occurs and some users get shut out completely.</p><p>In the new study, the researchers analyzed whether every congestion-control algorithm of which they were aware, as well as some new ones they devised, could avoid starvation. The scientists were surprised to find there were always scenarios with each algorithm where some people got all the bandwidth, and at least one person got basically nothing.</p><p>“Some users could be experiencing very poor performance, and we didn’t know about it sooner,” Arun says. “Extreme unfairness happens even when everybody cooperates, and it is nobody’s fault.”</p><p>The researchers found that all existing congestion-control algorithms that seek to curb delays are what they call “delay-convergent algorithms” that will always suffer from starvation. The fact that this weakness in these widely used algorithms remained unknown for so long is likely due to how empirical testing alone “could attribute poor performance to insufficient network capacity rather than poor algorithmic decision-making,” Arun says.</p><p>Although existing approaches toward congestion control may not be able to avoid starvation, the aim now is to develop a new strategy that does, Arun says. “Better algorithms can enable predictable performance at a reduced cost,” he says.</p><p>Arun notes that this research may have applications beyond analyzing network congestion. “We are currently using our method of modeling computer systems to reason about other algorithms that allocate resources in computer systems,” he says. “The goal is to help build systems with predictable performance, which is important since we rely on computers for increasingly critical things. For instance, lives could depend on self-driving cars making timely decisions.”</p><p>The scientists will detail <u><a href="http://people.csail.mit.edu/venkatar/cc-starvation.pdf" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">their findings</a></u> 24 August at the ACM Special Interest Group on Data Communications (<u><a href="https://conferences.sigcomm.org/sigcomm/2022/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">SIGCOMM</a></u>) conference.</p>]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Aug 2022 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spectrum.ieee.org/internet-congestion-control</guid><category>Algorithms</category><category>Packet switching</category><category>Networks</category><category>Google</category><category>Congestion</category><category>Network traffic</category><dc:creator>Charles Q. Choi</dc:creator><media:content medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/stop-lights-amongst-a-dark-colorful-background.jpg?id=31093971&amp;width=980"></media:content></item><item><title>Space 5G Is On the Launchpad</title><link>https://spectrum.ieee.org/5g-satellite</link><description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/a-chamber-with-a-gold-apparatus-with-many-structures-coming-off-it.jpg?id=30991831&width=1245&height=700&coordinates=0%2C326%2C0%2C327"/><br/><br/><p>The next generation of cellphone networks won’t just be 5G or 6G—they will be zero <em>g</em>. In April, <a href="https://lynk.world/lynk-announces-successful-deployment-of-worlds-first-commercial-ready-cell-tower-in-space" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Lynk Global launched the first direct-to-mobile commercial satellite</a>, and on 15 August a competitor, AST SpaceMobile, <a href="https://ast-science.com/2022/08/03/ast-spacemobile-to-provide-quarterly-business-update/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">confirmed plans to launch</a> an experimental direct-to-mobile satellite of its own in mid-September. Inmarsat and <a href="https://www.qualcomm.com/news/releases/2022/07/ericsson--qualcomm-and-thales-to-take-5g-into-space?mkt_tok=Mzg1LVRXUy04MDMAAAGFixVm3yjIiJQD4N11E1p1c7Znm0qMzA2ISDZYLC7tBdq9LFmz_vMMNDO2RNpu-tnbiIat6mzlM0wMmdFA-duWoOvoMqYswlpvlYgLo5xC6nwxug" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">other companies</a> are <a href="https://www.fiercewireless.com/5g/inmarsat-combines-satellite-and-5g-for-new-type-network" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">working on their own low Earth orbit (LEO) cellular solutions</a> as launch prices drop, satellite fabrication methods improve, and telecoms engineers push new network capabilities.</p><p>LEO satellite systems such as SpaceX’s <a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/spacex-starlink-dish-network" target="_self">Starlink</a> and Amazon’s <a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/amazons-project-kuiper-is-more-than-the-companys-response-to-spacex" target="_self">Kuiper</a> envision huge constellations of satellites. However, the U.S. Federal Communications Commission just rejected SpaceX’s application for some of the US $9 billion federal rural broadband fund—in part because the Starlink system requires a $600 ground station. Space-based cell service would not require special equipment, making it <a href="https://www.fiercewireless.com/tech/industry-voices-rysavy-solving-wireless-riddle-for-rural-broadband" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">a potential candidate for rural broadband funds</a> if companies can develop solutions to the many challenges that face satellite-based smartphone service.</p><p>“The main challenge is the link budget,” says electrical engineer <a href="https://sites.google.com/view/symeonchatzinotas" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Symeon Chatzinotas</a> of the University of Luxembourg, referring to the amount of power required to transmit and receive data between satellites and connected devices. “Sending signals to smartphones outdoors could be feasible by using low Earth orbit satellites with sizable antennas in the sky. However, receiving info would be even more challenging since the smartphone antennas usually disperse their energy in all directions.” </p><p class="pull-quote">“Network architectures are diverging. On the one hand, small cells are replacing Wi-Fi. On the other hand [telecom operators] are going to satellite-based systems with very wide coverage.”<br/>—Derek Long, Cambridge Consultants</p><p>The typical distance from a phone to an LEO satellite might be 500 kilometers, at least two orders of magnitude more than typical signal-transmission distances in urban settings, so the dispersion of the phone’s power would be at least eight times greater, and would be further complicated by the phone’s orientation. It is unlikely that a satellite-smartphone connection would work well when the handset is inside a building, for example.</p><p>Lynk Global’s initial offering, which it predicts will be available in late 2022, is narrowband—meaning limited voice calls, texting, and Internet of Things (IoT) traffic. That might not allow plutocrats to make 4K video calls from their ocean-faring yachts, but it would be enough for ship insurance companies or rescue services to remain in contact with vessels in places where they couldn’t be reached before, using off-the-shelf cellular devices. AST SpaceMobile’s is aiming for 4G and 5G broadband service for mobiles.</p><p>AST satellites will use a phased-array antenna, which consists of many antennas fanned out around the satellite. Each portion of the antenna will transmit within a well-defined cone terminating at the Earth’s surface; that will be the space-to-Earth equivalent of a cell originating from a single ground base station. The company plans for an initial fleet of 20 satellites to cover the equator and help fund the launch of subsequent satellites providing more global coverage.</p><p>The size of the coverage zone on the ground should exceed the limited size of those created by <a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/why-did-alphabets-loon-fail-to-bring-internet-to-the-world" target="_self">Alphabet’s failed balloon-based Project Loon</a>. Broader coverage areas should allow AST to serve more potential customers with the same number of antennas. The low Earth orbit AST is experimenting with yields round-trip signal travel times of around 25 milliseconds or less, an order of magnitude faster than is the case for higher-orbit geostationary satellites that have provided satellite telephony until now.</p><p>Plenty of behind-the-scenes technical work remains. The relatively high speed of LEO satellites will also <a href="https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/9658559" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">cause a Doppler shift in the signals for which the network will have to compensate</a>, according to a recent review in <em>IEEE Access</em>. New protocols for handoffs between satellites and terrestrial towers will also have to be created so that an active call can be carried from one cell to the next.</p><p>The international telecoms standards group <a href="https://www.ericsson.com/en/reports-and-papers/ericsson-technology-review/articles/5g-evolution-toward-5g-advanced" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">3GPP began providing guidelines for so-called nonterrestrial networks</a> in March in the 17th iteration of its cellular standards. “Nonterrestrial networks” refers not just to LEO satellites but also high-altitude platforms such as drones or balloons. Nonterrestrial networks will need further updates to 3GPP’s standards to accommodate their new network architecture, such as the longer distances between cell base stations and devices. </p><p>For example, <a href="https://www.stratosphericplatforms.com/news/world-first-5g-transmission/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Stratospheric Platforms</a> earlier this year tested a drone-based network prototype that would fly at altitudes greater than 18,000 meters. Its behavior as part of a 5G network will differ from that of a Lynk Global or AST satellite.</p><p>“Network architectures are diverging. On the one hand, small cells are replacing Wi-Fi. On the other hand [telecom operators] are going to satellite-based systems with very wide coverage. In the middle, traditional macrocells, which are kind of difficult economically, are being squeezed,” says <a href="https://uk.linkedin.com/in/derek-long-65a2b4" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Derek Long, head of telecommunications at Cambridge Consultants</a>. The company has advised Stratospheric Platforms and other companies working on nonterrestrial networks.</p><p>If telecom operators succeed, users won’t even notice their space-age smartphone networks. </p><p>“When you buy a phone, you expect it to work. Not just where someone says it will work, but everywhere. This is a step toward making that a possibility,” Long says. </p>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Aug 2022 17:53:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spectrum.ieee.org/5g-satellite</guid><category>Satellites</category><category>Spacex</category><category>Kuiper</category><category>Telecommunications</category><category>Cellphones</category><dc:creator>Lucas Laursen</dc:creator><media:content medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/a-chamber-with-a-gold-apparatus-with-many-structures-coming-off-it.jpg?id=30991831&amp;width=980"></media:content></item><item><title>The Fall and Rise of Russian Electronic Warfare</title><link>https://spectrum.ieee.org/the-fall-and-rise-of-russian-electronic-warfare</link><description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/side-profile-of-a-russian-krasukha-4-military-vehicle.jpg?id=30142963&width=1245&height=700&coordinates=0%2C281%2C0%2C281"/><br/><br/><p>
<strong>A month into Russia’s invasion,</strong> Ukrainian troops stumbled upon a nondescript shipping <a href="https://www.thedrive.com/the-war-zone/44879/ukraine-just-captured-part-of-one-of-russias-most-capable-electronic-warfare-systems" target="_blank">container</a> at an abandoned Russian command post outside Kyiv. They did not know it then, but the branch-covered box left by retreating Russian soldiers was possibly the biggest intelligence coup of the young war.
</p><p>
	Inside were the guts of one of Russia’s most sophisticated electronic warfare (EW) systems, the 
	<a href="https://www.armyrecognition.com/russia_russian_military_field_equipment/krasukha-4_1rl257_broadband_multifunctional_jamming_station_electronic_warfare_system_technical_data_sheet_pictures_video_10610156.html" target="_blank">Krasukha-4</a>. First fielded in 2014, the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Krasukha_(electronic_warfare_system)" target="_blank">Krasukha-4</a> is a centerpiece of Russia’s strategic EW complement. Designed primarily to jam airborne or satellite-based fire control radars in the <a href="https://www.microwaves101.com/encyclopedias/frequency-letter-bands" target="_blank">X- and K<sub>u</sub>-bands</a>, the Krasukha-4 Is often used <a href="https://defence.nridigital.com/global_defence_technology_mar22/russia_electronic_warfare" target="_blank">alongside</a> the Krasukha-2, which targets lower-frequency S-band search radars. Such radars are used on stalwart U.S. reconnaissance platforms, such as the E-8 Joint Surveillance Target Attack Radar System (<a href="https://www.af.mil/About-Us/Fact-Sheets/Display/Article/104507/e-8c-joint-stars/" target="_blank">JSTARS</a>) and Airborne Warning and Control System, or <a href="https://www.af.mil/About-Us/Fact-Sheets/Display/Article/104504/e-3-sentry-awacs/" target="_blank">AWACS</a>, aircraft.
</p><p>
	And now Ukraine, including by extension its intelligence partners in NATO, had a Krasukha-4 to dissect and analyze.
</p><p>
	That Russian troops would ditch the heart of such a valuable EW system was surprising in March, when Moscow was still making gains across the country and threatening Kyiv. Five months into the war, it is now apparent that Russia’s initial advance was already faltering when the Krasukha-4 was left by the roadside. With highways around Kyiv clogged by armored columns, 
	<a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/national-security/2022/04/06/pentagon-russia-withdraws-kyiv-chernihiv/" target="_blank">withdrawing</a> units needed to lighten their load.
</p><p>
	The abandoned Krasukha-4 was emblematic of the puzzling failure of Russian EW in the first few months of Russia’s invasion. After nearly a decade of owning the airwaves during a Moscow-backed insurgency in eastern Ukraine, EW was 
	<a href="https://www.thedrive.com/the-war-zone/this-is-whats-happened-so-far-in-ukraines-electronic-warfare-battle" target="_blank">not decisive</a> when Russia went to war in February. The key questions now are, why was this so, what is next for Russian EW in this oddly anachronistic war, and how might it affect the outcome?
</p><p class="pull-quote">
	At least three of Russia’s five electronic warfare brigades are engaged in Ukraine. And with more exposure to NATO-supplied radios, experienced Russian EW operators who cut their teeth in Syria are beginning to detect and degrade Ukrainian communications.
</p><p>
<strong>Electronic warfare is a pivotal</strong> if invisible part of modern warfare. Military forces rely on radios, radars, and infrared detectors to coordinate operations and find the enemy. They use EW to control the spectrum, protecting their own sensing and communications while denying access to the electromagnetic spectrum by enemy troops.
</p><p>
	U.S. military doctrine defines EW as comprising electronic attack (EA), electronic protection, and electronic support. The most familiar of these is EA, which includes jamming, where a transmitter overpowers or disrupts the waveform of a hostile radar or radio. For instance, the Russian 
	<a href="https://odin.tradoc.army.mil/mediawiki/index.php/R-330Zh_Zhitel_Russian_Cellular_Jamming_and_Direction_Finding_System" target="_blank">R-330Zh Zhitel</a> jammer can reportedly shut down—within a radius of tens of kilometers—GPS, satellite communications, and cellphone networks in the VHF and UHF bands. Deception is also part of EA, in which a system substitutes its own signal for an expected radar or radio transmission. For example, Russian forces sent propaganda and fake orders to troops and civilians during the 2014–2022 insurgency in eastern Ukraine by hijacking the local cellular network with the RB-341V <a href="https://odin.tradoc.army.mil/mediawiki/index.php?title=Leer-3_Russian_6x6_Mobile_Drone-Based_Electronic_Warfare_(EW)_System&printable=yes" target="_blank">Leer-3</a> system. Using soldier-portable Orlan-10 drones managed by a truck-mounted control system, the Leer-3 can extend its range and impact VHF and UHF communications over wider areas.
</p><p class="shortcode-media shortcode-media-rebelmouse-image">
<img alt="Three Russian soldiers climb on a wheeled vehicle supporting an antenna." class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="a97e7019b43b7732d50ae3c073b58bb1" data-rm-shortcode-name="rebelmouse-image" id="ad623" loading="lazy" src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/three-russian-soldiers-climb-on-a-wheeled-vehicle-supporting-an-antenna.png?id=30296258&width=980"/>
<small class="image-media media-caption" placeholder="Add Photo Caption...">The Zhitel jamming system can shut down, over tens of kilometers, GPS and satellite communications. This image shows the base of one of the four antennas in a typical setup.</small><small class="image-media media-photo-credit" placeholder="Add Photo Credit...">informnapalm.org</small>
</p><p>
	The converse of electronic attack is electronic support (ES), which is used to passively 
	<a href="https://www.thedrive.com/the-war-zone/33401/this-is-what-ground-forces-look-like-to-an-electronic-warfare-system-and-why-its-a-big-deal" target="_blank">detect and analyze</a> an opponent’s transmissions. ES is essential for understanding the potential vulnerabilities of an adversary’s radars or radios. Therefore, most Russian EA systems include ES capabilities that allow them to find and quickly characterize potential jamming targets. Using their ES capabilities, most EA systems can also geolocate enemy radio and cellphone transmissions and then pass that information on so that it can be used to direct artillery or rocket fire—with often <a href="https://www.thedrive.com/the-war-zone/30741/ukrainian-officer-details-russian-electronic-warfare-tactics-including-radio-virus" target="_blank">devastating</a> effects.
</p><p>
	A few Russian systems conduct ES exclusively; one example is the 
	<a href="https://odin.tradoc.army.mil/mediawiki/index.php?title=Moskva-1_(1L265)_Russian_Electronic_Warfare_Vehicle&printable=yes" target="_blank">Moskva-1</a>, which is a precision HF/VHF receiver that can use the reflections of TV and radio signals to conduct <a href="https://dsiac.org/articles/passive-coherent-location-radar-the-silent-threat/" target="_blank">passive coherent location</a> or passive radar operations. Basically, the system picks up the radio waves of commercial TV and radio transmitters in an area, which will reflect off targets like ships or aircraft. By triangulating among multiple sets of received waves, the target can be pinpointed with sufficient accuracy to track it and, if needed, shoot at it.
</p><h2>Key Russian Electronic Warfare Systems Deployed in Ukraine </h2><table border="0" style="white-space: unset;" width="100%">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td scope="col" width="25%">
<p>
Electronic Warfare System
		</p>
</td>
<td scope="col" width="25%">
<p>
Purpose
		</p>
</td>
<td scope="col" width="25%">
<p>
First Fielded
		</p>
</td>
<td scope="col" width="25%">
<p>
Notes
		</p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>
		1RL257 Krasukha-4
	</td>
<td>
		Targets X-band and K
		<sub>u</sub>-band radars, particularly on planes, drones, missiles, and low-orbit satellites
	</td>
<td>
		2014
	</td>
<td>
		Consists of two KamAZ-6350 trucks, one a command post and the other outfitted with sensors
	</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>
		1L269 Krasukha-2
	</td>
<td>
		Targets S-band radars, particularly on airborne platforms. Often used paired with the Krasukha-4
	</td>
<td>
		2011
	</td>
<td>
		Also based on two KamAZ-6350 trucks
	</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>
		RB-341V Leer-3
	</td>
<td>
		Disrupts VHF and UHF communications, including cellular communications and military radios, over hundreds of kilometers
	</td>
<td>
		2015
	</td>
<td>
		Consists of a truck-based command post that works with Orlan-10 drones to extend its range
	</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>
		RH-330Zh Zhitel
	</td>
<td>
		Jammer; can shut down GPS and satellite communications over a radius of tens of kilometers
	</td>
<td>
		2011
	</td>
<td>
		Consists of a truck command post and four telescopic-mast phased-array antennas
	</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>
		Murmansk-BN
	</td>
<td>
		Long-range detection and jamming of HF military radios
	</td>
<td>
		2020
	</td>
<td>
		Russian sources claim it can jam communications thousands of kilometers away
	</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>
		R-934B
	</td>
<td>
		VHF/UHF jammer that targets wireless and wired communications
	</td>
<td>
		1996
	</td>
<td>
		Consists of either a truck or a tracked vehicle and a towed 16-kilowatt generator
	</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>
		SPN-2, 3, 4
	</td>
<td>
		X- or K
		<sub>u</sub>-band jammers that target airborne radars and air-to-surface guidance-control radars
	</td>
<td>
		(not available)
	</td>
<td>
		Consists of a combat-control vehicle and an antenna vehicle
	</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>
		Repellent-1
	</td>
<td>
		Antidrone system
	</td>
<td>
		2016
	</td>
<td>
		Weighs more than 20 tonnes
	</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>
		Moéskva-1
	</td>
<td>
		Precision HF/VHF receiver for passive coherent location of enemy ships and planes
	</td>
<td>
		2015
	</td>
<td>
		Published sources cite a range of up to 400 kilometers
	</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td colspan="4">
		Sources: Wikipedia; Military Factory; 
		<u>Global Defence Technology</u>; U.S. Army; <u>Air Power Australia</u>; U.S. Army Training and Doctrine Command; <i>Russian Electronic Warfare: The Role of Electronic Warfare in the Russian Armed Forces</i>, Jonas Kjellén, Swedish Defence Research Agency (FOI), 2018; <u>Defence24</u>
</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table><p>
	Russia uses specialized electronic-warfare units to conduct its EA and ES operations. In its 
	<a href="https://icds.ee/wp-content/uploads/2018/ICDS_Report_Russias_Electronic_Warfare_to_2025.pdf" target="_blank">ground forces</a>, dedicated EW brigades of several hundred soldiers are assigned to the five Russian military districts—West, South, North, Central, and East—to support regional EW operations that include disrupting enemy surveillance radars and satellite communication networks over hundreds of kilometers. EW brigades are equipped with the larger Krasukha-2 and -4, Leer-3, Moskva-1, and Murmansk-BN systems (the latter of which detects and jams HF radios). Each Russian army maneuver brigade also includes an EW company of about 100 personnel that is trained to support local actions within about 50 kilometers using smaller systems, like the R-330Zh Zhitel.
</p><p>
<span style="background-color: initial;">Militaries use electronic protection (EP), also known as electronic countermeasures, to defend against EA and ES. Long considered an afterthought by western forces after the Cold War, EP has risen again to be perhaps the most important aspect of EW as Russia and China field increasingly sophisticated jammers and sensors. EP includes tactics and technologies to shield radio transmissions from being detected or jammed. Typical techniques include using narrow beams or low</span><span style="background-color: initial;">-</span><span style="background-color: initial;">power transmissions, as well as advanced waveforms that are resistant to jamming.</span>
</p><p>
<a href="https://www.foi.se/en/foi/reports/report-summary.html?reportNo=FOI-R--4625--SE" target="_blank">Experts</a> have long touted Russia as having some of the most experienced and best-equipped EW units in the world. So in the early days of the 24 February invasion, analysts expected Russian forces to quickly gain control of, and then dominate, the electromagnetic spectrum. Since the annexation of Crimea in 2014, EW has been a key part of Russian operations in the “<a href="https://www.atlanticcouncil.org/blogs/new-atlanticist/todays-wars-are-fought-in-the-gray-zone-heres-everything-you-need-to-know-about-it/" target="_blank">gray zone</a>,” the shadowy realm between peace and war, in the Donbas region. Using Leer-3 EW vehicles and Orlan-10 drones, Moscow-backed separatists and mercenaries would jam Ukrainian communications and send propaganda over local mobile-phone networks. When Russian forces were ready to strike, the ground and airborne systems would detect Ukrainian radios and target them with rocket attacks.
</p><p>
	But after nearly a decade of rehearsals in eastern Ukraine, when 
	<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/2022_Russian_invasion_of_Ukraine#:~:text=On%2024%20February%202022%2C%20Russia,third%20of%20the%20population%20displaced." target="_blank">the latest escalation and invasion began in February</a>, Russian EW was a no-show. Ukrainian defenders did not experience the jamming they faced in the Donbas and were not being targeted by drones or ground-based electronic surveillance. Although Russian forces did blow up some broadcast radio and television towers, Ukraine’s leaders continued to reach the outside world unimpeded by Russian EW.
</p><p class="pull-quote">
	Using counter-drone systems provided by the United States before the invasion, Ukrainian troops have downed hundreds of Russian drones by jamming their GPS signals or possibly by damaging their electronics with high-powered microwave beams.
</p><p>
	Russia is 
	<a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/national-security/2022/06/13/severodonetsk-donbas-russian-advance/" target="_blank">gaining</a> the upper hand now, having consolidated control in Ukraine's east and south as the invaded country begins running out of soldiers, weapons, and time. With more defined front lines and better logistics support from their homeland, Russian troops are now <a href="https://apnews.com/article/russia-ukraine-kyiv-technology-90d760f01105b9aaf1886427dbfba917" target="_blank">using</a> their EW systems to guide artillery and rocket strikes. But instead of being the leading edge of Russia’s offensive, EW is coming into play only after Moscow resorted to siege tactics that call to mind the origins of EW in World War I.
</p><p>
	The RF spectrum was a lot less busy then. Commanders used their new radios to coordinate troop movements and direct fire and employed early passive direction-finding equipment to locate or listen to enemy radio transmissions. While communications jamming emerged at the same time, it was not widely employed. Radio operators realized that simply keying their systems could send out a blast of white noise to drown the transmissions of other radios operating at the same frequencies. But this tactic had limited operational value, because it also prevented forces doing the jamming from using the same radio frequencies to communicate. Moreover, warfare happened slowly enough that the victim could simply wait out the jammer.
</p><p>
	Thus, World War I EW was exemplified by passive detection of radio transmissions and infrequent, rudimentary jamming. The shift to more sophisticated EW systems and tactics occurred with World War II, when technological advances made airborne radars and jammers practical, better tuners allowed jamming and communicating on separate frequencies, and the increased tempo of warfare gave combatants an incentive to not just jam enemy transmissions but to intercept and exploit them as well.
</p><p>
	Consider the Battle of Britain, when the main 
	<a href="https://csbaonline.org/uploads/documents/What-it-Takes-to-Win.pdf" target="_blank">challenge</a> for German pilots was reaching the right spot to drop their bombs. Germany used a radio-beacon system it called <em>Knickebein</em> (“crooked leg” in English) to guide its bombers to British aircraft factories, which the British countered with fake beacons that they code-named Aspirin. To support British warplanes attacking Germany in 1942, the Royal Air Force (RAF) fielded the GEE hyperbolic radio navigation system that allowed its bomber crews to use transmissions from British ground stations to determine their in-flight positions. Germany countered with jammers that drowned out the GEE transmissions.
</p><p>
	The World War II EW competition 
	<a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B06Y94D4LV/ref=dp-kindle-redirect?_encoding=UTF8&btkr=1" target="_blank">extended</a> to sensing and communication networks. RAF and U.S. bombers dispensed clouds of metallic chaff called Window that confused German air-defense radars by creating thousands of false radar targets. And they used VHF communication jammers, which the British called Jostle, to interfere with German ground controllers attempting to vector fighters toward allied bombers.
</p><p>
	The move-countermove cycle accelerated in response to Soviet military aggressions and advances in the 1950s. Active countermeasures such as jammers or decoys proliferated, thanks to technological advances that enabled EW systems with greater power, wider frequency ranges, and more complex waveforms, and which were small enough to fit aircraft as well as ships.
</p><p>
	Later, as Soviet military sensors, surface-to-air missiles, and antiship cruise missiles grew in their sophistication and numbers, the U.S. Department of Defense sought to break out of the radar-versus-electronic-attack competition by leveraging emerging materials, computer simulation, and other technologies. In the years since, the U.S. military has developed multiple generations of stealth aircraft and ships with severely reduced radio-frequency, infrared, acoustic, and visual signatures. Russia followed with its own stealth platforms, albeit more slowly after the Soviet Union’s collapse.
</p><p>
<strong>But today, years of </strong><a href="https://www.economist.com/interactive/2022/03/08/curious-case-russias-missing-air-force" target="_blank"><strong>underfunded</strong></a><strong> aviation training</strong> and maintenance and the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/FIM-92_Stinger#Russian_invasion_of_Ukraine" target="_blank">rapid introduction by NATO of Stinger shoulder-launched surface-to-air missiles </a>have largely grounded Russian jets and helicopters during the Ukraine invasion. So when Russian troops crossed the border, they faced a situation not unlike the armies of World War I.
</p><p>
	Without airpower, the Russian assault crawled at the speed of their trucks and tanks. And although they proved effective in the Donbas during the last decade, Russian drones are controlled by line-of-sight radios operating in the 
	<a href="https://www.esa.int/Applications/Telecommunications_Integrated_Applications/Satellite_frequency_bands" target="_blank">K<sub>a</sub>- and K<sub>u</sub>-bands</a>, which prevented them from straying too far from their operators on the ground. With Russian columns moving along multiple axes into Ukraine and unable to send EW drones well over the horizon, any jamming of Ukrainian forces, some of which were interspersed between Russian formations, would have also taken out Russian radios.
</p><p>
	Russian EW units did use Leer-3 units to find Ukrainian fighters via their radio and cellphone transmissions, as they had in the Donbas. But unlike Ukraine’s rural east, the areas around Kyiv are relatively densely populated. With civilian cellphone transmissions mixed in with military communications, Russian ES systems were unable to pinpoint military transmitters and use that information to target Ukrainian troops. Making matters worse for the Russians, Ukrainian forces also began using the NATO Single-Channel Ground and Airborne Radio System, or 
	<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/SINCGARS" target="_blank">SINCGARS</a>.
</p><p>
	Ukrainian troops had trained for a decade with SINCGARS, but the portable VHF combat radios were scarce until the lead-up to the Russian invasion, when the flood of NATO support sent SINCGARS radios to nearly every Ukrainian ground unit. Unlike Ukraine’s previous radios, which were Russian-built and included 
	<a href="https://www.thedrive.com/the-war-zone/30741/ukrainian-officer-details-russian-electronic-warfare-tactics-including-radio-virus" target="_blank">backdoors</a> for the convenience of Russian intelligence, <a href="https://irp.fas.org/doddir/army/miobc/lp-sincg.htm" target="_blank">SINCGARS</a> have built-in encryption. To protect against jamming and interception, SINCGARS automatically hops among frequencies up to 100 times a second across its overall coverage of 30 to 88 megahertz. Because <a href="https://dsm.forecastinternational.com/wordpress/2022/05/17/life-in-the-old-waveform-yet/" target="_blank">SINCGARS</a> can control signals within 25-kilohertz bands, the user can select among more than 2,000 channels.
</p><p>
	As in World War I, the lack of airpower also affected the speed of conflict. The widely circulated videos of Russian armored convoys stuck along the roads around Kyiv were a stark reminder that ground operations can only move as fast as their fuel supply. In World War II and the Cold War, bombing missions and other air operations happened so quickly that even if jamming impacted friendly forces, the effect would be temporary, as the positions of jammers, jamming targets, and bystanders would quickly change. But when Russian forces were trundling toward the urban areas of northern Ukraine, they were going so slowly that they were unable to exploit changing geometries to get their jammers into positions from which they could have substantial effects. At the same time, Russian troops were not sitting still, which prevented them from setting up a large system like the Krasukha-4 to blind NATO radars in the air and in space.
</p><p class="pull-quote">
	Russian EW is gaining an advantage only now because Moscow’s strategy of quickly taking Kyiv failed, and it shifted to a grinding war of attrition in Ukraine’s south.
</p><p>
<strong>So what’s next?</strong> The Kremlin’s fortunes have improved now that its soldiers are fighting from Russian-held territory in Ukraine’s east. No longer spread out along multiple lines in suburban areas, invading troops are now <a href="https://www.timesofisrael.com/theyre-jamming-everything-secretive-electronic-warfare-shapes-war-in-ukraine/" target="_blank">able to use EW</a> to support a strategy of incrementally gaining territory by finding Ukrainian positions and overwhelming them with Russia’s roughly <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2022/jun/10/were-almost-out-of-ammunition-and-relying-on-western-arms-says-ukraine" target="_blank">10-to-1</a> advantage in artillery.
</p><p>
	As of this writing, at least three of Russia’s five EW brigades are engaged in Ukraine. And with more exposure to NATO-supplied radios, experienced Russian EW operators who cut their teeth in the last decade of war in Syria are beginning to 
	<a href="https://www.newsweek.com/theyre-jamming-everything-putins-electronic-warfare-turns-tide-war-1712784" target="_blank">detect and degrade</a> Ukrainian communications. EW brigades are using the Leer-3’s Orlan-10 drones to detect Ukrainian artillery positions based on their radio emissions, although the encryption and frequency hopping of SINCGARS radios makes them hard to intercept and exploit. Because the front lines are now better defined compared to the early war around Kyiv, Russian forces can assume the detections are from Ukrainian military units and direct artillery and rocket fire against those locations.
</p><p class="shortcode-media shortcode-media-rebelmouse-image">
<img alt="side profile of an orlan 10 drone and a LEER-3 Russian military vehicle" class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="551c3721d12b04d90453d62ef70b04b1" data-rm-shortcode-name="rebelmouse-image" id="04145" loading="lazy" src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/side-profile-of-an-orlan-10-drone-and-a-leer-3-russian-military-vehicle.jpg?id=30142961&width=980"/>
<small class="image-media media-caption" placeholder="Add Photo Caption...">Russian troops are using Orlan-10 drones [foreground] in conjunction with the Leer-3 electronic-warfare system (which includes the truck in the background) to identify and attack Ukrainian units. </small><small class="image-media media-photo-credit" placeholder="Add Photo Credit...">iStockphoto</small>
</p><p>
	The Krasukha-4, which was too powerful and unwieldy to be useful during the assault on Kyiv, is also making a reappearance. Exploiting Russia’s territorial control in the Donbas, EW brigades are using the Krasukha-4 to 
	<a href="https://www.newsweek.com/russia-says-electronic-warfare-system-took-out-ukrainian-drone-1720399" target="_blank">jam</a> the radars on such Ukrainian drones as the Bayraktar TB2, and to interfere with their communication links, preventing Ukrainian forces from locating Russian artillery emplacements.
</p><p>
<span style="background-color: initial;">To gain flexibility and mobility leading up to the invasion, the Russian army </span><a href="https://www.fpri.org/article/2022/02/electronic-warfare-russias-approach/" target="_blank">broke</a><span style="background-color: initial;"> its 2,000-soldier maneuver brigades into smaller battalion tactical groups (BTGs) of 300</span> to <span style="background-color: initial;">800 personnel in such a way that each included a portion of the original maneuver brigade’s EW company. Today, BTGs operating in southern and eastern Ukraine are employing shorter-range VHF-UHF electronic attack systems like the R-330Zh </span><span style="background-color: initial;">Zhitel</span> to disable <a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/ukraine-drone-war" target="_self">Ukrainian drones</a><span style="background-color: initial;"> ranging from Bayraktar TB2s to small DJI </span><span style="background-color: initial;">Mavics</span> by jamming their GPS signals. BTGs are also attacking Ukrainian communications using R-934B VHF and SPR-2 VHF/UHF jammers, with some success. Although Ukrainian soldiers have SINCGARS radios, they still rely on vulnerable cellphones and radios without encryption or frequency hopping when SINCGARS is down or unavailable.
</p><p>
	But Ukraine is fighting back against Russia’s spectrum assault. Using counter-drone systems 
	<a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/aerospace-defense/eying-russia-pentagon-send-ukraine-counter-drone-electronic-warfare-equipment-2021-06-11/" target="_blank">provided</a> by the United States before the invasion, Ukrainian troops have downed hundreds of Russian drones by jamming their GPS signals or <a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/ukraine-drone-war" target="_self">possibly</a> by damaging their electronics with <a href="https://issuu.com/ukrainian_defense_review/docs/udr-04-2014/39" target="_blank">high-powered microwave</a> beams, a specific type of EA where electromagnetic energy is used to generate high voltages in sensitive microelectronics that damage transistors and integrated circuits.
</p><p>
	Ukrainian forces are also leveraging U.S.-supplied EW systems and 
	<a href="https://www.c4isrnet.com/electronic-warfare/2022/05/19/ukrainian-troops-training-with-us-electronic-jamming-kit/" target="_blank">training</a> to <a href="https://www.businessinsider.com/cyber-and-electronic-warfare-on-display-in-ukraine-russia-war-2022-6" target="_blank">jam</a> Russian communications. Unlike their Ukrainian counterparts, Russian troops do not have a system like SINCGARS and often rely on cellphones or unencrypted radios to coordinate operations, making them susceptible to Ukrainian geolocation and jamming. In this way, stabilization of the front lines also helps Ukraine’s EW efforts because it allows quick correlation of transmissions to locations. Ukraine’s defenders also exploited a weakness of the large and powerful Russian EW systems—they are easy to find. Using U.S.-supplied ES gear, Ukrainian troops have been able to <a href="https://www.businessinsider.com/cyber-and-electronic-warfare-on-display-in-ukraine-russia-war-2022-6" target="_blank">detect</a> transmissions from systems like the Leer-3 or Krasukha-4 and direct rocket, artillery, and drone counterattacks against the truck-borne Russian systems.
</p><p>
<strong>The Ukraine invasion</strong> shows EW can change the course of a war, but it’s also showing that the fundamentals still matter. Without airpower or satellite-guided drones, Russia’s army could not get jammers over the horizon to degrade Ukrainian communications and radars in advance of troops moving on Kyiv. Forced to use short-range unmanned aircraft and ground systems, Russian EW brigades operating with BTGs had to worry about interfering with friendly operations and could not distinguish Ukrainian troops from civilians. They also had to stay on the move, reducing the utility of their large multivehicle EW systems. Russian EW is gaining an advantage only now because Moscow’s strategy of quickly taking Kyiv failed, and it shifted to a grinding war of attrition in Ukraine’s south.
</p><p>
	So for now, unable to reach over the horizon, Russian EW ground units can jam Ukrainian troops only when they are separated by clearly defined battle lines. They are relying on systems like the Leer-3 to find Ukrainian emissions so Russian artillery can then overwhelm the defenders with volleys of shells and rockets. Russian EW systems like the Krasukha-4 and R-330Zh Zhitel can disable GPS or radars on Ukrainian drones, but it’s not substantially different from shooting down aircraft with guns. And although ES systems like the Moskva-4 could hear signals over the horizon, Russia is 
	<a href="https://ukdefencejournal.org.uk/russia-running-out-of-precision-weapons/" target="_blank">running out</a> of the long-range missiles that could exploit such detections.
</p><p>
	Perhaps the biggest lesson from Ukraine for EW is that winning the airwaves does not equal winning the war. Russia is on top of the EW war now only because its lighting assault became a pulverizing slog. The situation could quickly flip if Kyiv’s troops, with western support, regain control of Ukraine’s skies, where they could electronically and physically disrupt the management and logistics that keep Russia’s rickety war machine trundling along. 
	<span class="ieee-end-mark"></span>
</p>]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 30 Jul 2022 15:00:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spectrum.ieee.org/the-fall-and-rise-of-russian-electronic-warfare</guid><category>Electronic warfare</category><category>Russia-ukraine war</category><category>Electronic countermeasures</category><category>Military radios</category><category>Communications security</category><dc:creator>Bryan Clark</dc:creator><media:content medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/side-profile-of-a-russian-krasukha-4-military-vehicle.jpg?id=30142963&amp;width=980"></media:content></item><item><title>Sounding Out the Acoustic Integrated Circuit</title><link>https://spectrum.ieee.org/acoustic-integrated-circuit</link><description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/a-gold-chip-on-a-copper-peg-board-with-wires.jpg?id=30154689&width=1245&height=700&coordinates=0%2C281%2C0%2C281"/><br/><br/><p>
	Acoustic devices now play key roles in mobile phones and other electronics, but these often control sound waves passively. Now scientists have for the first time developed a way to electrically control and modify sound waves on a chip actively, potentially one day enabling more complex acoustic circuitry.<br/>
</p><p>
	A modern cellphone possesses dozens of <a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/acoustic-amplifier" target="_self">acoustic devices</a> based on piezoelectric crystals, which can convert electric signals to sound waves and vice versa. These components are often used to manipulate acoustic waves that ripple on the surfaces of solid materials.
</p><p>
	Acoustic waves travel at the speed of sound, making them much slower than electromagnetic signals of the same frequency. However, they also possess much shorter wavelengths. For instance, compared with gigahertz electromagnetic waves, acoustic wavelengths are five orders of magnitude shorter.
</p><p>
	The comparably shorter wavelengths of acoustic waves means they are often easy to use in ultracompact devices. Surface acoustic wave (SAW) filters are often used in mobile phones to help extract desirable signals from all the radio waves hitting their antennas.
</p><p>
	However, most acoustic devices are passive components. Now scientists have developed a way to control and tune SAWs electrically. This may one day open the door to more complex sound-based devices, such as acoustic integrated circuits.
</p><p>
	In a new study, researchers experimented with the piezoelectric material <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lithium_niobate" target="_blank">lithium niobate</a>. When they applied an electric field to it, they could vary the lithium niobate’s elasticity—how much it distorted in the face of mechanical pressure—due to a phenomenon known as the <a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/topics/physics-and-astronomy/electroacoustics" target="_blank">electroacoustic effect</a>. In this way, they could manipulate the phase, amplitude, and frequency of gigahertz SAWs rippling across the lithium niobate.
</p><p>
	The scientists not only showed they could manipulate acoustic waves at room temperature, but also at millikelvin temperatures a few thousandths of a degree above absolute zero. “Most semiconductor devices cannot work at both temperatures, but our devices work well,” says study lead author Linbo Shao at Virginia Tech in Blacksburg.
</p><p>
	These findings suggest this breakthrough might find applications in quantum computing, which often requires extraordinary cold to keep heat from disrupting their workings. Previous research suggested that pulses of acoustic energy known as <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Phonon" target="_blank">phonons</a> may help relay information between the components known as <a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/silicon-spin-qubits" target="_self">quantum bits or qubits</a> on which quantum computers rely.
</p><p>
	The researchers are now working to build more complex, large-scale acoustic devices.
</p><p>
	“We envision a hardware platform of acoustic-wave integrated circuits, which can be potentially used for microwave signal processing and also quantum circuits,” Shao says.
</p><p>
	The scientists detailed <a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41928-022-00773-3" target="_blank">their findings</a> last month in the journal <em>Nature Electronics</em>.
</p>]]></description><pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2022 13:44:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spectrum.ieee.org/acoustic-integrated-circuit</guid><category>Saw</category><category>Phonons</category><category>Lithium niobate</category><category>Quantum computing</category><category>Qubits</category><category>Acoustics</category><category>Electroacoustic effect</category><dc:creator>Charles Q. Choi</dc:creator><media:content medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/a-gold-chip-on-a-copper-peg-board-with-wires.jpg?id=30154689&amp;width=980"></media:content></item><item><title>X-Rays Could Carry Quantum Signals Across the Stars</title><link>https://spectrum.ieee.org/search-for-extraterrestrial-intelligence</link><description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/colorful-streams-of-light.jpg?id=30142338&width=1245&height=700&coordinates=0%2C187%2C0%2C187"/><br/><br/><p>
	Quantum signals may possess a number of advantages over regular forms of communication, leading scientists to wonder if humanity was not alone in discovering such benefits. Now a new study suggests that, for hypothetical extraterrestrial civilizations, quantum transmissions using X-rays may be possible across interstellar distances.
</p><p>
	Quantum communication relies on a quantum phenomenon known as 
	<u><a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/what-is-quantum-entanglement" target="_self">entanglement</a></u>. Essentially, two or more particles such as photons that get “linked” via entanglement can, in theory, influence each other instantly no matter how far apart they are.
</p><p>
	Entanglement is essential to 
	<u><a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/quantum-teleportation" target="_self">quantum teleportation</a></u>, in which data can essentially disappear one place and reappear someplace else. Since this information does not travel across the intervening space, there is no chance the information will be lost.
</p><p>
	To accomplish quantum teleportation, one would first entangle two photons. Then, one of the photons—the one to be teleported—is kept at one location while the other is beamed to whatever destination is desired.
</p><p>
	Next, the photon at the destination's quantum state—which defines its key characteristics—is analyzed, an act that also destroys its quantum state. Entanglement will lead the destination photon to prove identical to its partner. For all intents and purposes, the photon at the origin point “teleported” to the destination point—no physical matter moved, but the two photons are physically indistinguishable.
</p><p>
	And to be clear, quantum teleportation cannot send information faster than the speed of light, because the destination photon must still be transmitted via conventional means.
</p><p>
	One weakness of quantum communication is that entanglement is fragile. Still, researchers have successfully transmitted entangled photons that remained stable or “<u><a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/longlasting-qubits" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">coherent</a></u>” enough for quantum teleportation across distances as great as <u><a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/nature23675/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">1,400 kilometers</a></u>.
</p><p>
	Such findings led theoretical physicist 
	<a href="https://www.ph.ed.ac.uk/people/arjun-berera" target="_blank">Arjun Berera</a> at the University of Edinburgh to wonder just how far quantum signals might stay coherent. First, he discovered <u><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2009.00356" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">quantum coherence might survive interstellar distances within our galaxy</a></u>, and then he and his colleagues found <u><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2107.06914" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">quantum coherence might survive intergalactic distances</a></u>.
</p><p>
	“If photons in Earth’s atmosphere don’t decohere to 100 km, then in interstellar space where the medium is much less dense then our atmosphere, photons won’t decohere up to even the size of the galaxy,” Berera says.
</p><p>
	In the new study, the researchers investigated whether and how well quantum communication might survive interstellar distances. Quantum signals might face disruption from a number of factors, such as the gravitational pull of interstellar bodies, they note.
</p><p>
	The scientists discovered the best quantum communication channels for interstellar messages are X-rays. Such frequencies are easier to focus and detect across interstellar distances. (NASA has tested deep-space X-ray communication with its 
	<a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/nasa-wants-to-place-calls-to-deep-space-with-xrays" target="_self">XCOM</a> experiment.) The researchers also found that the optical and microwave bands could enable communication across large distances as well, albeit less effectively than X-rays.
</p><p>
	Although coherence might survive interstellar distances, Berera does note quantum signals might lose fidelity. “This means the quantum state is sustained, but it can have a phase shift, so although the quantum information is preserved in these states, it has been altered by the effect of gravity.” Therefore, it may “take some work at the receiving end to account for these phase shifts and be able to assess the information contained in the original state.”
</p><p>
	Why might an interstellar civilization transmit quantum signals as opposed to regular ones? The researchers note that quantum communication may allow 
	<a href="https://journals.aps.org/pra/abstract/10.1103/PhysRevA.51.2738" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">greater data compression</a> and, in some cases, <a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/quant-ph/0607174" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">exponentially</a> <a href="https://dl.acm.org/doi/10.1145/1007352.1007379" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">faster</a> speeds than classical channels. Such a boost in efficiency might prove very useful for civilizations separated by interstellar distances.
</p><p>
	“It could be that quantum communication is the main communication mode in an extraterrestrial's world, so they just apply what is at hand to send signals into the cosmos,” Berera says.
</p><p>
	The scientists detailed 
	<u><a href="https://journals.aps.org/prd/abstract/10.1103/PhysRevD.105.123033" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">their findings</a></u> online 28 June in the journal <em>Physical Review D</em>.
</p>]]></description><pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2022 15:07:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spectrum.ieee.org/search-for-extraterrestrial-intelligence</guid><category>Extraterrestrial</category><category>Entanglement</category><category>Teleportation</category><category>X-rays</category><category>Coherence</category><category>Decoherence</category><category>Quantum communications</category><dc:creator>Charles Q. Choi</dc:creator><media:content medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/colorful-streams-of-light.jpg?id=30142338&amp;width=980"></media:content></item><item><title>SpaceX and Dish’s Super-Shady War for the World</title><link>https://spectrum.ieee.org/spacex-starlink-dish-network</link><description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/map-of-globe-with-blue-orbs-of-light-around.jpg?id=30131119&width=1245&height=700&coordinates=0%2C187%2C0%2C187"/><br/><br/><p>
	Billionaires, satellite links, political chicanery: a present-day, oligopolistic game of jockeying for prime placement in the 12-gigahertz spectrum has at least a few of the ingredients of a thriller. Or—given the outsize personalities involved (including Elon Musk and Michael Dell) and the epic, five-year duration of the dispute to date—maybe more like a space opera.
</p><p>
	At issue is a set of frequencies where Musk’s SpaceX sets its <a href="https://www.starlink.com/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Starlink</a> Internet service, the company’s well-publicized play for broadband beaming down from low-Earth orbit to satellite dishes in remote areas. Charlie Ergen’s <a href="https://about.dish.com/company-info" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Dish Network Corp.</a>, which transmits TV on these frequencies and is one of the two big satellite viewing providers in the United States, has launched a 5G wireless service and wants to increase its signal volume in this wavelength. Musk’s side says the move would make debilitating static for his satellites; Ergen’s engineers say that’s nonsense. As for Dell (you may recall Dell laptops) his <a href="https://www.msdcapital.com/Michael_Dell" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">private investment firm</a> holds interest in some of the airwaves in play. At the moment, they’re siding with Dish.
</p><p>
	The current field, more precisely 12.2 to 12.7 GHz in the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ku_band" target="_blank">Ku microwave band</a>, is a lot of bandwidth lightly used—primarily today for assorted satellite broadcasts, live feeds, ISS tracking, and military recon drones. But the corporates fighting over it recently <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/elon-musks-starlink-satellite-internet-service-battles-dish-over-airwaves-11657359181" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">cranked up their clashing</a>. The <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-10-09/billionaires-musk-ergen-and-dell-brawling-over-spectrum-at-fcc" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">sides are lobbying a shorthanded</a> Federal Communications Commission, with recent highlight swipes including Musk blasting his foes as “super shady and unethical” while taking return fire from Dish for “flimsy” and “far-fetched” objections to opening bandwidth.
</p><p>
	But what’s it mean for those outside the immediate fray? For civilians going about their daily business? For people—possible satellite service subscribers, all—around the world?
</p><p>
	Only a handful of people who understand the nature of possible interference and related issues seem to be paying attention now. “Rights to use frequencies have not been sharply defined, and the overlapping permits generate controversy,” says Thomas Hazlett, a Clemson University economist <a href="https://www.abebooks.com/9780300210507/Political-Spectrum-Tumultuous-Liberation-Wireless-0300210507/plp" target="_blank">who writes about</a> bandwidth battles (and once served as FCC chief economist). But the rulings—and market activities that result—stand to have real social impact wherever signals from satellite broadcasts or satellite Internet connections may one day fall. Which means pretty much everywhere.
</p><p>
	It’s a stark contrast given the economic value placed on frequency rights. More than <a href="https://www.fcc.gov/auctions-summary" target="_blank">100 bandwidth auctions</a> over the last 30 years have netted about US $280 billion for the U.S. Treasury. And as with television, radio, and the railway before that, citizens aren’t likely to tune in until more tangible developments happen. But others are paying attention, and the pressures are intense. “In the U.S., it is purely market driven,” says Shahed Mazumder, global director of telecom solutions at <a href="https://aerospike.com/author/smazumder/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Aerospike</a>, a database firm. SpaceX has launched thousands of new satellites; Dish is trying to move into new services. <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/pulse/5g-spectrum-series-what-happening-12-ghz-shahed-mazumder" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Neither wants interference</a>.
</p><p>
	“The political pressure, the business pressure, the monetary pressure: There are legitimately major things going on here,” says Mike Dano, who’s been <a href="https://www.lightreading.com/iot/5g-skirmishes-at-12ghz-may-escalate-into-all-out-spectrum-war/d/d-id/765009" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">following the dispute</a> as editorial director at <a href="https://www.lightreading.com/profile.asp?piddl_userid=551155" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Light Reading</a>, a news website covering international teleco. Billions of dollars of value, potentially, to be created or destroyed depending on how an FCC engineer finally decides on it.” Meanwhile the politically appointed commissioners at the FCC are <a href="https://www.spglobal.com/marketintelligence/en/news-insights/latest-news-headlines/telecom-players-divided-on-gigi-sohn-s-fcc-prospects-as-august-recess-looms-70878011" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">down one member</a>, splitting it 2-2 along party lines. It makes controversial calls more difficult.
</p><p>
	More techie influences may also affect the spectrum spat. In 2018 the United States became the first to approve a <a href="https://www.nist.gov/news-events/news/2018/03/nist-helps-facilitate-first-ever-spectrum-sharing-between-military-and" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">spectrum-sharing setup</a> in the Citizens Broadband Radio Service band (3.5 GHz). It’s an advanced concept allowing different sets of users to share spectrum—making more room. Dano says the FCC is under pressure to allocate 12 GHz in a way set up for spectrum sharing.
</p><p>
	This notably did not happen with U.S 5G network rollouts, which turned into a <a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/5g-faa" target="_self">snarling issue earlier this year</a> over fears of interference in the C-band between high-speed cellular service towers and plane altimeters in low-visibility conditions on approach to airports.
</p><p>
	Meanwhile Starlink wants to open its satellite show in further-flung places, seeking to <a href="https://spacenews.com/uk-mulls-starlink-expansion-plan-under-new-ngso-regulations/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">open gateways in the United Kingdom</a>. While its 12-GHz fight with Dish is centered in the United States and Dish’s U.S. services, satellite spectrum allocation is...special. Space has international dimensions, points out Plum Consulting’s Selçuk Kırtay, who was <a href="https://www.academia.edu/9483627/Broadband_satellite_system_technologies" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">writing about spectrum sharing</a> in 2002. Slicing up the Ku band has history—it even <a href="https://ui.adsabs.harvard.edu/abs/1977prag.iafcX....S/abstract" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">left its mark</a> at a global astronautical confab in then-Czechoslovakia in <em>Star Wars</em>-era 1977.
</p><p>
	Ofcom, the U.K. regulator, is monitoring developments with U.S. allocations in 12 GHz. The German network authority is preparing to discuss the 12.2-to-12.7-GHz frequency range at next year’s <a href="https://www.itu.int/en/ITU-R/conferences/wrc/Pages/default.aspx" target="_blank">ITU World Radiocommunication Conference</a> in the United Arab Emirates.
</p><p>
	Stay tuned, say experts and satellite industry watchers. “How the conflicts are resolved in the USA will materially affect markets around the world,” Hazlett says.<br/>
</p><p>
<em>This article appears in the October 2022 print issue as “Billionaires Battle
for Global Spectrum Domination.”</em>
</p>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2022 15:32:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spectrum.ieee.org/spacex-starlink-dish-network</guid><category>Satellites</category><category>Spacex</category><category>Starlink</category><category>Dell</category><category>Dish network</category><category>Elon musk</category><dc:creator>Michael Dumiak</dc:creator><media:content medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/map-of-globe-with-blue-orbs-of-light-around.jpg?id=30131119&amp;width=980"></media:content></item><item><title>150,000 Qubits Printed on a Chip</title><link>https://spectrum.ieee.org/silicon-spin-qubits</link><description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/multicolored-data-visualization.jpg?id=30125442&width=1245&height=700&coordinates=0%2C187%2C0%2C187"/><br/><br/><p>Quantum computers can theoretically solve problems no classical computer ever could—even given billions of years—but only if they possess many components known as qubits. Now scientists have fabricated more than 150,000 silicon-based qubits on a chip that they may be able to link together with light, to help form powerful quantum computers connected by a quantum Internet.</p><p>Classical computers switch transistors either on or off to represent data as ones or zeroes. In contrast, quantum computers use quantum bits, also known as qubits. Because of the surreal nature of quantum physics, qubits can exist in a state called superposition, in which they are essentially both 1 and 0 at the same time. This phenomenon lets each qubit perform two calculations at once. The more qubits are quantum mechanically linked, or <a data-linked-post="2657446195" href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/what-is-quantum-entanglement" target="_blank">entangled (see our explainer)</a>, within a quantum computer, the greater its computational power can grow, in an exponential fashion.</p><p>Currently quantum computers are <a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/quantum-computing" target="_self">noisy intermediate-scale quantum</a> (NISQ) platforms, meaning their qubits number up to a few hundred at most. To prove useful for practical applications, future quantum computers will likely need thousands of qubits to help compensate for <a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/fault-tolerant-quantum-computing" target="_self">errors</a>.</p><p>There are many different types of qubits under development, such as <a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/googles-quantum-computer-exponentially-suppress-errors" target="_self">superconducting circuits</a>, <a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/lithium-air-battery-quantum-computing" target="_self">electromagnetically trapped ions</a>, and even <a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/neon-qubit" target="_self">frozen neon</a>. Recently scientists have discovered that so-called spin qubits manufactured in silicon may prove especially promising for quantum computing.</p><p>“Silicon spins are some of nature’s very best natural qubits,” says study cosenior author <a href="https://www.sfu.ca/physics/people/faculty/s_simmons.html" target="_blank">Stephanie Simmons</a>, a quantum engineer at Simon Fraser University in Burnaby, B.C., Canada.</p><p>The “spin” in spin qubits is the angular momentum of a particle such as an electron or an atomic nucleus. Spin can point up or down in a manner analogous to a compass needle that points north or south. A spin qubit can exist in a superposition where it is oriented both ways at once.</p><p>Silicon spin qubits are among the most stable qubits created to date. In addition, this technology can theoretically rapidly scale up with the support of the decades of work spent developing the global semiconductor industry.</p><p>Until now, scientists had measured single spins only electrically in silicon. This in turn meant that the only way to entangle spins together was electromagnetically, “which must be done with qubits in very close proximity to each other,” Simmons says. “This is hard to scale from an engineering perspective.”</p><p>Now, for the first time, researchers have detected single spins optically in qubits in silicon. Such optical access to spin qubits suggests it may one day be possible to use light to “have qubits entangling with each other across a chip, or across a data center as easily as if they’re side by side,” Simmons says.</p><p>The new spin qubits are based on <a href="https://aip.scitation.org/doi/10.1063/5.0093822" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">radiation damage centers</a>—defects within silicon created using ion implantation or irradiation with high-energy electrons. Specifically, they are <a href="https://journals.aps.org/prxquantum/abstract/10.1103/PRXQuantum.1.020301" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">T centers</a>, each comprised of two carbon atoms, one hydrogen atom, and an unpaired electron.</p><p>Each T center features an unpaired electron spin and a hydrogen nuclear spin, each of which can serve as a qubit. The electron spin can stay coherent, or stable, for more than 2 milliseconds; the hydrogen nuclear spin can remain so for more than 1.1 seconds. “Our silicon spin qubits’ long lifetimes are already quite competitive, and we have ideas on how to push them far further,” Simmons says.</p><p>The researchers printed 150,000 spots dubbed “micropucks” on commercial industry-standard silicon-on-insulator integrated photonic wafers. Each micropuck ranged from 0.5 to 2.2 micrometers wide and held one T center on average, says study lead author <a href="https://www.sfu.ca/physics/people/postdocs-researchers/dhigginb.html" target="_blank">Daniel Higginbottom, </a>at Simon Fraser University.</p><p class="shortcode-media shortcode-media-rebelmouse-image">
<img alt="an array of micropucks" class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="cd56edc0f493fcc8f363fbb54ba2bb89" data-rm-shortcode-name="rebelmouse-image" id="fca14" loading="lazy" src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/an-array-of-micropucks.png?id=30125716&width=980"/>
<small class="image-media media-caption" placeholder="Add Photo Caption...">Under the microscope: An array of thousands of micropucks.</small><small class="image-media media-photo-credit" placeholder="Add Photo Credit...">Simon Fraser University</small></p><p>Under a magnetic field, the spin qubit states in each T center have slightly different energies, and each emit a different wavelength of light. This lets the scientists detect the states of each spin qubit optically in these T centers.<br/></p><p>The wavelengths these spin qubits emit lie in the near-infrared <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fiber-optic_communication#Optical_bands" target="_blank">O-band</a>. This means these spin qubits can link with other qubits by emitting the kind of light often used in telecommunications networks, helping qubits work together inside a quantum processor and helping quantum computers partner over a quantum Internet.</p><p>In addition, “the electron and nuclear spin qubits can be operated together—the nuclear spin as a long-lived memory qubit and the electron spin as an optically coupled communication qubit, and information can be swapped between them using microwave fields,” Simmons says. “No other physical quantum system combines high-performance quantum memories, direct and strong links to telecom photons, and the commercial prospects of silicon, which is the world’s top platform for both modern microelectronics as well as integrated photonics.”</p><p>Scientists have known about T centers since the 1970s. “We do not know why we are the first to start investigating T centers as qubits in silicon,” Simmons says. “It is possible that researchers assumed that candidate spin-photon qubits in silicon were simply less likely to compete with candidates in other materials such as diamond and silicon carbide. It’s a mystery to us.”</p><p>All in all, “we are most excited about the fundamental scalability of these qubits,” Simmons says. “It’s a new entrant to the international race for a quantum computer, and we think the prospects are very bright.”</p><p>Although the researchers have fabricated many qubits in this new study, “these have not yet been wired up into a working quantum computer,” Simmons cautions. “The optical access to these spins will make this wiring a lot easier than many other approaches, but this technology is still very young and there is a lot of work to be done.”</p><p>The scientists detailed <u><a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-022-04821-y" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">their findings</a></u> online 13 June in the journal <em>Nature</em>.</p>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2022 14:28:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spectrum.ieee.org/silicon-spin-qubits</guid><category>Qubit</category><category>Silicon spin qubits</category><category>Quantum networks</category><category>Quantum internet</category><category>Silicon-on-insulator</category><category>Quantum computing</category><dc:creator>Charles Q. Choi</dc:creator><media:content medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/multicolored-data-visualization.jpg?id=30125442&amp;width=980"></media:content></item><item><title>The Webb Space Telescope’s Profound Data Challenges</title><link>https://spectrum.ieee.org/james-webb-telescope-communications</link><description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/two-men-fix-metal-rods-to-a-gold-foiled-satellite-component-in-a-warehouse-clean-room-environment.png?id=30076160&width=1245&height=700&coordinates=0%2C149%2C0%2C150"/><br/><br/><p class="ieee-editors-note">
<em>For a deep dive into the engineering behind the James Webb Space Telescope, <a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/collections/james-webb-telescope/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">see our collection of posts here</a>.</em>
</p><p>
	When the 
	<a href="https://www.jwst.nasa.gov/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">James Webb Space Telescope</a> (JWST) <a rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"></a><a href="https://www.nasa.gov/feature/goddard/2022/first-images-from-nasa-s-webb-space-telescope-coming-soon" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">reveals its first images</a> on 12 July, they will be the by-product of carefully crafted mirrors and scientific instruments. But all of its data-collecting prowess would be moot without the spacecraft’s communications subsystem.
</p><p>
	The Webb’s comms aren’t flashy. Rather, the data and communication systems are designed to be incredibly, unquestionably dependable and reliable. And while some aspects of them are relatively new—it’s the first mission to use 
	<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ka_band" target="_blank">K<sub>a</sub>-band</a> frequencies for such high data rates so far from Earth, for example—above all else, JWST’s comms provide the foundation upon which JWST’s scientific endeavors sit.
</p><hr/><p>
	As previous articles in this series have noted, JWST is parked at 
	<a href="https://www.nasa.gov/topics/universe/features/webb-l2.html" target="_blank">Lagrange point L2</a>. It’s a point of gravitational equilibrium located about 1.5 million kilometers beyond Earth on a straight line between the planet and the sun. It’s an ideal location for JWST to observe the universe without obstruction and with minimal orbital adjustments.
</p><p>
	Being so far away from Earth, however, means that data has farther to travel to make it back in one piece. It also means the communications subsystem needs to be reliable, because the prospect of a repair mission being sent to address a problem is, for the near term at least, highly unlikely. Given the cost and time involved, says 
	<a href="https://www.jwst.nasa.gov/content/meetTheTeam/people/menzel.html" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Michael Menzel</a>, the mission systems engineer for JWST, “I would not encourage a rendezvous and servicing mission unless something went wildly wrong.”
</p><p>
	According to Menzel, who has worked on JWST in some capacity for over 20 years, the plan has always been to use well-understood K
	<sub>a</sub>-band frequencies for the bulky transmissions of scientific data. Specifically, JWST is transmitting data back to Earth on a 25.9-gigahertz channel at up to 28 megabits per second. The K<sub>a</sub>-band is a portion of the broader <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/K_band_(IEEE)" target="_blank">K-band</a> (another portion, the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ku_band" target="_blank">Ku-band</a>, was also considered).
</p><p class="shortcode-media shortcode-media-rebelmouse-image">
<img alt="An illustration depicting different Lagrange points and where the Webb Telescope is." class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="e917bd84316ffff0c175bcd0bc5611a8" data-rm-shortcode-name="rebelmouse-image" id="80442" loading="lazy" src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/an-illustration-depicting-different-lagrange-points-and-where-the-webb-telescope-is.png?id=30819133&width=980"/>
<small class="image-media media-caption" placeholder="Add Photo Caption...">The Lagrange points are equilibrium locations where competing gravitational tugs on an object net out to zero. JWST is one of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_objects_at_Lagrange_points#L2" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">three craft</a> currently occupying L2 (Shown here at an exaggerated distance from Earth). </small><small class="image-media media-photo-credit" placeholder="Add Photo Credit...">IEEE Spectrum</small>
</p><p>
	Both the data-collection and transmission rates of JWST dwarf those of the older 
	<a href="https://hubblesite.org/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Hubble Space Telescope</a>. Compared to Hubble, which is still active and generates 1 to 2 gigabytes of data daily, JWST can produce up to 57 GB each day (although that amount is dependent on what observations are scheduled).
</p><p>
	Menzel says he first saw the frequency selection proposals for JWST around 2000, when he was working at 
	<a href="https://www.northropgrumman.com/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Northrop Grumman</a>. He became the mission systems engineer in 2004. “I knew where the risks were in this mission. And I wanted to make sure that we didn’t get any new risks,” he says.
</p><p class="shortcode-media shortcode-media-rebelmouse-image rm-resized-container rm-resized-container-25 rm-float-left" data-rm-resized-container="25%" style="float: left;">
<img class="rm-shortcode rm-resized-image" data-rm-shortcode-id="ef72723df77b044205bda548f7515acd" data-rm-shortcode-name="rebelmouse-image" id="54fee" loading="lazy" src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/image.png?id=30076351&width=980" style="max-width: 100%"/>
<small class="image-media media-photo-credit" placeholder="Add Photo Credit..." style="max-width: 100%;">IEEE Spectrum</small>
</p><p>
	Besides, K
	<sub>a</sub>-band frequencies can transmit more data than <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/X_band" target="_blank">X-band</a> (7 to 11.2 GHz) or <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/S_band" target="_blank">S-band</a> (2 to 4 GHz), common choices for craft in deep space. A high data rate is a necessity for the scientific work JWST will be undertaking. In addition, according to <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/carl-hansen-858a1b68" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Carl Hansen</a>, a flight systems engineer at the <a href="https://www.stsci.edu/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Space Telescope Science Institute</a> (the science operations center for JWST), a comparable X-band antenna would be so large that the spacecraft would have trouble remaining steady for imaging.
</p><p>
	Although the 25.9-GHz K
	<sub>a</sub>-band frequency is the telescope’s workhorse communication channel, it also employs two channels in the S-band. One is the 2.09-GHz uplink that ferries future transmission and scientific observation schedules to the telescope at 16 kilobits per second. The other is the 2.27-GHz, 40-kb/s downlink over which the telescope transmits engineering data—including its operational status, systems health, and other information concerning the telescope’s day-to-day activities.
</p><p>
	Any scientific data the JWST collects during its lifetime will need to be stored on board, because the spacecraft doesn’t maintain round-the-clock contact with Earth. Data gathered from its scientific instruments, once collected, is stored within the spacecraft’s 68-GB solid-state drive (3 percent is reserved for engineering and telemetry data). 
	<a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/alex-hunter-3918a111" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Alex Hunter</a>, also a flight systems engineer at the Space Telescope Science Institute, says that by the end of JWST’s 10-year mission life, they expect to be down to about 60 GB because of deep-space radiation and wear and tear.
</p><p>
	The onboard storage is enough to collect data for about 24 hours before it runs out of room. Well before that becomes an issue, JWST will have scheduled opportunities to beam that invaluable data to Earth.
</p><p>
	JWST will stay connected via the 
	<a href="https://www.nasa.gov/directorates/heo/scan/services/networks/deep_space_network/about" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Deep Space Network</a> (DSN)—a <a href="https://eyes.nasa.gov/dsn/dsn.html" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">resource it shares</a> with the <a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/how-the-parker-solar-probe-survives-close-encounters-with-the-sun" target="_self">Parker Solar Probe</a>, <a href="https://www.nasa.gov/tess-transiting-exoplanet-survey-satellite" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Transiting Exoplanet Survey Satellite</a>, the <a href="https://voyager.jpl.nasa.gov/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Voyager probes</a>, and the entire ensemble of <a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/how-nasa-is-adapting-radios-to-a-noisier-mars" target="_self">Mars rovers and orbiters</a>, to name just a few of the other heavyweights. The DSN consists of <a href="https://www.nasa.gov/directorates/heo/scan/services/networks/deep_space_network/complexes" target="_blank">three antenna complexes</a>: Canberra, Australia; Madrid, Spain; and Barstow, Calif. JWST needs to share finite antenna time with plenty of other deep-space missions, each with unique communications needs and schedules.</p><p class="shortcode-media shortcode-media-rebelmouse-image rm-resized-container rm-resized-container-25 rm-float-left" data-rm-resized-container="25%" style="float: left;">
<img class="rm-shortcode rm-resized-image" data-rm-shortcode-id="fedee7e9bbe254af34d3bc428d80b060" data-rm-shortcode-name="rebelmouse-image" id="c5111" loading="lazy" src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/image.png?id=30844323&width=980" style="max-width: 100%"/>
<small class="image-media media-photo-credit" placeholder="Add Photo Credit..." style="max-width: 100%;">IEEE Spectrum</small></p><p>
<a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/sandykwan" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Sandy Kwan</a>, a DSN systems engineer, says that contact windows with spacecraft are scheduled 12 to 20 weeks in advance. JWST had a greater number of scheduled contact windows during its commissioning phase, as instruments were brought on line, checked, and calibrated. Most of that process required real-time communication with Earth.</p><p>All of the communications channels use the 
	<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Reed%E2%80%93Solomon_error_correction" target="_blank">Reed-Solomon</a> <a href="https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/book/5264570" target="_blank">error-correction protocol</a>—the same error-correction standard as used in DVDs and Blu-ray discs as well as QR codes. The lower data-rate S-band channels use <a href="https://technav.ieee.org/topic/binary-phase-shift-keying" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">binary phase-shift key</a> modulation—involving phase shifting of a signal’s carrier wave. The K-band channel, however, uses a quadrature phase-shift key modulation. Quadrature phase-shift keying can double a channel’s data rate, at the cost of more complicated transmitters and receivers.
</p><p>
	JWST’s communications with Earth incorporate an acknowledgement protocol—only after the JWST gets confirmation that a file has been successfully received will it go ahead and delete its copy of the data to clear up space.
	<a href="#_msocom_6" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"></a>
</p><p>
	The communications subsystem was assembled along with the rest of the spacecraft bus by 
	<a href="https://www.northropgrumman.com/space/james-webb-space-telescope/" target="_blank">Northrop Grumman</a>, using off-the-shelf components sourced from multiple manufacturers.
</p><p>
	JWST has had a long and 
	<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Timeline_of_the_James_Webb_Space_Telescope" target="_blank">often-delayed development</a>, but its communications system has always been a bedrock for the rest of the project. Keeping at least one system dependable means it’s one less thing to worry about. Menzel can remember, for instance, ideas for <a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/lunar-pioneers-will-use-lasers-to-phone-home" target="_self">laser-based optical systems</a> that were invariably rejected. “I can count at least two times where I had been approached by people who wanted to experiment with optical communications,” says Menzel. “Each time they came to me, I sent them away with the old ‘Thank you, but I don’t need it. And I don’t want it.’”
</p>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2022 18:03:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spectrum.ieee.org/james-webb-telescope-communications</guid><category>James webb space telescope</category><category>Nasa</category><category>Space telescopes</category><category>Data compression</category><category>Deep space network</category><dc:creator>Michael Koziol</dc:creator><media:content medium="image" type="image/png" url="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/two-men-fix-metal-rods-to-a-gold-foiled-satellite-component-in-a-warehouse-clean-room-environment.png?id=30076160&amp;width=980"></media:content></item></channel></rss>