<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>ProoFFreader</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.prooffreader.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.prooffreader.com</link>
	<description>Data, Software and Technology Tutorials</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Oct 2021 19:10:37 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://www.prooffreader.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/favicon-1.ico</url>
	<title>ProoFFreader</title>
	<link>https://www.prooffreader.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>How to Install Exodus Redux &#038; Exodus Kodi Addon</title>
		<link>https://www.prooffreader.com/exodus-redux-install</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[David]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Oct 2021 19:07:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Kodi]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.prooffreader.com/?p=1245</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Exodus was arguably one of the best entertainment addons available on Kodi. But, it was discontinued in 2018, and the ... </p>
<p class="read-more-container"><a title="How to Install Exodus Redux &#038; Exodus Kodi Addon" class="read-more button" href="https://www.prooffreader.com/exodus-redux-install#more-1245" aria-label="More on How to Install Exodus Redux &#038; Exodus Kodi Addon">Read more</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prooffreader.com/exodus-redux-install">How to Install Exodus Redux &#038; Exodus Kodi Addon</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prooffreader.com">ProoFFreader</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Exodus was arguably one of the best entertainment addons available on Kodi. But, it was discontinued in 2018, and the original developers ditched it altogether. In 2020, Exodus Redux, a fork of the original Exodus, was launched.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Both have the same logo and interface, but they are two different addons. The Exodus Redux addon is faster thanks to the Lampard scrappers and regular software updates.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This addon has many features and categories, such as movies, TV shows, documentaries, sports channels, kids&#8217; shows, and more.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Here&#8217;s all you need to know about it.&nbsp;</p>



<h2>Installation Prerequisites</h2>



<p>Exodus Redux is a third-party addon, meaning you will need to install it from a third-party repository. To do this, you need to allow installation from unknown sources from Kodi settings.&nbsp;</p>



<p>After that, install the Exodus Redux repository, which is the home of the Exodus Redux addon.</p>



<p>You will also need to integrate the addon with Real-Debrid to access multiple high-quality links within the shortest time possible.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Here is all the necessary information:</p>



<ol><li>Name of the add on: Exodus Redux</li><li>Repository name: IAC </li><li>Category: Media sources</li><li>Media source name: Exodus</li><li>Latest working URL:<a href="https://i-a-c.github.io/"> https://i-a-c.github.io/</a></li></ol>



<h2>Installation Guide</h2>



<h3><strong>First Things First – Enable Installation From Unknown Sources</strong></h3>



<p>Go to Home Screen, click on the gear icon, click on system, select “add-ons” on the left side menu, allow installation from “Unknown Sources”, click “yes” when the warning popup appears.&nbsp;</p>



<h3><strong>Installing Exodus Redux Repository</strong></h3>



<ol><li>Go to Home Screen, click on Gear Icon, click on File Manager;</li><li>Click Add Source, Click None, Type in the URL <strong>“<strong>https://i-a-c.github.io</strong>”</strong> and click Done;</li><li>Pick a name for the repository (i.e. REDUX) and enter it in the bottom box and click OK;</li><li>Click back until you are in the Main Menu, select Addons on the left side; </li><li>Click on the Box Symbol (top left corner), Choose Install From ZIP file, click Yes when a warning appears;</li><li>Open “<strong>REDUX</strong>” Source and choose this file: <strong>“<strong>repository.exodusredux-0.0.6.zip</strong>”</strong></li><li>A notification saying “Installed Successfully” will appear.</li></ol>



<h3><strong>Installing Exodus Redux Kodi Addon</strong></h3>



<ol><li>Go to Home Screen, find Add-ons on the left side, select the box symbol (top left corner) to get to the Addon Browser;</li><li>Click on Install From Repository, choose <strong>Exodus Repo</strong>, click on Video Addons in the category section;</li><li>Click on Exodus and hit install, select OK to confirm the installation of dependencies (don’t appear in Kodi 19 Matrix);</li><li>A notification saying “Installed Successfully” will appear;</li><li>You have now downloaded Exodus to Kodi. You can now access the addon from the main menu. </li></ol>



<h2>Outstanding Features&nbsp;</h2>



<p>Here are some of the features of the Exodus Redux addon:&nbsp;</p>



<ul><li>Has Open and Lambda scrappers, which guarantee high-quality links from the internet.</li><li>Regularly updated, preventing multiple errors.&nbsp;</li><li>Supports Track.tv and non-English streams&nbsp;</li><li>Scraps over 50 media sources.&nbsp;</li></ul>



<h2>Compatibility</h2>



<p>The original Exodus V8 addon was one of the first third-party Kodi addons to be built. Unfortunately, Exodus Redux, a fork of Exodus V8, is still not compatible with the latest Kodi 19 Matrix version. Instead, it can only work on Kodi 18.1, 18.2, and 17.6.&nbsp;</p>



<h2>Exodus Redux Kodi Addon Alternatives</h2>



<p>Exodus Redux is arguably one of the best entertainment Kodi addons available, but it is not compatible with the new Kodi 19 update. If you&#8217;re looking for a worthy alternative, here are a few options:&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Movie Theater Butter </strong>offers free access to lots of movies, documentaries, and TV shows. In addition, it features content in over 30 languages.</p>



<p><strong><a href="http://www.prooffreader.com/venom-kodi-addon/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Venom</a> </strong>offers premium content and comes equipped with advanced features, such as a YouTube section, library integration, Real-Debrid, Trakt TV support, and so on. </p>



<p><strong>Asgard </strong>is a great alternative if you want an all-around entertainment hub; it features movies, TV shows, anime, sports, documentaries, animation, and so on. Besides, it is compatible with the latest Kodi version.&nbsp;</p>



<h2>Exodus Redux Problems and Troubleshooting Tips&nbsp;</h2>



<p>Once in a while, you are bound to encounter various errors with the Exodus Redux addon, as discussed below.&nbsp;</p>



<h3>No Stream Available Error&nbsp;</h3>



<p>This error may appear because of the following issues:</p>



<ul><li>Outdated version of Exodus Redux.&nbsp;</li><li>Attempting to stream Ultra High Definition (UHD) content with an unstable internet connection.&nbsp;</li><li>Unavailable content.&nbsp;</li><li>Problems with your internet service provider.&nbsp;</li><li>A component in your network connection prevents Exodus from accessing the content you desire.&nbsp;</li></ul>



<p>Here&#8217;s how to fix these issues.</p>



<h4>Check Video Availability and Network Connection</h4>



<p>You may encounter this error when accessing geo-restricted content on Kodi.&nbsp;</p>



<p>To fix it:</p>



<ol><li>Conduct a free online speed test (fast.com is a great alternative) to check if your ISP has throttled your connection.&nbsp;</li><li>Compare the internet speed when not connected to a VPN with the speed when connected.&nbsp;</li><li>Reboot your device, relaunch Kodi and then search for the video once again.&nbsp;</li></ol>



<h4>Update Your Exodus Redux Version</h4>



<p>Check the Exodus Redux repository to ensure you have the latest version. If your version is outdated, install the latest, and restart Kodi.</p>



<h4>Clear Cache and Excess Data</h4>



<p>Accumulated cache causes streams to lag, leading to the &#8216;No Stream Available&#8217; error. You can easily clear cache data by heading over to the Tools section then clicking on Clear Cache or Clear Providers.</p>



<h4>Check the Providers&#8217; Timeout Option</h4>



<p>Each provider has a timeout option that displays the &#8216;No Stream Available&#8217; error if the video you are trying to watch does not load within a stipulated time. If your internet is slow and you want to access High Definition content, it would be best to alter the timeout speed to 60 seconds.</p>



<h4>Invest In a Great VPN</h4>



<p>Attempting to access geo-restricted content could cause the &#8216;No Streams Available&#8217; error. In such cases, either your ISP or the government has blocked the content you&#8217;re trying to access. A VPN helps bypass such restrictions by masking your IP address.&nbsp;</p>



<h3>Video Cannot Play&nbsp;</h3>



<p>This error appears when you attempt to load a video that’s too large or corrupted.</p>



<p>Whenever the Exodus Redux detects that the video you want to play is corrupted, it will automatically stop streaming and display the &#8216;Video Cannot Play&#8217; error. In this case, all you need to do is choose an alternative link.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The error might also appear because of playback problems, missing frames, audio-video syncing errors, misplaced subtitles, etc. When that happens, you will need to perform an advanced video repair.</p>



<p>To do this, upload the problematic video on video repairing apps such as Wondershare Repairit video repair.</p>



<h3>Change the Video Playback Quality</h3>



<p>You will most likely encounter this error if the video you are trying to access is of High Definition, yet your internet speed is slow. To fix this, change the video quality from settings or choose a video with a lower resolution. You have three options to choose from; Ultra High Definition (4K), High Definition (HD), and Standard Definition.&nbsp;</p>



<p>It is worth noting that the Exodus Redux is legal, but streaming prohibited, geo-restricted, or copyrighted material can still land you in trouble with the authorities. For this reason, it is imperative to connect to a VPN to hide your IP address.&nbsp;</p>



<h2>The difference between Exodus Redux and Exodus V8&nbsp;</h2>



<p>Exodus V8 was discontinued in 2018 and is not available on Kodi anymore. Exodus Redux is a fork of the original Exodus; an independent developer created it hoping to revive the original Exodus V8 addon.&nbsp;</p>



<h2>Frequently Asked Questions About Exodus Redux&nbsp;</h2>



<h3>Does Exodus Redux Work on the Amazon Fire Stick?</h3>



<p>Yes, Exodus Redux works on all Kodi-compatible devices.</p>



<h3>Does Exodus Redux Still Work In 2021?</h3>



<p>Yes, but it doesn&#8217;t work with the latest Kodi version.&nbsp;</p>



<h3>Can I Download Content on the Exodus Redux Platform?</h3>



<p>Yes, you can, but you&#8217;ll first need to enable downloads from Kodi settings.</p>



<h3>Is Exodus Redux Free?</h3>



<p>Yes, it is free.&nbsp;</p>



<h3>Do I Need A VPN to Use Exodus?</h3>



<p>Not really, but using a VPN will protect your privacy and reduce your bandwidth by 50%, which in return improves the content quality.</p>



<h3>How Do I Update Exodus Redux?</h3>



<p>On Kodi’s homepage, click Addons on the left menu, and then click Update on the addon information page.&nbsp;</p>



<h2>Conclusion</h2>



<p>Exodus Redux is slowly reclaiming its predecessor&#8217;s position as one of the best Kodi entertainment addons. It comes equipped with open scrappers that guarantee high-quality links in seconds, an easy-to-use interface, and a vast content library.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prooffreader.com/exodus-redux-install">How to Install Exodus Redux &#038; Exodus Kodi Addon</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prooffreader.com">ProoFFreader</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Venom Kodi Addon &#124; Install &#038; Use</title>
		<link>https://www.prooffreader.com/venom-kodi-addon/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[David]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 16 Oct 2021 13:42:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.prooffreader.com/?p=1236</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Venom is an improved and compact fork of the popular Exodus Kodi add-on. This add-on has become the go-to option ... </p>
<p class="read-more-container"><a title="Venom Kodi Addon &#124; Install &#038; Use" class="read-more button" href="https://www.prooffreader.com/venom-kodi-addon/#more-1236" aria-label="More on Venom Kodi Addon &#124; Install &#038; Use">Read more</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prooffreader.com/venom-kodi-addon/">Venom Kodi Addon | Install &#038; Use</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prooffreader.com">ProoFFreader</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Venom is an improved and compact fork of the popular Exodus Kodi add-on. This add-on has become the go-to option for many media content enthusiasts because of its many high-quality features, including Trakt.tv support, library integration, Youtube section, Debrid cloud manager, among others.</p>



<h2>General Description + Features</h2>



<p>One of the most outstanding features of the Venom add-on is the auto-play feature. Instead of manually clicking on a link to play a video when you add a movie or TV show title, this feature selects the link with the highest quality and automatically plays it from the link&#8217;s source.</p>



<p>For Venom to work correctly, you will need a premium Real Debrid, All Debrid, or Premiumize account. Using any of these premium accounts lets you access high-quality content from various servers and cached-torrents.</p>



<p>Cached torrent support ensures that your Real-Debrid or Premiumize account stores media content from torrent files in a primary location, allowing you access anytime. Real-debrid integration also helps you download content better and faster while avoiding buffering issues when streaming content.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Here is a list of the add-on&#8217;s menu options:</p>



<ul><li>Discover TV Shows</li><li>My Movies</li><li>My TV Shows</li><li>YouTube Videos</li><li>Search</li><li>Tools</li><li>Premium Services</li><li>News and Info</li><li>Change Log</li><li>Music TV and Videos</li><li>Fringe TV</li><li>Recommended section</li><li>Real Debrid integration</li><li>Trakt.TV integration</li><li>Live TV Channels</li><li>Up next function</li><li>Kids TV</li><li>Library integration</li><li>Debrid cloud manager</li></ul>



<h2>Advantages of Venom</h2>



<p>Here are some of the reasons you&#8217;ll love the Venom add-on:</p>



<ul><li>Simple interface that helps users load and search content quickly.</li><li>Easy-to-navigate menu </li><li>Kodi 19 Matrix and Kodi 18 Leia compatible</li><li>Add-ons&#8217; latest update removes its redundant features, reducing bloat and improving functionality.</li><li>Access to Open Scrapers, a scraper that sources and plays high-quality links.</li><li>Supports cached torrents.</li></ul>



<pre class="wp-block-preformatted has-pale-ocean-gradient-background has-background" style="font-size:18px"><strong>How Not To F*ck Up Your Kodi Experience:</strong> Streaming movies and TV shows on any of the 3rd party Kodi-addons may be illegal in your country due to copyright issues. 

Consider using a VPN if you truly care about protecting your online privacy.

<strong>Here are the key benefits of hiding your IP (using VPN):</strong>

1) Encrypts your internet traffic.
2) You can access Geo-restricted content.
3) You can avoid ISP throttling.
4) You can avoid unwanted surveillance by government agencies and ISPs.
5) You can protect yourself from hackers.

Connect VPN on all of your streaming devices (iOS, Windows, Android, Amazon Fire TV, etc.) and enjoy worry-free &amp; high-speed movie experience 24/7.

<strong>The Most Popular VPN Providers Among Kodi Users Are:</strong>

1) <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="http://www.prooffreader.com/recommends/cyberghostvpn/" target="_blank"><strong>Get CyberGhost</strong></a> - 45-Day Money-Back Guarantee
2) <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="http://www.prooffreader.com/recommends/expressvpn/" target="_blank"><strong>Get ExpressVPN</strong></a> - 30-Day Money-Back Guarantee
3) <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="http://www.prooffreader.com/recommends/privatevpn/" target="_blank"><strong>Get</strong> <strong>PrivateVPN</strong></a> - 30-Day Money-Back Guarantee</pre>



<h2>Compatibility</h2>



<p>Venom is compatible with all major operating systems, including Android, Windows, Linux, Mac OS, and iOS; for this reason, you can stream and view your favorite content effortlessly across all devices.</p>



<p>This add-on&#8217;s recent update also makes it fully compatible with Kodi 19 Matrix and Kodi 18 Leia.</p>



<h2>Installation Prerequisites</h2>



<p>As earlier noted, Venom is compatible with all major platforms, which makes installation easy and convenient. Unfortunately, like other third-party add-ons, Venom is unavailable in the official Kodi repository.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You, therefore, need to set your device to <strong>allow installation from unknown sources</strong> to complete Venom installation.</p>



<p>In summary, here are the steps to follow to install venom:&nbsp;</p>



<ul><li>Enable unknown sources.</li><li>Add media source.</li><li>Install Venom add-on from the repository.</li></ul>



<p>Before you begin the installation, ensure you have the latest versions of both the add-on and Kodi to avoid installation failures and errors.</p>



<p>That said, here&#8217;s the location and repository info you need for this process to work:&nbsp;</p>



<ol><li>Name of the Add-on: Venom</li><li>Repository Name: Venom Repo</li><li>Category: Media sources</li><li>Media source naming: Venom</li><li>Latest working source URL: <a href="https://123venom.github.io/">https://123venom.github.io/</a></li></ol>



<h2>Installation Guide</h2>



<h3><strong>First Things First – Enable Installation From Unknown Sources</strong></h3>



<p>Go to Home Screen, click on the gear icon, click on system, select “add-ons” on the left side menu, allow installation from “Unknown Sources”, click “yes” when the warning popup appears.&nbsp;</p>



<h3><strong>Installing Venom Repository</strong></h3>



<ol><li>Go to Home Screen, click on Gear Icon, click on File Manager;</li><li>Click Add Source, Click None, Type in the URL <strong>“<strong>http://123venom.github.io</strong>”</strong> and click Done;</li><li>Pick a name for the repository (i.e. Venom) and enter it in the bottom box and click OK;</li><li>Click back until you are in the Main Menu, select Addons on the left side; </li><li>Click on the Box Symbol (top left corner), Choose Install From ZIP file, click Yes when a warning appears;</li><li>Open “<strong>Venom</strong>” Source and choose this file: <strong>“<strong>repository.venom-x.x.zip</strong>”</strong></li><li>A notification saying “Installed Successfully” will appear.</li></ol>



<h3><strong>Installing Venom Kodi Addon</strong></h3>



<ol><li>Go to Home Screen, find Add-ons on the left side, select the box symbol (top left corner) to get to the Addon Browser;</li><li>Click on Install From Repository, choose <strong>Venom Repository</strong>, click on Video Addons in the category section;</li><li>Click on Venom and hit install, select OK to confirm the installation of dependencies (don’t appear in Kodi 19 Matrix);</li><li>A notification saying “Installed Successfully” will appear;</li><li>You have now downloaded Venom to Kodi. You can now access the addon from the main menu. </li></ol>



<h2>Alternative add-ons</h2>



<p>There are several Kodi add-ons similar to Venom in terms of features and ease of navigation. Below are some of the best alternatives to choose from:</p>



<p><strong>The Crew </strong>add-on only became compatible with Kodi 19 matrix recently. It has various content categories, including movies, TV shows, Sports, IPTV, Kids, 1-Clicks, CC-Collections, Radio, Standup Comedy, and more.</p>



<p><strong>Seren 2.0 </strong>is an excellent Venom alternative. Seren is popular for its innovative features like the back-to-back episode playing option, its smooth interface, and cached torrent support.</p>



<p><strong>Asgard</strong> is one of the most popular Kodi add-ons out there. It has a great user interface and also features a variety of content for a better streaming experience.</p>



<h2>Common Issues With Venom</h2>



<p>Sometimes, you may face several challenges while installing or using add-ons like Venom. Here are some of the problems you may encounter with Venom and their most effective solutions:</p>



<h3>Venom &#8216;Failed to Install Dependency Error&#8217;</h3>



<p>The most common reason for this error is internet failure or shutting down of the repository. If the repository you are using to install Venom is not working, the add-on will still appear on the list of add-ons on your device.</p>



<p>But when you proceed to install it, an &#8216;Installation Failed&#8217; error message will appear on the screen. Here are some of the best ways to fix this problem:</p>



<h4>Check Your Internet Connection</h4>



<p>A good internet connection is required to install any add-ons that have online hosts. So before you begin installing Venom, ensure you set up Kodi network settings correctly. Also, check the speed and stability of the device&#8217;s internet connection.&nbsp;</p>



<h4>Enable Unknown Sources on the Device</h4>



<p>For security reasons, many streaming devices automatically default to blocking app installation from third-party sources. Therefore, to properly install the Venom add-on on Kodi, other than enabling unknown sources, you need to enable the unknown sources feature on your streaming device, too; otherwise, the installation will fail.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You can find this option in your device&#8217;s Settings menu.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<h4>Use the Official Repository</h4>



<p>While Venom is available on many repositories, only a few of these will work correctly. Most will bring up the &#8216;Failed To Install Dependency&#8217; error when you try to install.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Other unofficial repositories have add-ons with viruses that you may accidentally install. As a result, it&#8217;s advisable to install Venom from the official repository, which is safe, to avoid these unnecessary risks and installation failure errors.</p>



<h4>Install the Latest Version of Venom Add-On</h4>



<p>Kodi can&#8217;t install an outdated version of Venom. To fix this problem, install the add-on&#8217;s latest working version available from the official repository.</p>



<h3>Venom Error Check Log</h3>



<p>&#8216;Check Log&#8217; error is another major problem you may encounter when trying to install Venom. This error mainly appears when the repository you are using to install the add-on has missing files. However, having a full cache can also cause an Error Check Log.</p>



<p>Here are a few quick fixes for this problem:</p>



<h4>Clear Kodi Cache</h4>



<p>As earlier mentioned, a cache is a temporary spot that saves data you frequently use for easy access in the future. However, all add-ons, including Venom, only require a certain amount of data.&nbsp;</p>



<h4>Updating the URL Resolver</h4>



<p>Exceeding this set amount usually will prompt the &#8216;Error Check Log&#8217; message and also cause buffering. But clearing the Kodi cache frees up necessary space, eventually fixing the error. It also allows Venom to have room for a video playback buffer, giving you an excellent streaming performance.</p>



<p>URL Resolver is one of Kodi&#8217;s fundamental content streaming tools. Almost all add-ons, including Venom, function with the help of URL resolvers. A URL resolver is a tool that scrapes links from different sources on the internet and decodes file hosts when you click on a streaming link to play a video. Therefore, an outdated URL resolver may lead to a &#8216;Check Log&#8217; Error.</p>



<p>URL resolver currently has torrent and magnet link support for Premiumize and Real Debrid, meaning you automatically receive the latest version when installing the Venom add-on. But if you still see the &#8216;Check The Log For More Information&#8217; error even with the latest Venom add-on version, manually updating the URL resolver may be necessary.</p>



<h4>Use a VPN</h4>



<p>If you still receive the error after clearing cache and updating your URL Resolver, it may be because you are trying to access geo-restricted or copyrighted content. This error may also appear when your Internet Service Provider blocks a source for copyright infringement.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Connecting to a VPN lets you bypass any geo-restrictions and ISP blocks. This way, you can stream content anonymously and securely.&nbsp;</p>



<h3>Venom &#8216;No Stream Available Error&#8217;</h3>



<p>You may also notice a &#8216;No Streams Available&#8217; error when you launch Venom, search for a movie or TV show. This error mainly occurs when the stream you&#8217;re looking for is new, thus unavailable or when it&#8217;s too old for your web scrapers to grab.</p>



<p>Other times, Venom may fail to play content from the provider because of your network connectivity, firewall, or cache. Here are some of the best solutions to this problem:</p>



<h4>Clear Cache</h4>



<p>As earlier noted, clearing cache regularly is essential for the Venom add-on to function correctly. It&#8217;s also another way to keep your add-on running smoothly and removes any unnecessary clutter slowing down your device and add-on, leading to the &#8216;No Stream Available&#8217; error.&nbsp;</p>



<h4>Fix Any Network Problems</h4>



<p>Network interference can sometimes cause a &#8216;No Streams Available&#8217; error. The good news is that network problems are generally easy to fix. First, unplug your router from its power source, and wait for a few minutes then plug it back in. This usually solves any connection issue.</p>



<p>If the problem persists, increase your internet timeout from Kodi settings. Timeout adjustment is an excellent solution to the &#8216;No Stream Available&#8217; error, especially when your internet speed is decent but your device isn&#8217;t streaming or downloading fast enough. Still, it&#8217;s essential to test your internet speed before adjusting the timeout just in case speed is the problem.</p>



<h2>Frequently Asked Questions (FAQs)</h2>



<h3>Do I Need a Real-Debrid Account To Use Venom?</h3>



<p>Yes, because Venom&#8217;s recent updates lock out free sources.</p>



<h3>Do I Need a VPN To Use Venom?</h3>



<p>While using a VPN secures your data and maintains your privacy, a VPN is not always necessary when using the Venom add-on. Premium accounts like Real-Debrid encrypt your internet traffic in HTTPS, ensuring privacy.</p>



<h3>Is It Safe To Use Cached Torrents With the Venom Add-On?</h3>



<p>Yes, accessing cached files with this add-on is safe. Premium account integration means that you download and store files on your debrid service provider&#8217;s server using the HTTPS encryption protocol.&nbsp;</p>



<h3>Is the Venom Add-On Legal?</h3>



<p>Yes, using the Venom add-on itself is safe and legal. Using Venom to stream copyrighted content that is otherwise not freely available is, however, illegal.</p>



<h2>Conclusion</h2>



<p>Overall, Venom is an excellent entertainment add-on with a simple yet beautiful user interface. Besides, its Real-Debrid integration makes it a top choice for any media content enthusiast keen on variety and high-quality streaming.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prooffreader.com/venom-kodi-addon/">Venom Kodi Addon | Install &#038; Use</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prooffreader.com">ProoFFreader</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Chaturbate Kodi Add-on &#124; Install &#038; Use</title>
		<link>https://www.prooffreader.com/chaturbate-kodi-addon/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[David]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 16 Oct 2021 13:32:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Kodi]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.prooffreader.com/?p=1230</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Chaturbate is a Kodi video addon for streaming adult content. This addon has a simple user interface, allowing you to ... </p>
<p class="read-more-container"><a title="Chaturbate Kodi Add-on &#124; Install &#038; Use" class="read-more button" href="https://www.prooffreader.com/chaturbate-kodi-addon/#more-1230" aria-label="More on Chaturbate Kodi Add-on &#124; Install &#038; Use">Read more</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prooffreader.com/chaturbate-kodi-addon/">Chaturbate Kodi Add-on | Install &#038; Use</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prooffreader.com">ProoFFreader</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Chaturbate is a Kodi video addon for streaming adult content. This addon has a simple user interface, allowing you to search adult content according to categories, tags and also create a password to keep the addon private.</p>



<p>You can install this addon from the Kodimans Public Repository.&nbsp;</p>



<h2>Chaturbate Kodi Addon Sections</h2>



<p>The sections in this addon include:</p>



<ul><li>Category</li><li>Tags</li><li>Favorite</li><li>Records</li></ul>



<p>Sub-sections under Categories include:&nbsp;</p>



<ul><li>Featured</li><li>Females</li><li>Males</li><li>Couples</li><li>Transsexual</li><li>Parental Controls</li></ul>



<pre class="wp-block-preformatted has-pale-ocean-gradient-background has-background" style="font-size:18px"><strong>How Not To F*ck Up Your Kodi Experience:</strong> Streaming movies and TV shows on any of the 3rd party Kodi-addons may be illegal in your country due to copyright issues. 

Consider using a VPN if you truly care about protecting your online privacy.

<strong>Here are the key benefits of hiding your IP (using VPN):</strong>

1) Encrypts your internet traffic.
2) You can access Geo-restricted content.
3) You can avoid ISP throttling.
4) You can avoid unwanted surveillance by government agencies and ISPs.
5) You can protect yourself from hackers.

Connect VPN on all of your streaming devices (iOS, Windows, Android, Amazon Fire TV, etc.) and enjoy worry-free &amp; high-speed movie experience 24/7.

<strong>The Most Popular VPN Providers Among Kodi Users Are:</strong>

1) <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="http://www.prooffreader.com/recommends/cyberghostvpn/" target="_blank"><strong>Get CyberGhost</strong></a> - 45-Day Money-Back Guarantee
2) <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="http://www.prooffreader.com/recommends/expressvpn/" target="_blank"><strong>Get ExpressVPN</strong></a> - 30-Day Money-Back Guarantee
3) <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="http://www.prooffreader.com/recommends/privatevpn/" target="_blank"><strong>Get</strong> <strong>PrivateVPN</strong></a> - 30-Day Money-Back Guarantee</pre>



<h2>Chaturbate Add-On Installation Prerequisites</h2>



<p>Given that the Kodimans Public is a third-party repository, it has been disabled by default. For this reason, you need to switch the settings to Enable Unknown Sources to install this addon.</p>



<h2>Chaturbate Addon Information</h2>



<ol><li>Name of the addon: Chaturbate</li><li>Repository name: Kodimans Public Repository</li><li>Category: Media sources</li><li>Media source name: Kodiman</li><li>Latest working URL:<a href="https://hsk.kodiman.net/hsk/hsk_gruppe/"> https://hsk.kodiman.net/hsk/hsk_gruppe/</a></li></ol>



<h2>Installation Guide</h2>



<h3><strong>First Things First – Enable Installation From Unknown Sources</strong></h3>



<p>Go to Home Screen, click on the gear icon, click on system, select “add-ons” on the left side menu, allow installation from “Unknown Sources”, click “yes” when the warning popup appears.&nbsp;</p>



<h3><strong>Installing HSK-DE Repository</strong></h3>



<ol><li>Go to Home Screen, click on Gear Icon, click on File Manager;</li><li>Click Add Source, Click None, Type in the URL&nbsp;<strong>“<strong>https://repo.guidos-skinbase.de/</strong>”</strong>&nbsp;and click Done;</li><li>Pick a name for the repository (i.e. HSK) and enter it in the bottom box and click OK;</li><li>Click back until you are in the Main Menu, select Addons on the left side;&nbsp;</li><li>Click on the Box Symbol (top left corner), Choose Install From ZIP file, click Yes when a warning appears;</li><li>Open “<strong>HSK</strong>” Source and choose this file:&nbsp;<strong>“<strong>repository.hsk.repo.19-x.x.xx.zip</strong>”</strong></li><li>A notification saying “Installed Successfully” will appear.</li></ol>



<h3><strong>Installing Chaturbate Kodi Addon</strong></h3>



<ol><li>Go to Home Screen, find Add-ons on the left side, select the box symbol (top left corner) to get to the Addon Browser;</li><li>Click on Install From Repository, choose <strong>HSK-DE Repository</strong>, click on Video Addons in the category section;</li><li>Click on Chaturbate and hit install, select OK to confirm the installation of dependencies (don’t appear in Kodi 19 Matrix);</li><li>A notification saying “Installed Successfully” will appear;</li><li>You have now downloaded Chaturbate to Kodi. You can now access the addon from the main menu.&nbsp;</li></ol>



<h2>Compatibility</h2>



<p>Chaturbate is compatible with Kodi 18 and 19. Like most Kodi addons, you can use it on your Fire TV Stick, Apple TV, Amazon Fire Stick, Android, Linux, Raspberry, Mac, IOS, Windows, among other devices.</p>



<h2>Alternative Addons</h2>



<p>Chaturbate is famous for webcams; however, if you wish to explore other categories of adult content such as movie scenes, video clips, and live streams, check out the following alternatives:</p>



<p><strong><a href="http://www.prooffreader.com/how-to-install-cumination-kodi-addon/">Cumination</a> </strong>addon delivers high-quality adult content, including video clips, live streams, and webcams. It is compatible with Kodi 18 and 19.</p>



<p><strong><a href="http://www.prooffreader.com/use-and-install-xxx-o-dus-kodi-addon/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">XXX-O-DUS</a> </strong>addon is a fork of the popular <a href="http://www.prooffreader.com/exodus-redux-install" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Exodus Kodi addon</a>. It delivers purely adult content, pulling quality links from popular porn sites such as RedTube, PornHub, and xHamster, among others. XXX-O-DUS works with both Kodi 18 Leia and 19 Matrix.</p>



<p><strong><a href="http://www.prooffreader.com/videodevil-kodi-addon/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">VideoDevil </a></strong>add-on delivers thousands of adult videos and lets you choose your preferences and the video quality. It pulls streams from over 40 adult sites such as xVideos, XNXX, and RedTube. VideoDevil is compatible with Kodi 18 Leia and 19 Matrix.</p>



<h2>Common Issues with Chaturbate Addon</h2>



<p>You may experience some problems when using Chaturbate. Here are some of the common issues and how to solve them:</p>



<h3>Chaturbate Addon Fails To Launch</h3>



<p>The problem of Chaturbate failing to launch occurs because of two reasons, as explained below.</p>



<h3>Accumulation Of Cache</h3>



<p>The Kodi app, addons, and your devices accumulate cache as you stream content. When this cache builds up over time, it may prevent certain addons from launching.&nbsp;</p>



<h4>How To Clear Cache on Kodi</h4>



<p>You have two options to clear the cache on the addon. First, head over to the Settings menu on Kodi and click on Clear Cache.</p>



<p>The other option is using Kodi maintenance tools such as SG Wizard. The latter clears the cache and accumulated data across all Kodi-connected devices.</p>



<h3>Incorrect Proxy Settings</h3>



<p>To stream content on Kodi without interruption, your device&#8217;s port number and proxy servers should match those of the network. If the proxy settings do not match, Chaturbate may fail to launch.</p>



<p>Here&#8217;s how to solve this problem:&nbsp;</p>



<p>Simply match your network&#8217;s port number and proxy servers to those of your device, then restart Kodi.</p>



<h3>Chaturbate Addon Shows the &#8216;No Stream Available&#8217; Error</h3>



<p>When you search for content on Chaturbate, Kodi scrapers roam the internet, searching for links from sites with such content. Upon tracing a matching link, the scrapers avail the link to you to play or download. Unfortunately, sometimes the scrapers fail to return links, displaying the &#8216;No Streams Available&#8217; error instead.</p>



<p>The following are the probable causes of this error:</p>



<ul><li>Restricted access to content by Internet Service Provider.&nbsp;</li><li>Buildup of video cache.</li><li>Outdated version of Chaturbate.&nbsp;</li><li>Weak internet connection.&nbsp;</li><li>Unavailable content.&nbsp;</li><li>Disabled Kodi providers.</li></ul>



<h3>Chaturbate ‘No Stream Available&#8217; Error Solved&nbsp;</h3>



<p>Here&#8217;s how to solve the &#8216;No Stream Available&#8217; error on Chaturbate:&nbsp;</p>



<h4>Use a VPN</h4>



<p>Chaturbate fetches links from adult content websites. These sites, especially the live stream and webcam sites, consume a lot of data, which prompts ISPs to restrict access to such sites. To bypass these restrictions, consider investing in a premium VPN.</p>



<h4>Clear All Cache</h4>



<p>Too much cache affects the performance of Kodi addons. Clear the cache and check if it fixes the error.</p>



<h4>Update the Addon</h4>



<p>Using an outdated addon can cause the &#8216;No Stream Available&#8217; error on Kodi. To avoid this, constantly update the Chaturbate addon as soon as the developer releases a newer version.&nbsp;</p>



<h4>Fix Your Internet Connection</h4>



<p>A slow or weak internet connection interrupts the data path between Kodi&#8217;s servers and the internet servers. For instance, slow internet will have your search request timed out. In addition, a broken internet connection interrupts Kodi scrapers, returning no links.</p>



<p>The first thing you need to do is establish if your connection buffers only on Kodi or other apps. To test your connection, open another application on your device, such as Netflix or YouTube. If the connection is also slow on these apps, consider the following:&nbsp;</p>



<ul><li>Disconnect your router from the power outlet and leave it for a few minutes, then reconnect it.</li><li>Turn off the modem and remove the service card, re-insert it, and then turn on the modem.&nbsp;</li></ul>



<p>After restoring your connection, restart Kodi and check if the error persists.</p>



<h4>Enable All Kodi Providers</h4>



<p>In most cases, Kodi addons share the same providers. For this reason, make sure all your Kodi providers are enabled.</p>



<h3>Chaturbate Fails To Play Links</h3>



<p>This problem occurs when your URLResolver is broken, or your playback has been set to &#8216;autoplay.&#8217;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Here&#8217;s what to do to fix this error:&nbsp;</p>



<ul><li>Troubleshoot your URLResolver by disabling it, restarting the Kodi app, and enabling it again.</li><li>Change your playback settings to Source Select. If the first link fails to play, you simply move on to the next until you find one that works.&nbsp;</li></ul>



<h3>Chaturbate Addon Says, &#8216;To Play This Video, Streaming Authorization Is Required&#8217;</h3>



<p>This error is common with adult content sites that use content links as advertisement baits. You can also encounter this error when you sign in to Kodi on a new device.</p>



<p>To solve this error, use a static IP address. This kind of IP address is specific to your Kodi-connected devices. When you sign in to Kodi using this IP address, the hoster sites save your login credentials. Then, the hoster sites automatically allow access to content even if you sign in with a different device.</p>



<h3>Chaturbate Addon Shows the &#8216;Failed To Install a Dependency&#8217; Error</h3>



<p>You can narrow down this error to two possible causes:</p>



<ul><li>Buildup of cache</li><li>Failure to install supportive files.&nbsp;</li></ul>



<p>Here&#8217;s how to solve the &#8216;Failed To Install a Dependency&#8217; error:&nbsp;</p>



<ul><li>Clear Kodi cache.</li><li>Uninstall the Chaturbate addon, then install it afresh.</li></ul>



<h3>Chaturbate Addon Shows the &#8220;Dependencies Could Not Be Satisfied&#8221; Error</h3>



<p>This error occurs when the Chaturbate addon&#8217;s python code is incompatible with that of the Kodi version. This can happen when you update the addon but continue using the older version of Kodi—for instance, using a Kodi-19-specific addon on Kodi 18.</p>



<p>To solve this error, ensure your Kodi version is compatible with the addon version.</p>



<h3>Chaturbate Addon Shows the &#8216;Check the Log for More Information&#8217; Error</h3>



<p>This error occurs due to any of the following reasons:</p>



<ul><li>Incorrect installation of the addon.</li><li>Accumulation of Kodi cache.</li><li>Faulty internet connection.</li></ul>



<p>Here&#8217;s what to do to fix this error:&nbsp;</p>



<ul><li>Clear the Kodi cache.</li><li>Troubleshoot your internet connection.</li><li>Uninstall and reinstall the addon.&nbsp;</li></ul>



<h2>Frequently Asked Questions About Chaturbate Kodi Addon&nbsp;</h2>



<h3>Is Chaturbate Kodi Addon Legal?</h3>



<p>Yes, it is completely legal.&nbsp;</p>



<h3>Is Chaturbate Kodi Addon Free?</h3>



<p>Yes, this addon provides free links.</p>



<h3>Do I Need a VPN With the Chaturbate Kodi Addon?</h3>



<p>A VPN is essential when streaming adult content. It will help you bypass site restrictions, mask your original IP address and keep your online traffic private.</p>



<h3>Does the Chaturbate Kodi Addon Still Work in 2021?</h3>



<p>Yes, it does.</p>



<h2>Conclusion</h2>



<p>To recap, Chaturbate is one of the best free adult content addons on Kodi. Furthermore, it provides the content in different categories, allowing the user to choose one that suits their desires.&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prooffreader.com/chaturbate-kodi-addon/">Chaturbate Kodi Add-on | Install &#038; Use</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prooffreader.com">ProoFFreader</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How To Install Castaway Kodi Add-on</title>
		<link>https://www.prooffreader.com/how-to-install-castaway-kodi-add-on/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[James Austin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 30 Sep 2021 18:51:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Kodi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.prooffreader.com/?p=1223</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The Castaway Kodi addon is popular for streaming live sporting events, such as the English Premier League and college football. ... </p>
<p class="read-more-container"><a title="How To Install Castaway Kodi Add-on" class="read-more button" href="https://www.prooffreader.com/how-to-install-castaway-kodi-add-on/#more-1223" aria-label="More on How To Install Castaway Kodi Add-on">Read more</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prooffreader.com/how-to-install-castaway-kodi-add-on/">How To Install Castaway Kodi Add-on</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prooffreader.com">ProoFFreader</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The Castaway Kodi addon is popular for streaming live sporting events, such as the English Premier League and college football. This addon comes with different categories, airing Tennis, Basketball, Baseball, Hockey, and many more.</p>



<h2>General Features and Functionality</h2>



<p>One of the most outstanding qualities of the Castaway addon is that it uses peer-to-peer (P2P) technology, or what is currently referred to as torrenting. Unlike other conventional Kodi addons that use link scrappers, the Castaway P2P technique enables users to upload, download or stream content from an online host.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Uploading the content means that content will remain in circulation even if the hosting server is down or offline.</p>



<p>With traditional link scrapping Kodi addons, there are times when online hosts shut down due to high traffic. When servers are down, much of the content they host is unavailable to users. But this doesn&#8217;t usually happen with P2P Kodi addons like Castaway because of the content uploading and sharing factor.</p>



<p>Another advantage of Castaway compared to other link-scrapping Kodi addons is that when streaming using this addon, the content is partially downloaded to minimize video lagging and buffering for a better streaming experience. Castaway also allows you to download content from multiple sources for offline viewing.</p>



<p>Castaway Kodi addon menu options include:</p>



<p><strong>Live Sports </strong>features several streaming options covering soccer, NFL, basketball, baseball, and more.</p>



<p><strong>Live TV </strong>has a vast selection of broadcast TV channel sources. It is also divided into multiple sub-categories for easier browsing and channel selection.</p>



<p><strong>P2P Corne</strong> streams live sports from the source or downloads it directly to your Kodi device.</p>



<p><strong>Sports on Demand </strong>is a dedicated section for sports archives. It includes sports such as American football, hockey, basketball, soccer, and more.</p>



<p><strong>Subreddits</strong> are forums following a specific topic on the popular social media platform Reddit. For example, you can add an American football subreddit that shares game highlights, high scores, and live games.</p>



<h2>Compatibility</h2>



<p>The Castaway addon works well with all major platforms. They include:&nbsp;</p>



<ul><li>Android</li><li>Windows</li><li>Linux</li><li>Mac OS</li><li>iOS</li></ul>



<p>Unfortunately, the Castaway addon is currently incompatible with Kodi 19 Matrix but works well with Kodi 18 Leia and Kodi 17.</p>



<h2>Installation Prerequisites</h2>



<p>You need to allow installation from unknown sources from Kodi settings. This step is necessary because Castaway is not available in the official Kodi repository, given that it is a third-party addon.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Next, ensure you have the URL to the official Castaway addon repository, Super Repo.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Remember, it&#8217;s best to use the repository with the addon&#8217;s latest version when installing Castaway. This makes the installation process easier and gives you access to the newest features.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Finally, integrate your addon with a premium account like Real-Debrid or Premiumize to upgrade your link sources.</p>



<p>In summary, follow the steps below to install the Castaway addon:</p>



<ul><li>Enable unknown sources.</li><li>Add a media source.</li><li>Install Castaway addon from the repository.</li></ul>



<p>Here&#8217;s the repository information you need for proper installation:</p>



<ol><li>Name of the Add-on: Castaway addon</li><li>Repository name: Super Repo</li><li>Category: Video sources</li><li>Media source naming: Castaway</li><li>The latest working source URL:  <a href="http://srp.nu/">http://srp.nu/</a></li></ol>



<pre class="wp-block-preformatted has-pale-ocean-gradient-background has-background" style="font-size:18px"><strong>How Not To F*ck Up Your Kodi Experience:</strong> Streaming movies and TV shows on any of the 3rd party Kodi-addons may be illegal in your country due to copyright issues. 

Consider using a VPN if you truly care about protecting your online privacy.

<strong>Here are the key benefits of hiding your IP (using VPN):</strong>

1) Encrypts your internet traffic.
2) You can access Geo-restricted content.
3) You can avoid ISP throttling.
4) You can avoid unwanted surveillance by government agencies and ISPs.
5) You can protect yourself from hackers.

Connect VPN on all of your streaming devices (iOS, Windows, Android, Amazon Fire TV, etc.) and enjoy worry-free &amp; high-speed movie experience 24/7.

<strong>The Most Popular VPN Providers Among Kodi Users Are:</strong>

1) <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="http://www.prooffreader.com/recommends/cyberghostvpn/" target="_blank"><strong>Get CyberGhost</strong></a> - 45-Day Money-Back Guarantee
2) <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="http://www.prooffreader.com/recommends/expressvpn/" target="_blank"><strong>Get ExpressVPN</strong></a> - 30-Day Money-Back Guarantee
3) <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="http://www.prooffreader.com/recommends/privatevpn/" target="_blank"><strong>Get</strong> <strong>PrivateVPN</strong></a> - 30-Day Money-Back Guarantee</pre>



<h2>Installation Guide</h2>



<h3><strong>First Things First – Enable Installation From Unknown Sources</strong></h3>



<p>Go to Home Screen, click on the gear icon, click on system, select “add-ons” on the left side menu, allow installation from “Unknown Sources”, click “yes” when the warning popup appears.&nbsp;</p>



<h3><strong>Installing Super Repository</strong></h3>



<ol><li>Go to Home Screen, click on Gear Icon, click on File Manager;</li><li>Click Add Source, Click None, Type in the URL <strong>&#8220;<strong>http://srp.nu/</strong>”</strong> and click Done;</li><li>Pick a name for the repository (i.e. Super) and enter it in the bottom box and click OK;</li><li>Click back until you are in the Main Menu, select Addons on the left side; </li><li>Click on the Box Symbol (top left corner), Choose Install From ZIP file, click Yes when a warning appears;</li><li>Open “Alfa” Source and choose this file: <strong>“<strong>superrepo.kodi.krypton.all-0.7.04.zip</strong>”</strong></li><li>A notification saying “Installed Successfully” will appear.</li></ol>



<h3><strong>Installing Castaway Kodi Addon</strong></h3>



<ol><li>Go to Home Screen, find Add-ons on the left side, select the box symbol (top left corner) to get to the Addon Browser;</li><li>Click on Install From Repository, choose Super Addon Repo, click on Video Addons in the category section;</li><li>Click on Castaway and hit install, select OK to confirm the installation of dependencies (don’t appear in Kodi 19 Matrix);</li><li>A notification saying “Installed Successfully” will appear;</li><li>You have now downloaded Castaway to Kodi. You can now access the addon from the main menu. </li></ol>



<h2>Alternative Addons</h2>



<p>As earlier mentioned, Castaway is not compatible with the latest Kodi version, Kodi 19 Matrix. Fortunately, several alternative addons work great on Kodi 19.&nbsp;</p>



<ul><li><strong>SportsDevil </strong>is one of the best Kodi sports addons. It comes with great features and a high-quality live sports stream. Besides, the SportsDevil addon offers a well-categorized menu that is easy to navigate and a vast library of sports content worldwide.<br></li><li><strong>Apex Sports</strong> is a new Kodi addon from the Arctic-ape repository. This addon comes with a wide selection of sports replays, live sports events, and highlights from more than a dozen popular sports websites. Apex Sports works well with Kodi 19 Matrix and Kodi 18 Leia.<br></li><li><strong>Q Sports</strong> features a massive library of sports content with Live Sports, Soccer Streams, Sports Bay, Roja Direct, US TV Go, and many more.</li></ul>



<h2>Common Issues With Castaway Addon</h2>



<p>Here are some of the most common issues you may encounter with the Castaway addon and how to solve them:</p>



<h3>Castaway Installation Failure</h3>



<p>This error occurs when you attempt to install the addon from unofficial repositories, or your internet connection is unstable. Luckily, the problem of installation failure is easy to diagnose and solve, as explained below.</p>



<h3>Use the Official Repository</h3>



<p>The Castaway addon is available on various repositories, which makes it easy to access and install. Unfortunately, using most of these repositories to install this addon will likely lead to installation failure because unofficial repositories do not contain the latest working version of the Castaway addon.</p>



<p>In this case, the best solution is to install Castaway from Super Repo.</p>



<h3>Check Your Internet Connection</h3>



<p>Fast and stable internet is a necessity when installing any addon like Castaway with an online host. If you are encountering addon installation failure, check to see if your internet connection is stable.</p>



<p>If you establish that the installation failure is due to a slow connection, unplug your router, then wait for a few minutes before plugging it in. Then, you can proceed with the Castaway addon installation when the connection is stable.</p>



<h3>Castaway Error Check Log</h3>



<p>The &#8216;Error Check Log&#8217; occurs due to using a repository that has missing files or when you have a filled-up cache. In that case, here&#8217;s what to do:&nbsp;</p>



<h3>Clear Cache</h3>



<p>Cache is the temporary storage that saves online data you frequently use for easy access in the future. When you have more accumulated data within your addon than is necessary, your videos will take too long to load or fail play at all, causing the &#8216;Error Check Log.&#8217;</p>



<p>To clear cache, click on the addon&#8217;s Settings under the tools section, select Clear Cache, or use a maintenance tool like OpenWizard.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Clearing cache is also an excellent solution to any video buffering and lagging issues you may be experiencing with Castaway.</p>



<h3>Use a VPN</h3>



<p>It is also common to encounter the &#8216;Error Check Log&#8217; when streaming geo-restricted content or when your Internet Service Provider blocks a source. Connecting to a VPN is one of the best ways to circumvent geo-restrictions and ISP blocks.</p>



<p>A VPN is also a great way to browse anonymously while keeping your internet data secure.</p>



<h3>Update the URLResolver</h3>



<p>A URLResolver works in the background of an addon to decode any files requested by the addon into a format you can understand.</p>



<p>In most cases, you automatically receive the latest version of the URLResolver when installing the Castaway addon. But if you still notice an &#8216;Error Check Log&#8217; after clearing cache and using a VPN, you may need to update your URLResolver.</p>



<p>To download the latest URLResolver, go to <a href="https://github.com/">Github</a> and search for your addon&#8217;s URL resolver. After downloading and installing the URLResolver, relaunch the Castaway addon.&nbsp;</p>



<h3>Castaway &#8216;No Stream Available&#8217; Error</h3>



<p>The &#8216;No Stream Available&#8217; error occurs when the link to the content you are looking for is too old to grab or too recent, meaning it&#8217;s not yet available on the main online hosts. This error can also occur when you have a poor internet connection.</p>



<p>Here&#8217;s to solve the &#8216;No Stream Available&#8217; error on Castaway.&nbsp;</p>



<h4>Clear Cache</h4>



<p>In most cases, data accumulation on your addon leaves little room for video playback. When there is insufficient space for playback, videos take too long to load, resulting in the &#8216;No Stream Available&#8217; error.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Luckily, you only need to click on the Clear Cache option under your addon&#8217;s settings to fix this issue.</p>



<h4>Fix Any Network Problems</h4>



<p>Network interference can sometimes cause a &#8216;No Streams Available&#8217; error. To fix this problem, unplug your router from its power source, and wait for a few minutes to plug it back in.</p>



<h4>Adjust Your Timeout Settings</h4>



<p>Sometimes trying to stream large, high-quality video files can lead to the &#8216;No Stream Available&#8217; error. The best solution to this problem is to adjust the providers&#8217; timeout settings to at least 60 seconds, giving the addon enough time to load the content before being timed out.&nbsp;</p>



<h3>Castaway Cannot Connect to the Server</h3>



<p>This issue usually occurs due to a poor internet connection or the repository source moving to a new URL. To fix it, check if the repository URL is still online and works.&nbsp;</p>



<p>If the repository URL no longer works, use a different one to install the Castaway addon. After installing, relaunch the addon.</p>



<p>If the issue persists, check if your internet connection is stable enough. If unstable, unplug the router from the power outlet and then wait a few minutes before plugging it in.&nbsp;</p>



<h2>&nbsp;</h2>



<h2>Frequently Asked Questions About Castaway Kodi Addon&nbsp;</h2>



<h3>Do I Need a VPN To Use the Castaway Addon?</h3>



<p>It is advisable to use a VPN with third-party Kodi addons like Castaway. A VPN not only protects your privacy only, but also reduces bandwidth by 50%.&nbsp;</p>



<h3>Is the Castaway Kodi Addon Free?&nbsp;</h3>



<p>Yes, downloading and installing this addon is free.</p>



<h3>Is the Castaway Addon Legal?</h3>



<p>Yes, using the Castaway addon itself is safe and legal. But using Castaway to stream copyrighted content is illegal.&nbsp;</p>



<h3>Why Is Castaway Not Working?</h3>



<p>The problem of Castaway not working usually derives from different scenarios, as explained earlier in this article. Follow our troubleshooting tips to find the best solution to the specific problem.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<h2>Conclusion</h2>



<p>With Castaway&#8217;s great selection of sports channels and live sports options, it&#8217;s no surprise that this addon has been popular among sports fans for years. The addon&#8217;s P2P file-sharing technique is a game-changer. It provides the ultimate sports streaming experience, placing this addon ahead of many Kodi sports addons available in the market.&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prooffreader.com/how-to-install-castaway-kodi-add-on/">How To Install Castaway Kodi Add-on</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prooffreader.com">ProoFFreader</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How To Install Bubbles Kodi Addon &#124; All You Need To Know</title>
		<link>https://www.prooffreader.com/how-to-install-bubbles-kodi-addon</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Williams]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 18 Sep 2021 09:41:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Kodi]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.prooffreader.com/?p=1216</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Bubbles is an entertainment addon used to stream movies, TV shows, documentaries, and short films. The addon fetches links from ... </p>
<p class="read-more-container"><a title="How To Install Bubbles Kodi Addon &#124; All You Need To Know" class="read-more button" href="https://www.prooffreader.com/how-to-install-bubbles-kodi-addon#more-1216" aria-label="More on How To Install Bubbles Kodi Addon &#124; All You Need To Know">Read more</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prooffreader.com/how-to-install-bubbles-kodi-addon">How To Install Bubbles Kodi Addon | All You Need To Know</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prooffreader.com">ProoFFreader</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Bubbles is an entertainment addon used to stream movies, TV shows, documentaries, and short films. The addon fetches links from hoster sites, torrents, and Usenet service providers.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In addition, you can integrate it with your Premiumize or Real Debrid account to access high-quality links from the best hosting providers on the internet.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The addon has a relatively more complicated setup than most Kodi addons. Also, most of the free hoster sites the addon pulls links from don&#8217;t contain legal content. For this reason, there&#8217;s a high likelihood of streaming pirated content via this addon.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<h2>General Features and Functionality</h2>



<p>The addon works best when integrated with Premiumize. Some of its features include:&nbsp;</p>



<ul><li>Manual downloads.</li><li>Automatic local caching.</li><li>Lightpack control device.</li><li>Speed test.</li><li>Provider and account verification.</li></ul>



<h2>Advantages of the Bubbles Kodi Addon</h2>



<p>The Bubbles addon has several advantages over other Kodi entertainment addons as listed below:</p>



<ul><li>Supplies its own seeds, offering users more choices.</li><li>Can be integrated with subscription services such as Premiumize, Real-Debrid, OffCloud, EasyNews, All Debrid, Rapid Premium, and many others.</li><li>Supports Trakt, making it possible to keep a record of all the content you watch on Kodi.&nbsp;</li></ul>



<h2>Available Sections and Channels</h2>



<p>The Bubbles addon has sections such as:</p>



<ul><li>Launch section</li><li>Language section</li><li>Playback section</li><li>VPN section</li><li>Statistics section</li><li>Access section</li><li>Theme section</li><li>Appearance section</li><li>Language section</li><li>Navigation section</li><li>Stream layout section</li><li>Title layout section</li><li>Menus section</li><li>Arrivals section</li><li>Shows section</li><li>Favorites section</li><li>Artwork section</li><li>Informants section</li><li>Premium section</li><li>Universal providers section</li><li>Updates section</li><li>Locations section</li></ul>



<pre class="wp-block-preformatted has-pale-ocean-gradient-background has-background" style="font-size:18px"><strong>How Not To F*ck Up Your Kodi Experience:</strong> Streaming movies and TV shows on any of the 3rd party Kodi-addons may be illegal in your country due to copyright issues. 

Consider using a VPN if you truly care about protecting your online privacy.

<strong>Here are the key benefits of hiding your IP (using VPN):</strong>

1) Encrypts your internet traffic.
2) You can access Geo-restricted content.
3) You can avoid ISP throttling.
4) You can avoid unwanted surveillance by government agencies and ISPs.
5) You can protect yourself from hackers.

Connect VPN on all of your streaming devices (iOS, Windows, Android, Amazon Fire TV, etc.) and enjoy worry-free &amp; high-speed movie experience 24/7.

<strong>The Most Popular VPN Providers Among Kodi Users Are:</strong>

1) <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="http://www.prooffreader.com/recommends/cyberghostvpn/" target="_blank"><strong>Get CyberGhost</strong></a> - 45-Day Money-Back Guarantee
2) <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="http://www.prooffreader.com/recommends/expressvpn/" target="_blank"><strong>Get ExpressVPN</strong></a> - 30-Day Money-Back Guarantee
3) <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="http://www.prooffreader.com/recommends/privatevpn/" target="_blank"><strong>Get</strong> <strong>PrivateVPN</strong></a> - 30-Day Money-Back Guarantee</pre>



<h2>Bubbles Addon Installation Prerequisites</h2>



<p>Bubbles is not found in the official Kodi repository. For this reason, you&#8217;ll need to install it from a third-party repository by allowing installation from unknown sources from Kodi&#8217;s settings.</p>



<h2>Bubbles Information and Location</h2>



<ol><li>Name of the addon: Bubbles</li><li>Repository name: Bubbles Repo</li><li>Category: Video addons</li><li>Media source name: Bubbles</li><li>Bubbles repo zip file: repository.bubbles.1-2.0.0.zip</li><li>Bubbles addon Repo URL: https://archive.org/download/repository.bubbles.1-2.0.0/</li><li>Latest working URL: <a href="http://repo.gaiakodi.com/">http://repo.gaiakodi.com/</a></li></ol>



<p>As of January 2018, the addon changed its name to Gaia, and as a result, the original repository of the addon is no longer accessible. Remember to type the Kodi repo URL correctly for successful installation of the addon.</p>



<p></p>



<h2>How To Configure Bubbles Kodi Add-on</h2>



<p>After installing the Bubbles Kodi addon and launching it, you&#8217;ll notice three disclaimers displayed. Click on Continue or Agree to all.</p>



<p>After that, the Bubbles addon configuration wizard appears; select Yes to continue.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The addon will prompt you to choose a default language for subtitles and information display. You can change the language from the Tools section later on if you wish.</p>



<p>Click on Continue.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The last step involves enabling Trakt or a free Real Debrid account for addon testing purposes.</p>



<p>Bubbles have free &#8216;happy hours&#8217; for users who install the addon for the first time. During the happy hour, you can test how the addon works with subscription services such as Real Debrid. You can also download restricted files hosted on different providers at high speeds free of charge as long as you integrate the addon with a Real Debrid account.</p>



<p>If you need to enable torrent streaming, it is advisable to use your Premiumize account instead of the direct torrent player. This is because ISPs can monitor direct torrenting activity and might throttle your bandwidth or impose other penalties.</p>



<p>Premiumize has an inbuilt VPN service that encrypts your traffic from ISPs, ensuring online privacy for its users.</p>



<p>Bubbles have a Usenet feature that requires you to sign in to a Premiumize account to enable Usenet providers. If you fail to sign in to a Premiumize account, the Usenet streams won&#8217;t work on Bubble. In addition, users who don&#8217;t need this feature can disable it from the configuration wizard. </p>



<p>If you don&#8217;t have a Real Debrid or Premiumize account and want to stream content using the Bubbles addon, you&#8217;ll need to enable free hoster providers. These hoster providers, such as NoobsAndNerds, provide streaming links for free, but they may be of lower quality than the ones provided by Real Debrid or Premiumize.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Note that you need to enable Bubbles addon providers manually from Settings for the hoster providers to function.</p>



<p>Also, not all free hoster providers work; ISPs block most of them due to copyright infringement. For this reason, you need to enable the automatic failure detection feature. This feature detects hoster providers that are down or those with high failure rates and ignores them when you search for content online.&nbsp;</p>



<p>If a blocked hoster provider comes back online, the feature reincorporates it into the search results. This feature is useful to users without a Premiumize or Real Debrid account.&nbsp;</p>



<p>On the other hand, Kodi users with a Premiumize or Real Debrid account don&#8217;t need the feature because the subscription services have many premium hosts, which don&#8217;t usually experience downtime.&nbsp;</p>



<p>After concluding the addon configuration, the addon will conduct a connection speed test to determine how fast your internet service is and the quality of your connection.&nbsp;</p>



<h2>How To Use The Bubbles Kodi Addon</h2>



<p>Here&#8217;s how to access content on Bubbles Kodi addon:&nbsp;</p>



<ul><li>Select a category of your choice from the main menu, e.g. movies, TV shows, etc.</li><li>Select a subcategory, e.g., Arrivals, then select the content you want from the list that appears.&nbsp;</li><li>You&#8217;ll need to wait for at least four minutes, depending on how fast your internet connection is, for the addon to search for content from the internet.</li><li>After scraping for content online, the addon will display a list of streaming options.&nbsp;</li><li>Click on a streaming link of your choice and begin watching content.</li></ul>



<p>There are several types of streams available on the addon: <strong>Direct and Torrent stream</strong>.&nbsp;</p>



<p>A direct stream establishes the stream connection from hoster sites and Bubbles addon providers, while a torrent stream establishes the stream connection from Peer-to-Peer networks.</p>



<h2>Compatibility</h2>



<p>The developer has optimized the addon to fully support Premiumize, but it has limited Real-Debrid support. You can use Premiumize to torrent or download content for free or copy torrent magnet links and turn them into direct downloads. In addition, Premiumize has an inbuilt VPN that you can use to unlock geo-restricted content.&nbsp;</p>



<p>If you want to access content not widely available on the internet, you can opt for Usenet streaming. Note that Premiumize is a paid service with its own high-speed servers, download tools, and plugins. The addon is also compatible with all devices and operating systems that support Kodi.</p>



<h2>Alternative Addons</h2>



<p>Despite being popular among Kodi users, the Bubbles addon has a reputation for sourcing links containing copyrighted content. Therefore, it is not suitable for users who want to watch legal entertainment content on Kodi. The original Bubbles addon is also currently unavailable (replaced by Gaia).&nbsp;</p>



<p>Some alternatives to Bubbles Kodi addon include:&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>FilmOn.TV: </strong>An<strong> </strong>entertainment addon that provides live TV streams from across the globe. It has legitimate content, and you can install it from the SuperRepo repository.</p>



<p><strong>The Crew:</strong> An all-inclusive entertainment addon that integrates with Real Debrid and is compatible with the latest version of Kodi.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Seren:</strong> A premium Kodi addon that only works with a Real Debrid account. It provides high-quality links and is compatible with Kodi 19 Matrix.</p>



<h2>Frequently Asked Questions About Bubbles Kodi addon&nbsp;</h2>



<h3>Is the Bubbles Addon Available in 2021?</h3>



<p>The Bubbles addon is not available in 2021 and has been replaced by the Gaia addon.</p>



<h3>How Can You Download Content Using the Bubbles Addon?&nbsp;</h3>



<p>The best way to download content on the Bubbles addon is via Usenet, but you&#8217;ll need to sign in with your Premiumize account first before initiating downloads.</p>



<h3>Is the Bubbles Kodi Addon Free?</h3>



<p>You can install the addon free of charge, but you&#8217;ll need to register for a paid subscription service such as Premiumize if you want to access high-quality streaming links.&nbsp;</p>



<h3>Do You Need a VPN To Use Bubbles Kodi Addon?</h3>



<p>Connecting to a VPN service is advisable while using the addon because most of its hoster sites contain illegal content. However, you can still sign in to your Premiumize and watch content anonymously without connecting to a VPN service.</p>



<h2>Conclusion</h2>



<p>Bubbles is a Kodi entertainment addon offering a wide range of movies, documentaries, and TV shows. It is optimized to work well with popular Kodi subscription services such as Premiumize (preferred), Real Debrid, etc. Additionally, the addon pulls content from tons of sources, including torrent sites, Usenet, and online hosters. However, the vast majority of its content is pirated, which is why you need a Premiumize account or premium VPN.&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prooffreader.com/how-to-install-bubbles-kodi-addon">How To Install Bubbles Kodi Addon | All You Need To Know</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prooffreader.com">ProoFFreader</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How To Install Alfa (Spanish) Kodi Add-on</title>
		<link>https://www.prooffreader.com/how-to-install-spanish-alfa-kodi-add-on/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[James Austin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 18 Sep 2021 09:31:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Kodi]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.prooffreader.com/?p=1208</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Alfa add-on, or simply known as Alpha, is a Kodi add-on found in the Alfa repository. The add-on&#8217;s content primarily ... </p>
<p class="read-more-container"><a title="How To Install Alfa (Spanish) Kodi Add-on" class="read-more button" href="https://www.prooffreader.com/how-to-install-spanish-alfa-kodi-add-on/#more-1208" aria-label="More on How To Install Alfa (Spanish) Kodi Add-on">Read more</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prooffreader.com/how-to-install-spanish-alfa-kodi-add-on/">How To Install Alfa (Spanish) Kodi Add-on</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prooffreader.com">ProoFFreader</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Alfa add-on, or simply known as Alpha, is a Kodi add-on found in the Alfa repository. The add-on&#8217;s content primarily targets a Spanish-speaking audience.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The Alfa add-on comes with sections such as Movies, TV Shows, Anime, Documentaries, Direct, Downloads, and much more.&nbsp;</p>



<h2>General Features and Functionality</h2>



<p>Alfa, unlike most Kodi add-ons, uses P2P technology for streaming. This technology has an advantage over the traditional link scrapper method used by other add-ons because links to movies and TV shows will partially download content before streaming, preventing videos from buffering.</p>



<p>With the traditional link scraping method, high demand for the same content usually overloads the server, causing buffering or video lagging.</p>



<p>When compared to conventional link scraping add-ons, P2P add-ons offer a better streaming experience because of the link downloading technique.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Alfa also lets you download content from multiple sources for offline viewing. It has various cloud-hosting providers and uses multiple sources such as channels, servers, and torrents to access high-quality content.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This add-on&#8217;s main menu categories include:&nbsp;</p>



<ul><li>Movies</li><li>Movies 4K</li><li>Horror movies</li><li>Kids</li><li>TV series episodes</li><li>Anime Episodes</li><li>Castellan</li><li>Latin</li><li>Documentaries</li><li>Torrent</li><li>Settings</li></ul>



<h2>Sections Overview</h2>



<ul><li>Recent</li><li>Channels</li><li>My Links</li><li>Global Search</li><li>Favorites</li><li>Videolibrary</li><li>Downloads</li><li>Reportar un fallo</li><li>Help</li></ul>



<h2>Advantages of Alfa Add-on</h2>



<p>Here are some of the reasons why you&#8217;ll love the Alfa Kodi add-on:</p>



<ul><li>Uses the P2P file-sharing technique to provide a buffer-free streaming experience.&nbsp;</li><li>Comes with an easy-to-navigate menu.&nbsp;</li><li>Has a Resume Watching function.&nbsp;</li><li>Has a vast library of media content.&nbsp;</li><li>Compatible with Kodi 19 Matrix and Kodi 18 Leia.&nbsp;</li><li>Integrates with subscription services such as Real-Debrid.&nbsp;</li></ul>



<h2>Compatibility</h2>



<p>The Alfa add-on works well with all major operating systems such as Android, Windows, Linux, and Mac OS. It is also fully compatible with Kodi 19 Matrix and Kodi 18 Leia.</p>



<h2>Installation Prerequisites</h2>



<p>You&#8217;ll need to allow installation from unknown sources on your device&#8217;s settings because Alfa is a third-party add-on unavailable in the official Kodi repository.</p>



<p>After allowing installation from unknown sources, ensure you have the URL to the Alfa add-on repository, Alfa Repo.</p>



<p>While this add-on is available in various repositories, using unofficial repositories comes at high risk of installing malware and viruses along with the add-on. Viruses leave your device vulnerable to hackers, consequently exposing your personal information to third parties.</p>



<p>Follow the steps below to install the Alfa add-on:</p>



<ul><li>Enable unknown sources.</li><li>Add media source.</li><li>Install Alfa add-on from the repository.</li></ul>



<p>Finally, ensure you have the latest versions of both the add-on and Kodi to avoid potential installation failures and errors.</p>



<p>Here&#8217;s the add-on and repository information you need for a successful installation process:</p>



<ol><li>Name of the Add-on: Alfa add-on</li><li>Repository Name: Alfa Repo</li><li>Category: Media sources</li><li>Media source naming: Alfa</li><li>The Latest Working Source URL:  <a href="https://alfa-addon.com/alfa/">https://alfa-addon.com/alfa/</a></li></ol>



<pre class="wp-block-preformatted has-pale-ocean-gradient-background has-background" style="font-size:18px"><strong>How Not To F*ck Up Your Kodi Experience:</strong> Streaming movies and TV shows on any of the 3rd party Kodi-addons may be illegal in your country due to copyright issues. 

Consider using a VPN if you truly care about protecting your online privacy.

<strong>Here are the key benefits of hiding your IP (using VPN):</strong>

1) Encrypts your internet traffic.
2) You can access Geo-restricted content.
3) You can avoid ISP throttling.
4) You can avoid unwanted surveillance by government agencies and ISPs.
5) You can protect yourself from hackers.

Connect VPN on all of your streaming devices (iOS, Windows, Android, Amazon Fire TV, etc.) and enjoy worry-free &amp; high-speed movie experience 24/7.

<strong>The Most Popular VPN Providers Among Kodi Users Are:</strong>

1) <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="http://www.prooffreader.com/recommends/cyberghostvpn/" target="_blank"><strong>Get CyberGhost</strong></a> - 45-Day Money-Back Guarantee
2) <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="http://www.prooffreader.com/recommends/expressvpn/" target="_blank"><strong>Get ExpressVPN</strong></a> - 30-Day Money-Back Guarantee
3) <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="http://www.prooffreader.com/recommends/privatevpn/" target="_blank"><strong>Get</strong> <strong>PrivateVPN</strong></a> - 30-Day Money-Back Guarantee</pre>



<h2>Installation Guide</h2>



<h3><strong>First Things First – Enable Installation From Unknown Sources</strong></h3>



<p>Go to Home Screen, click on the gear icon, click on system, select “add-ons” on the left side menu, allow installation from “Unknown Sources”, click “yes” when the warning popup appears.&nbsp;</p>



<h3><strong>Installing Alfa Addon Repository</strong></h3>



<ol><li>Go to Home Screen, click on Gear Icon, click on File Manager;</li><li>Click Add Source, Click None, Type in the URL&nbsp;<strong>“<strong>https://alfa-addon.com/alfa/</strong>”</strong>&nbsp;and click Done;</li><li>Pick a name for the repository (i.e. Alfa) and enter it in the bottom box and click OK;</li><li>Click back until you are in the Main Menu, select Addons on the left side;&nbsp;</li><li>Click on the Box Symbol (top left corner), Choose Install From ZIP file, click Yes when a warning appears;</li><li>Open “Alfa” Source and choose this file:&nbsp;<strong>“<strong>repository.alfa-addon-x.x.x.zip</strong>”</strong></li><li>A notification saying “Installed Successfully” will appear.</li></ol>



<h3><strong>Installing Alfa Kodi Addon</strong></h3>



<ol><li>Go to Home Screen, find Add-ons on the left side, select the box symbol (top left corner) to get to the Addon Browser;</li><li>Click on Install From Repository, choose Alfa Addon Repo, click on Video Addons in the category section;</li><li>Click on Alfa and hit install, select OK to confirm the installation of dependencies (don’t appear in Kodi 19 Matrix);</li><li>A notification saying “Installed Successfully” will appear;</li><li>You have now downloaded Alfa to Kodi. You can now access the addon from the main menu.&nbsp;</li></ol>



<h2>Alternative Add-ons</h2>



<p>If for some reason, you can&#8217;t install the Alfa add-on on your device, or it&#8217;s not what you&#8217;re looking for, you can opt for the add-ons listed below:</p>



<p><strong>TV Chopo</strong>, like Alfa, also caters to a Spanish audience and features a vast library of entertainment content, including movies, TV shows, Live Sports channels, Fitness videos, Kids&#8217; channels, Documentaries, and much more.</p>



<p><strong>Tubi TV</strong> is popular among Kodi users because it offers High Definition (HD) TV shows and movies. The add-on&#8217;s content is primarily in English, but you will find Spanish Movies and Spanish TV show sections within the add-on.</p>



<p><strong>Midian</strong> is located in the &#8216;Where The Monsters Live&#8217; repository. The Median add-on has a vast library of movies and TV shows and features unique categories. To stream content in Spanish, click on the Spanish category on the add-on&#8217;s main menu.</p>



<h2>Common Issues With Alfa Kodi Addon</h2>



<p>Here are some of the most common problems you might encounter with this add-on and the best possible ways to solve them:</p>



<h3>Alfa&#8217; No Stream Available&#8217; Error</h3>



<p>The &#8216;No Stream Available Error&#8217; occurs mostly when searching for content on the Alfa add-on because of:&nbsp;</p>



<ul><li>Poor network connection:&nbsp;</li><li>ISP restrictions.&nbsp;</li><li>Wrong repository.&nbsp;</li><li>Unavailable content.</li><li>Full cache.&nbsp;</li><li>Security or malware issues.&nbsp;</li></ul>



<p>Consider the following solutions when you encounter this error:&nbsp;</p>



<h4>Check Your Network Connection</h4>



<p>Having a weak or unstable internet connection can sometimes lead to the &#8216;No Stream Available&#8217; error. To solve this, unplug your router from the power source, then wait for a few minutes before plugging it in.&nbsp;</p>



<p>If the error persists, try testing your internet speed by accessing other websites through your web browser. If you realize that your speeds are slower than usual, it may be a case of connection throttling by your ISP.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Connection throttling is when your ISP intentionally slows your internet speed to limit your bandwidth usage. Slow internet leads to a longer loading time for videos, causing the &#8216;No Stream Available&#8217; error.&nbsp;</p>



<p>However, the best way to prevent ISP throttling is by using a VPN service.</p>



<h4>Clear Cache</h4>



<p>Data accumulation within the add-on is another reason you may encounter the &#8216;No Stream Available&#8217; error. Usually, when there is a backlog of cached data, videos take too long to load, resulting in this error.&nbsp;</p>



<p>For the Alfa add-on to function correctly, remember to clear the cache regularly. To clear cache, go to your add-on&#8217;s settings and click on the Clear Cache option under Tools. You can also download a maintenance tool such OpenWizard or SG Wizard to help clear cache.</p>



<h4>Use a VPN</h4>



<p>You may encounter the &#8216;No Stream Available&#8217; error because your ISP has blocked you from accessing certain links or sources. It is imperative to note that third-party and P2P file sharing add-ons like Alfa use torrents and link scrappers to source content from multiple online hosts.</p>



<p>These add-ons make it easier for users to view copyrighted content or those behind paywalls, prompting ISPs to block them. But using a VPN will hide your internet traffic from your ISP; they won&#8217;t know the kind of content you access on Kodi. Besides hiding your IP address, VPNs keep your data private, preventing hacking, identity theft, phishing, among other cybercrimes.&nbsp;</p>



<h4>Adjust the Providers&#8217; Timeout Options</h4>



<p>Even though Alfa uses the P2P technique to stream content, streaming Ultra High Definition (UHD) files can lead to the &#8216;No Stream Available&#8217; error. The best way to fix this problem is to upgrade your timeout options.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Consider increasing the timeout limit to 60 seconds, which is usually enough time to load UHD videos.&nbsp;</p>



<p>To adjust the timeout, go to the add-on&#8217;s main menu, then click on Tools under the Settings button.</p>



<h4>Use Real- Debrid</h4>



<p>Sometimes, locating a link to a movie or TV show that&#8217;s too old or too recent will lead to an error. The error occurs mainly when Alfa fails to find any links to the content on its cloud-based sources.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In this case, integrating your add-on with Real Debrid is an excellent solution. Real- Debrid is a premium service that offers fresh, high-quality links from a variety of sources.</p>



<p>Using Real-Debrid with P2P add-ons that have a torrent function like Alfa can sometimes be confusing. For your add-on to work correctly with Debrid services, you need to authenticate Debrid providers.&nbsp;</p>



<p>To authenticate Debrid providers, turn on Real-Debrid from Kodi settings, then launch the Alfa Kodi add-on. Wait for a few seconds for a message prompting you to authenticate Real-Debrid in Alfa, then click on it. After authentication is complete, your add-on should be streaming smoothly with no buffering or &#8216;No Stream Available&#8217; errors.</p>



<p>Note that you need to have an active Real Debrid account for the above solution to work.</p>



<h4>Install the Add-On From the Official Repository</h4>



<p>As earlier noted, the Alfa add-on is available in various repositories. Unfortunately, using unofficial repositories to install the add-on will most likely lead to failures and errors, including the &#8216;No Stream Available&#8217; error.</p>



<p>If you opt for an unofficial repository to install the Alfa Kodi add-on, the add-on will work well initially and then begin to fail or display errors after some time. In most cases, unofficial repositories may contain malware that interferes with the add-on&#8217;s functionality leading to errors.</p>



<h3>Alfa Failed To Install Dependency&#8217; Error</h3>



<p>The &#8216;Failed to Install Dependency&#8217; error mainly occurs when you have a poor internet connection or install Alfa from an unofficial repo. Here are some of the best solutions to fix this error:</p>



<h4>Use the Official Repository</h4>



<p>As mentioned earlier, installing add-ons from unofficial repositories is not encouraged. If you installed the Alfa add-on from an unofficial repo, uninstall it and re-install it from the official Alfa repo. Launch the add-on and check if the issue has been fixed.&nbsp;</p>



<h4>Clear Cache</h4>



<p>A full video cache may cause the &#8216;Failed to Install Dependency&#8217; error when you try to install Alfa. In this case, try clearing the cache and check if this fixes the issue.</p>



<h4>Use the Latest Version of the Add-On</h4>



<p>If none of the above solutions fix the error, check the official source to establish if you&#8217;ve installed the latest version of Alfa. It is possible that you may have been using an outdated version incompatible with your Kodi player, causing the &#8216;Failed to Install Dependency&#8217; error.</p>



<h2>Frequently Asked Questions About Alfa Kodi Addon&nbsp;</h2>



<h3>Is Alfa Kodi Add-on Free?</h3>



<p>Yes, the Alfa Kodi add-on is 100% free.</p>



<h3>Is the Alfa Kodi Add-on Legal?</h3>



<p>Yes, downloading and installing Alfa is legal. However, using this add-on to view copyrighted content is illegal.&nbsp;</p>



<h3>Do I Need Real-Debrid To Use Alfa?</h3>



<p>No, you do not need to subscribe to a premium service to use Alfa. This add-on uses P2P technology to source content from online hosts and provides a buffer-free streaming experience.</p>



<h2>Conclusion</h2>



<p>Alfa&#8217;s in-built torrent function makes it one of the best Spanish Kodi add-ons out there. With its vast media library and user-friendly interface, Alfa is a must-have add-on for any Spanish-speaking Kodi user.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prooffreader.com/how-to-install-spanish-alfa-kodi-add-on/">How To Install Alfa (Spanish) Kodi Add-on</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prooffreader.com">ProoFFreader</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Brazuca Play Kodi Addon &#124; Install &#038; Use</title>
		<link>https://www.prooffreader.com/brazuca-play-kodi-addon/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[David]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 16 Sep 2021 19:03:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Kodi]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.prooffreader.com/?p=1202</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Brazuca Play is a video addon that streams Brazilian content such as TV shows, movies, sports, music, and much more. ... </p>
<p class="read-more-container"><a title="Brazuca Play Kodi Addon &#124; Install &#038; Use" class="read-more button" href="https://www.prooffreader.com/brazuca-play-kodi-addon/#more-1202" aria-label="More on Brazuca Play Kodi Addon &#124; Install &#038; Use">Read more</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prooffreader.com/brazuca-play-kodi-addon/">Brazuca Play Kodi Addon | Install &#038; Use</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prooffreader.com">ProoFFreader</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Brazuca Play is a video addon that streams Brazilian content such as TV shows, movies, sports, music, and much more. In addition, the addon comes in the Portuguese language making it popular among users in Portuguese-speaking regions.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Brazuca Play is compatible with Kodi 18 Leia and 19 Matrix.</p>



<p>Brazuca Play has a simple user interface with categories such as movies, TV shows, and soap operas.</p>



<h2>Brazuca Play addon sections</h2>



<p>The sections in this addon include:</p>



<ul><li>TV Ao Vivo</li><li>Filmes</li><li>Series</li><li>Desenhos</li><li>Animes</li><li>Novelas</li><li>Configuracoes</li></ul>



<h2>Brazuca Play Addon Installation Prerequisites</h2>



<p>You can find this addon in the Vikings repository. But before installing Brazuca Play, you&#8217;ll need to change Kodi settings to allow installation from unknown sources.</p>



<h2>Brazuca Play Addon Information</h2>



<ol><li>Name of the addon: Brazuca Play</li><li>Repository name: Vikings Repositorio</li><li>Category: Media sources</li><li>Media source name: vkodi</li><li>Latest working URL:<a href="http://vkodi.net/repo/"> http://vkodi.net/repo/</a></li></ol>



<pre class="wp-block-preformatted has-pale-ocean-gradient-background has-background" style="font-size:18px"><strong>How Not To F*ck Up Your Kodi Experience:</strong> Streaming movies and TV shows on any of the 3rd party Kodi-addons may be illegal in your country due to copyright issues. 

Consider using a VPN if you truly care about protecting your online privacy.

<strong>Here are the key benefits of hiding your IP (using VPN):</strong>

1) Encrypts your internet traffic.
2) You can access Geo-restricted content.
3) You can avoid ISP throttling.
4) You can avoid unwanted surveillance by government agencies and ISPs.
5) You can protect yourself from hackers.

Connect VPN on all of your streaming devices (iOS, Windows, Android, Amazon Fire TV, etc.) and enjoy worry-free &amp; high-speed movie experience 24/7.

<strong>The Most Popular VPN Providers Among Kodi Users Are:</strong>

1) <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="http://www.prooffreader.com/recommends/cyberghostvpn/" target="_blank"><strong>Get CyberGhost</strong></a> - 45-Day Money-Back Guarantee
2) <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="http://www.prooffreader.com/recommends/expressvpn/" target="_blank"><strong>Get ExpressVPN</strong></a> - 30-Day Money-Back Guarantee
3) <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="http://www.prooffreader.com/recommends/privatevpn/" target="_blank"><strong>Get</strong> <strong>PrivateVPN</strong></a> - 30-Day Money-Back Guarantee</pre>



<h2>Installation Guide</h2>



<h3><strong>First Things First – Enable Installation From Unknown Sources</strong></h3>



<p>Go to Home Screen, click on the gear icon, click on system, select “add-ons” on the left side menu, allow installation from “Unknown Sources”, click “yes” when the warning popup appears.&nbsp;</p>



<h3><strong>Installing Vikings Repositorio</strong></h3>



<ol><li>Go to Home Screen, click on Gear Icon, click on File Manager;</li><li>Click Add Source, Click None, Type in the URL&nbsp;<strong>“<strong>http://vkodi.net/repo</strong>”</strong>&nbsp;and click Done;</li><li>Pick a name for the repository (i.e. vKODI) and enter it in the bottom box and click OK;</li><li>Click back until you are in the Main Menu, select Addons on the left side;&nbsp;</li><li>Click on the Box Symbol (top left corner), Choose Install From ZIP file, click Yes when a warning appears;</li><li>Open “vKODI” Source and choose this file:&nbsp;<strong>“<strong>repository.vikings.zip</strong>”</strong></li><li>A notification saying “Installed Successfully” will appear.</li></ol>



<h3><strong>Installing Brazuca Play Kodi Addon</strong></h3>



<ol><li>Go to Home Screen, find Add-ons on the left side, select the box symbol (top left corner) to get to the Addon Browser;</li><li>Click on Install From Repository, choose Vikings Repositorio, click on Video Addons in the category section;</li><li>Click on Brazuca Play and hit install, select OK to confirm the installation of dependencies (don’t appear in Kodi 19 Matrix);</li><li>A notification saying “Installed Successfully” will appear;</li><li>You can now access the Brazuca Play addon from the main menu.&nbsp;</li></ol>



<h2>Compatibility</h2>



<p>Brazuca Play is compatible with Kodi 18 Leia and 19 Matrix. In addition, the addon works perfectly with several devices, including Amazon Fire Stick, Fire TV Stick, and Apple TV.</p>



<h2>Alternative Addons</h2>



<p>Is Brazuca Play not what you&#8217;re looking for? Here are some great alternatives:&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Zeus</strong> delivers high-quality movies, TV shows, music, and sports in English, Portuguese and other languages. It is compatible with Kodi 18 Leia and 19 Matrix.</p>



<p><strong>Apollo</strong> lets you stream movies and TV shows in Portuguese. It is compatible with Kodi 18 Leia and 19 Matrix.</p>



<p><strong>One Play</strong> is a video addon from the Vikings repo, offering streaming links for movies, TV shows, soap operas, animation, and much more in Portuguese. One Play is compatible with Kodi 18 Leia and 19 Matrix.</p>



<h2>Common Issues With Brazuca Play Addon</h2>



<p>Here are some common problems with the Brazuca Pay addon and their solutions.&nbsp;</p>



<h3>Brazuca Play Addon Shows a &#8216;No Stream Available&#8217; Error</h3>



<p>Kodi depends on scrapers to fetch streaming links from the internet. When the scrapers fail to fetch the links due to any reason, Kodi displays the &#8216;No Stream Available&#8217; error.</p>



<p>Here are probable reasons for this kind of error:&nbsp;</p>



<ul><li>The content you seek is unavailable on the internet.</li><li>Your Brazuca Play addon is incompatible with the Kodi version.</li><li>Buildup of cache.</li><li>Poor internet connection.</li><li>The available links come from restricted sites.</li><li>Some Kodi providers are disabled.</li></ul>



<p>Probable solutions to this error include:&nbsp;</p>



<h4>Clear cache</h4>



<p>Streaming content on Kodi for a long time without clearing browser cache and data history can slow down the application. When the app slows down, it affects the addon&#8217;s performance, resulting in the &#8216;No Stream Available&#8217; error.</p>



<p>Clear the cache to refresh the app and the addon. You can do this from the Settings menu on the addon, denoted as Configuracoes in Portuguese.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Navigate to the Clear Cache option and press OK.</p>



<p>You can also use Kodi maintenance tools to clear cache across all your Kodi-connected devices. Some examples of such tools include Open Wizard, Aliunde Maintenance Wizard, and SG wizard.</p>



<h4>Use a VPN&nbsp;</h4>



<p>A VPN allows you to bypass geo-restrictions and firewalls to access content from certain sites. If you suspect your Internet Service Provider has created firewalls to block access to certain sites, connect to a premium VPN to circumvent these restrictions.&nbsp;</p>



<h4>Fix Faulty Internet Connection</h4>



<p>A broken internet connection causes several errors when streaming content on Brazuca Play. Among them is the &#8216;No Stream Available&#8217; error when the connection between Kodi servers and internet servers is lost.</p>



<p>Here&#8217;s how to resolve a faulty internet connection:</p>



<ul><li>Turn off the router for a few minutes, then restart.&nbsp;</li><li>Force close your modem, remove the service card, reinsert it, and then turn the modem back on.&nbsp;</li></ul>



<h4>Update the Addon</h4>



<p>You may also encounter the &#8216;No Stream Available&#8217; error due to incompatibility between the Brazuca Play version and the Kodi version. Update the addon to the latest version and check if that fixes the issue.</p>



<h4>Enable All Providers</h4>



<p>Most related addons use common providers to pull streaming links from the internet. For instance, addons located in the same repository will share some of the providers. If any of the shared providers are disabled, you may receive the &#8216;No Stream Available&#8217; error message.</p>



<p>Follow these steps to enable all providers:</p>



<ul><li>Disable all providers.</li><li>Restart Kodi app.</li><li>Enable all the providers afresh.</li><li>Restart the addon.&nbsp;</li></ul>



<p>If the above solutions do not resolve the error, then the content you are searching for may be unavailable on the internet.</p>



<h3>Brazuca Play Addon Fails To Launch</h3>



<p>Here&#8217;s why the Brazuca Play addon might fail to launch.&nbsp;</p>



<h4>Accumulation of Cache</h4>



<p>A buildup of cache can slow down the Brazuca Play addon. Too much cache can also make the addon fail to launch or launch then stops unexpectedly. For best results, clear your cache and see if that fixes the issue.</p>



<h4>Incorrect Proxy Settings</h4>



<p>The Brazuca Kodi addon works seamlessly when the Kodi device&#8217;s proxy settings match those of the network. These settings include the <strong>port number and proxy servers</strong>. One of the causes of deviation of these credentials is signing in to Kodi with a new device.</p>



<p>Using a different internet connection, such as a friend&#8217;s or hotel&#8217;s Wi-Fi, can also cause a mismatch of these proxy settings.</p>



<p>To resolve the proxy deviation problem, check to confirm your device&#8217;s port number and proxy server matches your network&#8217;s.</p>



<h2>Brazuca Play Addon Shows the &#8216;Check the Log for More Information&#8217; Error</h2>



<p>When you notice the &#8216;Check the Log for More Information&#8217; error, it may derive from the following:&nbsp;</p>



<ul><li>The Brazuca Play addon is out of date.</li><li>Buildup of cache.</li><li>Faulty internet connection.</li></ul>



<p>However, to fix this issue,&nbsp;</p>



<ul><li>Clear all cache.</li><li>Troubleshoot your network.</li><li>Update the Brazuca Play addon to the latest version</li></ul>



<p>.</p>



<h2>Brazuca Play Addon Fails To Play Links or Requires Authorization</h2>



<p>Failure to play links is one of the common issues reported by Brazuca Play users. This error may emanate from the following:&nbsp;</p>



<h4>Playback Settings Set To Autoplay</h4>



<p>When you set your playback settings to auto-play, the streaming links play in chronological order. In case the top link is broken or invalid, it won&#8217;t play.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The source select playback settings, on the other hand, let you choose only the best links. The latter reduces the instances of links failing to play by allowing you to hand-pick valid links.</p>



<h4>Faulty URLResolver</h4>



<p>The URL resolver checks the most suitable links from the many links found on the internet when you search for content on Kodi. If this feature is broken, you may receive invalid links which won&#8217;t play.&nbsp;</p>



<h4>You Have Signed In to Kodi on a New Device</h4>



<p>When you synchronize your Kodi-connected devices, hoster sites automatically pair with the devices. Logging in to Kodi with a new device may result in the &#8216;To Play This Video, Authorization Is Required&#8217; error.</p>



<p>To resolve the above issue, try the following options:</p>



<ul><li>Troubleshoot your URLResolver.</li><li>Switch your playback settings to source select.</li><li>Use a static IP address. This type of IP allows the automatic pairing of your devices to hoster sites, eliminating the need for authorization.</li></ul>



<h2>Brazuca Play Addon Shows &#8216;The Dependencies Could Not Be Satisfied&#8217; Error</h2>



<p>You may encounter the ‘Dependencies Could Not Be Satisfied’ error when installing the Brazuca Play addon. When this happens, it&#8217;s usually due to a python code incompatibility between the addon version and the Kodi version.</p>



<p>Given that developers are constantly updating their addons to match the requirements of the latest Kodi version, incompatibility issues may arise if you use a newer addon version with an older Kodi version.</p>



<p>To resolve this problem, uninstall the old Kodi version and install the latest.&nbsp;</p>



<h2>Frequently Asked Questions Brazuca Play Kodi Addon&nbsp;</h2>



<h3>Is the Brazuca Play Kodi Addon Legal?</h3>



<p>Yes, Brazuca Kodi provides legal content that is readily available in the public domain.</p>



<h3>Is the Brazuca Play Kodi Addon Free?</h3>



<p>Yes, the Brazuca Play addon provides free streaming links.</p>



<h3>Do I Need a VPN With the Brazuca Play Kodi Addon?</h3>



<p>Though not mandatory, using a VPN lets you browse content privately, access geo-restricted sites, and reduce bandwidth by 50%.&nbsp;</p>



<h3>Does the Brazuca Play Kodi Addon Still Work in 2021?</h3>



<p>Yes, it does.</p>



<h2>Conclusion</h2>



<p>To sum up, Brazuca Play is a video addon popular for providing movies, TV shows, animations, sports, and soap operas in the Portuguese language. It is found in Viking&#8217;s repository and offers free and high-quality streaming links, making it a fan-favorite among Portuguese-speaking users. In addition, this addon is compatible with the latest Kodi version.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prooffreader.com/brazuca-play-kodi-addon/">Brazuca Play Kodi Addon | Install &#038; Use</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prooffreader.com">ProoFFreader</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How To Install &#038; Use 4K Kodi Add-On</title>
		<link>https://www.prooffreader.com/install-and-use-4k-kodi-addon/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[David]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 02 Sep 2021 11:53:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Kodi]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.prooffreader.com/?p=1181</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>4K is a video add-on developed by NaR for streaming movies and TV shows on Kodi. As the name suggests, ... </p>
<p class="read-more-container"><a title="How To Install &#038; Use 4K Kodi Add-On" class="read-more button" href="https://www.prooffreader.com/install-and-use-4k-kodi-addon/#more-1181" aria-label="More on How To Install &#038; Use 4K Kodi Add-On">Read more</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prooffreader.com/install-and-use-4k-kodi-addon/">How To Install &#038; Use 4K Kodi Add-On</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prooffreader.com">ProoFFreader</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>4K is a video add-on developed by NaR for streaming movies and TV shows on Kodi. As the name suggests, this add-on fetches high-quality links in 4K resolution.&nbsp;</p>



<p>It has a simple user interface with sections such as movies by years, genres, alphabetical order, and TV shows. In addition, the add-on&#8217;s homepage has a main section category with sub-sections such as classic movies and A-Z movies.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-style-large"><p><strong>The 4K Kodi add-on is compatible with Kodi 18 Leia and 19 Matrix.&nbsp;</strong></p></blockquote>



<p>Initially, it was relatively new when Kodi 19 was launched but has since become popular due to its high-quality links. You can integrate it with Real-Debrid to pull high-quality links from the internet.</p>



<p>You can also integrate this add-on with Trakt to sync your streaming links across various Kodi-connected devices.</p>



<h2>4K Kodi Add-On Sections</h2>



<p>The sections in this add-on include:</p>



<ul><li>Main section Movies by Year</li><li>Movie Alphabetically</li><li>Movies Box Sets</li><li>Movies Genres</li><li>Kids Movies</li><li>TV shows</li><li>Search</li><li>Trakt</li><li>Settings</li></ul>



<h2>Main Section Sub-Categories</h2>



<p>Sub-categories under this section include:</p>



<ul><li>4K Movies</li><li>4K TV Shows</li><li>4K A-Z Movies</li><li>4K Back to the Future Box Set</li><li>4K Beverly Hills Cop Box Set</li><li>4K Bourne Box Set</li><li>4K Classic Movies</li><li>4K Crouching Tiger, Hidden Dragon Box Set</li><li>4K Underworld Box Set</li><li>4K Pirates of the Caribbean Box Set</li><li>4K The Mummy Box set</li></ul>



<h2>4K Add-On Installation Prerequisites</h2>



<p>For starters, 4K is not an official Kodi add-on; Kodi disables installation from third-party sources by default, and that&#8217;s why you need to allow installation from unknown sources on the Kodi settings.</p>



<p>Secondly, 4K is a Debrid-only add-on, meaning you need to open a Real Debrid account and configure it with the add-on. The following Real –Debrid accounts are compatible with the 4K add-on:</p>



<ul><li>Premiumize</li><li>Real-Debrid</li><li>All Debrid</li><li>LinkSnappy</li></ul>



<p>The last requirement is to integrate the add-on with Trakt TV. Trakt synchronizes your streaming links and file libraries across all your Kodi-connected devices. This feature allows you to keep track of videos you&#8217;ve watched, resume watching, and so on.</p>



<h2>4K Kodi Add-On Information</h2>



<ol><li>Name of the add-on: 4K</li><li>Repository name: Narcacist&#8217;s Wizard Repository</li><li>Category: Media Sources</li><li>Media source name: Narcacist</li><li>Latest working URL: <a href="http://www.narcacist.com/repo/">http://www.narcacist.com/repo/</a></li></ol>



<pre class="wp-block-preformatted has-pale-ocean-gradient-background has-background" style="font-size:18px"><strong>How Not To F*ck Up Your Kodi Experience:</strong> Streaming movies and TV shows on any of the 3rd party Kodi-addons may be illegal in your country due to copyright issues. 

Consider using a VPN if you truly care about protecting your online privacy.

<strong>Here are the key benefits of hiding your IP (using VPN):</strong>

1) Encrypts your internet traffic.
2) You can access Geo-restricted content.
3) You can avoid ISP throttling.
4) You can avoid unwanted surveillance by government agencies and ISPs.
5) You can protect yourself from hackers.

Connect VPN on all of your streaming devices (iOS, Windows, Android, Amazon Fire TV, etc.) and enjoy worry-free &amp; high-speed movie experience 24/7.

<strong>The Most Popular VPN Providers Among Kodi Users Are:</strong>

1) <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="http://www.prooffreader.com/recommends/cyberghostvpn/" target="_blank"><strong>Get CyberGhost</strong></a> - 45-Day Money-Back Guarantee
2) <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="http://www.prooffreader.com/recommends/expressvpn/" target="_blank"><strong>Get ExpressVPN</strong></a> - 30-Day Money-Back Guarantee
3) <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="http://www.prooffreader.com/recommends/privatevpn/" target="_blank"><strong>Get</strong> <strong>PrivateVPN</strong></a> - 30-Day Money-Back Guarantee</pre>



<h2>Installation Guide</h2>



<h3><strong>First Things First – Enable Installation From Unknown Sources</strong></h3>



<p>Go to Home Screen, click on the gear icon, click on system, select “add-ons” on the left side menu, allow installation from “Unknown Sources”, click “yes” when the warning popup appears.&nbsp;</p>



<h3><strong>Installing Narcacist&#8217;s Wizard Repository</strong></h3>



<ol><li>Go to Home Screen, click on Gear Icon, click on File Manager;</li><li>Click Add Source, Click None, Type in the URL <strong>“http://narcacist.com/repo”</strong> and click Done;</li><li>Pick a name for the repository (i.e. Narcacist) and enter it in the bottom box and click OK;</li><li>Click back until you are in the Main Menu, select Addons on the left side;&nbsp;</li><li>Click on the Box Symbol (top left corner), Choose Install From ZIP file, click Yes when a warning appears;</li><li>Open “Narcacist” Source and choose this file: <strong>“repository.NarcasistWizard.zip”</strong></li><li>A notification saying “Installed Successfully” will appear.</li></ol>



<h3><strong>Installing 4K Kodi Addon</strong></h3>



<ol><li>Go to Home Screen, find Add-ons on the left side, select the box symbol (top left corner) to get to the Addon Browser;</li><li>Click on Install From Repository, choose Narcacist&#8217;s Wizard Repo, click on Video Addons in the category section;</li><li>Click on 4K and hit install, select OK to confirm the installation of dependencies (don’t appear in Kodi 19 Matrix);</li><li>A notification saying “Installed Successfully” will appear;</li><li>You have now downloaded 4K to Kodi. You can now access the addon from the main menu.&nbsp;</li></ol>



<h2>Compatibility</h2>



<p>The 4K add-on is compatible with Kodi 18 Leia and 19 Matrix. It&#8217;s also compatible with Android, Mac, iOS, Windows, and Linux devices.&nbsp;</p>



<h2>Alternative Add-Ons</h2>



<p>4K is dependent on a Real-Debrid account to stream high-quality videos. But if it doesn&#8217;t work for you, check out these alternatives:&nbsp;</p>



<ul><li><strong>Asgard</strong> is also housed in The Narcacist&#8217;s Wizard Repo. It provides high-quality movies, TV shows, documentaries, and animations. In addition, you can access the non-Debrid section videos if you don&#8217;t have a Debrid subscription.</li></ul>



<ul><li>Housed in the StreamArmy repo, the <strong>EnterTain ME</strong> add-on offers high-quality links for movies and TV shows. It is compatible with Kodi 18 Leia and 19 Matrix.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Tubi TV</strong> provides high-quality movies and TV shows on the most popular genres. It is an official Kodi add-on, compatible with Leia and Matrix.</li></ul>



<h2>Common Issues With 4K Add-On</h2>



<p>You might encounter some issues using the 4K add-on to stream content on Kodi, as discussed below.&nbsp;</p>



<h3>4K Add-On Shows the &#8216;No Stream Available&#8217; Error</h3>



<p>Unlike Netflix, Kodi does not own the content it airs. The videos you stream originate from other sites with the help of web scrapers.&nbsp;</p>



<p>For this reason, when the scrapers are faulty, or the request is interrupted, you might encounter this error.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Here are some additional reasons for the &#8216;No Stream Available&#8217; error:</p>



<ul><li>The video you are searching for is currently unavailable on the internet.</li><li>Your internet service provider has blocked access to certain sites.</li><li>Faulty internet connection.</li><li>Accumulation of Kodi cache.</li><li>The add-on is obsolete.</li></ul>



<p>Now let&#8217;s head over to the solutions.&nbsp;</p>



<h4>Clear Kodi Cache</h4>



<p>When you browse and stream videos on Kodi over time, it leads to the accumulation of cache and browsing history. It is therefore advisable to clear this cache after a while to refresh the app.&nbsp;</p>



<p>A cache buildup can cause the Kodi add-on to freeze or return searches with the &#8216;No Stream Available&#8217; error.&nbsp;</p>



<p>To clear the cache on the 4K add-on, head over to the settings option and click Clear Cache. You can also clear all the cache from your device via the device&#8217;s settings or a Kodi maintenance tool such as the SG wizard.</p>



<p>Restart the Kodi app after clearing the cache.</p>



<h4>Use a VPN or a Proxy Server To Bypass ISP Restrictions</h4>



<p>If your ISP has blocked the hoster sites you intend to access, opt for a VPN or a proxy server to circumvent the firewall. 4K is a Debrid add-on (Debrid restricts some VPNs); for this reason, check the official Debrid site to ascertain if your VPN is whitelisted.</p>



<p>If your VPN has been blacklisted, you may use a proxy server to access the restricted sites.</p>



<h4>Troubleshoot Faulty Internet Connection</h4>



<p>Slow or broken internet may cause the 4K Kodi &#8216;No Stream Available&#8217; error. This is because the connection is timed out or interrupted before returning the desired response to your request.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Here&#8217;s what to do when that happens:&nbsp;</p>



<ul><li>Turn off the router or disconnect it from the socket for a few minutes, then turn it on again.</li><li>Reboot your modem and remove the internet card for a few minutes, then re-insert it in the modem.&nbsp;</li></ul>



<h4>Check Your Debrid Subscription</h4>



<p>4K cannot provide links without an active Real Debrid account. Check your Debrid subscription and top-up if expired. If that was the problem, topping up the account should fix the error.</p>



<h4>Enable All Kodi Providers</h4>



<p>Most third-party Kodi add-ons use shared external providers to pull streams from the internet. Ensure all the providers are enabled before streaming content on 4K. You may disable all of them, restart Kodi then enable them again.</p>



<h4><strong>Update the Add-On</strong></h4>



<p>Using an out-of-date add-on may also cause this kind of error. If you can&#8217;t update the add-on for whatever reason, consider uninstalling the add-on and then install the latest version.</p>



<p>If the issue persists, the video is likely not available on the internet or has been pulled down from the internet.</p>



<h3>4K Add-On Fails To Launch</h3>



<p>When your 4K add-on fails to launch or runs for some seconds then stops, it could be because of incorrect proxy settings or cache buildup.&nbsp;</p>



<h4>Incorrect Proxy Settings</h4>



<p>For a Kodi add-on to work seamlessly, your Kodi-connected device&#8217;s port number, proxy server, and those of your network should match. This is why Kodi fails to launch when using a restaurant, library, or a public park&#8217;s Wi-Fi.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Match the proxy settings and check if it fixes the problem.</p>



<h4>Buildup of Cache</h4>



<p>An accumulation of streaming cache slows down an add-on&#8217;s performance. This is because the add-on responds to too much cache by failing to start or stopping moments after launching.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Clear the cache to resolve this issue.</p>



<h3>4K Add-On Fails To Play Links or Requires Authorization</h3>



<p>When you click on a link, and it fails to play or shows the &#8216;To Play This Video, Streaming Authorization Is Required&#8217; error, you can narrow down the issue to the following causes:</p>



<ul><li>Your Debrid subscription has expired.</li><li>Autoplay playback settings.</li><li>The URL resolver is broken.</li></ul>



<p>To solve this issue, try any of the following solutions:&nbsp;</p>



<ul><li>Top up your Debrid subscription.</li><li>Troubleshoot the URLResolver by disabling the Openload URLResolver, restarting Kodi, then enabling the URLResolver again.</li><li>Switch your playback settings to Source Select.&nbsp;</li><li>Use a static Internet Protocol (IP) address; this kind of IP requires your Kodi devices to pair with hoster sites only once, and then the device will pair automatically the next time.&nbsp;</li></ul>



<h3>4K Add-On Shows&#8217; Error Check Log for More Information&#8217;</h3>



<p>You may encounter the &#8216;Error Check Log for More Information&#8217; issue when streaming content on 4K. This error occurs due to the following reasons:</p>



<ul><li>Outdated add-on.&nbsp;</li><li>Cache buildup.&nbsp;</li><li>Lost or unstable connection.&nbsp;</li></ul>



<p>Simply clear the Kodi cache, then restart the app to solve this error.&nbsp;</p>



<h3>4K Add-On Says &#8216;The Dependencies Could Not Be Satisfied&#8217;</h3>



<p>When you encounter this error on 4K, it indicates that the add-on version is not compatible with the Kodi version you&#8217;ve installed. To solve this problem, make sure the add-on version is compatible with Kodi. 4K is compatible with both Kodi 18 Leia and Kodi 19 Matrix.</p>



<h2>Frequently Asked Questions About 4K Kodi Addon&nbsp;</h2>



<h3>Is the 4K Kodi add-on legal?</h3>



<p>Yes, the 4K Kodi add-on is 100% legal.</p>



<h3>Is the 4K Kodi Add-on Free?</h3>



<p>No. You need a Real –Debrid account to stream content on 4K.</p>



<h3>Do I Need a VPN With the 4K Kodi Add-On?</h3>



<p>A VPN is essential when streaming content on the 4K add-on. It conceals your original IP address and can circumvent geo-restrictions.</p>



<h3>Does the 4K Kodi Add-On Still Work in 2021?</h3>



<p>Yes, it does.</p>



<h2>Conclusion</h2>



<p>To recap, 4K is a video add-on that delivers movies and TV shows in 4K quality on Kodi. It is a Debrid-only add-on created by the developer behind the Asgard video add-on. You can integrate it with Trakt TV and synchronize your file libraries across Kodi-connected devices. Lastly, the 4K Kodi add-on is compatible with Kodi 18 Leia and 19 Matrix.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prooffreader.com/install-and-use-4k-kodi-addon/">How To Install &#038; Use 4K Kodi Add-On</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prooffreader.com">ProoFFreader</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Best Kodi Builds</title>
		<link>https://www.prooffreader.com/best-kodi-builds/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[David]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 13 Aug 2021 12:23:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Kodi]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.prooffreader.com/?p=1168</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Do you need to access unlimited streaming content? Internet streaming services have grown exponentially to serve millions of people around ... </p>
<p class="read-more-container"><a title="Best Kodi Builds" class="read-more button" href="https://www.prooffreader.com/best-kodi-builds/#more-1168" aria-label="More on Best Kodi Builds">Read more</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prooffreader.com/best-kodi-builds/">Best Kodi Builds</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prooffreader.com">ProoFFreader</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Do you need to access unlimited streaming content? Internet streaming services have grown exponentially to serve <a href="https://www.broadbandtechreport.com/video/article/16445859/global-iptv-numbers-to-triple-in-5-years" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank">millions of people</a> around the world. To access the streaming channels, broadcasts, and more TV content, you need a platform, and Kodi might be the right choice for you.</p>



<p>Kodi is a hosting program that allows you to download add-ons or builds and access all the content you need.</p>



<p>All you need is a strong internet connection and a compatible device. Kodi can be accessed on different devices and is supported by many platforms, such as iOS devices, Windows, Android, and many more.&nbsp;</p>



<p>After downloading and installing Kodi, you still need to include add-ons because Kodi does not produce any content by itself. Installing add-ons can be a lot of work, but luckily, things are easier with Kodi builds.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Browsing through different Kodi builds to find the right one can be a daunting task; for this reason, this article provides a list of the best Kodi builds in the market. The builds are compatible with FireStick, Android phones, Windows, MacBooks, and other devices.</p>



<h2>What Is Kodi?</h2>



<p>Kodi is basically an open-source content streaming software, and has been around <a href="https://ting.com/blog/a-short-history-of-kodi/#:~:text=Kodi%20was%20first%20released%20in,and%20the%20abbreviated%20name%20stuck." rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank">for nearly two decades</a>.</p>



<p>Before being named Kodi, it had two other names: Xbox Media Player and Xbox Media Centre.</p>



<p>This software allows you to access your content from local storage or over the internet using IP addresses. IPs, short for Internet Protocols, are a set of numbers that provide information about your location and the device you’re using to access the internet.</p>



<p>With Kodi, you&#8217;ll be able to access an online library of movie streaming channels, shows, sports events, and even more content. Kodi can also be customized with other software, such as addons or Kodi builds to help you access your favorite content.</p>



<p>Most platforms support Kodi, and you can download it online on Google Play, Windows Store, etc. The software does not require much expertise to install and set up, as you will find out later in this article. Kodi also updates its software frequently, meaning some of the builds mentioned here can only work on specific Kodi versions.</p>



<h3>Kodi Installation</h3>



<p>You can use Kodi on Amazon Firestick, Fire TV Stick, Fire TV Cube, Android Platforms, Windows, and Xbox.</p>



<h3>Kodi For Amazon Devices</h3>



<p>Kodi is not on the Amazon App store, but you can still load it by following specific steps. Using the downloader app on the Amazon App Store, set up the Firestick for installation by:</p>



<ul><li>Enabling ADB Debugging</li><li>Permitting app installation from unknown sources.</li><li>Turning off device usage data.</li><li>Turning off collect app data.</li></ul>



<h3>Kodi On Android Platforms</h3>



<p>On Android devices, you can download Kodi from the Google Play Store.</p>



<h3>Kodi On Windows And Xbox</h3>



<p>On Windows and Xbox devices, head over to the Windows Store, type <strong>&#8216;Kodi&#8217;</strong> into the search bar, and then install the software from the search results.</p>



<h3>Kodi On Mac And Other iOS Devices</h3>



<p>On the <a href="https://kodi.tv/download/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank">Download page</a> of Kodi&#8217;s website, you will notice a download link for different types of devices. Select MacOs from the provided options, and then click on the provided download button.</p>



<h2>What Next After Installation?</h2>



<p>Kodi is designed to help you play your own content. To access the online media content, you will need to install add-ons and builds.</p>



<h2>What Are Kodi Builds?</h2>



<p>Kodi builds change the entire appearance of the Kodi platform in different ways. Builds are also equipped with useful addons to get you started with Kodi right after installation.</p>



<p>After installing a Kodi build, it comes with add-on settings, interfaces, an electric program guide, and many other exciting features.</p>



<p>With a Kodi build, you do not need to download addons or worry about complex setups; it is basically a pre-packed version of Kodi.</p>



<h3>What Are Kodi Add-ons?</h3>



<p>Add-ons are programs created by developers to help you access available content with a few clicks. Addons usually work almost the same as extensions do on your browser.</p>



<p><strong>Read more: </strong><a href="http://www.prooffreader.com/best-kodi-addons/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><strong>Best Kodi Addons</strong> </a></p>



<pre class="wp-block-preformatted has-pale-ocean-gradient-background has-background" style="font-size:18px"><strong>How Not To F*ck Up Your Kodi Experience:</strong> Streaming movies and TV shows on any of the 3rd party Kodi-addons may be illegal in your country due to copyright issues. 

Consider using a VPN if you truly care about protecting your online privacy.

<strong>Here are the key benefits of hiding your IP (using VPN):</strong>

1) Encrypts your internet traffic.
2) You can access Geo-restricted content.
3) You can avoid ISP throttling.
4) You can avoid unwanted surveillance by government agencies and ISPs.
5) You can protect yourself from hackers.

Connect VPN on all of your streaming devices (iOS, Windows, Android, Amazon Fire TV, etc.) and enjoy worry-free &amp; high-speed movie experience 24/7.

<strong>The Most Popular VPN Providers Among Kodi Users Are:</strong>

1) <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="http://www.prooffreader.com/recommends/cyberghostvpn/" target="_blank"><strong>Get CyberGhost</strong></a> - 45-Day Money-Back Guarantee
2) <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="http://www.prooffreader.com/recommends/expressvpn/" target="_blank"><strong>Get ExpressVPN</strong></a> - 30-Day Money-Back Guarantee
3) <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="http://www.prooffreader.com/recommends/privatevpn/" target="_blank"><strong>Get</strong> <strong>PrivateVPN</strong></a> - 30-Day Money-Back Guarantee</pre>



<h2>Best Builds For Kodi</h2>



<p>Now that you know more about Kodi, the installation process for various devices, and the role addons play in this software, it&#8217;s time to check out some of the best Kodi builds.</p>



<h3>No Limits Magic</h3>



<p>No Limits Magic is one of the most popular Kodi builds available today.</p>



<p>One thing about this Kodi build is it doesn’t need any computing skills to operate. The build also doesn’t limit how much content you stream.</p>



<p>The No Limits Magic Build works with both Kodi 18.1 and 17.6.</p>



<p>When you run No Limit Magic, it can give you access to a lot of content, but some might be unavailable due to legal issues. To access the geo-restricted content on the No Limit Magic build, you will need a good VPN, such as CyberGhost VPN. A VPN lets you stream anonymously, avoiding the legal trouble associated with streaming copyrighted content.</p>



<p>No Limits Magic has frequent updates with new features for the best streaming experience. Some popular addons on this build include:</p>



<ul><li>Pulse Fitness</li><li>Sport’s Devil</li><li>The Magic Dragon</li><li>Cloud TV</li><li>And more.</li></ul>



<p>Addons allow you to access a vast selection of online media content, from movies, live TV to music, and so much more.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The build comes in different packages; you can choose between the Regular (271-276 MB) or the Firestick Lite version (171-176 MB).</p>



<p>The regular version features an adult section while the FireStick Lite doesn&#8217;t. However, both versions are highly customizable for the best viewing experience.</p>



<h3>Titanium</h3>



<p>The Titanium build is compatible with Kodi 18 and 17.6 Krypton versions. It offers live sports, movies, YouTube streaming, television shows, and even more content from the US and UK.</p>



<p>The comprehensive online library of the Titanium Build is due to add-ons such as DeathStar and Gaia.</p>



<p>DeathStar addon is relatively new to Kodi and comes with a wide collection of video content. Given that DeathStar comes with preloaded addons, it is easy to confuse it with a Kodi build. In reality, it is actually an addon created by 11 developers.</p>



<h3>Misfit Mods Lite</h3>



<p>The Misfits Mods Lite is only compatible with Kodi 18 Leia. With this build, you&#8217;ll have access to a variety of movies, TV shows, kids zone, etc. Popular addons on this platform include:</p>



<ul><li>Death Star</li><li>Sports Devil</li><li>Magic Dragon</li><li>Exodus Redux</li><li>Yoda</li></ul>



<p>Some of the features of Misfit Mods include a simple design, availability of top-rated addons, movies, and other media.</p>



<p>It is important to note that this easy-to-install build is also compatible with Real Debrid.</p>



<h3>Slamious</h3>



<p>For your streaming needs, the Slamious Kodi build has over 40 popular add-ons that come with lots of exciting features.</p>



<p>Given that this build has plenty of features, it may take a while before you get used to its user interface, but once you do, you&#8217;ll enjoy every bit of it.</p>



<p>One good thing about this build is that it is regularly updated, keeping it free from bugs while adding even more content for the best streaming experience.</p>



<p>Located in the Slaminous Repository, Slamious Kodi build works with both Kodi 18 and 17.6 versions.</p>



<p>The build is also compatible with most devices and operating systems, and has a user-friendly interface to allow easy navigation.</p>



<p>Lastly, this build is also safe and easy to install.</p>



<h3>Xanax</h3>



<p>Xanax Kodi build shares the same developer as the Durex build, which explains the striking resemblance between the two.</p>



<p>Unfortunately, the Durex build is no longer functional, but Xanax performs just as well.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The Xanax build has a clean interface and features popular add-ons like Yoda, Exodus Redox, Magic Dragon, Maverick Dragon, and many others. With all the options available, you&#8217;ll enjoy using this Kodi build.</p>



<p>The software also doesn’t take up too much space, so you don’t have to worry about your device lagging. Once you enable installation from unknown sources on Kodi, installation is safe and easy.</p>



<p>During the installation of Xanax, you will be prompted to choose between Leia and Krypton builds. Click on Leia if your Kodi version is 18 and above or the Krypton one if your Kodi version is below 18.1.</p>



<p>After closing and relaunching Kodi during the installation process of the Xanax build, you might still not be able to access some content.</p>



<p>To bypass these restrictions, consider installing a reliable VPN like CyberGhostVPN.</p>



<h3>Xontech</h3>



<p>Created by Team Falcon, this build works with Kodi 18 Lea only.</p>



<p>It is not only attractive but also easy to navigate. It comes with lots of streaming addons, which are regularly updated for an optimum performance.</p>



<p>The Xontech Kodi build has a futuristic design, something that makes it standout from the rest. It also groups its content in multiple categories, such as 3D-4K, A-Team, Movies, Shows, Music, Kids, Live TV, etc.</p>



<p>Popular addons on Xontech include Yoda, DeathStar, Exodus Redux, The Magic Dragon, Sports Devil, Hootloop V2, etc.</p>



<p>But before installing the Kodi build, make sure to reset Kodi to default settings on your device. To access your default settings and addons on Kodi, choose the Regular Install button instead of Fresh Install, located towards the end of the installation procedure.</p>



<p>The build works well on devices with commendable computational power; Xontech is built to stream content at a higher speed and better clarity.</p>



<h3>The Maze</h3>



<p>For more flexibility and improved usability, the Maze Kodi is a great option. The build rarely experiences performance issues, even when installed on a device with low specifications.</p>



<p>Furthermore, the Maze is compatible with various devices, such as Android TV Box, Kodi, Windows, Firestick, etc.</p>



<p>The Maze build originates from the Maze Wizard and has plenty of great add-ons to choose from, such as:</p>



<ul><li>Exodus Redux.</li><li>YouTube.</li><li>Sports Devil.</li><li>The Magic Dragon.</li><li>DeathStar.</li><li>The Loop.</li><li>And more.</li></ul>



<p>Other features of the Maze include:</p>



<ul><li>Well-organized content, making it easy to navigate and use.</li><li>Small-sized installation package (124 MB).</li><li>Customizable add-ons for a better streaming experience.</li><li>A clean interface and layout.</li><li>Compatibility with many streaming devices.</li></ul>



<p>Moments after installing the Maze, give it a few minutes to configure and update various add-ons and settings. Remember that most content hosted by third party streaming apps have copyright issues, but you can hide your online identity by using CyberGhostVPN.</p>



<h3>Silvo</h3>



<p>The Build works with Kodi 18.1, 18.9 Leia, and 17.6 Krypton. Silvo has everything you need from a typical build despite being relatively lightweight.</p>



<p>Popular add-ons on Silvo include Yoda, Maverick TV, cCloud TV, Sports Devil, and many others.</p>



<p>The add-ons allow you to watch movies, TV shows, documentaries, kid’s content, etc., from the US and UK.</p>



<p>Recently, the developers of Silvo reduced the size of the build from 540MB to 250MB, enabling users with low-storage devices to join the fun.</p>



<p>The Silvo Kodi build, created by the Multi Build Wizard Team, features 35 themes or skins. You can utilize the customizable features to adjust the build to suit your taste.</p>



<p>For Silvo to work, it needs encryption, which means you&#8217;ll need a reliable VPN like CyberGhostVPN.</p>



<p>One thing you need to know about this build is that the adult section is easily accessible from the main menu. Therefore, you need to proceed with caution, especially where minors are involved.</p>



<h3>Diggz Xenon Build</h3>



<p>Also known as the Diggz Xenon Plus, this build works only on Kodi 18.1 and is highly recommended for users who want to install Kodi on Android TV boxes and Firestick devices.</p>



<p>The user interface on Diggz Xenon Build has nice visuals and animations. The layout is also exciting and anticipatory, given that Xenon is mainly associated with superhero movies.</p>



<p>Some key features of Xenon Kodi build include:</p>



<ul><li>Streams without lagging</li><li>Plenty of games available</li><li>Incorporates popular addons such as Seren, Exodus, Yoda, etc.</li><li>Availability of content for all ages</li></ul>



<p>However, one thing you need to know about this build is that it is quite large; it takes up to 600MB storage space. But this is quite understandable considering its many useful feature and vast repository of movies.</p>



<h3>Reaper</h3>



<p>The build is a fan-favorite among Reddit Kodi users. Reaper constantly updates its repository and cuts off unnecessary or inactive add-ons to maintain efficiency. The developer team also carries out routine maintenance to get rid of bugs and any other issues that would affect the quality of stream.</p>



<p>Reaper&#8217;s interface is almost the same as Kodi’s; they both utilize the Estuary interface. Some notable a add-ons on Reaper include Seren, 13Clowns, Gaia, etc.</p>



<p>The Reaper build also houses other essential services like OpenInfo, Trakt, Premiumizer, and Real Debrid.</p>



<p>If simplicity is what you are looking for in a Kodi build, you&#8217;ll love the Reaper. And, of course, for a better and safer streaming experience, you&#8217;ll need a top-rated VPN, such as CyberGhostVPN.</p>



<h3>DaButcher</h3>



<p>For minimalists, DaButcher is one of the best bets. Due to its simplicity, users get to enjoy the seamless streaming performance. Like other builds, you also get popular add-ons, new skins for customization, the ability to add personalized widgets, among other exciting features.</p>



<p>DaButcher has a well-organized and easy-to-navigate content section. The menu comes with different categories, such as movies, TV shows, Live TV, Kids Zone, Comedy, Documentaries, Fitness, etc. In terms of the installation package size, it’s small, making it compatible with most low spec devices. The installation process of the build is easy and takes only 10-15 minutes of your time.</p>



<h3>BK Nox</h3>



<p>The BK Nox build has a futuristic interface, just like the Titanium build, attracting many users to the platform. The build also has decent performance levels despite carrying a large package size of 300 MB.</p>



<p>So, what makes the BK Nox Kodi build unique? It has a dedicated section for sports that includes sub-categories, such as live sports, baseball, and many others in the sports world. You can also try out the Real Debrid, Tempest, and Premiumizer services in the home menu for a better streaming experience.&nbsp;</p>



<p>BK Nox build is ideal for sports fanatics, given its wide collection of sports content from all corners of the world.</p>



<h3>Blue Magic</h3>



<p>The Blue Magic build started as the Luxury Build wizard, which hosted many other builds.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The build has a complete package of add-on supports, a smooth interface for easy customization, and multiple streaming options. Blue Magic’s small size also translates to good performance, and you can access the vast online library of movies, TV series, Live TV, and sports channels seamlessly.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The Blue Magic’s team regularly updates its add-ons and plugins, saving you the trouble of having to do it yourself manually. Installation of Blue Magic is straightforward and besides, this build is compatible with the Kodi 18 and Kodi 17.6 versions.</p>



<p>One of the most standout features of this build is the <strong>free section</strong>, which lets you watch live TV without IPTV subscription.</p>



<h3>Streamline</h3>



<p>Streamline was developed explicitly for Kodi version 18 and is compatible with all the Leia versions. The build was launched recently and has gained a lot of traction.</p>



<p>Streamline’s interface has animations, custom menus, and a unique homepage to streamline your streaming experience. The build saves your progress on movies and TV shows which is unique and convenient.</p>



<p>For instance, if you watch a movie, stop halfway and then resume later, the system will provide you with the option to resume from where you previously left.</p>



<p>Streamline also hosts Trakt and Real Debrid, allowing you to sync all your data across your Kodi builds.</p>



<p>Popular add-ons on Streamline include: At the Flix, Rising Tides, Planet MMA, SportsDevil, Magic Dragon, Exodus Redux, and more.</p>



<h3>Grindhouse</h3>



<p>The Grindhouse build is ideal for classics lovers. The build has a smooth user interface that is easy to use and hosts plenty of content. You get to watch old movies, TV series, and a lot of other content to fill you with nostalgia. The build also has subtitle addons that you can utilize to enhance your movie experience.</p>



<p>Grindhouse’s performance is also quite fast, allowing you to stream content with little to no buffering. The add-ons provided with this build include Numb3r5, Magic Dragon, Jor-El, The Red Queen, Aeon Nox, among others. However, streaming content using the Grindhouse build is not legal, and you might need a trustworthy VPN that doesn’t keep your logs.</p>



<p>CyberGhost VPN is a great example of such a VPN.</p>



<h3>Equinox</h3>



<p>Equinox is among the top Kodi builds due to its clean and elegant layout. The build is quite large (400 MB), requiring a lot of installation space, therefore not suitable for low storage devices.</p>



<p>Equinox comes with various add-ons such as Genre TV, Genie TV, Sports, Yoda, Sports Devil, Merin Project, Genesis Reborn, etc.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Some impressive features of the Equinox build include:</p>



<ul><li>A large number of add-ons to choose from.</li><li>Access to the Genie TV premium service.</li><li>Beautiful, easy-to-use interface.</li><li>Regular updates.</li><li>Availability of adult section.</li><li>Extensive library of movies, TV shows, music, and Live TV.</li></ul>



<p>Equinox derives from the Genie TV repository, which was launched in 2018. It comes with a broad list of addons to choose from. Examples include:</p>



<ul><li>Merin Project</li><li>Monster Munch</li><li>Pure Sport</li><li>Maverick TV</li><li>Now Music</li><li>Genie TV</li><li>At the Flix</li><li>Genesis Reborn</li><li>Big Star Movies</li><li>Cartoon 8</li></ul>



<h3>The Joker</h3>



<p>The Joker build comes lightweight features, suitable for low memory devices such as Firestick.&nbsp;</p>



<p>When you install the Joker build, you&#8217;ll have access to movies, documentaries, sports, music, and more entertaining content.</p>



<p>Some other impressive features of the Joker build include:</p>



<ul><li>Huge database of addons with a lot of media content.</li><li>Clean, customizable and easy-to-navigate interface.</li><li>Allows you to download themes and skins or choose from the wide selection offered.</li><li>Compatible with most devices and platforms.</li></ul>



<p>Given that this build is relatively small and lightweight, it is easy to install and also performs greatly.</p>



<h3>The Grind</h3>



<p>The Grind Kodi build works well on Kodi version 18.1, 18.9, and 17.6 Krypton. Fire TV Guru developers created the build, which works incredibly well on most platforms.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Popular add-ons on the grind include Venom, 7 Of 9, Exodus Redux, The Crew, The Magic Dragon, and many more. When you launch the build, you will have access to various types of online media, such as TV shows, live TV, sports, Pay Per View content, and different kid’s shows.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Installation of the Grind build on Kodi is easy and only 350 MB storage space. Given that this build is lightweight, it performs even better, making it compatible even on devices with small RAM sizes.</p>



<h3>Plutonium</h3>



<p>You&#8217;ll find this build in the EzzerMacs Repository. Plutonium’s user interface is vibrant, has outstanding animations, and comes with popular add-ons like Magic Dragon, DeathStar, Yoda, Sports Devil, etc.</p>



<p>This build is ideal for Amazon FireStick 4k.</p>



<p>Additionally, it is also compatible with many other devices, such as:</p>



<ul><li>Fire TVs</li><li>Fire TV Cubes</li><li>Android TV boxes</li><li>NVIDIA SHIELDS</li></ul>



<p>This build is about 160MB, which is pretty lightweight when compared to other builds we have reviewed so far. One thing you need to know is when you install Plutonium Kodi build for the first time, it may appear slow. This shouldn&#8217;t be a problem; the build updates addons and other features in the background, which explains the (temporary)</p>



<p>reduced processing speed.</p>



<p>Other great features by Plutonium include:</p>



<ul><li>Massive inventory of tools and addons at your disposal.</li><li>Multiple skins and design layouts that you can easily download and install.</li><li>Clean, organized, and easy-to-navigate layout, allowing easy personalization.</li><li>Compatible with most streaming services such as Roku, Chromecast, Smart TV, AppleTV, etc.</li><li>Works on almost all operating systems such as iOS, Windows, Android, Amazon, etc.</li></ul>



<h3>CellarDoor TV</h3>



<p>The CellarDoor TV is one of the best Kodi builds in the market; it houses multiple builds compatible with the Krypton version of Kodi.</p>



<p>All the builds on the platform come with add-ons containing multiple media resources. Examples of add-ons you&#8217;ll find on this platform include The Magic Dragon, SportsDevil, Seren, Numbers, etc.</p>



<p>Some key CellarDoor features and components include:</p>



<ul><li>Speedy performance, simplicity and stability.</li><li>User-friendly interface, which resembles the default estuary skin</li><li>Multiple streaming categories, such as TV Shows, Movies, Kids Zone, Weather, Sports, etc.</li></ul>



<p>CellarDoor is compatible with Kodi 18 Leia and 17.6 Krypton versions.</p>



<p>When using Kodi builds, such as CellarDoor, you should always remember that you (the end-user) are responsible for whatever you stream online.</p>



<p>Therefore, to protect yourself from third parties accessing your information when streaming your favorite TV show, free movies, or any other kind of content, you&#8217;ll need a premium VPN such as CyberGhostVPN.</p>



<p>This VPN won&#8217;t log your data, meaning no one will keep track of whatever you do online.</p>



<h3>SG Wizard</h3>



<p>The SG Wizard build has a collection of builds with Leia 18 compatibility. The builds come in a small installation package, and integrate seamlessly on a variety of platforms. With the SG Wizard Build, it is nearly impossible to run out of content to watch.</p>



<p>There is never a dull day with this incredible build for Kodi.</p>



<p>SG wizard builds range from 172 MB (SG Professional) to 230 MB (SG Upscon). The builds aren&#8217;t the most attractive, but come with commendable performance, given that they are pretty lightweight.</p>



<p>Popular add-ons on the SG Wizard include Fire Cat, Monster Munch, cCloud Tv, Supremacy, DAB Radi and Angelus.</p>



<h3>Duff Light</h3>



<p>Do you need a TV streaming device for Amazon Firestick and Android Boxes? Duff Light is a great option to consider.</p>



<p>This build is compatible with TVs and personal computers.</p>



<p>The Duff Light build has a sleek and simple skin, is regularly updated, and comes with a wide variety of addons to choose from.</p>



<p>The build has addons such as Kratos Reborn, suitable for most of your streaming needs. Despite having a vast collection of addons pre-installed, Duff Light still offers you the freedom to install other add-ons of your choice.</p>



<h3>Hard Nox</h3>



<p>The Hard Nox build resembles the No Limits Magic Kodi Build, which also utilizes the Aeon Nox 5: Silvo Skin.</p>



<p>It is compatible with Kodi 18 Leia and Kodi 17.6 Krypton.</p>



<p>Located in the MisFits Repository, Hard Nox is a great Kodi build for Firestick.</p>



<p>Here are some common characteristics of this build.</p>



<ul><li>User-friendliness.</li><li>Great content to choose from.</li><li>Multiple categories, such as Kids, Fans, Movies, Fitness, Sports and more.</li><li>Integration with Real Debrid &#8211; highly recommended.</li></ul>



<h3>EzzerMacs</h3>



<p>The EzzerMacs build hosts various Kodi builds compatible with Kodi 18 Leia. The build also has third party builds you can choose from.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The builds hosted on EzzerMacs include:</p>



<ul><li>Wullie’s Mini Sci-Fi</li><li>Plutonium</li><li>Peaky Blinders</li><li>Nymeria 80s Retro Wave</li><li>Franks II Nymeria Fortnite and others ranging from 15 MB to 284 MB</li></ul>



<p>EzzerMacs comes with great features to enhance your viewing experience. Examples include:</p>



<ul><li>Neat, clutter-free interface with the standard design, themes, and skins for customization.</li><li>Lightweight and compatible with low-memory devices.</li><li>Vast collection of content to choose from.</li><li>Cross-platform compatibility (android, iOS, MAC, Linux, Windows, and more).</li><li>Provides links from different sources</li></ul>



<h3>Innovation Kodi Build</h3>



<p>The Innovation build comes in two versions:</p>



<ul><li>Innovation Colors Adult.</li><li>Innovation Colors Family.</li></ul>



<p>The build also features various Kodi addons, such as Numbers, Nole Cinema, Sports Devil, Seren, Magic Dragon, and many others.</p>



<p>Innovation is compatible with many devices, allows fast and easy access to streaming content, and works well on devices with low specs.</p>



<p>The interface is user-friendly and easy to navigate.</p>



<p>For more content, you can try out other addons available on this build to make sure you never miss anything.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The Innovation build is also easy to install and compatible with Kodi 18 and 17.6 versions.</p>



<h3>Doomzday</h3>



<p>The Doomzday build has various lightweight builds which work well on multiple devices such as Firestick, Android TV, Chromecast, and many more. The build, launched in 2019, offers other builds you can download and install on PCs and mobile devices. Doomzday is popular because of its usability, stability, and easy navigation.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Some examples of builds that come with Doomzday include:</p>



<ul><li>Easy Rider</li><li>USA lite</li><li>Voodoo Mojo</li><li>Endura</li><li>BK Nox</li><li>Templarious</li><li>Ancient Egypt</li><li>Kev’s Angel</li><li>Arceus</li><li>House of Cards</li></ul>



<h3>Dominus</h3>



<p>The Dominus Kodi build is downloadable via the Ares Wizard and comes with several plugins and addons for the best streaming experience.</p>



<p>The Dominus features a user-friendly layout that allows easy navigation, including different categories available on the home screen, such as Movies, Discover, Sports, Kidzone, Tools, System, and more.</p>



<p>Some popular addons that come with this build include Numbers, The Crew, Seren, Shadow and The Magic Dragon. After installation, Dominus allows you to view pre recorded news, TV Pro, TV shows, documentaries, live TV, sports, kids, and many more.&nbsp;</p>



<h3>Xbox Alpha</h3>



<p>You will find Xbox Alpha in the Lockdown repository. This Kodi build is compatible with Kodi 18 Leia.</p>



<p>Popular addons to expect from this build include:</p>



<ul><li>Neptune Rising</li><li>Pure Sports</li><li>Maverick TV</li></ul>



<p>The Xbox Alpha build is still in its development stages, but you can still access movies, Live TV and other media content on this platform.</p>



<h3>Nephilim</h3>



<p>The Nephilim build is created by Man Cave and is a smooth running platform on Kodi. Also relatively new, it is compatible with many devices, especially FireStick.</p>



<h3>Nefarious</h3>



<p>The Nefarious build requires installation from an external source, and it’s located in the LostKodi Wizard. The popularity of this build is due to the smooth interface, a good content library, a wide selection of categories, and its small size.</p>



<p>The size enhances performance and compatibility with low spec devices.</p>



<p>The Nefarious build has different categories such as Movies, TV Shows, Music, Kids, Catchup, Apps, System and Power.</p>



<h3>Fire TV Guru</h3>



<p>Developed for the FireStick 18.6 Leia,&nbsp;Fire TV Guru build is popular worldwide due to its clean design, fast response and user-friendliness. Fire TV Guru is one of the best Kodi builds for Firestick.</p>



<p>The only downside with Fire TV Guru is that it is around 600 MB, which requires more storage space. The large size of this build means it may not be the best addon for low spec devices.</p>



<p>The build is compatible with the Amazon Fire TV box and Fire TV Stick, and you can stream live TV, videos and premium movies for free.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The Fire TV Guru also comes with pre installed addons such as Covenant, Elysium, Tinklepad, Bob Unleashed, Specto, and many more.</p>



<p>The build allows you to update skins and other settings seamlessly, and has 13 different menu categories. Some examples of these categories include Movies, Her Place, Music and Streams, Kids Corner and Sports.</p>



<p>The music section is also popular on this build, thanks to a good number of audio options such as YouTube, TuneIn Radio and Now Music. Fire TV Guru has an installation package of about 300 MB and was built specifically for Amazon Streaming Services.</p>



<h3>Turbo</h3>



<p>Turbo is pretty new Kodi build in the market, but has gained a lot of attention due to its features, allowing an enjoyable streaming experience.</p>



<p>Despite having many add-ons, Turbo Kodi is lightweight, needing only 260 MBs worth of storage space.</p>



<p>The small size allows easy installation, fast performance and compatibility with small RAM devices. The main addons on the platform include Covenant, Magic Dragon, Stream Army, Live Premiership, Star-Tec, Neptune Rising, WWE, MMA, Good Fellas, and more.</p>



<p><strong>Khaos</strong></p>



<p>Khaos build has had rising popularity over the years and features all the latest add-ons for your TV Shows, Movies, Sports, Live TV, Cartoons, etc. The build also has a small installation package size of 140 MB, ranking it among the best lightweight Kodi builds in the market.</p>



<p>The build is also compatible with Kodi Krypton and 18 Leia Kodi versions.</p>



<p>In the Khaos build, you&#8217;ll get a good number of popular add-ons such as Now Music USA, Maverick TV, Star Tec. The add-ons gives you access to movies, fitness content, music, comedy, horror, and a lot more.</p>



<h2>Frequently Asked Questions About Kodi Builds</h2>



<p>Given that Kodi builds derive from different developers, many Kodi users have a lot of questions concerning these platforms. Here are some of the most common, and their answers.&nbsp;</p>



<h3>Why Do I Need A VPN To Use Kodi Builds?</h3>



<p>Some Kodi builds contain pirated content that could land you in legal trouble. Also, government, ISPs, and other third parties such as hackers can easily track your activities online when using Kodi. To keep yourself protected always, you’ll need a VPN.</p>



<p>A VPN masks your IP address, making it difficult for third parties to identify you on the internet. When that happens, it becomes nearly impossible for anyone to tell what you are doing on the internet.&nbsp;</p>



<h3>What Is A Good VPN for Kodi Builds?</h3>



<p>There are countless VPN in the market, but it is always advisable to choose the one that best suits your purpose. For example, when it comes to live streaming movies and TV shows on platforms such as Kodi, CyberGhostVPN is one of the best VPNs out there.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This VPN has a strict no-logs policy, dedicated streaming server, Wi-Fi protection, 45-day money back guarantee, and more than 7100 servers worldwide.&nbsp;</p>



<h3>What Is The Difference Between A Kodi Build, Repository and Addon?</h3>



<p>A Kodi build is basically a collection of popular pre installed add ons. It also contains numerous Kodi skins.</p>



<p>On the other hand, a Kodi repository, also known as a Repo, is a container where Kodi addons are stored.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And finally, a Kodi addon is a collection of packages that have certain features and functionalities that are not included with Kodi.</p>



<p>To further understand what a Kodi addon is, think of your computer’s internet browser. If you are using Chrome, for example, you can install extensions from Google, to improve the functionality of your browser.</p>



<p>Browser extensions serve different purposes, such as taking full-page screenshots, blocking ads, translating pages, changing the appearance of the browser, etc.&nbsp;</p>



<h3>Why Should I Enable Unknown Sources Before Installing Any Build For Kodi?</h3>



<p>Anything that is not offered in the official Kodi repository is considered to be a third-party. Meaning, it has not been verified by the Kodi team of developers, and may have certain issues, such as copyright infringement. By allowing installation from unknown sources, it is a way of acknowledging that you understand the risks that come with this decision and that you, not Kodi, will be fully liable of any consequence that may arise from the installation.&nbsp;</p>



<h3>Why Should I Reset Kodi To Factory Settings Before Installing Any Build?</h3>



<p>Resetting Kodi before installing any build has three main advantages. It frees up memory and space and avoids any compatibility issues that may arise during the installation process.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Now that you know a thing or two about the best Kodi builds, you should not have a problem choosing the right one for you. While at it, please remember that having a great VPN like CyberGhostVPN will improve your viewing experience while at the same time keeping you anonymous online.</p>



<h3>What&#8217;s The Best Working Kodi Build For Movies, TV Shows and Sports?</h3>



<p>We&#8217;ve listed some great examples in this article. To recap, Khaos, Dominus, Innovation, CellarDoor TV, and Plutonium are a great place to start if you are looking for high-quality movies, TV shows, sports, and so much more!</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prooffreader.com/best-kodi-builds/">Best Kodi Builds</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prooffreader.com">ProoFFreader</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>AdultFlix Kodi Addon &#124; Install and Use</title>
		<link>https://www.prooffreader.com/how-to-install-adultflix-kodi-addon/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[James Austin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 03 Aug 2021 12:54:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Kodi]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.prooffreader.com/?p=1160</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>What is AdultFlix addon? AdultFlix is an adult Kodi addon that scrapes content from third-party 18+ sources to give you ... </p>
<p class="read-more-container"><a title="AdultFlix Kodi Addon &#124; Install and Use" class="read-more button" href="https://www.prooffreader.com/how-to-install-adultflix-kodi-addon/#more-1160" aria-label="More on AdultFlix Kodi Addon &#124; Install and Use">Read more</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prooffreader.com/how-to-install-adultflix-kodi-addon/">AdultFlix Kodi Addon | Install and Use</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prooffreader.com">ProoFFreader</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<h2><strong>What is AdultFlix addon?</strong></h2>



<p>AdultFlix is an adult Kodi addon that scrapes content from third-party 18+ sources to give you hundreds of thousands of adult video content. Scraped sources include major adult and XXX sites such as <a href="http://www.prooffreader.com/chaturbate-kodi-addon/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Chaturbate</a>, Daftporn, RedTube, FourTube, Madthumbs, Motherless, Pandamovie, Perfectgirls, PornHD, PornHub, and more.  </p>



<p>It ranks as one of the best porn addons available today in terms of content variety and performance. You can find some unique content types like comics, scenes, images, clips, and live cam.</p>



<p>The well-laid-out interface and organized structure make it easy to find and enjoy content with just a few clicks. You can stream videos in HD quality for most categories without any issues.</p>



<p>AdultFlix Kodi addon has additional functional features that make it more versatile. These functions include Parental Control, Downloads, View History, and Favorites.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>As of the time of writing this guide, this addon</strong> <strong>is not compatible with Kodi 19 Matrix but works on other versions up to Kodi 18.9</strong></p>



<h2><strong>AdultFlix Repository</strong></h2>



<p>AdultFlix can be found in the following repositories.</p>



<ul><li>TVAddons Repo (<a href="http://fusion.tvaddons.co/">http://fusion.tvaddons.co</a>)</li><li>Ghost Repo (<a href="http://ghost-repo.de/">http://ghost-repo.de/</a>)</li></ul>



<h2>Guide To Install Ghost Repository and AdultFlix Kodi Addon</h2>



<h3><strong>First Things First – Enable Unknown Sources</strong></h3>



<ol><li>Go to Home Screen, click on the gear icon, click on system, select “add-ons” on the left side menu, allow installation from “Unknown Sources”, click “yes” when the warning popup appears.&nbsp;</li></ol>



<h3><strong>Installing Ghost Repository</strong></h3>



<ol><li>Go to Home Screen, click on Gear Icon, click on File Manager;</li><li>Click Add Source, Click None, Type in the URL “<strong>http://ghost-repo.de/</strong>” and click Done;</li><li>Pick a name for the repository (i.e. Ghost) and enter it in the bottom box and click OK;</li><li>Click back until you are in the Main Menu, select Addons on the left side&nbsp;</li><li>Click on the Box Symbol (top left corner), Choose Install From ZIP file, click Yes when a warning appears;</li><li>Open “Ghost” Source and choose this file: “<strong>.zip</strong>”</li><li>A notification saying “Installed Successfully” will appear.</li></ol>



<h3><strong>Installing Adult Flix Kodi Addon</strong></h3>



<ol><li>Go to Home Screen, find Add-ons on the left side, select the box symbol (top left corner) to get to the Addon Browser;</li><li>Click on Install From Repository, choose Ghost Repo, click on Video Addons in the category section;</li><li>Click on AdultFlix and hit install, select OK to confirm the installation of dependencies (don’t appear in Kodi 19 Matrix);</li><li>A notification saying “<strong>Installed Successfully</strong>” will appear;</li><li>You have now downloaded Adult Flix to Kodi. You can now access the addon from the main menu.&nbsp;</li></ol>



<h2><strong>AdultFlix Alternatives</strong></h2>



<p>Similar add-ons to AdultFlix include:</p>



<ul><li>LubeTube – this addon can be found in the TVaddons.co Repository. It is often described as the YouTube of free porn, boasting over 51 different porn categories.</li></ul>



<ul><li><a href="http://www.prooffreader.com/videodevil-kodi-addon/">VideoDevil </a>– this addon has a huge collection of adult material from popular sites like PornoTube, xHamster, PornoTube, Boysfood, and Tube8. <strong><a href="http://www.prooffreader.com/videodevil-kodi-addon/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Video Devil</a> is compatible with Kodi 19 Matrix</strong>. </li></ul>



<ul><li>EFUKT – if you are a fan of amateur porn, this addon is for you. It has a simple layout and interfaces with categories such as Latest Videos, Trending, Random Videos, and EFUKT Favorites.</li></ul>



<h2><strong>Adult Flix Addon Sections and Channels</strong></h2>



<p>1. &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; Comics</p>



<p>2. &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; Vintage</p>



<p>3. &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; Live Cams</p>



<p>4. &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; Hentai</p>



<p>5. &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; Porn Scenes</p>



<p>6. &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; Fetish</p>



<p>7. &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; Pictures</p>



<p>8. &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; Virtual Reality</p>



<p>9. &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; Porn Movies</p>



<p>10. &nbsp; Tubes</p>



<h2><strong>Common Problems and Fixes</strong></h2>



<p>AdultFlix addon has an active developer community that maintains and updates the addon. This ensures that there are fewer issues to deal with when using the addon. We tested most of the links and they are working just fine. However, you might encounter the occasional issues found with other addons. Here’s how to fix them.</p>



<h3><strong>Error Check Log</strong></h3>



<p>As you continue to stream content with the addon, your backend data is stored and cached for easier access the next time you want to enjoy watching the same content. A filled-up cache causes the error check log issue to appear every time you launch the addon. You can fix this issue by clearing up your cache in device settings and rebooting the app. However, if you still see the error again, it’s time to install the addon afresh.</p>



<h3 class="gb-headline gb-headline-90005f0e gb-headline-text"><strong>Stream Not Working</strong></h3>



<p>This type of error is caused by a number of factors which may include a poor internet connection or broken links. Other times, your Internet Service Provider (ISP) may have blocked your access to certain sites. This could be the case if you live in a region/country where adult content is illegal to stream.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Check that your internet connection is fast and try refreshing the link. You can wait up to 15 seconds for some videos to stream/load and start playing. Clearing the cache will also help fix this problem. If the error persists, then it is likely caused by a hosting error on the server.</p>



<h3 class="gb-headline gb-headline-db6e091e gb-headline-text"><strong>Failed to Install a Dependency</strong></h3>



<p>A dependency error appears when there is a discrepancy in the python code dependencies of the addon. This can prevent you from installing any new addons. To fix this problem, check that you are using the latest version of Kodi. Also, clearing up the cache data will fix this issue.</p>



<h3 class="gb-headline gb-headline-ebac4673 gb-headline-text"><strong>Stream Authorization</strong></h3>



<p>This type of error prevents you from streaming content directly as you are required to enter a valid token to access content. While this is not a technical error of the addon, it prevents you from streaming popular and high quality videos.</p>



<p>You can use debrid services such as Premiumize and Real Debrid to access high quality streams. To use these premium services you must first remove the free hosters from the app settings.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Matching the hosting sites with a static IP address will also fix this problem.</p>



<h2><strong>Is AdultFlix Addon Legal?</strong></h2>



<p>AdultFlix addon cannot be downloaded from the official Kodi repository. Also, the addon does not host any of its content but scrapes from other websites. This poses the risk of streaming copyrighted material which may put you at odds with your local authorities. So it is important to know which copyright laws are applicable to your country/region.</p>



<h2><strong>FAQ</strong></h2>



<h3><strong>Does AdultFlix Addon Use a PIN System?</strong></h3>



<p>No, the add-on doesn’t use a PIN system. You will not be required to generate a PIN in order to watch content with this addon. Some popular adult addons like XXX-O-DUS and FapZone require users to enter a unique generated token in order to access adult content. This is not the case with AdultFlix and you can instantly watch adult content as long as you are 18+.</p>



<ul><li><a href="http://www.prooffreader.com/use-and-install-xxx-o-dus-kodi-addon/">Guide To Install XXX-O-DUS Add-on</a></li><li><a href="http://www.prooffreader.com/use-and-install-fapzone-kodi-addon/">Guide To Install FapZone Add-on</a></li></ul>



<h3><strong>Do I need a VPN to Unblock Content?</strong></h3>



<p>Yes. We highly recommend using a VPN to watch content with AdultFlix addon. Your ISP may block you from accessing certain types of content, especially X-rated material. Getting a reliable VPN will unblock such content.</p>



<h2><strong>Final Thoughts</strong></h2>



<p>AdultFlix is a great Kodi add-on boasting of some unique XXX categories not found in most other addons. Cool features like Search allow you to find the exact type of content you&#8217;re looking for. The addon offers a wide range of content, more than any other adult addon currently.&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prooffreader.com/how-to-install-adultflix-kodi-addon/">AdultFlix Kodi Addon | Install and Use</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prooffreader.com">ProoFFreader</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
