<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<rdf:RDF
 xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
 xmlns="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/"
 xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
 xmlns:taxo="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/taxonomy/"
 xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
 xmlns:syn="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
 xmlns:admin="http://webns.net/mvcb/"
>

<channel rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/">
<title>cs.NI updates on arXiv.org</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">Computer Science -- Networking and Internet Architecture (cs.NI) updates on the arXiv.org e-print archive</description>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:date>2022-11-03T20:30:00-05:00</dc:date>
<dc:publisher>help@arxiv.org</dc:publisher>
<dc:subject>Computer Science -- Networking and Internet Architecture</dc:subject>
<syn:updateBase>1901-01-01T00:00+00:00</syn:updateBase>
<syn:updateFrequency>1</syn:updateFrequency>
<syn:updatePeriod>daily</syn:updatePeriod>
<items>
 <rdf:Seq>
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01712" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01726" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01759" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01763" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01924" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01980" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2205.03832" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2209.09775" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01016" />
 </rdf:Seq>
</items>
<image rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif" />
</channel>
<image rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif">
<title>arXiv.org</title>
<url>http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif</url>
<link>http://arxiv.org/</link>
</image>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01712">
<title>Trust Management for Internet of Things: A Systematic Literature Review. (arXiv:2211.01712v1 [cs.NI])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01712</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Internet of Things (IoT) is a network of devices that communicate with each
other through the internet and provides intelligence to industry and people.
These devices are running in potentially hostile environments, so the need for
security is critical. Trust Management aims to ensure the reliability of the
network by assigning a trust value in every node indicating its trust level.
This paper presents an exhaustive survey of the current Trust Management
techniques for IoT, a classification based on the methods used in every work
and a discussion of the open challenges and future research directions.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Konsta_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Alyzia Maria Konsta&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Lafuente_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Alberto Lluch Lafuente&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Dragoni_N/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Nicola Dragoni&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01726">
<title>SQUID: Faster Analytics via Sampled Quantiles Data-structure. (arXiv:2211.01726v1 [cs.DS])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01726</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Measurement is a fundamental enabler of network applications such as load
balancing, attack detection and mitigation, and traffic engineering. A key
building block in many critical measurement tasks is \emph{q-MAX}, where we
wish to find the largest $q$ values in a number stream. A standard approach of
maintaining a heap of the largest $q$ values ordered results in logarithmic
runtime, which is too slow for large measurements. Modern approaches attain a
constant runtime by removing small items in bulk and retaining the largest $q$
items at all times. Yet, these approaches are bottlenecked by an expensive
quantile calculation method.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We propose SQUID, a method that redesigns q-MAX to allow the use of
\emph{approximate quantiles}, which we can compute efficiently, thereby
accelerating the solution and, subsequently, many measurement tasks. We
demonstrate the benefit of our approach by designing a novel weighted heavy
hitters data structure that is faster and more accurate than the existing
alternatives. Here, we combine our previous techniques with a lazy deletion of
small entries, which expiates the maintenance process and increases the
accuracy. We also demonstrate the applicability of our algorithmic approach in
a general algorithmic scope by implementing the LRFU cache policy with a
constant update time. Furthermore, we also show the practicality of SQUID for
improving real-world networked systems, by implementing a P4 prototype of SQUID
for in-network caching and demonstrating how SQUID enables a wide spectrum of
score-based caching policies directly on a P4 switch.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Ben_Basat_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ran Ben-Basat&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Einziger_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Gil Einziger&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Han_W/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Wenchen Han&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Tayh_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Bilal Tayh&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01759">
<title>Resource-aware Deep Learning for Wireless Fingerprinting Localization. (arXiv:2211.01759v1 [cs.NI])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01759</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Location based services, already popular with end users, are now inevitably
becoming part of new wireless infrastructures and emerging business processes.
The increasingly popular Deep Learning (DL) artificial intelligence methods
perform very well in wireless fingerprinting localization based on extensive
indoor radio measurement data. However, with the increasing complexity these
methods become computationally very intensive and energy hungry, both for their
training and subsequent operation. Considering only mobile users, estimated to
exceed 7.4 billion by the end of 2025, and assuming that the networks serving
these users will need to perform only one localization per user per hour on
average, the machine learning models used for the calculation would need to
perform $65 \times 10^{12}$ predictions per year. Add to this equation tens of
billions of other connected devices and applications that rely heavily on more
frequent location updates, and it becomes apparent that localization will
contribute significantly to carbon emissions unless more energy-efficient
models are developed and used. In this Chapter, we discuss the latest results
and trends in wireless localization and look at paths towards achieving more
sustainable AI. We then elaborate on a methodology for computing DL model
complexity, energy consumption and carbon footprint and show on a concrete
example how to develop a more resource-aware model for fingerprinting. We
finally compare relevant works in terms of complexity and training CO$_2$
footprint.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Cerar_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Gregor Cerar&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Bertalanic_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Bla&amp;#x17e; Bertalani&amp;#x10d;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Fortuna_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Carolina Fortuna&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01763">
<title>Implementation of the Digital QS-SVM-based Beamformer on an FPGA Platform. (arXiv:2211.01763v1 [cs.NI])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01763</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;To address practical challenges in establishing and maintaining robust
wireless connectivity such as multi-path effects, low latency, size reduction,
and high data rate, the digital beamformer is performed by the hybrid antenna
array at the frequency of operation of 10 GHz. The proposed digital beamformer,
as a spatial filter, is capable of performing Direction of Arrival (DOA)
estimation and beamforming. The most well-established machine learning
technique of support vector machine (SVM) for the DoA estimation is limited to
problems with linearly-separable datasets.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To overcome the aforementioned constraint, in the proposed beamformer, the
QS-SVM classifier with a small regularizer has been used for the DoA estimation
in addition to the two beamforming techniques of LCMV and MVDR. The
QS-SVM-based beamformer has been deployed in an FPGA board, as demonstrated in
detail in this work. The implementation results have verified the strong
performance of the QS-SVM-based beamformer in suppressing undesired signals,
deep nulls with powers less than -10 dB in undesired signals, and transferring
desired signals. Furthermore, we have demonstrated that the performance of the
QS-SVM-based beamformer consists of other advantages of average latency time in
the order of milliseconds, performance efficiency of more than 90\%, and
throughput of about 100\%.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Komeylian_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Somayeh Komeylian&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Paolini_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Christopher Paolini&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01924">
<title>A New Agent-Based Intelligent Network Architecture. (arXiv:2211.01924v1 [cs.NI])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01924</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The advent of 5G and the design of its architecture has become possible
because of the previous individual scientific works and standardization efforts
on cloud computing and network softwarization. Software-defined Networking and
Network Function Virtualization started separately to find their convolution
into 5G network architecture. Then, the ongoing design of the future beyond 5G
(B5G) and 6G network architecture cannot overlook the pivotal inputs of
different independent standardization efforts about autonomic networking,
service-based communication systems, and multi-access edge computing. This
article provides the design and the characteristics of an agent-based,
softwarized, and intelligent architecture, which coherently condenses and
merges the independent proposed architectural works by different
standardization working groups and bodies. This novel work is a helpful means
for the design and standardization process of the futureB5G and 6G network
architecture.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Arzo_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Sisay Tadesse Arzo&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Scotece_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Domenico Scotece&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Bassoli_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Riccardo Bassoli&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Granelli_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Fabrizio Granelli&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Foschini_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Luca Foschini&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Fitzek_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Frank H.P. Fitzek&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01980">
<title>Learning to Configure Computer Networks with Neural Algorithmic Reasoning. (arXiv:2211.01980v1 [cs.NI])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01980</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We present a new method for scaling automatic configuration of computer
networks. The key idea is to relax the computationally hard search problem of
finding a configuration that satisfies a given specification into an
approximate objective amenable to learning-based techniques. Based on this
idea, we train a neural algorithmic model which learns to generate
configurations likely to (fully or partially) satisfy a given specification
under existing routing protocols. By relaxing the rigid satisfaction
guarantees, our approach (i) enables greater flexibility: it is
protocol-agnostic, enables cross-protocol reasoning, and does not depend on
hardcoded rules; and (ii) finds configurations for much larger computer
networks than previously possible. Our learned synthesizer is up to 490x faster
than state-of-the-art SMT-based methods, while producing configurations which
on average satisfy more than 93% of the provided requirements.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Beurer_Kellner_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Luca Beurer-Kellner&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Vechev_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Martin Vechev&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Vanbever_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Laurent Vanbever&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Velickovic_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Petar Veli&amp;#x10d;kovi&amp;#x107;&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2205.03832">
<title>Blockchain Application on the Internet of Vehicles (IoV). (arXiv:2205.03832v2 [cs.NI] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2205.03832</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;With the rapid development of the Internet of Things (IoT) and its potential
integration with the traditional Vehicular Ad-Hoc Networks (VANETs), we have
witnessed the emergence of the Internet of Vehicles (IoV), which promises to
seamlessly integrate into smart transportation systems. However, the key
characteristics of IoV, such as high-speed mobility and frequent disconnections
make it difficult to manage its security and privacy. The Blockchain, as a
distributed tamper-resistant ledge, has been proposed as an innovative solution
that guarantees privacy-preserving yet secure schemes. In this paper, we review
recent literature on the application of blockchain to IoV, in particular, and
intelligent transportation systems in general.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Aung_N/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Nyothiri Aung&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Kechadi_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Tahar Kechadi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zhu_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Tao Zhu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zerdoumi_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Saber Zerdoumi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Guerbouz_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Tahar Guerbouz&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Dhelim_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Sahraoui Dhelim&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2209.09775">
<title>FedToken: Tokenized Incentives for Data Contribution in Federated Learning. (arXiv:2209.09775v2 [cs.LG] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2209.09775</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Incentives that compensate for the involved costs in the decentralized
training of a Federated Learning (FL) model act as a key stimulus for clients&apos;
long-term participation. However, it is challenging to convince clients for
quality participation in FL due to the absence of: (i) full information on the
client&apos;s data quality and properties; (ii) the value of client&apos;s data
contributions; and (iii) the trusted mechanism for monetary incentive offers.
This often leads to poor efficiency in training and communication. While
several works focus on strategic incentive designs and client selection to
overcome this problem, there is a major knowledge gap in terms of an overall
design tailored to the foreseen digital economy, including Web 3.0, while
simultaneously meeting the learning objectives. To address this gap, we propose
a contribution-based tokenized incentive scheme, namely \texttt{FedToken},
backed by blockchain technology that ensures fair allocation of tokens amongst
the clients that corresponds to the valuation of their data during model
training. Leveraging the engineered Shapley-based scheme, we first approximate
the contribution of local models during model aggregation, then strategically
schedule clients lowering the communication rounds for convergence and anchor
ways to allocate \emph{affordable} tokens under a constrained monetary budget.
Extensive simulations demonstrate the efficacy of our proposed method.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Pandey_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Shashi Raj Pandey&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Nguyen_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Lam Duc Nguyen&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Popovski_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Petar Popovski&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01016">
<title>Holographic-Type Communication for Digital Twin: A Learning-based Auction Approach. (arXiv:2211.01016v2 [cs.NI] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01016</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Digital Twin (DT) technologies, which aim to build digital replicas of
physical entities, are the key to providing efficient, concurrent simulation
and analysis of real-world objects. In displaying DTs, Holographic-Type
Communication (HTC), which supports the transmission of holographic data such
as Light Field (LF), can provide an immersive way for users to interact with
Holographic DTs (HDT). However, it is challenging to effectively allocate
interactive and resource-intensive HDT services among HDT users and providers.
In this paper, we integrate the paradigms of HTC and DT to form a HTC for DT
system, design a marketplace for HDT services where HDT users&apos; and providers&apos;
prices are evaluated by their valuation functions, and propose an auction-based
mechanism to match HDT services using a learning-based Double Dutch Auction
(DDA). Specifically, we apply DDA and train an agent acting as the auctioneer
to adjust the auction clock dynamically using Deep Reinforcement Learning
(DRL), aiming to achieve the best market efficiency. Simulation results
demonstrate that the proposed learning-based auctioneer can achieve
near-optimal social welfare at halved auction information exchange cost of the
baseline method.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zhang_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;XiuYu Zhang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Xu_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Minrui Xu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Tan_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Rui Tan&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Niyato_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Dusit Niyato&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
</rdf:RDF>