<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns:yt="http://www.youtube.com/xml/schemas/2015" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
 <link rel="self" href="http://www.youtube.com/feeds/videos.xml?channel_id=UCV4Rx1m-9HmtqHET7GjnVOA"/>
 <id>yt:channel:UCV4Rx1m-9HmtqHET7GjnVOA</id>
 <yt:channelId>UCV4Rx1m-9HmtqHET7GjnVOA</yt:channelId>
 <title>braintruffle</title>
 <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCV4Rx1m-9HmtqHET7GjnVOA"/>
 <author>
  <name>braintruffle</name>
  <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCV4Rx1m-9HmtqHET7GjnVOA</uri>
 </author>
 <published>2020-11-10T10:36:40+00:00</published>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:sSJmUmCHAJY</id>
  <yt:videoId>sSJmUmCHAJY</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCV4Rx1m-9HmtqHET7GjnVOA</yt:channelId>
  <title>The surprising variety of simulating fluids - a vivid exploration</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=sSJmUmCHAJY"/>
  <author>
   <name>braintruffle</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCV4Rx1m-9HmtqHET7GjnVOA</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-06-17T10:04:35+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-06-30T16:30:38+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>The surprising variety of simulating fluids - a vivid exploration</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/sSJmUmCHAJY?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i4.ytimg.com/vi/sSJmUmCHAJY/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>A vivid introduction to fluid simulation.

Topics covered: rarefied gas dynamics, continuum gas dynamics, fluid motion descriptions &amp; coordinates (spatially fixed (Eulerian), material-fixed (Lagrangian), arbitrary), reducibility aspects, motivation on modeling unresolved flow structures, ensemble averages of microscopically and macroscopically varying data, usefulness of the modeling hierarchy, simplifying and decoupling the evolution equations, Navier-Stokes equations, compressible flow and the incompressible flow assumptions, and buoyancy-driven flow (Boussinesq approximation).


Special thanks to my supporters:
-----------------------------------------------------
AxisAngles
Yuxuan Zhang
Houston Lucas
Patrick Gibson
... and all my patrons!

If you like what you see and want to support my work, join my Patreon feed. I really appreciate it!
https://www.patreon.com/braintruffle


Timetable:
-----------------
00:00 - What's going on
02:15 - Recap on continuous fluid fields
05:06 - Continuous evolution and local similarity
06:52 - Motion description and evolution equations
20:41 - Ensemble averages of macroscopic data
23:52 - Usefulness of the modeling hierarchy
25:13 - Playing with the equations
27:50 - Compressible and incompressible flow
32:39 - Buoyancy-driven flow
37:22 - Decoupling of the equations
39:30 - Thanks to my supporters and recap


Selected Learning Resources:
------------------------------------------------
02:15 - Continuous flow fields from rarefied gas dynamics and continuum gas dynamics: [1,2,3,4,5,6]
04:10 - Continuous perspective on the microscale; continuum micromechanics (to be discussed): [7]
06:52 - Fluid motion description and coordinates (spatially fixed (Eulerian), material-fixed (Lagrangian), arbitrary); evolution equations; material derivative; discretization aspects: [8,9,10]
22:05 - Ensemble averages of microscopic and macroscopic data; modeling unresolved flow structures; Kolmogorov microscales (to be discussed); turbulence modelling (to be discussed); 2d vs 3d turbulence (to be discussed): [1,11,12]
27:50 - Compressible flow; incompressible flow assumptions: [2]
32:39 - Buoyancy-driven flow (Boussinesq approximation); treating slight density variations: [13]
37:22 - Decoupling the equations: [2]

References:
[1] - Lecture Notes: from &quot;http://volkov.eng.ua.edu/ME591_491_NEGD/2017-Spring-NEGD-01-ElemKineticTheory.pdf&quot; to &quot;NEGD-06&quot;
[2] - Book: White, Frank M. &quot;Fluid mechanics.&quot; Tata McGraw-Hill Education, 2010.
[3] - Book: Anderson, John D. &quot;Governing equations of fluid dynamics. Computational fluid dynamics.&quot; Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg, 1992. 15-51.
[4] - Paper: Macrossan, M. N. &quot;Scaling parameters for hypersonic flow: correlation of sphere drag data.&quot;, 2007.
[5] - Lecture Notes: Cerfon, Antoine. &quot;Mechanics (Classical and Quantum).&quot; &quot;https://www.math.nyu.edu/~cerfon/mechanics.html&quot;
[6] - Lecture Notes: Kenkre, V. M.. &quot;Statistical Mechanics.&quot; &quot;https://www.unm.edu/~aierides/505/&quot; specifically &quot;.../bbgky2.pdf&quot; &amp;  &quot;.../bbgky3.pdf&quot;
[7] - Paper: Zaoui, André. &quot;Continuum micromechanics: survey.&quot; Journal of Engineering Mechanics-ASCE 128.8 (2002): 808-816.
[8] - Essay: Price, James F. &quot;Lagrangian and eulerian representations of fluid flow: Kinematics and the equations of motion.&quot; MIT OpenCourseWare, 2006.
[9] - Book: Donea, J., Huerta, A., Ponthot, J.-Ph. and Rodríguez-Ferran, A., &quot;Arbitrary Lagrangian-Eulerian methods,
The Encyclopedia of Computational Mechanics&quot;, Wiley, Vol. 1, Chapter 14, pp. 413-437, 2004
[10] - Book: Bennett, Andrew. &quot;Lagrangian fluid dynamics.&quot; Cambridge University Press, 2006.
[11] - Lecture Notes: Lermusiaux, P. &quot;Numerical Fluid Mechanics.&quot; &quot;https://ocw.mit.edu/courses/2-29-numerical-fluid-mechanics-spring-2015/pages/syllabus/&quot;
[12] - Paper: Boffetta, Guido, and Robert E. Ecke. &quot;Two-dimensional turbulence.&quot; Annual review of fluid mechanics 44.1 (2012): 427-451.
[13] - Paper: Mayeli, Peyman, and Gregory J. Sheard. &quot;Buoyancy-driven flows beyond the Boussinesq approximation: A brief review.&quot; International Communications in Heat and Mass Transfer 125 (2021): 105316.


Please note:
--------------------
This series focuses specifically on the aspect of information reduction in dynamical systems. For clarity, I had to omit many exciting facets of the topics addressed in the video. So, the video itself is a reduction. :-)

I hope you enjoyed this little braintruffle!</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="3184" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="95986"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:8vBuq3lyjxs</id>
  <yt:videoId>8vBuq3lyjxs</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCV4Rx1m-9HmtqHET7GjnVOA</yt:channelId>
  <title>How statistics prevent simulating back in time - excluding energy anti-dissipation</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8vBuq3lyjxs"/>
  <author>
   <name>braintruffle</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCV4Rx1m-9HmtqHET7GjnVOA</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2021-12-08T12:20:47+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-06-30T16:30:26+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>How statistics prevent simulating back in time - excluding energy anti-dissipation</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/8vBuq3lyjxs?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i1.ytimg.com/vi/8vBuq3lyjxs/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>This follow-up discusses fluid simulation related information reduction in view of time irreversibility of the governing evolution equations.

We gain an overview of a statistical perspective on the microscopic motion and highlight the implied time irreversibility as well as the exclusion of anti-dissipation.

Topics covered/used: Kinetic Theory of Gases, Boltzmann Equation, One-Particle Phase Space Density Function, Information Reduction, Laws of Evolution, Microscopic and Macroscopic Perspective, Laws of Motion, Time Reversibility vs. Time Irreversibility, Dissipation.

Timetable:
-----------------
00:00 - Microscopic Motion vs. Macroscopic Experience
01:33 - Macroscopic Influence on Microscopic Motion and Dissipative Tendency
04:38 - Statistical Perspective on Microscopic Motion and Information Reduction
08:54 - Time Irreversibility of the Statistical Perspective
10:13 - What's coming next? (Fluid Simulation Series!)


Important Note:
-----------------
I recommend exploring the literature further (see a few selected references below), as there are many more aspects necessary to fully understand the nature of time irreversibility, which may be covered in an extended version of this part. In particular, for brevity, I have chosen not to introduce the n-particle phase-space density perspective here, useful to talk about densities of (anti-)trajectories what could be done to define dissipation and related concepts probabilistically. This is addressed more verbally by saying things like &quot;some anti-time behavior&quot;, implying that probabilities should not be attached to individual trajectories, but rather that one should think in terms of probability densities. For the short version, I have tried to convey such aspects at least verbally, but if you are interested, you should know that there is of course much more to say.


Selected Papers and Learning Resources:
-------------------------------------------------------------------
Book: Evans, Denis James, Debra Joy Searles, and Stephen Rodney Williams. Fundamentals of classical statistical thermodynamics: dissipation, relaxation, and fluctuation theorems. John Wiley &amp; Sons, 2016.

Book: Hoover, William Graham, and Carol Griswold Hoover. Time reversibility, computer simulation, algorithms, chaos. Vol. 13. World Scientific, 2012.

Paper: Lebowitz, Joel L. &quot;Boltzmann's entropy and time's arrow.&quot; Physics today 46 (1993): 32-32.

Paper: Ardourel, Vincent. &quot;Irreversibility in the derivation of the Boltzmann equation.&quot; Foundations of Physics 47.4 (2017): 471-489.

Paper: Maes, Christian, and Karel Netočný. &quot;Time-reversal and entropy.&quot; Journal of statistical physics 110.1 (2003): 269-310.

Lecture Notes: from &quot;http://volkov.eng.ua.edu/ME591_491_NEGD/2017-Spring-NEGD-01-ElemKineticTheory.pdf&quot; to &quot;NEGD-06&quot;

Lecture Notes: &quot;Kenkre, V. M.. Statistical Mechanics. https://www.unm.edu/~aierides/505/&quot; specifically &quot;.../bbgky2.pdf&quot; &amp;  &quot;.../bbgky3.pdf&quot;

Lecture Notes: &quot;Cerfon, Antoine. Mechanics (Classical and Quantum). https://www.math.nyu.edu/~cerfon/mechanics.html&quot;


Disclaimer:
------------------
This series focuses specifically on the aspect of information reduction in dynamical systems. For the sake of clarity, I had to omit many interesting aspects of the topics addressed in the video. So, the video itself is a reduction. :-)

I hope you enjoyed this little braintruffle!

If you like this series and want to support my work, you may consider subscribing to the channel and support me on Patreon.
https://www.patreon.com/braintruffle</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="2485" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="36719"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:4b80sR-joNY</id>
  <yt:videoId>4b80sR-joNY</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCV4Rx1m-9HmtqHET7GjnVOA</yt:channelId>
  <title>Who cares about atoms - simulating a continuous perspective on matter</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4b80sR-joNY"/>
  <author>
   <name>braintruffle</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCV4Rx1m-9HmtqHET7GjnVOA</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2021-09-03T12:33:09+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-06-28T09:02:22+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Who cares about atoms - simulating a continuous perspective on matter</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/4b80sR-joNY?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i1.ytimg.com/vi/4b80sR-joNY/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>This is the second part in a series about Computational Fluid Dynamics where we build a Fluid Simulator from scratch.

We derive the Macroscopic Perspective (Continuum) from the Microscopic Perspective (Molecules) covering: Collective Molecular Behavior, Local (Non-)Equilibria, Classical Statistical Mechanics, Rarefied Gas Dynamics, and Continuum Gas Dynamics.

The Macroscopic Perspective provides the ground for the next part where we make it all numerically accessible - the Discretization.


Timetable:
-----------------
00:00 - Why we need a Macroscopic Perspective
01:44 - Particles Collective Behavior
05:33 - Using Equilibria for Reduction
08:17 - Statistical Mechanics and Rarefied Gas Dynamics
12:00 - Continuum Gas Dynamics
16:09 - Building Macroscopic Quantities
23:05 - Linking Macroscopic Quantities
34:09 - Recap


Selected Papers and Learning Resources:
-------------------------------------------------------------------
Sorted by Topics:
01:44 - Local (Non-)Equilibrium; Necessity of Collisions; Fluctuations; Molecular Chaos; Initial Perturbation; Statistical Perspective; Statistical Ensemble Averaging; Time Reversibility (to be discussed), Equilibria of different Degrees-of-Freedom (to be discussed): [1,2,3]
08:17 - Rarefied Gas Dynamics: [1,4]
08:17 - Phase Space (one-particle vs. N-particle): [1,5,6]
08:17 - Boltzmann Equation derived via BBGKY Hierarchy from Liouville Theorem: [6]
12:00 - Continuum Gas Dynamics, Continuum Hypothesis/Assumption, Alternative Flow Regimes Classifications: [1]
12:00 - Local Knudsen Number and alternative Rarefaction Indicators: [1,4]
16:09 - Macroscopic Quantities: Density, Flow Velocity, Pressure, Temperature [1]
23:05 - Macroscopic Equations: Conservation Laws; Mass; Momentum; Energy [1]
27:20 - Navier-Stokes Equations; Densities of Forces; Pressure Gradient; Viscosity: [1,7]
27:41 - Time Derivatives along with flow; Lagrangian vs. Eulerian Formulation; Lagrangian vs. Eulerian Coordinate Systems: [8]
30:12 - Velocity and Temperature Profiles for Couette Flow: [9]
32:45 - Macroscopic Equations: Equations of State; Ideal Gas Law; Calorically Perfect Gas: [1]

Selected References:
[1] - Lecture Notes: from &quot;http://volkov.eng.ua.edu/ME591_491_NEGD/2017-Spring-NEGD-01-ElemKineticTheory.pdf&quot; to &quot;NEGD-06&quot;
[2] - Paper: Maes, Christian, and Karel Netočný. &quot;Time-reversal and entropy.&quot; Journal of statistical physics 110.1 (2003): 269-310.
[3] - Paper: &quot;Parker, J. G. Rotational and vibrational relaxation in diatomic gases. The Physics of Fluids 2.4 (1959): 449-462.&quot;
[4] - Paper: Macrossan, M. N. &quot;Scaling parameters for hypersonic flow: correlation of sphere drag data.&quot;, 2007.
[5] - Lecture Notes: &quot;Cerfon, Antoine. Mechanics (Classical and Quantum). https://www.math.nyu.edu/~cerfon/mechanics.html&quot;
[6] - Lecture Notes: &quot;Kenkre, V. M.. Statistical Mechanics. https://www.unm.edu/~aierides/505/&quot; specifically &quot;.../bbgky2.pdf&quot; &amp;  &quot;.../bbgky3.pdf&quot;
[7] - Book: Anderson, John D. &quot;Governing equations of fluid dynamics.&quot; Computational fluid dynamics. Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg, 1992. 15-51.
[8] - Essay: Price, James F. &quot;Lagrangian and eulerian representations of fluid flow: Kinematics and the equations of motion.&quot; MIT OpenCourseWare, 2006.
[9] - Paper: Marques Jr, W., G. M. Kremer, and F. M. Sharipov. &quot;Couette flow with slip and jump boundary conditions.&quot; Continuum Mechanics and Thermodynamics 12.6 (2000): 379-386.


Disclaimer:
------------------
This series focuses specifically on the aspect of information reduction in dynamical systems. For the sake of clarity, I had to omit many interesting aspects of the topics addressed in the video. So, the video itself is a reduction. :-)


Please note:
------------------
Watching this video with very low resolution produces the continua right away :-), thanks to the video compression!


I hope you enjoyed this little braintruffle!

If you like this series and want to support my work, you may consider subscribing to the channel. I would really appreciate it!

Thank you for watching and I hope to see you next time!</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="4478" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="113522"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:MXs_vkc8hpY</id>
  <yt:videoId>MXs_vkc8hpY</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCV4Rx1m-9HmtqHET7GjnVOA</yt:channelId>
  <title>Quantum mechanics to fluid simulation - the story of everything</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MXs_vkc8hpY"/>
  <author>
   <name>braintruffle</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCV4Rx1m-9HmtqHET7GjnVOA</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2021-05-02T08:41:52+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-06-25T21:04:12+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Quantum mechanics to fluid simulation - the story of everything</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/MXs_vkc8hpY?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i2.ytimg.com/vi/MXs_vkc8hpY/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>This is the first part in a series about Computational Fluid Dynamics where we build a Fluid Simulator from scratch.

We highlight the Microscopic Perspective on Quantum Mechanics, Molecular Dynamics, and the Kinetic Theory of Gases that underlies and justifies Fluid Simulation Formulations in the first place.

The Microscopic Perspective provides the ground for the next part where we focus on the Macroscopic Perspective with concepts such as Pressure, Viscosity, Temperature, and Flow Velocity as well as its evolution with time.


Timetable:
-----------------
00:00 - What We Build
02:06 - Guiding Principle - Information Reduction
04:03 - Measurement of Small Things
07:09 - Quantum Mechanics and Wave Functions
13:45 - Model Order Reduction
16:48 - Molecular Dynamics and Classical Mechanics
26:50 - Kinetic Theory of Gases
30:23 - Recap


Selected Papers and Learning Resources:
-------------------------------------------------------------------
05:03 Experiment:
Paper: &quot;Stodolna, Aneta S., et al. Hydrogen atoms under magnification: direct observation of the nodal structure of stark states. Physical review letters 110.21 (2013): 213001.&quot;

06:49 Atomic- and Molecular Orbitals Tomography:
Paper: &quot;Vozzi, Caterina, et al. Generalized molecular orbital tomography. Nature Physics 7.10 (2011): 822-826.&quot;
Paper: &quot;Itatani, Jiro, et al. Tomographic imaging of molecular orbitals. Nature 432.7019 (2004): 867-871.&quot;

07:24 Matter Waves, Double Slit Experiment:
Paper: &quot;Jönsson, Claus. Elektroneninterferenzen an mehreren künstlich hergestellten Feinspalten. Zeitschrift für Physik 161.4 (1961): 454-474.&quot;
Paper: &quot;Jönsson, Claus. Electron diffraction at multiple slits. American Journal of Physics 42.1 (1974): 4-11.&quot;

07:57 Quantum Mechanics Overview, Wave packets, Standing Waves, Eigenstates:
E-Book: &quot;Mathur, Samir D. https://www.asc.ohio-state.edu/mathur.16/quantummechanics27-11-17/navigation.html&quot;
E-Book: &quot;van Dommelen, Leon. Quantum mechanics for engineers. https://web1.eng.famu.fsu.edu/~dommelen/quantum/style_a/index.html (2004)&quot;

16:01 Model Order Reduction, Modes:
Lecture Notes: from &quot;Farhat, Charbel. Model Reduction. https://web.stanford.edu/group/frg/course_work/CME345/CA-CME345-Ch1.pdf&quot; to &quot;CA-CME345-Ch9&quot;

17:17 Classical Mechanics, Phase Space:
Lecture Notes: &quot;Cerfon, Antoine. Mechanics (Classical and Quantum). https://www.math.nyu.edu/~cerfon/mechanics.html&quot;

18:15 Molecular Dynamics, Born-Oppenheimer Approximation, Potential Energy Surface, and Non-Quantized Approximation of Energy Levels:
Lecture Notes: &quot;Allen, Michael P. Introduction to molecular dynamics simulation. Computational soft matter: from synthetic polymers to proteins 23.1 (2004): 1-28.&quot;
Paper: &quot;Parker, J. G. Rotational and vibrational relaxation in diatomic gases. The Physics of Fluids 2.4 (1959): 449-462.&quot;
Paper: &quot;Valentini, Paolo, et al. Direct molecular simulation of nitrogen dissociation based on an ab initio potential energy surface. Physics of Fluids 27.8 (2015): 086102.&quot;
E-Book Chapter: &quot;van Dommelen, Leon. Quantum mechanics for engineers. 9.2 The Born-Oppenheimer Approximation. https://web1.eng.famu.fsu.edu/~dommelen/quantum/style_a/bo.html (2004)&quot;

20:11 One-Dimensional Hydrogen Atom Approximation for the Coulomb Potential as opposed to the &quot;true&quot; One-Dimensional Coulomb Potential:
&quot;Loudon, Rodney. One-dimensional hydrogen atom. American journal of physics 27.9 (1959): 649-655.&quot;
&quot;Loudon, Rodney. One-dimensional hydrogen atom. Proceedings of the Royal Society A: Mathematical, Physical and Engineering Sciences 472.2185 (2016): 20150534.&quot;

27:06 Kinetic Theory of Gases, (Variable) Hard Sphere Approximation of Molecules:
Lecture Notes: from &quot;http://volkov.eng.ua.edu/ME591_491_NEGD/2017-Spring-NEGD-01-ElemKineticTheory.pdf&quot; to &quot;NEGD-06&quot;


Disclaimer:
------------------
This series focuses specifically on the aspect of information reduction in dynamical systems. For the sake of clarity, I had to omit many interesting aspects of the topics addressed in the video. So, the video itself is a reduction. :-)


I hope you enjoyed this little braintruffle! 

If you like this series, let the YouTube algorithm know by subscribing to the channel and ringing the bell icon.

Thank you for watching and see you next time!</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="16777" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="1098024"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
</feed>
