<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xml:base="https://www.splcenter.org"  xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<channel>
 <title>Southern Poverty Law Center</title>
 <link>https://www.splcenter.org</link>
 <description></description>
 <language>en</language>
<item>
 <title>Conspiracy Theories About Pelosi Attack Spread Unchecked on &#039;Alt-tech&#039; Sites, Conservative Media </title>
 <link>https://www.splcenter.org/hatewatch/2022/11/04/conspiracy-theories-about-pelosi-attack-spread-unchecked-alt-tech-sites-conservative-media</link>
 <description>&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-field-story-type field-type-list-text field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;
                &lt;div class=&quot;field-item even &quot;&gt;Hatewatch&lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-field-long-text field-type-text-long field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;
                &lt;div class=&quot;field-item even &quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Conspiracy theories about the home invasion and hammer attack on Paul Pelosi, husband of House Speaker Nancy Pelosi, continue to spread across conservative media, social media and “alt-tech” sites, even as a federal criminal complaint appears to debunk false narratives extremists and right-wing influencers have spread.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-field-image field-type-image field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;
                &lt;div class=&quot;field-item even &quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-title-field field-type-text field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;
                &lt;div class=&quot;field-item even &quot;&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Conspiracy Theories About Pelosi Attack Spread Unchecked on &amp;#039;Alt-tech&amp;#039; Sites, Conservative Media &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-body field-type-text-with-summary field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;
                &lt;div class=&quot;field-item even &quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The response shows Republicans and the far right pushing back in a unified way on critics who linked intemperate political rhetoric and political violence, in an effort to limit electoral consequences in the midterms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div data-embed-button=&quot;media&quot; data-entity-id=&quot;35333&quot; data-entity-label=&quot;Media&quot; data-entity-type=&quot;file&quot; data-entity-uuid=&quot;0c1e1b8b-982c-42ee-ac37-c9b14b84845e&quot; data-splc-media-url=&quot;&quot; data-view-mode=&quot;full&quot; class=&quot;align-right&quot;&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;file-35333&quot; class=&quot;file file-image file-image-jpeg&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;element-invisible&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/files/inlineimage1jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;content&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.splcenter.org/sites/default/files/inline_image1.jpg&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; height=&quot;467&quot; alt=&quot;Nancy and Paul Pelosi&quot; title=&quot;Nancy and Paul Pelosi&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-field-file-caption field-type-text-long field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;field-item even &quot;&gt;Speaker of the House Nancy Pelosi, D-California, and her husband, Paul Pelosi, arrive at the State Department for the Kennedy Center Honors State Department Dinner on Dec. 7, 2019, in Washington, D.C. (Photo via Associated Press/Kevin Wolf) &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.justice.gov/opa/press-release/file/1548106/download?utm_medium=email&amp;amp;utm_source=govdelivery&quot;&gt; detailed criminal complaint&lt;/a&gt; from the Department of Justice filed Monday shows prosecutors alleging that suspect David DePape entered the Pelosis’ residence with a hammer and struck Paul Pelosi with it in front of arresting officers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prosecutors also allege that Speaker Pelosi was the intruder’s primary target, citing his own apparent confession that he had entered her home in order to “break &#039;her kneecaps,’” due to his belief that Pelosi was “‘leader of the pack’ of lies told by the Democratic Party.” They also alleged that DePape had planned to target other politicians.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The charges came after a wide range of right-wing influencers attempted to muddy the waters with conspiracy theories – some homophobic – and mischaracterizations of DePape, 42, of Berkeley, California.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the clear picture of the events in the documents did not slow the generation of false conspiracy narratives later in the week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Gateway Pundit: fake news influencer&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Leading the charge was Jim Hoft’s junk news site, The Gateway Pundit, which has published &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/search?q=site:thegatewaypundit.com+pelosi&amp;amp;source=lnt&amp;amp;tbs=qdr:w&amp;amp;sa=X&amp;amp;ved=2ahUKEwixrPnatJL7AhX6MjQIHYwEAioQpwV6BAgBEBc&amp;amp;biw=1670&amp;amp;bih=822&amp;amp;dpr=1&quot;&gt; more than 60 posts&lt;/a&gt; on the Pelosi attack. These posts have asserted a range of false narratives about the attack, many of which spread to social media and other websites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They included suggestions that DePape and Paul Pelosi were lovers due to the assailant being arrested in his underwear, and that the Pelosis’ marriage was a &lt;a href=&quot;https://archive.ph/KVcBb&quot;&gt;sham&lt;/a&gt; to cover for Paul Pelosi’s homosexuality. Gateway Pundit also pushed false narratives suggesting that security camera footage had been withheld by the Pelosis, and that a number of &lt;a href=&quot;https://archive.ph/vDza9&quot;&gt;websites and social media accounts&lt;/a&gt; associated with the alleged attacker were “false flag” deceptions seeking to link Republicans with the incident.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div data-embed-button=&quot;media&quot; data-entity-id=&quot;35334&quot; data-entity-label=&quot;Media&quot; data-entity-type=&quot;file&quot; data-entity-uuid=&quot;3f4267b6-95ea-47e5-ad3b-117a3cc16835&quot; data-splc-media-url=&quot;&quot; data-view-mode=&quot;full&quot; class=&quot;align-right&quot;&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;file-35334&quot; class=&quot;file file-image file-image-jpeg&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;element-invisible&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/files/inlineimage2jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;content&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.splcenter.org/sites/default/files/inline_image2.jpg&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; height=&quot;467&quot; alt=&quot;David DePape&quot; title=&quot;David DePape&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-field-file-caption field-type-text-long field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;field-item even &quot;&gt;David DePape, right, records the nude wedding of Gypsy Taub outside City Hall on Dec. 19, 2013, in San Francisco. DePape is accused of breaking into House Speaker Nancy Pelosi&#039;s California home and severely beating her husband Paul with a hammer. DePape was known in Berkeley, California, as a pro-nudity activist who had picketed naked at protests against local ordinances requiring people to be clothed in public. (Photo via Associated Press/Eric Risberg)&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gateway Pundit also repeatedly characterized DePape. a Canadian citizen, as an “illegal immigrant.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The website also &lt;a href=&quot;https://archive.ph/eyOPi&quot;&gt;celebrated&lt;/a&gt; Elon Musk’s short-lived advocacy of a false conspiracy theory about the attack. Twitter’s new proprietor had linked to a story from a fake news website that asserted without evidence that the two men knew each other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gateway Pundit is consistently ranked in the top 10% of websites by popularity, according to Hatewatch’s analysis of Cisco’s Umbrella survey of the top million websites online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to data from Internet monitoring service Pyrra, Gateway Pundit also prolifically posted links to its Pelosi stories on “alt-tech” sites Gettr and Trump-owned Truth Social.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pyrra also showed that narratives Gateway Pundit and other right-wing websites promoted were shared and repeated widely across those and other low-moderation “alt-tech” websites. Hundreds of posts using the hashtag #pelosi on sites including Gab, Gettr, Truth Social and WeMe spread false information about the attacker’s motive, the Pelosis’ security and other aspects of the attack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Facebook clone Minds, one user asked: “Criminal? Lover? Drug Dealer? Who is David DePape to Paul Pelosi??? The narrative keeps changing too much.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Thursday, Gateway Pundit published a story by &lt;a href=&quot;https://archive.ph/8bApR&quot;&gt;Brian Lupo&lt;/a&gt; that sought to discredit the FBI investigation and claimed there was a “huge anomaly” in the timeline offered in the criminal complaint.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That story became a &lt;a href=&quot;https://archive.ph/MS9j0&quot;&gt;trending topic&lt;/a&gt; on Gab, the far-right friendly site run by self-described Christian nationalist Andrew Torba, where it was spread and enjoyed by the site’s user base of extremists. Gab also &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.documentcloud.org/documents/23261602-20221103-https___gabcom_tags_pelosi&quot;&gt; played host&lt;/a&gt; to memes and false narratives about Paul Pelosi’s relationship with DePape.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another &lt;a href=&quot;https://archive.ph/l4kyt&quot;&gt;story&lt;/a&gt; from the antigovernment John Birch Society outlet &lt;em&gt;The New American&lt;/em&gt; was &lt;a href=&quot;https://archive.ph/vK0I4&quot;&gt;trending&lt;/a&gt; on Gab at the same time. In it, Benjamin Faulkner made an argument that had already been repeated across a range of more mainstream conservative outlets: that the attack, like the Democrats’ response to the Jan. 6, 2021, riots, was primarily an electoral tactic, and was part of a “climate of fear and hysteria created by a power-mad class that feels their grip on power weakening.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Midterm projections&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Senior Democrats including President &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2022/11/02/us/politics/transcript-biden-speech-democracy.html&quot;&gt; Joe Biden&lt;/a&gt;, former President &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.axios.com/2022/10/29/obama-pelosi-attack-rhetoric&quot;&gt; Barack Obama&lt;/a&gt; and former Secretary of State &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/HillaryClinton/status/1586411168880807936&quot;&gt; Hillary Clinton&lt;/a&gt; all linked the alleged violent attack to Trumpist political rhetoric in a succession of speeches and public statements during the week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Biden linked the attack to the Jan. 6, 2021, attack on the U.S. Capitol, saying that when DePape allegedly asked, “Where’s Nancy?” he used “the very same words used by the mob when they stormed the Capitol.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But throughout the week, right-wing influencers, including those with platforms in mainstream publications, tried to depict concerns about political violence as mere Democratic Party electioneering.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A &lt;a href=&quot;https://archive.ph/OJFQS&quot;&gt;Sunday column&lt;/a&gt; in the Murdoch family-owned &lt;em&gt;New York Post&lt;/em&gt; by Miranda Devine attacked what it called a “false depiction of the alleged attacker as a MAGA Republican in defiance of his drug-addicted hippy lifestyle,” and put aside any scruples about mixed metaphors to claim that condemnations of political violence were “a full-court press designed to flip the attack on the House speaker’s husband into an ‘October surprise’ as Dems look down the barrel of a brutal shellacking from the voters next week.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Monday night, Tucker Carlson also &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-4NFYNnTOX8&quot;&gt; claimed&lt;/a&gt; that the response to the attack was an attempt to limit damage in midterms, after using details about DePape’s living circumstances to mock the idea that he had right-wing politics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;YouTube performer Dave Rubin &lt;a href=&quot;https://archive.ph/OFBzV&quot;&gt;accused&lt;/a&gt; Hillary Clinton of exploiting the attack for “midterm votes,” and called her “shameless.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By week’s end, almost no one on the right – whether open extremist or ostensibly respectable conservative commentator – was acknowledging that the attack was an act of political violence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Photo illustration by SPLC&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-field-byline field-type-text field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;
                &lt;div class=&quot;field-item even &quot;&gt;Jason Wilson&lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-field-addthis field-type-addthis field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;
                &lt;div class=&quot;field-item even &quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;addthis_toolbox addthis_default_style  &quot; addthis:title=&quot;Conspiracy Theories About Pelosi Attack Spread Unchecked on &amp;#039;Alt-tech&amp;#039; Sites, Conservative Media  - Southern Poverty Law Center&quot; addthis:url=&quot;https://www.splcenter.org/hatewatch/2022/11/04/conspiracy-theories-about-pelosi-attack-spread-unchecked-alt-tech-sites-conservative-media&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot; &quot; class=&quot;addthis_button_facebook&quot; aria-label=&quot;Facebook: Share this page&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot; &quot; class=&quot;addthis_button_twitter&quot; aria-label=&quot;Twitter: Share this page&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-field-publish-date field-type-date field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;
                &lt;div class=&quot;field-item even &quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;date-display-single&quot;&gt;November 04, 2022&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
 <pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2022 19:34:15 +0000</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>chris.heller_1541</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">17217 at https://www.splcenter.org</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>Defending Unhoused People: SPLC fights back against discriminatory ordinances that punish individuals who do not have homes</title>
 <link>https://www.splcenter.org/news/2022/11/04/defending-unhoused-people</link>
 <description>&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-field-story-type field-type-list-text field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;
                &lt;div class=&quot;field-item even &quot;&gt;Features and Stories&lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-field-image field-type-image field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;
                &lt;div class=&quot;field-item even &quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-title-field field-type-text field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;
                &lt;div class=&quot;field-item even &quot;&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Defending Unhoused People: SPLC fights back against discriminatory ordinances that punish individuals who do not have homes&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-body field-type-text-with-summary field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;
                &lt;div class=&quot;field-item even &quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;I am a homeless lawyer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No, I have never personally experienced homelessness. But it is fitting that the first thing you know about me is that I am a lawyer who has spent nearly my entire legal career representing people who do not have a safe place to call home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is, after all, the first thing we are told about a person – that they are homeless. Most often it is the only thing we ever know, without ever learning the person’s name. It reads like a credential, erasing any other identity such as parent, sibling, neighbor or friend. So I wear my own credential – that of a homeless lawyer – in solidarity with the people whose names I know and whose stories I carry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is this work that brought me to the Southern Poverty Law Center in 2021, where I currently serve as the deputy legal director of the Economic Justice Project. In this role, I lead a team of lawyers and legal professionals working across the Deep South to advance the SPLC’s goal of eradicating poverty by expanding access to opportunity and eliminating racial economic inequality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the early days of the COVID-19 pandemic in March 2020, states across the country began issuing orders for people to stay at home to prevent the spread of the novel coronavirus. The ability to stay home without severe economic consequences depended in large part on the types of jobs people held. The pandemic instantly realigned our society across a new driver of inequality: those who can choose to stay home to protect their health, and those who cannot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But for the more than 500,000 individuals experiencing homelessness in our country, how do you stay home when you do not have a place to call home?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The pandemic revealed again and again the safety and stability that only housing provides, which is not available to all on equal terms. Racism in our housing and economic systems has created a homelessness crisis that &lt;a href=&quot;https://endhomelessness.org/resource/racial-inequalities-homelessness-numbers/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;disproportionately impacts Black and Brown communities&lt;/a&gt;. African Americans make up 13% of the general population but 40% of the unhoused population.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cities across the country, and in the Deep South where we work, have responded to the visibility of people who are unhoused and unsheltered in our communities with laws restricting sleeping or camping outdoors. These laws are unconstitutional because they punish individuals for being human beings who need sleep, a life-sustaining activity that must occur at some time and some place. For most of us, that is our homes. But for too many of our unhoused friends and neighbors, these ordinances make their very existence a crime.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Racially discriminatory&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In August of this year, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://tbinternet.ohchr.org/Treaties/CERD/Shared%20Documents/USA/CERD_C_USA_CO_10-12_49769_E.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;U.N. Committee on the Elimination of Racial Discrimination&lt;/a&gt; expressed its view that the criminalization of homelessness in the U.S. is racially discriminatory, noting “it remains concerned at the increasing number of state and local laws that criminalize homelessness and at the disproportionately high number of persons belonging to racial and ethnic minorities affected by homelessness.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the past year, we worked with a coalition of partners to successfully defeat a proposed camping ordinance in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.al.com/news/2022/01/is-anti-camping-ordinance-aimed-at-mobiles-homeless-council-set-to-debate.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Mobile, Alabama&lt;/a&gt;. We opposed ordinances banning camping in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theadvocate.com/baton_rouge/news/article_c021b430-f267-11ec-bb18-c3cecb679762.amp.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Baton Rouge, Louisiana&lt;/a&gt;, and in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pewtrusts.org/en/research-and-analysis/blogs/stateline/2022/04/08/homeless-camping-bans-are-spreading-this-group-shaped-the-bills&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Lula, Georgia&lt;/a&gt;, that ultimately passed despite our warnings that these ordinances may violate the U.S. Constitution by criminalizing the status of being homeless. We also provided legal support to grassroots organizations working to delay closure of a large encampment that resulted in additional procedures to allow people time to relocate, avoiding mass arrests and property destruction in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.alreporter.com/2022/06/10/splc-huntsville-plan-to-evict-homeless-from-encampment-threatens-their-health-and-lives/?amp&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Huntsville, Alabama&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, as SPLC attorney Clara Potter told the local ABC affiliate during the closure of the Huntsville camp, “these camp closures are part of a larger problem, where there’s an emphasis on law enforcement solutions but not sufficient equal emphasis on long-term housing solutions, and only those supportive housing solutions are really going to help folks get back on their feet.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite clear evidence that &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.usich.gov/news/collaborate-dont-criminalize-how-communities-can-effectively-and-humanely-address-homelessness&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;criminalization is not a solution to homelessness&lt;/a&gt;, we also contended with a bill proposed during the 2022 Georgia legislative session to ban camping statewide and create incentives for local law enforcement of camping bans, effectively criminalizing homelessness in the entire state. The bill did not pass, and instead the Legislature set up a commission to study homelessness. This bill is part of a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pewtrusts.org/en/research-and-analysis/blogs/stateline/2022/04/08/homeless-camping-bans-are-spreading-this-group-shaped-the-bills&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;growing trend of state legislatures&lt;/a&gt; endorsing handcuffs as a solution to homelessness instead of the housing that people need.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And, in response to the visibility of people holding signs in public places to communicate their need for help and other charitable assistance, state and local law enforcement agencies enforce state statutes and local ordinances criminalizing charitable solicitation in the form of bans against panhandling or begging. Such measures are clearly unconstitutional restrictions on protected speech, as evidenced by our lawsuit against the city of Montgomery, Alabama, and the sheriff of Montgomery County for enforcement of statutes that restricted asking for charity in public places throughout the state.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We reached an early &lt;a href=&quot;/news/2020/12/14/housing-not-handcuffs-splc-allies-end-police-harassment-people-panhandling-montgomery&quot;&gt;settlement agreement with the city&lt;/a&gt; on behalf of Jonathan Singleton, Ricky Vickery, and Micki Holmes, and after a judge issued a &lt;a href=&quot;/presscenter/judge-finds-laws-criminalizing-panhandling-be-unconstitutional&quot;&gt;preliminary injunction&lt;/a&gt;, the sheriff recently agreed not to enforce the challenged statutes. Our litigation continues against the Alabama Law Enforcement Agency, as we work to ensure that people who need help are not silenced because they are communicating a message many people would rather not hear about hunger and homelessness in our communities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It should be a crime to allow homelessness to exist in this country, the richest country in the world. Yet we misplace the blame and instead punish unhoused people based on a misguided belief that we can end homelessness if we simply make it a crime. As though homelessness were a personal choice, instead of a predictable consequence of treating &lt;a href=&quot;https://housingmatters.urban.org/articles/naming-housing-human-right-first-step-solving-housing-crisis&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;housing as a privilege instead of a human right&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is simply wrong. Criminalizing homelessness does nothing to address the root causes of the housing crisis. Instead, it causes untold human suffering and makes it more difficult for people to exit homelessness. Criminalization misplaces blame for homelessness on people, instead of the unjust systems that need to be reformed so that everyone has a safe place to call home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Picture at top: Paul Bradbury/Getty Images&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-field-person field-type-entityreference field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;
                &lt;div class=&quot;field-item even &quot;&gt;&lt;article id=&quot;node-16811&quot; class=&quot;node node-person node-teaser node-odd&quot;&gt;

  
  &lt;div class=&quot;content&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-field-image field-type-image field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;
                &lt;div class=&quot;field-item even &quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/about/staff/kirsten-anderson&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.splcenter.org/sites/default/files/styles/splc_person_circle_small/public/web_kirsten-anderson.jpg?itok=Goime5Gx&quot; width=&quot;64&quot; height=&quot;64&quot; alt=&quot;Kirsten Anderson&quot; title=&quot;Kirsten Anderson&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;group-text-field-group&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-title-field field-type-text field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;
                &lt;div class=&quot;field-item even &quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/about/staff/kirsten-anderson&quot;&gt;Kirsten Anderson&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-field-person-title field-type-text field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;
                &lt;div class=&quot;field-item even &quot;&gt;Deputy Legal Director for Economic Justice &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;  &lt;/div&gt; &lt;!-- /content --&gt;

  
      &lt;div class=&quot;links&quot;&gt;
          &lt;/div&gt; &lt;!-- /links --&gt;
  
  &lt;/article&gt; &lt;!-- /article #node --&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-field-addthis field-type-addthis field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;
                &lt;div class=&quot;field-item even &quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;addthis_toolbox addthis_default_style  &quot; addthis:title=&quot;Defending Unhoused People: SPLC fights back against discriminatory ordinances that punish individuals who do not have homes - Southern Poverty Law Center&quot; addthis:url=&quot;https://www.splcenter.org/news/2022/11/04/defending-unhoused-people&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot; &quot; class=&quot;addthis_button_facebook&quot; aria-label=&quot;Facebook: Share this page&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot; &quot; class=&quot;addthis_button_twitter&quot; aria-label=&quot;Twitter: Share this page&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-field-publish-date field-type-date field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;
                &lt;div class=&quot;field-item even &quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;date-display-single&quot;&gt;November 04, 2022&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
 <pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2022 19:21:41 +0000</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>rudy.isaza_2663</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">17216 at https://www.splcenter.org</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>Omaha Police Cancel Deal With Far Right-Linked Gun Shop</title>
 <link>https://www.splcenter.org/hatewatch/2022/11/04/omaha-police-cancel-deal-far-right-linked-gun-shop</link>
 <description>&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-field-story-type field-type-list-text field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;
                &lt;div class=&quot;field-item even &quot;&gt;Hatewatch&lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-field-long-text field-type-text-long field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;
                &lt;div class=&quot;field-item even &quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Omaha Police Department (OPD) in Nebraska confirmed to Hatewatch it has permanently scrapped a proposed equipment swap with a far right-linked gun shop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-field-image field-type-image field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;
                &lt;div class=&quot;field-item even &quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-title-field field-type-text field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;
                &lt;div class=&quot;field-item even &quot;&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Omaha Police Cancel Deal With Far Right-Linked Gun Shop&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-body field-type-text-with-summary field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;
                &lt;div class=&quot;field-item even &quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;88 Tactical is a large gun range and store on the outskirts of Omaha where “civilians as well as law enforcement and military personnel” train, according to its website. In 2017, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.splcenter.org/hatewatch/2017/09/12/disgraced-ex-fbi-agent-john-guandolo-visit-iowa-and-nebraska-week&quot;&gt; Hatewatch reported&lt;/a&gt; that 88 Tactical and the anti-Muslim Global Faith Institute invited anti-Muslim ex-FBI agent and author John Guandolo to Nebraska. In August, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.splcenter.org/hatewatch/2022/08/22/emails-show-omaha-police-planned-deal-far-right-linked-gun-shop&quot;&gt; Hatewatch reported&lt;/a&gt; on the emails surrounding the exchange and local Nebraska activists’ concerns over the deal. They called attention to what they say is the business’s use of far-right imagery. Activists further voiced concerns over an 88 Tactical instructor Devin Crinklaw, who also works as an OPD officer and has espoused anti-Muslim views on social media. Hatewatch reported on those posts in the August article.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OPD public information officer Lt. Neal Bonacci told Hatewatch OPD has “no plans in entertaining that deal any further.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bonacci also told Hatewatch that Crinklaw is still on the force but was relieved of his position as an instructor for his SWAT team. Crinklaw was previously the primary firearms and tactics trainer for the team. Bonacci said OPD conducted a review of Crinklaw’s social media because of Hatewatch’s reporting. The review contributed to the decision to remove him as an instructor. 88 Tactical did not respond to Hatewatch’s request for comment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The swap would have seen OPD give 88 Tactical 28 expired ballistic helmets and 28 expired rifle plates for 120 Coyote AR magazines, 60 Glock 17 magazines and 30 orange Glock magazine base plates. If purchased new, the equipment OPD agreed to give would be valued at around $45,000, while 88 Tactical’s part of the deal was worth around $3,100. The Omaha City Council removed the deal from its agenda in July, but its fate was uncertain, Bonacci told the &lt;em&gt;Omaha World-Herald&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It’s great that this particular exchange got canceled,” Melody Vaccaro, executive director of Grassroots nonprofit Nebraskans Against Gun Violence (NAGV), told Hatewatch. NAGV opposed the deal since it appeared on the Omaha City Council’s agenda. Vaccaro said in a July press release the “private market is absolutely the wrong place for military and law enforcement gear” and the gear should be “retired.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Though she welcomed the cancellation, the fact that authorities considered the deal “leaves lingering questions about the cozy relationship between radicalized private companies and Omaha police,” Vaccaro said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Activists decry the business’s use of “88,” which neo-Nazis use as a code for “Heil Hitler,” the Nazi salute. 88 Tactical also features elevation maps throughout the store with the highest point at 1488 feet. Peak Bagger, a website that tracks elevations, states Omaha’s highest point is around 1,270 feet. “1488” combines “Heil Hitler” and the white nationalist “14 Words,” a saying about securing a future for white children. White nationalist extremist &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.splcenter.org/fighting-hate/extremist-files/individual/david-lane&quot;&gt; David Lane&lt;/a&gt; coined the saying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;88 Tactical CEO Shea Degan has repeatedly denied any affiliations with white supremacy and claims the name refers to &lt;a href=&quot;https://88tactical.com/the-truth-behind-our-name/&quot;&gt; Nebraska police code&lt;/a&gt;. 88 Tactical also &lt;a href=&quot;https://88tactical.com/88-tactical-city-ventures-announce-future-locations-in-16-cities/&quot;&gt; said it removed&lt;/a&gt; the maps displaying “1488” after it learned its meaning. 88 Tactical has not responded to Hatewatch’s requests about its past collaboration with the Global Faith Institute to invite John Guandolo to Nebraska.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;88 Tactical has plans to expand. The company partnered with City+Ventures, an Omaha-based real estate and investment firm, in 2017. In 2020, The companies announced plans to expand to 16 cities across the United States, from Nevada to Virginia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The plan frames the expansion, which will include locations that feature gun ranges, training classes and 24-hour fitness facilities, as a “one-of-a-kind Guntry Club.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-field-byline field-type-text field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;
                &lt;div class=&quot;field-item even &quot;&gt;Creede Newton&lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-field-addthis field-type-addthis field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;
                &lt;div class=&quot;field-item even &quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;addthis_toolbox addthis_default_style  &quot; addthis:title=&quot;Omaha Police Cancel Deal With Far Right-Linked Gun Shop - Southern Poverty Law Center&quot; addthis:url=&quot;https://www.splcenter.org/hatewatch/2022/11/04/omaha-police-cancel-deal-far-right-linked-gun-shop&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot; &quot; class=&quot;addthis_button_facebook&quot; aria-label=&quot;Facebook: Share this page&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot; &quot; class=&quot;addthis_button_twitter&quot; aria-label=&quot;Twitter: Share this page&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-field-publish-date field-type-date field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;
                &lt;div class=&quot;field-item even &quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;date-display-single&quot;&gt;November 04, 2022&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
 <pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2022 14:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>chris.heller_1541</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">17212 at https://www.splcenter.org</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>Former ICE Chief Taps Anti-Muslim Hate Group To Help Run Border-Focused Project</title>
 <link>https://www.splcenter.org/hatewatch/2022/11/03/former-ice-chief-taps-anti-muslim-hate-group-help-run-border-focused-project</link>
 <description>&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-field-story-type field-type-list-text field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;
                &lt;div class=&quot;field-item even &quot;&gt;Hatewatch&lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-field-long-text field-type-text-long field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;
                &lt;div class=&quot;field-item even &quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tom Homan, a former acting director of U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement (ICE) and prominent conservative media figure, is collaborating with an anti-Muslim hate group on a new project aimed at fearmongering about the U.S. Southern border. The project held a fundraising event at former President Donald Trump’s Mar-a-Lago resort in Florida on Nov. 1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-field-image field-type-image field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;
                &lt;div class=&quot;field-item even &quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-title-field field-type-text field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;
                &lt;div class=&quot;field-item even &quot;&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Former ICE Chief Taps Anti-Muslim Hate Group To Help Run Border-Focused Project&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-body field-type-text-with-summary field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;
                &lt;div class=&quot;field-item even &quot;&gt;&lt;div data-embed-button=&quot;media&quot; data-entity-id=&quot;35315&quot; data-entity-label=&quot;Media&quot; data-entity-type=&quot;file&quot; data-entity-uuid=&quot;a4f036d6-3474-46f0-88e0-136cbad0a799&quot; data-splc-media-url=&quot;&quot; data-view-mode=&quot;full&quot; class=&quot;align-right&quot;&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;file-35315&quot; class=&quot;file file-image file-image-jpeg&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;element-invisible&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/files/tomhomanap-700pxjpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;content&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.splcenter.org/sites/default/files/tom_homan_ap-700px.jpg&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; height=&quot;467&quot; alt=&quot;Tom Homan&quot; title=&quot;Tom Homan&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-field-file-caption field-type-text-long field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;field-item even &quot;&gt;Former acting Immigration and Customs Enforcement Director Tom Homan speaks following a border tour with former Vice President Mike Pence, Monday, June 13, 2022, in Phoenix, Arizona. (Photo via AP Images/Matt York)&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The project, Defend the Border and Save Lives, is a media and promotional endeavor tied to Homan’s personal brand and a book of his with the same title. A Hatewatch review of the project’s website revealed it is closely tied to The United West, an SPLC-designated anti-Muslim hate group. This includes sharing an address and staff with the anti-Muslim group.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Homan formerly served as acting director of ICE under Trump. He has leveraged those credentials to become an oft-booked media commentator on issues related to immigration and the border. He is known for his hard-liner stances on these issues, such as backing the border wall and showing unwavering support for the Department of Homeland Security’s deportation arm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Along with his book &lt;em&gt;Defend the Border and Save Lives&lt;/em&gt;, Homan launched “a two-year educational program on the crisis at our southern border” and has tapped The United West for help. One of the main figures working with Homan on the project is Tom Trento, founder and director of The United West, a group that has been stoking anti-Muslim hate for over a decade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We have entered into an agreement with Tom Homan to tell his story,” Trento says in a promotional video. Defend the Border and Save Lives did not return request for comment from Hatewatch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trento and his group have claimed the U.S. and West are at war with Muslims and Islam.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“There is no doubt that, for those with eyes to see, we are at war with devout Muslims who follow the jihad teachings of doctrinal Islam,” Trento wrote in a 2016 email to supporters. “Therefore, it is essential that all Americans adopt a ‘war-footing’ mentality and are constantly prepared for any threat, any situation, any problem.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a 2015 email around the anniversary of 9/11, Trento wrote, “I knew all my years of academic work in Islam and related areas of law enforcement and activism would be required in what will be an extended, vicious, deadly, horrible war in a clash of two incompatible civilizations, the Judeo-Christian West and Islam.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2013, Trento’s web show spread an Islamophobic conspiracy theory claiming that John Brennan, former President Obama’s then-nominee to run the CIA, was a secret Muslim.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Muslim civil rights group Council on American-Islamic Relations (CAIR) has been tracking The United West’s Islamophobia over the years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Homan’s choice to partner with documented anti-Muslim bigots reflects the poor decision-making he exemplified at U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement,” Corey Saylor, CAIR’s director of research and advocacy, told Hatewatch via email. “Partnership with United West, Tom Trento and Clare Lopez ensures wasted time, wasted money, and conclusions fit only for the next conspiracy theorists’ rally.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Defend the Border and Save Lives appears to be closely tied with The United West. On the group’s donation page, checks can be mailed to the same post office box in Lake Worth, Florida, that is associated with The United West. A link to the Defend the Border and Save Lives website is also on The United West’s website. The group is also hosting fundraising events for the project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Defend the Border and Save Lives page is riddled with nativist content. The group’s donation page reads: “AMERICA INVADED. Help Us Stop This Threat!” Lawmakers and immigration advocates have &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dallasobserver.com/news/abbotts-order-to-arrest-migrants-at-the-border-and-invasion-rhetoric-could-lead-to-violence-some-say-14404675&quot;&gt; criticized&lt;/a&gt; bombastic claims of an invasion happening at the Southern border as dangerous rhetoric. The accused mass shooter responsible for killing over 20 people at a Wal-Mart in El Paso, Texas, in 2019 allegedly &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.elpasotimes.com/story/news/2022/08/04/el-paso-walmart-shooting-patrick-crusius-gop-rhetoric-invasion/7585100001/&quot;&gt; said&lt;/a&gt; in a manifesto left behind that the “attack is a response to the Hispanic invasion of Texas.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zachary Mueller, political director at the immigration advocacy organization America’s Voice, expressed his concerns about the project collaborating with Trento and pushing such ideas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;It is unsurprising but still deeply concerning that the ‘intellectual father’ of family separation (Tom Homan) is working with the anti-immigrant zealot Trento to fundraise for their venture by peddling the absurd conspiracy theory that asylum seekers and migrants constitute an ‘invasion,’” Mueller told Hatewatch in an email. He added the idea is “inexorably linked to ‘replacement theory’ and has direct connections to multiple mass murders in Pittsburgh, El Paso, Buffalo and elsewhere.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The website features other right-wing, alarmist and inflammatory talking points about the border, like the Biden administration supposedly refusing to secure it and hyping the criminality of immigrants. An excerpt on the site reads: “For decades, the globalist media jihad has successfully blinded Americans to the truth. For the first time in US history, an incoming administration has intentionally weakened the security of the nation within hours of assuming power. … The reality of America’s open border is that it is killing Americans.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other staffers associated with Defend the Border and Save Lives includes figures known for peddling Islamophobia. The director of research for the project is Clare Lopez, a former CIA analyst turned anti-Muslim conspiracy theorist. Lopez has said that in addition to houses of worship, mosques are “centers for indoctrination, the dispensing of Sharia justice, the stockpiling of weapons, and the launching of jihad.” She also said in 2013: “When people in other bona fide religions follow their doctrines they become better people – Buddhists, Hindus, Christians, Jews. When Muslims follow their doctrine, they become jihadists.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The project’s director of operations is Mary Wierbicki, who also serves as social media director for The United West and is co-founder of Sharia Crime Stoppers, another project tied to Trento’s group that produces anti-Islam content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During a 2018 webinar produced by Sharia Crime Stoppers, Wierbicki lamented there being around 3,200 mosques across America. “When on 9/11, there were only about 1,000,” she said on the show. “Which means there are an increased number of imams preaching the hate and death of Sharia that this culture promotes. These imams are not trained to preach assimilation or peace with non-Muslims.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The United West organized a private fundraising event on Nov. 1 at Trump’s Mar-a-Lago. The event’s advertisement says it premiered a television program associated with Defend the Border and Save Lives. Tickets for that event, which was said to be sold out, ranged from $1,000 to $25,000. The United West held another private fundraising event for Homan in April, according to an email from the group. Pictures of an event sponsored by The United West were at the bottom of the November event’s ticket page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Trump Organization did not respond for comment about the event.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is not the first time Homan has aligned himself with hate groups. In 2019, Homan was a &lt;a href=&quot;https://theintercept.com/2018/09/01/act-for-america-conference-thomas-homan/&quot;&gt; keynote speaker&lt;/a&gt; at an event in Washington, D.C., put on by the anti-Muslim hate group ACT for America. In late October, Homan appeared at Hold Their Feet to Fire, an annual radio and networking event in D.C. organized by the anti-immigrant hate group Federation for American Immigration Reform (FAIR). A link to FAIR’s event was &lt;a href=&quot;https://archive.ph/tsQ89&quot;&gt;posted&lt;/a&gt; on Defend the Border and Save Lives’ website. Homan also &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=HJkQMam_JTk&quot;&gt;appeared&lt;/a&gt; in a 2021 fundraising video for FAIR’s legal arm, Immigration Reform Law Institute.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Photo illustration by SPLC&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-field-byline field-type-text field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;
                &lt;div class=&quot;field-item even &quot;&gt;Caleb Kieffer&lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-field-addthis field-type-addthis field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;
                &lt;div class=&quot;field-item even &quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;addthis_toolbox addthis_default_style  &quot; addthis:title=&quot;Former ICE Chief Taps Anti-Muslim Hate Group To Help Run Border-Focused Project - Southern Poverty Law Center&quot; addthis:url=&quot;https://www.splcenter.org/hatewatch/2022/11/03/former-ice-chief-taps-anti-muslim-hate-group-help-run-border-focused-project&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot; &quot; class=&quot;addthis_button_facebook&quot; aria-label=&quot;Facebook: Share this page&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot; &quot; class=&quot;addthis_button_twitter&quot; aria-label=&quot;Twitter: Share this page&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-field-publish-date field-type-date field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;
                &lt;div class=&quot;field-item even &quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;date-display-single&quot;&gt;November 03, 2022&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
 <pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 16:30:51 +0000</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>chris.heller_1541</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">17210 at https://www.splcenter.org</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>‘Connecting the Dots’: Southern Echo takes on Mississippi’s voter suppression laws</title>
 <link>https://www.splcenter.org/news/2022/11/01/vote-your-voice-southern-echo-mississippi</link>
 <description>&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-field-story-type field-type-list-text field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;
                &lt;div class=&quot;field-item even &quot;&gt;Features and Stories&lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-field-image field-type-image field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;
                &lt;div class=&quot;field-item even &quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-title-field field-type-text field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;
                &lt;div class=&quot;field-item even &quot;&gt;&lt;h1&gt;‘Connecting the Dots’: Southern Echo takes on Mississippi’s voter suppression laws&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-body field-type-text-with-summary field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;
                &lt;div class=&quot;field-item even &quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mississippian Brenda Hyde well remembers the heart-wrenching experience she had voting in the 2020 presidential election.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“At my precinct, there was a very long line,” she said. “Hours long. I stayed in line, but I saw people giving up and leaving. It was dark and cold. A truck came through with bullhorns, driving fast, covered in Trump flags, support stickers and wooden signs [that read]: ‘Make America Great Again.’ They were loud, hollering. The police were called. It was a form of intimidation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I had on a nice, black T-shirt with a printed saying on the back: ‘They try to silence me. Scare me. Suppress me. Erase me. And still I vote.’ On the front it says: ‘And still I vote.’”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A white man got upset and started talking with other white people around him, Hyde recalled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“He was angry that I was wearing that shirt. It’s an empowerment saying to Black and Brown people – that white people try to intimidate us, but we still vote.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Some white folks get mad when they see the shirt and say, ‘Why are you separating?’ When we wear those shirts, we’re not saying that white votes don’t matter, but we have experienced Black voter suppression, and we’ve gone from not having the right to vote to still facing the fight to vote. This is about power.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hyde is the deputy director of the Jackson-based nonprofit organization &lt;a href=&quot;https://southernecho.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Southern Echo&lt;/a&gt; Inc., an intergenerational leadership development, education and training organization. Southern Echo works with grassroots individuals, groups and other organizations to dismantle institutional and systemic racism in our education, economic, environmental, political and health systems. Its civic engagement work with Black and Brown communities centers around organizing and public education, specifically voting, census and redistricting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During this redistricting and election cycle, Southern Echo is educating and training individuals and grassroots organizations how to draw and promote fair and equitable redistricting maps, engage in get-out-the-vote (GOTV) activities and increase voter participation in elections.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Southern Echo is among 39 voter outreach organizations across the Deep South that are receiving more than &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.splcenter.org/news/2022/08/29/splc-awards-2022-vote-your-voice-grants&quot;&gt;$4.6 million in funding&lt;/a&gt; as part of the new round of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.splcenter.org/vote-your-voice&quot;&gt;Vote Your Voice&lt;/a&gt; grants announced in August. The initiative is a partnership between the SPLC and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://cfgreateratlanta.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Community Foundation for Greater Atlanta&lt;/a&gt; to increase voter registration, participation and civic engagement among communities of color in the Deep South.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The SPLC has &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.splcenter.org/news/2021/12/06/vote-your-voice-expands-splc-pledges-100-million-support-voter-engagement-and-pro-democracy&quot;&gt;pledged to invest $100 million&lt;/a&gt; in Vote Your Voice grants through 2032.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Pathway to change&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div data-embed-button=&quot;media&quot; data-entity-id=&quot;35305&quot; data-entity-label=&quot;Media&quot; data-entity-type=&quot;file&quot; data-entity-uuid=&quot;9a90ead7-f4da-450a-912b-0236db3fc3a2&quot; data-splc-media-url=&quot;&quot; data-view-mode=&quot;full&quot; class=&quot;align-right&quot;&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;file-35305&quot; class=&quot;file file-image file-image-jpeg&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;element-invisible&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/files/webvyv-southern-echo-ms-inline-brenda-shirt2022jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;content&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.splcenter.org/sites/default/files/web_vyv-southern-echo-ms-inline-brenda-shirt_2022.jpg&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; height=&quot;879&quot; alt=&quot;Person wearing And Still I Vote T-shirt&quot; title=&quot;brenda-hyde-vote-t-shirt&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-field-file-caption field-type-text-long field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;field-item even &quot;&gt;Brenda Hyde, deputy director of Southern Echo, wearing the T-shirt she wore while voting in the 2020 presidential election. “Some white folks get mad when they see the shirt,” she says. “When we wear those shirts, we’re not saying that white votes don’t matter. ... This is about power.” (Courtesy of Southern Echo)&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Southern Echo was awarded an additional $120,000 over last year’s $400,000 grant. That grant largely funded the organization’s 365 VOTE, a campaign that included a strong field and education effort to organize voters. It included training poll workers and poll watchers, and educating communities about the importance of voting, voter registration, voter ID, absentee voting, and voter purging.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sixty percent of the new grant will support the continuation of those efforts, but in 2022-2023 Southern Echo will increase education on voter ID requirements and help communities address voter roll purges, which disproportionately affect communities of color. The organization will hold voter restoration workshops and trainings for members of the community who have been incarcerated and disenfranchised. And it will closely monitor polling place closures to inform communities of any changes in their voting locations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Southern Echo will use the remaining 40% of the grant for its fair redistricting map education program. The organization has a redistricting team of 12 members, including eight redistricting fellows and four staff, which covers 58 of Mississippi’s 82 counties. The redistricting team encourages communities to participate in the redistricting process, analyze data and maps and draw community alternative redistricting plans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rachel Mayes, Southern Echo’s executive director, called redistricting “the pathway to democracy and policy change.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The organization uses the metaphor “connecting the dots” in its work to help Black and Brown communities understand the connection between the census, fair redistricting and voting and how each impacts overall quality of life outcomes. This knowledge strengthens the resolve of voters of color to overcome more than a century of concerted Black and Brown voter suppression and disenfranchisement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We as leaders and organizers have to help people navigate their personal experiences as well as what they see in the media, and the reality of January 6&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt;. We need to help address their concerns, motivate and inspire hope, so that they believe that there is still POWER in the VOTE,” Mayes said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;‘Ugly history’&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Getting to that place is no small order in a state that has the highest percentage of Black residents in the country yet whose history of Black and Brown &lt;a href=&quot;https://dce.olemiss.edu/um-votes-exploring-the-history-of-voting-suppression-in-ms/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;voter suppression&lt;/a&gt; remains one of the country’s most racist repudiations of the 14&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; Amendment’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://constitution.congress.gov/browse/amendment-14/#:~:text=No%20State%20shall%20make%20or,equal%20protection%20of%20the%20laws.&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;equal protection clause&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As recently as 2020, Mississippi ranked first among states with 10.6% of its voting age population disenfranchised due to &lt;a href=&quot;https://mississippitoday.org/2020/10/19/study-11-of-all-mississippians-16-of-black-mississippians-cant-vote-because-of-felony-convictions/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;felony convictions&lt;/a&gt;, and third in the country for its 16% Black disenfranchised voting age residents, according to a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sentencingproject.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/Locked-Out-2020.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Sentencing Project&lt;/a&gt; study.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;States in the South tend to have the most &lt;a href=&quot;https://attheu.utah.edu/facultystaff/liu-voting-rights/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;restrictive voting laws&lt;/a&gt;, historically and today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mississippi is among the five states with the most voter restrictions. Its &lt;a href=&quot;/our-future-our-vote/mississippi-voter-guide&quot;&gt;voter ID&lt;/a&gt; laws are strict and discriminatory. They require a driver’s license with photo ID, a U.S. passport or a free voter ID card issued by a circuit court clerk to in-person applicants with accepted forms of proof of identification.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The voter ID law is particularly burdensome for the Black community in Mississippi, where disenfranchisement remains &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mississippifreepress.org/26643/a-wrong-never-righted-court-upholds-mississippis-1890-jim-crow-voting-law&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;structurally entrenched&lt;/a&gt; nearly six decades after the end of the Jim Crow era. The state ranks 48th among states in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.valuepenguin.com/auto-insurance/car-ownership-statistics#state-per-capita&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;number of registered cars per capita&lt;/a&gt;, and many Black people lack driver’s licenses because they cannot afford a vehicle. Some lack other accepted forms of ID proof because their birth at home by midwives was not officially recorded.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition, the state’s confusing and &lt;a href=&quot;https://apnews.com/article/mississippi-voting-rights-delbert-hosemann-elections-voter-registration-be764ae42ca49a8e64e593b3f419c7aa&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;limited absentee balloting&lt;/a&gt; and one-day in-person voting, absence of drop boxes and online voting, and voter intimidation at the polls impose more barriers to the ballot box.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, Black people make up 38% of the state’s population; while 56% of the population is non-Hispanic white, according to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.census.gov/quickfacts/MS&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;2020 U.S. census&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the 2020 presidential election, Mississippi ranked &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.statista.com/statistics/1184621/presidential-election-voter-turnout-rate-state/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;near the bottom&lt;/a&gt; of states for voter participation. At the same time, early and absentee voting &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.census.gov/library/stories/2021/04/what-methods-did-people-use-to-vote-in-2020-election.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;surged&lt;/a&gt; across the country, from 44% in 2016 to 69% in 2020. Black voters in general cast ballots early or absentee at an even higher rate of 69.6%, exceeded only by Asian American Pacific Islander and Latinx voters. While the COVID-19 pandemic largely drove the increase, early mail-in voting for the 2018 midterm elections was the highest then to date. Big early voting numbers for the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnn.com/2022/10/28/politics/midterm-elections-early-absentee-voting-ballots/index.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;2022 midterm elections&lt;/a&gt; point to a continuing trend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But in Mississippi, the voter ID law makes it difficult for many would-be voters who lack a driver’s license or other photo ID and have to appear before a circuit court clerk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“This process isn’t easy and can be frustrating for people,” Mayes said. “You’re supposed to be able to just go in there and say you don’t have a photo ID and be given one, but people are intimidated to go to circuit clerk office for fear that they will be confronted with questions. It makes it hard for people.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Voting should be easy, right? You shouldn’t have to go through what we do to vote. This is just another tactic to keep people away from the polls. It’s consistent with an ugly history of voter suppression in Mississippi,” Mayes said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Fighting against gerrymandering&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the years since 2018 when Southern Echo began its “Connecting the Dots” trainings on voting, census and redistricting, the organization has helped communities draw more than 70 alternative redistricting maps. (Every 10 years after the U.S. census is completed, district maps on the federal, state and local levels are supposed to be reconsidered based on population and demographic changes.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that Southern Echo has resumed in-person education and training, the organization plans to assist even more communities in drawing alternative redistricting plans. The organization is training communities to negotiate directly with city, county and local governing bodies on the “front end” as officials start the process of drawing a new or revised map. If successful, communities will act more as collaborators rather than as angry critics when inequitable maps are introduced at public hearings – often with restricted public comment period before a vote.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“In the past, under &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.americanprogress.org/article/5-reasons-why-section-5-of-the-voting-rights-act-enhances-our-democracy/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;pre-clearance&lt;/a&gt;, Southern states with a history of voter suppression could send both a community map and the jurisdiction’s map to the Justice Department, which would then decide which map to choose,” Mayes explained. “Now the community &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.justice.gov/crt/about-section-5-voting-rights-act#:~:text=On%20June%2025%2C%202013%2C%20the,570%20U.S.%20529%20(2013).&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;can’t send their map&lt;/a&gt; to the Justice Department.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mayes noted that while community activists have been unsuccessful challenging maps that deny Black and Brown voters’ fair representation at the state and federal levels, they have been more successful at the local level. “We are a majority at the city and county level where minority voting strength wasn’t diluted,” she said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“When we talk about redistricting and the connection to voting and strategizing values around the vote, we are connecting the dots. ‘How do we come together as a community to organize to get out the vote?’ ” Mayes said is the ongoing question, “because it’s all connected.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Picture at top: Southern Echo, based in Jackson, Mississippi, is one of 39 voter outreach organizations that are receiving funding from the Vote Your Vote initiative, a partnership between the SPLC and the Community Foundation for Greater Atlanta. Since 2018, Southern Echo has helped communities draw 70 alternative redistricting maps. (Courtesy of Southern Echo)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-field-person field-type-entityreference field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;
                &lt;div class=&quot;field-item even &quot;&gt;&lt;article id=&quot;node-16901&quot; class=&quot;node node-person node-teaser node-even&quot;&gt;

  
  &lt;div class=&quot;content&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;group-text-field-group&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-title-field field-type-text field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;
                &lt;div class=&quot;field-item even &quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/about/staff/rhonda-sonnenberg&quot;&gt;Rhonda Sonnenberg&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-field-person-title field-type-text field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;
                &lt;div class=&quot;field-item even &quot;&gt;Senior Staff Writer&lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;  &lt;/div&gt; &lt;!-- /content --&gt;

  
      &lt;div class=&quot;links&quot;&gt;
          &lt;/div&gt; &lt;!-- /links --&gt;
  
  &lt;/article&gt; &lt;!-- /article #node --&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-field-addthis field-type-addthis field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;
                &lt;div class=&quot;field-item even &quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;addthis_toolbox addthis_default_style  &quot; addthis:title=&quot;&amp;amp;lsquo;Connecting the Dots&amp;amp;rsquo;: Southern Echo takes on Mississippi&amp;amp;rsquo;s voter suppression laws - Southern Poverty Law Center&quot; addthis:url=&quot;https://www.splcenter.org/news/2022/11/01/vote-your-voice-southern-echo-mississippi&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot; &quot; class=&quot;addthis_button_facebook&quot; aria-label=&quot;Facebook: Share this page&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot; &quot; class=&quot;addthis_button_twitter&quot; aria-label=&quot;Twitter: Share this page&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-field-publish-date field-type-date field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;
                &lt;div class=&quot;field-item even &quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;date-display-single&quot;&gt;November 01, 2022&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
 <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2022 18:54:11 +0000</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>rudy.isaza_2663</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">17205 at https://www.splcenter.org</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>Liberty Counsel Used Documents From Gab, ADF for Its Anti-COVID Vaccine Campaign</title>
 <link>https://www.splcenter.org/hatewatch/2022/11/01/liberty-counsel-used-documents-gab-adf-its-anti-covid-vaccine-campaign</link>
 <description>&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-field-story-type field-type-list-text field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;
                &lt;div class=&quot;field-item even &quot;&gt;Hatewatch&lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-field-long-text field-type-text-long field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;
                &lt;div class=&quot;field-item even &quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Liberty Counsel (LC) took documents from outside hate groups and hard-right figures to craft religious-based vaccine exemption requests during the COVID-19 pandemic, leaked documents reviewed by Hatewatch appear to show.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-field-image field-type-image field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;
                &lt;div class=&quot;field-item even &quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-title-field field-type-text field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;
                &lt;div class=&quot;field-item even &quot;&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Liberty Counsel Used Documents From Gab, ADF for Its Anti-COVID Vaccine Campaign&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-body field-type-text-with-summary field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;
                &lt;div class=&quot;field-item even &quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hatewatch reviewed over 40 documents from a leak of files showing the LC’s anti-vaccine and health protocol activism. Most of the documents are publicly available on the LC website. However, the LC website was down after a hacker who identifies with the Anonymous movement &lt;a href=&quot;https://theintercept.com/2022/08/25/liberty-counsel-data-breach/&quot;&gt; exploited vulnerabilities&lt;/a&gt; in the website’s software. The hacker released the leak on Enlace Hacktivista, a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.checkpoint.com/cyber-hub/threat-prevention/what-is-hacktivism/&quot;&gt; hacktivist&lt;/a&gt; site. Transparency collective Distributed Denial of Secrets, which provides access to journalists, allowed Hatewatch to review the documents. Hatewatch then reviewed the documents on the LC website when it was back online. The documents’ metadata matched.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The documents include LC’s boilerplate religious exemption requests for various faiths, students, employees and pastors.&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;Hatewatch reviewed metadata from the files and public information suggesting that some of these requests were created by outside parties, including an employee of the SPLC-designated anti-LGBTQ hate group Alliance Defending Freedom (ADF) and Andrew Torba, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.splcenter.org/hatewatch/2019/06/19/gab-waited-days-remove-user-arrested-inciting-violence&quot;&gt; the CEO of Gab&lt;/a&gt;, a social media site popular with the hard right.&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;The leak also shows the LC stored a trove of misinformation regarding COVID-19 vaccines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The LC is an &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.splcenter.org/fighting-hate/extremist-files/group/liberty-counsel&quot;&gt; anti-LGBTQ hate group&lt;/a&gt;, but it works on various cultural issues popular with the hard right under the guise of religious activism. The U.S. Supreme Court cited an LC brief in its June 24 decision to end 50 years of abortion protection. The LC has also worked against vaccine mandates for decades.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The LC did not respond to Hatewatch’s request for comment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Boilerplate requests&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The LC hosts boilerplate religious exemptions on its website for Catholic, Orthodox and Protestant Christians and Jewish people. Also, the leak contains broad employment and student exemption requests. Hatewatch examined metadata for these files, some of which appears to show who created the documents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Metadata lists Bridgett DeLapp as the creator of the student, employment and pastoral exemption requests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DeLapp worked as a digital designer at the White House during the Trump administration, according to government records. DeLapp attended Hillsdale College in Hillsdale, Michigan. In 2016, she also told the &lt;em&gt;Hillsdale Collegian&lt;/em&gt;, the college newspaper, that she worked on the campaigns of two conservative Republican Michigan Supreme Court justices, Joan Larsen and David Viviano. Larsen was on Trump’s short list for Supreme Court vacancies, and Viviano is DeLapp’s uncle, she said. DeLapp also told the Hillsdale College Student Activities Board in 2018 that she was the digital director for the Michigan Republican Party.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the leaving the White House, DeLapp joined the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.splcenter.org/fighting-hate/extremist-files/group/alliance-defending-freedom&quot;&gt; Alliance Defending Freedom&lt;/a&gt;, an anti-LGBTQ hate group, as a campaign manager in February 2021, according to a data broker. DeLapp became ADF’s director for visual communications in August 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The metadata for the student exemption suggests DeLapp created the document while employed at ADF.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hatewatch asked the LC and ADF about the documents. Neither responded. Hatewatch was unable to find DeLapp’s contact information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The metadata for the Orthodox Christian request lists “John and Karen Seipp” as the creator. But the document’s origins likely lie in Gab, a social media site popular with the hard right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The document shares metadata with another trove of religious exemption requests on Gab. The metadata for the Gab files also contains the names John and Karen Seipp, but the “create” and “modify” dates in the Gab files precede those on the LC files, suggesting the LC retrieved some of its exemption requests from Gab.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A Change.org petition calling for Michigan State University to end its mask-wearing and vaccine mandates features the text of the LC and Gab Orthodox exemption request. However, the petition lists Gab CEO Andrew Torba as the author. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.adl.org/blog/gab-ceo-andrew-torba-broadcasts-his-antisemitism-across-social-media-platforms&quot;&gt; Torba espouses antisemitic&lt;/a&gt;, far-right Christian Nationalist rhetoric.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Torba did not respond to Hatewatch’s request for comment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Religious reasoning&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Liberty Counsel discusses its reasoning for its anti-vaccine positions in a presentation titled “Vaccines and Religious Liberty.” LC chairperson Matthew Staver appears to have given the presentation on Oct. 22, 2020, less than two months before U.S. health officials &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.supremecourt.gov/opinions/urls_cited/ot2021/21a90/21a90-1.pdf&quot;&gt; administered the first COVID-19 vaccine&lt;/a&gt; to the public.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The document, which contains PowerPoint slides, starts with anti-abortion talking points and cites the chicken pox, hepatitis A and rubella vaccines, versions of which use fetal cells derived from aborted fetuses. Health officials say the fetuses were voluntarily aborted in the 1960s and no new abortions are required to produce these vaccines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The LC has since claimed in legal threats and in its boilerplate exemption forms that the use of fetal tissue in the testing of the Pfizer and Moderna vaccines constitutes a reasonable religious objection. Neither &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.health.nd.gov/sites/www/files/documents/COVID%20Vaccine%20Page/COVID-19_Vaccine_Fetal_Cell_Handout.pdf&quot;&gt; use&lt;/a&gt; aborted fetal tissue in their development or production. However, researchers used fetal tissue to prove cells could accept the vaccines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Catholic Church takes an anti-abortion stance, which has caused some Catholics to worry about receiving the vaccines. But the Catholic Church approved the use of COVID-19 vaccines in December 2020, Dr. Jason Eberl, a professor of healthcare ethics and director of the Albert Gnaegi Center for Health Care Ethics at Saint Louis University, told Hatewatch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The church’s Congregation for the Doctrine of the Faith (CDF), which Eberl described as “arguably the most important office in the Vatican other than the pope himself,” declared, “It’s permissible to … receive a vaccine despite this connection to abortion” to safeguard personal and public health.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Basically, what the CDF said is that any Catholic in good conscience can receive any of the approved or authorized COVID-19 vaccines,” Eberl said. He explained the December 2020 pronouncement followed a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.immunize.org/talking-about-vaccines/vaticandocument.htm&quot;&gt; similar decision in 2005&lt;/a&gt; from an advisory council called the Pontifical Academy for Life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“To my knowledge,” Eberl continued, “no church leader who’s in communion with the Vatican has definitively said that a Catholic cannot receive these vaccines.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similarly, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goarch.org/-/holy-eparchial-synod-ccmmunique&quot;&gt; Orthodox Church said&lt;/a&gt;, “There is no exemption in the Orthodox Church for Her faithful from any vaccination for religious reasons, including the coronavirus vaccine.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mainstream, anti-abortion, conservative Protestant organizations such as the Christian Medical &amp;amp; Dental Associations (CMDA) have said the vaccines &lt;a href=&quot;https://cmda.org/the-ethics-of-the-sars-cov-2-vaccines-revisited/&quot;&gt; are ethically sound&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are various &lt;a href=&quot;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/12309928/&quot;&gt;views on abortion&lt;/a&gt; among Jewish people. Generally, followers of Judaism hold life as sacred, but some &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncjw.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/Judaism-and-Abortion-FINAL.pdf&quot;&gt; do not consider a fetus alive&lt;/a&gt; until birth has begun. However, even conservative movements such as the ultra-Orthodox Chabad movement &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.chabad.org/library/article_cdo/aid/4980531/jewish/Can-I-Use-Vaccines-Made-From-Fetal-Tissue-or-Non-Kosher-Animals.htm&quot;&gt; say it is fine to take the COVID-19 vaccine&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Misinformation trove&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hatewatch’s review of the cache found the LC stored a trove of misinformation and mistruths regarding COVID-19 vaccines, many of which news media and health experts fought to dispel as misinformation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The LC files contain debunked papers about mRNA COVID-19 vaccines that osteopathic physician Joseph Mercola authored. &lt;em&gt;The New York Times&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2021/07/24/technology/joseph-mercola-coronavirus-misinformation-online.html&quot;&gt; called&lt;/a&gt; Mercola the “most influential spreader of coronavirus misinformation online” in a 2021 article.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One LC-hosted Mercola publication titled “Might COVID Injections Reduce Lifespan?” claims evidence suggests the COVID vaccine shortened lifespans by years. Social media users posted similar misinformation “thousands” of times, according to Reuters. This claim is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reuters.com/article/factcheck-mrna-vaccines/fact-check-there-is-no-evidence-mrna-vaccines-reduce-life-expectancy-or-cause-severe-health-issues-including-infertility-and-neuro-cognitive-problems-idUSL1N2MC0VF&quot;&gt; false&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another Mercola paper claims COVID-19 vaccines cause miscarriages. The paper said, “Getting the COVID shot during the first 20 weeks of pregnancy is extremely risky – the risk of miscarriage is anywhere between 82% and 91%.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The paper uses a faulty analysis of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention’s (CDC) Vaccine Adverse Effects Reporting System (VAERS) database, where people can report side effects they experience after vaccination.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Studies disprove these claims. One &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nejm.org/doi/full/10.1056/NEJMc2113891&quot;&gt;study&lt;/a&gt; showed the risk of miscarriage following a COVID-19 vaccination during the first 20 weeks of pregnancy was roughly 18%, well within the expected risk range.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similar misinformation appears in religious exemption requests. The Jewish request document contains similarly misleading claims about the VAERS database.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;VAERS does not prove causation for side effects. According to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.muhealth.org/our-stories/scary-reports-deaths-following-covid-19-vaccination-arent-what-they-seem&quot;&gt; MU Health Care&lt;/a&gt;, part of the University of Missouri, “If a 90-year-old nursing home resident got the vaccine and then died days, weeks or even months later of another ailment, the resident’s death would be reported to VAERS.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Further, all VAERS reports are unverified.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Editor’s note: Megan Squire contributed to this reporting.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-field-byline field-type-text field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;
                &lt;div class=&quot;field-item even &quot;&gt;Creede Newton&lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-field-addthis field-type-addthis field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;
                &lt;div class=&quot;field-item even &quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;addthis_toolbox addthis_default_style  &quot; addthis:title=&quot;Liberty Counsel Used Documents From Gab, ADF for Its Anti-COVID Vaccine Campaign - Southern Poverty Law Center&quot; addthis:url=&quot;https://www.splcenter.org/hatewatch/2022/11/01/liberty-counsel-used-documents-gab-adf-its-anti-covid-vaccine-campaign&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot; &quot; class=&quot;addthis_button_facebook&quot; aria-label=&quot;Facebook: Share this page&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot; &quot; class=&quot;addthis_button_twitter&quot; aria-label=&quot;Twitter: Share this page&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-field-publish-date field-type-date field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;
                &lt;div class=&quot;field-item even &quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;date-display-single&quot;&gt;November 01, 2022&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
 <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2022 14:38:25 +0000</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>chris.heller_1541</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">17204 at https://www.splcenter.org</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>Newsweek Embraces the Anti-Democracy Hard Right</title>
 <link>https://www.splcenter.org/hatewatch/2022/11/04/newsweek-embraces-anti-democracy-hard-right</link>
 <description>&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-field-story-type field-type-list-text field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;
                &lt;div class=&quot;field-item even &quot;&gt;Hatewatch&lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-field-long-text field-type-text-long field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;
                &lt;div class=&quot;field-item even &quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Newsweek&lt;/em&gt; positioned political activist Josh Hammer to run their opinion pages during the runup to the 2020 presidential election, and since that time, the publication has taken a marked radical right turn by buoying extremists and promoting authoritarian leaders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-field-image field-type-image field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;
                &lt;div class=&quot;field-item even &quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-title-field field-type-text field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;
                &lt;div class=&quot;field-item even &quot;&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Newsweek Embraces the Anti-Democracy Hard Right&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-body field-type-text-with-summary field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;
                &lt;div class=&quot;field-item even &quot;&gt;&lt;div data-embed-button=&quot;media&quot; data-entity-id=&quot;35286&quot; data-entity-label=&quot;Media&quot; data-entity-type=&quot;file&quot; data-entity-uuid=&quot;41e21ee7-5db4-4ee0-9912-0920c8c48401&quot; data-splc-media-url=&quot;&quot; data-view-mode=&quot;full&quot; class=&quot;align-right&quot;&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;file-35286&quot; class=&quot;file file-image file-image-jpeg&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;element-invisible&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/files/joshhammergageskidmore-700pxjpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;content&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.splcenter.org/sites/default/files/josh_hammer_gage_skidmore-700px.jpg&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; height=&quot;467&quot; alt=&quot;Josh Hammer&quot; title=&quot;Josh Hammer&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-field-file-caption field-type-text-long field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;field-item even &quot;&gt;Josh Hammer speaks with attendees at the 2021 Student Action Summit hosted by Turning Point USA at the Tampa Convention Center in Tampa, Florida. (Photo by Gage Skidmore)&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although opinion pages in ostensibly nonpartisan, mainstream publications promote political opinions, sometimes controversial ones, &lt;em&gt;Newsweek&lt;/em&gt; stands alone among such brands in its willingness to elevate such figures as &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.splcenter.org/fighting-hate/extremist-files/individual/jack-posobiec&quot;&gt; Jack Posobiec&lt;/a&gt;, known for promoting the Pizzagate disinformation campaign, and Dinesh D’Souza, whose film &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.npr.org/2022/09/20/1123898736/prominent-election-deniers-are-facing-growing-legal-trouble&quot;&gt; &lt;em&gt;2000 Mules&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; researchers roundly debunked for spreading conspiracies about the 2020 election. Under Hammer’s leadership, &lt;em&gt;Newsweek&lt;/em&gt; has also aired bigoted views, like appearing to call for the state to deny adults access to trans-affirming medical care and supporting a ban on all legal immigration into the U.S. They have also spread baseless conspiracies about COVID-19, with one of Hammer’s collaborators describing vaccines designed to fight the virus as a “bioweapon.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Newsweek&lt;/em&gt; has also failed to disclose potential conflicts of interest emerging in the content published through Hammer’s opinion section and his &lt;em&gt;Newsweek&lt;/em&gt;-branded podcast, “The Josh Hammer Show.” Hammer donated to the campaign of Arizona U.S. Senate candidate Blake Masters and at least four times published the work of a man who ran one of Masters’ fundraisers. On his podcast, Hammer told &lt;em&gt;Newsweek&lt;/em&gt;’s audience to “go ahead and vote for Blake Masters.” Hammer also promoted hard-right Hungarian leader Viktor Orbán in a &lt;em&gt;Newsweek&lt;/em&gt; dispatch authored from Hungary, without disclosing that he arrived there in collaboration with a group directly affiliated with the Hungarian government. Hammer also claims membership in a number of reactionary activist groups, and regularly publishes people who are also affiliated with them. He will appear on behalf of the New York Young Republican Club alongside Posobiec and QAnon influencer-turned-congressperson &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.splcenter.org/hatewatch/2020/09/09/congressional-candidate-marjorie-taylor-greene-has-several-ties-conspiracy-hate-groups&quot;&gt; Marjorie Taylor Greene&lt;/a&gt; in December.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hatewatch reached out to &lt;em&gt;Newsweek&lt;/em&gt; for comment about the reporting published in this analysis. &lt;em&gt;Newsweek&lt;/em&gt; first introduced Hatewatch to a representative of the journalism-focused non-profit Poynter, whom they contracted to advise them on ethics in 2019. Hatewatch had three different conversations with Poynter about &lt;em&gt;Newsweek&lt;/em&gt; and their relationship, which are detailed later in this analysis. A representative from the public relations agency LBG PR replied asking for our questions. Hatewatch responded by emailing 19 different specific questions inspired by the reporting in this analysis, and LBG PR issued the following statement in reply:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Newsweek’s opinions section features voices across the political and cultural spectrum. While he offers up his own opinions on the Newsweek platform, as Opinions Editor, Josh Hammer has embraced the mission of &#039;The Debate&#039; and delivered an expansive forum for diverse perspectives and dialogue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Campaigning for Blake Masters through &lt;em&gt;Newsweek&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div data-embed-button=&quot;media&quot; data-entity-id=&quot;35289&quot; data-entity-label=&quot;Media&quot; data-entity-type=&quot;file&quot; data-entity-uuid=&quot;b4556040-40e6-4a80-9d7d-1cccdca0e5ec&quot; data-splc-media-url=&quot;&quot; data-view-mode=&quot;full&quot; class=&quot;align-left&quot;&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;file-35289&quot; class=&quot;file file-image file-image-png&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;element-invisible&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/files/joshhammertweetblakemasters-700pxpng&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;content&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.splcenter.org/sites/default/files/josh_hammer_tweet_blakemasters-700px.png&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; height=&quot;584&quot; alt=&quot;Hammer and Masters&quot; title=&quot;Hammer and Masters&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-field-file-caption field-type-text-long field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;field-item even &quot;&gt;Josh Hammer (left) and Blake Masters. (Photo via Twitter)&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blake Masters, the Republican candidate for Arizona’s U.S. Senate seat, has emerged as a favored candidate of white nationalists, neo-Nazis and other admirers of fascism. (One of his major donors, tech billionaire Peter Thiel, has said he no longer believes freedom and democracy are “compatible.”) The notorious white supremacist website &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.splcenter.org/fighting-hate/extremist-files/group/american-renaissance&quot;&gt; American Renaissance&lt;/a&gt; has republished versions of stories about Masters’ controversies from other outlets, drawing cheers from their notoriously racist comment section. White nationalist &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.splcenter.org/fighting-hate/extremist-files/individual/nick-fuentes&quot;&gt; Nick Fuentes&lt;/a&gt;, who praises such fascist dictators as Adolf Hitler and Benito Mussolini, also supports Masters. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.splcenter.org/fighting-hate/extremist-files/individual/andrew-anglin&quot;&gt; Neo-Nazi Andrew Anglin&lt;/a&gt; of the hate site The Daily Stormer &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.azcentral.com/story/news/politics/elections/2022/07/01/trump-backed-senate-candidate-blake-masters-rejects-endorsement-of-neo-nazi-site-founder/7792690001/&quot;&gt; wrote to his fans&lt;/a&gt; about Masters in June:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;I cannot give a more forceful endorsement, and I demand that anyone in Arizona (who is not some kind of known neo-Nazi or whatever) get in contact with his campaign and see what kind of help he needs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hammer donated $500 to Masters in February, according to public records, and seven months later told &lt;em&gt;Newsweek&lt;/em&gt;’s audience in explicit terms to vote for him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“If you are in Arizona and listening to this podcast, go ahead and vote for Blake Masters,” Hammer told &lt;em&gt;Newsweek&lt;/em&gt;’s audience on a Sept. 5 podcast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Newsweek&lt;/em&gt;’s opinion section has featured other Masters advocates. A man named Austin Stone has published at least four opinion pieces under Hammer’s leadership. Stone gave $5,800 to Masters’ campaign on Aug. 5, 2021, which is the maximum allowed. Stone hosted a fundraiser for Masters, which featured as guests a who’s who of radical right figures including &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.splcenter.org/fighting-hate/extremist-files/individual/jack-posobiec&quot;&gt; Posobiec&lt;/a&gt;, the anti-LGBTQ, right-wing activist &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/education/2021/06/19/critical-race-theory-rufo-republicans/&quot;&gt; Christopher Rufo&lt;/a&gt;, and British disinformation hustler &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.adl.org/blog/at-the-extremes-the-2020-election-and-american-extremism-part-1&quot;&gt; Raheem Kassam&lt;/a&gt;. All three of those men have contributed to &lt;em&gt;Newsweek&lt;/em&gt; and boast ties to the Claremont Institute, who gave Hammer a fellowship in 2018. &lt;em&gt;Newsweek&lt;/em&gt; also published the opinions of Nick Lindquist, a strategist for Stone’s consultancy firm. Lindquist donated $250 to Masters on Oct. 26, 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;News articles on &lt;em&gt;Newsweek&lt;/em&gt;’s own website underscore why their opinion editor’s advocacy of Masters might provoke concern.&lt;em&gt;Newsweek&lt;/em&gt; reported in August 2021 that Masters railed against &lt;a href=&quot;https://archive.ph/PYpxD&quot;&gt; “anti-white”&lt;/a&gt; racism, and this June that he blamed gun violence on &lt;a href=&quot;https://archive.ph/orK7T&quot;&gt;“Black people,”&lt;/a&gt; evoking talking points that white nationalists often embrace. &lt;em&gt;Newsweek&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://archive.ph/OMhsJ#selection-955.0-955.132&quot;&gt;reported&lt;/a&gt; in June that Masters amplified unfounded conspiracies about the 2021 attack on the Capitol by asking, “Don’t we suspect that like one-third of the people outside of the Capitol complex on January 6 were actual FBI agents hanging out?” An &lt;a href=&quot;https://archive.ph/zZ3Wz#selection-807.0-807.75&quot;&gt; Aug. 29 &lt;em&gt;Newsweek&lt;/em&gt; headline&lt;/a&gt; also declared, “Blake Masters Suggests Female, Black and Gay Officials Hurting U.S. Economy,” referring to comments he made about employees of the Federal Reserve.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Newsweek opinion and shifting the ‘Overton window’&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When searching Apple podcasts for “Newsweek,” several products &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.documentcloud.org/documents/22337216-screen-shot-2022-09-13-at-11415-pm&quot;&gt; surface&lt;/a&gt;, but first among them is “The Josh Hammer Show,” Hammer’s weekly podcast. &lt;em&gt;Newsweek&lt;/em&gt; positions a stream of “The Josh Hammer Show” &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.documentcloud.org/documents/22337374-screen-shot-2022-09-13-at-11902-pm&quot;&gt; on its homepage&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;em&gt;Newsweek&lt;/em&gt; also links to it a second time on the homepage through &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.documentcloud.org/documents/22338277-screen-shot-2022-09-13-at-12254-pm&quot;&gt; a clickable image&lt;/a&gt;, meaning that casual visitors can listen to Hammer speak twice without even visiting the opinion section he runs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Newsweek&lt;/em&gt; published the first episode of Hammer’s podcast on Feb. 1, and he used it to talk about how the purpose of his show would focus on building a political movement, rather than simply comment on the news, something that stands out from the work of opinion editors from publications that aspire to be mainstream. He used the phrase “[shifting] the Overton window” in describing the show, which refers to the idea of moving the culture to places where previously unthinkable political realities would emerge. Among many other places, writers for such racist, radical-right websites as &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.documentcloud.org/documents/22415300-screen-shot-2022-09-14-at-34112-pm&quot;&gt; VDARE&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.documentcloud.org/documents/22415304-screen-shot-2022-09-14-at-34531-pm&quot;&gt; American Renaissance&lt;/a&gt; commonly write about shifting or destroying the current “Overton window.” Hammer suggested that the goal of his &lt;em&gt;Newsweek&lt;/em&gt;-branded podcast is to workshop ways to defeat “the woke, illiberal left”:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;We’re going to have a lot of great guests, we’re going to bring them on in a weekly fashion for you, we’re going to spruce in some monologues, some guest commentary, and what we’re going to be talking about here, this is a conservative podcast, we’re talking about conservatism, what is conservatism, what has conservatism been doing right, what has it been doing wrong, what has the Republican party, which obviously is the vehicle for conservatism, what has that been doing right, what has that been doing wrong, what needs to be changed. And it’s a really exciting time obviously to be engaged in this sort of conversation. I mean if you go back just a few years ago obviously 2016 Donald Trump comes out of nowhere, shakes up the world, absolutely obliterates the field in a highly contested presidential primary, slays all sorts of old orthodoxies, that proves that they were way more easily destroyful [sic] than anyone had previously thought, And that period of intellectual ferment, of all sorts of new thoughts, of Overton window shifting, of exploring new ideas. What is it that we really stand for? What do we want this to be about? How do we best form a movement? How do we best organize a political party? Ultimately of course for the goal of defeating the woke, illiberal left and ultimately saving America.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The guests on Hammer’s show reliably advance pro-Trump, reactionary and sometimes overtly authoritarian viewpoints. Some of them, such as Michael Knowles, express hateful views of the LGBTQ+ community. Knowles, a pundit for Ben Shapiro’s The Daily Wire, used his appearance on the &lt;em&gt;Newsweek&lt;/em&gt;-branded show to argue that he is within his rights to tell adult transgender women that they are not women. Knowles made the comment in the context of a discussion with Hammer about how conservatives could wield state power to enforce upon all people the values they hold.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“What the new conservatives … are saying is: ‘No, I actually can tell the difference between a man and a woman. I actually can tell men that they shouldn’t mutilate themselves to look more like women,’” Knowles said on Hammer’s show.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hatewatch emailed Knowles to clarify whether he supported using state power to forbid adults from transitioning, but he did not respond by press time. Following initial publication of this story, he shared his response on Twitter. In his &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.documentcloud.org/documents/23270444-screen-shot-2022-11-04-at-53920-pm&quot;&gt;comments&lt;/a&gt;, Knowles confirms he does in fact support the use of state power to prevent adults from transitioning, comparing gender affirming surgery to cutting off the limbs of a hypothetical able-bodied person &quot;claiming to be a quadriplegic.&quot; On Twitter, Knowles said he emailed his response in September, but Hatewatch found no record of the correspondence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hatewatch also emailed the question to &lt;em&gt;Newsweek&lt;/em&gt;, but they ignored it. Through &lt;em&gt;Newsweek&lt;/em&gt;, Hammer repeatedly argues for using wielding state power to enforce what he describes as conservative values. He has also argued for using the state not to better anyone’s life in particular, but to enact revenge on political opponents, as he wrote in Aug. 12 op-ed called “American Stasi,” referring to the defunct East German military police:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;The imperative for conservatives is to respond not merely by tsk-tsking but by recognizing “what time it is” in this ailing, late-stage republic and to demonstrate a willingness to counter the Left’s brazen assaults with our own willingness to prudentially engage in escalatory, tit-for-tat, mutually assured destruction tactics. Sometimes, the only way out is through.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In his op-ed written from Hungary, wherein &lt;em&gt;Newsweek&lt;/em&gt; failed to disclose the purpose of his visit, Hammer described Viktor Orbán’s authoritarian Fidesz Party as a potential model for American politics. He argued in it for a “greater imperative to wield state power.” Fidesz has &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2018/9/13/17823488/hungary-democracy-authoritarianism-trump&quot;&gt; &lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2018/9/13/17823488/hungary-democracy-authoritarianism-trump&quot;&gt; levied&lt;/a&gt; state power, as Hammer describes it, to &lt;a href=&quot;https://cpj.org/2021/11/hungary-klubradio-andras-arato-loss-broadcast-license/&quot;&gt; clamp down on press freedoms&lt;/a&gt; and dissent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hammer hosted Daniel Horowitz of The Blaze on April 5, who described vaccines that treat COVID-19 as a “bioweapon.” More specifically, Horowitz said that elites were “creating, foisting upon us viruses, blocking the treatment for it and then foisting another bioweapon upon us to treat it.” Hammer also featured Ann Coulter on June 14. Coulter has contributed regularly to the white nationalist website VDARE, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.splcenter.org/hatewatch/2021/04/25/chauvin-trial-inspires-racist-conspiracy-theories&quot;&gt; including several pieces&lt;/a&gt; defending Derek Chauvin, the police officer found guilty of murdering George Floyd. Coulter used her appearance to advocate for banning all legal immigration into the U.S.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We need a total moratorium on immigration,” Coulter said on her June 14 appearance on &lt;em&gt;Newsweek&lt;/em&gt;’s podcast, echoing rhetoric that is familiar to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.splcenter.org/hatewatch/2019/11/12/stephen-millers-affinity-white-nationalism-revealed-leaked-emails&quot;&gt; readers of white nationalist websites&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Newsweek&lt;/em&gt; ignored questions Hatewatch asked about whether they knew they aired opinions including calling COVID-19 a bioweapon, advocating for the government to bar legal immigration into the U.S. and forbidding adults to be transgender. They also ignored questions about Hammer’s trip to Hungary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Propaganda about civil war&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hammer repeatedly frames news events in terms of friends fighting enemies in a civil war. Hammer himself fights in the war he describes, along with his friends, according to his rhetoric. He often invites the listener along, talking about what “we” must do to defeat “our” enemies:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;The onus for our side is … to call out the nonsense … to soberly recognize where we are in what appears to be a falling, decadent, late-stage republic and to act accordingly … to know what time it is … and to command our side’s battle stations accordingly … to go to battle in this roiling, cold civil war against our domestic foes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;div data-embed-button=&quot;media&quot; data-entity-id=&quot;35287&quot; data-entity-label=&quot;Media&quot; data-entity-type=&quot;file&quot; data-entity-uuid=&quot;fa190fae-20f5-4fb7-92ce-45af55fff3f6&quot; data-splc-media-url=&quot;&quot; data-view-mode=&quot;full&quot; class=&quot;align-right&quot;&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;file-35287&quot; class=&quot;file file-image file-image-jpeg&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;element-invisible&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/files/jackposobiecgageskidmore-700pxjpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;content&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.splcenter.org/sites/default/files/jack_posobiec_gage_skidmore-700px.jpg&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; height=&quot;467&quot; alt=&quot;Jack Posobiec&quot; title=&quot;Jack Posobiec&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-field-file-caption field-type-text-long field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;field-item even &quot;&gt;Jack Posobiec speaks with attendees at the 2020 Student Action Summit hosted by Turning Point USA at the Palm Beach County Convention Center in West Palm Beach, Florida. (Photo by Gage Skidmore)&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hammer made those comments on an Aug. 8 episode of his &lt;em&gt;Newsweek&lt;/em&gt;-branded podcast, one in which hosted the extremist Posobiec, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.splcenter.org/fighting-hate/extremist-files/individual/jack-posobiec&quot;&gt; &lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.splcenter.org/fighting-hate/extremist-files/individual/jack-posobiec&quot;&gt; a man primarily known&lt;/a&gt; for spreading viral disinformation campaigns, such as Stop the Steal and Pizzagate. Posobiec has promoted and worked with antigovernment groups and hate groups who attacked the Capitol on Jan. 6, 2021, including the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=HDSb02EJhDE&quot;&gt; &lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=HDSb02EJhDE&quot;&gt; Oath Keepers and Proud Boys&lt;/a&gt;&lt;u&gt;,&lt;/u&gt; respectively. He also associates with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.splcenter.org/hatewatch/2020/07/22/oanns-posobiec-met-polish-neo-fascists-and-amplified-their-messages-online&quot;&gt; &lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.splcenter.org/hatewatch/2020/07/22/oanns-posobiec-met-polish-neo-fascists-and-amplified-their-messages-online&quot;&gt; Polish neofascists&lt;/a&gt;, and filmed far-right propaganda videos at least twice with a pair of terroristic, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=r5j0JBItheA&quot;&gt;neo-Nazi&lt;/a&gt; brothers. On Twitter, Hammer has called the racist internet performer &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.documentcloud.org/documents/22415314-screen-shot-2022-09-14-at-35856-pm&quot;&gt; &lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.documentcloud.org/documents/22415314-screen-shot-2022-09-14-at-35856-pm&quot;&gt; “a great American patriot.” &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hammer and Posobiec spoke about the FBI’s retrieval of classified documents from Trump’s Mar-a-Lago residence in Florida, making conspiratorial assertions without offering evidence in support. “What do we do when the notion of equal justice under law is just crumbling before our very eyes?” Hammer asked Posobiec during that appearance. Posobiec then claimed of Attorney General Merrick Garland, “I don’t have any specific reporting on this but I like to think … he’s getting revenge” for Republicans blocking his Supreme Court candidacy in 2016. Hammer agreed with enthusiasm, replying: “It is vindictive. It is revenge.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div data-embed-button=&quot;media&quot; data-entity-id=&quot;35290&quot; data-entity-label=&quot;Media&quot; data-entity-type=&quot;file&quot; data-entity-uuid=&quot;e96734fb-875c-4770-9df4-19869cf79c8e&quot; data-splc-media-url=&quot;&quot; data-view-mode=&quot;full&quot; class=&quot;align-left&quot;&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;file-35290&quot; class=&quot;file file-image file-image-png&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;element-invisible&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/files/joshhammertweetjackpwarroom-700pxpng&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;content&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.splcenter.org/sites/default/files/josh_hammer_tweet_jackp_war_room-700px.png&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; height=&quot;602&quot; alt=&quot;Hammer Posobiec tweet&quot; title=&quot;Hammer Posobiec tweet&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-field-file-caption field-type-text-long field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;field-item even &quot;&gt;Josh Hammer thanked Jack Posobiec for hosting him on Steve Bannon’s &#039;War Room&#039; podcast in this Feb. 2 tweet. (Photo via Twitter)&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“[Trump] is unambiguously the victim here,” Hammer told Posobiec. “He is clearly the victim of an unprecedented sicking of federal law enforcement.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Newsweek&lt;/em&gt; published the podcast more than two weeks before the Justice Department revealed a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnbc.com/2022/08/26/doj-reveals-redacted-affidavit-justifying-trump-mar-a-lago-raid.html&quot;&gt; &lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnbc.com/2022/08/26/doj-reveals-redacted-affidavit-justifying-trump-mar-a-lago-raid.html&quot;&gt; highly-redacted copy&lt;/a&gt; of the affidavit they used to justify the raid of Trump’s property. A few weeks after Hammer’s conversation with Posobiec, and the day after President Biden gave a Sept. 1 speech criticizing the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.splcenter.org/hatewatch/2021/12/30/one-year-after-jan-6-hard-right-digs&quot;&gt; &lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.splcenter.org/hatewatch/2021/12/30/one-year-after-jan-6-hard-right-digs&quot;&gt; Trump-influenced&lt;/a&gt; rebrand of the Republican Party, Hammer &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.documentcloud.org/documents/22274618-screen-shot-2022-09-02-at-31746-pm&quot;&gt; &lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.documentcloud.org/documents/22274618-screen-shot-2022-09-02-at-31746-pm&quot;&gt; tweeted out&lt;/a&gt; comments framing America as a country at war, a common trope of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.splcenter.org/hatewatch/2020/08/27/fascist-underpinnings-pro-trump-media-interview-author-jason-stanley&quot;&gt; &lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.splcenter.org/hatewatch/2020/08/27/fascist-underpinnings-pro-trump-media-interview-author-jason-stanley&quot;&gt; vintage fascist propaganda&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;No more ‘peace-time’ conservatism, people. Stop fighting last century’s war. Our side needs a lot of war time consiglieres, and we need them now.&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Hyping &lt;em&gt;2000 Mules &lt;/em&gt; through &lt;em&gt;Newsweek&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div data-embed-button=&quot;media&quot; data-entity-id=&quot;35318&quot; data-entity-label=&quot;Media&quot; data-entity-type=&quot;file&quot; data-entity-uuid=&quot;2c9c5013-e840-4686-a915-d2ef9f8a48a6&quot; data-splc-media-url=&quot;Newsweek promotes radical right talking points through The Josh Hammer Show.&quot; data-view-mode=&quot;full&quot; class=&quot;align-right&quot;&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;file-35318&quot; class=&quot;file file-video file-video-youtube&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;element-invisible&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/files/excerpts-newsweeks-hard-right-turn&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;content&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;media-youtube-video media-youtube-1&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe class=&quot;media-youtube-player&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;390&quot; title=&quot;Excerpts from Newsweek&#039;s Hard Right Turn&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/TXFuPpPfxDo?wmode=opaque&amp;amp;controls=&amp;amp;rel=0&quot; name=&quot;Excerpts from Newsweek&#039;s Hard Right Turn&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; id=&quot;Excerpts from Newsweek&#039;s Hard Right Turn&quot;&gt;Video of Excerpts from Newsweek&amp;amp;#039;s Hard Right Turn&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-field-file-caption field-type-text-long field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;field-item even &quot;&gt;Newsweek promotes radical right talking points through The Josh Hammer Show.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hammer hosted right-wing performer Dinesh D’Souza on the May 10 episode of his podcast to promote his book and accompanying film &lt;em&gt;2000 Mules&lt;/em&gt;, which falsely allege that Biden defeated Trump in the 2020 election due to widespread fraud. Non-partisan fact checkers from across the journalism industry have &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reuters.com/article/factcheck-usa-mules/fact-check-does-2000-mules-provide-evidence-of-voter-fraud-in-the-2020-u-s-presidential-election-idUSL2N2XJ0OQ&quot;&gt; debunked D’Souza’s premise&lt;/a&gt;. Radical right publisher Regnery even &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.npr.org/2022/09/08/1121648290/a-publisher-abruptly-recalled-the-2-000-mules-election-denial-book-npr-got-a-cop&quot;&gt; pulled the book version&lt;/a&gt; of &lt;em&gt;2000 Mules&lt;/em&gt; from stores in September due to potentially “libelous” claims.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“A mule is a paid operative that is hired, in our case, by a left-wing organization, to deliver fraudulent and illegal votes to a mail-in drop box. So, that’s what a mule is,” D’Souza said on &lt;em&gt;Newsweek&lt;/em&gt;’s podcast, “The Josh Hammer Show.” “The mule is a middleman. The mule doesn’t come up with ballots. The mule goes to a left-wing organization, is handed a satchel or a backpack filled with ballots and then they go kind of on a route from one drop box to another, to another.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;D’Souza continued, suggesting that operatives pick this strategy in order to avoid detection. Hammer made no effort to interrogate D’Souza during the conversation, allowing him to describe the plot of the book in detail. &lt;em&gt;Newsweek&lt;/em&gt; never offered an update to that podcast to address concerns over the legitimacy of D’Souza’s claims.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We found in five states, or actually in the urban areas of five states, more than 2,000 mules,” D’Souza concluded. “The actual number of mules is vastly greater.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Early warning signs from coup-plotter John Eastman&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div data-embed-button=&quot;media&quot; data-entity-id=&quot;35288&quot; data-entity-label=&quot;Media&quot; data-entity-type=&quot;file&quot; data-entity-uuid=&quot;a303e807-17f4-4eb9-a537-bf11a2de636e&quot; data-splc-media-url=&quot;&quot; data-view-mode=&quot;full&quot; class=&quot;align-right&quot;&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;file-35288&quot; class=&quot;file file-image file-image-jpeg&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;element-invisible&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/files/johneastman2e1cd3d-700pxjpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;content&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.splcenter.org/sites/default/files/john_eastman_2e1cd3d-700px.jpg&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; height=&quot;467&quot; alt=&quot;John Eastman&quot; title=&quot;John Eastman&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-field-file-caption field-type-text-long field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;field-item even &quot;&gt;Chapman University law professor John Eastman, next to U.S. President Donald Trump&#039;s personal lawyer Rudy Giuliani, gestures as he speaks while Trump supporters gather ahead of his speech to contest the certification by the U.S. Congress of the results of the 2020 U.S. presidential election in Washington, D.C., Jan. 6, 2021. (Photo via Reuters/Jim Bourg)&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hammer started working for &lt;em&gt;Newsweek&lt;/em&gt; in May 2020. In August 2020, &lt;em&gt;The New Republic&lt;/em&gt; labeled &lt;em&gt;Newsweek&lt;/em&gt; a &lt;a href=&quot;https://newrepublic.com/article/158968/newsweek-rise-zombie-magazine&quot;&gt; “zombie magazine”&lt;/a&gt; known for laundering “right-wing ideas and conspiracy theories.” &lt;em&gt;The New Republic&lt;/em&gt;’s criticism followed Hammer’s opinion section publishing a now-infamous op-ed by lawyer John Eastman. Eastman floated in his &lt;em&gt;Newsweek&lt;/em&gt; piece a legal argument for nullifying non-white, California-born Kamala Harris’s then-current vice presidential candidacy. Readers repeatedly called Eastman’s op-ed racist on social media and in comment sections. Employees of the publication complained internally, and Hammer, along with Cooper, applied multiple editors’ notes to Eastman’s post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Newsweek&lt;/em&gt;’s editorial notes did not detail the significant overlap between Hammer and Eastman at University of Chicago Law School and in prominent reactionary advocacy groups. (&lt;em&gt;Newsweek&lt;/em&gt; readers &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.documentcloud.org/documents/23118791-screen-shot-2022-10-04-at-93525-pm&quot;&gt; picked up on these connections&lt;/a&gt; in the comments.) Both the Federalist Society and the Claremont Institute feature the two men on their websites. Hammer described Eastman as “my friend” on his &lt;em&gt;Newsweek&lt;/em&gt;-branded podcast as recently as August. He has also referred to him as his friend &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.documentcloud.org/documents/22416370-screen-shot-2022-09-15-at-125856-pm&quot;&gt; on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;. He wrote about Eastman’s influence on him in a Q&amp;amp;A published on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://archive.ph/YGyM9#selection-543.0-547.370&quot;&gt; Claremont Institute’s website&lt;/a&gt;, depicting him as a mentor figure:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;I had heard of Claremont and the &lt;em&gt;Claremont Review of Books&lt;/em&gt; going back at least as far back as college, but I first started hearing of friends applying to the John Marshall Fellowship when I was in law school at the University of Chicago. Given (University of Chicago Law alum) John Eastman’s long-standing leadership of the John Marshall program, the ties between that particular fellowship and Chicago are of course quite deep.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shortly after Hammer and &lt;em&gt;Newsweek&lt;/em&gt; published Eastman’s op-ed, the lawyer pushed the Stop the Steal disinformation campaign and helped lay out a blueprint for Trump staging &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2021/10/02/us/politics/john-eastman-trump-memo.html&quot;&gt; a coup following his defeat in the election&lt;/a&gt;. Hammer has portrayed Eastman on his podcast as a victim of a corrupt FBI, which he claims targets Trump supporters unfairly. (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/national-security/2022/06/27/eastman-phone-seized-fbi-jan6/&quot;&gt;The FBI seized the embattled lawyer’s phone&lt;/a&gt; this June.) Eastman has also involved himself in other anti-democracy activism, including lobbying the Supreme Court to adopt &lt;a href=&quot;https://newrepublic.com/article/167285/independent-state-legislature-theory-elections&quot;&gt; “independent state legislator theory,”&lt;/a&gt; which would &lt;a href=&quot;https://newrepublic.com/article/167721/john-eastman-independent-state-legislature&quot;&gt; further advance gerrymandering&lt;/a&gt; and weaken U.S. elections.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hammer speaks cagily about the outcome of the 2020 election on his &lt;em&gt;Newsweek&lt;/em&gt; podcast. For example, he described the outcome of the 2020 election in Arizona as something “a lot of people had some very heated thoughts on, one way or the other.” Although that may be true of some people misled by a radical-right &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2022/04/trump-voters-big-lie-stolen-election/629572/&quot;&gt; disinformation campaign&lt;/a&gt;, Biden unequivocally won Arizona. Even a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.npr.org/2021/09/24/1040327483/the-controversial-election-review-in-arizona-confirms-bidens-win&quot;&gt; controversial and discredited&lt;/a&gt; GOP-led attempt to recount ballots in the state found Biden ahead of Trump, and even added votes onto his total lead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hammer called depictions of what happened on Jan. 6 as an attempted coup or insurrection to be “ludicrous” and “laughable, on its face,” during a 2022 episode of &lt;em&gt;Newsweek&lt;/em&gt;’s “The Debate” podcast focused on the attack’s anniversary. He compared the attack, which left five people dead, to the anti-tax, 18&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt;-century Whiskey Rebellion under George Washington, and suggested the majority of Trump supporters involved could be described as “peacefully rioting.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Fallout with ‘The Debate’&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Newsweek&lt;/em&gt; claimed in their statement about Hammer to Hatewatch that he “has embraced the mission of ‘The Debate.’” However, Hammer’s name no longer appears as a co-host of the podcast of that name. &lt;em&gt;Newsweek&lt;/em&gt; listed him as a co-host alongside veteran journalist Celeste Headlee as recently as the Jan. 6, 2021, episode in which he described pro-Trump Jan. 6 participants as “peacefully rioting.” Headlee continues to host “The Debate” alongside journalist Andrew Tallman.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One month earlier, podcast producers had to edit out a conversation between him and his co-host at the time, Celeste Headlee. Headlee is a veteran journalist who has anchored NPR programs including “All Things Considered” and “Weekend Edition.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Newsweek&lt;/em&gt;’s “The Debate” podcast featured two guests during its Dec. 3, 2021, episode: reactionary YouTube performer Dave Rubin and libertarian journalist Nick Gillespie. The episode ostensibly focused on the sustainability of our two-party political system in the U.S. Rubin quickly tilted the conversation to attack what he described as “woke” people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Headlee objected to Rubin using the slang word “woke” to generalize about people with whom he disagrees, noting the term’s origins in the Black community, and said, “I’m the only person of color here.” (Headlee’s family lineage is Black and Jewish.) Hammer interjected to endorse what he perceived to be the soundness in using the term, describing it as an “illiberal, leftist ideology.” In the unedited version, Rubin said, “You’re a woman of color, what color are you?” according to Headlee.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It kind of devolved from there,” Headlee said to Hatewatch. “Josh was upset. He felt that I had embarrassed him in front of his friends.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Headlee said Hammer did not apologize but instead expected an apology from her. Hatewatch reached out to Rubin through an email address belonging to his publicist, and on Sept. 15, he tweeted out a response to his followers criticizing SPLC as a “far-left hate group.” He also belittled Headlee, calling her “the girl” and added that “she looked white to me, and I honestly can’t remember what she said.” (Hammer &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.documentcloud.org/documents/22415389-screen-shot-2022-09-14-at-52608-pm&quot;&gt; responded&lt;/a&gt; by liking the tweet.) A day later, Rubin continued on Twitter, posting photos of Headlee, asking his followers to determine her race.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I’ve been a journalist for a very long time,” Headlee told Hatewatch of the incident on &lt;em&gt;Newsweek&lt;/em&gt;’s “The Debate” podcast. “It was a very uncomfortable position to be in. It was uncomfortable and it was … upsetting. It was an upsetting situation.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Newsweek&lt;/em&gt; did not respond to questions about Hammer’s interaction with Headlee. The publication gave him his solo podcast show a little less than two months later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Accusations of special treatment for Hammer&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hatewatch interviewed over two dozen current and former &lt;em&gt;Newsweek&lt;/em&gt; employees, most of whom intersected with Hammer, and the feedback they gave about him and his worldview was universally negative. Employees, the majority of whom declined to be named, citing conditions of &lt;em&gt;Newsweek&lt;/em&gt;’s contract, described the company’s managerial staff as giving Hammer preferential treatment and a kind of celebrity status, which they did not believe his resume or contribution warranted. One former &lt;em&gt;Newsweek&lt;/em&gt; reporter, Benjamin Fearnow, told Hatewatch by phone that Hammer made suggestions to him over the Slack messaging platform about how he should write his news articles, making recommendations to cite reactionary academics in a &lt;em&gt;Newsweek&lt;/em&gt; section over which he had no authority. &lt;em&gt;Newsweek&lt;/em&gt; did not answer a question about Fearnow’s claim.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The employees also said managers, such as editor Nancy Cooper and chief content officer Dayan Candappa, indulged Hammer’s involvement in radical-right politics, while striking a markedly different tone with other employees. Far from labeling itself as an activist organization, &lt;em&gt;Newsweek&lt;/em&gt; has warned writers in multiple meetings and on email chains about publicly supporting political causes, employees said. K. Thor Jensen, a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.documentcloud.org/documents/22277245-screen-shot-2022-09-08-at-15039-pm&quot;&gt; former &lt;em&gt;Newsweek&lt;/em&gt; employee&lt;/a&gt;, told Hatewatch that the publication’s editor Cooper fired him over his use of social media in February 2020. Jensen’s editor had recently started a conversation with him over violating a policy of advocating political support for left-leaning causes. Nicole Goodkind, now a reporter for CNN Business, recalled to Hatewatch a meeting in fall 2018, during the runup to midterm elections, wherein &lt;em&gt;Newsweek&lt;/em&gt;’s leadership warned employees against promoting political views online. Four other employees also recalled the meeting she described.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“&lt;em&gt;Newsweek&lt;/em&gt; has a firm policy of newsroom editors and [reporters] not donating to political campaigns. This does not apply to those in the opinions section,” LBG PR told Hatewatch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to the details previously mentioned about Hammer’s advocacy of Blake Masters, both in and out of &lt;em&gt;Newsweek&lt;/em&gt;, he has also repeatedly hyped him on Twitter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Huge congrats to [Blake Masters], a real political talent who is going to be a tremendous force for good as a U.S. Senator,” Hammer posted to Twitter on Aug. 3, after Masters won the GOP Primary in his state. “Let’s retire Mark Kelly,” he wrote of his Democratic opponent, the husband of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.indiewire.com/2022/03/gabby-giffords-wont-back-down-interview-mark-kelly-1234706619/&quot;&gt; assassination attempt survivor&lt;/a&gt; Gabby Giffords.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Poynter relationship and ‘journalism in a for-profit world’&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Journalism experts have raised concerns about &lt;em&gt;Newsweek&lt;/em&gt;’s business practices for years, dating back to before they formed a partnership with Poynter in April 2019. When &lt;em&gt;Newsweek&lt;/em&gt; formed the relationship with Poynter, &lt;em&gt;Columbia Journalism Review&lt;/em&gt; had already started work on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cjr.org/special_report/newsweek.php&quot;&gt; an investigative story&lt;/a&gt; called “Dropshipping Journalism,” which detailed how the company’s financial troubles harmed its quality of reporting and dealt a blow to the mental health of the employees delivering that reporting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hatewatch reached out to Poynter about &lt;em&gt;Newsweek&lt;/em&gt;’s opinion section on July 7, regarding Hammer’s connections to Blake Masters, and media business analyst Rick Edmonds responded. Edmonds said that while some publications with a clearly understood political slant, like &lt;em&gt;The Nation&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;The National Review&lt;/em&gt;, might tolerate involvement in a political campaign, &lt;em&gt;Newsweek&lt;/em&gt;’s treatment of Hammer’s political activism would be considered highly unorthodox.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“&lt;em&gt;Newsweek&lt;/em&gt;’s current owners are trading on its name, and it is not at all news that the company has gotten into financial trouble,” Edmonds said, regarding Hammer’s involvement in hard right causes and activism. “If the selling point is that this is &lt;em&gt;Newsweek&lt;/em&gt; like you remember &lt;em&gt;Newsweek&lt;/em&gt;, it’s especially deceptive.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Days later, &lt;em&gt;Newsweek&lt;/em&gt; introduced Hatewatch to Kelly McBride, a senior vice president and the chair of the Craig Newmark Center for Ethics and Leadership at Poynter. In 2018, McBride &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.poynter.org/newsletters/2018/what-we-do-with-money-from-the-koch-foundation/&quot;&gt; defended&lt;/a&gt; Poynter’s use of money donated from Koch Industries, owned by the reactionary billionaire Charles Koch, from criticism. In response to Edmonds’ comments, McBride told Hatewatch that analysts at Poynter were permitted to have differences of opinion. After Hatewatch relayed details about Hammer’s promotion of radical-right talking points and politicians, McBride said that she would look into some of the details published in this investigation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The advice I have given &lt;em&gt;Newsweek&lt;/em&gt; is with the understanding that they intend and aspire to be a credible national news source and that they want to use their name and their brand for good,” McBride said of Hammer on July 12. “I’m going to call them up and get some more details on this.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div data-embed-button=&quot;media&quot; data-entity-id=&quot;35291&quot; data-entity-label=&quot;Media&quot; data-entity-type=&quot;file&quot; data-entity-uuid=&quot;6a21ee55-0cc2-46eb-95fb-60cff813ce53&quot; data-splc-media-url=&quot;&quot; data-view-mode=&quot;full&quot; class=&quot;align-left&quot;&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;file-35291&quot; class=&quot;file file-image file-image-png&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;element-invisible&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/files/joshhammertweetgovrondesantis-700pxpng&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;content&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.splcenter.org/sites/default/files/josh_hammer_tweet_govrondesantis-700px.png&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; height=&quot;726&quot; alt=&quot;Hammer and DeSantis&quot; title=&quot;Hammer and DeSantis&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-field-file-caption field-type-text-long field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;field-item even &quot;&gt;Josh Hammer (left) and Florida Gov. Ron DeSantis pose in January. (Photo via Twitter)&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hatewatch followed up with McBride two months later, on Sept. 12, after Hammer brought the neo-Nazi collaborator and disinformation specialist Posobiec onto his podcast and ranted about going “to battle in this roiling, cold civil war against our domestic foes,” referring to other Americans with whom he shared political disagreements. Hatewatch asked McBride about her discussions with &lt;em&gt;Newsweek&lt;/em&gt; and whether she found it ethical for Hammer to ask &lt;em&gt;Newsweek&lt;/em&gt;’s audience in Arizona directly to vote for Blake Masters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“So … they haven’t asked me to look at that,” McBride said. “I can say generically, and if you use this, make sure you use this in the proper context of ‘generically,’ we work with a lot of clients who engage in a lot of practices that are outside the work of our consultancy. And, you know, that is … that is journalism, you know, in a for-profit world.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hatewatch asked McBride if Poynter would take money from Gateway Pundit, the notorious website that publishes hard-right disinformation, including lies about the 2020 election and stories that &lt;a href=&quot;https://archive.ph/otZZt&quot;&gt;recycle propaganda&lt;/a&gt; from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.splcenter.org/fighting-hate/extremist-files/group/proud-boys&quot;&gt;Proud Boys&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Gateway Pundit has never called and asked for help, but we would take the phone call,” McBride said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hatewatch asked if Poynter would then take money from Gateway Pundit after taking a phone call of this nature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“If they wanted to get better on ethics, yeah,” McBride said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hatewatch reached out to other experts in journalism for context about Hammer’s employment and political activity. Few agreed to comment on the record and no one spoke favorably of Hammer. Some responded by simply dismissing the credibility of &lt;em&gt;Newsweek&lt;/em&gt; outright. New York University journalism instructor Jay Rosen referred Hatewatch to a tweet he issued in response to a &lt;em&gt;Newsweek&lt;/em&gt; opinion piece authored by Donald Trump Jr. with the headline, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.documentcloud.org/documents/22924766-screen-shot-2022-09-25-at-50138-pm&quot;&gt; “Trump was right about everything,”&lt;/a&gt; from March 16.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“&lt;em&gt;Newsweek&lt;/em&gt; is not a thing. It’s like an animal that lives in the discarded shell of another animal,” &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.documentcloud.org/documents/22924768-screen-shot-2022-09-25-at-64156-pm&quot;&gt; Rosen wrote&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt; Megan Squire contributed to this reporting.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Editor&#039;s note: This story has been updated to include comment from Michael Knowles, who posted his response on Twitter following initial publication. He also said on Twitter that he sent his reply in September, but Hatewatch found no record of the email.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The author, Michael Edison Hayden, worked for &lt;/em&gt; Newsweek &lt;em&gt; from September 2017 to May 2018, covering far-right extremism as a beat from the publication’s politics desk. He also appeared as a source in the &lt;/em&gt; Columbia Journalism Review&lt;em&gt; feature about &lt;/em&gt;Newsweek&lt;em&gt;, &lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cjr.org/special_report/newsweek.php&quot;&gt; &lt;em&gt;“Dropshipping Journalism.”&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Hayden reported for &lt;/em&gt; Newsweek &lt;em&gt; on some of the radical right figures mentioned in this story, including &lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.splcenter.org/fighting-hate/extremist-files/individual/jack-posobiec&quot;&gt; &lt;em&gt;the extremist Jack Posobiec&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; on multiple occasions&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Photo illustration by SPLC&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-field-person field-type-entityreference field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;
                &lt;div class=&quot;field-item even &quot;&gt;&lt;article id=&quot;node-15258&quot; class=&quot;node node-person node-teaser node-odd&quot;&gt;

  
  &lt;div class=&quot;content&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;group-text-field-group&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-title-field field-type-text field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;
                &lt;div class=&quot;field-item even &quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/about/staff/michael-edison-hayden&quot;&gt;Michael Edison Hayden&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;  &lt;/div&gt; &lt;!-- /content --&gt;

  
      &lt;div class=&quot;links&quot;&gt;
          &lt;/div&gt; &lt;!-- /links --&gt;
  
  &lt;/article&gt; &lt;!-- /article #node --&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-field-addthis field-type-addthis field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;
                &lt;div class=&quot;field-item even &quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;addthis_toolbox addthis_default_style  &quot; addthis:title=&quot;Newsweek Embraces the Anti-Democracy Hard Right - Southern Poverty Law Center&quot; addthis:url=&quot;https://www.splcenter.org/hatewatch/2022/11/04/newsweek-embraces-anti-democracy-hard-right&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot; &quot; class=&quot;addthis_button_facebook&quot; aria-label=&quot;Facebook: Share this page&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot; &quot; class=&quot;addthis_button_twitter&quot; aria-label=&quot;Twitter: Share this page&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-field-publish-date field-type-date field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;
                &lt;div class=&quot;field-item even &quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;date-display-single&quot;&gt;November 04, 2022&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
 <pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2022 18:25:07 +0000</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>chris.heller_1541</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">17203 at https://www.splcenter.org</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>‘Traveling While Black’: Virtual reality exhibit at Civil Rights Memorial Center will immerse audiences in Black experience on the road</title>
 <link>https://www.splcenter.org/news/2022/10/28/traveling-while-black-virtual-reality-civil-rights-memorial-center-black-experience</link>
 <description>&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-field-story-type field-type-list-text field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;
                &lt;div class=&quot;field-item even &quot;&gt;Features and Stories&lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-field-image field-type-image field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;
                &lt;div class=&quot;field-item even &quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-title-field field-type-text field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;
                &lt;div class=&quot;field-item even &quot;&gt;&lt;h1&gt;‘Traveling While Black’: Virtual reality exhibit at Civil Rights Memorial Center will immerse audiences in Black experience on the road&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-body field-type-text-with-summary field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;
                &lt;div class=&quot;field-item even &quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;As a young boy, Roger Ross Williams would travel with his mother, a single woman who worked as a house cleaner in a small Pennsylvania town, to visit relatives on their farm in Charleston, South Carolina.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We would pack everything into the car, and we did it in one shot. We never stopped. I never understood why,” Williams, who grew up to be an Academy Award-winning movie director, recalled in an interview released by his film production company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an adult, Williams said, he realized why his mom drove 12 hours without a break: “It’s just the reality of being Black in America.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;• &lt;strong&gt;CRMC Event:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;/conversation-efren-c-olivares-crmc&quot;&gt;A conversation with SPLC’s Efren Olivares&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That reality is the subject of a bold, genre-bending 3D film experience directed by Williams that will be shown at the Southern Poverty Law Center’s &lt;a href=&quot;/civil-rights-memorial&quot;&gt;Civil Rights Memorial Center&lt;/a&gt; in Montgomery, Alabama, starting Nov. 1 and running until Jan. 22, 2023. The project, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.imdb.com/title/tt10254868/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;“Traveling While Black,”&lt;/a&gt; uses high-concept documentary and virtual reality technology to immerse participants into the terrifying world of the United States during legal segregation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stepping into an exhibit space set up as a replica of the iconic, Black-owned restaurant Ben’s Chili Bowl in Washington, D.C., viewers will don Oculus Go headsets and, for 18 minutes, join conversations with patrons depicted through virtual reality technology who share their intimate experiences of traveling and living in the U.S. when a simple bathroom stop could be life-threatening. The virtual reality project portrays the era Williams, now 60, was born into in 1962, when the set of laws and customs known as Jim Crow were omnipresent across the American South, and when Black people faced persistent racial prejudice, price-gouging and physical violence while traveling throughout the U.S.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div data-embed-button=&quot;media&quot; data-entity-id=&quot;35278&quot; data-entity-label=&quot;Media&quot; data-entity-type=&quot;file&quot; data-entity-uuid=&quot;d11d5c29-45d6-4f49-99c5-963122a1b76d&quot; data-splc-media-url=&quot;&quot; data-view-mode=&quot;teaser&quot;&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;file-35278&quot; class=&quot;file file-image file-image-jpeg&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;element-invisible&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/files/webtraveling-while-black-inline1jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;content&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.splcenter.org/sites/default/files/web_traveling-while-black-inline1.jpg&quot; width=&quot;1044&quot; height=&quot;587&quot; alt=&quot;Negro Motorist Green Book&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-field-file-caption field-type-text-long field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;field-item even &quot;&gt;The Negro Motorist Green Book, the brainchild of postal carrier Victor Hugo Green, was published for 30 years, beginning in 1936. (Courtesy of “Traveling While Black”)&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With Black travelers aware they went on the road at their peril, a guide published from 1936 to 1966 became their lifeline to finding establishments, like Ben’s Chili Bowl, where they would be welcomed rather than threatened or turned away. The guide, &lt;a href=&quot;https://negromotoristgreenbook.si.edu/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Negro Motorist Green Book,&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; was the brainchild of a Harlem, New York-based postal carrier, Victor Hugo Green, who had grown weary of the discrimination Black people faced when they left their neighborhoods. It provided a list of hotels, boarding houses, taverns, restaurants, service stations and other establishments throughout the country that served Black patrons. Traveling while Black required ingenuity and courage, and establishments like Ben’s – with its famous half-smokes, chili dogs and milkshakes, and its role at the heart of the vibrant area known as “Black Broadway” – were safe spaces, respites from the reality of white supremacy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Traveling While Black,” though, is explicitly designed to be more than history. It illuminates the story of segregation through personal stories, employing a collection of interviews and cinematic re-creations. The film weaves significant civil rights milestones into the experience and is designed to give participants not only a deeper historical understanding of the past, but a recognition of the depressingly enduring dangers of being Black in the United States today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“There was a time when travel for Black people was a matter of life and death,” Williams wrote in a director’s statement that accompanies the project. “So, for me, the project started as a way to talk about this forgotten period in history. But the more I began to think about the past, I realized that not a lot has changed today … the risk we face just leaving our homes and our need for safe spaces are just as prevalent as they were during the days of the &lt;em&gt;Green Book&lt;/em&gt;.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div data-embed-button=&quot;media&quot; data-entity-id=&quot;35279&quot; data-entity-label=&quot;Media&quot; data-entity-type=&quot;file&quot; data-entity-uuid=&quot;5db66c62-7322-4dce-af12-ab4fa4dae23c&quot; data-splc-media-url=&quot;&quot; data-view-mode=&quot;teaser&quot; class=&quot;align-right&quot;&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;file-35279&quot; class=&quot;file file-image file-image-jpeg&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;element-invisible&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/files/webtraveling-while-black-inline2jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;content&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.splcenter.org/sites/default/files/web_traveling-while-black-inline2.jpg&quot; width=&quot;1008&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; alt=&quot;Traveling While Black exhibit flyer&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-field-file-caption field-type-text-long field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;field-item even &quot;&gt;The “Traveling While Black” virtual reality experience will open Nov. 1 at the SPLC’s Civil Rights Memorial Center in Montgomery, Alabama. (Courtesy of “Traveling While Black”)&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Sparking conversations&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tafeni English, director of the Civil Rights Memorial Center, said that in a nation where inequality between white and Black Americans persists in almost every aspect of society and the economy, the exhibit has deep relevance and poignancy. Two years ago, the streets of American cities and towns erupted in protests after the &lt;a href=&quot;/news/2021/05/28/his-last-breath-year-after-george-floyds-murder-nation-reckons-history-racism-police&quot;&gt;murder of George Floyd&lt;/a&gt; by a Minneapolis police officer cast attention on the abiding dangers Black Americans face. Showing the documentary project in Montgomery, site of the first large-scale U.S. demonstration against segregation – the &lt;a href=&quot;/news/2020/12/04/journey-justice-celebrating-65th-anniversary-montgomery-bus-boycott-sparked-civil-rights&quot;&gt;Montgomery Bus Boycott&lt;/a&gt; of 1955 and 1956 – gives the project a unique power to “spark conversations around issues of race,” English said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;English said the decision to install the “Traveling While Black” exhibit at the Civil Rights Memorial Center is part of a larger mission by the SPLC to delve deep into the roots and continuing dangers of systemic racism. During the pandemic, for example, the SPLC published &lt;a href=&quot;/news/2021/04/02/movement-and-space-civil-rights-memorial-center-releases-new-community-guide-help-fight&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Movement and Space: CRMC Community Guide&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, a public education resource that explores the current and historic constraints on Black people’s right to move freely and occupy space. Like Williams’ virtual reality documentary, the guide is designed to encourage community groups, museum educators, high school students and others to facilitate difficult conversations about race.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The ‘Traveling While Black’ exhibit also may in some cases change the perspective of others when they experience the treatment of others during those times,” English said. “We’re interested in being a part of the solution as it relates to the issue of race, and that begins with having honest and hard conversations with each other.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The exhibit, English said, “will not only provide insight to what it was like for Black people to travel in the 1950s and 1960s but will draw parallels to things we’re seeing happen in our country today. We hope people will walk away further inspired to take an active role in dismantling racist systems.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;‘Lived experience’&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That is exactly what happened when the exhibit, which is traveling around the country, was shown at Georgia Tech Arts, at the Georgia Institute of Technology in Atlanta last year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During its three-month run, the exhibit drew a broad range of people, said Aaron Shackelford, director of Georgia Tech Arts. Alumni shared stories with staff. Students who had grown up only tangentially aware of the history of segregation sat rapt, transported to a world they had never experienced before. Community members joined conversations with academics, and importantly at a leading technology institution, young people studying computer design, engineering and other disciplines were exposed to a vivid example of how their particular set of skills could be used for art and for good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“‘Traveling While Black’ was a test case for us to show our students that this is what we mean when we say that the technology they are working on has a storytelling impact that can really affect lives,” Shackelford said. “The technology of virtual reality creates the best version of oral history that I have ever seen. It allows you to sit across the table from someone. And since you are sitting there, you have to hear what they have to say. You have to engage with them in a much more powerful way than you would with any other medium.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div data-embed-button=&quot;media&quot; data-entity-id=&quot;35280&quot; data-entity-label=&quot;Media&quot; data-entity-type=&quot;file&quot; data-entity-uuid=&quot;130c85c8-c8e4-4351-8873-efe72872154b&quot; data-splc-media-url=&quot;&quot; data-view-mode=&quot;teaser&quot;&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;file-35280&quot; class=&quot;file file-image file-image-jpeg&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;element-invisible&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/files/webtraveling-while-black-inline3jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;content&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.splcenter.org/sites/default/files/web_traveling-while-black-inline3.jpg&quot; width=&quot;1044&quot; height=&quot;587&quot; alt=&quot;Traveling While Black exhibit&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-field-file-caption field-type-text-long field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;field-item even &quot;&gt;Ben’s Chili Bowl, a Washington, D.C., restaurant, figures prominently in the “Traveling While Black” exhibit, which uses virtual reality technology to immerse visitors in the Jim Crow era of the U.S. (Courtesy of “Traveling While Black”)&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The proof of that engagement at Georgia Tech became, during the run of the exhibit, a wall display just outside for all to see. In a lounge area, Shackelford set up comfortable seating where visitors could write their responses and post them on a corkboard strip on the wall. Collected by the curators later and made into a short film, the responses remain poignant reminders of the exhibit’s power:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Every human should watch this film,” one visitor wrote.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I feel humbled and determined to contribute whatever I can to improve the human condition,” wrote another.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I feel sad we still have to travel while Black,” wrote a third. “I hope this exhibit shifts the culture.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I knew that Black people were far from being safe in America, but I didn’t know the true extent,” another response card reads. “I feel frustrated and sad that we are still talking about the same problems.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And another one admonished, “Awareness does not stop in this room.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The message of the exhibit, Shackelford said, is one that Black people in this country do not have the luxury of forgetting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“This really isn’t history, it is lived experience,” Shackelford said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Photo at top: The “Traveling While Black” exhibit space replicates Ben’s Chili Bowl, a Washington, D.C., restaurant that was a safe space for Black travelers during segregation in the U.S. (Courtesy of “Traveling While Black”)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-field-byline field-type-text field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;
                &lt;div class=&quot;field-item even &quot;&gt;Esther Schrader&lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-field-addthis field-type-addthis field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;
                &lt;div class=&quot;field-item even &quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;addthis_toolbox addthis_default_style  &quot; addthis:title=&quot;&amp;amp;lsquo;Traveling While Black&amp;amp;rsquo;: Virtual reality exhibit at Civil Rights Memorial Center will immerse audiences in Black experience on the road - Southern Poverty Law Center&quot; addthis:url=&quot;https://www.splcenter.org/news/2022/10/28/traveling-while-black-virtual-reality-civil-rights-memorial-center-black-experience&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot; &quot; class=&quot;addthis_button_facebook&quot; aria-label=&quot;Facebook: Share this page&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot; &quot; class=&quot;addthis_button_twitter&quot; aria-label=&quot;Twitter: Share this page&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-field-publish-date field-type-date field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;
                &lt;div class=&quot;field-item even &quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;date-display-single&quot;&gt;October 28, 2022&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
 <pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2022 20:56:21 +0000</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>sam.alefsen_2664</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">17202 at https://www.splcenter.org</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>Protesters Maced at Canceled Far-right ‘Comedy’ Event at Penn State</title>
 <link>https://www.splcenter.org/hatewatch/2022/10/25/protesters-maced-canceled-far-right-comedy-event-penn-state</link>
 <description>&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-field-story-type field-type-list-text field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;
                &lt;div class=&quot;field-item even &quot;&gt;Hatewatch&lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-field-long-text field-type-text-long field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;
                &lt;div class=&quot;field-item even &quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Right-wing agitators allegedly sprayed protesters with mace at a far-right “comedy” event on Penn State’s campus in State College, Pennsylvania, on Monday night.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-field-image field-type-image field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;
                &lt;div class=&quot;field-item even &quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-title-field field-type-text field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;
                &lt;div class=&quot;field-item even &quot;&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Protesters Maced at Canceled Far-right ‘Comedy’ Event at Penn State&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-body field-type-text-with-summary field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;
                &lt;div class=&quot;field-item even &quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Amid escalating tensions on Monday evening, Penn State canceled the event, which featured Gavin McInnes, founder of hate group the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.splcenter.org/fighting-hate/extremist-files/group/proud-boys&quot;&gt; Proud Boys&lt;/a&gt;, and right-wing YouTube performer Alex Stein. Until then, the university had ignored protesters and experts who warned that the gathering would attract violence to the campus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div data-embed-button=&quot;media&quot; data-entity-id=&quot;35273&quot; data-entity-label=&quot;Media&quot; data-entity-type=&quot;file&quot; data-entity-uuid=&quot;f6d527b3-25c6-44c8-b1bb-3b0e7ace0c07&quot; data-splc-media-url=&quot;&quot; data-view-mode=&quot;full&quot; class=&quot;align-right&quot;&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;file-35273&quot; class=&quot;file file-image file-image-jpeg&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;element-invisible&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/files/pennstateviolence2reuters-700pxjpg-0&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;content&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.splcenter.org/sites/default/files/penn_state_violence_2_reuters-700px_0.jpg&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; height=&quot;490&quot; alt=&quot;Penn State violence&quot; title=&quot;Penn State violence&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-field-file-caption field-type-text-long field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;field-item even &quot;&gt;An unidentified person wields a can of bear mace Monday before using it on protesters ahead of a scheduled event featuring Proud Boys founder Gavin McInnes at Penn State University in State College, Pennsylvania. The event was canceled by Penn State officials &quot;due to the threat of escalating violence.&quot; (Photo via Reuters/Leah Millis)&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The group that hosted the event, meanwhile – which has connections to a broad network of far-right activists and groups – is advertising further events at other universities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A participant in the rally (whose name is being withheld over personal safety concerns) told Hatewatch that the mood among 200 or so protesters on campus had been defiant but upbeat until the event was escalated in two ways by campus police.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At one point, the protester said, a number of mounted police moved to a small area on one side of the venue, in close proximity to one group of protesters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“That escalated things. People started yelling, ‘Fuck you!’ at the cops,” he told Hatewatch in a telephone conversation, “and some of them started saying, ‘Fuck you!’ back.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Video of the event &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/StreamerWayward/status/1584816255885664256&quot;&gt; posted on social media&lt;/a&gt; appears to confirm this account of police entering into a contentious interaction with protesters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soon afterwards, he said, police allowed Alex Stein – one of the scheduled speakers – to mingle with the crowd at some distance from law enforcement, provoking them as he often does to generate outrage content for his YouTube channel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Very obviously, [Stein] was trying to get in people’s faces to get content,” the protester said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Daryle Lamont Jenkins, who reported on the event for independent antifascist news website &lt;a href=&quot;http://idavox.com/index.php/2022/10/25/fash-started-it-and-penn-state-ended-it-gavin-mcinnes-campus-event-shut-down/&quot;&gt; Idavox&lt;/a&gt;, confirmed that Stein attempted to “&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/IdavoxOPP/status/1584719838567878656?s=20&amp;amp;t=HoACC8JYunnNmLLXv43fug&quot;&gt;troll&lt;/a&gt;” the crowd.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He told Hatewatch in a telephone conversation that until that point, the focus had been on “maintaining a vigil,” but “the mood changed when Alex Stein started provoking people.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“He shouldn’t have been allowed to do that,” Jenkins added.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The police weren’t standing close enough to intervene had someone thrown a punch,” Jenkins said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“To the credit of protesters, almost no one took the bait,” Jenkins said. “Stein was &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/IdavoxOPP/status/1584883948483936256?s=20&amp;amp;t=HoACC8JYunnNmLLXv43fug&quot;&gt; visibly frustrated&lt;/a&gt; that people were not being more aggressive in their responses to him.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soon after, according to Jenkins, a number of Proud Boys emerged into the crowd and began interacting aggressively with protesters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally in an incident captured on &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/FordFischer/status/1584904927234719745?s=20&amp;amp;t=A-9-yqHZWM5Q3anTOVofkA&quot;&gt; multiple videos&lt;/a&gt; posted to social media, a protester on the far-right side – clad in body armor and facial protection gear that obscured his identity – released pepper spray into the crowd without provocation, disabling nearby students and reporters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soon after, Penn State canceled the event and issued a statement that appeared to blame student protesters for violence, without citing evidence. The statement condemned &quot;polarization&quot; rather than far-right violence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The statement defended Penn State’s actions while offering an idiosyncratic theory of protest, stating, “We have encouraged peaceful protest, and, while protest is an acceptable means of expression, it becomes unacceptable when it obstructs the basic exchange of ideas.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Such obstruction is a form of censorship, no matter who initiates it or for what reasons,” the statement added.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Neither that statement, nor a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.psu.edu/news/campus-life/story/message-president-neeli-bendapudi-cancellation-campus-event/&quot;&gt; follow-up&lt;/a&gt; signed by Penn State president Neeli Bendapudi, acknowledged that student protesters had been pepper-sprayed by far-right activists, with Bendapudi claiming that it was “unclear which individuals onsite then resorted to ... using pepper spray.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hatewatch contacted Penn State’s strategic communication office for comment on the actions of police and the outcome of the event, but there was no immediate response.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, Uncensored America (UA), which hosted the event, is still advertising future events and promoting its chapters at Penn State, the University of Tennessee, Knoxville, and the University of Wisconsin-Madison. All the group’s past and future events platform far-right speakers, sometimes in “debates” with other social media performers who style themselves as liberals or centrists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As Hatewatch &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.splcenter.org/hatewatch/2022/10/20/far-right-student-organization-brings-extremists-mcinnes-doyle-penn-state-and-tennessee&quot;&gt; previously reported&lt;/a&gt;, the group was founded by Sean Semanko, whose membership in the pro-Trump student group the Bull Moose Party links him with a network of far-right actors that includes the principals of white nationalist publishing house &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.splcenter.org/hatewatch/2022/06/13/white-nationalist-book-publishers-revealed&quot;&gt; Antelope Hill&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In September, the event was approved for funding by Penn State’s University Park Allocation Committee (UPAC), which allocates a proportion of student fees to registered student organizations for on-campus events.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UPAC records show that funding included $6,500 total in honoraria for McInnes and Stein, and over $1,000 for their airfares, according to UPAC meeting records.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Penn State’s decision to host the event, Jenkins, the journalist, said that alongside the threat to public safety, these payments from student fees were the main concerns of protesters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the administration’s decision to try to hold the event, Jenkins said: “Free speech is not a suicide pact. You knew this was coming.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-field-byline field-type-text field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;
                &lt;div class=&quot;field-item even &quot;&gt;Jason Wilson&lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-field-addthis field-type-addthis field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;
                &lt;div class=&quot;field-item even &quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;addthis_toolbox addthis_default_style  &quot; addthis:title=&quot;Protesters Maced at Canceled Far-right &amp;amp;lsquo;Comedy&amp;amp;rsquo; Event at Penn State - Southern Poverty Law Center&quot; addthis:url=&quot;https://www.splcenter.org/hatewatch/2022/10/25/protesters-maced-canceled-far-right-comedy-event-penn-state&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot; &quot; class=&quot;addthis_button_facebook&quot; aria-label=&quot;Facebook: Share this page&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot; &quot; class=&quot;addthis_button_twitter&quot; aria-label=&quot;Twitter: Share this page&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-field-publish-date field-type-date field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;
                &lt;div class=&quot;field-item even &quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;date-display-single&quot;&gt;October 25, 2022&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
 <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 21:08:25 +0000</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>chris.heller_1541</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">17199 at https://www.splcenter.org</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>50 Forward: An evening with the SPLC looks ahead to the next half century</title>
 <link>https://www.splcenter.org/news/2022/10/21/50-forward-evening-splc-looks-ahead-next-half-century</link>
 <description>&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-field-story-type field-type-list-text field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;
                &lt;div class=&quot;field-item even &quot;&gt;Features and Stories&lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-field-image field-type-image field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;
                &lt;div class=&quot;field-item even &quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-title-field field-type-text field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;
                &lt;div class=&quot;field-item even &quot;&gt;&lt;h1&gt;50 Forward: An evening with the SPLC looks ahead to the next half century&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-body field-type-text-with-summary field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;
                &lt;div class=&quot;field-item even &quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Southern Poverty Law Center commemorated its &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.splcenter.org/50-forward-live&quot;&gt;51&lt;sup&gt;st&lt;/sup&gt; anniversary tonight&lt;/a&gt; at a celebration that recalled its singular, historic achievements as one of the country’s most prominent civil rights organizations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div data-embed-button=&quot;media&quot; data-entity-id=&quot;35264&quot; data-entity-label=&quot;Media&quot; data-entity-type=&quot;file&quot; data-entity-uuid=&quot;e7ace6a2-a3fd-4055-9504-3b28a93ff46a&quot; data-splc-media-url=&quot;&quot; data-view-mode=&quot;full&quot; class=&quot;align-right&quot;&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;file-35264&quot; class=&quot;file file-image file-image-jpeg&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;element-invisible&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/files/web50forwardinline1jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;content&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.splcenter.org/sites/default/files/web_50forward_inline1.jpg&quot; width=&quot;1200&quot; height=&quot;900&quot; alt=&quot;Event crowd&quot; title=&quot;splc-50-forward&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-field-file-caption field-type-text-long field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;field-item even &quot;&gt;50 Forward attendees included Lecia Brooks, Karol V. Mason, Joseph J. Levin Jr., Tafeni English and Seth Levi. (Credit: Mhandy Gerard/SPLC)&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SPLC President and CEO Margaret Huang laid out the vision for the organization’s next 50 years by sharing the SPLC’s new vision for racial justice in the South. This vision recognizes that activists and freedom fighters in the South have demonstrated courage and resilience, and we will continue to support the movement for justice despite the challenges we face today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The event, &lt;em&gt;50 Forward: An Evening with the SPLC&lt;/em&gt;, held at Atlanta’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://novareevents.com/foundry-at-puritan-mill/&quot;&gt;Foundry at Puritan Mill&lt;/a&gt;, brought SPLC senior leaders together with the organization’s partners, including &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.splcenter.org/vote-your-voice&quot;&gt;Vote Your Voice&lt;/a&gt; grant recipients, community allies and SPLC supporters. Members of the audience included Georgia state representatives David Wilkerson and William Boddie, whom Huang recognized from the podium.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Karol V. Mason, the SPLC board vice chair, said at the beginning of the event, “The name of tonight’s event is 50 Forward, and a major purpose of our gathering is to learn about the course that the SPLC will be charting into the future. I know how proud the SPLC community is of the numerous victories achieved during the organization’s first 50 years. But I also know that so much work remains to be done — and that we will not be satisfied until our ‘vision for a just future’ becomes a reality.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The SPLC, Huang said, will focus on key issues including fighting hate and extremism, promoting democracy and civil rights, and pursuing legal, immigrant and economic justice on behalf of Black and Brown communities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To highlight the work of these partners and give the audience an understanding of how the SPLC collaborates with them, during panel discussions partner representatives discussed efforts to promote democracy and counter the effects of hate and extremism on immigration policy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Our overarching vision is to have a significant impact on the issues affecting the communities we seek to serve in our Southern states,” Huang said. “We will never accomplish this work alone – it will take the entire movement working together.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Investing in communities&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In its largest, most direct community investment, the SPLC will move its metro Atlanta office to a historically Black community. While the location of a newly constructed office building has not yet been determined, it will have spaces and programming for the benefit of the area residents, activists and allies, according to SPLC Chief Strategy Officer Seth Levi, who discussed the move in a separate conversation before tonight’s event.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We’re trying to rethink how we use our office spaces, exploring how they can be a tool to achieve our strategic framework,” Levi said. “An office building can be so much more than a place where staff come in to work at their computers and meet in conference rooms. We’re trying to imagine all of the ways in which our property spaces can be used to directly impact the communities we serve.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The building may also include commercial spaces designed to help create jobs and build wealth, such as discounted retail rental space for Black and Brown entrepreneurs in their first years in business, when receipts are typically low. The SPLC is also exploring ways to make a local investment in affordable housing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Huang explained how the redevelopment aligns with the SPLC’s new strategic framework.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We view these investments in communities as opportunities that will make economic improvement in people’s lives. … We think it’s time to start using our resources and our capacity to do that,” she said in another conversation before tonight’s event.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The SPLC’s direction for the future will be visible in another way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Rebranding the SPLC&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div data-embed-button=&quot;media&quot; data-entity-id=&quot;35265&quot; data-entity-label=&quot;Media&quot; data-entity-type=&quot;file&quot; data-entity-uuid=&quot;02b38f41-7c62-4267-b2b6-afa44c36ae23&quot; data-splc-media-url=&quot;&quot; data-view-mode=&quot;full&quot; class=&quot;align-right&quot;&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;file-35265&quot; class=&quot;file file-image file-image-jpeg&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;element-invisible&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/files/splcrebrandpostersjpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;content&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.splcenter.org/sites/default/files/splc_rebrand_posters.jpg&quot; width=&quot;3375&quot; height=&quot;2250&quot; alt=&quot;SPLC brand&quot; title=&quot;splc-brand&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-field-file-caption field-type-text-long field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;field-item even &quot;&gt;During the 50 Forward event, SPLC President and CEO Margaret Huang unveiled the organization&#039;s new logo.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At tonight’s event, Huang introduced the SPLC’s rebranding and logo, which will become the new symbol of the SPLC’s vision of a more inclusive, holistic organization and a reflection of the multifaceted nature of its work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The individual SPLC letters of the logo &lt;em&gt;are&lt;/em&gt; the logo and were designed to evoke both historic and modern sensibilities. The letters are punctuated with a vertically centered dot, known as an interpunct. The new design also was driven in part by the emergence of the New South, which has seen growing diversification, and now has the &lt;a href=&quot;https://williamsinstitute.law.ucla.edu/lgbtdivide/#/ethnicity&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;highest LGBTQ+ population&lt;/a&gt; in the country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The full set of rebranding imagery will appear anywhere that the SPLC logo appears: on the forthcoming new SPLC website, stationery, in email signature lines, on social media, business cards, branded T-shirts, tote bags, posters, stickers and Learning for Justice materials.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The challenges of the future and the triumphs and struggles of the past are also reflected at the SPLC’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.splcenter.org/civil-rights-memorial&quot;&gt;Civil Rights Memorial Center&lt;/a&gt; (CRMC), which announced how it plans to further its mission of educating and connecting communities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Connecting through technology&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div data-embed-button=&quot;media&quot; data-entity-id=&quot;35261&quot; data-entity-label=&quot;Media&quot; data-entity-type=&quot;file&quot; data-entity-uuid=&quot;a4a08630-5f39-40f9-afcc-44e03778d37b&quot; data-splc-media-url=&quot;&quot; data-view-mode=&quot;full&quot; class=&quot;align-right&quot;&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;file-35261&quot; class=&quot;file file-image file-image-jpeg&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;element-invisible&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/files/webcrmc-appinline-promo1044jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;content&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.splcenter.org/sites/default/files/web_crmc-app_inline-promo_1044.jpg&quot; width=&quot;1044&quot; height=&quot;773&quot; alt=&quot;CRMC app on mobile devices&quot; title=&quot;crmc-app-display&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-field-file-caption field-type-text-long field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;field-item even &quot;&gt;During the SPLC&#039;s 50 Forward event, the Civil Rights Memorial Center unveiled its new mobile app, which will feature virtual tours of the Center and a condensed version of the film Apathy Is Not an Option.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The CRMC has launched a mobile phone app, which CRMC Director Tafeni English introduced to the audience tonight. The app will enable students and others who cannot visit the CRMC in person to tour galleries virtually and learn about the modern civil rights movement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Imploring audience members to pull out their phones at tonight’s event, English said, “You can download the Civil Rights Memorial Center app, and we don’t want you to just download it and keep it to yourself. We want you to share it. Share it with your family. Share it with educators. Share it with activists. … Whether they’re doing it virtually or in person, we hope to impart this message into each of our visitors: We are still marching, and we still have a long way to go.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The CRMC, a project of the SPLC, is a cultural institution for racial justice and is now the first museum in Montgomery to employ an app. English first conceived of adding the app to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.splcenter.org/what-we-do/civil-rights-memorial/experience&quot;&gt;museum’s experience&lt;/a&gt; before the COVID-19 pandemic struck, but the idea gained steam in 2020 when museums, including the CRMC, closed and struggled to stay relevant when programming became virtual.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The app increases our visibility [in areas] where we know the pandemic has impacted schools’ ability to take field trips,” English said. “We aren’t seeing as many visitors as before the pandemic. Those who engage with the app will have the opportunity to learn about the SPLC’s current work.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The app can be downloaded free from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://apps.apple.com/us/app/civil-rights-memorial-center/id1644410341&quot;&gt;Apple Store&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.mytoursapp.android.app6113&quot;&gt;Google Play&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The announcement of the app wasn’t the only instance of recognizing the importance of the past and its impact on the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Looking back and ahead&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div data-embed-button=&quot;media&quot; data-entity-id=&quot;35262&quot; data-entity-label=&quot;Media&quot; data-entity-type=&quot;file&quot; data-entity-uuid=&quot;92cbf6df-2da9-4e74-8574-18bb7b4c4879&quot; data-splc-media-url=&quot;&quot; data-view-mode=&quot;full&quot; class=&quot;align-right&quot;&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;file-35262&quot; class=&quot;file file-image file-image-jpeg&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;element-invisible&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/files/50forward-eventrecap-3jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;content&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.splcenter.org/sites/default/files/50forward-eventrecap-_3.jpg&quot; width=&quot;1200&quot; height=&quot;900&quot; alt=&quot;Lecia Brooks&quot; title=&quot;lecia-brooks-splc-50forward&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-field-file-caption field-type-text-long field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;field-item even &quot;&gt;Lecia Brooks, the SPLC&#039;s chief of staff and culture, reflects on the organization&#039;s history during her remarks at the 50 Forward event in Atlanta. (Credit: Mhandy Gerard/SPLC)&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SPLC co-founder Joe Levin and Lecia Brooks, chief of staff and culture, who joined the SPLC in 2004, described the beginnings of the organization and its evolution over the past 51 years to the present.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Levin recalled the founders’ inspiration to establish the SPLC by “witnessing the cruelty of institutional racial injustice and the violence of vigilante groups, particularly the Ku Klux Klan.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tonight, Levin declared, “Our fragile, imperfect democracy is in crisis.” He cited the normalization of white supremacy, the spread of the “great replacement” conspiracy theory, the Jan. 6, 2021, insurrection at the U.S. Capitol, and the rise in hate crimes against racial, religious, ethnic and LGBTQ+ communities. Still, he said, the SPLC of today is up to its task.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It is reassuring and empowering to know that we are not the same SPLC that we were in the 20th century. We’ve transformed into an organization that is prepared to meet the South’s new challenges. … I could not be more impressed with the outstanding leadership of Margaret Huang, with our diverse and engaged board and with our unrelenting and brilliant staff. This event is a remarkable way to pass the torch to a new generation of Southern Poverty Law Center leadership. The visionary strategy presented today is proof that the future of the SPLC is in excellent hands.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Brooks said she has seen the growing depth and breadth of the good work of the SPLC. She recalled just some of that growth: the opening of the CRMC in 2005, where she was founding director; the establishment of the Immigrant Justice Project, also in 2005; the opening of regional offices; the transformation of the original “Klanwatch” into &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.splcenter.org/hatewatch/&quot;&gt;Hatewatch&lt;/a&gt;; and some of the seminal legal cases that the SPLC won, such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.splcenter.org/news/2015/07/14/20-million-settlement-agreement-reached-labor-trafficking-cases-coordinated-splc-behalf&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;David v. Signal International&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, a labor trafficking case decided in 2015. Brooks noted that when she arrived at the SPLC, there were about 100 employees. Today there are about 450.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Huang summed up the powerful arc of the SPLC’s past and future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The SPLC has been doing incredible work for 50 years,” she said. “I wanted to celebrate that. We’ve had successes in litigation, but the problems are just as compelling and just as urgent for us to tackle as ever before. ... The SPLC is still going strong, but we recognize how much work we still have ahead of us.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Concluding her remarks to the audience, Huang said, “Change is possible. A better future for the South is on the horizon. A future of justice, of inclusion, of multiracial democracy. And I know we can achieve it together.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Picture at top: SPLC President and CEO Margaret Huang speaks during the organization’s 50 Forward event in Atlanta. (Credit: Mhandy Gerard/SPLC)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-field-person field-type-entityreference field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;
                &lt;div class=&quot;field-item even &quot;&gt;&lt;article id=&quot;node-16901&quot; class=&quot;node node-person node-teaser node-even&quot;&gt;

  
  &lt;div class=&quot;content&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;group-text-field-group&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-title-field field-type-text field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;
                &lt;div class=&quot;field-item even &quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/about/staff/rhonda-sonnenberg&quot;&gt;Rhonda Sonnenberg&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-field-person-title field-type-text field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;
                &lt;div class=&quot;field-item even &quot;&gt;Senior Staff Writer&lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;  &lt;/div&gt; &lt;!-- /content --&gt;

  
      &lt;div class=&quot;links&quot;&gt;
          &lt;/div&gt; &lt;!-- /links --&gt;
  
  &lt;/article&gt; &lt;!-- /article #node --&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-field-addthis field-type-addthis field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;
                &lt;div class=&quot;field-item even &quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;addthis_toolbox addthis_default_style  &quot; addthis:title=&quot;50 Forward: An evening with the SPLC looks ahead to the next half century - Southern Poverty Law Center&quot; addthis:url=&quot;https://www.splcenter.org/news/2022/10/21/50-forward-evening-splc-looks-ahead-next-half-century&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot; &quot; class=&quot;addthis_button_facebook&quot; aria-label=&quot;Facebook: Share this page&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot; &quot; class=&quot;addthis_button_twitter&quot; aria-label=&quot;Twitter: Share this page&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-field-publish-date field-type-date field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;
                &lt;div class=&quot;field-item even &quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;date-display-single&quot;&gt;October 21, 2022&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
 <pubDate>Sat, 22 Oct 2022 01:52:20 +0000</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>rudy.isaza_2663</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">17198 at https://www.splcenter.org</guid>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
