<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<rdf:RDF
 xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
 xmlns="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/"
 xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
 xmlns:taxo="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/taxonomy/"
 xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
 xmlns:syn="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
 xmlns:admin="http://webns.net/mvcb/"
>

<channel rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/">
<title>hep-th updates on arXiv.org</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">High Energy Physics - Theory (hep-th) updates on the arXiv.org e-print archive</description>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:date>2022-11-03T20:30:00-05:00</dc:date>
<dc:publisher>www-admin@arxiv.org</dc:publisher>
<dc:subject>High Energy Physics - Theory</dc:subject>
<syn:updateBase>1901-01-01T00:00+00:00</syn:updateBase>
<syn:updateFrequency>1</syn:updateFrequency>
<syn:updatePeriod>daily</syn:updatePeriod>
<items>
 <rdf:Seq>
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01376" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01385" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01386" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01392" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01394" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01397" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01403" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01404" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01409" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01419" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01420" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01525" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01546" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01611" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01632" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01650" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01674" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01702" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01760" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01766" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01769" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01792" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01794" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01795" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01838" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01949" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2109.06342" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2201.09016" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2202.04498" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2206.10339" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2206.12597" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2206.12924" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2206.14277" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2207.02933" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2207.03183" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2207.10658" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2208.11982" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.00492" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.00906" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.02431" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.07698" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.09457" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.10891" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01099" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01130" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.16304" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01268" />
 </rdf:Seq>
</items>
<image rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif" />
</channel>
<image rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif">
<title>arXiv.org</title>
<url>http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif</url>
<link>http://arxiv.org/</link>
</image>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01376">
<title>Higgs Condensates are Symmetry-Protected Topological Phases: I. Discrete Symmetries. (arXiv:2211.01376v1 [cond-mat.str-el])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01376</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Where in the landscape of many-body phases of matter do we place the Higgs
condensate of a gauge theory? On the one hand, the Higgs phase is gapped, has
no local order parameter, and for fundamental Higgs fields is adiabatically
connected to the confined phase. On the other hand, Higgs phases such as
superconductors display rich phenomenology. In this work, we propose a minimal
description of the Higgs phase as a symmetry-protected topological (SPT) phase,
utilizing conventional and higher-form symmetries. In this first part, we focus
on 2+1D $\mathbb Z_2$ gauge theory and find that the Higgs phase is protected
by a higher-form magnetic symmetry and a matter symmetry, whose meaning depends
on the physical context. While this proposal captures known properties of Higgs
phases, it also predicts that the Higgs phase of the Fradkin-Shenker model has
SPT edge modes in the symmetric part of the phase diagram, which we confirm
analytically. In addition, we argue that this SPT property is remarkably robust
upon explicitly breaking the magnetic symmetry. Although the Higgs and confined
phases are then connected without a bulk transition, they are separated by a
boundary phase transition, which we confirm with tensor network simulations.
More generally, the boundary anomaly of the Higgs SPT phase coincides with the
emergent anomaly of symmetry-breaking phases, making precise the relation
between Higgs phases and symmetry breaking. The SPT nature of the Higgs phase
can also manifest in the bulk, e.g., at transitions between distinct Higgs
condensates. Finally, we extract insights which are applicable to general SPT
phases, such as a &apos;bulk-defect correspondence&apos; generalizing discrete gauge
group analogs of Superconductor-Insulator-Superconductor (SIS) junctions. The
sequel to this work will generalize &apos;Higgs=SPT&apos; to continuous symmetries,
interpreting superconductivity as an SPT property.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Verresen_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ruben Verresen&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Borla_U/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Umberto Borla&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Vishwanath_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ashvin Vishwanath&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Moroz_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Sergej Moroz&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Thorngren_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ryan Thorngren&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01385">
<title>A deformed IR: a new IR fixed point for four-dimensional holographic theories. (arXiv:2211.01385v1 [hep-th])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01385</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;In holography, the IR behavior of a quantum system at nonzero density is
described by the near horizon geometry of an extremal charged black hole. It is
commonly believed that for systems on $S^3$, this near horizon geometry is
$AdS_2\times S^3 $. We show that this is not the case: generic static,
nonspherical perturbations of $AdS_2\times S^3 $ blow up at the horizon,
showing that it is not a stable IR fixed point. We then construct a new near
horizon geometry which is invariant under only $SO(3)$ (and not $SO(4)$)
symmetry and show that it is stable to $SO(3)$-preserving perturbations (but
not in general). We also show that an open set of nonextremal,
$SO(3)$-invariant charged black holes develop this new near horizon geometry in
the limit $T \to 0$. Our new IR geometry still has $AdS_2$ symmetry, but it is
warped over a deformed sphere. We also construct many other near horizon
geometries, including some with no rotational symmetries, but expect them all
to be unstable IR fixed points.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Horowitz_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Gary T. Horowitz&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Kolanowski_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Maciej Kolanowski&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Santos_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jorge E. Santos&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01386">
<title>Double copy for tree-level form factors I: foundations. (arXiv:2211.01386v1 [hep-th])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01386</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The double-copy construction for form factors was reported in our previous
work, in which a novel mechanism of turning spurious poles in Yang-Mills theory
into physical poles in gravity is observed. This paper is the first of a series
of two papers providing the details as well as various generalizations on the
double-copy construction of tree-level form factors. In this paper, we
establish the generic formalism by focusing on the form factor of ${\rm
tr}(\phi^2)$ in the Yang-Mills-scalar theory. A thorough discussion is given on
the emergence of the &quot;spurious&quot;-type poles and various related properties. We
also discuss two generalizations: the Higgs amplitudes in QCD, and the ${\rm
tr}(\phi^2)$ form factors with multiple external scalar states.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Lin_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Guanda Lin&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Yang_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Gang Yang&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01392">
<title>R\&apos;enyi Mutual Information in Quantum Field Theory. (arXiv:2211.01392v1 [hep-th])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01392</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We study a proper definition of R\&apos;enyi mutual information (RMI) in quantum
field theory as defined via the Petz R\&apos;enyi relative entropy. Unlike the
standard definition, the RMI we compute is a genuine measure of correlations
between subsystems, as evidenced by its non-negativity and monotonicity under
local operations. Furthermore, the RMI is UV finite and well-defined in the
continuum limit. We develop a replica path integral approach for the RMI in
quantum field theories and evaluate it explicitly in 1+1D conformal field
theory using twist fields. We prove that it bounds connected correlation
functions and check our results against exact numerics in the massless free
fermion theory.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Kudler_Flam_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jonah Kudler-Flam&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01394">
<title>Self-Similar Gravitational Dynamics, Singularities and Criticality in 2D. (arXiv:2211.01394v1 [hep-th])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01394</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We initiate a systematic study of continuously self-similar (CSS)
gravitational dynamics in two dimensions, motivated by critical phenomena
observed in higher dimensional gravitational theories. We consider CSS
spacetimes admitting a homothetic Killing vector (HKV) field. For a general
two-dimensional gravitational theory coupled to a dilaton field and Maxwell
field, we find that the assumption of continuous self-similarity determines the
form of the dilaton coupling to the curvature. Certain limits produce two
important classes of models, one of which is closely related to two-dimensional
target space string theory and the other being Liouville gravity. The gauge
field is shown to produce a shift in the dilaton potential strength. We
consider static black hole solutions and find spacetimes with uncommon
asymptotic behaviour. We show the vacuum self-similar spacetimes to be special
limits of the static solutions. We add matter fields consistent with
self-similarity (including a certain model of semi-classical gravity) and write
down the autonomous ordinary differential equations governing the gravitational
dynamics. Based on the phenomenon of finite-time blow-up in ODEs, we argue that
spacetime singularities are generic in our models. We present qualitatively
diverse results from analytical and numerical investigations regarding matter
field collapse and singularities. We find interesting hints of a Choptuik-like
scaling law.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Moitra_U/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Upamanyu Moitra&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01397">
<title>The fate of discrete torsion on resolved heterotic Z2xZ2 orbifolds using (0,2) GLSMs. (arXiv:2211.01397v1 [hep-th])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01397</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;This paper aims to shed light on what becomes of discrete torsion within
heterotic orbifolds when they are resolved to smooth geometries. Gauged Linear
Sigma Models (GLSMs) possessing (0,2) worldsheet supersymmetry are employed as
interpolations between them. This question is addressed for resolutions of the
non-compact C3/Z2xZ2 and the compact T6/Z2xZ2 orbifolds to keep track of local
and global aspects. The GLSMs associated with the non-compact orbifold with or
without torsion are to a large extent equivalent: only when expressed in the
same superfield basis, a field redefinition anomaly arises among them, which in
the orbifold limit reproduces the discrete torsion phases. Previously unknown,
novel resolution GLSMs for T6/Z2xZ2 are constructed. The GLSM associated with
the torsional compact orbifold suffers from mixed gauge anomalies, which need
to be cancelled by appropriate logarithmic superfield dependent FI-terms on the
worldsheet, signalling H-flux due to NS5-branes supported at the exceptional
cycles.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Faraggi_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;A.E. Faraggi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Nibbelink_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;S. Groot Nibbelink&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Heredia_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;M. Hurtado Heredia&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01403">
<title>Exact multi-instantons in topological string theory. (arXiv:2211.01403v1 [hep-th])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01403</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Topological string theory has multi-instanton sectors which lead to
non-perturbative effects in the string coupling constant and control the large
order behavior of the perturbative genus expansion. As proposed by Couso,
Edelstein, Schiappa and Vonk, these sectors can be described by a trans-series
extension of the BCOV holomorphic anomaly equations. In this paper we find
exact, closed form solutions for these multi-instanton trans-series in the case
of local Calabi-Yau manifolds. The resulting multi-instanton amplitudes turn
out to be very similar to the eigenvalue tunneling amplitudes of matrix models.
Their form suggests that the flat coordinates of the Calabi-Yau manifold are
naturally quantized in units of the string coupling constant, as postulated in
large $N$ dualities. Based on our results we obtain a general picture for the
resurgent structure of the topological string in the local case, which we
illustrate with explicit calculations in the case of local $\mathbb{P}^2$.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Gu_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jie Gu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Marino_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Marcos Marino&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01404">
<title>Illuminating new and known relations between knot invariants. (arXiv:2211.01404v1 [math.GT])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01404</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We automate the process of machine learning correlations between knot
invariants. For nearly 200,000 distinct sets of input knot invariants together
with an output invariant, we attempt to learn the output invariant by training
a neural network on the input invariants. Correlation between invariants is
measured by the accuracy of the neural network prediction, and bipartite or
tripartite correlations are sequentially filtered from the input invariant sets
so that experiments with larger input sets are checking for true multipartite
correlation. We rediscover several known relationships between polynomial,
homological, and hyperbolic knot invariants, while also finding novel
correlations which are not explained by known results in knot theory. These
unexplained correlations strengthen previous observations concerning links
between Khovanov and knot Floer homology. Our results also point to a new
connection between quantum algebraic and hyperbolic invariants, similar to the
generalized volume conjecture.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Craven_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jessica Craven&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Hughes_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Mark Hughes&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Jejjala_V/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Vishnu Jejjala&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Kar_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Arjun Kar&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01409">
<title>EFT strings and emergence. (arXiv:2211.01409v1 [hep-th])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01409</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We revisit the Emergence Proposal in 4d ${\cal N}=2$ vector multiplet sectors
that arise from type II string Calabi--Yau compactifications, with emphasis on
the role of axionic fundamental strings, or EFT strings. We focus on
large-volume type IIA compactifications, where EFT strings arise from
NS5-branes wrapping internal four-cycles, and consider a set of
infinite-distance moduli-space limits that can be classified in terms of a
scaling weight $w=1,2,3$. It has been shown before how one-loop threshold
effects of an infinite tower of BPS particles made up of D2/D0-branes generate
the asymptotic behaviour of the gauge kinetic functions along limits with
$w=3$. We extend this result to $w=2$ limits, by taking into account D2-brane
multi-wrapping numbers. In $w=1$ limits the leading tower involves EFT string
oscillations, and one can reproduce the behaviour of both weakly and
strongly-coupled $U(1)$&apos;s independently on whether the EFT string is critical
or not, by assuming that charged modes dominate the light spectrum.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Marchesano_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Fernando Marchesano&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Melotti_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Luca Melotti&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01419">
<title>Twisted holography without conformal symmetry. (arXiv:2211.01419v1 [hep-th])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01419</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We discuss the notion of translation-invariant vacua for 2d chiral algebras
and relate it to the notion of the associated variety. The two-dimensional
chiral algebra associated to four-dimensional ${\cal N}=4$ $U(N)$ SYM has a
conjectural holographic dual involving the B-model topological string theory.
We study the effect of non-zero vacuum expectation values on the chiral algebra
correlation functions and derive a holographic dual Calabi-Yau geometry. We
test our proposal by a large $N$ analysis of correlation functions of
determinant operators, whose saddles can be matched with semi-classical
configurations of &quot;Giant Graviton&quot; D-branes in the bulk
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Budzik_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Kasia Budzik&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Gaiotto_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Davide Gaiotto&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01420">
<title>A Complete Set of the Dimension-8 Green&apos;s Basis Operators in the Standard Model Effective Field Theory. (arXiv:2211.01420v1 [hep-ph])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01420</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We present a complete and independent off-shell Green&apos;s basis of the
dimension 8 operators in the Standard Model effective field theory (SMEFT). We
propose an off-shell amplitude formalism such that this new kind of amplitudes
has a one-to-one correspondence to general operators carrying all kinds of
redundancies. The advantage of such formalism is that all kinds of redundancies
can be formulated explicitly in terms of the off-shell spinors and thus be
removed systematically from the exhaustive list of the general off-shell
amplitudes. Following such procedure, redundant operators can be reduced to the
ones with the only redundancy from the equation of motion kept, the Green&apos;s
basis. We find there are (993+1649) independent (on-shell + off-shell)
operators for one generation of fermions and (44807+66197) ones for three
generations at the dimension 8. This systematic method can be applied to obtain
the Green&apos;s basis at any mass dimension for general EFTs.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Ren_Z/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Zhe Ren&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Yu_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jiang-Hao Yu&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01525">
<title>Exploring quantum geometry created by quantum matter. (arXiv:2211.01525v1 [gr-qc])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01525</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Exactly soluble models can serve as excellent tools to explore conceptual
issues in non-perturbative quantum gravity. In perturbative approaches, it is
only the two radiative modes of the linearized gravitational field that are
quantized. The goal of this investigation is to probe the `Coulombic&apos; aspects
of quantum geometry that are governed entirely by matter sources. Since there
are no gravitational waves in 3 dimensions, 3-d gravity coupled to matter
provides an ideal arena for this task. Our analysis will reveal novel aspects
of quantum gravity that bring out limitations of classical and semi-classical
theories in unforeseen regimes: non-linearities of general relativity can
magnify small quantum fluctuations in the matter sector to large effects in the
gravitational sector. Finally, this analysis leads to thought experiments that
bring out rather starkly why understanding of the nature of physical reality
depends sensitively on the theoretical lens with which it is probed. As
theories becomes richer, new scales emerge, triggering novel effects that could
not be imagined before. The model provides a concise realization of this
well-known chain.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Ashtekar_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Abhay Ashtekar&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01546">
<title>On the superstring-inspired quantum correction to the Starobinsky model of inflation. (arXiv:2211.01546v1 [gr-qc])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01546</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Superstring/M-theory is the theory of quantum gravity that can provide the
UV-completion to viable inflation models. We modify the Starobinsky inflation
model by adding the Bel-Robinson tensor $T^{\mu\nu\lambda\rho}$ squared term
proposed as the leading quantum correction inspired by superstring theory. The
$(R+\frac{1}{6m^2}R^2 -\frac{\beta}{8m^6}T^2)$ model under consideration has
two parameters: the inflaton mass $m$ and the string-inspired positive
parameter $\beta$. We derive the equations of motion in the
Friedmann-Lemaitre-Robertson-Walker universe and investigate its solutions. We
find the physical bounds on the value of the parameter $\beta$ by demanding the
absence of ghosts and consistency of the derived inflationary observables with
the measurements of the cosmic microwave background radiation.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Ketov_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Sergei V. Ketov&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Pozdeeva_E/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ekaterina O. Pozdeeva&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Vernov_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Sergey Yu. Vernov&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01611">
<title>Adelic Amplitudes and Intricacies of Infinite Products. (arXiv:2211.01611v1 [hep-th])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01611</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;For every prime number $p$ it is possible to define a $p$-adic version of the
Veneziano amplitude and its higher-point generalizations. Multiplying together
the real amplitude with all its $p$-adic counterparts yields the adelic
amplitude. At four points it has been argued that the adelic amplitude, after
regulating the product that defines it, equals one. For the adelic 5-point
amplitude, there exist kinematic regimes where no regularization is needed.
This paper demonstrates that in special cases within this regime, the adelic
product can be explicitly evaluated in terms of ratios of the Riemann zeta
function, and observes that the 5-point adelic amplitude is not given by a
single analytic function. Motivated by this fact to study new regularization
procedures for the 4-point amplitude, an alternative formalism is presented,
resulting in non-constant amplitudes that are piecewise analytic in the three
scattering channels, including one non-constant adelic amplitude previously
suggested in the literature. Decomposing the residues of these amplitudes into
weighted sums of Gegenbauer polynomials, numerical evidence indicates that in
special ranges of spacetime dimensions all the coefficients are positive, as
required by unitarity.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Jepsen_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Christian B. Jepsen&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01632">
<title>Equivalence of the modified Villain formulation and the dual Hamiltonian method in the duality of the XY-plaquette model. (arXiv:2211.01632v1 [hep-th])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01632</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Regarding the duality of the XY-placket model in the $2+1d$ system, We
compared and discussed the equivalence and difference between the modified
Villain formulation, recently introduced by Gorantla et al. to study duality in
exotic field theories such as fracton theory, and the standard Villain
formulation and dual Hamiltonian method we introduced in our previous paper to
study duality between Josephson junctions and quantum phase slips in the $1+1d$
system.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Yoneda_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Morishige Yoneda&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01650">
<title>Universality and its limits in non-Hermitian many-body quantum chaos using the Sachdev-Ye-Kitaev model. (arXiv:2211.01650v1 [hep-th])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01650</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Spectral rigidity in Hermitian quantum chaotic systems signals the presence
of dynamical universal features at time scales that can be much shorter than
the Heisenberg time. We study the analogue of this time scale in many-body
non-Hermitian quantum chaos by a detailed analysis of long-range spectral
correlators. For that purpose, we investigate the number variance and the
spectral form factor of a non-Hermitian $q$-body Sachdev-Ye-Kitaev (nHSYK)
model, which describes $N$ fermions in zero spatial dimensions. After an
analytical and numerical analysis of these spectral observables for
non-Hermitian random matrices, and a careful unfolding, we find good agreement
with the nHSYK model for $q &amp;gt; 2$ starting at a time scale that decreases
sharply with $q$. The source of deviation from universality, identified
analytically, is ensemble fluctuations not related to the quantum dynamics. For
fixed $q$ and large enough $N$, these fluctuations become dominant up until
after the Heisenberg time, so that the spectral form factor is no longer useful
for the study of quantum chaos. In all cases, our results point to a weakened
or vanishing spectral rigidity that effectively delays the observation of full
quantum ergodicity. We also show that the number variance displays
non-stationary spectral correlations for both the nHSYK model and random
matrices. This non-stationarity, also not related to the quantum dynamics,
points to intrinsic limitations of these observables to describe the quantum
chaotic motion. On the other hand, we introduce the local spectral form factor,
which is shown to be stationary and not affected by collective fluctuations,
and propose it as an effective diagnostic of non-Hermitian quantum chaos. For
$q = 2$, we find saturation to Poisson statistics at a time scale of $\log D$,
compared to a scale of $\sqrt D$ for $ q&amp;gt;2$, with $D $ the total number of
states.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Garcia_Garcia_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Antonio M. Garc&amp;#xed;a-Garc&amp;#xed;a&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Sa_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Lucas S&amp;#xe1;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Verbaarschot_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jacobus J. M. Verbaarschot&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01674">
<title>Photon Rings Around Warped Black Holes. (arXiv:2211.01674v1 [gr-qc])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01674</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The black hole photon ring is a prime target for upcoming space-based VLBI
missions seeking to image the fine structure of astrophysical black holes. The
classical Lyapunov exponents of the corresponding nearly bound null geodesics
control the quasinormal ringing of a perturbed black hole as it settles back
down to equilibrium, and they admit a holographic interpretation in terms of
quantum Ruelle resonances of the microstate dual to the Kerr black hole. Recent
work has identified a number of emergent symmetries related to the intricate
self-similar structure of the photon ring. Here, we explore this web of
interrelated phenomena in an exactly soluble example that arises as an
approximation to the near-extremal Kerr black hole. The self-dual warped
AdS$_3$ geometry has a photon ring as well as $\mathsf{SL}(2,\mathbb{R})$
isometries and an exactly calculable quasinormal mode (QNM) spectrum. We show
explicitly that the geometric optics approximation reproduces the eikonal limit
of the exact QNM spectrum, as well as the approximate &quot;near-ring&quot;
wavefunctions. The $\mathsf{SL}(2,\mathbb{R})$ isometries are directly related
to the emergent conformal symmetry of the photon ring in black hole images but
are distinct from a recently discussed conformal symmetry of the eikonal QNM
spectrum. The equivalence of the classical QNM spectrum -- and thus the photon
ring -- to the quantum Ruelle resonances in the context of a spacetime with a
putative holographic dual suggests that the photon ring of a warped black hole
is indeed part of the black hole hologram.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Kapec_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Daniel Kapec&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Lupsasca_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Alexandru Lupsasca&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Strominger_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Andrew Strominger&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01702">
<title>On diagonal canonical solutions to the Einstein field equations and their meromorphic deformations. (arXiv:2211.01702v1 [math-ph])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01702</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Explicit solutions to the non-linear field equations of gravitational
theories can be obtained, using a Riemann-Hilbert approach, from an appropriate
factorization of certain matrix functions. Here we study a class of solutions,
which we call diagonal canonical solutions, obtained via Wiener-Hopf
factorization of diagonal matrices. This class comprises, among others, the
Schwarzschild, Kasner, Einstein-Rosen and gravitational pulse wave solutions.
We show that new solutions can be obtained by a method of meromorphic
deformation of the diagonal canonical solutions and that we can define Abelian
groups of such solutions indexed by a curve in the complex plane.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math-ph/1/au:+Camara_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;M. Cristina C&amp;#xe2;mara&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math-ph/1/au:+Cardoso_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Gabriel Lopes Cardoso&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01760">
<title>Holography and magnetohydrodynamics with dynamical gauge fields. (arXiv:2211.01760v1 [hep-th])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01760</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Within the framework of holography, the Einstein-Maxwell action with
Dirichlet boundary conditions corresponds to a dual conformal field theory in
presence of an external gauge field. Nevertheless, in many real-world
applications, e.g., magnetohydrodynamics, plasma physics, superconductors, etc.
dynamical gauge fields and Coulomb interactions are fundamental. In this work,
we consider bottom-up holographic models at finite magnetic field and (free)
charge density in presence of dynamical boundary gauge fields which are
introduced using mixed boundary conditions. We numerically study the spectrum
of the lowest quasi-normal modes and successfully compare the obtained results
to magnetohydrodynamics theory in $2+1$ dimensions. Surprisingly, as far as the
electromagnetic coupling is small enough, we find perfect agreement even in the
large magnetic field limit. Our results prove that a holographic description of
magnetohydrodynamics does not necessarily need higher-form bulk fields but can
be consistently derived using mixed boundary conditions for standard gauge
fields.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Ahn_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yongjun Ahn&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Baggioli_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Matteo Baggioli&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Huh_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Kyoung-Bum Huh&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Jeong_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Hyun-Sik Jeong&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Kim_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Keun-Young Kim&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Sun_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ya-Wen Sun&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01766">
<title>Scalarization. (arXiv:2211.01766v1 [gr-qc])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01766</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Scalarization is a mechanism that endows strongly self-gravitating bodies,
such as neutron stars and black holes, with a scalar field configuration. It
resembles a phase transition in that the scalar configuration only appears when
a certain quantity that characterizes the compact object, e.g., its compactness
or spin, is beyond a threshold. We provide a critical and comprehensive review
of scalarization, including the mechanism itself, theories that exhibit it, its
manifestation in neutron stars, black holes, and their binaries, potential
extension to other fields, and a thorough discussion of future perspectives.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Doneva_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Daniela D. Doneva&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Ramazanoglu_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Fethi M. Ramazano&amp;#x11f;lu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Silva_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Hector O. Silva&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Sotiriou_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Thomas P. Sotiriou&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Yazadjiev_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Stoytcho S. Yazadjiev&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01769">
<title>Beyond Schwarzschild-de Sitter spacetimes: I. A new exhaustive class of metrics inspired by Buchdahl for pure $R^2$ gravity in a compact form. (arXiv:2211.01769v1 [gr-qc])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01769</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Some sixty years ago Buchdahl pioneered a program in search of static
spherically symmetric vacua for pure $R^{2}$ gravity (Nuovo Cimento, Vol 23, No
1, pp 141-157 (1962); [https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/BF02733549]).
Surpassing several obstacles, his work culminated in a non-linear second-order
ordinary differential equation (ODE) which required being solved. However
Buchdahl deemed the ODE intractable and prematurely abandoned his pursuit for
an analytical solution. We have finally managed to break this six-decades-old
impasse and accomplish his goal. Reformulating the Buchdahl ODE, we obtain a
novel exhaustive class of metrics (which we shall call the Buchdahl-inspired
metrics hereafter) in a compact form. We are able to verify ex post, via direct
inspection, that the metric obtained herein satisfies the $R^{2}$ vacuo field
equation, hence establishing its validity. We show why the Buchdahl-inspired
metrics, which exhibit non-constant scalar curvature, defeat a
Lichnerowicz-type no-go theorem, previously proved for quadratic gravity, by
evading the overly strong restriction on the asymptotic falloff of the metric
at spatial infinity. Our novel solution thereby completes Buchdahl&apos;s
six-decades-old program. We also explore the mathematical properties of the
Buchdahl-inspired metrics in the limit of small k and in the region around the
coordinate origin.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Nguyen_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Hoang Ky Nguyen&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01792">
<title>The two-loop eight-point amplitude in ABJM theory. (arXiv:2211.01792v1 [hep-th])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01792</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;In this paper, we present the two-loop correction to scattering amplitudes in
three-dimensional $\mathcal{N}=6$ Chern-Simons matter theory. We use
eight-point case as our main example, but the method generalizes to all
multiplicities. The integrand is completely fixed by dual conformal symmetry,
maximal cuts, constraints from soft-collinear behavior and from vanishing of
odd-multiplicity amplitudes. After performing integrations with Higgs
regularizations, the integrated results demonstrate that the infrared
divergence is again identical to that of ${\cal N}=4$ super Yang-Mills. After
subtracting divergences, the finite part is dual conformal invariant, and
respects various symmetries; it has uniform transcendentality weight two and
exhibits nice analytic structure.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+He_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Song He&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Huang_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yu-tin Huang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Kuo_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Chia-Kai Kuo&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Li_Z/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Zhenjie Li&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01794">
<title>Kinks Multiply Mesons. (arXiv:2211.01794v1 [hep-th])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01794</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;In a (1+1)-dimensional scalar quantum field theory, we calculate the
leading-order probability of meson multiplication, which is the inelastic
scattering process: kink + meson $\rightarrow$ kink + 2 mesons. We also
calculate the differential probability with respect to the final meson momenta
and the probability that one or two of the final mesons recoils back towards
the source. In the ultrarelativistic limit of the initial meson, the total
probability tends to a constant, which we calculate analytically in the
$\phi^4$ model. At this order the meson sector conserves energy on its own,
while the incoming meson applies a positive pressure to the kink. This is in
contrast with the situation in classical field theory, where Romanczukiewicz
and collaborators have shown that, in the presence of a reflectionless kink,
only meson fusion is allowed, resulting in a negative radiation pressure on the
kink.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Evslin_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jarah Evslin&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Liu_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Hui Liu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Zhang_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Baiyang Zhang&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01795">
<title>Nonrelativistic Approximations of Closed Bosonic String Theory. (arXiv:2211.01795v1 [hep-th])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01795</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We further develop the string $1/c^2$ expansion of closed bosonic string
theory, where $c$ is the speed of light. The expansion will be performed up to
and including the next-to-next-to-leading order (NNLO). We show that the
next-to-leading order (NLO) theory is equal to the Gomis--Ooguri string,
generalised to a curved target space, provided the target space geometry admits
a certain class of co-dimension-2 foliations. We compute the energy of the
string up to NNLO for a flat target space with a circle that must be wound by
the string, and we show that it agrees with the $1/c^2$ expansion of the
relativistic energy. We also compute the algebra of Noether charges for a flat
target space and show that this matches order-by-order with an appropriate
expansion of the Poincar\&apos;e algebra, which at NLO gives the string Bargmann
algebra. Finally, we expand the phase space action, which allows us to perform
the Dirac procedure and pass to the quantum theory. It turns out that the
Poisson brackets change at each order, and we show that the normal ordering
constant of the relativistic theory, which does not depend on $c$, can be
reproduced by the NLO and NNLO theories.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Hartong_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jelle Hartong&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Have_E/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Emil Have&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01838">
<title>On the Operator Origins of Classical and Quantum Wave Functions. (arXiv:2211.01838v1 [math-ph])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01838</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We investigate operator algebraic origins of the classical Koopman-von
Neumann wave function $\psi_{KvN}$ as well as the quantum mechanical one
$\psi_{QM}$. We introduce a formalism of Operator Mechanics (OM) based on a
noncommutative Poisson, symplectic and noncommutative differential structures.
OM serves as a pre-quantum algebra from which algebraic structures relevant to
real-world classical and quantum mechanics follow. In particular, $\psi_{KvN}$
and $\psi_{QM}$ are both consequences of this pre-quantum formalism. No a
priori Hilbert space is needed. OM admits an algebraic notion of operator
expectation values without invoking states. A phase space bundle ${\cal E}$
follows from this. $\psi_{KvN}$ and $\psi_{QM}$ are shown to be sections in
${\cal E}$. The difference between $\psi_{KvN}$ and $\psi_{QM}$ originates from
a quantization map interpreted as &quot;twisting&quot; of sections over ${\cal E}$. We
also show that the Schr\&quot;{o}dinger equation is obtained from the Koopman-von
Neumann equation. What this suggests is that neither the Schr\&quot;{o}dinger
equation nor the quantum wave function are fundamental structures. Rather, they
both originate from a pre-quantum operator algebra.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math-ph/1/au:+Arsiwalla_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xerxes D. Arsiwalla&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math-ph/1/au:+Chester_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;David Chester&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math-ph/1/au:+Kauffman_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Louis H. Kauffman&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01949">
<title>Impact of multiple modes on the evolution of self-interacting axion condensate around rotating black holes. (arXiv:2211.01949v1 [gr-qc])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01949</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Ultra-light particles, such as axions, form a macroscopic condensate around a
highly spinning black hole by the superradiant instability. Due to its
macroscopic nature, the condensate opens the possibility of detecting the axion
through gravitational wave observations. However, the precise evolution of the
condensate must be known for the actual detection. For future observation, we
numerically study the influence of the self-interaction, especially interaction
between different modes, on the evolution of the condensate in detail. First,
we focus on the case when condensate starts with the smallest possible angular
quantum number. For this case, we perform the non-linear calculation and show
that the dissipation induced by the mode interaction is strong enough to
saturate the superradiant instability, even if the secondary cloud starts with
quantum fluctuations. Our result indicates that explosive phenomena such as
bosenova do not occur in this case. We also show that the condensate settles to
a quasi-stationary state mainly composed of two modes, one with the smallest
angular quantum number for which the superradiant instability occurs and the
other with the adjacent higher angular quantum number. We also study the case
when the condensate starts with the dominance of the higher angular quantum
number. We show that the dissipation process induced by the mode coupling does
not occur for small gravitational coupling. Therefore, bosenova might occur in
this case.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Omiya_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Hidetoshi Omiya&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Takahashi_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Takuya Takahashi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Tanaka_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Takahiro Tanaka&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Yoshino_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Hirotaka Yoshino&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2109.06342">
<title>Gravity from symmetry: Duality and impulsive waves. (arXiv:2109.06342v4 [hep-th] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2109.06342</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We show that we can derive the asymptotic Einstein&apos;s equations that arises at
order $1/r$ in asymptotically flat gravity purely from symmetry considerations.
This is achieved by studying the transformation properties of functionals of
the metric and the stress-energy tensor under the action of the Weyl BMS group,
a recently introduced asymptotic symmetry group that includes arbitrary
diffeomorphisms and local conformal transformations of the metric on the
2-sphere. Our derivation, which encompasses the inclusion of matter sources,
leads to the identification of covariant observables that provide a definition
of conserved charges parametrizing the non-radiative corner phase space. These
observables, related to the Weyl scalars, reveal a duality symmetry and a
spin-2 generator which allow us to recast the asymptotic evolution equations in
a simple and elegant form as conservation equations for a null fluid living at
null infinity. Finally we identify non-linear gravitational impulse waves that
describe transitions among gravitational vacua and are non-perturbative
solutions of the asymptotic Einstein&apos;s equations. This provides a new picture
of quantization of the asymptotic phase space, where gravitational vacua are
representations of the asymptotic symmetry group and impulsive waves are
encoded in their couplings.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Freidel_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Laurent Freidel&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Pranzetti_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Daniele Pranzetti&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2201.09016">
<title>A minimal self tuning model to solve the cosmological constant problem. (arXiv:2201.09016v2 [astro-ph.CO] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2201.09016</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The expansion of the Universe is observed to be accelerating, with the
simplest solution being a classical cosmological constant. However, this
receives contributions from the quantum vacuum, which are predicted to be many
orders of magnitude larger than observations, and suffers from radiative
instabilities requiring repeated fine tuning. In this paper we present a
minimal, self tuning scalar field model that can dynamically cancel a large
quantum vacuum energy, avoiding Weinberg&apos;s No Go Theorem, and produce
accelerated de Sitter expansion at a lower energy scale as a solution to the
problem. Our minimal model, which contains a non canonical kinetic energy and a
linear potential, belongs to the Kinetic Gravity Braiding subclass of Horndeski
theory which is not observationally excluded, and lies outside of the known Fab
Four or Well Tempered models. We find analytic solutions in the limits of slow
roll and fast roll, and numerically solve the equations of motion to illustrate
our model. We show that the model allows for a matter dominated era, and that
the attractor solution is stable under a phase transition in the vacuum energy
density. We also consider the energy scales required to match observations. Our
model shows the existence of a wider class of successful self tuning models
than previously assumed.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Khan_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Arnaz Khan&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Taylor_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Andy Taylor&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2202.04498">
<title>Analytic thin wall false vacuum decay rate. (arXiv:2202.04498v4 [hep-th] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2202.04498</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We derive a closed-form false vacuum decay rate at one loop in the thin wall
limit, where the true and false vacua are nearly degenerate. We obtain the
bounce configuration in $D$ dimensions, together with the Euclidean action with
a higher order correction, counter-terms and renormalization group running. We
extract the functional determinant via the Gel&apos;fand-Yaglom theorem for low and
generic orbital multipoles. The negative and zero eigenvalues appear for low
multipoles and the translational zeroes are removed. We compute the
fluctuations for generic multipoles, multiply and regulate the orbital modes.
We find an explicit finite renormalized decay rate in $D = 3, 4$ and give a
closed-form expression for the finite functional determinant in any dimension.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Ivanov_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Aleksandar Ivanov&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Matteini_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Marco Matteini&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Nemevsek_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Miha Nemev&amp;#x161;ek&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Ubaldi_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Lorenzo Ubaldi&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2206.10339">
<title>Unitary Constraints on Semiclassical Schwarzschild Black Holes in the Presence of Island. (arXiv:2206.10339v3 [hep-th] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2206.10339</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We reconsider $D\geq4$ dimensional asymptotically flat eternal Schwarzschild
black hole, and focus on the situation where the inner boundary of the
radiation region is chosen to be near the horizon (i.e. $\beta\ll 1$). The
tension between the near horizon condition and the short-distance approximation
emerges in large dimensions in previous papers. We remove this tension by
introducing a more proper near horizon condition, thus the resulting island
solution is well-behaved in any $D\geq4$ dimensional spacetime. Interestingly,
a novel constraint is obtained in this situation as required by the existence
of the island solution, which directly leads to the constraints on the size of
the Schwarzschild black hole, the position of the inner boundary for the
radiation region, or the value of $c\cdot\tilde{G}_{N}$ in any $D\geq4$
dimension. When considering the large $D$ limit, the constraint on the size of
the Schwarzschild black hole obtained in this situation is in agreement with
the result given in $[Phys.Rev.D 102 (2020) 2, 026016]$. We interpret these as
the unitary constraints implied by the presence of island in semiclassical
gravity.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Du_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Dong-Hui Du&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Gan_W/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Wen-Cong Gan&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Shu_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Fu-Wen Shu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Sun_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jia-Rui Sun&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2206.12597">
<title>Metric reconstruction from celestial multipoles. (arXiv:2206.12597v2 [hep-th] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2206.12597</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The most general vacuum solution to Einstein&apos;s field equations with no
incoming radiation can be constructed perturbatively from two infinite sets of
canonical multipole moments, which are found to be mapped into each other under
gravitational electric-magnetic duality at the non-linear level. We demonstrate
that in non-radiative regions such spacetimes are completely characterized by a
set of conserved celestial charges that consist of the Geroch-Hansen multipole
moments, the generalized BMS charges and additional celestial multipoles
accounting for subleading memory effects. Transitions among non-radiative
regions, induced by radiative processes, are therefore labelled by celestial
charges, which are identified in terms of canonical multipole moments of the
linearized gravitational field. The dictionary between celestial charges and
canonical multipole moments allows to holographically reconstruct the metric in
de Donder, Newman-Unti or Bondi gauge outside of sources.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Compere_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Geoffrey Comp&amp;#xe8;re&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Oliveri_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Roberto Oliveri&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Seraj_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ali Seraj&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2206.12924">
<title>Low-temperature behavior of the $O(N)$ models below two dimensions. (arXiv:2206.12924v2 [cond-mat.stat-mech] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2206.12924</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We investigate the critical behavior and the nature of the low-temperature
phase of the $O(N)$ models treating the number of field components $N$ and the
dimension $d$ as continuous variables with a focus on the $d\leq 2$ and $N\leq
2$ quadrant of the $(d,N)$ plane. We precisely chart a region of the $(d,N)$
plane where the low-temperature phase is characterized by an algebraic
correlation function decay similar to that of the Kosterlitz-Thouless phase but
with a temperature-independent anomalous dimension $\eta$. We revisit the
Cardy-Hamber analysis leading to a prediction concerning the nonanalytic
behavior of the $O(N)$ models&apos; critical exponents and emphasize the previously
not broadly appreciated consequences of this approach in $d&amp;lt;2$. In particular,
we discuss how this framework leads to destabilization of the long-range order
in favour of the quasi long-range order in systems with $d&amp;lt;2$ and $N&amp;lt;2$.
Subsequently, within a scheme of the nonperturbative renormalization group we
identify the low-temperature fixed points controlling the quasi long-range
ordered phase and demonstrate a collision between the critical and the
low-temperature fixed points upon approaching the lower critical dimension. We
evaluate the critical exponents $\eta(d,N)$ and $\nu^{-1}(d,N)$ and demonstrate
a very good agreement between the predictions of the Cardy-Hamber type analysis
and the nonperturbative renormalization group in $d&amp;lt;2$.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Chlebicki_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Andrzej Chlebicki&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Jakubczyk_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Pawe&amp;#x142; Jakubczyk&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2206.14277">
<title>Integrable Floquet systems related to logarithmic conformal field theory. (arXiv:2206.14277v2 [quant-ph] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2206.14277</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We study an integrable Floquet quantum system related to lattice statistical
systems in the universality class of dense polymers. These systems are
described by a particular non-unitary representation of the Temperley-Lieb
algebra. We find a simple Lie algebra structure for the elements of
Temperley-Lieb algebra which are invariant under shift by two lattice sites,
and show how the local Floquet conserved charges and the Floquet Hamiltonian
are expressed in terms of this algebra. The system has a phase transition
between local and non-local phases of the Floquet Hamiltonian. We provide a
strong indication that in the scaling limit this non-equilibrium system is
described by the logarithmic conformal field theory.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Yashin_V/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Vsevolod I. Yashin&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Kurlov_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Denis V. Kurlov&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Fedorov_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Aleksey K. Fedorov&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Gritsev_V/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Vladimir Gritsev&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2207.02933">
<title>On the two-dimensional time-dependent anisotropic harmonic oscillator in a magnetic field. (arXiv:2207.02933v2 [quant-ph] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2207.02933</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;A Charged harmonic oscillator in a magnetic field, Landau problems, and an
oscillator in a noncommutative space, share the same mathematical structure in
their Hamiltonians. We have considered a two-dimensional anisotropic harmonic
oscillator (AHO) with arbitrarily time-dependent parameters (effective mass and
frequencies), placed in an arbitrarily time-dependent magnetic field. A class
of quadratic invariant operators (in the sense of Lewis and Riesenfeld) have
been constructed. The invariant operators ($\hat{\mathcal{I}}$) have been
reduced to a simplified representative form by a linear canonical
transformation (the group $Sp(4, \mathbb{R})$). An orthonormal basis of the
Hilbert space consisting of the eigenvectors of $\hat{\mathcal{I}}$ is
obtained. In order to obtain the solutions of the time-dependent
Schr\&quot;{o}dinger equation corresponding to the system, both the geometric and
dynamical phase-factors are constructed. Peres-Horodecki Separability Criterion
for the bipartite coherent states corresponding to our system has been
demonstrated.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Patra_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Pinaki Patra&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2207.03183">
<title>Trouble with geodesics in black-to-white hole bouncing scenarios. (arXiv:2207.03183v2 [gr-qc] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2207.03183</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;By utilizing the thin shell approximation, we investigate the behavior of
radial timelike geodesics in a black hole to white hole bouncing scenario with
a mass (de-)amplification relation. We show that those geodesics lose energy
after crossing the transition surface if the white hole mass is less than the
black hole mass and vice versa. That is, the bounded timelike radial geodesics
become closer to the event horizon in the mass decreasing direction. We then
show that by tracing a finite amount of bouncing cycles along the mass
decreasing direction, all bounded radial geodesics can be squeezed into the
range of the stretched horizon while the black hole and white hole are still
massive. Those highly squeezed geodesics are problematic since there exists a
Planck-scale blueshift between them and the regular infalling trajectories. We
also discuss the possible implication and rescues.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Hong_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Deog Ki Hong&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Lin_W/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Wei-Chen Lin&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Yeom_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Dong-han Yeom&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2207.10658">
<title>Local Dirac energy decay in the 5D Myers-Perry geometry using an integral spectral representation for the Dirac propagator. (arXiv:2207.10658v3 [gr-qc] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2207.10658</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We consider the massive Dirac equation in the exterior region of the
5-dimensional Myers-Perry black hole. Using the resulting ODEs obtained from
the separation of variables of the Dirac equation, we construct an integral
spectral representation for the solution of the Cauchy problem with compactly
supported smooth initial data. We then prove that the probability of presence
of a Dirac particle to be in any compact region of space decays to zero as
$t\to\infty$, in analogy with the case of the Dirac operator in the Kerr-Newman
geometry.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Wang_Q/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Qiu Shi Wang&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2208.11982">
<title>Island on codimension-two branes in AdS/dCFT. (arXiv:2208.11982v2 [hep-th] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2208.11982</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The previous studies of the island and double holography mainly focus on
codimension-one branes. This paper explores the island on the codimension-two
brane in AdS/dCFT. The codimension-two brane is closely related to conical
singularity, which is very different from the codimension-one brane. We analyze
the mass spectrum of gravitons on the codimension-two brane and find that the
larger the brane tension is, the smaller the gravitational mass is. The
massless mode is forbidden by either the boundary or normalization conditions.
We prove that the first massive gravitational mode is located on the
codimension-two brane; the larger the tension, the better the localization. It
is similar to the case of codimension-one brane and builds an excellent
physical foundation for the study of black hole evolution on codimension-two
branes. We find that the Page curve of eternal black holes can be recovered due
to the island ending on the codimension-two brane. The new feature is that the
extremal surface passing the horizon cannot be defined after some finite time
in the no-island phase. Fortunately, this unusual situation does not affect the
Page curve since it happens after Page time.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Hu_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Peng-Ju Hu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Li_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Dongqi Li&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Miao_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Rong-Xin Miao&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.00492">
<title>Properties of a proposed background independent exact renormalization group. (arXiv:2210.00492v2 [hep-th] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.00492</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We explore the properties of a recently proposed background independent exact
renormalization group approach to gauge theories and gravity. In the process we
also develop the machinery needed to study it rigorously. The proposal comes
with some advantages. It preserves gauge invariance manifestly, avoids
introducing unphysical fields, such as ghosts and Pauli-Villars fields, and
does not require gauge-fixing. However, we show that in the simple case of
SU(N) Yang-Mills it does not completely regularise the longitudinal part of
vertex functions already at one loop, invalidating certain methods for
extracting universal components. Moreover we demonstrate a kind of no-go
theorem: within the proposed structure, whatever choice is made for
covariantisation and cutoff profiles, the two-point vertex flow equation at one
loop cannot be both transverse, as required by gauge invariance, and fully
regularised.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Mandric_V/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Vlad-Mihai Mandric&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Morris_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Tim R. Morris&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.00906">
<title>Correspondence from renormalized frequency to heat capacity caused by anharmonic oscillations in diatomic molecules. (arXiv:2210.00906v3 [cond-mat.stat-mech] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.00906</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Anharmonicity plays important roles in distant areas, in classical mechanics
in which it exhibits renormalization of the bare frequency, and in statistical
mechanics in which the simplest situation is that it causes a correction to the
vibrational contribution of the heat capacity of an ideal gas composed of
diatomic molecules, and in $ {\phi}^4 $ model in quantum field theory and
various anharmonic effects in condensed matter physics, etc. A novel two-to-one
correspondence is identified from the renormalized frequencies of anharmonic
oscillations in diatomic molecules to the heat capacity corrections for an
ideal gas of the diatomic molecules. When the frequency and the heat capacity
are expressed in perturbative series, respective, in terms of the
characteristic quantities in mechanics and thermal physics, the expansion
coefficients are essentially defined by the renormalization of the bare
frequency, and two expansion coefficients in former corresponds to one in the
latter.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Liu_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Y. T. Liu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Zhong_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Y. Zhong&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Zhang_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;J. H. Zhang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Liu_Q/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Q. H. Liu&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.02431">
<title>Black hole thermodynamics from logotropic fluids. (arXiv:2210.02431v2 [gr-qc] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.02431</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We show that Einstein&apos;s field equations with a negative cosmological constant
can admit black hole solutions whose thermodynamics coincides with that of
logotropic fluids, recently investigated to heal some cosmological and
astrophysical issues. For this purpose, we adopt the Anton-Schmidt equation of
state, which represents a generalized version of logotropic fluids. We thus
propose a general treatment to obtain an asymptotic anti-de Sitter metric,
reproducing the thermodynamic properties of both Anton-Schmidt and logotropic
fluids. Hence, we explore how to construct suitable spacetime functions,
invoking an event horizon and fulfilling the null, weak, strong and dominant
energy conditions. We further relax the strong energy condition to search for
possible additional solutions. Finally, we discuss the optical properties
related to a specific class of metrics and show how to construct an effective
refractive index depending on the spacetime functions and the thermodynamic
quantities of the fluid under study. We also explore possible departures with
respect to the case without the fluid.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Capozziello_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Salvatore Capozziello&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+DAgostino_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Rocco D&amp;#x27;Agostino&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Lapponi_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Alessio Lapponi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Luongo_O/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Orlando Luongo&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.07698">
<title>Multisymplectic Constraint Analysis of Scalar Field Theories, Chern-Simons Gravity, and Bosonic String Theory. (arXiv:2210.07698v2 [math-ph] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.07698</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The (pre)multisymplectic geometry of the De Donder--Weyl formalism for field
theories is further developed for a variety of field theories including a
scalar field theory from the canonical Klein-Gordon action, the electric and
magnetic Carrollian scalar field theories, bosonic string theory from the
Nambu-Goto action, and $2+1$ gravity as a Chern-Simons theory. The Lagrangians
for the scalar field theories and for $2+1$ Chern-Simons gravity are found to
be singular in the De Donder--Weyl sense while the Nambu-Goto Lagrangian is
found to be regular. Furthermore, the constraint structure of the
premultisymplectic phase spaces of singular field theories is explained and
applied to these theories. Finally, it is studied how symmetries are developed
on the multisymplectic phase spaces in the presence of constraints.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math-ph/1/au:+Gomis_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Joaquim Gomis&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math-ph/1/au:+Guerra_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Arnoldo Guerra IV&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math-ph/1/au:+Roman_Roy_N/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Narciso Rom&amp;#xe1;n-Roy&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.09457">
<title>Pseudo Entropy in dS/CFT and Time-like Entanglement Entropy. (arXiv:2210.09457v2 [hep-th] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.09457</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We study holographic entanglement entropy in dS/CFT and introduce time-like
entanglement entropy in CFTs. Both of them take complex values in general and
are related with each other via an analytical continuation. We argue that they
are correctly understood as pseudo entropy. We find that the imaginary part of
pseudo entropy implies an emergence of time in dS/CFT.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Doi_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Kazuki Doi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Harper_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jonathan Harper&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Mollabashi_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ali Mollabashi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Takayanagi_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Tadashi Takayanagi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Taki_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yusuke Taki&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.10891">
<title>Covariantly Constant Anomalies on Conformal Manifolds. (arXiv:2210.10891v2 [hep-th] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.10891</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Operators with integer scaling dimensions in even-dimensional conformal field
theories exhibit well-known type-B Weyl anomalies. In general, these anomalies
depend non-trivially on exactly marginal couplings. We study the corresponding
fully covariantised anomaly functional on conformal manifolds in several
examples. We show that a natural consequence of the Wess-Zumino consistency
condition is that the anomalies are covariantly constant with respect to the
exactly marginal couplings. The argument is general and applies even when the
conformal symmetry is spontaneously broken on moduli spaces of vacua.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Andriolo_E/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Enrico Andriolo&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Niarchos_V/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Vasilis Niarchos&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Papageorgakis_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Constantinos Papageorgakis&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Pomoni_E/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Elli Pomoni&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01099">
<title>Unitarity Problem in Gribov-Zwanziger Theory. (arXiv:2211.01099v2 [hep-th] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01099</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We show that the unitarity problem in the Gribov-Zwanziger theory can be
solved by the famous quartet mechanism. The construction of the new quartet in
such a theory suggests the introduction of a new form of ghost charge and
projection operator
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Sainapha_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Thitipat Sainapha&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Kondo_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Kei-Ichi Kondo&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01130">
<title>Unimodular gravity and the gauge/gravity duality. (arXiv:2211.01130v2 [hep-th] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01130</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Unimodular gravity can be formulated so that transverse diffeomorphisms and
Weyl transformations are symmetries of the theory. For this formulation of
unimodular gravity, we work out the two-point and three-point $h_{\mu\nu}$
contributions to the on-shell classical gravity action in the leading
approximation and for an Euclidean AdS background. We conclude that these
contributions do not agree with those obtained by using General Relativity due
to IR divergent contact terms. The subtraction of these IR divergent terms
yields the same IR finite result for both unimodular gravity and General
Relativity. Equivalence between unimodular gravity and General Relativity with
regard to the gauge/gravity duality thus emerges in a non trivial way.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Anero_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jesus Anero&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Martin_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Carmelo P. Martin&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.16304">
<title>Fermi Surface Symmetric Mass Generation. (arXiv:2210.16304v1 [cond-mat.str-el] CROSS LISTED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.16304</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Symmetric mass generation is a novel mechanism to give gapless fermions a
mass gap by non-perturbative interactions without generating any fermion
bilinear condensation. The previous studies of symmetric mass generation have
been limited to Dirac/Weyl/Majorana fermions with zero Fermi volume in the free
fermion limit. In this work, we generalize the concept of symmetric mass
generation to Fermi liquid with a finite Fermi volume and discuss how to gap
out the Fermi surfaces by interactions without breaking the U(1) loop group
symmetry or developing topological orders. We provide examples of Fermi surface
symmetric mass generation in both (1+1)D and (2+1)D Fermi liquid systems when
several Fermi surfaces together cancel the Fermi surface anomaly. However, the
U(1) loop group symmetry in these cases is still restrictive enough to rule out
all possible fermion bilinear gapping terms, such that a non-perturbative
interaction mechanism is the only way to gap out the Fermi surfaces. This
symmetric Fermi surface reconstruction is in contrast to the conventional
symmetry-breaking mechanism to gap the Fermi surfaces. As a side product, our
model provides a pristine 1D lattice regularization for the (1+1)D U(1)
symmetric chiral fermion model (e.g., the 3-4-5-0 model) by utilizing a lattice
translation symmetry as an emergent U(1) symmetry at low energy. This opens up
the opportunity for efficient numerical simulations of chiral fermions in their
own dimensions without introducing mirror fermions under the domain wall
fermion construction.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Lu_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Da-Chuan Lu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Zeng_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Meng Zeng&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Wang_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Juven Wang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+You_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yi-Zhuang You&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01268">
<title>On the Role of Fiducial Structures in Minisuperspace Reduction and Quantum Fluctuations in LQC. (arXiv:2211.01268v1 [gr-qc] CROSS LISTED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01268</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We study the homogeneous minisuperspace reduction within the canonical
framework for a scalar field theory and gravity. Symmetry reduction is
implemented via second class constraints for the field modes over a
partitioning of the non-compact spatial slice $\Sigma$ into disjoint cells. The
canonical structure of the resulting homogeneous theories is obtained via the
associated Dirac bracket which can only be defined on a finite number of cells
homogeneously patched together and agrees with the full theory Poisson bracket
for the averaged fields. This identifies a finite region $V_o$, the fiducial
cell, whose size $L$ sets the physical scale over which homogeneity is imposed,
namely a wavelength cutoff. The reduced theory results from 1) selecting a
subset of $V_o$-averaged observables of the full theory; 2) neglecting
inhomogeneous $\vec k\neq\mathbf0$ modes with wavelengths $\lambda\geq L$ and
$\lambda&amp;lt; L$; 3) neglecting boundary terms encoding interactions between
neighbouring cells. The error made is of order $\mathcal O(1/kL)$. As a result,
the off-shell structures of the reduced theory depend on the size of $V_o$ and
different $V_o$ identify canonically inequivalent theories whose dynamics
though is $V_o$-independent. Their quantisation leads then to a family of
$V_o$-labeled quantum representations and the quantum version of an active
rescaling of $V_o$ is implemented via a suitable dynamics-preserving
isomorphism between the different theories. We discuss the consequences for
statistical moments, fluctuations, and semiclassical states in both a standard
and polymer quantisation. For a scalar field of mass $m$, we also sketch the
quantum reduction and identify a subsector of the QFT where the results of
the&quot;first reduced, then quantised&quot; theories can be reproduced with good
approximation as long as $m\gg1/L$. Finally, a strategy to include
inhomogeneities in cosmology is outlined.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Mele_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Fabio M. Mele&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Munch_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Johannes M&amp;#xfc;nch&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
</rdf:RDF>