<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<rdf:RDF
 xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
 xmlns="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/"
 xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
 xmlns:taxo="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/taxonomy/"
 xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
 xmlns:syn="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
 xmlns:admin="http://webns.net/mvcb/"
>

<channel rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/">
<title>cs.NA updates on arXiv.org</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">Computer Science -- Numerical Analysis (cs.NA) updates on the arXiv.org e-print archive</description>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:date>2022-11-03T20:30:00-05:00</dc:date>
<dc:publisher>help@arxiv.org</dc:publisher>
<dc:subject>Computer Science -- Numerical Analysis</dc:subject>
<syn:updateBase>1901-01-01T00:00+00:00</syn:updateBase>
<syn:updateFrequency>1</syn:updateFrequency>
<syn:updatePeriod>daily</syn:updatePeriod>
<items>
 <rdf:Seq>
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01462" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01499" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01531" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01554" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01648" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01804" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01926" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01967" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01973" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01974" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.02018" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/1804.02128" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2001.01075" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2006.05551" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2108.02465" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2110.09854" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2111.02208" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2201.03236" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2202.05652" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2208.13772" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2209.05279" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.01123" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.05164" />
 </rdf:Seq>
</items>
<image rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif" />
</channel>
<image rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif">
<title>arXiv.org</title>
<url>http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif</url>
<link>http://arxiv.org/</link>
</image>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01462">
<title>Drift approximation by the modified Boris algorithm of charged-particle dynamics in toroidal geometry. (arXiv:2211.01462v1 [math.NA])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01462</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;In this paper, we study the charged-particle dynamics under strong magnetic
field in a toroidal axi-symmetric geometry. Using modulated Fourier expansions
of the exact and numerical solutions, the long-term drift motion of the exact
solution in toroidal geometry is derived and the error analysis of the
large-stepsize modified Boris algorithm over long time scales is provided.
Numerical experiments illustrate the theoretical results.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Shi_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yanyan Shi&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01499">
<title>Angle-free cluster robust Ritz value bounds for restarted block eigensolvers. (arXiv:2211.01499v1 [math.NA])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01499</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Convergence rates of block iterations for solving eigenvalue problems
typically measure errors of Ritz values approximating eigenvalues. The errors
of the Ritz values are commonly bounded in terms of principal angles between
the initial or iterative subspace and the invariant subspace associated with
the target eigenvalues. Such bounds thus cannot be applied repeatedly as needed
for restarted block eigensolvers, since the left- and right-hand sides of the
bounds use different terms. They must be combined with additional bounds which
could cause an overestimation. Alternative repeatable bounds that are
angle-free and depend only on the errors of the Ritz values have been pioneered
for Hermitian eigenvalue problems in doi:10.1515/rnam.1987.2.5.371 but only for
a single extreme Ritz value. We extend this result to all Ritz values and
achieve robustness for clustered eigenvalues by utilizing nonconsecutive
eigenvalues. Our new bounds cover the restarted block Lanczos method and its
modifications with shift-and-invert and deflation, and are numerically
advantageous.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Zhou_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ming Zhou&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Knyazev_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Andrew V. Knyazev&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Neymeyr_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Klaus Neymeyr&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01531">
<title>Adaptive sparse grid discontinuous Galerkin method: review and software implementation. (arXiv:2211.01531v1 [math.NA])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01531</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;This paper reviews the adaptive sparse grid discontinuous Galerkin (aSG-DG)
method for computing high dimensional partial differential equations (PDEs) and
its software implementation. The C\texttt{++} software package called AdaM-DG,
implementing the aSG-DG method, is available on Github at
\url{https://github.com/JuntaoHuang/adaptive-multiresolution-DG}. The package
is capable of treating a large class of high dimensional linear and nonlinear
PDEs. We review the essential components of the algorithm and the functionality
of the software, including the multiwavelets used, assembling of bilinear
operators, fast matrix-vector product for data with hierarchical structures. We
further demonstrate the performance of the package by reporting numerical error
and CPU cost for several benchmark test, including linear transport equations,
wave equations and Hamilton-Jacobi equations.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Huang_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Juntao Huang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Guo_W/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Wei Guo&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Cheng_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yingda Cheng&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01554">
<title>Embed and Emulate: Learning to estimate parameters of dynamical systems with uncertainty quantification. (arXiv:2211.01554v1 [cs.LG])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01554</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;This paper explores learning emulators for parameter estimation with
uncertainty estimation of high-dimensional dynamical systems. We assume access
to a computationally complex simulator that inputs a candidate parameter and
outputs a corresponding multichannel time series. Our task is to accurately
estimate a range of likely values of the underlying parameters. Standard
iterative approaches necessitate running the simulator many times, which is
computationally prohibitive. This paper describes a novel framework for
learning feature embeddings of observed dynamics jointly with an emulator that
can replace high-cost simulators for parameter estimation. Leveraging a
contrastive learning approach, our method exploits intrinsic data properties
within and across parameter and trajectory domains. On a coupled
396-dimensional multiscale Lorenz 96 system, our method significantly
outperforms a typical parameter estimation method based on predefined metrics
and a classical numerical simulator, and with only 1.19% of the baseline&apos;s
computation time. Ablation studies highlight the potential of explicitly
designing learned emulators for parameter estimation by leveraging contrastive
learning.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Jiang_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ruoxi Jiang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Willett_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Rebecca Willett&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01648">
<title>A Scharfetter-Gummerl stabilization scheme for HDG approximations of convection-diffusion problems. (arXiv:2211.01648v1 [math.NA])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01648</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We present a Scharfetter-Gummel (SG) stabilization scheme for high-order
Hybrid Discontinuous Galerkin (HDG) approximations of convection-diffusion
problems. The scheme is based on a careful choice of the stabilization
parameters used to define the numerical flux in the HDG method. We show that,
in one dimension, the SG-HDG scheme is equivalent to the Finite Volume method
stabilized with the Scharfetter--Gummel on the dual grid, for all orders of HDG
schemes.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Piani_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Stefano Piani&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Heltai_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Luca Heltai&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Lei_W/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Wenyu Lei&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01804">
<title>Wasserstein Steepest Descent Flows of Discrepancies with Riesz Kernels. (arXiv:2211.01804v1 [math.OC])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01804</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The aim of this paper is twofold. Based on the geometric Wasserstein tangent
space, we first introduce Wasserstein steepest descent flows. These are locally
absolutely continuous curves in the Wasserstein space whose tangent vectors
point into a steepest descent direction of a given functional. This allows the
use of Euler forward schemes instead of the minimizing movement scheme (MMS)
introduced by Jordan, Kinderlehrer, and Otto. The MMS finds Wasserstein
gradient flows by successively computing Wasserstein proxies. For locally
Lipschitz continuous functionals which are $\lambda$-convex along generalized
geodesics, we show that there exists a unique Wasserstein steepest descent flow
coinciding with the Wasserstein gradient flow.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second aim is to study Wasserstein flows of the (maximum mean)
discrepancy with respect to Riesz kernels. The crucial part is hereby the
treatment of the interaction energy. Although it is not $\lambda$-convex along
generalized geodesics, we give analytic expressions for Wasserstein steepest
descent flows of the interaction energy starting at Dirac measures. In contrast
to smooth kernels, the particle may explode, i.e., the particle goes over to
non-Dirac measures. The computation of steepest descent flows amounts to
finding equilibrium measures with external fields, which nicely links
Wasserstein flows of interaction energies with potential theory. Furthermore,
we prove convergence of MMS to our Wasserstein steepest descent flows. Finally,
we provide analytic Wasserstein steepest descent flows of discrepancies in one
dimension and numerical simulations in two and three dimensions showing
relations to interaction energy flows.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Hertrich_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Johannes Hertrich&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Graf_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Manuel Gr&amp;#xe4;f&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Beinert_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Robert Beinert&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Steidl_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Gabriele Steidl&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01926">
<title>Swelling-induced pattern transformations of periodic hydrogels -- from the wrinkling of internal surfaces to the buckling of thin films. (arXiv:2211.01926v1 [math.NA])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01926</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We investigate pattern transformations of periodic hydrogel systems that are
triggered by swelling-induced structural instabilities. The types of
microstructures considered in the present work include single-phase and
two-phase voided hydrogel structures as well as reinforced hydrogel thin films.
While the observed transformations of the single-phase structures show good
agreement with experimental findings, the two-phase materials provide novel
patterns associated with wrinkling of internal surfaces. Furthermore, an
extensive parametric study on the reinforced hydrogel thin films reveals new
opportunities for the design of complex out-of-plane surface modes caused by
swelling-induced instabilities. Next to the mentioned buckling-type
instabilities, we encountered the development of micro-creases at the internal
surfaces of periodic media before the loss of strong ellipticity of effective
moduli.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Polukhov_E/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Elten Polukhov&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Pytel_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Laura Pytel&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Keip_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Marc-Andre Keip&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01967">
<title>On a Calder\&apos;on preconditioner for the symmetric formulation of the electroencephalography forward problem without barycentric refinements. (arXiv:2211.01967v1 [math.NA])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01967</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We present a Calder\&apos;on preconditioning scheme for the symmetric formulation
of the forward electroencephalographic (EEG) problem that cures both the dense
discretization and the high-contrast breakdown. Unlike existing Calder\&apos;on
schemes presented for the EEG problem, it is refinement-free, that is, the
electrostatic integral operators are not discretized with basis functions
defined on the barycentrically-refined dual mesh. In fact, in the
preconditioner, we reuse the original system matrix thus reducing computational
burden. Moreover, the proposed formulation gives rise to a symmetric,
positive-definite system of linear equations, which allows the application of
the conjugate gradient method, an iterative method that exhibits a smaller
computational cost compared to other Krylov subspace methods applicable to
non-symmetric problems. Numerical results corroborate the theoretical analysis
and attest of the efficacy of the proposed preconditioning technique on both
canonical and realistic scenarios.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Giunzioni_V/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Viviana Giunzioni&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+G%2E_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;John E. Ortiz G.&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Merlini_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Adrien Merlini&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Adrian_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Simon B. Adrian&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Andriulli_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Francesco P. Andriulli&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01973">
<title>On the invariant region for compressible Euler equations with a general equation of state. (arXiv:2211.01973v1 [math.AP])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01973</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The state space for solutions of the compressible Euler equations with a
general equation of state is examined. An arbitrary equation of state is
allowed, subject only to the physical requirements of thermodynamics. An
invariant region of the resulting Euler system is identified and the convexity
property of this region is justified by using only very minimal thermodynamical
assumptions. Finally, we show how an invariant-region-preserving (IRP) limiter
can be constructed for use in high order finite-volume type schemes to solve
the compressible Euler equations with a general constitutive relation.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Liu_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Hailiang Liu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Thein_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ferdinand Thein&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01974">
<title>Discrete approximations to Dirichlet and Neumann Laplacians on a half-space and norm resolvent convergence. (arXiv:2211.01974v1 [math.FA])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01974</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We extend recent results on discrete approximations of the Laplacian in
$\mathbf{R}^d$ with norm resolvent convergence to the corresponding results for
Dirichlet and Neumann Laplacians on a half-space. The resolvents of the
discrete Dirichlet/Neumann Laplacians are embedded into the continuum using
natural discretization and embedding operators. Norm resolvent convergence to
their continuous counterparts is proven with a quadratic rate in the mesh size.
These results generalize with a limited rate to also include operators with a
real, bounded, and H\&quot;older continuous potential, as well as certain functions
of the Dirichlet/Neumann Laplacians, including any positive real power.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Cornean_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Horia Cornean&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Garde_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Henrik Garde&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Jensen_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Arne Jensen&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.02018">
<title>A unconditionally energy dissipative, adaptive IMEX BDF2 scheme and its error estimates for Cahn-Hilliard equation on generalized SAV approach. (arXiv:2211.02018v1 [math.NA])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.02018</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;An adaptive implicit-explicit (IMEX) BDF2 scheme is investigated on
generalized SAV approach for the Cahn-Hilliard equation by combining with
Fourier spectral method in space. It is proved that the modified energy
dissipation law is unconditionally preserved at discrete levels. Under a mild
ratio restriction, i.e., \Ass{1}: $0&amp;lt;r_k:=\tau_k/\tau_{k-1}&amp;lt; r_{\max}\approx
4.8645$, we establish a rigorous error estimate in $H^1$-norm and achieve
optimal second-order accuracy in time. The proof involves the tools of discrete
orthogonal convolution (DOC) kernels and inequality zoom. It is worth noting
that the presented adaptive time-step scheme only requires solving one linear
system with constant coefficients at each time step. In our analysis, the
first-consistent BDF1 for the first step does not bring the order reduction in
$H^1$-norm. The $H^1$ bound of the numerical solution under periodic boundary
conditions can be derived without any restriction (such as zero mean of the
initial data). Finally, numerical examples are provided to verify our
theoretical analysis and the algorithm efficiency.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Wei_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yifan Wei&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Zhang_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jiwei Zhang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Zhao_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Chengchao Zhao&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Zhao_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yanmin Zhao&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/1804.02128">
<title>The Numerical Invariant Measure of Stochastic Differential Equations With Markovian Switching. (arXiv:1804.02128v2 [math.PR] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/1804.02128</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The existence and uniqueness of the numerical invariant measure of the
backward Euler-Maruyama method for stochastic differential equations with
Markovian switching is yielded, and it is revealed that the numerical invariant
measure converges to the underlying invariant measure in the Wasserstein
metric. Under the polynomial growth condition of drift term the convergence
rate is estimated. The global Lipschitz condition on the drift coefficients
required by Bao et al., 2016 and Yuan et al., 2005 is released. Several
examples and numerical experiments are given to verify our theory.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Li_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xiaoyue Li&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Ma_Q/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Qianlin Ma&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Yang_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Hongfu Yang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Yuan_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Chenggui Yuan&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2001.01075">
<title>Finite Difference/Galerkin Finite Element Simulation of the Semi-Linear Wave Equation with Scale-Invariant Damping and Mass and Power Non-Linearity. (arXiv:2001.01075v2 [math.NA] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2001.01075</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;This study is concern with the numerical solution of the initial boundary
value problem (IBVP) for the semilinear scale-invariant wave equation with
damping and mass and power non-linearity. Numerical results of the
aforementioned IBVP is obtained by using standart Galerkin finite element
method (GFEM) for the spatial variable and the temporal variable is discretized
with the finite difference method (FDM). The FDM is also used for the
discretization of the spatial variable for the accuracy of the numerical
results. The obtained numerical results with different numerical schemes are
observed compatible. Numerical simulation of the considered problem is given
for the different initial conditions.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Selvitopi_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Harun Selvitopi&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2006.05551">
<title>Recursive moment computation in Filon methods and application to high-frequency wave scattering in two dimensions. (arXiv:2006.05551v2 [math.NA] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2006.05551</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We study the efficient approximation of highly oscillatory integrals using
Filon methods. A crucial step in the implementation of these methods is the
accurate and fast computation of the Filon quadrature moments. In this work we
demonstrate how recurrences can be constructed for a wide class of oscillatory
kernel functions, based on the observation that many physically relevant kernel
functions are in the null space of a linear differential operator whose action
on the Filon interpolation basis is represented by a banded (infinite) matrix.
We discuss in further detail the application to two classes of particular
interest, integrals with algebraic singularities and stationary points and
integrals involving a Hankel function. We provide rigorous stability results
for the moment computation for the first of these classes and demonstrate how
the corresponding Filon method results in an accurate approximation at truly
frequency-independent cost. For the Hankel kernel, we derive error estimates
which describe the convergence behaviour of the method in terms of frequency
and number of Filon quadrature points. Finally, we show how Filon methods with
recursive moment computation can be applied to compute efficiently integrals
arising in hybrid numerical-asymptotic collocation methods for high-frequency
wave scattering on a screen.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Maierhofer_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;G. Maierhofer&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Iserles_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;A. Iserles&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Peake_N/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;N. Peake&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2108.02465">
<title>On Regularization via Frame Decompositions with Applications in Tomography. (arXiv:2108.02465v4 [math.NA] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2108.02465</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;In this paper, we consider linear ill-posed problems in Hilbert spaces and
their regularization via frame decompositions, which are generalizations of the
singular-value decomposition. In particular, we prove convergence for a general
class of continuous regularization methods and derive convergence rates under
both a-priori and a-posteriori parameter choice rules. Furthermore, we apply
our derived results to a standard tomography problem based on the Radon
transform.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Hubmer_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Simon Hubmer&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Ramlau_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ronny Ramlau&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Weissinger_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Lukas Weissinger&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2110.09854">
<title>A New Extension of Chubanov&apos;s Method to Symmetric Cones. (arXiv:2110.09854v3 [math.OC] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2110.09854</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We propose a new variant of Chubanov&apos;s method for solving the feasibility
problem over the symmetric cone by extending Roos&apos;s method (2018) of solving
the feasibility problem over the nonnegative orthant. The proposed method
considers a feasibility problem associated with a norm induced by the maximum
eigenvalue of an element and uses a rescaling focusing on the upper bound for
the sum of eigenvalues of any feasible solution to the problem. Its
computational bound is (i) equivalent to that of Roos&apos;s original method (2018)
and superior to that of Louren\c{c}o et al.&apos;s method (2019) when the symmetric
cone is the nonnegative orthant, (ii) superior to that of Louren\c{c}o et al.&apos;s
method (2019) when the symmetric cone is a Cartesian product of second-order
cones, (iii) equivalent to that of Louren\c{c}o et al.&apos;s method (2019) when the
symmetric cone is the simple positive semidefinite cone, and (iv) superior to
that of Pena and Soheili&apos;s method (2017) for any simple symmetric cones under
the feasibility assumption of the problem imposed in Pena and Soheili&apos;s method
(2017). We also conduct numerical experiments that compare the performance of
our method with existing methods by generating instances in three types:
strongly (but ill-conditioned) feasible instances, weakly feasible instances,
and infeasible instances. For any of these instances, the proposed method is
rather more efficient than the existing methods in terms of accuracy and
execution time.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Kanoh_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Shin-ichi Kanoh&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Yoshise_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Akiko Yoshise&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2111.02208">
<title>On role extraction for digraphs via neighbourhood pattern similarity. (arXiv:2111.02208v3 [math.NA] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2111.02208</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We analyse the recovery of different roles in a network modelled by a
directed graph, based on the so-called Neighbourhood Pattern Similarity
approach. Our analysis uses results from random matrix theory to show that when
assuming the graph is generated as a particular Stochastic Block Model with
Bernoulli probability distributions for the different blocks, then the recovery
is asymptotically correct when the graph has a sufficiently large dimension.
Under these assumptions there is a sufficient gap between the dominant and
dominated eigenvalues of the similarity matrix, which guarantees the asymptotic
correct identification of the number of different roles. We also comment on the
connections with the literature on Stochastic Block Models, including the case
of probabilities of order log(n)/n where n is the graph size. We provide
numerical experiments to assess the effectiveness of the method when applied to
practical networks of finite size.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Barbarino_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Giovanni Barbarino&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Noferini_V/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Vanni Noferini&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Dooren_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Paul Van Dooren&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2201.03236">
<title>Projection based semi--implicit partitioned Reduced Basis Method for non parametrized and parametrized Fluid--Structure Interaction problems. (arXiv:2201.03236v2 [math.NA] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2201.03236</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We present a partitioned Model Order Reduction method for multiphysics
problems, that is based on a semi-implicit treatment of the coupling
conditions, and on a projection scheme. The proposed Reduced Order Method is
based on the Proper Orthogonal Decomposition and on a Galerkin projection onto
the reduced basis spaces; we aim of addressing both time-dependent and
time-dependent, parametrized Fluid-Structure Interaction problems, where the
fluid is incompressible and the structure is linear, elastic and two
dimensional.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Nonino_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Monica Nonino&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Ballarin_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Francesco Ballarin&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Rozza_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Gianluigi Rozza&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Maday_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yvon Maday&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2202.05652">
<title>Numerical schemes for a multi-species BGK model with velocity-dependent collision frequency. (arXiv:2202.05652v2 [math.NA] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2202.05652</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We consider a kinetic description of a multi-species gas mixture modeled with
Bhatnagar-Gross-Krook (BGK) collision operators, in which the collision
frequency varies not only in time and space but also with the microscopic
velocity. In this model, the Maxwellians typically used in standard BGK
operators are replaced by a generalization of such target functions, which are
defined by a variational procedure \cite{&lt;a href=&quot;/abs/2101.09047&quot;&gt;arXiv:2101.09047&lt;/a&gt;}. In this paper we
present a numerical method for simulating this model, which uses an
Implicit-Explicit (IMEX) scheme to minimize a certain potential function,
mimicking the Lagrange functional that appears in the theoretical derivation.
We show that theoretical properties such as conservation of mass, total
momentum and total energy as well as positivity of the distribution functions
are preserved by the numerical method, and illustrate its usefulness and
effectiveness with numerical examples.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Haack_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jeffrey Haack&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Hauck_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Cory Hauck&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Klingenberg_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Christian Klingenberg&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Pirner_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Marlies Pirner&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Warnecke_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Sandra Warnecke&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2208.13772">
<title>Computing committors via Mahalanobis diffusion maps with enhanced sampling data. (arXiv:2208.13772v2 [physics.comp-ph] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2208.13772</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The study of phenomena such as protein folding and conformational changes in
molecules is a central theme in chemical physics. Molecular dynamics (MD)
simulation is the primary tool for the study of transition processes in
biomolecules, but it is hampered by a huge timescale gap between the processes
of interest and atomic vibrations which dictate the time step size. Therefore,
it is imperative to combine MD simulations with other techniques in order to
quantify the transition processes taking place on large timescales. In this
work, the diffusion map with Mahalanobis kernel, a meshless approach for
approximating the Backward Kolmogorov Operator (BKO) in collective variables,
is upgraded to incorporate standard enhanced sampling techniques such as
metadynamics. The resulting algorithm, which we call the &quot;target measure
Mahalanobis diffusion map&quot; (tm-mmap), is suitable for a moderate number of
collective variables in which one can approximate the diffusion tensor and free
energy. Imposing appropriate boundary conditions allows use of the approximated
BKO to solve for the committor function and utilization of transition path
theory to find the reactive current delineating the transition channels and the
transition rate. The proposed algorithm, tm-mmap, is tested on the
two-dimensional Moro-Cardin two-well system with position-dependent diffusion
coefficient and on alanine dipeptide in two collective variables where the
committor, the reactive current, and the transition rate are compared to those
computed by the finite element method (FEM). Finally, tm-mmap is applied to
alanine dipeptide in four collective variables where the use of finite elements
is infeasible.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Evans_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Luke Evans&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Cameron_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Maria K. Cameron&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Tiwary_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Pratyush Tiwary&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2209.05279">
<title>Data assimilation: A dynamic homotopy-based coupling approach. (arXiv:2209.05279v2 [math.NA] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2209.05279</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Homotopy approaches to Bayesian inference have found widespread use
especially if the Kullback-Leibler divergence between the prior and the
posterior distribution is large. Here we extend one of these homotopy approach
to include an underlying stochastic diffusion process. The underlying
mathematical problem is closely related to the Schr\&quot;odinger bridge problem for
given marginal distributions. We demonstrate that the proposed homotopy
approach provides a computationally tractable approximation to the underlying
bridge problem. In particular, our implementation builds upon the widely used
ensemble Kalman filter methodology and extends it to Schr\&quot;odinger bridge
problems within the context of sequential data assimilation.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Reich_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Sebastian Reich&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.01123">
<title>Towards Learned Simulators for Cell Migration. (arXiv:2210.01123v2 [q-bio.QM] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.01123</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Simulators driven by deep learning are gaining popularity as a tool for
efficiently emulating accurate but expensive numerical simulators. Successful
applications of such neural simulators can be found in the domains of physics,
chemistry, and structural biology, amongst others. Likewise, a neural simulator
for cellular dynamics can augment lab experiments and traditional computational
methods to enhance our understanding of a cell&apos;s interaction with its physical
environment. In this work, we propose an autoregressive probabilistic model
that can reproduce spatiotemporal dynamics of single cell migration,
traditionally simulated with the Cellular Potts model. We observe that standard
single-step training methods do not only lead to inconsistent rollout
stability, but also fail to accurately capture the stochastic aspects of the
dynamics, and we propose training strategies to mitigate these issues. Our
evaluation on two proof-of-concept experimental scenarios shows that neural
methods have the potential to faithfully simulate stochastic cellular dynamics
at least an order of magnitude faster than a state-of-the-art implementation of
the Cellular Potts model.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/q-bio/1/au:+Minartz_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Koen Minartz&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/q-bio/1/au:+Poels_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yoeri Poels&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/q-bio/1/au:+Menkovski_V/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Vlado Menkovski&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.05164">
<title>Tight Error Bounds for Nonnegative Orthogonality Constraints and Exact Penalties. (arXiv:2210.05164v4 [math.OC] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.05164</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;For the intersection of the Stiefel manifold and the set of nonnegative
matrices in $\mathbb{R}^{n\times r}$, we present global and local error bounds
with easily computable residual functions and explicit coefficients. Moreover,
we show that the error bounds cannot be improved except for the coefficients,
which explains why two square-root terms are necessary in the bounds when $1 &amp;lt;
r &amp;lt; n$ for the nonnegativity and orthogonality, respectively. The error bounds
are applied to penalty methods for minimizing a Lipschitz continuous function
with nonnegative orthogonality constraints. Under only the Lipschitz continuity
of the objective function, we prove the exactness of penalty problems that
penalize the nonnegativity constraint, or the orthogonality constraint, or both
constraints. Our results cover both global and local minimizers.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Chen_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xiaojun Chen&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+He_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yifan He&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Zhang_Z/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Zaikun Zhang&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
</rdf:RDF>