<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<rdf:RDF
 xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
 xmlns="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/"
 xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
 xmlns:taxo="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/taxonomy/"
 xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
 xmlns:syn="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
 xmlns:admin="http://webns.net/mvcb/"
>

<channel rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/">
<title>math.PR updates on arXiv.org</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">Mathematics -- Probability (math.PR) updates on the arXiv.org e-print archive</description>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:date>2022-11-03T20:30:00-05:00</dc:date>
<dc:publisher>help@arxiv.org</dc:publisher>
<dc:subject>Mathematics -- Probability</dc:subject>
<syn:updateBase>1901-01-01T00:00+00:00</syn:updateBase>
<syn:updateFrequency>1</syn:updateFrequency>
<syn:updatePeriod>daily</syn:updatePeriod>
<items>
 <rdf:Seq>
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01464" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01503" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01596" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01643" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01667" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01688" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01710" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01774" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01788" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01804" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01828" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01844" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01872" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01940" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01961" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01986" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.02009" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.02032" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.02034" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/1512.02208" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/1804.02128" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2104.12716" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2105.04175" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2108.04777" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2110.12977" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2111.12403" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2201.00292" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2201.07659" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2204.08031" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2205.03095" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2207.09340" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.13121" />
 </rdf:Seq>
</items>
<image rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif" />
</channel>
<image rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif">
<title>arXiv.org</title>
<url>http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif</url>
<link>http://arxiv.org/</link>
</image>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01464">
<title>On the existence and regularity of local times. (arXiv:2211.01464v1 [math.PR])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01464</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We study the existence and regularity of local times for general
$d$-dimensional stochastic processes. We give a general condition for their
existence and regularity properties. To emphasize the contribution of our
results, we show that they include various prominent examples, among others
solutions to stochastic differential equations driven by fractional Brownian
motion, where the behavior of the local time was not fully understood up to now
and remained as an open problem in the stochastic analysis literature. In
particular this completes the picture regarding the local time behavior of such
equations, above all includes high dimensions and both large and small Hurst
parameters. As other main examples, we also show that by using our general
approach, one can quite easily cover and extend some recently obtained results
on the local times of the Rosenblatt process and Gaussian quasi-helices.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Sottinen_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Tommi Sottinen&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Sonmez_E/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ercan S&amp;#xf6;nmez&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Viitasaari_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Lauri Viitasaari&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01503">
<title>Jensen&apos;s and Cantelli&apos;s Inequalities with Imprecise Previsions. (arXiv:2211.01503v1 [math.PR])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01503</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We investigate how basic probability inequalities can be extended to an
imprecise framework, where (precise) probabilities and expectations are
replaced by imprecise probabilities and lower/upper previsions. We focus on
inequalities giving information on a single bounded random variable $X$,
considering either convex/concave functions of $X$ (Jensen&apos;s inequalities) or
one-sided bounds such as $(X\geq c)$ or $(X\leq c)$ (Markov&apos;s and Cantelli&apos;s
inequalities). As for the consistency of the relevant imprecise uncertainty
measures, our analysis considers coherence as well as weaker requirements,
notably $2$-coherence, which proves to be often sufficient. Jensen-like
inequalities are introduced, as well as a generalisation of a recent
improvement to Jensen&apos;s inequality. Some of their applications are proposed:
extensions of Lyapunov&apos;s inequality and inferential problems. After discussing
upper and lower Markov&apos;s inequalities, Cantelli-like inequalities are proven
with different degrees of consistency for the related lower/upper previsions.
In the case of coherent imprecise previsions, the corresponding Cantelli&apos;s
inequalities make use of Walley&apos;s lower and upper variances, generally ensuring
better bounds.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Pelessoni_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Renato Pelessoni&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Vicig_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Paolo Vicig&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01596">
<title>Probability bounds for $n$ random events under $(n-1)$-wise independence. (arXiv:2211.01596v1 [math.PR])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01596</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;A collection of $n$ random events is said to be $(n - 1)$-wise independent if
any $n - 1$ events among them are mutually independent. We characterise all
probability measures with respect to which $n$ random events are $(n - 1)$-wise
independent. We provide sharp upper and lower bounds on the probability that at
least $k$ out of $n$ events with given marginal probabilities occur over these
probability measures. The bounds are shown to be computable in polynomial time.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Natarajan_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Karthik Natarajan&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Ramachandra_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Arjun Kodagehalli Ramachandra&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Tan_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Colin Tan&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01643">
<title>Existence of quasi-stationary distributions for downward skip-free Markov chains. (arXiv:2211.01643v1 [math.PR])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01643</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;For downward skip-free Markov chains on non-negative integers killed at $0$,
existence of a quasi-stationary distribution is studied. Scale functions for
these processes are introduced and the boundary is classified by the
integrability of the scale function, which gives an extension of Feller&apos;s
classification of the boundary for birth-and-death processes. The existence and
the set of quasi-stationary distributions are characterized by scale functions
and the classification of the boundary.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Yamato_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Kosuke Yamato&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01667">
<title>AoI-Based Opportunistic-Fair mmWave Schedulers. (arXiv:2211.01667v1 [math.OC])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01667</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We consider a system with a Base Station (BS) and multiple mobile/stationary
users. BS uses millimeter waves (mmWaves) for data transmission and hence needs
to align beams in the directions of the end-users. The idea is to avail regular
user-position estimates, which help in accurate beam alignment towards multiple
users, paving way for opportunistic mmWave schedulers. We propose an online
algorithm that uses a dual opportunistic and fair scheduler to allocate data as
well as position-update channels, in each slot. Towards this, well-known
alpha-fair objective functions of utilities of various users, which further
depend upon the age of position-information, are optimized. We illustrate the
advantages of the opportunistic scheduler, by comparing it with the previously
proposed mmWave schemes; these schedulers choose one user in each slot and
start data transmission only after accurate beam alignment. We also discuss two
ways of introducing fairness in such schemes, both of which perform inferior to
the proposed age-based opportunistic scheduler.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Singhal_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Shiksha Singhal&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Kavitha_V/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Veeraruna Kavitha&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Ramanath_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Sreenath Ramanath&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01688">
<title>Nearly tight universal bounds for the binomial tail probabilities. (arXiv:2211.01688v1 [math.PR])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01688</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We derive simple but nearly tight upper and lower bounds for the binomial
lower tail probability (with straightforward generalization to the upper tail
probability) that apply to the whole parameter regime. These bounds are easy to
compute and are tight within a constant factor of $89/44$. Moreover, they are
asymptotically tight in the regimes of large deviation and moderate deviation.
By virtue of a surprising connection with Ramanujan&apos;s equation, we also provide
strong evidences suggesting that the lower bound is tight within a factor of
$1.26434$. It may even be regarded as the natural lower bound, given its
simplicity and appealing properties. Our bounds significantly outperform the
familiar Chernoff bound and reverse Chernoff bounds known in the literature and
may find applications in various research areas.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Zhu_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Huangjun Zhu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Li_Z/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Zihao Li&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Hayashi_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Masahito Hayashi&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01710">
<title>Bernoulli variables, classical exclusion processes and free probability. (arXiv:2211.01710v1 [math-ph])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01710</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We present a new description of the known large deviation function of the
classical symmetric simple exclusion process by exploiting its connection with
the quantum symmetric simple exclusion processes and using tools from free
probability. This may seem paradoxal as free probability usually deals with non
commutative probability while the simple exclusion process belongs to the realm
of classical probability. On the way, we give a new formula for the free energy
-- alias the logarithm of the Laplace transform of the probability distribution
-- of correlated Bernoulli variables in terms of the set of their cumulants
with non-coinciding indices. This latter result is obtained either by
developing a combinatorial approach for cumulants of products of random
variables or by borrowing techniques from Feynman graphs.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math-ph/1/au:+Bauer_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Michel Bauer&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math-ph/1/au:+Bernard_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Denis Bernard&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math-ph/1/au:+Biane_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Philippe Biane&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math-ph/1/au:+Hruza_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ludwig Hruza&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01774">
<title>Jump-Diffusion Langevin Dynamics for Multimodal Posterior Sampling. (arXiv:2211.01774v1 [stat.ML])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01774</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Bayesian methods of sampling from a posterior distribution are becoming
increasingly popular due to their ability to precisely display the uncertainty
of a model fit. Classical methods based on iterative random sampling and
posterior evaluation such as Metropolis-Hastings are known to have desirable
long run mixing properties, however are slow to converge. Gradient based
methods, such as Langevin Dynamics (and its stochastic gradient counterpart)
exhibit favorable dimension-dependence and fast mixing times for log-concave,
and &quot;close&quot; to log-concave distributions, however also have long escape times
from local minimizers. Many contemporary applications such as Bayesian Neural
Networks are both high-dimensional and highly multimodal. In this paper we
investigate the performance of a hybrid Metropolis and Langevin sampling method
akin to Jump Diffusion on a range of synthetic and real data, indicating that
careful calibration of mixing sampling jumps with gradient based chains
significantly outperforms both pure gradient-based or sampling based schemes.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/stat/1/au:+Guidolin_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jacopo Guidolin&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/stat/1/au:+Kungurtsev_V/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Vyacheslav Kungurtsev&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/stat/1/au:+Kuzelka_O/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ond&amp;#x159;ej Ku&amp;#x17e;elka&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01788">
<title>Common Information, Noise Stability, and Their Extensions. (arXiv:2211.01788v1 [cs.IT])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01788</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Common information (CI) is ubiquitous in information theory and related areas
such as theoretical computer science and discrete probability. However, because
there are multiple notions of CI, a unified understanding of the deep
interconnections between them is lacking. This monograph seeks to fill this gap
by leveraging a small set of mathematical techniques that are applicable across
seemingly disparate problems.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Part I, we review the operational tasks and properties associated with
Wyner&apos;s and G\&apos;acs-K\&quot;orner-Witsenhausen&apos;s (GKW&apos;s) CI. In PartII, we discuss
extensions of the former from the perspective of distributed source simulation.
This includes the R\&apos;enyi CI which forms a bridge between Wyner&apos;s CI and the
exact CI. Via a surprising equivalence between the R\&apos;enyi CI of order~$\infty$
and the exact CI, we demonstrate the existence of a joint source in which the
exact CI strictly exceeds Wyner&apos;s CI. Other closely related topics discussed in
Part II include the channel synthesis problem and the connection of Wyner&apos;s and
exact CI to the nonnegative rank of matrices.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Part III, we examine GKW&apos;s CI with a more refined lens via the noise
stability or NICD problem in which we quantify the agreement probability of
extracted bits from a bivariate source. We then extend this to the $k$-user
NICD and $q$-stability problems, and discuss various conjectures in information
theory and discrete probability, such as the Courtade-Kumar, Li-M\&apos;edard and
Mossell-O&apos;Donnell conjectures. Finally, we consider hypercontractivity and
Brascamp-Lieb inequalities, which further generalize noise stability via
replacing the Boolean functions therein by nonnnegative functions. The key
ideas behind the proofs in Part III can be presented in a pedagogically
coherent manner and unified via information-theoretic and Fourier-analytic
methods.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Yu_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Lei Yu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Tan_V/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Vincent Y. F. Tan&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01804">
<title>Wasserstein Steepest Descent Flows of Discrepancies with Riesz Kernels. (arXiv:2211.01804v1 [math.OC])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01804</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The aim of this paper is twofold. Based on the geometric Wasserstein tangent
space, we first introduce Wasserstein steepest descent flows. These are locally
absolutely continuous curves in the Wasserstein space whose tangent vectors
point into a steepest descent direction of a given functional. This allows the
use of Euler forward schemes instead of the minimizing movement scheme (MMS)
introduced by Jordan, Kinderlehrer, and Otto. The MMS finds Wasserstein
gradient flows by successively computing Wasserstein proxies. For locally
Lipschitz continuous functionals which are $\lambda$-convex along generalized
geodesics, we show that there exists a unique Wasserstein steepest descent flow
coinciding with the Wasserstein gradient flow.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second aim is to study Wasserstein flows of the (maximum mean)
discrepancy with respect to Riesz kernels. The crucial part is hereby the
treatment of the interaction energy. Although it is not $\lambda$-convex along
generalized geodesics, we give analytic expressions for Wasserstein steepest
descent flows of the interaction energy starting at Dirac measures. In contrast
to smooth kernels, the particle may explode, i.e., the particle goes over to
non-Dirac measures. The computation of steepest descent flows amounts to
finding equilibrium measures with external fields, which nicely links
Wasserstein flows of interaction energies with potential theory. Furthermore,
we prove convergence of MMS to our Wasserstein steepest descent flows. Finally,
we provide analytic Wasserstein steepest descent flows of discrepancies in one
dimension and numerical simulations in two and three dimensions showing
relations to interaction energy flows.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Hertrich_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Johannes Hertrich&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Graf_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Manuel Gr&amp;#xe4;f&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Beinert_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Robert Beinert&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Steidl_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Gabriele Steidl&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01828">
<title>Erd\&quot;os-R\&apos;enyi Poissonized. (arXiv:2211.01828v1 [math.PR])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01828</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We introduce a variant of the Erd\&quot;os--R\&apos;enyi random graph where the number
of vertices is random and follows a Poisson law. A very simple Markov property
of the model entails that the Lukasiewicz exploration is made of
\textit{independent} Poisson increments. Using a vanilla Poisson counting
process, this enables us to give very short proofs of classical results such as
the phase transition for the giant component or the connectedness for the
standard Erd\&quot;os--R\&apos;enyi model.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Curien_N/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Nicolas Curien&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01844">
<title>Space-grid approximations of hybrid stochastic differential equations and first passage properties. (arXiv:2211.01844v1 [math.PR])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01844</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Hybrid stochastic differential equations are a useful tool to model
continuously varying stochastic systems which are modulated by a random
environment that may depend on the system state itself. In this paper, we
establish the pathwise convergence of the solutions to hybrid stochastic
differential equations via space-grid discretizations. While time-grid
discretizations are a classical approach for simulation purposes, our
space-grid discretization provides a link with multi-regime Markov modulated
Brownian motions, leading to computational tractability. We exploit our
convergence result to obtain efficient approximations to first passage
probabilities and expected occupation times of the solutions hybrid stochastic
differential equations, results which are the first of their kind for such a
robust framework. We finally illustrate the performance of the resulting
approximations in numerical examples.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Albrecher_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Hansjoerg Albrecher&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Peralta_O/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Oscar Peralta&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01872">
<title>Counting Deranged Matchings. (arXiv:2211.01872v1 [math.CO])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01872</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Let $\mathrm{pm}(G)$ denote the number of perfect matchings of a graph $G$,
and let $K_{r\times 2n/r}$ denote the complete $r$-partite graph where each
part has size $2n/r$. Johnson, Kayll, and Palmer conjectured that for any
perfect matching $M$ of $K_{r\times 2n/r}$, we have for $2n$ divisible by $r$
\[\frac{\mathrm{pm}(K_{r\times 2n/r}-M)}{\mathrm{pm}(K_{r\times 2n/r})}\sim
e^{-r/(2r-2)}.\] This conjecture can be viewed as a common generalization of
counting the number of derangements on $n$ letters, and of counting the number
of deranged matchings of $K_{2n}$. We prove this conjecture. In fact, we prove
the stronger result that if $R$ is a uniformly random perfect matching of
$K_{r\times 2n/r}$, then the number of edges that $R$ has in common with $M$
converges to a Poisson distribution with parameter $\frac{r}{2r-2}$.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Spiro_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Sam Spiro&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Surya_E/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Erlang Surya&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01940">
<title>Approximate Gibbsian structure in strongly correlated point fields and generalized Gaussian zero ensembles. (arXiv:2211.01940v1 [math.PR])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01940</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Gibbsian structure in random point fields has been a classical tool for
studying their spatial properties. However, exact Gibbs property is available
only in a relatively limited class of models, and it does not adequately
address many random fields with a strongly dependent spatial structure. In this
work, we provide a general framework for approximate Gibbsian structure for
strongly correlated random point fields. These include processes that exhibit
strong spatial rigidity, in particular, a certain one-parameter family of
analytic Gaussian zero point fields, namely the $\alpha$-GAFs. Our framework
entails conditions that may be verified via finite particle approximations to
the process, a phenomenon that we call an approximate Gibbs property. We show
that these enable one to compare the spatial conditional measures in the
infinite volume limit with Gibbs-type densities supported on appropriate
singular manifolds, a phenomenon we refer to as a generalized Gibbs property.
We demonstrate the scope of our approach by showing that a generalized Gibbs
property holds with a logarithmic pair potential for the $\alpha$-GAFs for any
value of $\alpha$. This establishes the level of rigidity of the $\alpha$-GAF
zero process to be exactly $\lfloor \frac{1}{\alpha} \rfloor$, settling in the
affirmative an open question regarding the existence of point processes with
any specified level of rigidity. For processes such as the zeros of
$\alpha$-GAFs, which involve complex, many-body interactions, our results imply
that the local behaviour of the random points still exhibits 2D Coulomb-type
repulsion in the short range. Our techniques can be leveraged to estimate the
relative energies of configurations under local perturbations, with possible
implications for dynamics and stochastic geometry on strongly correlated random
point fields.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Gangopadhyay_U/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ujan Gangopadhyay&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Ghosh_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Subhroshekhar Ghosh&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01961">
<title>The LP-update policy for weakly coupled Markov decision processes. (arXiv:2211.01961v1 [math.OC])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01961</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;In this work we propose a novel policy called the LP-update policy for finite
horizon weakly coupled Markov decision processes. The latter can be seen as
multi-constraint multi-action bandits, and generalizes the classical restless
bandit problems (that are single-constraint two-action bandits), widely studied
in the literature. We consider a scaling model with $N$ statistically identical
arms. We show that our LP-update policy becomes asymptotically optimal at rate
$O(1/\sqrt{N})$ for any problem. This rate can be improved to $O(1/N)$ if the
problem is non-degenerate, and even to $e^{-\Omega(N)}$ if in addition the
problem admits a perfect rounding. The definition of non-degeneracy extends the
same notion for the classical two-action restless bandits. By using this
property, we also provide a more efficient implementation of the LP-update
policy. We illustrate the performance of our policy in a generalized applicant
screening problem.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Gast_N/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Nicolas Gast&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Gaujal_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Bruno Gaujal&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Yan_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Chen Yan&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01986">
<title>Resilience of cube slicing in $\ell_p$. (arXiv:2211.01986v1 [math.FA])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01986</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Ball&apos;s celebrated cube slicing (1986) asserts that among hyperplane sections
of the cube in $\mathbb{R}^n$, the central section orthogonal to
$(1,1,0,\dots,0)$ has the greatest volume. We show that the same continues to
hold for slicing $\ell_p$ balls when $p &amp;gt; 10^{15}$, as well as that the same
hyperplane minimizes the volume of projections of $\ell_q$ balls for $1 &amp;lt; q &amp;lt; 1
+ 10^{-12}$. This extends Szarek&apos;s optimal Khinchin inequality (1976) which
corresponds to $q=1$. These results thus address the resilience of the
Ball--Szarek hyperplane in the ranges $2 &amp;lt; p &amp;lt; \infty$ and $1 &amp;lt; q &amp;lt; 2$, where
analysis of the extremizers has been elusive since the works of Koldobsky
(1998), Barthe--Naor (2002) and Oleszkiewicz (2003).
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Eskenazis_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Alexandros Eskenazis&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Nayar_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Piotr Nayar&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Tkocz_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Tomasz Tkocz&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.02009">
<title>Normal approximation of Kabanov-Skorohod integrals on Poisson spaces. (arXiv:2211.02009v1 [math.PR])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.02009</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We consider the normal approximation of Kabanov-Skorohod integrals on a
general Poisson space. Our bounds are for the Wasserstein and the Kolmogorov
distance and involve only difference operators of the integrand of the
Kabanov-Skorohod integral. The proofs rely on the Malliavin-Stein method and,
in particular, on multiple applications of integration by parts formulae. As
examples, we study some linear statistics of point processes that can be
constructed by Poisson embeddings and functionals related to Pareto optimal
points of a Poisson process.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Last_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;G&amp;#xfc;nter Last&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Molchanov_I/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ilya Molchanov&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Schulte_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Matthias Schulte&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.02032">
<title>To spike or not to spike: the whims of the Wonham filter in the strong noise regime. (arXiv:2211.02032v1 [math.PR])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.02032</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We study the celebrated Shiryaev-Wonham filter in its historical setup of
Wonham (1964) where the hidden Markov jump process has two states. We are
interested in the weak noise regime for the observation equation.
Interestingly, this becomes a strong noise regime for the filtering equations.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Earlier results of the authors show the appearance of spikes in the filtered
process, akin to a metastability phenomenon. This paper is aimed at
understanding the smoothed optimal filter, which is relevant for any system
with feedback. In particular, we demonstrate that there is a sharp phase
transition between a spiking regime and a regime with perfect smoothing.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Cedric_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Bernardin C&amp;#xe9;dric&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Reda_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Chhaibi Reda&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Joseph_N/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Najnudel Joseph&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Clement_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Pellegrini Cl&amp;#xe9;ment&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.02034">
<title>Convergence of the logarithm of the characteristic polynomial of unitary Brownian motion to the Gaussian free field. (arXiv:2211.02034v1 [math.PR])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.02034</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We prove that the real and imaginary parts of the logarithm of the
characteristic polynomial of unitary Brownian motion converge to Gaussian free
fields on the cylinder, as the matrix dimension goes to infinity. This is the
natural dynamical analogue of the result for a fixed time by Hughes, Keating
and O&apos;Connell [1]. Further it complements a result by Spohn [2] on linear
statistics of unitary Brownian motion, and a recent result by Bourgade and
Falconet [3] connecting the characteristic polynomial of unitary Brownian
motion to a Gaussian multiplicative chaos measure. In the course of this
research we also proved a Wick-type identity, which we include in this paper,
as it might be of independent interest.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Forkel_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Johannes Forkel&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Sauzedde_I/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Isao Sauzedde&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/1512.02208">
<title>A bijection for nonorientable general maps. (arXiv:1512.02208v5 [math.CO] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/1512.02208</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We give a different presentation of a recent bijection due to Chapuy and
Dol\k{e}ga for nonorientable bipartite quadrangulations and we extend it to the
case of nonorientable general maps. This can be seen as a Bouttier--Di
Francesco--Guitter-like generalization of the Cori--Vauquelin--Schaeffer
bijection in the context of general nonorientable surfaces. In the particular
case of triangulations, the encoding objects take a particularly simple form
and this allows us to recover a famous asymptotic enumeration formula found by
Gao.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Bettinelli_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;J&amp;#xe9;r&amp;#xe9;mie Bettinelli&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/1804.02128">
<title>The Numerical Invariant Measure of Stochastic Differential Equations With Markovian Switching. (arXiv:1804.02128v2 [math.PR] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/1804.02128</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The existence and uniqueness of the numerical invariant measure of the
backward Euler-Maruyama method for stochastic differential equations with
Markovian switching is yielded, and it is revealed that the numerical invariant
measure converges to the underlying invariant measure in the Wasserstein
metric. Under the polynomial growth condition of drift term the convergence
rate is estimated. The global Lipschitz condition on the drift coefficients
required by Bao et al., 2016 and Yuan et al., 2005 is released. Several
examples and numerical experiments are given to verify our theory.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Li_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xiaoyue Li&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Ma_Q/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Qianlin Ma&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Yang_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Hongfu Yang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Yuan_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Chenggui Yuan&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2104.12716">
<title>Scaling limit of random plane quadrangulations with a simple boundary, via restriction. (arXiv:2104.12716v2 [math.PR] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2104.12716</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The main purpose of this work is to provide a framework for proving that,
given a family of random maps known to converge in the Gromov--Hausdorff sense,
then some (suitable) conditional families of random maps converge to the same
limit. As a proof of concept, we show that quadrangulations with a simple
boundary converge to the Brownian disk. More precisely, we fix a sequence
$(p_n)$ of even positive integers with $p_n\sim 2\alpha \sqrt{2n}$ for some
$\alpha\in(0,\infty)$. Then, for the Gromov--Hausdorff topology, a
quadrangulation with a simple boundary uniformly sampled among those with $n$
inner faces and boundary length $p_n$ weakly converges, in the usual scaling
$n^{-1/4}$, toward the Brownian disk of perimeter $3\alpha$.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Bettinelli_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;J&amp;#xe9;r&amp;#xe9;mie Bettinelli&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Curien_N/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Nicolas Curien&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Fredes_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Luis Fredes&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Sepulveda_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Avelio Sep&amp;#xfa;lveda&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2105.04175">
<title>Explicit Numerical Approximations for McKean-Vlasov Neutral Stochastic Differential Delay Equations. (arXiv:2105.04175v2 [math.PR] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2105.04175</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;This paper studies the numerical methods to approximate the solutions for a
sort of McKean-Vlasov neutral stochastic differential delay equations
(MV-NSDDEs) that the growth of the drift coefficients is super-linear. First,
We obtain that the solution of MV-NSDDE exists and is unique. Then, we use a
stochastic particle method, which is on the basis of the results about the
propagation of chaos between particle system and the original MV-NSDDE, to deal
with the approximation of the law. Furthermore, we construct the tamed
Euler-Maruyama numerical scheme with respect to the corresponding particle
system and obtain the rate of convergence. Combining propagation of chaos and
the convergence rate of the numerical solution to the particle system, we get a
convergence error between the numerical solution and exact solution of the
original MV-NSDDE in the stepsize and number of particles.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Cui_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yuanping Cui&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Li_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xiaoyue Li&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Liu_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yi Liu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Yuan_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Chenggui Yuan&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2108.04777">
<title>Approximation and Error Analysis of Forward-Backward SDEs driven by General L\&apos;evy Processes using Shot Noise Series Representations. (arXiv:2108.04777v3 [math.PR] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2108.04777</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We consider the simulation of a system of decoupled forward-backward
stochastic differential equations (FBSDEs) driven by a pure jump L\&apos;evy process
$L$ and an independent Brownian motion $B$. We allow the L\&apos;evy process $L$ to
have an infinite jump activity. Therefore, it is necessary for the simulation
to employ a finite approximation of its L\&apos;evy measure. We use the generalized
shot noise series representation method by Rosinski (2001) to approximate the
driving L\&apos;evy process $L$. We compute the $L^p$ error, $p\ge2$, between the
true and the approximated FBSDEs which arises from the finite truncation of the
shot noise series (given sufficient conditions for existence and uniqueness of
the FBSDE). We also derive the $L^p$ error between the true solution and the
discretization of the approximated FBSDE using an appropriate backward Euler
scheme.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Massing_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Till Massing&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2110.12977">
<title>Large deviations for random matrices in the orthogonal group and Stiefel manifold with applications to random projections of product distributions. (arXiv:2110.12977v3 [math.PR] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2110.12977</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We prove large deviation principles (LDPs) for random matrices in the
orthogonal group and Stiefel manifold, determining both the speed and good
convex rate functions that are explicitly given in terms of certain
log-determinants of trace-class operators and are finite on the set of
Hilbert-Schmidt operators $M$ satisfying $\|MM^*\|&amp;lt;1$. As an application of
those LDPs, we determine the precise large deviation behavior of
$k$-dimensional random projections of high-dimensional product distributions
using an appropriate interpretation in terms of point processes, also
characterizing the space of all possible deviations. The case of uniform
distributions on $\ell_p$-balls, $1\leq p \leq \infty$, is then considered and
reduced to appropriate product measures. Those applications generalize
considerably the recent work [Johnston, Kabluchko, Prochno: Projections of the
uniform distribution on the cube - a large deviation perspective, Studia
Mathematica 264 (2022), 103-119].
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Kabluchko_Z/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Zakhar Kabluchko&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Prochno_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Joscha Prochno&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2111.12403">
<title>Combinatorics of the Quantum Symmetric Simple Exclusion Process, associahedra and free cumulants. (arXiv:2111.12403v2 [math.CO] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2111.12403</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The Quantum Symmetric Simple Exclusion Process (QSSEP) is a model of quantum
particles hopping on a finite interval and satisfying the exclusion principle.
Recently Bernard and Jin have studied the fluctuations of the invariant measure
for this process, when the number of sites goes to infinity. These fluctuations
are encoded into polynomials, for which they have given equations and proved
that these equations determine the polynomials completely. In this paper, I
give an explicit combinatorial formula for these polynomials, in terms of
Schr\&quot;oder trees. I also show that, quite surprisingly, these polynomials can
be interpreted as free cumulants of a family of commuting random variables.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Biane_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Philippe Biane&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2201.00292">
<title>Fair Data Representation for Machine Learning at the Pareto Frontier. (arXiv:2201.00292v2 [stat.ML] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2201.00292</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;As machine learning powered decision making is playing an increasingly
important role in our daily lives, it is imperative to strive for fairness of
the underlying data processing and algorithms. We propose a pre-processing
algorithm for fair data representation via which L2- objective supervised
learning algorithms result in an estimation of the Pareto frontier between
prediction error and statistical disparity. In particular, the present work
applies the optimal positive definite affine transport maps to approach the
post-processing Wasserstein barycenter characterization of the optimal fair
L2-objective supervised learning via a pre-processing data deformation. We call
the resulting data Wasserstein pseudo-barycenter. Furthermore, we show that the
Wasserstein geodesics from the learning outcome marginals to the barycenter
characterizes the Pareto frontier between L2-loss and total Wasserstein
distance among learning outcome marginals. Thereby, an application of McCann
interpolation generalizes the pseudo-barycenter to a family of data
representations via which L2-objective supervised learning algorithms result in
the Pareto frontier. Numerical simulations underscore the advantages of the
proposed data representation: (1) the pre-processing step is compositive with
arbitrary L2-objective supervised learning methods and unseen data; (2) the
fair representation protects data privacy by preventing the training machine
from direct or indirect access to the sensitive information of the data; (3)
the optimal affine map results in efficient computation of fair supervised
learning on high-dimensional data; (4) experimental results shed light on the
fairness of L2-objective unsupervised learning via the proposed fair data
representation.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/stat/1/au:+Xu_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Shizhou Xu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/stat/1/au:+Strohmer_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Thomas Strohmer&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2201.07659">
<title>Equilibria of Time-inconsistent Stopping for One-dimensional Diffusion Processes. (arXiv:2201.07659v2 [math.PR] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2201.07659</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We consider three equilibrium concepts proposed in the literature for
time-inconsistent stopping problems, including mild equilibria, weak equilibria
and strong equilibria. The discount function is assumed to be log sub-additive
and the underlying process is one-dimensional diffusion. We first provide
necessary and sufficient conditions for the characterization of weak
equilibria. The smooth-fit condition is obtained as a by-product. Next, based
on the characterization of weak equilibria, we show that an optimal mild
equilibrium is also weak. Then we provide conditions under which a weak
equilibrium is strong. We further show that an optimal mild equilibrium is also
strong under a certain condition. Finally, we provide several examples
including one shows a weak equilibrium may not be strong, and another one shows
a strong equilibrium may not be optimal mild.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Bayraktar_E/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Erhan Bayraktar&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Wang_Z/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Zhenhua Wang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Zhou_Z/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Zhou Zhou&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2204.08031">
<title>Limit theorems of Chatterjee&apos;s rank correlation. (arXiv:2204.08031v3 [math.ST] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2204.08031</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Establishing the limiting distribution of Chatterjee&apos;s rank correlation for a
general, possibly non-independent, pair of random variables has been eagerly
awaited to many. This paper shows that (a) Chatterjee&apos;s rank correlation is
asymptotically normal as long as one variable is not a measurable function of
the other, (b) the corresponding asymptotic variance is uniformly bounded by
36, and (c) a consistent variance estimator exists. Similar results also hold
for Azadkia-Chatterjee&apos;s graph-based correlation coefficient, a multivariate
analogue of Chatterjee&apos;s original proposal. The proof is given by appealing to
H\&apos;ajek representation and Chatterjee&apos;s nearest-neighbor CLT.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Lin_Z/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Zhexiao Lin&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Han_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Fang Han&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2205.03095">
<title>The well-posedness of the stochastic nonlinear Schr\&quot;odinger equations in $H^2(\mathbb{R}^d)$. (arXiv:2205.03095v2 [math.AP] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2205.03095</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The Cauchy problem for the stochastic nonlinear Schr\&quot;odinger equation with a
multiplicable noise is considered where the nonlinear term is of a power type
and its coefficients are complex numbers. In particular, it is extremely
important to consider the complex coefficients in the noise which cover
non-conservative case, because they include measurement effects in quantum
physics. The main purpose of this paper is to construct classical solutions in
$H^2(\mathbb{R}^d)$ for the problem in question. The time local well-posedness
in $L^2(\mathbb{R}^d)$ and $H^1(\mathbb{R}^d)$ was investigated in the papers
[7,8]. In this paper we study the well-posedness in $H^2(\mathbb{R}^d)$ by
making use of the rescaling approach as a main tool for dealing with the
multiple noise, where we need to take advantage of a slight modification of the
deterministic Strichartz estimate to fit into requirements under the setting of
$H^2(\mathbb{R}^d)$. The other difficulty lies on the discussion on smoothness
of functions in the nonlinear term, where the proof of time local
well-posedness for the case of $H^2$-solutions does not go similarly as in the
cases of $L^2$-solutions or $H^1$-solutions, because of the complexity in the
computation of the nonlinear term with lower exponent $\alpha$. The techniques
of Kato [18,19] work well on this difficulty even for the stochastic equations.
We use the stochastic Strichartz estimate [4,16,17] as well to deal with white
noise which did not appear in the proof for $L^2$-solutions or $H^1$-solutions.
We also discuss time-global solutions in $H^2(\mathbb{R}^d)$.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Doku_I/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Isamu D&amp;#xf4;ku&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Hashimoto_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Shunya Hashimoto&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Machihara_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Shuji Machihara&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2207.09340">
<title>A coherence parameter characterizing generative compressed sensing with Fourier measurements. (arXiv:2207.09340v4 [cs.IT] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2207.09340</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;In Bora et al. (2017), a mathematical framework was developed for compressed
sensing guarantees in the setting where the measurement matrix is Gaussian and
the signal structure is the range of a generative neural network (GNN). The
problem of compressed sensing with GNNs has since been extensively analyzed
when the measurement matrix and/or network weights follow a subgaussian
distribution. We move beyond the subgaussian assumption, to measurement
matrices that are derived by sampling uniformly at random rows of a unitary
matrix (including subsampled Fourier measurements as a special case).
Specifically, we prove the first known restricted isometry guarantee for
generative compressed sensing with subsampled isometries, and provide recovery
bounds with nearly order-optimal sample complexity, addressing an open problem
of Scarlett et al. (2022, p. 10). Recovery efficacy is characterized by the
coherence, a new parameter, which measures the interplay between the range of
the network and the measurement matrix. Our approach relies on subspace
counting arguments and ideas central to high-dimensional probability.
Furthermore, we propose a regularization strategy for training GNNs to have
favourable coherence with the measurement operator. We provide compelling
numerical simulations that support this regularized training strategy: our
strategy yields low coherence networks that require fewer measurements for
signal recovery. This, together with our theoretical results, supports
coherence as a natural quantity for characterizing generative compressed
sensing with subsampled isometries.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Berk_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Aaron Berk&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Brugiapaglia_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Simone Brugiapaglia&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Joshi_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Babhru Joshi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Plan_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yaniv Plan&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Scott_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Matthew Scott&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Yilmaz_O/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;&amp;#xd6;zg&amp;#xfc;r Yilmaz&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.13121">
<title>The Entropy Method in Large Deviation Theory. (arXiv:2210.13121v2 [math.PR] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.13121</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;This paper illustrates the power of the entropy method in addressing problems
from large deviation theory. We provide and review entropy proofs for most
fundamental results in large deviation theory, including Cramer&apos;s theorem, the
G\&quot;artner--Ellis theorem, and Sanov&apos;s theorem. Moreover, by the entropy method,
we also strengthen Sanov&apos;s theorem to the strong version.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Yu_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Lei Yu&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
</rdf:RDF>