<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>ESI Money</title>
	<atom:link href="https://esimoney.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://esimoney.com/</link>
	<description>Three Simple Steps to Wealth</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2022 21:07:55 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	

<image>
	<url>https://esimoney.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/11/cropped-ESI-MONEY-ICON-3_512px-75x75.png</url>
	<title>ESI Money</title>
	<link>https://esimoney.com/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Millionaire Thoughts on Buying Time</title>
		<link>https://esimoney.com/millionaire-thoughts-on-buying-time/</link>
					<comments>https://esimoney.com/millionaire-thoughts-on-buying-time/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[ESI]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2022 09:00:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Books]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Save]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://esimoney.com/?p=8747</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;m in the middle of a series on the book Happy Money: The Science of Happier Spending. In the last post, we talked about being happier by buying time &#8212; basically trading money for time and avoiding unpleasant tasks by hiring someone to do them. We&#8217;ve discussed this issue quite a bit in the Millionaire [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://esimoney.com/millionaire-thoughts-on-buying-time/">Millionaire Thoughts on Buying Time</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://esimoney.com">ESI Money</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://esimoney.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Lawn-mower-grass-new.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-8748" src="https://esimoney.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Lawn-mower-grass-new-300x185.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="185" srcset="https://esimoney.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Lawn-mower-grass-new-300x185.jpg 300w, https://esimoney.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Lawn-mower-grass-new.jpg 750w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a>I&#8217;m in the middle of a series on the book <a href="https://amzn.to/3xYv1ft">Happy Money: The Science of Happier Spending</a>.</p>
<p>In the last post, we talked about <a href="https://esimoney.com/be-happier-by-buying-time/">being happier by buying time</a> &#8212; basically trading money for time and avoiding unpleasant tasks by hiring someone to do them.</p>
<p>We&#8217;ve discussed this issue quite a bit in the <a href="https://millionairemoneymentors.com/">Millionaire Money Mentors</a> forums and I thought I&#8217;d share some of those comments with you today.</p>
<p>As I&#8217;ve said previously, I wasn&#8217;t good at buying time for most of my life, which is something I would certainly focus on more if I could do it over again.</p>
<p>For this post, I&#8217;ll simply share some highlights from the forums on this subject as I think several members and mentors have good perspectives and tips on buying back their time.</p>
<p>Our discussion started with this post:</p>
<p style="padding-left: 40px;"><em><strong>Over the last couple of months I’ve been thinking about hiring a cleaning service, and more recently, maybe lawn care. With a toddler and a newborn, our hands are full, and it’d be nice to know that once a week a larger cleaning would occur, with us just doing the smaller ‘clean as you go’ type maintenance. Cleaning isn’t a task I add any value to, the best case scenario is things are the way they should be, nothing gets cleaner than clean.</strong></em></p>
<p style="padding-left: 40px;"><em><strong>Hiring someone to do it hurts me on the inside, because it feels like it goes against the efforts I’ve been making over the last couple years to reduce ongoing costs. Why hire someone when I can do it myself? But if getting an hour back means I can generate another hour of income at a higher rate than what I’m paying, that should be a no-brainer, right? Hire out the low value tasks in life (not saying these tasks have no value, but the value I can personally add to it vs some else who can do it the same, or specializes in it and does it better), spend efforts on tasks with a higher return, or higher happiness like playing with the kids.</strong></em></p>
<p style="padding-left: 40px;"><em><strong>Would really appreciate any thoughts or stories on how y’all approach this sort of stuff, why you do or don’t offload certain tasks to others, or what kind of work/tasks you’ve found most beneficial having someone else take over.</strong></em></p>
<p>&#8220;Hiring someone to do it hurts me on the inside, because it feels like it goes against the efforts I’ve been making over the last couple years to reduce ongoing costs. Why hire someone when I can do it myself?&#8221; This was my line of thinking for most of my life. Hence I mowed the yard and shoveled snow (and there was a lot of snow in Michigan) and my wife cleaned the house for many, many years when we would have been better served (in hindsight) to hire those tasks out.</p>
<p>Thankfully, this forums member is much wiser than I was.</p>
<p>What followed were several comments back and forth, starting with this great advice from a mentor:</p>
<p style="padding-left: 40px;"><em><strong>Bottom line…if you don’t enjoy it and can afford to outsource it…then do it and if you are fortunate enough to be able to make more incremental income than a task costs to outsource than do it. Life is too short to be doing low value things you don’t want to especially if it is taking away from time with your family or things you enjoy.</strong></em></p>
<p>There are two facts I didn&#8217;t think of in my younger days:</p>
<ul>
<li>Life is too short &#8212; I could have outsourced tasks and enjoyed that time in many different ways.</li>
<li>I could have earned more &#8212; even if I didn&#8217;t enjoy the time I saved, I could have worked instead and likely made more than the cost of the service.</li>
</ul>
<p>Another mentor had similar thoughts:</p>
<p style="padding-left: 40px;"><em><strong>Pretty simple equation to me…if you can make more money NOT doing the task (or already have the NW) AND it’s not a task you enjoy, offload/outsource it.</strong></em></p>
<p>Then a member shared a situation where they wished they had taken a different approach:</p>
<p style="padding-left: 40px;"><em><strong>I had this harebrained idea that we (wife and I) could paint the exterior of our house years ago. I bought the paint, scheduled the rental of the sprayer, and scheduled a week off work. I was filling in the cracks of the stucco and within an hour, my fingers were bleeding and I was less than 10% done with crack repair. I called a local painter and he came by and gave a quote that was about the same cost for us to do it. Plus, it probably saved a potential divorce situation…Ha ha.</strong></em></p>
<p style="padding-left: 40px;"><em><strong>It took a crew of four, four days to do it. No way were we going to do it in 5 days. Plus, we saved money on the sprayer and returning the paint since he gets a contractor discount. We also saved our vacation time. That was my Ah Ha moment. My wife told me she was just waiting for me to wise up. Ha ha.</strong></em></p>
<p style="padding-left: 40px;"><em><strong>Time is very valuable as we learn as we get older. We all have regrets on the time we lost that we can’t get back. Learn from us elders. ha ha.</strong></em></p>
<p>Then I joined in with my own hard won lesson:</p>
<p style="padding-left: 40px;"><em><strong>Here’s an even more harebrained idea…</strong></em></p>
<p style="padding-left: 40px;"><em><strong>My wife bought 13 tons (yes, tons!) of rock a couple years ago and thought we could “save money” by hauling it from the front drive to the back yard.</strong></em></p>
<p style="padding-left: 40px;"><em><strong>Do you know how heavy 13 tons is??? (I bet you do!) <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/14.0.0/72x72/1f642.png" alt="🙂" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></strong></em></p>
<p style="padding-left: 40px;"><em><strong>It’s also about a bazillion wheelbarrows full of very heavy rock.</strong></em></p>
<p style="padding-left: 40px;"><em><strong>Never doing that again…</strong></em></p>
<p>From another member:</p>
<p style="padding-left: 40px;"><em><strong>I’m in a similar boat &#8211; young kids, work full time, spouse works full time, also have elder caregiving responsibilities. We do a cleaning service 2x/month, and we only do the top floor of the house. So, for ~$250/month I don’t have to do a bunch of stuff I hate very most (floors, toilets mainly). The amount of dread that resolves for me is well worth it for 3k/yr. We of course have to do all the routine cleaning in between. With small kids, I tell you what, that cleaner earns every cent.</strong></em></p>
<p style="padding-left: 40px;"><em><strong>I’ve been considering adding some yard maintenance to our mix. Spending another 1k/yr for people to just come pull weeds a few times throughout the summer seems like a value add too. We’re trying to start a side hustle so time spent doing low wage or unliked chores is a barrier to our success. At least that&#8217;s how I’m justifying it to myself :).</strong></em></p>
<p style="padding-left: 40px;"><em><strong>I’ve grown to love our cleaning service so much that I’d give up my car and start doing uber only, I think, before I gave up the cleaner. Side bonus &#8211; the day before the cleaner comes is the 2x per month that nobody can argue about helping pick up and get the house ready &#8211; that alone is worth something!</strong></em></p>
<p>And another:</p>
<p style="padding-left: 40px;"><em><strong>Personal experience, I hired the cleaning service. It still hurts occasionally, but I look at it this way. Annually, it costs me $2300 and saves me about 75 hours of my life. That’s nearly 2 weeks of work.</strong></em></p>
<p style="padding-left: 40px;"><em><strong>Would you see value in lowering your salary by 2300 to get 2 additional weeks of vacation. I would make that trade any time, any day.</strong></em></p>
<p>And another vote for going for it:</p>
<p style="padding-left: 40px;"><em><strong>Do it. Cleaning and lawn service are worth every penny, even if you don’t work those hours to theoretically make more than you are paying. Use the time for life experience points, and you will be so much better off.</strong></em></p>
<p style="padding-left: 40px;"><em><strong>One other point I’ll make is that the cleaning thing was a huge friction point in the early years of my marriage (typically, as the guy my definition of clean had a lower bar than my dear wife’s) &#8211; so we have had a cleaning service since the kids were born almost 20 years ago and well before our NW was over 7 figures. Problem was solved, and I don’t regret that trade off one bit.</strong></em></p>
<p>This one really saved some time &#8212; and the trade-off was well worth it:</p>
<p style="padding-left: 40px;"><em><strong>You won’t regret having someone else do the sucky stuff.</strong></em></p>
<p style="padding-left: 40px;"><em><strong>I used to do all my own yard work and had the best equipment so that I could knock it out quickly. Then my dad needed help with his huge yard so I started cutting his too. Then my sister bought a house and didn’t have access to a mower and was broke all the time so I cut hers too. At my church we would have cleanup days but it seemed that most everyone had to “work” those Saturdays so my sons and I were the only ones cutting the grass/trimming the shrubs there. Oh yeah, I have a medical building that has lots of landscaping so that was on the rotation as well.</strong></em></p>
<p style="padding-left: 40px;"><em><strong>After a few years of 6 hour Saturdays every other week from April to September I sold it all and hired out the house and practice landscaping. The amount I got from the equipment paid for 2-3 years of cuts and now I spend Saturdays working out and playing in the pool.</strong></em></p>
<p style="padding-left: 40px;"><em><strong>We used a twice a month cleaner at the house for several years and it definitely helped around the edges. My wife and I were working long days at the practice and she was irritated with having to come home and cook and do laundry etc. We had a couple of really good years in a row so she talked me into hiring a full time housekeeper/cook/assistant. Was that the best thing that ever happened to us? No…but it has been pretty darn close!</strong></em></p>
<p style="padding-left: 40px;"><em><strong>She’s awesome! We come home from the office and dinner is on the table, the dry cleaning has been picked up and the packages mailed and the clean laundry folded and sitting in our respective closets. She does the grocery shopping and in the summertime makes sure the kids have food at lunch and even drives them around when needed. We have definitely become spoiled in that regard but my wife can see enough patients in an hour to cover that person’s entire paycheck for 2 weeks. Now we can come home and relax and enjoy dinner and our children.</strong></em></p>
<p>Here&#8217;s a comment with some good guidance &#8212; and a GREAT point about employing others (something that&#8217;s not often considered but is valuable IMO):</p>
<p style="padding-left: 40px;"><em><strong>Do it yourself and continue to be as frugal as possible IF:</strong></em></p>
<ul>
<li><em><strong>you have credit card debt</strong></em></li>
<li><em><strong>you don’t have adequate emergency savings</strong></em></li>
<li><em><strong>you aren’t contributing at least 15% to retirement investments each year</strong></em></li>
<li><em><strong>cash flow each month is super tight or negative</strong></em></li>
</ul>
<p style="padding-left: 40px;"><em><strong>Otherwise, outsourcing home maintenance including cleaning would be near the top of my personal values list. Other things I added quickly to my budget once I achieved the above basic financial security included a fairly expensive gym membership, better flights when I traveled (direct, better times), a monthly massage membership, and a bigger clothing budget for my work wardrobe.</strong></em></p>
<p style="padding-left: 40px;"><em><strong>It’s all about values, but TBH I’ve had a house cleaner since my mid-20s (when I got my first pet), well before I was a millionaire. I could afford it, but I struggled with the identity portion of it &#8211; being the kind of person who paid someone else to clean my very small condo when I was single and had plenty of free time and ability to do it myself. But I’ve never gone back and honestly I’d cut cable before I cut my house cleaner.</strong></em></p>
<p style="padding-left: 40px;"><em><strong>Another factor for me that helped me rationalize it is that I’m giving this woman employment. She needs/wants a job and I need/want my house cleaned, and I pay her well. I have tipped from day one and also give her raises each year even though she’s never asked and also give holiday presents. She isn’t even that good a cleaner haha &#8211; but she’s better than what I would do!</strong></em></p>
<p style="padding-left: 40px;"><em><strong>Plus the impact on my marriage to avoid negotiating about who cleans the toilet is priceless.</strong></em></p>
<p>And the comments kept going:</p>
<p style="padding-left: 40px;"><em><strong>When we were making way less combined than one of us makes today we hired a lawn service. We agreed that should there ever be a budget squeeze on us we would cut cable over the lawn service as we valued our time and maintenance of the property over entertainment. Since then we’ve added a cleaning service that comes once a month cutting our hours spent cleaning from 6-8 per week to 2-4 per week. Currently debating on adding a 2nd visit as the kids are bigger and the dirt seems to multiply with their growth and their friends who roam through our house.</strong></em></p>
<p style="padding-left: 40px;"><em><strong>Two years ago we added a laundry service. The fact that half our weekly laundry now is shoved in a bag once a week and set on the porch on a Thursday and arrives Friday washed and folded (or on hangers if I tell them to) and can be in drawers and out of my life in minutes versus 2-3 hours for a wash/dry/fold cycle continues to make me happy. Now we do 1-2 loads during the week to wash mask, sports stuff and delicates, all manageable without having to declare a “laundry day”.</strong></em></p>
<p>Here&#8217;s one with a focus on the difference kids make:</p>
<p style="padding-left: 40px;"><em><strong>My thoughts on this have changed and a lot of this had to do with having children. Before kids I did almost everything myself. I would paint my own rentals, fix stuff up, whatever it took. Now I find it way more efficient to hire a professional that can do it in a fraction of the time and also do it better than I can.</strong></em></p>
<p style="padding-left: 40px;"><em><strong>I have also started to hire out a lot of the tasks in my business that I am not as skilled at and that don’t propel my business forward I love Upwork for this. Just creating marketing, spread sheets, or other things like that there are really talented people that can create things like that for me cheaper and faster than I ever could.</strong></em></p>
<p style="padding-left: 40px;"><em><strong>Now this is not directed at anyone but I personally hate the saying “time is money.” To me that implies that I should always be out trading my time for money and anytime I am not doing that I am wasting time. I do trade my time for money currently but that&#8217;s what I am trying to get away from. I want to make money that&#8217;s not tied to my time. There are a lot of activities that I do with my time that do not have a ROI on them monetarily but in my opinion have far more value than making money.</strong></em></p>
<p>Some good points there. I also employ several people with ESI Money and Millionaire Money Mentors as they can do things better/faster/simpler than I can.</p>
<p>At this point in the conversation, I chimed in again:</p>
<p style="padding-left: 40px;"><em><strong>Just came upon these thoughts from the book <a href="https://esimoney.com/how-to-die-with-zero-introduction-and-rule-1/">Die with Zero</a>:</strong></em></p>
<p style="padding-left: 40px;"><em><strong>The other big opportunity I see for creating a more balanced life is to exchange money for free time – a tactic that usually has the most impact in one’s middle year, when you have more money than time. The classic example is laundry, a time-consuming weekly chore that most people dread doing and that, in many places, can be done inexpensively by an outside service that specializes in it.</strong></em></p>
<p style="padding-left: 40px;"><em><strong>The more money you have, the more you should be using this tactic, because your time is a lot more scarce and finite then your cash. I am constantly trading money back into time. I’ll never get more than 24 hours in a day, but I can do my utmost to free up as much of that finite time as I possibly can.</strong></em></p>
<p>Then a member commented as follows:</p>
<p style="padding-left: 40px;"><em><strong>My wife and I have agreed that while we are both working and our kids are young, we will outsource as many household tasks as possible so that we can maximize our evenings and weekends. So we pay for lawn care and housekeeping. We also pay for someone to deal with laundry, plant watering, dishes, and other odd jobs around the house.</strong></em></p>
<p style="padding-left: 40px;"><em><strong>I actually like manual labor…within reason (not 13 tons of rocks). It’s a welcome break from staring at a screen all day, and at some primal level I like working with my hands. But there are only so many hours in a day when you’ve subtracted working (your day job), eating, sleeping, child care, etc.</strong></em></p>
<p style="padding-left: 40px;"><em><strong>Currently I’m debating whether to replace my entire back fence myself or hire it out. I’ve replaced a few sections myself, including jackhammering out the old posts. I don’t consider it “joyless”. But again, how many hours do I have? At this rate it will take months if not years…</strong></em></p>
<p>I actually don&#8217;t mind some decent manual labor myself. I do still mow our yard, though it&#8217;s much smaller now than it has been at other homes. It takes me 15 minutes to do the back yard (my nice neighbor does our front yard because he&#8217;s a grass perfectionist and can do it better than I can &#8212; lol) and I get some steps in.</p>
<p>I usually water the roses (front and back yard) when I mow as well.</p>
<p>Here&#8217;s another perspective from a like-minded mower:</p>
<p style="padding-left: 40px;"><em><strong>So, I have a different perspective than what I have seen in the rest of this thread…</strong></em></p>
<p style="padding-left: 40px;"><em><strong>When I was a teen, I cut a LOT of lawns. It was more and easier money than what I made washing dishes in a bar by hand. When Mrs. McDuck and I bought our first personal residence I did the yard work myself for a couple of years, but then I got a big head and decided that I needed other people to start doing this manual labor for me because I could make more money in that time than I paid my landscaper. I outsourced my lawn care for probably 10 years after that.</strong></em></p>
<p style="padding-left: 40px;"><em><strong>About 5 years ago I realized that I had been looking at things the wrong way. Yard work wasn’t a manual labor task that I needed to outsource. It was an opportunity for an extra workout, usually an extra cardio workout.</strong></em></p>
<p style="padding-left: 40px;"><em><strong>I probably get enough total exercise already but nothing gets my heart rate up to a high sustained rate like pushing around my non-self propelled mower for an hour. Half the season I cut the grass once a week and half I cut it twice a week. It’s probably the best heart decision I’ve ever made.</strong></em></p>
<p style="padding-left: 40px;"><em><strong>Trimming trees and bushes and pulling weeds feels like more work for me but the bending and stretching is good for me too.</strong></em></p>
<p>The thread continues with a response to the mowing fan:</p>
<p style="padding-left: 40px;"><em><strong>Agree to some extent. I was having someone come in to mow the lawn (small lawn) several times a month and just realized it was costing me way more than I wanted to spend and it was on an already crappy lawn. Twice a month was $100 and then you add the tip each time on top of that. Went out and bought all of the equipment to do it myself and it all paid for itself in 4 months. Not for my time obviously but like you, it is now an opportunity for exercise. Now we actually have a nice lawn with new sod etc., but we still do the lawncare ourselves.</strong></em></p>
<p style="padding-left: 40px;"><em><strong>However; anything beyond mowing the lawn, I’ll bring someone in to do because the humidity is just so miserable to work in. I grew up doing hard labor and I did a 130 foot French drain at one point last year with a bad hip (since replaced) and I will never do that again…lol. I could do it in what I consider normal temps but in heat…that’s for the birds.</strong></em></p>
<p>Here&#8217;s another &#8212; with a new task outsourced:</p>
<p style="padding-left: 40px;"><em><strong>I can’t believe I am saying this, but we just got each of our cars fully detailed for the first time ever. At $400/each it wasn’t cheap (it&#8217;s a quality shop) but they spent a full 8 hours on each of them and did a far more thorough job than I would. That and the fact that I can’t even seem to bother washing or waxing them by myself anymore (which I used to enjoy) told me that I have probably reached the point in life where loosening up and paying someone to do this occasionally makes sense.</strong></em></p>
<p style="padding-left: 40px;"><em><strong>BTW &#8211; the kids did a lot of damage to my 12 year old BMW interior (which is tan) and absolutely destroyed our light grey, 6 year old minivan interior. Fixing that and many years of salt buildup in the carpet were both major wins.</strong></em></p>
<p style="padding-left: 40px;"><em><strong>Bottom line is that I make enough in a day to pay for both cars and have money left over but I still struggle(d) with offloading this work.</strong></em></p>
<p>And a final comment:</p>
<p style="padding-left: 40px;"><em><strong>I formerly paid someone to cut my lawn. I didn’t hate doing it, but I hated the fact that it took 3+hours to complete the task. We paid someone else to do it for 3 years. Last year, after the 3rd person who took the work started to get more than moderately annoying, we decided to spend some money on a riding mower and bring the work back in house in a more manageable way. I still had to rake pine needles in my yard in the fall which was always a huge hassle even after paying someone. Hopefully I will need to do much less of that now.</strong></em></p>
<p style="padding-left: 40px;"><em><strong>The first two people that did the work for us were very nice, but were less reliable than I needed. The lawn would go 2-3 weeks without being cut and start to get unruly. The last guy was a bit more reliable, but was a real nut job. He was calling and texting multiple times in a row if we didn’t answer immediately, told us long, pointless, and inappropriate personal stories, and then told my wife that she looked terrible and should try drinking more so she wasn’t miserable.</strong></em></p>
<p style="padding-left: 40px;"><em><strong>Fun bonus, my daughter loves “her new tractor” and has cut the grass with me twice already! It now takes less than an hour (would be shorter if my daughter wasn’t on my lap and I could go faster, but I prefer this way), but I do have to take the clippings over to the municipal drop off site which adds another 20 minutes or so.</strong></em></p>
<p>Ok, so maybe all those comments were a bit over-kill, but I wanted to hit this topic hard to make the following points:</p>
<ul>
<li>It&#8217;s ok to trade money for time by outsourcing unpleasant tasks. You can always get more money, but you can&#8217;t get more time.</li>
<li>If you make more by outsourcing, that&#8217;s great. But you don&#8217;t have to &#8212; you can just enjoy life instead.</li>
<li>There are a wide variety of things to outsource. Pick the ones (or them all) that you really dislike and get rid of those.</li>
<li>You don&#8217;t have to wait until you are financially independent to outsource tasks. These are millionaires and members (most of whom are doing quite well themselves) and they are fine paying for these services.</li>
<li>If it helps (and I think it&#8217;s a valid point), consider that you&#8217;re actually spreading your wealth around and helping someone else by employing them.</li>
</ul>
<p>Finally, <a href="https://spilledcoffee.substack.com/p/return-on-hassle?s=r">here&#8217;s a list of things that could be outsourced from Spilled Coffee</a> (and a good article on this subject):</p>
<ul>
<li>Cleaning and laundry</li>
<li>Mowing the lawn and shoveling snow</li>
<li>Ordering something online that will arrive in a few days on your doorstep versus the time and cost of gas to drive somewhere to pick it up.</li>
<li>Trips to the bank or post office</li>
<li>Cleaning up and putting new mulch in your landscape.</li>
<li>Spending the money and the minutes it takes to go through the car wash versus all the time of washing it yourself.</li>
<li>Hiring a financial advisor instead of stressing and spending time handling all your own investments.</li>
<li>Spending all the time researching investments versus just investing in index funds.</li>
<li>Hiring an accountant to take care of your taxes versus trying to tackle them on your own.</li>
<li>Hanging Christmas lights</li>
<li>Managing physical rental properties versus just investing in REITs.</li>
<li>Having food delivered versus getting in your car and driving to go pick up food to then just bring it back home.</li>
</ul>
<p>So&#8230;now it&#8217;s your turn. Anyone reading this outsource any (unpleasant) tasks? Let us know which ones in the comments below.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://esimoney.com/millionaire-thoughts-on-buying-time/">Millionaire Thoughts on Buying Time</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://esimoney.com">ESI Money</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://esimoney.com/millionaire-thoughts-on-buying-time/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>6</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Retirement Update: 6.25 Years</title>
		<link>https://esimoney.com/retirement-update-6-25-years/</link>
					<comments>https://esimoney.com/retirement-update-6-25-years/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[ESI]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2022 09:00:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Retirement]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://esimoney.com/?p=9155</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Well, it&#8217;s that time again &#8212; time for another retirement update where I share what it&#8217;s like in the retired world of ESI! And there&#8217;s some big news in this post! FYI, I did an update in August titled Retirement Update: 6 Years. If you missed that you may want to go there first to [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://esimoney.com/retirement-update-6-25-years/">Retirement Update: 6.25 Years</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://esimoney.com">ESI Money</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://esimoney.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Ft-Lauderdale-Beach-FL-new.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-9156" src="https://esimoney.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Ft-Lauderdale-Beach-FL-new-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://esimoney.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Ft-Lauderdale-Beach-FL-new-300x200.jpg 300w, https://esimoney.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Ft-Lauderdale-Beach-FL-new.jpg 750w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a>Well, it&#8217;s that time again &#8212; time for another retirement update where I share what it&#8217;s like in the retired world of ESI! And there&#8217;s some big news in this post!</p>
<p>FYI, I did an update in August titled <a href="https://esimoney.com/retirement-update-6-years/">Retirement Update: 6 Years</a>. If you missed that you may want to go there first to catch up.</p>
<p>FWIW, this might be my last &#8220;official&#8221; retirement update for several months. That&#8217;s because I&#8217;m headed to Florida this winter and will likely give monthly updates from The Villages (like I did last year). These will provide more than enough details as to what&#8217;s going on with us in retirement. We&#8217;ll see what I decide to do. As you&#8217;ll find out in a moment&#8230;we&#8217;re kind of in flux right now.</p>
<p>With that said, let&#8217;s get started with the big news&#8230;</p>
<h4><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>We Bought a House in The Villages</strong></span></h4>
<p>Yep. We just bought a place in The Villages (TV). Actually, we&#8217;re in the process of buying and close in late November. Here&#8217;s how it all came to be&#8230;</p>
<p>Our plan had been to rent there early next year and (hopefully/maybe) buy a place near the new town square of Eastport in 2023.</p>
<p>A few months ago, that looked like a reasonable plan.</p>
<p>But as things have developed, it appears that Eastport won&#8217;t be done and homes around it available for much longer &#8212; 2-3 years down the road (maybe 2024 or 2025).</p>
<p>This meant that we&#8217;d be renting for this year AND two more years most likely&#8230;and even then the developments we would like might not be the first they completed&#8230;so our wait could be longer. Rental prices are going nowhere but up with Jan-April at $18k (this year &#8212; what we locked in back in May &#8212; it&#8217;s much higher now), will be $20k+ next year and look to be even higher the year after that.</p>
<p>When we began looking at $60k in rental fees over three years not to mention the hassle of trying to find a place, get our stuff down there, and all the associated issues with renting, we thought about buying a small place, using it as a vacation home (for 4-8 months a year), and if need be, selling it if we didn&#8217;t like it/no longer wanted it (FYI, when you buy a new home in TV you sign an agreement saying you won&#8217;t/can&#8217;t sell it within the first year).</p>
<p>We talked to our agent and there was only one village we were interested in between now and the development of Eastport (from what we know currently and what the agent knows) and that&#8217;s the Village of Richmond. The great thing about it is that it&#8217;s very close to a town square &#8212; Brownwood Paddock Square (which was the reason we were interested in Eastport as well &#8212; we wanted a place near a town square).</p>
<p>Here&#8217;s a relatively recent tour of Richmond:</p>
<p><center><iframe loading="lazy" title="YouTube video player" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/nsRNb_1xZmM" width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></center>The problem with Richmond is that they were selling homes currently. Not in 2-3 months or even in a year &#8212; they have been on the market for some time (I&#8217;d say about half the homes are sold) and are going like hotcakes.</p>
<p>So we had to decide &#8212; were we willing to make the move right away or did we want to wait? And even if we did try immediately, there was no guarantee we&#8217;d get something. The forums I follow on TV said sometimes there were up to 10 buyers trying to get a place in Richmond when it came available. Yikes!</p>
<p>Eventually we decided we&#8217;d try to buy a place. Initially we looked at <a href="https://www.thevillages.com/our-homes/patio-villas">patio villas</a>, small 2 bed/2 bath places &#8212; the same type that my dad has.</p>
<p>But if we bought a place like that, we would be banking on someplace in Eastport being open that we liked (if we ever decided to move down there full time or wanted a better vacation spot) as we didn&#8217;t want to live in a place that small. Plus, there weren&#8217;t really any places/styles/locations we liked in the patio villa options. So we went to plan B&#8230;</p>
<p>We then moved on to the next levels of homes &#8212; <a href="https://www.thevillages.com/our-homes/the-verandas">Verandas</a> and <a href="https://www.thevillages.com/our-homes/designer-homes">Designer</a> homes. These are bigger (and more expensive) but also might be places we really liked, would want to live in eventually, and might take buying another place in Eastport out of the equation (or at least give us options).</p>
<p>Our realtor sent us a map of places available by lot as well as what style home was going to be on each lot. From there we looked at lots we wanted that had homes on them we liked and made a Google spreadsheet for our realtor. Then we could track what we were interested in, when it was up for sale, etc.</p>
<p>We sent her the list on Saturday, October 22. On Monday, October 24, we got a call from our realtor at 5 p.m. that said two of the homes near the top of our list were going on sale the next day.</p>
<p>As a refresher in case you don&#8217;t know, here&#8217;s how TV sells new homes:</p>
<ul>
<li>The night before they become available, TV lets realtors know which homes will be for sale the next day at 8 am.</li>
<li>The realtors then contact their buyers, determine whether they are interested or not, and proceed accordingly.</li>
<li>If the buyers are interested, the realtor will be at his/her computer at 8 am the next morning, refreshing the screen constantly as it&#8217;s first come, first served. The first one to get a home once it shows up as available has 24 hours to commit to it. If they do not, it goes to the second in line and so on until there&#8217;s a final buyer.</li>
</ul>
<p>When my dad bought his place, he tried 3 or 4 times until he got one. He was second, third, and even farther back all the other times until he got a place.</p>
<p>Our place was a bit bigger and more expensive, so there would probably be fewer competitors, but it would still be a race to get it. I pegged our chances of being first at 1 in 3.</p>
<p>The other thing was the first homes to come up for sale were not at the top of our list. They were in the top 5 or so (out of 15 we had identified), but not #1.</p>
<p>And&#8230;even though we knew we approved of the lot and the home&#8217;s layout, we did not know if we liked the inside designs. Those could be perfect for us or ones we hated.</p>
<p>So our agent went to the homes on Monday night, videotaped them, and sent us the videos. We got to see the colors, fixtures, etc. plus any extra add ons (both places had expanded lanais (which we liked) and one had carpet in the bedrooms and two master closets (which we also liked.))</p>
<p>After looking over the videos and having a hour or so to determine what to do, we decided we&#8217;d bid on one of the homes. It was a &#8220;Begonia&#8221; design&#8230;which <a href="https://www.thevillages.com/homefinder/model/Begonia?new&amp;preowned&amp;homesites&amp;status&amp;lng=-81.99355979584547&amp;lat=28.87421165371721&amp;lvl=0">you can see here</a>.</p>
<p>My wife liked the colors and design much better than the other one and we liked the carpet in the bedrooms and the expanded lanai.</p>
<p>Coincidently, this is the same model type we rented in January-March of this year from our friends, so we knew it well.</p>
<p>The location was good, but not perfect. The second home had a BIT better location IMO (not as good in my wife&#8217;s opinion).</p>
<p>It is in the heart of the action (near a recreation center), which is what we wanted. It&#8217;s also close to the walking path, so we could WALK to Brownwood &#8212; very nice. And we can see the pickleball courts from the house, basically giving us our own backyard pickleball courts. Hahaha.</p>
<p>We will see how we like it and can go in several different ways:</p>
<ul>
<li>If we do like it, we could keep it and use it either as a vacation home or as a main home if we ever decided to move down there.</li>
<li>If we don&#8217;t like it and want to move to Eastport or completely abandon TV, we could sell it. The purchase price is a decent amount and homes like it are going for more on the secondary market as of now.</li>
<li>Or, if we don&#8217;t like it, we could move to Eastport and keep it &#8212; either renting it out (Jan-Mar rental numbers would cover all annual expenses) or use it for friends and family to stay in.</li>
</ul>
<p>As for our house in Colorado, how we transition, etc., that&#8217;s all a work in progress as of now. We don&#8217;t need to sell anything and had enough in cash (barely) to buy the new place outright and not sell our current home (I had money remaining from the sale of our rentals last year).</p>
<p>We will most likely move our state of residence to Florida as we&#8217;ll be there more than six months per year (our current plan is to be there from December 2022 until sometime in May, then come back in October-December 2023, sooner if we sell our Colorado home.) Anyway, there&#8217;s no state income tax in Florida, so I&#8217;m looking forward to that! <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/14.0.0/72x72/1f609.png" alt="😉" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></p>
<p>FYI, we still do have our rental in the Village of St. Catherine for January-April. The good news is that we rented it through a rental company closely associated with The Villages and they are more than helpful in renting out places to others when you&#8217;re buying something from them. LOL. They are pretty confident they can rent it out for us (and thus release us from our agreement) from Jan-Mar (and probably get more than what we agreed to pay as rates are way up). They are fairly confident they can rent it out in April. If they can&#8217;t for April, we&#8217;ll use it for friends and family who want to visit, treating them to a free vacation. <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/14.0.0/72x72/1f609.png" alt="😉" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></p>
<p>Anyway, that&#8217;s it for now.</p>
<h4><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>Life</strong></span></h4>
<p>It was a pretty normal late summer and early fall in Colorado. Nothing too out of the ordinary or noteworthy. We spent most of it close to home, playing pickleball, and hanging out with family. But there were a few notable happenings&#8230;</p>
<ul>
<li>In September my brother-in-law was supposed to visit us but he got Covid and had to cancel. But my biological father did come and brought his new wife. We had a good visit and made a couple standard <a href="https://esimoney.com/what-to-do-when-visiting-colorado-springs/">Colorado Springs tourist stops</a>. The first was to the <a href="https://gardenofgods.com/">Garden of the Gods</a> (a must see, of course). The second was a trip to the top of Pikes Peak via the <a href="https://www.cograilway.com/">Cog Railway</a> one day. I posted some pictures of both trips on Instagram &#8212; so <a href="https://www.instagram.com/esimoneyblog/">if you follow me there</a> you&#8217;ve seen them.</li>
<li>My dad (step-dad) has now been living in The Villages for six months and LOVES it. He&#8217;s making friends, going to Zumba, working out at the gym I went to last winter in Brownwood Square, and listening to music most nights on the square. I got to see him in September when my daughter and I drove up from Orlando (see below for details) and he&#8217;s doing well. Hurricane Ian missed the Villages &#8212; all they had was a few inches of rain and some downed palm branches.</li>
<li>Speaking of Hurricane Ian, I watched a lot of footage of the damage in Ft. Myers Beach and was able to find the vacation house we had stayed in many years ago (detailed in <a href="https://esimoney.com/retirement-update-3-25-years/">Retirement Update: 3.25 Years</a>.) It&#8217;s gone. Completely gone. The only thing left is the pool that was in the back yard. So sad.</li>
<li>We did the annual Parade of Homes in September &#8212; my wife, daughter, son-in-law, and me &#8212; seeing 25 homes or so in two days (we have a system and know how to map out a good route.) As usual it was fun to see new homes and how people are designing them. We didn&#8217;t get any ideas for our place this year, but we do have tentative plans for some new carpet and paint while we&#8217;re gone this winter.</li>
<li>We&#8217;ll be going to The Villages earlier than we&#8217;d planned. Anyway, <a href="https://www.instagram.com/esimoneyblog/">stay tuned to both Instagram</a> (I post &#8220;retirement life&#8221; pictures there weekly) and ESI Money (with more in-depth coverage) to keep up.</li>
</ul>
<h4><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>Health</strong></span></h4>
<ul>
<li>I am still working out six times a week &#8212; three cardio days and three weights days. I see my trainer every 4 weeks for a new weight routine. I thought I might need to do a bit more, but at my annual physical my doctor said my vitals were &#8220;perfect.&#8221; I asked if I should do anything different exercise-wise and he said, &#8220;I wouldn&#8217;t change a thing. Your vitals are perfect, so keep doing whatever you&#8217;re doing.&#8221;</li>
<li>Now that it&#8217;s turned colder, more people have joined our gym to play pickleball. We upgraded our membership to &#8220;Signature&#8221; level, which for an extra $60 a month allows us to play unlimited pickleball. Given that it&#8217;s $10 a pop to play each time and I play five times a week (not to mention what my wife plays), you can see how $60 is a better deal. Hahahaha.</li>
<li>In early October our gym had its first fall classic pickleball tournament. My partner and I were going to sign up for 4.0 men&#8217;s doubles, but since they didn&#8217;t segregate the teams by ages (which most bigger tournaments do), we elected to play 3.5 men&#8217;s (we are 4.0 for our ages, but playing against 20 and 30-year olds makes it pretty tough on us.) We had an up and down day and did just enough to barely squeak into the gold medal match. Once there, we played like we knew we could and won 2 out of 3 in two games &#8212; 11-5 and 11-2 (beating a team that had beaten us in the round robin section earlier that day). We were happy (of course) and thrilled to win. FYI, I shared a picture of us on Instagram as well.</li>
<li>I&#8217;m also still walking a lot and averaging over 20k steps per day. The summer was actually a time when I averaged fewer than 20,000 a day (too hot to walk sometimes) but now that it&#8217;s cooler I&#8217;m hitting 25k+ on some days (like when I do cardio and play pickleball).</li>
<li>I have been seeing doctors left and right to get in all my visits before we leave for Florida. All I have left is a second dentist appointment (six month visit)!</li>
</ul>
<h4><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>Entertainment</strong></span></h4>
<ul>
<li>My wife and I got wind of <a href="https://www.hallmarkchannel.com/chesapeake-shores">Chesapeake Shores</a>, a Hallmark Channel TV series that has been on for six seasons (the last (and final) season was just this year). We have spent the last couple months watching through all the seasons and finally finished it in October. We also watched/are watching the Lord of the Rings series with our kids (when they come over every Saturday), Young Sheldon, AFV, Shark Tank, This Old House, House Hunters, and a few more.</li>
<li>We also watch a lot of YouTube. Funny videos (like Fail Army) and posts on The Villages are the mainstays together, but I also watch several money channels, video game channels, and a few channels on creating a YouTube channel (see below for more on that.)</li>
<li>I have spent a lot of time with my PS5 the last quarter. I got Horizon Forbidden West and have about 80 hours played so far (I spend a lot of time wandering and doing side missions.) My plan is to be done with it before we head to Florida at the end of December. Gotham Knights is just out and I would normally buy it, but I won&#8217;t have time to do it justice before we go, so I&#8217;ll wait until we get back in May. Besides, when I order games on launch day, I generally get done with them after a couple months. Then some cool DLC stuff comes out after six months and by then I have forgotten how to play my amped up character. So I&#8217;ll wait and some good extra content may be out by the time I get back.</li>
<li>I have been reading several books (both actual reading and audio listening) the past few months which are listed below. I&#8217;m still enjoying the amount of reading time I have these days. I am also listening to several podcasts.</li>
</ul>
<h4><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>Finances</strong></span></h4>
<ul>
<li>We ended October with a net worth of $6.1 million, down $430k from a year ago and the same from our high of $6.5 million (December 2021). Easy come, easy go. LOL! I&#8217;m still up almost $3 million since retiring and income is more than twice spending, so it&#8217;s not a big deal.</li>
<li>I had two syndication deals end this quarter (short-term land deals) and I reinvested the money into other projects. As of now I have 12 syndication deals for a total of $1.025 million invested. Together these pay $72,250 per year in income over the course of their investment periods (which is usually 5-7 years). I&#8217;m not looking for any additional deals as my current level of commitment is where I would like to stay for the time being. FYI, my dad got into one of the deals with me and he&#8217;s THRLLED that he&#8217;s earning 10% back on his money with a short-term (18 months) commitment.</li>
<li>As you&#8217;ll read in a month or so, we&#8217;ve ramped up our giving plan for the next five years. This quarter we sent a container of donated supplies to Ukraine as well as sent money to Florida to help people and the clean-up from Hurricane Ian. We&#8217;ll make one more small gift before the year is out that will put us at or over $100k for the year.</li>
</ul>
<h4><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>ESI Money and Millionaire Money Mentors</strong></span></h4>
<ul>
<li>ESI Money is still doing well&#8230;chugging along like always. I have hit a stride of sharing more interviews because I feel like the more stories people hear about how others have become wealthy, the more ideas and insights they&#8217;ll have to apply themselves.</li>
<li>There will be a change to ESI Money in 2023 as I&#8217;ll move from three posts a week to two. The move came after chatting about this with the mentors &#8212; they are GREAT to bounce ideas off of and discuss various options. I am spending more and more time in the Millionaire Money Mentors (MMM) forums and need to free up some time for other projects and pickleball. <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/14.0.0/72x72/1f609.png" alt="😉" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> I might start to syndicate posts from other bloggers which could bring the total posts per week back up to three, but that is still TBD. If you are a blogger and have a great post you&#8217;d like me to consider for syndication and/or you have a guest post you&#8217;d like to pitch, please email me your thoughts.</li>
<li>As you may have seen me mention here and there, my plan is to do minimal blog writing while we&#8217;re in Florida this winter. As such, I have been slaving away at posts and now have them completed through May 2023. As you&#8217;ll notice, some of the interviews take place a few months before they will post, but I have mentioned that on each one for some context.</li>
<li>I&#8217;ll be reaching a blogging milestone in a few years. In 2025 I&#8217;ll celebrate 20 years of blogging. I was writing (for national magazines) before that and coaching before that, so 2022 actually makes 30 years I have been teaching and writing about money. It&#8217;s pretty wild to think it&#8217;s been that long.</li>
<li>My daughter and I went to FinCon (money media conference) in Orlando in early September. It was part business, part vacation. We flew first class (which is way better than coach for long trips) and had fun visiting Universal Studios, Disney Springs, an outlet mall, and made a trip to see my dad for a day in the Villages. On the business side we attended some seminars and met some great people (my daughter picked up a couple clients). I also got to have dinner with JD Roth from get Rich Slowly as well as a couple awesome friends from the Millionaire Money Mentors forums. It was a really great time.</li>
<li>I have been considering ramping up (and taking seriously) my YouTube channel. I&#8217;m going through a course on it now and working through whether or not I&#8217;ll take it as a major project in 2023 (it&#8217;s probably 50/50 at the moment). All I have there now are some whiteboard videos my son did for me, so I need to do much more to get it in shape. If you want to follow me there just to see what happens, <a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCsdvovOqxDL3hbkKiFbrn8A">here&#8217;s my YouTube channel</a>.</li>
<li>I have been writing a TON in addition to getting ahead on ESI Money. I currently have 10 ebooks completed and edited&#8230;now I just need to get them designed. That might happen before we head to Florida but if not, I can manage that while down there. It&#8217;s part of my plan to offer products of various depths at various prices. I have ESI Money (free) and the <a href="https://esimoney.com/email-series/">email money series</a> (free), will have ebooks (very affordable), have a membership site (a bit more, but still a great deal), and might have courses some day (which will likely be the most costly but also have the most-focused content.) FYI, I&#8217;m also taking a course on how to create a course. Hahahaha.</li>
<li>The Millionaire Money Mentors site is now at record membership (it pretty much reaches a new record every time I have a sale). As noted above, I spend much more time there than I do on ESI Money and really enjoy the community, topics we discuss, and the wisdom from so many great people. I have made some great online friendships and hope to turn some of those into real-life friendships.</li>
<li>As a heads up, my next MMM sale will be Black Friday/Cyber Monday. It will be a great time to join the group (in time for the new year). It will be the last sale of the year (and probably last one for several months) and could be the final sale where the price is below $300. Hope to see you all there soon!</li>
<li>I always need more millionaire and (especially) retirement interviews!!!! I&#8217;m well ahead but time passes and we&#8217;ll use up all the ones I have backlogged, so if you&#8217;re interested in sharing one, please email me and I&#8217;ll send you the details. And remember, if you do a millionaire interview and agree to some low-level posting requirements, your MMM membership is free once your interview goes live (no refunds to existing members, but you don&#8217;t have to renew either.)</li>
<li>Finally, if you&#8217;re a regular ESI Money reader and have gotten something out of reading, please do me a favor and tell others about the site. I&#8217;d like to impact as many people as possible with some good financial content.</li>
</ul>
<h4><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>Books and Podcasts</strong></span></h4>
<p>Here are some of the books I&#8217;ve read since my last update plus a few podcasts I really enjoy:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://podcasts.apple.com/us/podcast/missed-fortune/id1636560953">Missed Fortune</a> &#8212; Tells the story of the treasure hunt started by Forrest Fenn &#8212; and in particular focuses on the story of one guy looking for it. Very fascinating. FYI, <a href="https://www.outsideonline.com/outdoor-adventure/exploration-survival/forrest-fenn-treasure-jack-stuef/">here&#8217;s an article with the highlights as well as details on the guy who found the treasure</a>.</li>
<li><a href="https://amzn.to/3yJkqEN">How to Get Paid for What You Know</a> &#8212; It&#8217;s a book about creating a course. It&#8217;s very good IMO and I&#8217;ll likely take it to Florida with me and re-read again. Plus I&#8217;ll then begin to plan my first course (I have one idea about 75% done, but I need to revisit it now that I&#8217;ve studied a bit &#8212; I can make it better.)</li>
<li><a href="https://amzn.to/3rUUHFt">YouTube Secrets</a> &#8212; This one I bought both the audio version as well as the book. I&#8217;ve listened to the book once and will be going through it a second time soon. It&#8217;s very good stuff and along with the course I&#8217;m taking, I think they have let me know what I should do on YouTube if I decide to go big there.</li>
<li><a href="https://amzn.to/3TlNBW5">Sparring Partners</a> &#8212; I love me some John Grisham! There are three short stories here with two of them (first and third) being quite good IMO.</li>
<li><a href="https://amzn.to/3CBPOG9">The Boys from Biloxi</a> &#8212; This is Grisham&#8217;s latest book which I&#8217;m listening to (and loving) now.</li>
<li><a href="https://amzn.to/3T3aFcD">The Five People You Meet in Heaven</a> &#8212; An oldie but a goodie! I remember wanting to buy it many years ago but it got pushed off my list by other books, so I got the Audible version and LOVED listening to it.</li>
<li><a href="https://podcasts.apple.com/us/podcast/the-villages-daily-sun-podcast/id1507397935">The Villages podcast</a> &#8212; I listen to it every Monday and know more about what&#8217;s going on in The Villages than most of the people who live there. LOL.</li>
</ul>
<p>That&#8217;s it for this report. Any thoughts or questions?</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://esimoney.com/retirement-update-6-25-years/">Retirement Update: 6.25 Years</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://esimoney.com">ESI Money</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://esimoney.com/retirement-update-6-25-years/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>16</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Millionaire Interview 340</title>
		<link>https://esimoney.com/millionaire-interview-340/</link>
					<comments>https://esimoney.com/millionaire-interview-340/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[ESI]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2022 09:00:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Millionaires]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://esimoney.com/?p=8795</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Here’s our latest interview with a millionaire as we seek to learn from those who have grown their wealth to high heights. If you’d like to be considered for an interview, drop me a note and we can chat about specifics. This interview took place in June. My questions are in bold italics and their [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://esimoney.com/millionaire-interview-340/">Millionaire Interview 340</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://esimoney.com">ESI Money</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://esimoney.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/Older-couple-walking-bridge-in-mountains-new.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-8800" src="https://esimoney.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/Older-couple-walking-bridge-in-mountains-new-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://esimoney.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/Older-couple-walking-bridge-in-mountains-new-300x200.jpg 300w, https://esimoney.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/Older-couple-walking-bridge-in-mountains-new.jpg 750w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a>Here’s our latest <a href="https://esimoney.com/category/millionaires/">interview with a millionaire</a> as we seek to learn from those who have grown their wealth to high heights.</p>
<p>If you’d like to be considered for an interview, <a href="https://esimoney.com/contact/">drop me a note</a> and we can chat about specifics.</p>
<p>This interview took place in June.</p>
<p>My questions are in bold italics and their responses follow in black.</p>
<p>Let&#8217;s get started&#8230;</p>
<h4><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>OVERVIEW</strong></span></h4>
<p><em><strong>How old are you (and spouse if applicable, plus how long you&#8217;ve been married)?</strong></em></p>
<p>I am 64 and my wife recently turned 65.</p>
<p>We have been married for 40 years though it seems like a much shorter period of time!</p>
<p>We’ve had some amazing experiences together and look forward to many more.</p>
<p><em><strong>Do you have kids/family (if so, how old are they)?</strong></em></p>
<p>We have 3 children.</p>
<p>Our two oldest are each in their mid-thirties, married and working.</p>
<p>Our third child is a 16 year old 11th grader who keeps us smiling!</p>
<p><em><strong>What area of the country do you live in (and urban or rural)?</strong></em></p>
<p>For the last 5 years we’ve lived in a suburb of a midsize Midwestern city.</p>
<p>Prior to that we lived in a smaller town as well as overseas.</p>
<p><em><strong>What is your current net worth?</strong></em></p>
<p>Our current net worth is $4,425,000.</p>
<p><em><strong>What are the main assets that make up your net worth (stocks, real estate, business, home, retirement accounts, etc.) and any debt that offsets part of these?</strong></em></p>
<p>Our net worth is invested primarily in low cost, ETF’s and mutual funds although we are currently holding a lot of cash. It breaks down like this:</p>
<p><a href="https://esimoney.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/MI-340-Chart-1-new.png"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-8796" src="https://esimoney.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/MI-340-Chart-1-new-777x1024.png" alt="" width="777" height="1024" srcset="https://esimoney.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/MI-340-Chart-1-new-777x1024.png 777w, https://esimoney.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/MI-340-Chart-1-new-228x300.png 228w, https://esimoney.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/MI-340-Chart-1-new-768x1012.png 768w, https://esimoney.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/MI-340-Chart-1-new.png 937w" sizes="(max-width: 777px) 100vw, 777px" /></a></p>
<h4><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>EARN</strong></span></h4>
<p><em><strong>What is your job?</strong></em></p>
<p>I think I’ve always had an entrepreneurial spirit. When I was in Jr. High School I was selling little trinkets that my friends and I made. I’d also buy candy bars at a discount and sell them at full price in school. The kids were happy to get the candy and trinkets and I was happy to make a small profit.</p>
<p>I started working my first real job part-time at 16 making $1.65 an hour. This was great and I was really thrilled when I received a .10 cent an hour raise for no apparent reason other than doing my job!</p>
<p>I participated in a number of different service and sales jobs working my way through college. Before completing my bachelor’s degree I took some time off from school and worked in the manufacturing sector with a small company where I enjoyed the opportunity to go from the lowest paid entry level job on the manufacturing floor through a number of positions to become Director of Operations. Moving through many positions in the company and learning how everything is connected and being able to contribute in a meaningful way confirmed that I really enjoyed business and in particular learning how businesses work and participating in improving them.</p>
<p>I moved on to other business opportunities but more importantly I fell in love with my future wife and then determined that the responsible thing to do was go back to school to complete my bachelor’s degree. During this time I started a business and continued developing it. About a year after graduating from college I sold that business and my wife and I used the proceeds to travel around the world for a year. We learned a lot, grew closer together and developed an appreciation for people and cultures around the world. We traveled to dozens of countries, experienced great hospitality and grew in our faith.</p>
<p>Returning home I had the opportunity to purchase a partnership interest in a small service business and it looked like a great opportunity for growth. This turned into a 15 year career in which the value of the business increased from $50,000 to a little over $2,000,000 culminating in the sale of the business in 2001.</p>
<p>Following the sale of the business both my wife and I have been involved with a non-profit organization as volunteers. As volunteers we did not receive any salary so in that sense we have been retired since 2002.</p>
<p><em><strong>What is your annual income?</strong></em></p>
<p>Currently we have no earned income.</p>
<p>We are trying to be more tax efficient at this stage of life. Our Adjusted Gross Income over the past 15 years has ranged from 49K to 134K. Some of the variation has to do with Roth IRA conversions.</p>
<p><em><strong>Tell us about your income performance over time. What was the starting salary of your first job, how did it grow from there (and what you did to make it grow), and where are you now?</strong></em></p>
<p>I started working part time while in high school at $1.65/hr in 1973. I don’t have good records of my earnings over the next 14 years but a good part of that time I was working part time while in school. I worked in various service jobs and sometimes operated my own businesses during this time.</p>
<p>The following table is my salary and bonus from 1987 – 2001. This was during the time that I was growing a service business. Over this 15 year period my average salary and bonus was about 105K per year.</p>
<p><a href="https://esimoney.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/MI-340-chart-2-new.png"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-8797" src="https://esimoney.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/MI-340-chart-2-new.png" alt="" width="397" height="975" srcset="https://esimoney.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/MI-340-chart-2-new.png 397w, https://esimoney.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/MI-340-chart-2-new-122x300.png 122w" sizes="(max-width: 397px) 100vw, 397px" /></a></p>
<p>2001 was really the end of my earning period. From 2002 – 2017 I had an average earned income of 12K per year (this was the value of an insurance benefit received from the non-profit, which was treated as income for tax purposes).</p>
<p><em><strong>What tips do you have for others who want to grow their career-related income?</strong></em></p>
<p>My career income has been primarily from self-employment. In that arena you look for ways to be more efficient and increase profit which allows you to increase wages.</p>
<p>I did go back to college again while running the business in order to obtain an <a href="https://esimoney.com/the-value-of-an-mba/">MBA</a>. The ideas and skills I learned in the MBA program helped to increase our revenue, profits and business value.</p>
<p>In addition, participating in industry conferences and meetings helped us develop in ways we might never have been aware of otherwise. I think <a href="https://esimoney.com/7-steps-to-millions-more-continue-learning-and-developing-skills/">continual learning</a> and application of what you learn is a key to growing career-related income.</p>
<p><em><strong>What&#8217;s your work-life balance look like?</strong></em></p>
<p>Work-life balance has been pretty good most of the time. I think spending a year with my wife as we traveled early in our marriage had a positive impact on that.</p>
<p>As an owner and manager of the business I worked long hours at times but we also had opportunities for extended time away with our kids.</p>
<p>When becoming full time volunteers we considered ourselves “employees” but we included our kids in trips and various “work” activities all along the way.</p>
<p><em><strong>Do you have any sources of income besides your career? If so, can you list them, give us a feel for how much you earn with each, and offer some insight into how you developed them?</strong></em></p>
<p>We have 3 sources of current taxable income. The approximate amounts are:</p>
<ul>
<li>Rental income &#8211; 20K per year.</li>
<li><a href="https://esimoney.com/seven-steps-to-creating-passive-income-through-dividend-investing/">Dividend and interest income</a> – 25K. This is from our taxable accounts.</li>
<li>Social Security income – 39K</li>
</ul>
<p>I am temporarily taking Social Security income. Since we have a minor child at home there is an additional child benefit (about 66% of my benefit) which makes <a href="https://esimoney.com/a-case-for-claiming-social-security-early/">taking Social Security early</a> more attractive.</p>
<p>I plan to stop Social Security at age 66-1/2 when our child benefit ends and then wait until age 70 to start Social Security again in order to maximize the total payout.</p>
<h4><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>SAVE</strong></span></h4>
<p><em><strong>What is your annual spending?</strong></em></p>
<p>Our annual spending is about 90,000.</p>
<p><em><strong>What are the main categories (expenses) this spending breaks into?</strong></em></p>
<p><a href="https://esimoney.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/MI-340-Chart-3-new.png"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-8798" src="https://esimoney.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/MI-340-Chart-3-new-618x1024.png" alt="" width="618" height="1024" srcset="https://esimoney.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/MI-340-Chart-3-new-618x1024.png 618w, https://esimoney.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/MI-340-Chart-3-new-181x300.png 181w, https://esimoney.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/MI-340-Chart-3-new-768x1272.png 768w, https://esimoney.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/MI-340-Chart-3-new.png 812w" sizes="(max-width: 618px) 100vw, 618px" /></a></p>
<p><em><strong>Do you have a budget? If so, how do you implement it?</strong></em></p>
<p>Early in our marriage we used a formal budget and tracked everything to the penny. This was a big help at the time and helped us set up good habits so that spending has never gotten out of control for us.</p>
<p>We do not have a formal budget now. I take a look at credit card purchases and online bank statements fairly regularly. I set up email notifications on both so I get notified when there is a transaction.</p>
<p>I try to review transactions every few months to see if there is anything amiss and I look at the budgeting tool in Personal Capital to see a current breakdown of expenses. (I like the overview of the Personal Capital tool but I do have to go in and correct auto-generated categories that get mixed up quite regularly.)</p>
<p>My wife and I will agree on a projected (budget?) amount to set spending targets in major categories and we make any major purchases together.</p>
<p><em><strong>What percentage of your gross income do you save and how has that changed over time?</strong></em></p>
<p>Since we are not earning salaries at this time we are not saving.</p>
<p>I think we saved at a fairly high rate from 1987 to 2000 as our net worth during those 15 years went from 31K to 1,547K excluding the value of the business.</p>
<p><em><strong>What&#8217;s your best tip for saving (accumulating) money?</strong></em></p>
<p>Saving money for retirement should be viewed as a required expense which is paid out before many of life’s other “necessities”.</p>
<p>While flexibility and the freedom to vary from plans is an important part of making good decisions in order to enjoy life’s experiences, developing a habit of funding a savings program is foundational to acquiring a reasonable net worth.</p>
<p>Developing habits early on like giving regularly to church/charities, saving for retirement and saving for other purposes becomes a way of life. Over time the amounts can be increased but getting started early and being consistent is key.</p>
<p><em><strong>What&#8217;s your best tip for spending less money?</strong></em></p>
<p>We have found that spending can easily become such a habit that we don’t realize we are doing it. Many of our best experiences have been in other countries with people who don’t have the same basic resources that we have in western societies. Realizing that many of our own perceived needs are really luxuries for much of the world has helped us consider our spending more carefully.</p>
<p>We’ve learned to move a little more slowly in making major purchases. We purchase used vehicles and some of our furniture and household items were also purchased used. We are happy to take hand-me-downs from friends or neighbors when appropriate. We use the local library for online books and audio books as well as physical books. We look for local events that we can attend while paying little or nothing in entry fees. We walk a lot which is a great form of exercise and doesn’t cost much… we probably buy more shoes than we would need if not walking so much.</p>
<p><em><strong>What is your favorite thing to spend money on/your secret splurge?</strong></em></p>
<p>It’s not a secret that we love to travel and experience cultures different from our own.</p>
<p>We travel mostly as budget travelers which saves money but also allows us to experience things more like the locals in many settings.</p>
<h4><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>INVEST</strong></span></h4>
<p><em><strong>What is your investment philosophy/plan?</strong></em></p>
<p>We target a long-term average return that will support our retirement plans with a high degree of certainty.</p>
<p>I think of myself as fairly risk tolerant in investments primarily because I have always had a long-term horizon. So if investments dropped in value I felt fine riding it out over the long haul.</p>
<p>Now that we are in our mid-sixties we are becoming more interested in the shorter term since we actually are using our investment returns to fund our current expenses.</p>
<p>We are learning more about retirement planning and appropriate investing and will be developing a written plan in the near future.</p>
<p>Even though we have been living off of our retirement assets for the past 20 years I think we felt that if we ever had the need, we could stop what we were doing and go get a paying job to increase or replace income if we ever needed to. Now we are looking at a more traditional retirement timing and want to increase security and limit potential losses if possible.</p>
<p><em><strong>What has been your best investment?</strong></em></p>
<p>My best investment was buying into and then developing a business over 15 years.</p>
<p>This provided a good income and a good return on the investment allowing us to be retired by age 45.</p>
<p><em><strong>What has been your worst investment?</strong></em></p>
<p>My worst investment was some sort of a futures contract on Mexican Pesos in the late 70’s or early 80’s.</p>
<p>It was a $5,000 “investment” that turned into $0 overnight.</p>
<p>It was a good lesson and helped me really take to heart that investing in something you don’t understand is not a good idea. In fact it’s not really an investment at that point – just wild speculation.</p>
<p><em><strong>What&#8217;s been your overall return?</strong></em></p>
<p>I don’t have good data to determine my overall return but I do have a pretty good estimate of our net worth each year since 1987.</p>
<p>Here is that info:</p>
<p><a href="https://esimoney.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/MI-340-Chart-4-new.png"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-8799" src="https://esimoney.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/MI-340-Chart-4-new-291x1024.png" alt="" width="291" height="1024" srcset="https://esimoney.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/MI-340-Chart-4-new-291x1024.png 291w, https://esimoney.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/MI-340-Chart-4-new-85x300.png 85w, https://esimoney.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/MI-340-Chart-4-new.png 412w" sizes="(max-width: 291px) 100vw, 291px" /></a></p>
<p><em><strong>How often do you monitor/review your portfolio?</strong></em></p>
<p>I keep track of our portfolio in Personal Capital. At the end of each month I capture the values of each account and copy that into a spreadsheet. I use the spreadsheet to be able to look at different types of assets from a tax perspective.</p>
<p>I find it’s good to type in the numbers each month, looking at the previous month’s numbers to see how we are doing.</p>
<p>I don’t get too concerned about up or down movements as history indicates that we are heading in the right direction over time.</p>
<p>I don’t “watch” the financial markets but I will take a look from time to time.</p>
<h4><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>NET WORTH</strong></span></h4>
<p><em><strong>How did you accumulate your net worth?</strong></em></p>
<p>Consistent savings and investing along with developing the value of a business were our primary accumulation tools.</p>
<p>Lack of debt was also a factor in increasing our net worth. When we got married my wife had a small amount of student loan debt but that was it. Other than mortgages for the purchase of our homes we have not carried any additional personal debt.</p>
<p>In the late 1980’s I joined a local investment club and started investing in stocks. We would meet to discuss particular companies and decide whether or not to invest. We invested through Dividend Reinvestment Plans (DRIPs) which allowed small dollar purchases of partial shares and reinvestment of dividends. These transactions had no fees which was not the case with stock brokers in those days!</p>
<p>I learned about researching and investing and this was a major factor in growing our net worth in the 1990’s.</p>
<p><em><strong>What would you say is your greatest strength in the ESI wealth-building model (Earn, Save or Invest) and why would you say it&#8217;s tops?</strong></em></p>
<p>When I consider Earn &#8211; I feel like I have not earned that much in my lifetime. My highest earnings were the 15 years from 1987 to 2001 in which I average about 105K. Before that I made less and since then I have not really had any real earned income.</p>
<p>I think we have done well with both Save and Invest. I think in both of those categories our strength was not a super power or secret method but rather consistency over time.</p>
<p><em><strong>What road bumps did you face along the way to becoming a millionaire and how did you handle them?</strong></em></p>
<p>I can’t really identify any significant road bumps. Well maybe one…</p>
<p>While we were living internationally, and in a very remote area of the world, I had our investment accounts managed by an advisory firm back home. I felt that since I wasn’t accessible it would be wise to have someone else making decisions with our investments. I didn’t want to have everything crash and just ride it into the ground unaware.</p>
<p>It turned out that our accounts did go down substantially and then the advisor took us out of equities near the bottom and we missed out on a lot of the upside growth that followed.</p>
<p>I can’t really say if I would have done anything differently in the situation but I learned that I’d rather be the one making decisions no matter what the outcome when it comes to our investments!</p>
<p><em><strong>What are you currently doing to maintain/grow your net worth?</strong></em></p>
<p>Since we are not generating any additional capital to add to the base we are spending whatever we need and reinvesting any excess generated by our net worth.</p>
<p><em><strong>Do you have a target net worth you are trying to attain?</strong></em></p>
<p>We do not have a target net worth we are trying to attain.</p>
<p>Surprisingly it seems like whatever level we attain I’m always interested to see if we can get a little farther ahead of the game.</p>
<p>I have to say that I’m not primarily motivated by money but it is a way of keeping score in the game and I’m drawn to that.</p>
<p><em><strong>How old were you when you made your first million and have you had any significant behavior shifts since then?</strong></em></p>
<p>From preparing this interview I see that I was 40 or 41 when our net worth hit 1,000,000 excluding the value of the business we were building.</p>
<p>I don’t think it made an impact since we knew the business had some value but placing an accurate value on it was an exercise in futility.</p>
<p>When I was younger I knew I’d like to be a millionaire someday but it wasn’t a clear goal for me.</p>
<p>My lifetime goals in those days were to get married at 25 and be able to retire at 50. I beat them both getting married at 24 and being retired by 45.</p>
<p><em><strong>What money mistakes have you made along the way that others can learn from?</strong></em></p>
<p>If I was a little younger and planning to stay in one area I think I would get more involved with real estate rentals. This seems like a good fit as a side gig if you follow a good management system.</p>
<p>I did invest in a number of single family residences before I was married but then moved to another part of the country and had to work hard to sell off my highly leveraged properties since I wasn’t doing a great job of managing them from a long distance.</p>
<p><em><strong>What advice do you have for ESI Money readers on how to become wealthy?</strong></em></p>
<p>It’s never too late. Get started and keep at it.</p>
<p><a href="https://esimoney.com/the-best-way-to-maximize-your-investment-return/">Time is your friend in building wealth</a>.</p>
<h4><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>FUTURE</strong></span></h4>
<p><em><strong>What are your plans for the future regarding lifestyle?</strong></em></p>
<p>We don’t anticipate significant changes in lifestyle.</p>
<p>We might downsize the home to a condo and/or decide to buy some kind of recreational vehicle to travel/live in part time at some point in the future but not seeing this as a major lifestyle change.</p>
<p><em><strong>What are your retirement plans?</strong></em></p>
<p>Since we are already 20 years into retirement we want to have a more definitive plan that allows us to travel and participate in our chosen activities while providing a sense of long term security.</p>
<p><em><strong>Are there any issues in retirement that concern you? If so, how are you planning to address them?</strong></em></p>
<p>We navigated the health insurance issue with some years of group coverage as volunteers, some years of high deductible private insurance and some years of healthcare sharing ministries.</p>
<p>This year my wife and I will be covered by Medicare and we will look at the options for our 16 year old.</p>
<h4><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>MISCELLANEOUS</strong></span></h4>
<p><em><strong>How did you learn about finances and at what age did it &#8220;click&#8221;?</strong></em></p>
<p>I’ve always been interested in business and finance.</p>
<p>I don’t know when it clicked but I must have been a child. I remember going to the savings and loan association to open an account and get a passbook so I could ride my bicycle over to make deposits and increase my savings.</p>
<p><em><strong>Who inspired you to excel in life? Who are your heroes?</strong></em></p>
<p>Both of my parents were great role models. They worked hard but also played hard with the family going on camping trips, boating, dune buggies, etc.</p>
<p>They were generous with their possessions and I am blessed to have them as my parents.</p>
<p><em><strong>Do you have any favorite money books you like/recommend? If so, can you share with us your top three and why you like them?</strong></em></p>
<p>Three money books I read many years ago and enjoyed are:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://esimoney.com/the-best-personal-finance-books-of-all-time-your-money-or-your-life/">Your Money Or Your Life</a>&nbsp;</li>
<li><a href="https://esimoney.com/the-best-personal-finance-books-of-all-time-the-richest-man-in-babylon/">The Richest Man in Babylon</a>&nbsp;</li>
<li><a href="https://esimoney.com/the-best-personal-finance-books-of-all-time-the-millionaire-next-door/">The Millionaire Next Door</a>&nbsp;</li>
</ul>
<p>These days I enjoy reading a few blogs (like this one) and listening to a few podcasts in the personal finance space.</p>
<p>I also think the Bible has lots of good practical advice about finances and generosity.</p>
<p><em><strong>Do you give to charity? Why or why not? If you do, what percent of time/money do you give?</strong></em></p>
<p>We do give to charity. This is something I’ve done since first earning money. My parents taught me to put money in the offering at church when I was a child and it’s a good habit that stuck!</p>
<p>We always included giving to our church, missions and other charities as part of our everyday expenses. We have both volunteered on various boards of organizations and volunteered full-time for a number of years after selling the business.</p>
<p>Currently we continue to give to charities. We have set up a <a href="https://esimoney.com/the-advantages-of-using-a-donor-advised-fund/">Donor Advised Fund</a> (DAF) which is not part of our net worth since we have legally given the money to the fund. Currently the DAF has a balance of 256K which we direct to charitable organizations.</p>
<p>Giving to charity is part of who we are and we want to continue doing this throughout our lives.</p>
<p><em><strong>Do you plan to leave an inheritance for your heirs (how do you plan to distribute your wealth at your death)? What are your reasons behind this plan?</strong></em></p>
<p>Currently our will/trust provides some benefit for our children and some benefit for charities.</p>
<p>We need to work on this in more detail to update and determine appropriate amounts to share with our children and with charities. As we develop a more formal retirement plan it will help us define this more clearly in the near future. I think a part of our plan will include amounts to share with our kids in ways that will benefit and not harm them while we are still alive.</p>
<p>Overall we are so grateful and feel very blessed to have such wonderful opportunities.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://esimoney.com/millionaire-interview-340/">Millionaire Interview 340</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://esimoney.com">ESI Money</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://esimoney.com/millionaire-interview-340/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>4</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Retirement Interview 37</title>
		<link>https://esimoney.com/retirement-interview-37/</link>
					<comments>https://esimoney.com/retirement-interview-37/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[ESI]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2022 09:00:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Retirement]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://esimoney.com/?p=8856</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Here’s our latest interview with a retiree as we seek to learn from those who have actually taken the retirement plunge. If you’d like to be considered for an interview, drop me a note and we can chat about specifics. This interview was conducted in July. It&#8217;s with Akaisha and Billy from Retire Early Lifestyle. [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://esimoney.com/retirement-interview-37/">Retirement Interview 37</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://esimoney.com">ESI Money</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://esimoney.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/Billy-Akaisha-Chacala-Beach-new.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-8857" src="https://esimoney.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/Billy-Akaisha-Chacala-Beach-new-300x230.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="230" srcset="https://esimoney.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/Billy-Akaisha-Chacala-Beach-new-300x230.jpg 300w, https://esimoney.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/Billy-Akaisha-Chacala-Beach-new.jpg 750w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a>Here’s our latest interview with a retiree as we seek to learn from those who have actually taken the <a href="https://esimoney.com/category/retirement/">retirement</a> plunge.</p>
<p>If you’d like to be considered for an interview, <a href="https://esimoney.com/contact/">drop me a note</a> and we can chat about specifics.</p>
<p>This interview was conducted in July. It&#8217;s with Akaisha and Billy from <a href="https://www.retireearlylifestyle.com/">Retire Early Lifestyle</a>.</p>
<p>My questions are in bold italics and their responses follow in black.</p>
<p>Let&#8217;s get started&#8230;</p>
<h4><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>GENERAL OVERVIEW</strong></span></h4>
<p><em><strong>How old are you (and spouse if applicable, plus how long you&#8217;ve been married)?</strong></em></p>
<p>We just turned 70 this September, 2022.</p>
<p>We have been married for 44 years.</p>
<p><em><strong>Do you have kids/family (if so, how old are they)?</strong></em></p>
<p>We have no children.</p>
<p>During our younger years we were determined, and worked night and day running our restaurant. Then Billy was recruited to work as a stock broker for then Dean Witter, now known as Morgan Stanley Dean Witter.</p>
<p>We worked nights, weekends and holidays, not a great atmosphere in which to raise children.</p>
<p><em><strong>What area of the country do you live in (and urban or rural)?</strong></em></p>
<p>Although we both were born in Ohio, we met in coastal California and lived in a small touristy beach town.</p>
<p>We have been traveling the world for over 30 years, living in Asia, Mexico, Central America, the US and South America.</p>
<p>Currently we live in a small lakeside community in Chapala, Mexico.</p>
<p><em><strong>Is there anything else we should know about you?</strong></em></p>
<p>When we first met, Billy was a trained French Chef. We traveled Europe and came back to California to open up our own restaurant. We had no money so we purchased it with our own “no money down” approach, before this term was invented. We paid everyone off in 2 years.</p>
<p>Then, after 5 years running the restaurant 365 days a year, breakfast, lunch and dinner, Billy was recruited to be a stock broker, and shortly thereafter was promoted to office manager.</p>
<p>At the age of 38, in 1991, we retired from the conventional working world to travel the globe, before the 4% rule was created and before there was a FIRE movement.</p>
<h4><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>RETIREMENT OVERVIEW</strong></span></h4>
<p><em><strong>How do you define retirement?</strong></em></p>
<p>When we “retired” in 1991, there was no word for <a href="https://esimoney.com/what-is-financial-independence/">Financial Independence</a>. We don’t really use the word “retired” any longer, but rather describe ourselves as Financially independent – which means we can do what we want, when we want, where we want.</p>
<p>We spend a good deal of our time doing volunteer work, and our website is one of our volunteer projects. We want more people to become free of being wage slaves.</p>
<p>We use our free time to travel, learn languages and new skills.</p>
<p><em><strong>How long have you been retired?</strong></em></p>
<p>Since 1991, we are now in our 32st year.</p>
<p>In January of 2023 we begin our 33nd year.</p>
<p><em><strong>Is your spouse also retired?</strong></em></p>
<p>We retired together and began traveling the world.</p>
<p><em><strong>What was your career and income before retirement?</strong></em></p>
<p>When we became a team, Billy was the French Chef of our Restaurant, and Akaisha was the CEO.</p>
<p>Then Billy became a stock broker/manager and Akaisha ran the restaurant until we left the working world in January of 1991.</p>
<p>Once Billy became a stock broker we were making over 6 figures, paying down our mortgage and heavily investing the rest.</p>
<p><em><strong>Why did you retire?</strong></em></p>
<p>While we loved our jobs and both of us are very ambitious, our lives became filled with too many “have to’s” and we were like passing ships in the night. We wanted to have a life together, sharing, traveling, writing, photographing our travels, telling stories and helping others choose their best lives.</p>
<p>So, we took 2 years to plan this out, tracked our spending and found out that our investments could pay for our lifestyle. Then we gave 2 weeks’ notice and quit our jobs.</p>
<h4><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>PREPARATION FOR RETIREMENT</strong></span></h4>
<p><em><strong>When did you first start thinking seriously about retirement and when did that turn into a decision to do it?</strong></em></p>
<p>When we were 36 years old, Billy had the idea that we could travel the world and never have to work again.</p>
<p>We could live off our investments! We took 2 years to track our spending and realized that this was a doable proposition, so we retired in January of 1991.</p>
<p><em><strong>What were the major steps you took from deciding to retire to developing a plan to do so?</strong></em></p>
<p>We don’t know if there were any “major steps” other than save, save, save and the unshakable commitment that we wanted to be free to live the lives we chose.</p>
<p>Remember, back in 1991 there were no financial forums, no FIRE community, no internet, WiFi, PayPal, Twitter, Google and no mentors.</p>
<p>We decided to do it, and there was no room for failure.</p>
<p><em><strong>What did your pre-retirement financials look like?</strong></em></p>
<p>We had about $500,000 split between taxable and non-taxable accounts. Most of it was invested in Dean Whitter equity funds. Billy’s boss would get copies of our statement so he could not invest in no-load index funds without him finding out. He was a loyal employee. However we did invest in Vanguard Index 500 in Akaisha&#8217;s account.</p>
<p>Once we turned 55, after 17 years of living our lifestyle, we utilized Rule 72T and pulled out cash from our IRA’s in the same amount as our Social Security payment would be &#8212; thus creating a bridge until we started receiving Social Security. This kept us from selling shares in our regular accounts and letting them grow.</p>
<p>Once our SS began we stopped that and let our IRA accounts continue to increase in value.</p>
<p><em><strong>What was your overall financial plan for retirement?</strong></em></p>
<p>Like we mentioned earlier we tracked our spending for two years prior. We took out all house related expenses, car expenses, dry cleaning and more &#8212; anything that we would be eliminating once we started our journey. We found that we could live on $20,000 per year in 1991 dollars.</p>
<p>So, the question was how much money invested did we need in order to cover that amount. We multiplied 20K by 25 and $500,000 was the amounted we needed to have invested. We were there. Basically, this is the 4% rule in reverse, however the 4% rule didn’t exist in 1990.</p>
<p><em><strong>Did you make any specific moves to prepare your finances for retirement?</strong></em></p>
<p>We sold our home, cars, the restaurant and our belongings and hit the road.</p>
<p>We lived on the tiny Caribbean island of Nevis for 6 months, then went to Venezuela.</p>
<p>We returned to the States, bought a 5th wheel travel trailer and a 1-ton pickup and traveled the US for a couple of years.</p>
<p>Then we began our international travels where we first visited Chapala, Mexico for 2 months and stayed four years.</p>
<p>Another term that had not been invented at that time was geo-arbitrage &#8212; basically, earning dollars in the US and using a favorable exchange rate county in which to live. We figured this out in 1993.</p>
<p><em><strong>Who helped you develop this plan?</strong></em></p>
<p>Billy is our financial planner and there was no one else out there to guide us.</p>
<p>Again, in 1991, there was no internet, no financial forums, no FIRE community, no mentors. We cut the cord and went off on our own.</p>
<p><em><strong>What plans did you make in advance to leave your job?</strong></em></p>
<p>We gave them 2 weeks’ notice and hit the road, period!</p>
<p>We did not want any financial incentives to try and derail us.</p>
<p><em><strong>What were your pre-retirement concerns (financial or non-financial)?</strong></em></p>
<p>We had none.</p>
<p>We had faith in our financial planning and each other.</p>
<p>There was no room for failure. We had managed our own business with 15 employees, and Billy was a manager of a stock broker office with 15 brokers. We were used to taking responsibility, so we knew we could figure it out on our own.</p>
<p><em><strong>How did you handle deciding on and paying for healthcare?</strong></em></p>
<p>Because we had been self-employed for so long, we were already used to paying for our own health insurance.</p>
<p>For the first several years of our lives without a job we had a US-based, high deductible emergency health care plan. But since we were traveling the globe, we would find ourselves taking care of our medical needs in whatever country we might be – whether it was dental, being sick, having an emergency, getting special tests, eye glasses and so on.</p>
<p>We were participating in Medical Tourism before there was such a word. So eventually we just dropped our US health insurance and went “Naked” as they say in the community.</p>
<p>Now we qualify for Medicare but we get our medical needs taken care of here in Mexico.</p>
<p><em><strong>How did you tell your family and friends of your plans?</strong></em></p>
<p>We didn’t say anything until we quit our jobs, and then simply told them we were leaving our jobs to travel.</p>
<p>We rocked their world.</p>
<p>No one believed us or that what we were doing was possible, and some thought we’d be back in less than a year trying to find work again.</p>
<p>Our families were aghast. Being raised during the Depression, they had no reference point for our decision and couldn’t understand why we’d give up a beautiful home near the ocean in California and great jobs to uh… travel?</p>
<p>It took several years for people to adjust to the idea that we were not coming back and going to work.</p>
<h4><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>THE ACT OF RETIRING</strong></span></h4>
<p><em><strong>How did you ultimately retire?</strong></em></p>
<p>We took 2 years and tracked the spending of what we paid just for ourselves. We took out the costs of our mortgage, insurances and car payments, what we spent on work like transportation, lunches out, wardrobe expenses, and all subscriptions to services, magazines, garden and home care and so on.</p>
<p>We found that we could live on $20,000 in 1991 dollars (about $43,000 today), and our investments would cover that easily.</p>
<p>We sold all our belongings, our cars and home and flew to Nevis, British West Indies for a temporary interim adjustment job helping to open the 4 Seasons Hotel on the island.</p>
<p>During our working years we got to know the Captain of one of Windjammer’s sailing vessels. Billy managed his money and after our commitment in Nevis was finished, we jumped on board his 256 ft. sailing ship and sailed down through the Caribbean Islands, then flew to Venezuela.</p>
<p>Our adventure had begun!</p>
<p><em><strong>What went well? What didn&#8217;t go so well?</strong></em></p>
<p>Since we took 2 years to track our spending while we were still working, we decided to also ramp up our savings. The discipline to cut back even more spending, would often put us at odds with our previous entertainment style. Remember, we were restaurant owners and often entertained lavishly in California with Napa Valley wines and waiter service.</p>
<p>We also stopped our housekeeping and gardening services, ate at home more often and packed our lunches. Friends were confused, thought we were having financial problems, and some of them turned a cold social shoulder to us.</p>
<p>When we told family of our plans, they were confused, not understanding the concept. Akaisha’s mother thought we were going on welfare to live and was embarrassed. After Akaisha explained that we had purchased our freedom ourselves, she was a little bit more relieved but still did not understand the idea and it took a few years for her to adjust to it. She would have preferred that we lived the rest of our lives close to the family, and perhaps raise one of our own.</p>
<p>Looking back, it was the emotional component of retirement that was the hardest to juggle. The financial factor was the easier part.</p>
<p><em><strong>How did you ultimately find the courage to do it?</strong></em></p>
<p>As we mentioned, with Billy working days and having weekends off, and Akaisha working nights, weekends and holidays at the restaurant, we were like ships passing in the night. Our relationship suffered greatly, and we could choose to end our marriage or jump forward into living our dream of traveling the world.</p>
<p>By this time, we had managed several large business problems and had matured early in life. So, we knew we could figure out any problems we might face on this new road of adventure. We didn’t hesitate.</p>
<p>We retired in January of 1991…and then the Gulf War broke out that same month with US travel warnings everywhere. We pressed on. There is never a perfect time to retire.</p>
<h4><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>RETIREMENT LIFE</strong></span></h4>
<p><em><strong>How was the adjustment, especially the first few months after retirement?</strong></em></p>
<p>We spent our first 6 months or so on a Caribbean Paradise Island, then in Venezuela on the wonderful island of Isla Margarita.</p>
<p>We wanted to do something radical from our previous lives of full-on stress and working 60-80-hour workweeks. So, there was a bit of releasing all that pent-up intensity and learning to slow down, getting on island time.</p>
<p>And, of course, there was that emotional adjustment that Akaisha’s family was having a hard time with, which wasn’t easy for her.</p>
<p><em><strong>How is retirement life now? What do you like about it and what do you dislike?</strong></em></p>
<p>It’s hard to think of a downside to our lives now, as we have simply gotten better at this approach to living. Traveling as a lifestyle keeps us fresh, young, up-to-date on world views, cuisines, cultures, and geographical beauty. We value our independence greatly, and other than the bump-in-the-road that was Covid, life has been magnificently varied, fulfilling, surprising, and satisfying.</p>
<p>We take care of communication with family and friends over VOIP, email, and WhatsApp. Our medical needs are fulfilled in our adopted town in Mexico now, and Akaisha visits her family in the States yearly.</p>
<p>We like living a simplified life, and since we live in the middle of town, all of our shops, food vendors, physicians, and the lake are in walking distance.</p>
<p>For us, we are living our best lives.</p>
<p><em><strong>What do you do with your time? What does an average day look like?</strong></em></p>
<p>When we are not on the road traveling (during Covid we did a lot of traveling inside the country of Mexico), we get up early, get on the exercise bicycle, Billy makes breakfast and goes out to meet friends for morning coffee.</p>
<p>Akaisha does some volunteer work on the website and then walks to the open markets to pick up fresh vegetables, fruits and supplies.</p>
<p>We have lunch together either at a restaurant with friends or have one of Chef Billy’s fine meals at home. We like casual, two-hour lunches and great conversation.</p>
<p>Akaisha likes to spend her afternoons at her art table.</p>
<p>There is lots of time to read, learn new skills, volunteer, meet with friends, go to local musical presentations or to the local theater. Friends come to visit us from around the world, and really, there is always something to do.</p>
<p><em><strong>What are the major activities that fill up your time in retirement? Are there any new ones you&#8217;re planning to try?</strong></em></p>
<p>We hope to get back to Europe next spring and go to a Mexican vineyard area in the Baja this September.</p>
<p>We do a lot of reading and financial research, Akaisha likes making her art, and we prepare amazing cuisine for friends at our home.</p>
<p><em><strong>What is your social life like?</strong></em></p>
<p>Our social life is wide and varied. We host friends from around the world who come and visit, some from the Philippines, Panama, Thailand, Guatemala and the States.</p>
<p>There are private and public music concerts and theater and lots of activities like tennis, pickleball, going to the natural hot springs, hiking, and walking around town.</p>
<p><em><strong>Looking back, what would you have done differently?</strong></em></p>
<p>We might do two things differently.</p>
<p>Had we known better, we would not have sold our Exxon stock to purchase our home in the 1980s. The Exxon stock performed far better than our coastal home in California and was more liquid.</p>
<p>The second thing we would have done differently, is that we would have been more prepared for the emotional factor of leaving “conventional society.” We hadn’t expected the pushback and thought friends and family would be happy for us and supportive of our choice.</p>
<p>We learned a lot, but that was sometimes difficult, confusing and unexpected to go through.</p>
<p><em><strong>Was there any emotional impact from leaving the workforce?</strong></em></p>
<p>Other than de-stressing, there was no emotional impact from leaving the workforce.</p>
<p>We have always been productive people so we didn’t identify with our jobs per se. Our careers were just the framework within which we were creative and dynamic. When we left our professions we simply found other pathways to be valuable and to contribute.</p>
<p><em><strong>What surprises (financial or non-financial, good or bad) have you had since retiring and how have you handled them?</strong></em></p>
<p>The market downturns and bear markets are always a challenge more mentally than financially. We now have about 5 years of cash for spending during these periods so that our investments can remain untouched. Currently at age 70 we are drawing Social Security and between that and dividends our financial nut is more than covered.</p>
<p>A wonderful discovery was that we found good people everywhere, regardless of culture. They want to live their lives, raise a family, enjoy robust health, have fun and laugh. And…there are crabby and complaining people too, regardless of culture.</p>
<p><em><strong>What are your future plans?</strong></em></p>
<p>At our age our long-term plan is to make it to Friday. <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/14.0.0/72x72/1f609.png" alt="😉" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> Then we reset.</p>
<h4><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>RETIREMENT FINANCES</strong></span></h4>
<p><em><strong>How has your financial plan performed compared to what you had estimated before retirement?</strong></em></p>
<p>Our current net worth is higher today than when we started, even after inflation and spending.</p>
<p>That’s three decades of living this lifestyle and growing our net worth. So, we are doing well.</p>
<p>Our current holdings include VTI, DIA, VGT, MAIN, DVY and SPY.</p>
<p><em><strong>Can you give us some insights into your post-retirement spending and income? How much do you spend annually and on what? And where does the income to pay for your spending come from?</strong></em></p>
<p>You can <a href="https://retireearlylifestyle.com/aaa/annual_spending_update.htm">see our annual spending update here</a>.</p>
<p>We typically spend around $30,000 USD annually for all living expenses including travel, health care, dining, entertainment, food, rent &#8212; the usual. We do not budget separately for travel, as it is our lifestyle.</p>
<p>We live off our investments as we always have from the beginning. We now receive Social Security which we didn’t qualify for initially, and we have dividends. All of this income is far more than what we spend, so we re-invest in the market, and keep several years of spending in cash in case of market downturns.</p>
<p>We don’t budget at all. We track our spending daily, spending a fraction of our net worth, and we travel as a lifestyle, not a vacation. If we want something or need something we purchase it. We know right away in real time what percentage of our net worth we are spending.</p>
<p><em><strong>How are you handling Social Security, required minimum distributions, tax issues and the like?</strong></em></p>
<p>We <a href="https://esimoney.com/why-taking-social-security-early-might-be-the-best-option/">took Social Security at age 62</a> after crunching the numbers and deciding that Billy can do a better job of managing our money than the government.</p>
<p>We have been preparing ourselves for years for RMD’s as they keep raising the year to begin. Meanwhile we pull money out of our IRAs and reinvest in our regular account to prepare for the tax consequence in a couple of years.</p>
<p><em><strong>Did you return to paid work? Why or why not?</strong></em></p>
<p>There was only one time we even considered returning to paid work and that was in the down market of 2008-2009. But then we realized that by the time we purchased a car (with the costs of maintenance, insurance, parking, and fuel) and resupplied our work wardrobe (and lunches out, commuting time and expense) and moved to a location where employment was abundant, that we weren’t willing to make those adjustments.</p>
<p>We made some changes in our portfolio, tracked our spending, utilized geo-arbitrage to reduce spending and continued living our lifestyle. In fact, we made about 6 or 7 trips to Thailand during that time period and just after.</p>
<p><em><strong>Did you find it hard going from being a saver to a spender?</strong></em></p>
<p>As we have aged, it did feel odd to spend more.</p>
<p>We don’t have children, so besides the charities and special causes we will leave money to, there is no point in bringing this money with us to the grave.</p>
<p><em><strong>Looking back, what do you wish you knew in advance?</strong></em></p>
<p>Only that the emotional component of retirement could be a butt-kicker if we didn’t get a handle on it, and that we wished we would have kept our Exxon stock instead of buying our home in California.</p>
<p>Financially, we would have fared better.</p>
<p><em><strong>What advice do you have for those wanting to retire?</strong></em></p>
<p>Save, save, save, track your spending, learn the language of finance, find something productive and satisfying to do with your free time, don’t let anyone steal your dreams and prepare for the emotional component of retirement.</p>
<p>In summary, we purchased our restaurant with no money down before that concept was popular. We figured out the 4% rule before it was created. We left the conventional working world before the FIRE movement started and figured out the benefits of geo-arbitrage on our own. And we’re still here!</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://esimoney.com/retirement-interview-37/">Retirement Interview 37</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://esimoney.com">ESI Money</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://esimoney.com/retirement-interview-37/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>28</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Millionaire Interview 339</title>
		<link>https://esimoney.com/millionaire-interview-339/</link>
					<comments>https://esimoney.com/millionaire-interview-339/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[ESI]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 09:00:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Millionaires]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://esimoney.com/?p=8779</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Here’s our latest interview with a millionaire as we seek to learn from those who have grown their wealth to high heights. If you’d like to be considered for an interview, drop me a note and we can chat about specifics. This interview took place in June. My questions are in bold italics and their [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://esimoney.com/millionaire-interview-339/">Millionaire Interview 339</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://esimoney.com">ESI Money</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://esimoney.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/Mortgage-contract-with-mini-house-new.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-8780" src="https://esimoney.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/Mortgage-contract-with-mini-house-new-300x201.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="201" srcset="https://esimoney.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/Mortgage-contract-with-mini-house-new-300x201.jpg 300w, https://esimoney.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/Mortgage-contract-with-mini-house-new.jpg 750w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a>Here’s our latest <a href="https://esimoney.com/category/millionaires/">interview with a millionaire</a> as we seek to learn from those who have grown their wealth to high heights.</p>
<p>If you’d like to be considered for an interview, <a href="https://esimoney.com/contact/">drop me a note</a> and we can chat about specifics.</p>
<p>This interview took place in June.</p>
<p>My questions are in bold italics and their responses follow in black.</p>
<p>Let&#8217;s get started&#8230;</p>
<h4><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>OVERVIEW</strong></span></h4>
<p><em><strong>How old are you (and spouse if applicable, plus how long you&#8217;ve been married)?</strong></em></p>
<p>I am 49 years old, and my wife is 47 years old.</p>
<p>We have been married for 25 years.</p>
<p><em><strong>Do you have kids/family (if so, how old are they)?</strong></em></p>
<p>Yes, I have a 21-year-old and a 16-year-old. Both girls.</p>
<p>We also have two dogs.</p>
<p><em><strong>What area of the country do you live in (and urban or rural)?</strong></em></p>
<p>Rural, just outside of Charlotte at Lake Norman. My wife and I wanted to be on the water when we retired.</p>
<p>When Covid hit we asked ourselves, “what are we waiting for?&#8221; and decided to move to a lake. Lake Norman was perfect as it’s big and 30 miles from a major city (Charlotte).</p>
<p><em><strong>What is your current net worth?</strong></em></p>
<p>$3.1 million.</p>
<p><em><strong>What are the main assets that make up your net worth (stocks, real estate, business, home, retirement accounts, etc.) and any debt that offsets part of these?</strong></em></p>
<p>We have about around 650k in brokerage accounts. 500k of that is with a financial advisor the other 150k is with me that I play with. Those accounts are made up of mutual funds, stocks, and ETFs.</p>
<p>We have 10k in crypto, 15k with Fundrise, and 10k with Yieldstreet.</p>
<p>We keep 40-50k in checking and 185k in savings accounts.</p>
<p>We have about 700k in equity in our home and the rest is made up of retirement accounts, 1.5 million.</p>
<p>I stay cash-heavy because my income is commission-based and being in the mortgage industry you can have vast changes in income.</p>
<p>Once the economy gets more consistent, I will start to invest the cash back into the market. I will always maintain at least 150k in cash. I realize that is more than most but cash gives you options and takes stress off of income swings. I think this is important for self-employed or commission-based earners.</p>
<h4><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>EARN</strong></span></h4>
<p><em><strong>What is your job?</strong></em></p>
<p>I am in the mortgage business and oversee sales and growth. It’s a senior-level position.</p>
<p>I have been in the industry for 23 years.</p>
<p><em><strong>What is your annual income?</strong></em></p>
<p>It varies a good bit on average its 400k range.</p>
<p>My wife is in the dental industry on the sales and training side and makes 100k.</p>
<p><em><strong>Tell us about your income performance over time. What was the starting salary of your first job, how did it grow from there (and what you did to make it grow), and where are you now?</strong></em></p>
<p>My first year in the mortgage business I made 26k. Second yr 55k, 3rd year 100k and from that point on I never made less than six figures.</p>
<p>My biggest year was 1.1 million. Normal is 400k-500k. I didn’t get to that level until about 2017. Before that it was 200k-300k range. Every 10 years or so you hit it big when a refi boom hits and or the market takes off.</p>
<p>I moved out of sales and into management five years into my career. Doing this cut back on my income as sales is where the big money is at. Helping others was my passion so I never looked back.</p>
<p>My wife started as a dental assistant when we were first married. She stayed in that role until the dentist she worked with retired. She then went into dental sales, did that for a while, and then went to manage a practice for three years. She left that job and is in the position she is in now.</p>
<p>As she gained skills and experience in other areas of the dental world her pay increased gradually. She made low 30s for 3 years, then moved to mid-50s and jumped to 90-100k when she got on the sales side.</p>
<p><em><strong>What tips do you have for others who want to grow their career-related income?</strong></em></p>
<p>First is to love what you do. If you want to make good money, you’re going to have to fight like a dog to beat others out as it’s competitive.</p>
<p>Second, write down your goal. When I graduated college all I wanted to do was make 100k and wrote it down on a small card that I kept on me. Hitting that mark in my third year was more rewarding than making a million later in my career.</p>
<p>Third, hang out with people who make more money than you do. You will learn a lot from them. For example: how they carry themselves in public, their habits, and how they politic themselves within their company to be in a position for the next level.</p>
<p>Finally, you must put in the hours. Successful people do what others are not willing to do.</p>
<p><em><strong>What&#8217;s your work-life balance look like?</strong></em></p>
<p>I work a lot as I have to be available because I am in sales. However, it’s not hard work.</p>
<p>I did construction and worked for a moving company when I was in college. That’s hard work.</p>
<p>With cell phones and tech, my life is intertwined with work, and I think that’s a win given what I am paid. I catch 90% of my kid’s games and activities and I am home most nights.</p>
<p>My wife’s work is the same except her hours vary now because we are on the east coast, and she is doing a lot on the West Coast. She travels once or twice a month and enjoys that part.</p>
<p><em><strong>Do you have any sources of income besides your career?</strong></em></p>
<p>I don’t have any other sources of income.</p>
<p>I have tried buying investment properties, building houses, and trading stocks, all with limited success.</p>
<p>What I have found is the amount of time it takes to get up to speed and then actually do it takes away from what I do best &#8212; which are mortgages.</p>
<p>For example, we had an investment property for years and the net return on it over a 20-year term was 4.0%. For the work it required, I could have just bought a real estate ETF and got the time back that I spent on managing and maintaining it.</p>
<h4><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>SAVE</strong></span></h4>
<p><em><strong>What is your annual spending?</strong></em></p>
<p>To be honest I don’t track it. If my checking accounts hits 30k we tighten up. I hate budgets and I like to spend money.</p>
<p>The family I came from were super savers and I think it affected how I looked at the money. I have plenty of friends who have saved more than I have but it has come at a cost of enjoying life and having some fun.</p>
<p>The real winners to me are those who can balance the two &#8212; make enough to buy toys and/or experiences but at the same time save enough to help your family and others and not become someone else’s burden later in life.</p>
<p>Think about it, if you&#8217;re saving an extra 5-10% now for when your 70. I think you would enjoy the money now more than then. Odds are you are more active now than when you are at that age. No judgment either way from me, but this is based on what I have observed in my life.</p>
<p><em><strong>What are the main categories (expenses) this spending breaks into?</strong></em></p>
<p>We try to keep our fixed expenses at a minimum.</p>
<p>The only payment we have is our house payment and its around 3700.</p>
<p>Cars are paid for and if we finance them, it’s for a year or less.</p>
<p>All toys are paid for in cash for the most part.</p>
<p><em><strong>Do you have a budget? If so, how do you implement it?</strong></em></p>
<p>No budget as I don’t like them.</p>
<p>I run all the finances and if the checking account drops to 30k we tighten up.</p>
<p>Tightening up looks like eating out less, no travel, and putting projects and toys on hold.</p>
<p><em><strong>What percentage of your gross income do you save and how has that changed over time?</strong></em></p>
<p>At a minimum it’s 10%, sometimes it gets as high as 25% if I am having a big year.</p>
<p>Over time that has changed as we had more disposable income. When we were both starting out it was hard, but we still saved in retirement accounts as a minimum.</p>
<p><em><strong>What&#8217;s your best tip for saving (accumulating) money?</strong></em></p>
<p>I am a natural spender and not a saver.</p>
<p>What we do is auto deposits before we can get our hands on it. Max out your 401k, X amount auto-drafted to your brokerage account and other accounts you’re using to grow money. By doing this we don’t miss the money and I use our checking balance as a gauge of what we can do for the month.</p>
<p>Although it’s not saving I also round-up on my mortgage payment. For example: if the mortgage payment is 2820. I would round up to 2900.</p>
<p><em><strong>What&#8217;s your best tip for spending less money?</strong></em></p>
<p>Enjoy shopping and looking for deals.</p>
<p>I love looking for good deals. We usually only buy clothes and goods on sale. The same goes for vacations and travel.</p>
<p>Have drinks before you go out to eat. Cut back on going out to eat if you’re in a jam.</p>
<p>Shop all your insurance and go with a big deductible. Insurance companies don’t gamble &#8212; having a big deductible offsets that.</p>
<p><em><strong>What is your favorite thing to spend money on/your secret splurge?</strong></em></p>
<p>I like cars, toys and having a good time. We have two sports cars, one boat, and two jet skis. We have another car that we share that is practical.</p>
<p>I also golf and we like to go on mini vacations.</p>
<p>We have no problem spending money.</p>
<h4><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>INVEST</strong></span></h4>
<p><em><strong>What is your investment philosophy/plan?</strong></em></p>
<p>We have a financial planner. We tell him our goals and he manages the brokerage account and all the retirement.</p>
<p>My personal philosophy is to invest in what you know and stay in the U.S. Some advisors will tell you that 25% of your portfolio needs to be in international. My experience has been it never pays off. The world economy runs through the US, end of story.</p>
<p>Go opposite of the crowd. If the market is down, buy a little more than usual. If it’s up, take a little of the top.</p>
<p>Make sure you are diversified; you don’t know what you don’t know.</p>
<p><em><strong>What has been your best investment?</strong></em></p>
<p>Time, consistency, and positive cash flow have been my best investment.</p>
<p>Put the money into the general market in a number of stocks, ETFs, and mutual funds and watch it grow.</p>
<p>Keeping fixed expenses low holds the pressure down and allows us to adjust spending quickly if pay changes.</p>
<p><em><strong>What has been your worst investment?</strong></em></p>
<p>Life lesson here. I was in the mortgage business in 2008 when the financial world collapsed. The company I worked for matched dollar for dollar in stock via the 401k plan. I never sold the stock, and the company went under. It ended up costing us around 250k which at the time was half our savings.</p>
<p>I also bought a rental property because of the location and didn’t figure in the cost of upkeep. Run all your numbers before buying investment properties.</p>
<p>The third was raw land, I got a good deal on a large amount of acreage. The problem was you couldn’t get financing on it. I had to sell it at an auction to get rid of it at a loss. The lesson from that is if people can’t finance something it’s hard to sell.</p>
<p><em><strong>What&#8217;s been your overall return?</strong></em></p>
<p>I would estimate 6.5%.</p>
<p>It’s important to point out that I got into the stock market in 1999. Returns were flat until 2012.</p>
<p>Everything is all about timing, if you got into the market in 2012 you have had some great returns. If you just started this year your getting killed.</p>
<p>Good news is if you hang in there it will average out better than most investments.</p>
<p><em><strong>How often do you monitor/review your portfolio?</strong></em></p>
<p>I look at retirement funds about once a quarter.</p>
<p>My play money brokerage account I am in every other day.</p>
<p>If I get worried about the market or have a life change event, I do reach out to my financial advisor to play out my options and go over a plan.</p>
<h4><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>NET WORTH</strong></span></h4>
<p><em><strong>How did you accumulate your net worth?</strong></em></p>
<p>We made most of our money by investing in our 401ks, not touching it, and never spending the equity in the homes we bought over the years.</p>
<p>The rest was auto savings and not spending it.</p>
<p>We also make good money and it’s increased over the years.</p>
<p>Once you save over 500k it can really start growing quickly.</p>
<p>We had no inheritance, and I wouldn’t say we are savers like you see online, it’s just consistent and we don’t touch it.</p>
<p>I also came out of college with no debt. My parents covered the cost of school and I worked as well to cover living expenses. That helped as well.</p>
<p><em><strong>What would you say is your greatest strength in the ESI wealth-building model (Earn, Save or Invest) and why would you say it&#8217;s tops?</strong></em></p>
<p>Earning and investing is our greatest strength.</p>
<p>I don’t think our returns have been the best and I can honestly say we never made a ton of money on selling a home. I know that sounds crazy since I am in the mortgage business, but it just never worked out.</p>
<p>We could have saved more but it just wasn’t worth the time or loss of memories or good times. <a href="https://esimoney.com/life-is-short-retire-early/">Life is short</a>.</p>
<p><em><strong>What road bumps did you face along the way to becoming a millionaire and how did you handle them?</strong></em></p>
<p>The 2008 financial crisis was the biggest. We lost half our 401k, and I was also in the mortgage business which was tough for 3-4 years.</p>
<p>We overspent on renovating a home and that added up to about a 100k loss.</p>
<p>Early on we blew money on cars that we didn’t need or were not a good deal. What I learned from that is this: buy cars that don’t depreciate as much as a regular car. How? Buy used sports cars, trucks, or popular SUVs.</p>
<p><em><strong>What are you currently doing to maintain/grow your net worth?</strong></em></p>
<p>We are maxing out our 401k’s, HSA’s and investing what we can.</p>
<p>We have about 700k equity in our home and our rate is only 2.625. We will pay it down at some point because cash flow is king.</p>
<p>If I could give anyone one piece of advice it would be positive cash flow. Without it in personal or business you are going under.</p>
<p><em><strong>Do you have a target net worth you are trying to attain?</strong></em></p>
<p>Yes, I have a goal of 20 million.</p>
<p>I never plan to really retire as my dad retired early and he is no happier now than when he was working.</p>
<p>We have saved enough to have a good retirement as is. Because of that I am now in the process of buying into a company. My hope is being an owner of a company will take us to the next level of income.</p>
<p><em><strong>How old were you when you made your first million and have you had any significant behavior shifts since then?</strong></em></p>
<p>I think we were 40-42. The only major change since then was the size of the house we bought. We moved to Atlanta and bought a bigger home and got a bigger mortgage. We went from 500k house to 700k house.</p>
<p>When we moved to the lake, we jumped to a 900k house. The thought was with one lake house and no others it would be cheaper than having a primary residence and a second home.</p>
<p><em><strong>What money mistakes have you made along the way that others can learn from?</strong></em></p>
<p>I would never hold a company-matched stock in my 401k. If they are matching with stock, I would sell them and diversify.</p>
<p>We never saved for college for our kids. My oldest just graduated and that’s real money. Get a 529 and put a little in early, it will ease the burden later.</p>
<p><em><strong>What advice do you have for ESI Money readers on how to become wealthy?</strong></em></p>
<p>Invest early in your retirement accounts and learn how to save. <a href="https://esimoney.com/the-best-way-to-maximize-your-investment-return/">Time is your best friend</a> or worst enemy when it comes to investing.</p>
<p>Second, buy a home that needs a little work. You will get a better deal and gain some equity along the way. Just don’t go overboard on renovating or making changes to it.</p>
<p><a href="https://esimoney.com/the-cost-of-divorce/">Don’t get divorced</a>. I see people’s financials every day. Divorce will wreck your finances.</p>
<p>Buy used cars not new ones. I wouldn’t lease cars either, rarely is it a good deal.</p>
<p>Use auto drafts to invest it and forget it.</p>
<p>When getting a mortgage look at longer-term arms &#8212; 7 and 10 yr specifically. People are rarely in a home that long with the same mortgage. It can save you hundreds of dollars in payments. We have never had a fixed-rate mortgage ever.</p>
<p>Make sure you’re solving for a positive cash flow no matter what. That’s hard for someone starting out.</p>
<p>When we were first married all of our friends were going on vacations and traveling, we didn’t. It was major FOMO but we didn’t have the money and wouldn’t put it on a credit card.</p>
<p>This is the most important, so I saved it for the last. Learn how to save when you don’t have money. If you can save when you are broke it will be easy once you start making some money.</p>
<h4><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>FUTURE</strong></span></h4>
<p><em><strong>What are your plans for the future regarding lifestyle?</strong></em></p>
<p>My plans are to keep working and saving.</p>
<p>We save money because it gives us options and buys us time.</p>
<p>My wife will retire or stop working once my youngest is out of college. This is assuming she wants to. She’s type A so who knows.</p>
<p>Once we are empty nesters we will travel more.</p>
<p><em><strong>What are your retirement plans?</strong></em></p>
<p>I plan on always working at some level. I enjoy work and gives me purpose.</p>
<p>Over time we will travel more, and the rest will depend on our girls and where they are.</p>
<p>We do what we do to make sure everyone in the family has a good shot of success.</p>
<p><em><strong>Are there any issues in retirement that concern you? If so, how are you planning to address them?</strong></em></p>
<p>Yes, I worry about what the market is going to do.</p>
<p>What no one tells you is that if the market drops 20% it takes you that much longer to make up the difference.</p>
<p>All I can really do is keep saving and make sure we are diversified. Doing that and keeping our fixed expenses low is the plan.</p>
<h4><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>MISCELLANEOUS</strong></span></h4>
<p><em><strong>How did you learn about finances and at what age did it &#8220;click&#8221;?</strong></em></p>
<p>I learned early the basics as my dad was a super saver and was also in sales. He hammered into my head the positive cash flow rule and I am thankful for that.</p>
<p>I learned the rest from hanging out with people who made more money than me. Saving early and maxing out your 401k, don’t leave beyond your means.</p>
<p>Being in the mortgage business also helped because I could see what people were making and spending money on.</p>
<p>I do read a lot about the markets and finance because I enjoy it and its part of my job.</p>
<p><em><strong>Who inspired you to excel in life? Who are your heroes?</strong></em></p>
<p>My wife and I came from great families, and both made good livings but were grounded. It was more like a standard.</p>
<p>I have a disabled uncle who no one thought would live past 30 or have a life of his own. He is now 65, owns his own home, and functions as a solid member of society. Any time I start throwing a pity party I think of all he had to overcome to be where he is at.</p>
<p>If you focus, write down your goals and work towards them you can do anything.</p>
<p><em><strong>Do you have any favorite money books you like/recommend? If so, can you share with us your top three and why you like them?</strong></em></p>
<p>I listen to a book a week when I am driving or working out. That’s a great life hack.</p>
<p>Shoe Dog by Phil Knight is one of my favorites. If you read that you will understand what it’s like to really do what you love and at the same time embrace the grind.</p>
<p>The Storyteller by Dave Grohl is along the same lines although it’s not a business book.</p>
<p>Secrets of Closing the Sale by Zig Ziglar. Every salesperson needs to read it. It’s the baseline for all the new guys you see on social media.</p>
<p>The 4-Hour Work Week by Tim Ferris. It changed how I viewed retirement.</p>
<p><em><strong>Do you give to charity? Why or why not? If you do, what percent of time/money do you give?</strong></em></p>
<p>We give to causes and people that we think need help.</p>
<p>A lot of it these days is Go Fund Me donations for friends and friends of friends who need help.</p>
<p>We also support our local high school girl athletics. Why? Girl sports need it more than the others.</p>
<p><em><strong>Do you plan to leave an inheritance for your heirs (how do you plan to distribute your wealth at your death)? What are your reasons behind this plan?</strong></em></p>
<p>Yes, we will leave money to our girls and probably to whatever causes we get involved with later in life.</p>
<p>We want to make sure everyone in the family is in the best position possible for the next stage in life.</p>
<p>Money doesn’t buy happiness, friends and family do that. However, money does give you options.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://esimoney.com/millionaire-interview-339/">Millionaire Interview 339</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://esimoney.com">ESI Money</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://esimoney.com/millionaire-interview-339/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>6</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Millionaire Interview 338</title>
		<link>https://esimoney.com/millionaire-interview-338/</link>
					<comments>https://esimoney.com/millionaire-interview-338/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[ESI]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 09:00:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Millionaires]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://esimoney.com/?p=8776</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Here’s our latest interview with a millionaire as we seek to learn from those who have grown their wealth to high heights. If you’d like to be considered for an interview, drop me a note and we can chat about specifics. This interview took place in June. My questions are in bold italics and their [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://esimoney.com/millionaire-interview-338/">Millionaire Interview 338</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://esimoney.com">ESI Money</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://esimoney.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/Modern-apartment-complex-new.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-8777" src="https://esimoney.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/Modern-apartment-complex-new-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://esimoney.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/Modern-apartment-complex-new-300x200.jpg 300w, https://esimoney.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/Modern-apartment-complex-new.jpg 750w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a>Here’s our latest <a href="https://esimoney.com/category/millionaires/">interview with a millionaire</a> as we seek to learn from those who have grown their wealth to high heights.</p>
<p>If you’d like to be considered for an interview, <a href="https://esimoney.com/contact/">drop me a note</a> and we can chat about specifics.</p>
<p>This interview took place in June.</p>
<p>My questions are in bold italics and their responses follow in black.</p>
<p>Let&#8217;s get started&#8230;</p>
<h4><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>OVERVIEW</strong></span></h4>
<p><em><strong>How old are you (and spouse if applicable, plus how long you&#8217;ve been married)?</strong></em></p>
<p>I am a single, 52-year-old woman who has never been married.</p>
<p><em><strong>Do you have kids/family (if so, how old are they)?</strong></em></p>
<p>I have no kids.</p>
<p><em><strong>What area of the country do you live in (and urban or rural)?</strong></em></p>
<p>I live in the suburbs of Nevada.</p>
<p><em><strong>What is your current net worth?</strong></em></p>
<p>My current net worth is $15-20 million.</p>
<p><em><strong>What are the main assets that make up your net worth (stocks, real estate, business, home, retirement accounts, etc.) and any debt that offsets part of these?</strong></em></p>
<p>I currently share one commercial property with my sister and I own 12 houses. All of the real estate has been paid off.</p>
<p>I have $600,000 in the bank.</p>
<p>I have $1,030,000 million in a Roth IRA, $850,000 in another retirement fund, $10,600,000 in stocks and mutual funds.</p>
<p>My father passed away in March 2022 and left me $1,000,000 in his retirement fund.</p>
<h4><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>EARN</strong></span></h4>
<p><em><strong>What is your job?</strong></em></p>
<p>I previously owned my own medical practice but sold the practice in March 2022.</p>
<p>I am a family practice physician.</p>
<p><em><strong>What is your annual income?</strong></em></p>
<p>$310,000 per year from my job as a physician.</p>
<p><em><strong>Tell us about your income performance over time. What was the starting salary of your first job, how did it grow from there (and what you did to make it grow), and where are you now?</strong></em></p>
<p>My first job out of residency in California paid me $110,000 per year in 1999.</p>
<p>I moved out of state two years later and worked for a company for 6 months. The hospital subsidized my salary of $144,000 per year.</p>
<p>Unfortunately, they went bankrupt and I had to moonlight in urgent cares and workman comp facilities while I was building my practice. I worked 7 days a week for two years until my practice was stable for me to quit the moonlighting jobs.</p>
<p>When I opened my own practice, I had a few physicians work as independent contractors. I would pay them 50% of what they collected. I was often seeing over 40 patients a day, going to the office on Saturdays and just did not enjoy medicine.</p>
<p>Besides my own practice, I also did clinical research on the side. They rented part of the office and they would pay me a set amount of money for each patient I saw depending on the clinical study. For example, I could see a patient for a physical and get paid $50, evaluate an EKG and get $15.</p>
<p>I also teach medical students on the side. The school would pay me $350 per student per month. I usually see 2 students per month. Although I probably brought in $500,000 salary, I only paid myself $250,000 at the advice of my accountant.</p>
<p>In the last year, I decided to sell my practice and actually sold my practice which closed 3/15/22 for $1.7 million.</p>
<p>I quit research but continue to teach medical students. Since I have no kids, I see these students as my children and can pass on my knowledge.</p>
<p>Since then, my life has become much easier. I am now seeing about 25-30 patients a day, have my weekends free, and now I get 4 weeks of paid vacation plus continuing medical education time. I also eliminated all the administration duties.</p>
<p>I bought my first home in California in 2000 and then moved to Nevada. After buying and living in my first home in Nevada in 2001, I moved in 2 years and bought another home in 2003. After a few years, the real estate market dropped and I started to purchase single family homes in the area.</p>
<p>These are the purchase prices of my houses which I purchased. I’m not sure about the value of the house but put very conservative numbers for their current value:</p>
<ul>
<li>$259,000 California purchased 2000, estimated value $850,000</li>
<li>$202,500 Nevada purchased 2001, estimated value $450,000</li>
<li>$682,000 Nevada purchased 2003, estimated value $680,000</li>
<li>$805,000 Nevada commercial property 2005, estimated value $1,000,000</li>
<li>$336,000 Nevada purchased 2008,estimated value $600,000</li>
<li>$320,000 Nevada purchased 2009, estimated value $600,000</li>
<li>$296,000 Nevada purchased 2010, estimated value $600,000</li>
<li>$259,090 Nevada purchased 2010, estimated value $550,000</li>
<li>$299,900 Nevada purchased 2011, estimated value $600,000</li>
<li>$339,500 Nevada purchased 2011, estimated value $600,000</li>
<li>$349,200 Nevada purchased 2012, estimated value $600,000</li>
<li>$381,200 Nevada purchased 2017, estimated value $600,000</li>
<li>$395,990 Nevada purchased 2018, estimated value $600,000</li>
</ul>
<p>My rental income is $28,820 per month if every tenant pays.</p>
<p><em><strong>What tips do you have for others who want to grow their career-related income?</strong></em></p>
<p>I can only speak for medicine. Most physicians will tell you not to go into primary care. I agree in some aspects because we need to deal with several patient problems instead of just one issue. Just last week, I had a patient complaining about 5 different issues.</p>
<p>The good thing about primary care is that you do feel like a real physician because you can handle multiple medical issues. I have the ability to moonlight while building up my practice. If I were a Cardiologist, I could not moonlight at the urgent care. I also could participate in clinical research as well as teaching. My options are open.</p>
<p>If you really want to grow your practice, you can hire extenders to help you see patients. I think my issue is that I need to trust that the provider does not make a clinical error in case I get sued.</p>
<p>As I’ve done, you can also buy your own building and rent out the space back to yourself.</p>
<p><em><strong>What&#8217;s your work-life balance look like?</strong></em></p>
<p>After I sold my practice, I have more free time. I work my 40 hours and have my weekends back. This is all brand new to me. I do enjoy watching television and playing the piano. I love walking. I try to walk 5 miles on the weekdays and more on the weekends.</p>
<p>When I had my own practice, I was working after seeing patients, going to the clinic on the weekends to finished administrative duties or buying clinic items.</p>
<p>I also manage my own properties so usually there’s some errand that needs to be done.</p>
<p><em><strong>Do you have any sources of income besides your career? If so, can you list them, give us a feel for how much you earn with each, and offer some insight into how you developed them?</strong></em></p>
<p>Besides my salary, I have income from my rental properties.</p>
<p>I make $28,820 per month from my individual properties and I share the $8,670 per month with my sister for the commercial property.</p>
<p>The company that purchased my clinic is renting the clinic from us.</p>
<p>The medical school usually sends me 0-3 students per month and pays me $350 per student per month.</p>
<h4><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>SAVE</strong></span></h4>
<p><em><strong>What is your annual spending?</strong></em></p>
<p>My spending is minimum. Most of the expenses are associated with the rental houses such as the pool, HOA, gardening fees etc.</p>
<p>My splurge is usually going out to eat maybe once every 1-2 weeks and Netflix, Hulu, and Sling.</p>
<p>I’m fortunate because pharm reps often bring us food for lunch and I can often eat the left overs for dinner. Prior, I would buy clothes but as an employee, I have uniform scrubs.</p>
<p>My monthly expense not including investments are probably $1000-1500 depending on the electricity bill.</p>
<p><em><strong>What are the main categories (expenses) this spending breaks into?</strong></em></p>
<ul>
<li>Groceries $100-200</li>
<li>Utilities $500-750 ($92 gas, trash $50 every 3 months, power $165, solar $250, water $165)</li>
<li>Restaurant $100</li>
<li>Gas $100</li>
<li>Internet $63</li>
<li>TV $45</li>
</ul>
<p><em><strong>Do you have a budget? If so, how do you implement it?</strong></em></p>
<p>I have no budget.</p>
<p><em><strong>What percentage of your gross income do you save and how has that changed over time?</strong></em></p>
<p>I have autopayments of investments.</p>
<p>If the market drops, I’ll often purchase more stocks/mutual funds.</p>
<p>Currently, I invest in Vanguard $2,000 every month.</p>
<p>Because I recently became a salaried employee, I’m only taking in $400 per paycheck because I put most of the money in retirement and taxes. Just my last paycheck on Friday increased to a net income of $6,900 because I already maxed my retirement income so I’ll increase my monthly contribution to Vanguard.</p>
<p><em><strong>What&#8217;s your best tip for saving (accumulating) money?</strong></em></p>
<p>Automatically invest your money monthly.</p>
<p><em><strong>What&#8217;s your best tip for spending less money?</strong></em></p>
<p>I’m already pretty frugal so this is a hard question.</p>
<p>When we were young, my mom trained us. All I ever heard was that we have no money.</p>
<p>Maybe pay cash and then you are less willing to spend money.</p>
<p>When we were young, going out to eat was a treat and we needed to save money so I was trained that you only order water as a drink when dining out. To this day, I still only drink water as a beverage at restaurants. I don’t drink coffee and I don’t drink alcohol.</p>
<p><em><strong>What is your favorite thing to spend money on/your secret splurge?</strong></em></p>
<p>Hulu, Netflix, Sling and eating out.</p>
<h4><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>INVEST</strong></span></h4>
<p><em><strong>What is your investment philosophy/plan?</strong></em></p>
<p>I think you need to split your investments with a mixture of stocks and real estate.</p>
<p>If you have money, just buy and eventually, it should go up.</p>
<p>Make sure you have enough money if your rentals are empty.</p>
<p><em><strong>What has been your best investment?</strong></em></p>
<p>I think right now, it’s real estate. I was lucky.</p>
<p>I had $1 million cash that I decided to just put in $100,000 every month into Vanguard until the $1 million ran out. I must have entered it incorrectly. The Vanguard representative called me to ask if I really wanted to invest $1 million and I said yes. They actually purchased $1 million in stock that day.</p>
<p>When I saw what I did, I turned pale white. That stock is now over $3 million.</p>
<p><em><strong>What has been your worst investment?</strong></em></p>
<p>I loaned money to someone who went bankrupt.</p>
<p>I had held Exxon Mobil for 20 years and it was turning negative. I told myself everyone is going into electric cars and once it turned positive, I would sell.</p>
<p>After I sold and within a year or so, Russia invaded Ukraine and of course, the Exxon Mobil went up.</p>
<p><em><strong>What&#8217;s been your overall return?</strong></em></p>
<p>The stock market has taken a dip so it’s about 9%.</p>
<p>I have more than doubled my money on every house except 3 houses.</p>
<p><em><strong>How often do you monitor/review your portfolio?</strong></em></p>
<p>I use to look at the stock portfolio daily but with the drop in the market, I don’t want to look.</p>
<p>Previously, I would reassess every year.</p>
<h4><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>NET WORTH</strong></span></h4>
<p><em><strong>How did you accumulate your net worth?</strong></em></p>
<p>I started out in residency investing $50 per month automatically in Exxon Mobil.</p>
<p>When I had more money, that increased to $250 per dividend reinvestment company. I had 4 at that time &#8212; McDonald’s, SBC, and Pfizer. I would put $100-250 per month in each stock and reinvest the dividends. I then added Vanguard and would slowly increase how much I invested.</p>
<p>I also invested in other companies but my financial planner advised me to consolidate all of the stocks into Vanguard. At one point, I invested $6,350 per month.</p>
<p>After I moved to Vanguard, I invest $2000 per month because I could not continue the dividend reinvestment programs.</p>
<p>I also saved money and I would look at Zillow, Redfin, etc. and look for houses. I purchased property in my community. I would walk around and would call agents to make purchases of homes. I would see if they would give me a deal if I did not have an agent. I also went into a new housing development and purchased a home in my area.</p>
<p>If you have a decent location for your property, decent families will rent from you. If you are going to go into a new housing development, have your favorite agent represent you and see if they will give you a percentage back to you. The developers pay the agents a percent commission.</p>
<p>If you hold your properties and stocks long enough, I think it will grow. Just don’t get too greedy and over extend yourself.</p>
<p><em><strong>What would you say is your greatest strength in the ESI wealth-building model (Earn, Save or Invest) and why would you say it&#8217;s tops?</strong></em></p>
<p>I think you need all of these. I could not do it with only one.</p>
<p>Make your money, save and invest it into real estate and or stocks.</p>
<p><em><strong>What road bumps did you face along the way to becoming a millionaire and how did you handle them?</strong></em></p>
<p>At one time, half the houses I owned were empty. I was lucky because with my salary, I could afford the houses being empty. I would advertise the homes on Zillow, etc. and show the houses to the prospective tenants myself. I would find out what they did not like and try to show them another house I owed which was empty.</p>
<p>When I lost my job first moving to Nevada, I wanted to move back to California but I did not want to be a “failure” and ask for my old job back. As I mentioned, I worked two years straight working in workman’s comp and urgent cares while opening up my practice. I think I worked about 60-80 hours a week with no days off for two years straight. I was exhausted and often miserable but I was determined to succeed.</p>
<p><em><strong>What are you currently doing to maintain/grow your net worth?</strong></em></p>
<p>After I sold my practice, I decided I had enough of real estate. Although it’s made me more money, I manage all the properties so I was tired of dealing with broken items.</p>
<p>I invested in the stock market but lately, it has not been good. I hope they will increase with time.</p>
<p><em><strong>Do you have a target net worth you are trying to attain?</strong></em></p>
<p>I think I’ve reached my target net worth.</p>
<p><em><strong>How old were you when you made your first million and have you had any significant behavior shifts since then?</strong></em></p>
<p>I think I made my first million in the mid-30’s. Only recently have I shifted my behavior. I’ve always been frugal and that’s a characteristic that’s hard to change. I still try to buy things on sale, never order drinks at a restaurant, etc.</p>
<p>Because I sold my practice, I’m “forced” to take vacation because I cannot accumulate the hours. I will now need to go on vacation.</p>
<p><em><strong>What money mistakes have you made along the way that others can learn from?</strong></em></p>
<p>After lending money to that individual, I’m gun shy to lend anyone money.</p>
<p>I think I’m a control freak. Looking back, MAYBE I could have continued running my own office. I should have delegated more jobs to others. With medicine, the insurance companies may increase the premiums to their customers but they don’t share that with the physicians. With most insurances, I am paid the same amount I was paid 20 years ago so the only way to make more money is to see more patients and I already maxed out. With recent salary increases to the employees, I think I’m happy I sold my practice.</p>
<p>I think because I’m frugal, I don’t want to pay 8% to a property manager to run the rental homes. Because I was doing everything myself, I burned out. Between being a doctor and managing my practice, I just could not do everything. I forgot which book I read but it mentioned that you should spend your energy making more money and not spending your time doing things that others can do for you for less money.</p>
<p>Another mistake I made is to be friends with the tenants and when that happens, it’s very hard for me to increase the rent. Most of my houses are rented below value but I’m also lazy to try to clean them out and rent them again.</p>
<p><em><strong>What advice do you have for ESI Money readers on how to become wealthy?</strong></em></p>
<p>For me the stock market and real estate have helped me. I would invest as much as you feel comfortable slowly each month into the stock market. SP500 is great. You don’t need to think.</p>
<p>If you want to buy houses, I would save up for a down payment of 25%. Be sure you can pay the mortgage if you have no tenant and know there are bad tenants. Buy in an area with good school districts so you attract those families. You can also use your house as a starter home and upgrade and rent your first house. That way, you have a lower down payment and lower interest rate. Location is the key and make sure you are in an area that has potential to grow. Make sure your state is landlord friendly.</p>
<h4><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>FUTURE</strong></span></h4>
<p><em><strong>What are your plans for the future regarding lifestyle?</strong></em></p>
<p>I just started working for this company. My contract is for two years. After that, I will decide if I like working for someone or just retire.</p>
<p>Because I’m too young to qualify for Medicare and most of my friends are still working, I may just work enough hours to qualify for full time (30 hours) which should be easy. I just want the company to continue renting my property that I share with my sister.</p>
<p><em><strong>What are your retirement plans?</strong></em></p>
<p>I think I’ll just exercise more and take classes.</p>
<p>I may help my sister by helping to care for my niece.</p>
<p><em><strong>Are there any issues in retirement that concern you? If so, how are you planning to address them?</strong></em></p>
<p>I’m afraid I’ll be bored so that’s why I may work enough to maintain full time status.</p>
<p>I also need health insurance. I even thought of working for Starbuck’s part time just for health benefits and I don’t drink coffee!!</p>
<h4><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>MISCELLANEOUS</strong></span></h4>
<p><em><strong>How did you learn about finances and at what age did it &#8220;click&#8221;?</strong></em></p>
<p>My parents have always been involved with real estate but I hated it as a child because they would always go over the weekends to repair the apartments themselves.</p>
<p>My mom told me to invest and I would go to the library to read up on stocks. When I saw the investments grow to $100,000, that’s when it clicked.</p>
<p><em><strong>Who inspired you to excel in life? Who are your heroes?</strong></em></p>
<p>I owe everything to my parents. They came from another country and they are the American dream.</p>
<p>They have always told me to work hard, save, and be frugal. Without them, I am nothing.</p>
<p><em><strong>Do you have any favorite money books you like/recommend? If so, can you share with us your top three and why you like them?</strong></em></p>
<p>I love “<a href="https://esimoney.com/the-best-personal-finance-books-of-all-time-the-millionaire-next-door/">Millionaire Next Door</a>.”</p>
<p>I always thought millionaires spent a lot of money and drove expensive cars. I found out they worked just like me and that’s how they became rich.</p>
<p><em><strong>Do you give to charity? Why or why not? If you do, what percent of time/money do you give?</strong></em></p>
<p>I do contribute to charity. I usually donate in times a crisis like Ukraine, hurricane, etc. I usually do it when someone is willing to double my contribution. I also donate to my undergraduate, kids in need like Kevin Durant Foundation, Opus 188 Harlem School of Music.</p>
<p>Because my father recently died, he always wanted to set up a scholarship to help someone just like him and we will be doing that in his name this year. The university said that $100,000 would fund the scholarship for its lifetime.</p>
<p><em><strong>Do you plan to leave an inheritance for your heirs (how do you plan to distribute your wealth at your death)? What are your reasons behind this plan?</strong></em></p>
<p>I only have my sister and cousins. Right now, I have everything left to my sister but she has mentioned she doesn’t need all this so we will probably donate.</p>
<p>I don’t think it’s good to have one person inherit so much. I think you appreciate money more when you have worked for it.</p>
<p>I’ve opened 529 plans for my cousins’ kids. I think education is everything.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://esimoney.com/millionaire-interview-338/">Millionaire Interview 338</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://esimoney.com">ESI Money</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://esimoney.com/millionaire-interview-338/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>24</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Millionaire Interview 337</title>
		<link>https://esimoney.com/millionaire-interview-337/</link>
					<comments>https://esimoney.com/millionaire-interview-337/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[ESI]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2022 09:00:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Millionaires]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://esimoney.com/?p=8755</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Here’s our latest interview with a millionaire as we seek to learn from those who have grown their wealth to high heights. If you’d like to be considered for an interview, drop me a note and we can chat about specifics. This interview took place in May. My questions are in bold italics and their [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://esimoney.com/millionaire-interview-337/">Millionaire Interview 337</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://esimoney.com">ESI Money</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://esimoney.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Animal-shelter-volunteers-new.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-8756" src="https://esimoney.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Animal-shelter-volunteers-new-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://esimoney.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Animal-shelter-volunteers-new-300x200.jpg 300w, https://esimoney.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Animal-shelter-volunteers-new.jpg 750w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a>Here’s our latest <a href="https://esimoney.com/category/millionaires/">interview with a millionaire</a> as we seek to learn from those who have grown their wealth to high heights.</p>
<p>If you’d like to be considered for an interview, <a href="https://esimoney.com/contact/">drop me a note</a> and we can chat about specifics.</p>
<p>This interview took place in May.</p>
<p>My questions are in bold italics and their responses follow in black.</p>
<p>Let&#8217;s get started&#8230;</p>
<h4><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>OVERVIEW</strong></span></h4>
<p><em><strong>How old are you (and spouse if applicable, plus how long you&#8217;ve been married)?</strong></em></p>
<p>I am 56 and my husband is 59.</p>
<p>We’ve been married for nearly 30 years.</p>
<p><em><strong>Do you have kids/family (if so, how old are they)?</strong></em></p>
<p>Just the two of us – childless by choice.</p>
<p><em><strong>What area of the country do you live in (and urban or rural)?</strong></em></p>
<p>We live in the mid-Atlantic area of the US.</p>
<p><em><strong>What is your current net worth?</strong></em></p>
<p>Our current net worth is just north of $10 million.</p>
<p><em><strong>What are the main assets that make up your net worth (stocks, real estate, business, home, retirement accounts, etc.) and any debt that offsets part of these?</strong></em></p>
<ul>
<li>Taxable Investment Accounts: 36%</li>
<li>Tax Advantaged 401k/Traditional IRA Accounts/Tax Free: 37%</li>
<li>Deferred Compensation: 10%</li>
<li>Cash/I Bonds: 3%</li>
<li>Variable Annuity: 3%</li>
<li>Primary Residence: 10%</li>
</ul>
<p>The only debt we maintain is for an auto loan. We took advantage of a zero percent, 36 months loan.</p>
<h4><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>EARN</strong></span></h4>
<p><em><strong>What is your job?</strong></em></p>
<p>We retired in late 2021.</p>
<p>We each worked for Fortune 100 companies over the course of our careers.</p>
<p>I earned my <a href="https://esimoney.com/the-value-of-an-mba/">MBA</a>/Marketing undergrad degree and worked in product management and marketing.</p>
<p>My husband earned his MBA/Computer Science undergrad degree and worked in product management.</p>
<p>By the time we retired, we had worked in our chosen careers 31 and 35 years respectively.</p>
<p><em><strong>What is your annual income?</strong></em></p>
<p>In the past several years our annual income ran between $700k &#8211; $900k, depending on bonuses and restricted stock unit vesting.</p>
<p>While we both earned good salaries, I ended up being the primary earner for our family over the course of our careers.</p>
<p><em><strong>Tell us about your income performance over time. What was the starting salary of your first job, how did it grow from there (and what you did to make it grow), and where are you now?</strong></em></p>
<p>I graduated from college into the recession of the early 90s and jobs were difficult to find. I took a secretarial job (as they were referred to at that time). My salary was $20k annually. I worked hard, took on extra responsibilities and was able to get promoted within six months. That upped my salary to $30k.</p>
<p>My husband was recruited from college to a telecom company. He worked in product development/management/marketing. His starting salary was $40k. When he was promoted in the early 90s, the company relocated us which proved to be a financial stepping-stone (more on that later). He was also fortunate to have a company-paid sabbatical to get his MBA.</p>
<p>After a few years at my company, I was ready to take on more responsibility and move to a larger company. The economy was booming and there were a lot of job opportunities. I found my next role at a Fortune 100 company. My starting salary was $90k plus bonus.</p>
<p>After a few years, I started a part time MBA program. The company paid for 50% of tuition with the stipulation that I stayed for two years post-graduation. I stayed with that company for nearly 15 years and gradually rose through the ranks.</p>
<p>By the mid-2000s, our combined annual income had grown to around $400k per year which included bonuses, restricted stock awards and stock options.</p>
<p>In 2010, I was ready to step into a more senior role and felt that I needed to make a significant career change. I found a senior leadership role at another Fortune 100 company. We had the choice of several locations and decided to move to the mid-Atlantic area. My new role bumped our income to up $700k &#8211; $900k per year.</p>
<p><em><strong>What tips do you have for others who want to grow their career-related income?</strong></em></p>
<p>Middle to senior level leadership positions can be very lucrative in corporate America. If you are suited to and like the work, compensation can add up very quickly. I paid my dues early in my career taking on additional responsibilities, working to make my skill set, experience, and ability to deliver results relevant to my managers.</p>
<p>I think it’s important to learn how to network effectively and establish professional and personal relationships that can help you advance your career and help others advance their careers. <a href="https://esimoney.com/7-steps-to-millions-more-network/">Networking</a> has been one of the most challenging aspects of my corporate life as I don’t come by it naturally. I realized how valuable creating and sustaining professional connections is to cultivate a career.</p>
<p>Early on, I realized that corporate America can be a gravy train of monetary and non-monetary compensation. Our compensation typically included bonus, restricted stock, options as well as 401k matching and profit sharing. The cost of our graduate degrees was either eliminated or substantially reduced through company contributions.</p>
<p>Over the course of our careers, we took advantage of two lucrative relocation packages. In each instance, we were able to financially gain from geo-arbitraged housing markets, fully paid moves, subsidized closing costs, and below market mortgage rates.</p>
<p>It sounds obvious but worth stating to take advantage of every benefit your company can provide whether it be outright monetary compensation, training, or flexible work arrangements. It pays to ask for what matters to you.</p>
<p><em><strong>What&#8217;s your work-life balance look like?</strong></em></p>
<p>Since we retired, we don’t have to balance any longer and it’s been wonderful.</p>
<p>When we were working, work was all consuming for me.</p>
<p>My husband took a much more balance approach and was able to disconnect mentally and technology-wise when the day was over.</p>
<p>In my role, I felt I had to been “on call” and stay many steps ahead of my colleagues and my boss. I really enjoyed what I did and the people I worked with, but the demands were constant and increasingly challenging. When I first started in senior management, I loved the challenge of it. Over time, I found the routine and pointless meetings, regulatory red-tape, and people management aspects to be draining.</p>
<p><em><strong>Do you have any sources of income besides your career? If so, can you list them, give us a feel for how much you earn with each, and offer some insight into how you developed them?</strong></em></p>
<p>Our careers were our primary sources of income and that’s where we put our focus on maximizing our earnings potential.</p>
<p>Over time, we worked to structure our investments to provide income that would support our non-working years.</p>
<h4><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>SAVE</strong></span></h4>
<p><em><strong>What is your annual spending?</strong></em></p>
<p>For 2022, our spending will fall somewhere around $240k (including health insurance premiums and Fed/State taxes).</p>
<p>Pre-retirement, our spending was similar minus health insurance premiums and plus mortgages (primary and vacation properties) and savings.</p>
<p><em><strong>What are the main categories (expenses) this spending breaks into?</strong></em></p>
<p>Post-retirement spending is as follows:</p>
<ul>
<li>Auto loan/Tax/Maintenance: $20k</li>
<li>Charity: $10k</li>
<li>Food: $20k</li>
<li>Gas: $3k</li>
<li>Med/Dental/Vision Ins Premiums: $19k</li>
<li>Health/Wellness/Trainer: $15k</li>
<li>Home Maintenance: $16k</li>
<li>Insurance Home/Auto/Umbrella: $7k</li>
<li>Shopping/Pet/Other: $25k</li>
<li>Taxes: Fed/State: $65k</li>
<li>Taxes: Real Estate: $11k</li>
<li>Travel: $17k</li>
<li>Utilities/Subs/Streaming/Other: $12k</li>
</ul>
<p><em><strong>Do you have a budget? If so, how do you implement it?</strong></em></p>
<p>I manage the finances in our household. The situation works out well since my husband has little interest. We consult on all major decisions but the day to day is my responsibility and I enjoy it.</p>
<p>We began tracking our day-to-day spending in 2021 when we were planning for retirement. Prior to that, it was a process of elimination: priority was savings/investment first, then taxes, mortgage/non-discretionary and discretionary.</p>
<p>I conducted a detailed look back at our spending from the previous five years and that formed the basis of our retirement budget. Once we exclude mortgages and savings, our post-retirement spending is consistent to our pre-retirement spending.</p>
<p>We don’t have extravagant tastes and have cushion in the budget that we can cut back when necessary.</p>
<p><em><strong>What percentage of your gross income do you save and how has that changed over time?</strong></em></p>
<p>We’ve both been diligent savers, even when we had very little to save.</p>
<p>In the beginning of our marriage, we saved at least 10% of our income which was mostly comprised of 401k contributions.</p>
<p>Our savings rate gradually increased to 15-20% and in the past 10 years, we saved 30-40% of our annual income.</p>
<p><em><strong>What&#8217;s your best tip for saving (accumulating) money?</strong></em></p>
<p>Automated savings worked best for us. That included our contributions to our 401ks, Traditional IRAs and HSAs. Out of sight, out of mind.</p>
<p>I took advantage of my company’s deferred compensation plan to defer my annual bonus for several years. That enabled us to retire without having to dip into our portfolio for several years into our retirement.</p>
<p><em><strong>What&#8217;s your best tip for spending less money?</strong></em></p>
<p>Manage lifestyle inflation and be clear about what you value. It’s easy to say in concept but takes commitment and discipline to follow through.</p>
<p>Every time our income increased, it was so tempting to buy a bigger house, buy a new car, go on an expensive vacation, etc. In some ways, we tried to ignore incremental income. It was less tempting if we automated monthly savings and investment transfers.</p>
<p>Lifestyle inflation did happen over time, but we struck a good balance of enjoying the fruits of our labor within limits. It was very important to both of us that we avoided living a lifestyle that trapped us into a cycle of earning to spend.</p>
<p><em><strong>What is your favorite thing to spend money on/your secret splurge?</strong></em></p>
<p>As we got older, maintaining our health became increasingly important. We are very active and had a couple of health scares reminded us that we were not invincible. Fortunately, we are fine and made lifestyle changes to support our long-term health.</p>
<p>We have had a personal trainer for years, get regular massages, eat a high-quality diet, etc.</p>
<h4><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>INVEST</strong></span></h4>
<p><em><strong>What is your investment philosophy/plan?</strong></em></p>
<p>Aspects of my investment philosophy have stayed the same and some have changed.</p>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;">What’s stayed the same:</span></p>
<p>Invest for the long term, no matter how distracting the short term may be. As adults, we lived through the recession of the early 90s, the dot com bubble/early 2000s, the 2008/2009 financial crisis and now 2022. Throughout those times one thing remained consistent: keep investing. I remember how painful it was in the in the early 2000s, opening our quarterly brokerage and 401k statements. Every statement was red, every quarter. For years (at least it seemed at the time). Yet we had faith that persistent, long-term focused investing would pay off at some point.</p>
<p>Understand our investments and avoid what we don’t understand. As our income grew this was harder to maintain. As we looked for investments that would protect/defer our income from taxes inevitably options like whole life insurance, annuities, etc. were considered. We stayed away from whole life insurance as it never made sense to us. We did end up investing in a variable annuity but only a small amount of our portfolio and after we did substantial amount of research on the company and terms. We haven’t taken the leap into crypto at this point.</p>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;">What’s changed:</span></p>
<p>When we started out, low-cost investing was our mantra. Mainly because we had so little money to invest, and my father drilled the idea of low-cost <a href="https://esimoney.com/why-i-invest-with-index-funds/">index investing</a> into my head. Beyond our company 401ks, we kept a brokerage account at Vanguard.</p>
<p>Once our portfolio reached a certain size and knowing my husband had little interest in managing our money, we decided to hire a full-service advisor. That was a very difficult decision yet one that we are glad we made. We found a reputable advisor who understood our objectives and what mattered to us. We employed them for 10 years and have been very pleased with our portfolio performance and our relationship.</p>
<p>With retirement, we made a change to a reputable lower-cost advisor. The reason: we don’t have complex financial needs that our previous advisor offered, are ready to simplify the portfolio and lower our investment costs.</p>
<p><em><strong>What has been your best investment?</strong></em></p>
<p>As many in this forum have stated before me, my best investment was and is my relationship with my husband (and I would dare say vice versa).</p>
<p><em><strong>What has been your worst investment?</strong></em></p>
<p>There was a time when we had a small amount portion of our portfolio invested with an independent investment advisor. In the first few years of the relationship, the investment value increased. Then came March 2020 and this advisor could not handle the situation. In the Spring of 2020, the advisor called me almost daily and in a panic. So not only were we trying to make sense of what was going on in a world turned upside down, we were dealing with an advisor who clearly could not handle the pressure.</p>
<p>To this advisor’s credit, they admitted they did not know what advice to give us on our investments. It got to the point where we did the one thing that you never want to do when the market is tanking: we sold all of it. Fortunately, it was a small amount of our portfolio, but it hurt just the same. That was an expensive lesson in what panic really looks like.</p>
<p>We made the best of it by using the proceeds to pay off our mortgage and offset subsequent capital gains in 2020 and 2021 with the capital losses.</p>
<p><em><strong>What&#8217;s been your overall return?</strong></em></p>
<p>Over the past 10 years, our investments averaged somewhere north of 15% return annually.</p>
<p><em><strong>How often do you monitor/review your portfolio?</strong></em></p>
<p>I’ve been guilty of checking daily when the market is on the upswing. It feels great to see the market in the green every day and balances grow.</p>
<p>Of course, when the market trends down and swings violently like it has been lately, it gives me a stomachache.</p>
<p>So, I’m trying to strike a balance by checking at the end of every month.</p>
<p>Since we have an advisor, we meet quarterly to review where we are and what adjustments, if any, need to be made.</p>
<h4><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>NET WORTH</strong></span></h4>
<p><em><strong>How did you accumulate your net worth?</strong></em></p>
<p>We built our net worth from a combination of increasing our income through our careers, a consistently high savings rate and investing over a 30-year period.</p>
<p>As our incomes grew, our savings grew. We began contributing to our 401ks early in our careers. At first, we contributed as much as we could afford and increased to the maximum contribution limit as soon as our incomes allowed.</p>
<p>We saved a high percentage of our bonuses, stock options and restricted stock awards. I think what set us up for early retirement was the 2008/2009 downturn. Through some amount of dumb luck, we sold our house in the northeast at the market peak just before the 2007-2008 meltdown. We took the proceeds and DCA’d the majority into the market between 2008 – 2011.</p>
<p><em><strong>What would you say is your greatest strength in the ESI wealth-building model (Earn, Save or Invest) and why would you say it&#8217;s tops?</strong></em></p>
<p>I think it’s the combination of Save and Invest: our willingness and ability to save a significant portion of our income and our willingness to invest consistently over time.</p>
<p>The combination of the two has helped propel our net worth.</p>
<p><em><strong>What road bumps did you face along the way to becoming a millionaire and how did you handle them?</strong></em></p>
<p>We had two close calls with declining real estate values. Fortunately, we worked our way out of those situations through corporate relocations.</p>
<p>In each situation we broke even or lost a very small amount on the properties.</p>
<p>At the time, the market declines in the early 2000s and the financial crisis in 2008 seemed to set us back. Staying in the market turned that situation around over time.</p>
<p><em><strong>What are you currently doing to maintain/grow your net worth?</strong></em></p>
<p>Our portfolio has declined by ~10% YTD 2022. In addition, we just switched advisors.</p>
<p>We’re taking advantage of the market downturn to reposition our portfolio with the objective of reducing some fund costs and making the portfolio more tax efficient. It’s painful to sell at a loss yet we know it’s a long-term play.</p>
<p>We continue to reinvest dividends through dollar cost averaging, and we may even put some of our cash buffer into play if the market moves substantially lower.</p>
<p><em><strong>Do you have a target net worth you are trying to attain?</strong></em></p>
<p>For some reason we originally anchored on $3 million net worth. I can’t recall why but that was our goal.</p>
<p>Once we hit $1 million net worth, our portfolio started to grow quickly, and we soon passed the $3 million.</p>
<p>When we started working with our advisors, they helped us create a formal plan and focused on <a href="https://esimoney.com/multiple-streams-of-income-helping-you-get-to-financial-independence-and-beyond/">income streams</a> as well overall net worth.</p>
<p><em><strong>How old were you when you made your first million and have you had any significant behavior shifts since then?</strong></em></p>
<p>We reached the first million mark when I was 36 and my husband was 40.</p>
<p>It wasn’t until we reached $2 million that we started loosening the purse strings a bit. Our main splurge was to renovate our kitchen and bathrooms. We made that money back on that investment a few times over when we sold the property in 2007.</p>
<p>When our net worth hit $7 million, we decided to buy a small vacation condo a few hours from our home. We sold that condo when we decided to retire and didn’t want to carry any mortgage debt into retirement.</p>
<p><em><strong>What money mistakes have you made along the way that others can learn from?</strong></em></p>
<p>I tend to be on the conservative end of the investment spectrum. There were times early on in our investing journey when we should have taken on more risk than we did. This was mainly during the time I was self-managing our portfolio.</p>
<p>I know advisors tend to get a bad rap and the expense is a drag on investment returns however our advisors have helped us improve returns by helping us get comfortable with a more appropriate risk profile.</p>
<p>We could have better leveraged the vacation condo if we bought a property that could have been rented out short term. The condo association did not allow short term rentals. In retrospect, we were thinking too short term on that property.</p>
<p>While not necessarily a mistake, paying off the mortgage on our primary residence was a debate. We had a very low interest rate and were mid-way through a 15-year mortgage. Financially, it would have been more lucrative to keep the mortgage and invest the capital. Psychologically, it has been a wonderful feeling to own our home outright. I’ve read the debates online as this is a question people many consider. Peace of mind won out for us.</p>
<p><em><strong>What advice do you have for ESI Money readers on how to become wealthy?</strong></em></p>
<p>Focus on what you can control. For us, that meant investing in our careers, saving as much as we could as early as could and invest for the long term.</p>
<p>I really do believe that time in the market, particularly when the market declined, was the key to our ability to build wealth. The lesson I would extrapolate is to be willing to make investments now and over time for a long term pay off.</p>
<p>I have less faith in get rich quick opportunities like some of the day trading mania that occurred in 2020. I don’t doubt that money was made quickly but I am suspect about the ability to sustain it over time.</p>
<h4><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>FUTURE</strong></span></h4>
<p><em><strong>What are your retirement plans?</strong></em></p>
<p>My husband and I retired in 2021. Had the pandemic had not come along, we likely would have worked for a few more years.</p>
<p>So far, we are really enjoying our new life. I think we have both come to realize both how precious the next 10 years will be for us in that we’re both healthy and we can spend time on the activities we enjoy and with those we love.</p>
<p>Once we get into our early 70s and beyond, health could make activities more limiting (although we’re focused on keeping ourselves as healthy as possible).</p>
<p>In terms of finances, we will draw on my deferred compensation for the next five years. That will cover ~70%- 90% of our annual expenses. The remainder will come from a cash buffer.</p>
<p><em><strong>Are there any issues in retirement that concern you? If so, how are you planning to address them?</strong></em></p>
<p>There were several issues that we’ve been focused as we built our retirement plan.</p>
<p>The first was healthcare. We will have 7 – 10 years before we qualify for Medicare. We won’t qualify for the ACA subsidy due to our deferred compensation income. Fortunately, my husband officially retired from his company, and we participate in their retiree healthcare plan. The monthly premiums are not subsidized however it’s a good healthcare plan (the same plan we were on while he was working) and we planned for the on-going (and escalating) expense.</p>
<p>The second was a combination of sequence of return risk (SORR) and inflation. This has hit us right in the face this year. We have a little bit of insulation from SORR in the next five years since we will draw on deferred compensation and can continue to reinvest dividends as the market declines. Despite that, it&#8217;s still a major concern for us. There’s almost no protection against inflation although we don’t need to make any major purchases in the foreseeable future (no new cars, home, etc.). We have a good amount of flexibility built into our annual spending budget which I expect we will need to take advantage of at some point; and</p>
<p>The third is the future tax implications of our tax deferred accounts. We are just starting to wrap our heads around the tax consequences of our tax deferred accounts and required minimum distributions. We’re scheduled meet with our CPA to start planning for the time between 2023 (when my husband turns 59 ½) and 2035 (when he turns 72). We will know more about what different scenarios and our options look like shortly.</p>
<h4><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>MISCELLANEOUS</strong></span></h4>
<p><em><strong>How did you learn about finances and at what age did it &#8220;click&#8221;?</strong></em></p>
<p>I learned some hard but valuable lessons in college. When I was in high school, my father worked for a university and, as a benefit, his children’s tuition expense was capped at a fraction of the in-state tuition rate. Of course, my parents heavily lobbied for me to stay close to home. I did but it just wasn’t a fit for me. I decided to transfer to an out of state university where, as expected, tuition was much higher. My parents agreed to the transfer with the stipulation that I pay my own tuition. They would pay for books and provide a stipend for rent/food.</p>
<p>It was one of the best decisions I made. I worked full time for a year so I could save money and qualify for in-state tuition. I worked my way through undergraduate school, took out a small student loan and received small grants. I ended up graduating with honors within 3 years.</p>
<p>That experience brought to the surface how much I value my independence. I realized that having financial resources would allow me to make decisions based on what I want to do vs. have to do. That need for independence has been a big influence on the decisions I’ve made throughout my life.</p>
<p>My father handled the investments, and my mother handled the day-to-day budget in their household. I learned about investing from my father. He started investing in the 70s, threw in the towel at some point in the late 70s and got back in the market in the early 80s. He was a Vanguard/Boglehead type investor and made it a point to share his experience with me once I started my career and had money to invest.</p>
<p><em><strong>Who inspired you to excel in life? Who are your heroes?</strong></em></p>
<p>My parents are my heroes. They were children of the Great Depression, and each came from difficult childhood circumstances. My paternal grandfather died when my father was very young, leaving my grandmother to raise their children by herself, working as a maid. My maternal grandparents lost everything in the ’29 crash, divorced, and basically abandoned my mother when she was a toddler. She had to rely on the kindness of her relatives to raise her.</p>
<p>Through luck my parents found each other and built a remarkable life together, had and raised their children, and lived a comfortable, middle-class life. My family was never rich, yet we always lived in a home which my parents owned, had good healthcare, good public educations, always had food on the table and had each other. My parents worked, scraped, and sacrificed to create the stability and security they never had as children.</p>
<p>My parents had high expectations that their children excel with an emphasis on academics. They instilled discipline in each of us early on: school, homework, chores, church and only then could we partake in TV/sports, etc. We were all expected to get at least a college degree, which all six of achieved with half on scholarship.</p>
<p>I am deeply grateful for my parents and the way they raised me.</p>
<p><em><strong>Do you have any favorite money books you like/recommend? If so, can you share with us your top three and why you like them?</strong></em></p>
<p>I attended a professional curriculum at Wharton. Jeremy Siegel, the Russell E Palmer Professor of Finance, was the featured speaker. I read his book Stocks for the Long Run which I found helpful.</p>
<p>I read <a href="https://esimoney.com/the-best-personal-finance-books-of-all-time-the-millionaire-next-door/">The Millionaire Next Door</a> years ago.</p>
<p><em><strong>Do you give to charity? Why or why not? If you do, what percent of time/money do you give?</strong></em></p>
<p>We began regular charitable giving about 15 years ago.</p>
<p>Our primary focus is monetary giving to charities that benefit animals and the homeless.</p>
<p>We also regularly volunteer for these same organizations giving our time to day-to-day administrative tasks and various fund-raising events.</p>
<p><em><strong>Do you plan to leave an inheritance for your heirs (how do you plan to distribute your wealth at your death)? What are your reasons behind this plan?</strong></em></p>
<p>We expect there will be some funds to pass on after we are gone. Depending on the size of our portfolio over the next 10 years, we will create a <a href="https://esimoney.com/the-advantages-of-using-a-donor-advised-fund/">donor advised fund</a> and begin disbursing larger chunks of funds to our favorite charities.</p>
<p>Along with that plan, we expect to leave an inheritance to our nieces and nephews, although we haven’t made that known to them or their parents just yet.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://esimoney.com/millionaire-interview-337/">Millionaire Interview 337</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://esimoney.com">ESI Money</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://esimoney.com/millionaire-interview-337/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>11</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Millionaire Interview 336</title>
		<link>https://esimoney.com/millionaire-interview-336/</link>
					<comments>https://esimoney.com/millionaire-interview-336/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[ESI]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 09:00:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Millionaires]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://esimoney.com/?p=8743</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Here’s our latest interview with a millionaire as we seek to learn from those who have grown their wealth to high heights. If you’d like to be considered for an interview, drop me a note and we can chat about specifics. This interview took place in May. My questions are in bold italics and their [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://esimoney.com/millionaire-interview-336/">Millionaire Interview 336</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://esimoney.com">ESI Money</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://esimoney.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Business-people-at-meeting-new.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-8744" src="https://esimoney.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Business-people-at-meeting-new-300x240.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="240" srcset="https://esimoney.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Business-people-at-meeting-new-300x240.jpg 300w, https://esimoney.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Business-people-at-meeting-new.jpg 750w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a>Here’s our latest <a href="https://esimoney.com/category/millionaires/">interview with a millionaire</a> as we seek to learn from those who have grown their wealth to high heights.</p>
<p>If you’d like to be considered for an interview, <a href="https://esimoney.com/contact/">drop me a note</a> and we can chat about specifics.</p>
<p>This interview took place in May.</p>
<p>My questions are in bold italics and their responses follow in black.</p>
<p>Let&#8217;s get started&#8230;</p>
<h4><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>OVERVIEW</strong></span></h4>
<p><em><strong>How old are you (and spouse if applicable, plus how long you&#8217;ve been married)?</strong></em></p>
<p>I am 52 and my wife is 51.</p>
<p>We have been married for 26 years. (Hard to believe that is half of my life, but it’s definitely been the good half with my better half!)</p>
<p><em><strong>Do you have kids/family (if so, how old are they)?</strong></em></p>
<p>We have a daughter that is 22 and a son that is 18.</p>
<p><em><strong>What area of the country do you live in (and urban or rural)?</strong></em></p>
<p>We live in the suburbs of a city in the South-Central US.</p>
<p><em><strong>What is your current net worth?</strong></em></p>
<p>Our net worth is currently $4.25 million as reported in Personal Capital this morning.</p>
<p>It’s been a wild ride during the pandemic and with the uncertainty here in 2022 due to global instability and inflation impacts on interest rates and the market.</p>
<p><em><strong>What are the main assets that make up your net worth (stocks, real estate, business, home, retirement accounts, etc.) and any debt that offsets part of these?</strong></em></p>
<ul>
<li>Pre-Tax Retirement Accounts &#8211; value is $1.55M. Most of this is in a traditional 401K. For most of my career, I only focused on building my net worth or saving for retirement through my employer(s) 401K. I’ve been actively working to dramatically increase my tax free and post-tax balances over the past couple of years. Definitely one of my lessons learned later in life that I hope to help others avoid.</li>
<li>Post-Tax Investment Accounts &#8211; value is $945K. I’m not planning to add as much here for the next 5 years or so as I build up tax friendly cash flow from <a href="https://esimoney.com/how-to-get-started-investing-in-real-estate-syndications-part-1/">Real Estate Syndicate investments</a>.</li>
<li>Tax free investment accounts &#8211; $52K. I’ve been doing backdoor Roth IRA conversions at the max (now $1,000 higher that my wife and I are both over 50) for 4 years. I do have larger planned mega Roth conversions the first few years I’m retired and living off of cash reserves to improve my mix of assets in the different tax buckets.</li>
<li><a href="https://esimoney.com/how-to-get-started-investing-in-real-estate-syndications-part-1/">Real Estate Syndicate</a> Deals &#8211; $200K. I’ve done 4 different deals with a couple of different General Partners, in several different markets. I’ve enjoyed analyzing the various investment deals up front (some great tools out there to help with this) and then sitting back and tracking them all with the LP Analyzer excel spreadsheet I purchased. I am planning on adding 2 deals each year for the next 5 years or so as a way to somewhat replicate what a pension would have done had I been fortunate enough to work somewhere that offered one in my career. Two of these deals are very early and I just started receiving distributions, but I’m very happy with the trends and financials for the first two deals. I recognize the risks with these opportunities, but I’m optimistic that this will be an important part of my overall financial landscape well into retirement.</li>
<li>Property &#8211; $2.1M value with home equity of $1.5M after accounting for my remaining mortgage balance.</li>
<li>Cash &#8211; $165K after using some to “buy the dip” recently with the market downturn. I will also deploy some in the next few months on my next RE Syndicate deal.</li>
<li>529 – I will likely have ~$40K left in this account after my daughter graduates. I will transfer some to family for their college expenses and either pay the 10% penalty for the balance or use it for ongoing education expenses at some point for someone in the immediate family.</li>
</ul>
<p>I don’t count the value of our vehicles in my net worth, even though they could be sold for cash if needed. (We have several collector vehicles in addition to daily drivers for all drivers in the household.)</p>
<h4><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>EARN</strong></span></h4>
<p><em><strong>What is your job?</strong></em></p>
<p>I work for a Fortune 500 corporation in the C-Suite, reporting to the CEO. I have only recently attained this level, having worked my way up in a variety of departments and roles with long stops at certain levels. I feel very fortunate to enjoy the work I do with the people in the department I directly support, which wasn’t the case when I first got in role.</p>
<p>Quick tangent – never take the easy path or avoid confrontation with those that aren’t engaged, driven, or all-in to support the people they lead. The difference since I made some aggressive leadership changes is pronounced for the entirety of the team we support/lead, but it’s also made a huge difference with my personal quality of life and how I view work each day.</p>
<p>I’m learning every single day and I find the work challenging, yet rewarding. If there is improvement in the comradery and teamwork amongst my peers in the coming year or two, I will not be in a huge rush to retire. If not, I am comforted to know I’ll be in a place to move on if I continue to aggressively save and maximize the various variable pieces of my total compensation package.</p>
<p><em><strong>What is your annual income?</strong></em></p>
<p>Last year was right at $600K.</p>
<p>If all elements are somewhat near target, this should move to $900K next year with a result somewhere in between those numbers for this year.</p>
<p>Salary is in the low $300’s, so roughly two-thirds is tied up in annual bonus, long-term incentives, and various equity elements with my company.</p>
<p><em><strong>Tell us about your income performance over time. What was the starting salary of your first job, how did it grow from there (and what you did to make it grow), and where are you now?</strong></em></p>
<p>My starting wage at my first two jobs (both started after graduating college) were $6/hr and $7.75hr.</p>
<p>I went full-time with the $6/hr job (previously part-time at 25-30 hours a week) when I was moved up and started making more than I made at the full-time $7.75/hr job.</p>
<p>Here are my earnings by year going back to when I first started working:</p>
<ul>
<li>$19,732</li>
<li>$24,140</li>
<li>$30,632</li>
<li>$67,373</li>
<li>$65,216</li>
<li>$86,000</li>
<li>$89,724</li>
<li>$83,607</li>
<li>$114,069</li>
<li>$162,696</li>
<li>$191,873</li>
<li>$314,991</li>
<li>$228,056</li>
<li>$157,692</li>
<li>$199,571</li>
<li>$223,102</li>
<li>$178,786</li>
<li>$201,421</li>
<li>$187,894</li>
<li>$236,893</li>
<li>$265,187</li>
<li>$277,180</li>
<li>$254,655</li>
<li>$353,092</li>
<li>$324,429</li>
<li>$500,437</li>
<li>$361,944</li>
<li>$392,501</li>
<li>$600,000</li>
</ul>
<p><em><strong>What tips do you have for others who want to grow their career-related income?</strong></em></p>
<p>First, approach all new opportunities from a point of curiosity and interest.</p>
<p>Secondly, take jobs or roles that others pass on because they look too difficult or too challenging. The worse a department or team is doing, the more opportunity for improvement and the better the turnaround story!</p>
<p>Thirdly, volunteer for special assignments or projects. I’m constantly amazed that people wait for opportunities to land on them versus aggressively or actively pursuing personal or leadership growth. I recommend targeting growth in learning and thoughtful horizontal moves, without compensation or promotions even being included. These very often lead to amazing stories and crucial differentiators when you do interview for promotions down the line against what your competitors will have done or produced.</p>
<p><em><strong>What&#8217;s your work-life balance look like?</strong></em></p>
<p>I would say fair to pretty good most of the time.</p>
<p>You are never really totally “off”, but I am able to trust the people on my team to handle most of the urgent items that arise. I am only on point when it&#8217;s either dire or extremely high profile.</p>
<p><em><strong>Do you have any sources of income besides your career? If so, can you list them, give us a feel for how much you earn with each, and offer some insight into how you developed them?</strong></em></p>
<p>I do not have other income sources, aside from the RE syndicate deals that are now all cash flowing as described earlier.</p>
<p>I love that these are <a href="https://esimoney.com/five-categories-of-passive-income-and-how-to-evaluate-them/">passive income</a> streams after the initial due diligence period before choosing whether to invest or not.</p>
<h4><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>SAVE</strong></span></h4>
<p><em><strong>What is your annual spending?</strong></em></p>
<p>Our spending has averaged around $220K per year.</p>
<p><em><strong>What are the main categories (expenses) this spending breaks into?</strong></em></p>
<p>Aside from taxes, the largest portion of our spending is for food &amp; housing.</p>
<p>Housing is high because values on our home have got up dramatically and so have the associated taxes. We also have done some form of home improvement nearly every year and we spend a lot of time and money outdoors working on our landscape. We also partially support family aside from our home and kids.</p>
<p>We spend a great deal more than most on food. Some is due to special diet restrictions, but frankly this is an area where we splurge and dining out is a regular occurrence. Food costs for my daughter at college are outrageous as well, especially since it’s required when living on campus and she only eats about 10% of a what I did when I was in college!</p>
<p>We are also big into hobbies and mine are not inexpensive hobbies, nor as productive as my wife’s. She designs and sews her own clothes, among many other productive hobbies. I love vehicles and while I work on them myself, it’s still an expensive hobby and not nearly as productive as my wife’s hobbies.</p>
<p>Here is a rough breakdown of our spending by % of total after taxes:</p>
<ul>
<li>Housing – 22%</li>
<li>Food (Dining Out &amp; Groceries) – 10%</li>
<li>Vehicles – 12%</li>
<li>Hobbies – 3%</li>
<li>Charitable Donations – 12%</li>
<li>Entertainment – 2%</li>
<li>Household &amp; Misc – 6%</li>
<li>Education: Daughter’s School (non food) – 15%</li>
<li>Insurance/Health Expenses – 9%</li>
<li>Travel – 7%</li>
</ul>
<p><em><strong>Do you have a budget? If so, how do you implement it?</strong></em></p>
<p>We do not have a set budget per se, but I do track our monthly “P&amp;L” statement against the forecast I setup to start the year. Most of this is to forecast net worth by month, savings rate, and cash flow for our new passive income streams.</p>
<p>Historically, my wife has been very frugal &amp; not a spender. This has changed somewhat in the past few years, but if I’m honest her spending while more frequent is at a much lower level than the items or hobbies I’ve spent on.</p>
<p>Although my vehicle assortment has appreciated big-time over the past few years, historically I’ve likely been lucky to break-even all-up as I’ve continued flipping them.</p>
<p><em><strong>What percentage of your gross income do you save and how has that changed over time?</strong></em></p>
<p>Somewhere between 25-40%.</p>
<p>For most of my 30s I maxed out my 401K contribution, but I didn’t contribute anything to after tax investments.</p>
<p>I paid down extra on my mortgage and we spent more than we should have on trips and other items.</p>
<p>We also have had much more in healthcare expenses than what is typical as a family due to some health issues that coincide with the special dietary costs I referenced above.</p>
<p><em><strong>What&#8217;s your best tip for saving (accumulating) money?</strong></em></p>
<p>Track your progress &amp; set net worth goals both monthly and yearly.</p>
<p>I do a monthly update on how we are doing against my initial start of year forecast, and this competition with ourselves forces me to make adjustments when the market is underperforming what I expected coming into the year. (Basically, upping our savings rate since that is the only thing I directly control.)</p>
<p>I also funnel money each month into accounts that are setup to fund our Roth IRA conversions, RE Syndicate investments, and after-tax investment accounts at set intervals.</p>
<p>The other tip that I’m sure your readers all know is making sure your money is working hard for you, 24 hours a day, 7 days a week, &amp; 365 days a year.</p>
<p>I’ve taken on more risk than what many would be comfortable with, so knowing your risk tolerance and associated behaviors in down markets or economic circumstances is paramount. I hold true to my core investment strategy and my willingness to double down or “buy the dip” has served me well.</p>
<p>I’m more cautious at this stage of my career than earlier, but I still have far more money in equities than what is typical at my age. I will keep 3 years’ worth of cash on hand to help prepare for sequence of return risk when I do decide to hang it up, but I am on track to have ~80% of our current living expenses covered in 5 years if I stay the course and get even close to projected returns from the RE syndicate deals &amp; funds I’m investing in.</p>
<p>We will downsize our home and look at geo arbitrage as well given the relatively high cost of living where we are today. Like ESI, a smaller home in Florida in an active community would be ideal – depending on where our kids end up of course.</p>
<p><em><strong>What&#8217;s your best tip for spending less money?</strong></em></p>
<p>I’m not the best person for advice here, it’s definitely the area I’ve done the least well on out of E-S-I.</p>
<p>However, I’ve always been hyper-focused on getting a good deal. I do my homework and I’m not afraid to walk away if negotiations break down for purchases. My wife tells me she never knew that nearly everything is negotiable until she met me.</p>
<p>I meet with my insurance agent regularly to make sure we have the best rates, call our cell phone provider and get discounts as opposed to switching, and make sure we get maximum value for each dollar spent with points or cash back. I’m unfailingly polite about it, but I’m also politely relentless and I’ve found that people are very willing to be accommodating if you handle things the right way with an eye towards a win-win.</p>
<p>One small example is our homebuilder’s sales agent gave us an extra $50K in upgrades for various things during our build because we formed a bond when working with him and we were accommodating on delays that came up or with fixtures that were out of stock. It didn’t seem unreasonable to us, but he indicated it was pretty rare with the folks he usually deals with. Our builder even upgraded our outdoor grill area as a surprise, with extra high-end finishes at no charge since we had shared our sincere appreciation with the top executives in his company over his meticulous work with our home.</p>
<p>My point here is making every dollar go further is possible with education and intentionality, even if you aren’t a great saver like many I’ve read about throughout this forum and other great interview recaps.</p>
<p><em><strong>What is your favorite thing to spend money on/your secret splurge?</strong></em></p>
<p>Vehicles, food, and travel.</p>
<h4><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>INVEST</strong></span></h4>
<p><em><strong>What is your investment philosophy/plan?</strong></em></p>
<p>Like many, I subscribe to the Warren Buffet approach of buy quality and hold into perpetuity.</p>
<p>Other than rebalancing annually to stay on track with our asset allocation, most of my investments have remained since inception. (A few notable exceptions in my worst investments will come up below.)</p>
<p><em><strong>What has been your best investment?</strong></em></p>
<p>This is easy, my decision to marry my wife. I know it’s cliché, but nearly every single thing in your life forks off of this one decision. Other than my faith decision, nothing was more impactful in my life (financial or otherwise) than who I married.</p>
<p>Otherwise, property has had an outsized contribution to our net worth. Many corporate relocations have helped take out all of the costs of moving and commissions, but this has not been due to any skill on my part – aside from realizing that buying is a far better option than renting from a tax perspective and for building equity based on the tax code.</p>
<p><em><strong>What has been your worst investment?</strong></em></p>
<p>Early on I thought I could pick stocks and time the market. I had some initial success, which led to hubris and me thinking I had some sort of skill. A near full loss showed me the error of my ways and I’ve not returned to this way of thinking. If I don’t fully understand it, I don’t invest in it &amp; I don’t expect to beat the market on my own. Low cost funds and ETFs have been my way ever since.</p>
<p>Also, stay away from any investment that attempts to couple life insurance and investing together. No matter how enticing, both are much better handled separately. Term life insurance for a duration that fits your need &amp; investments where fees are fully transparent.</p>
<p><em><strong>What&#8217;s been your overall return?</strong></em></p>
<p>About 14% annually over the past 25 years, though this does include my 401K matches through the years.</p>
<p>It has accelerated the past 5-7 years, but regression to the mean (or lower) seems very likely moving forward.</p>
<p>My last 5 years of net worth increases YOY have been: 21.4%, 3.45%, 28.3%, 21.5%, &amp; 39%.</p>
<p><em><strong>How often do you monitor/review your portfolio?</strong></em></p>
<p>I use Personal Capital and go into it at least weekly. I download all transactions each month and use it to update my personal P&amp;L statement each month.</p>
<p>I use a great spreadsheet program that I believe I read about on this forum that was generated from an accountant. It’s taken my rudimentary spreadsheet that tracked and forecasted my income, net worth, expenses, 401k balance, stock options, etc…into a single coordinated &amp; automated file.</p>
<p>While it’s hard to see the several hundred thousand dollars drop in net worth over the past couple of months, the history chart gives me comfort because I can observe even worse dips historically in our net worth &amp; we recovered in time. I expect to see this cycle several more times in my lifetime, maybe it will get easier – but so far, it’s still unsettling. (Even if it’s “paper losses.”)</p>
<h4><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>NET WORTH</strong></span></h4>
<p><em><strong>How did you accumulate your net worth?</strong></em></p>
<p>I was fascinated with personal finance ever since I studied it in college. I paid for my undergrad myself and it’s when I learned crucial finance principles like: Opportunity Cost, NPV, compounding interest, Rule of 72, etc…</p>
<p>I grew up in a lower-class household and I was very motivated to live a different life myself than what I saw growing up. Money was a constant stress in our house growing up and I was extremely driven to change that for myself and my family.</p>
<p>I also am fascinated by business in general. I have read the WSJ daily for years and I spend my discretionary time following financial thought leaders and reading great blogs and websites like ESI!</p>
<p><em><strong>What would you say is your greatest strength in the ESI wealth-building model (Earn, Save or Invest) and why would you say it&#8217;s tops?</strong></em></p>
<p>I have been fortunate to become a fairly high earner, which has definitely had an outsized impact on my net worth so far.</p>
<p>I’ve also had a strong investment track record, which I mostly attribute to living in a great time to be an investor and the earning history more than any real inherent skill in investing. (Other than recognizing early on that fees are absolute killers of portfolio growth given compounding and staying in extremely low cost funds.)</p>
<p><em><strong>What road bumps did you face along the way to becoming a millionaire and how did you handle them?</strong></em></p>
<p>I lost my way during a chunk of my 30s and early 40s and my spending was far more than it should have been. In hindsight, I was unhappy with my job at the time and I was compensating by seeking enjoyment in things. Of course, that happiness from a purchase is fleeting and I learned the hard way that I needed to address the root cause versus masking it.</p>
<p>A lesson I learned that may benefit others is that the best way to deal with personal hardships or struggles is to focus on others. The more I focused on me or my circumstance, the unhappier I was. When I focused on others, specifically volunteering or helping others financially, physically, or emotionally – I gained perspective that generated feelings of appreciation and gratitude that were lacking previously.</p>
<p>It doesn’t take long to see that no matter what you are dealing with, there are others dealing with far worse. Volunteering on a non-profit board, anonymously helping a neighbor, and serving others created perspective that I was sorely lacking.</p>
<p><em><strong>What are you currently doing to maintain/grow your net worth?</strong></em></p>
<p>I have a 5-year roadmap to achieve full financial independence and legacy wealth for my family given some health situations that will require funding after my wife and I are in a better place. The need for this used to keep me up at night, but I’ve learned to trust in God and through the lesson on helping others I’ve realized just how incredibly fortunate I really am.</p>
<p>Otherwise, the plan calls for 14-16 RE Syndicate deals on a rotating basis by 2027 and continued progress towards a 50% savings rate year in and year out.</p>
<p><em><strong>Do you have a target net worth you are trying to attain?</strong></em></p>
<p>$10M. This is in addition to the passive income stream I’ve mentioned throughout.</p>
<p>It’s great to read about folks that have said that <a href="https://esimoney.com/youve-won-game-stop-playing/">when you win the game, you can stop playing</a>. My situation is a little different with the legacy element, but I am sure I will struggle with the OMY (one more year) syndrome due to inflation or other items that pop up along the way.</p>
<p>It’s comforting to see so many other folks navigating retirement with dignity and purpose, and I plan to use them as my role models in lieu of focusing on just a continually bigger number.</p>
<p><em><strong>How old were you when you made your first million and have you had any significant behavior shifts since then?</strong></em></p>
<p>I was 44 when I officially had a net worth of $1M+.</p>
<p>We didn’t change anything then and we really haven’t changed anything since from a personal standpoint.</p>
<p>I did start coaching others on financial principles right around that time though. I had started managing my parent&#8217;s accounts and investments right before this and it shocked me to see how they were being taken advantage of by some unscrupulous people and a lack of knowledge. They never had much money, but they could have had more if they weren’t paying up to 1.6% in fees in several accounts for decades!</p>
<p>I started helping a couple of people in small ways and the word spread. I shared principles with many, but a core few have applied them and are now in a much different place as a result.</p>
<p>Frankly, that’s one of the things that gives me the most joy of anything I’ve done as they now are paying it forward with their friends and families. I just can’t figure out why this stuff still isn’t taught in schools…</p>
<p><em><strong>What money mistakes have you made along the way that others can learn from?</strong></em></p>
<p>So many mistakes – it’s hard to pick just a few, but here it goes:</p>
<ul>
<li>Don’t only save in pre-tax investment accounts.</li>
<li>Start early! I made excuses early on even though I knew better. Simply no substitute for time in investing and gaining financial independence. I frittered away money in my 20s that would have me already retired today.</li>
<li>Get your estate in shape, with the appropriate paperwork, early and before anything happens. Living will, last will &amp; testament, trusts if applicable, etc…</li>
<li>Track your spending and don’t compound the problems in your life by compensating for stress with “stuff”.</li>
</ul>
<p><em><strong>What advice do you have for ESI Money readers on how to become wealthy?</strong></em></p>
<p>Surround yourself with high quality people or friends that follow strong financial principles and discipline. The wrong crowd hurts us as adults, just like it did when we were kids. (So &amp; so is going on another trip or has x new car or appliance, therefore I should too.)</p>
<p>When you are considering a purchase, evaluate it against the opportunity cost of what you could do with those funds against your financial goals &amp; objectives. It’s a balance, for me it’s not just live on 15% (or whatever) of your income to get to FIRE as quick as possible &amp; then check-out. Whatever your balance point is, find it &amp; stick to it.</p>
<h4><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>FUTURE</strong></span></h4>
<p><em><strong>What are your plans for the future regarding lifestyle?</strong></em></p>
<p>I do not plan to downsize careers, but for sure I’d like to downsize our house and retire early. 60 is not early by any means, but I see that as a reasonable finish line if things continue to go well at work.</p>
<p>It sounds cliché, but I feel that the work I do makes a real difference and I get to help people. I have other means of doing so outside of work, but the size and scale of what I can do at work is pretty big due to my role. It’s a chance to set a different example than what many people have likely seen or may expect to see from an executive.</p>
<p><em><strong>What are your retirement plans?</strong></em></p>
<p>All the great thoughts on the non-financial elements of retirement on this site have reaffirmed for me those great intentions aren’t enough. I have lots of interests, but getting them vetted prior to retiring will require planning and/or trial and error.</p>
<p>I have always loved sports and I’ve played competitive basketball, tennis, soccer, volleyball, and table tennis. Looking forward to trying pickleball, getting better at golf, and building a car from the ground up as new learning opportunities. Serving on a few boards (non-profit) and potentially as an angel investor with causes I’m passionate about.</p>
<p><em><strong>Are there any issues in retirement that concern you? If so, how are you planning to address them?</strong></em></p>
<p>Location is something I only have a theory on. I am planning to test out a few places by living there when I retire for a few months to see how it goes.</p>
<p>Aligning those with my wife and locations for my kids will also require some faith &amp; trust that I can’t see the path for quite yet.</p>
<h4><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>MISCELLANEOUS</strong></span></h4>
<p><em><strong>How did you learn about finances and at what age did it &#8220;click&#8221;?</strong></em></p>
<p>In college when I took finance classes.</p>
<p>That inspired me to maximize my finances, but I certainly took awhile to fully apply those principles vs. starting right after college as I should have!</p>
<p><em><strong>Who inspired you to excel in life? Who are your heroes?</strong></em></p>
<p>I don’t have a great singular answer to this question.</p>
<p>I have some teachers that made a big difference during my formative years, an Uncle that I saw achieve executive status and share some visibility into what that enabled – but most of my drive comes from a need to avoid the financial hardships I observed growing up.</p>
<p>In more recent years, I’m incredibly inspired by Warren Buffet and Bill Gates commitment to sharing their wealth in meaningful ways all across the world in a shared foundation. Eradicating disease in third world countries, funding libraries all across the US, etc…</p>
<p><em><strong>Do you have any favorite money books you like/recommend? If so, can you share with us your top three and why you like them?</strong></em></p>
<p>The obligatory “<a href="https://esimoney.com/the-best-personal-finance-books-of-all-time-the-millionaire-next-door/">Millionaire Next Door</a>” answer that most everyone gives was certainly a spring board to finally applying what I’d learned in college and putting it into practice after I got married and our daughter was born.</p>
<p>I also read the WSJ every day and many financial news feeds from various sources.</p>
<p>I’ve read “<a href="https://esimoney.com/rich-dad-poor-dad-book-review/">Rich Dad Poor Dad</a>”&nbsp; and several books on investing in Real Estate Syndications as well.</p>
<p>I’ll round out my three with The Hands-Off Investor: An Insider’s Guide to Investing in Passive Real Estate Syndications by Brian Burke and How Much Money Do I Need to Retire?: Uncommon Financial Planning Wisdom for a Stress-Free Retirement by Todd R. Tresidder.</p>
<p><em><strong>Do you give to charity? Why or why not? If you do, what percent of time/money do you give?</strong></em></p>
<p>Yes, we donate to our church and to many other causes that we feel passionate about.</p>
<p>This was not easy for me and it’s still something I’m working on building onto further.</p>
<p><em><strong>Do you plan to leave an inheritance for your heirs (how do you plan to distribute your wealth at your death)? What are your reasons behind this plan?</strong></em></p>
<p>Yes. We have a special circumstance with our kids that will require legacy money after my wife and I are gone. That is a major driver of our financial priorities, in addition to preparation for our own retirement situation.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://esimoney.com/millionaire-interview-336/">Millionaire Interview 336</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://esimoney.com">ESI Money</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://esimoney.com/millionaire-interview-336/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>4</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Millionaire Interview 335</title>
		<link>https://esimoney.com/millionaire-interview-335/</link>
					<comments>https://esimoney.com/millionaire-interview-335/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[ESI]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 09:00:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Millionaires]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://esimoney.com/?p=8733</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Here’s our latest interview with a millionaire as we seek to learn from those who have grown their wealth to high heights. If you’d like to be considered for an interview, drop me a note and we can chat about specifics. This interview took place in May. My questions are in bold italics and their [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://esimoney.com/millionaire-interview-335/">Millionaire Interview 335</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://esimoney.com">ESI Money</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://esimoney.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Close-up-of-piggy-bank-on-desk-new.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-8734" src="https://esimoney.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Close-up-of-piggy-bank-on-desk-new-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://esimoney.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Close-up-of-piggy-bank-on-desk-new-300x200.jpg 300w, https://esimoney.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Close-up-of-piggy-bank-on-desk-new.jpg 750w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a>Here’s our latest <a href="https://esimoney.com/category/millionaires/">interview with a millionaire</a> as we seek to learn from those who have grown their wealth to high heights.</p>
<p>If you’d like to be considered for an interview, <a href="https://esimoney.com/contact/">drop me a note</a> and we can chat about specifics.</p>
<p>This interview took place in May.</p>
<p>My questions are in bold italics and their responses follow in black.</p>
<p>Let&#8217;s get started&#8230;</p>
<h4><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>OVERVIEW</strong></span></h4>
<p><em><strong>How old are you (and spouse if applicable, plus how long you&#8217;ve been married)?</strong></em></p>
<p>I am 57 and my spouse is also 57.</p>
<p>We have been married for 34 years.</p>
<p><em><strong>Do you have kids/family (if so, how old are they)?</strong></em></p>
<p>We have one child, he is 31.</p>
<p>He is also married and a contributing member to society, he has been independent since graduating from college. That means we have been “empty nesters” for around 8 years.</p>
<p><em><strong>What area of the country do you live in (and urban or rural)?</strong></em></p>
<p>We live outside of a large metropolitan city in the southeast, mostly a bedroom community on the southside of the city.</p>
<p><em><strong>What is your current net worth?</strong></em></p>
<p>Current net worth sits at around $2.5 million.</p>
<p><em><strong>What are the main assets that make up your net worth (stocks, real estate, business, home, retirement accounts, etc.) and any debt that offsets part of these?</strong></em></p>
<p>Our main assets are as follows:</p>
<ul>
<li>401K &#8212; $1.515M &#8212; This is a managed fund, currently running about 60% stocks/40% bonds</li>
<li>Primary Residence &#8212; $340K &#8212; A bit inflated due to the recent uptick in the housing market, but hey who am I to complain!</li>
<li>Pension (value) &#8212; $252K &#8212; This is a guaranteed pension that was frozen a few years back during a downturn/bankruptcy. This type of traditional pension has fallen to the wayside. I based the value on the monthly amount and life expectancy</li>
<li>TD Ameritrade account &#8212; $206K &#8212; This fund is used to balance out the portfolio, more structured toward the bond side</li>
<li>Cash &#8212; $168k &#8212; I know, I know, way too heavy here but I will get into this later</li>
<li>HSA &#8212; $35K &#8212; We contribute the maximum amount that we can each year and plan to use this as a bridge supplement for healthcare</li>
<li>Bulk Pension &#8212; $30K &#8212; This was an add on when the above pension was frozen</li>
<li>Series EE Bonds &#8212; $7K &#8212; These are leftovers from when we started to fund my son’s college tuition account (pre 529 account availability)</li>
</ul>
<h4><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>EARN</strong></span></h4>
<p><em><strong>What is your job?</strong></em></p>
<p>I&#8217;m a mid-level manager working for a large transportation-based company.</p>
<p>Both my wife and I started our careers in the military &#8212; one in the Navy and one in the Marine Corps. This is where we met, soon after we left the military, and both entered into the private sector.</p>
<p>I had a brief 1 year stint working for the government but it was mostly a transition to my current company.</p>
<p>I am one of a dying breed these days that has stayed with my current company for the bulk of my career, currently just shy of 34 years. I have held various positions with increasing responsibilities over the span of my career. The ability to move laterally and the opportunities at my company are endless and maybe that is the reason I have stuck around for so long.</p>
<p><em><strong>What is your annual income?</strong></em></p>
<p>My current income is around $220k with bonuses, stock grants, etc.</p>
<p>My wife left her position some years ago and manages the household, which for me is priceless.</p>
<p><em><strong>Tell us about your income performance over time. What was the starting salary of your first job, how did it grow from there (and what you did to make it grow), and where are you now?</strong></em></p>
<p>Starting salary for my first job was $8k a year. Being an enlisted troop in the military does not pay well, but my housing and meals were all free so I guess when you factor that in it inflates considerably.</p>
<p>Working for the government grew my salary to around $18k per year.</p>
<p>Starting salary with my current company was around $34k per year (1988 dollars!)</p>
<p>Salary doubled to $60k in 1998.</p>
<p>$100k in 2008.</p>
<p>$219k in 2018.</p>
<p>I gave 10 year salary increments because I feel this is sometimes better than the year-by-year numbers that I have seen before. Especially when you have been at the same company for so many years.</p>
<p>We have no debt, we tend to buy cars and keep them for 10 years or so, and have been in the same house for over 25 years. Having no mortgage is the first step to financial freedom in my opinion.</p>
<p><em><strong>What tips do you have for others who want to grow their career-related income?</strong></em></p>
<p>I used to think it was “find a good company, and stick with it”, but I think my attitude has changed over time with the elimination of the traditional pension and the portability of the 401k based retirements. There is nothing keeping the current and next generation of workers in one place anymore, and I think that if I had it to do over again I would join them</p>
<p>Most are just looking for a better working environment and a better work life balance. I think the best advice I could give is always strive to be the best at what you do. If you are a ditch digger, then be the best one around. That goes all the way to CEO in my opinion. Why would you want to be mediocre and not want to be the best?</p>
<p><em><strong>What&#8217;s your work-life balance look like?</strong></em></p>
<p>Well until about a year ago it used to be terrible. I was in roles for almost 20 years that required me to be “on call” 24/7, 365 strapped to a pager, then a cell phone/email. That sometimes got in the way of enjoying the time that I did have outside of the standard work hours.</p>
<p>Over the past year I have drifted away from that type of demand. Now my work-life balance is much better and I enjoy my time off.</p>
<p>Nobody looks back at the end of their life and says “I wish that I had worked more…”.</p>
<p><em><strong>Do you have any sources of income besides your career? If so, can you list them, give us a feel for how much you earn with each, and offer some insight into how you developed them?</strong></em></p>
<p>We do not have any sources of income outside of my salary.</p>
<h4><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>SAVE</strong></span></h4>
<p><em><strong>What is your annual spending?</strong></em></p>
<p>Our annual spending is around $50-60k per year.</p>
<p>I have only been tracking this for the past couple of years. This is all inclusive with travel, home improvements, taxes, insurance, etc.</p>
<p><em><strong>What are the main categories (expenses) this spending breaks into?</strong></em></p>
<p>Mainly it is just the day to day expenses.</p>
<p>We are not big on eating out so we tend to dine in the majority of the time and any big expenses are discussed thoroughly. These are generally travel and home improvement. Home improvement is different than home maintenance.</p>
<p><em><strong>Do you have a budget? If so, how do you implement it?</strong></em></p>
<p>We do not have a formalized budget.</p>
<p>We do track spending using software so that we can see where we have overrun the pre-set limits on such things as travel, food, etc. I do reconcile it at the end of each month just to ensure that we are not way off track.</p>
<p>My wife (household CFO) takes charge of paying the bills and ensuring that the house keeps running smoothly.</p>
<p>Traditionally we do things ourselves but recently we have started to hire jobs out that we no longer want to do, or consider too risky, tree cutting, high ladder work, etc.</p>
<p><em><strong>What percentage of your gross income do you save and how has that changed over time?</strong></em></p>
<p>Currently around 30-40%.</p>
<p>This has certainly increased over time as income has changed and with the elimination of debt, mostly being mortgage free.</p>
<p><em><strong>What&#8217;s your best tip for saving (accumulating) money?</strong></em></p>
<p>Have the discipline to stick to it.</p>
<p>Not having a rainy day fund is a miserable feeling and can quickly turn you upside down financially.</p>
<p>Take a hard look at where the discretionary money goes, daily coffee, eating out for lunch every day, etc.</p>
<p><em><strong>What&#8217;s your best tip for spending less money?</strong></em></p>
<p>Watch the discretionary spending.</p>
<p>The $3-4 at a shot for things adds up quickly along with constantly eating out.</p>
<p>Spend more on life experiences and less on material things.</p>
<p>For big ticket items, take a pause before you purchase and let the cost sink in to ensure that it is a good decision and not a spur of the moment decision.</p>
<p><em><strong>What is your favorite thing to spend money on/your secret splurge?</strong></em></p>
<p>Definitely travel.</p>
<p>We love to travel overseas (or did love to travel overseas). We have started to travel again this year and are enjoying it.</p>
<p>This will also be important to us in retirement. Traveling is where you learn different cultures, ways of thinking, etc.</p>
<h4><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>INVEST</strong></span></h4>
<p><em><strong>What is your investment philosophy/plan?</strong></em></p>
<p>Up until a few years ago it was just head down forge forward, no real plan, just fund the 401k.</p>
<p>We met with a financial advisor a few years ago and he really pulled the whole picture together for us and is still helping us with allocation, retirement goals, etc.</p>
<p>I am not a financial guy by any means, I stick to my lanes for the most part.</p>
<p><em><strong>What has been your best investment?</strong></em></p>
<p>Marrying well for sure.</p>
<p>As many have posted on here there is no real substitute for having a partner who is on the same track as you and has the same goals.</p>
<p>When I first started out with my current company one of the senior people I was working with walked me through signing up for 401k, and told me to never stop the contributions, the best piece of advice ever. Even when there were pay cuts and reductions I stayed the course and it has paid off, compound interest over a large span of time.</p>
<p><em><strong>What has been your worst investment?</strong></em></p>
<p>Probably not paying attention to my 401k during the early/mid years.</p>
<p>I picked an allocation (mutual fund) and stuck with it. There were not the classes and education that there is now for these types of things.</p>
<p><em><strong>What&#8217;s been your overall return?</strong></em></p>
<p>I would guess around 8-10% for the duration.</p>
<p>We have some investments that do better and some worse so it is a balance.</p>
<p><em><strong>How often do you monitor/review your portfolio?</strong></em></p>
<p>I generally look at it once or twice a month.</p>
<p>Most of it is managed so I just check in to see how things are doing against expectations.</p>
<p>When the market tanked at the start of COVID, I did not look at it for quite a while, just to save myself the heartache but it recovered nicely.</p>
<p>The start of 2022 has been rough, but we are playing the long game and expect there to be bumps in the road.</p>
<h4><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>NET WORTH</strong></span></h4>
<p><em><strong>How did you accumulate your net worth?</strong></em></p>
<p>It has all been through saving money. I know that sounds simple but there have been no inheritances, lottery wins or anything like that.</p>
<p>My salary has steadily grown over time, and luckily it mostly outpaced inflation/cost of living. Once I reached a level where stock options and bonuses were awarded that is where it really started to kick in.</p>
<p>We never changed our lifestyle when our income increased. Having contributed to a 401k for over 30 years did not hurt either but more on that roller coaster later.</p>
<p><em><strong>What would you say is your greatest strength in the ESI wealth-building model (Earn, Save or Invest) and why would you say it&#8217;s tops?</strong></em></p>
<p>I think it is a toss up between earning and saving, more leaning toward the saving side since I needed to earn to get to the saving side. Saving allowed for investing so the center of it all seems to be the saving piece of the puzzle.</p>
<p>It has not always been easy and sometimes things were really tight financially but we always stuck to trying to save what we could. One of our greatest accomplishments was saving for our son’s college. We started out with EE bonds deducted from paychecks and eventually opened a 529 when available, this and the states “lottery funded scholarship” allowed him to graduate debt free. This cannot be underestimated when they are starting out in life after college.</p>
<p><em><strong>What road bumps did you face along the way to becoming a millionaire and how did you handle them?</strong></em></p>
<p>A company bankruptcy was the largest road bump in my opinion.</p>
<p>At the time the 401k matching was with company stock, so when the company filed for bankruptcy I lost half my 401k and my “guaranteed” pension was frozen at that point.</p>
<p>I learned a hard lesson on not having all your eggs in the same basket. I no longer hold onto company stock for very long after it is issued.</p>
<p><em><strong>What are you currently doing to maintain/grow your net worth?</strong></em></p>
<p>Since I am planning on retiring in 10 months we are more on the maintaining side of the equation.</p>
<p>I am hoping to fund retirement with pension/SSI/other to let the retirement fund (401k) continue to grow for a bit and to build that cushion to help me sleep better at night.</p>
<p><em><strong>Do you have a target net worth you are trying to attain?</strong></em></p>
<p>I never dreamed I would be where I am today financially so I don’t really have a target, just enough to be comfortable in retirement and be able to do the things we have always talked about doing (travel, etc.)</p>
<p><em><strong>How old were you when you made your first million and have you had any significant behavior shifts since then?</strong></em></p>
<p>You know, I am not really sure.</p>
<p>I had never thought about net worth until I started considering retirement. I know that sounds crazy but it’s true.</p>
<p>If I had to guess when our net worth hit the $1M mark I was probably 52-53 years old. I think the main behavior shift is that I no longer worry about having a job. I know that I can leave and be ok, maybe even find another career if that happens, so it has given me the freedom of choice. Now I get to choose if I stay or go. There is peace in that.</p>
<p><em><strong>What money mistakes have you made along the way that others can learn from?</strong></em></p>
<p>I think if I would do anything differently I would have been more of an active participant in where my 401k was invested.</p>
<p>For too many years I just let it go with my initial selections. Once I started having it professionally managed it really started to grow.</p>
<p>I know that that may not be a popular scenario but I am not a financial guy and will never profess to be one (or desire to be one), so getting help with that side of it was a good choice.</p>
<p><em><strong>What advice do you have for ESI Money readers on how to become wealthy?</strong></em></p>
<p>Save money. Even when it hurts, save money.</p>
<p>Invest in your retirement plans early in your career. If nothing else invest enough to get the company match if that is the plan offered, this is free money.</p>
<p>Start those habits early and they will pay off tremendously later in life when you can retire before you hit 67 years old!</p>
<h4><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>FUTURE</strong></span></h4>
<p><em><strong>What are your plans for the future regarding lifestyle?</strong></em></p>
<p>We can retire early. Well, not really that early but 9 years early is good enough for me.</p>
<p>I would imagine since we are not big spenders that we will maintain a similar lifestyle in retirement.</p>
<p>We have plans to move to another state that is more tax friendly and where our son currently resides.</p>
<p>I do not object to working some during retirement but it will have to be something that I just love to get up and do. After 35 years of corporate work, anything stress free will be a good compromise.</p>
<p>Travel domestically and abroad are top of the list items.</p>
<p><em><strong>What are your retirement plans?</strong></em></p>
<p>The current plan is to retire in 2023.</p>
<p>I currently do not have plans to work in retirement, but that can always change, if I find myself with time on my hands and I get bored, then maybe I will do something part time, or find a non-profit to contribute time to. Can’t see myself playing pickleball, but we will stay active. We love to hike, kayak, etc. so that will give us lots of opportunity for activities.</p>
<p>My wife has her own activities. It will just be up to me to expand on the things that I currently do now &#8212; I will just have more time to do them.</p>
<p><em><strong>Are there any issues in retirement that concern you? If so, how are you planning to address them?</strong></em></p>
<p>Ah yes. Healthcare.</p>
<p>I really would have thought that by now that the U.S. would have figured out healthcare, but it does not seem to be making progress. So we will need to figure this out soon.</p>
<p>Going to the open market is expensive and the company does offer a “retiree package” but it rivals the cost of the open market.</p>
<p>We do have plans to minimize income so that we can take advantage of all the credits and discounts that we can until we hit Medicare age.</p>
<p>Also a bit concerned about switching from saver to spender. I am sure there are many who read this blog that have made that transition and would be good to hear how you did that and how long it took to become comfortable with it.</p>
<p>Also being able to balance where to pull funds from early in retirement (pre-pension/SSI) and later when these kick in.</p>
<p>The age old question of when to start SSI is also something that I find very confusing.</p>
<h4><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>MISCELLANEOUS</strong></span></h4>
<p><em><strong>How did you learn about finances and at what age did it &#8220;click&#8221;?</strong></em></p>
<p>I think you learn about finances as you go through life.</p>
<p>When you are young and single you don’t really think about it too much, more when you get married, and even more when you have children. After that as you progress through life your attitude and priorities change to a more stable place.</p>
<p>I did not grow up with a lot of money. We were not “poor” by the definition but we did not have very much discretionary funds either. I think that teaches you to be careful with what funds you do have, and to spend them wisely.</p>
<p><em><strong>Who inspired you to excel in life? Who are your heroes?</strong></em></p>
<p>I don&#8217;t think I can honestly point to one person or another on this.</p>
<p>My parents were both hard working factory workers that pushed on raising 2 kids. I have the utmost appreciation for that now.</p>
<p><em><strong>Do you have any favorite money books you like/recommend? If so, can you share with us your top three and why you like them?</strong></em></p>
<p>I can hear the gasps now &#8212; I am not really a reader. When I do read they are more targeted toward leadership.</p>
<p>I do enjoy short articles on finance, business, etc. Maybe it is an attention span problem! Maybe I will read more in retirement…probably not.</p>
<ul>
<li>Essentialism by Greg Mckeown—taught me a lot on how to prioritize things, what is important and what is not.</li>
<li>It’s Your Ship by Michael Abrashoff—taught me to take control and drive for results.</li>
<li>Make Your Bed by William McRaven—do the small things first, set yourself up for success.</li>
</ul>
<p>I know these are not the normal books that you see on here but it is what I read.</p>
<p><em><strong>Do you give to charity? Why or why not? If you do, what percent of time/money do you give?</strong></em></p>
<p>We do not give to charity, other than clothes, etc. to local charity groups.</p>
<p>This is something that we may consider later on in life. It will take some research as there are many “charities” out there that are charities in name only.</p>
<p><em><strong>Do you plan to leave an inheritance for your heirs (how do you plan to distribute your wealth at your death)? What are your reasons behind this plan?</strong></em></p>
<p>Not really a plan, with only one heir it will be up to him to carry on.</p>
<p>I will have the conversation with him at some point on being a good steward of these types of things and to be sure that there is a plan to pass it on to the next generation.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://esimoney.com/millionaire-interview-335/">Millionaire Interview 335</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://esimoney.com">ESI Money</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://esimoney.com/millionaire-interview-335/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Be Happier by Buying Time</title>
		<link>https://esimoney.com/be-happier-by-buying-time/</link>
					<comments>https://esimoney.com/be-happier-by-buying-time/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[ESI]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 09:00:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Books]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Save]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://esimoney.com/?p=8737</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Today we continue sharing from the book Happy Money: The Science of Happier Spending. We&#8217;ve already covered principles 1 and 2 of this book. In case you missed them, you can catch up by reading Be Happier by Buying Experiences Over Things and Be Happier by Making Your Spending a Treat Friday. In this post [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://esimoney.com/be-happier-by-buying-time/">Be Happier by Buying Time</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://esimoney.com">ESI Money</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://esimoney.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Man-removing-snow-from-roof-new.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-8738" src="https://esimoney.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Man-removing-snow-from-roof-new-300x198.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="198" srcset="https://esimoney.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Man-removing-snow-from-roof-new-300x198.jpg 300w, https://esimoney.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Man-removing-snow-from-roof-new.jpg 750w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a>Today we continue sharing from the book <a href="https://amzn.to/3xYv1ft">Happy Money: The Science of Happier Spending</a>.</p>
<p>We&#8217;ve already covered principles 1 and 2 of this book. In case you missed them, you can catch up by reading <a href="https://esimoney.com/be-happier-by-buying-experiences-over-things/">Be Happier by Buying Experiences Over Things</a> and <a href="https://esimoney.com/be-happier-by-making-your-spending-a-treat/">Be Happier by Making Your Spending a Treat Friday</a>.</p>
<p>In this post I&#8217;ll highlight principle 3 as well as give you my thoughts on it.</p>
<p>Let&#8217;s get started&#8230;</p>
<h4><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>Principle 3: Buy Time</strong></span></h4>
<p>Here&#8217;s how the book describes principle 3:</p>
<p style="padding-left: 40px;"><em><strong>By permitting us to outsource our most dreaded tasks, from scrubbing toilets to cleaning gutters, money can transform the way we spend our time, freeing us to pursue our passions. Yet wealthier individuals do not spend their time in happier ways on a daily basis; thus they fail to use their money to buy themselves happier time.</strong></em></p>
<p style="padding-left: 40px;"><em><strong>We&#8217;ll show the wisdom of asking yourself a quick question before buying: How will this purchase change the way I use my time? When people focus on their time rather than their money, they act like scientists of happiness, choosing activities that promote their well-being.</strong></em></p>
<p>Ugh. This was another area where I was pretty far behind when I was younger (my wife was even worse).</p>
<p>Thankfully we have gotten better as we&#8217;ve gotten older.</p>
<p>For my part, there are things I should have outsourced&#8230;the main ones being mowing the lawn and shoveling snow.</p>
<p>I eventually did outsource the mowing once my son turned ten (hahahaha), but living in Michigan for 14 years and shoveling over 100 inches of snow a year was a BIG waste of time. Why didn&#8217;t I hire a service to manage it? (I did have snowblowers, but they don&#8217;t do everything &#8212; anyone ever used a roof rake?)</p>
<p>For my wife, it was getting the best price. I can remember one time when we had hamburgers but we didn&#8217;t have ketchup because the store she had been to that day didn&#8217;t have it on sale. The store across town did have it on sale for something like 20 cents less, so she would get it there in 3-4 days. The problem was we had burgers NOW and no ketchup NOW just to save 20 cents. Not to mention, was 20 cents worth the 30 minutes and expense (like gas) to go to the other store? No, it was not.</p>
<p>Nowadays we often buy something that we know is cheaper elsewhere simply because we are able to make the purchase now and save ourselves time.</p>
<p>Another example of this was with our real estate rental units. I used a management service even though it cut into profits because I didn&#8217;t want to spend my limited time and energy to manage people&#8217;s issues (and where you have people, you have issues). But even that got to be too much (managing the manager), so I <a href="https://esimoney.com/why-and-how-i-sold-my-last-rental-property/">sold our properties</a> and put the money into <a href="https://esimoney.com/how-to-get-started-investing-in-real-estate-syndications-part-1/">real estate syndications</a>.</p>
<p>These days, I like things even simpler and if that means spending money to save time, I&#8217;m all for it. One example: we belong to an expensive gym that is close enough we can walk to it (1,200 steps from my front door to theirs). Another example: I often pay for a dedicated pickleball court to play versus get one free at the local park because the paid version is two-hours of straight play while the park version is two-hours of play over a 3-4 hour time period (you take turns at the park, which is always crowded).</p>
<h4><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>Retirement Helps with the Time/Money Balance</strong></span></h4>
<p>The book elaborates on principle 3 with the following:</p>
<p style="padding-left: 40px;"><em><strong>Whether driving for an hour to get gas that is five cents cheaper, waiting in endless lines to get a free sample of the latest PowerBar, or taking an entire afternoon to abscond with a cheap umbrella, we too often sacrifice our free time just to save a little money.</strong></em></p>
<p style="padding-left: 40px;"><em><strong>Many of us wish we had more free time to do more of what we love. For Liz, it&#8217;s working out; for Mike, playing guitar. In theory, it&#8217;s possible to use money to buy more of this kind of time. But research suggests that people with more money do not spend their time in more enjoyable ways on a day-to-day basis. Wealthier individuals tend to spend more of their time on activities associated with relatively high levels of tension and stress, such as shopping, working, and commuting.</strong></em></p>
<p>This is a great thing about retirement&#8230;it takes two of the dreaded three out of the equation.</p>
<p>I don&#8217;t commute, at least not to work. I do have a couple different pickleball courts I drive to, but that&#8217;s different. And it&#8217;s certainly not rush hour when I do. <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/14.0.0/72x72/1f609.png" alt="😉" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></p>
<p>I don&#8217;t &#8220;work&#8221; in the traditional sense, i.e. working for &#8220;the man&#8221; to make money at a job that is &#8220;fine&#8221; or &#8220;ok&#8221; because I have to. Now I work from the comfort of my home office, sipping a coffee, listening to Christmas music, having my cat nearby looking out the window, and writing and discussing a topic I love (personal finance). It&#8217;s pretty cool!</p>
<p>And as for shopping, we make that as easy as possible. Step 1 of that is having things delivered at home. Amazon and Costco are frequent deliveries here. Step 2 is that we often pick some items up at the grocery store on our daily walks as it&#8217;s on our 5,000-step circuit. And Step 3 is shopping at Costco every two weeks or so, in the middle of the day when no one is there, to stock up on a ton of stuff.</p>
<p>Again, I&#8217;ll say this is very much in contrast to how we did things in our 30&#8217;s and 40&#8217;s so I don&#8217;t want to come off like I&#8217;ve had this all together for decades &#8212; because I haven&#8217;t. It&#8217;s only recently with retirement as well as discussions on the Millionaire Money Mentors forums that I&#8217;ve gotten much better at trading money for time.</p>
<h4><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>Three Areas to Outsource</strong></span></h4>
<p>The book goes on:</p>
<p style="padding-left: 40px;"><em><strong>Buying time isn&#8217;t always easy. Taking this principle seriously means rethinking many everyday expenditures and transforms decisions about money into decisions about time a kind of mental backflip that can make people more inclined toward happy choices.</strong></em></p>
<p style="padding-left: 40px;"><em><strong>People who feel they have plenty of free time are more likely to exercise, do volunteer work, and participate in other activities that are linked to increased happiness. Although money can be used to buy &#8220;free time,&#8221; in part by outsourcing the demands of daily life such as cooking, cleaning, and even grocery shopping, wealthier individuals report elevated levels of time pressure.</strong></em></p>
<p>Let&#8217;s pause for a moment and talk about &#8220;cooking, cleaning, and even grocery shopping.&#8221;</p>
<p>We&#8217;ve done all of these and continue to do them even to this day, so let me comment on them one by one:</p>
<ul>
<li>Cooking. What are our choices here &#8212; either hiring a chef or eating out more? Both of these come with their own downsides that I&#8217;m not sure are better than just doing it ourselves. But we do something each week that does make cooking faster/better. Our kids come over for a cookout every Saturday and I almost always make way more than we need (steak, ribs, etc.) Then we have these foods again for 1-3 &#8220;new&#8221; meals within the next week. Same thing happens when we buy a &#8220;Costco chicken&#8221; &#8212; it&#8217;s always two meals. Cooking then is made very simple and fast.</li>
<li>Cleaning. I hate it. My wife (who does most of it) hates it. For YEARS I have been trying to get her to hire a housekeeper, even every other week. But she will have none of it because &#8220;no one cleans my house like I do.&#8221; Okaaaaaaay&#8230;</li>
<li>Grocery shopping. We try to minimize trips on one hand which makes this less of a chore. And, as I said above, our closest grocery store is within walking distance, so if we need something we will walk to the store and get it. This way we get in a few thousand steps or so plus get what we need. It&#8217;s a win-win!</li>
</ul>
<h4><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>Big Time Suck 1: Commuting</strong></span></h4>
<p>The book now moves on to the big three time sucks &#8212; and no, they aren&#8217;t cooking, cleaning, and grocery shopping.</p>
<p>They are much, much worse:</p>
<p style="padding-left: 40px;"><em><strong>And while the Buy Time principle can be applied idiosyncratically, most people would benefit from using their money to change the amount of time they spend on three key activities: commuting, watching television, and hanging out with friends and family.</strong></em></p>
<p>As you might imagine, the book is in favor of less commuting and TV and more time with friends and family.</p>
<p>We&#8217;ll get to each of these in due course. Let&#8217;s begin with commuting:</p>
<p style="padding-left: 40px;"><em><strong>According to the U.S. Census Bureau, Americans spend more than two weeks of the year commuting, more than their typical annual vacation time. Transportation experts have suggested that developed countries are hitting &#8220;peak car,&#8221; rubbing up against the maximum amount of time that human beings are willing to spend traveling on a daily basis.</strong></em></p>
<p style="padding-left: 40px;"><em><strong>Taking a job that requires an hour-long commute each way has a negative effect on happiness similar in magnitude to not having a job at all. Although accepting a longer commute can provide access to both nicer houses and better jobs, people with longer commutes are no more satisfied with their homes, and they are less satisfied with their jobs. And individuals with long commutes are much less satisfied with their spare time. Commuting, it seems, undermines time affluence.</strong></em></p>
<p style="padding-left: 40px;"><em><strong>Most people consider the well-being of their families&#8211;not just their own&#8211;in deciding whether to take a job. Accepting a longer commute might make for a happier family. But there&#8217;s no evidence that this is the case. If anything, people report somewhat lower happiness when their spouse has a longer commute.</strong></em></p>
<p style="padding-left: 40px;"><em><strong>To offset the happiness costs of going from no commute to a twenty-two-minute commute, the average person would need to see their income rise by over a third&#8211;and that&#8217;s just to break even. Rather than bugging the boss for a raise, you could get a similar happiness boost, research shows, by moving closer to work.</strong></em></p>
<p style="padding-left: 40px;"><em><strong>When it comes to commuting, as with many things, length isn&#8217;t all that matters. David Mogolov took a new job with an even longer commute, but the location of the company makes it possible for him to take the train to work, rather than drive. &#8220;On the train,&#8221; David explains, &#8220;I don&#8217;t have to make decisions, or interact with other angry people before we&#8217;re properly caffeinated. I get where I&#8217;m going, I&#8217;m not angry, and I don&#8217;t endanger myself. Or others.&#8221;</strong></em></p>
<p style="padding-left: 40px;"><em><strong>In a 2011 study comparing almost three hundred commuters traveling from their homes in northern New Jersey to their jobs in New York City, people felt significantly less stressed and disgruntled after taking the train than after driving. Train travel was less effortful and more predictable than driving. &#8220;I&#8217;m not sure anyone would describe the commuter rail as a Zen garden, but David does arrive home considerably less stressed,&#8221; Lisa says.</strong></em></p>
<p>Many thoughts on this one:</p>
<ul>
<li>Thankfully, I never had a long commute. The longest I ever traveled to work was 30 minutes one way but most of my career the trip was 20 minutes or less. It wasn&#8217;t a freebie by any stretch as 40 minutes a day still adds up over the years, but one hour each way would have been a killer. I got to see how terrible that was when we had bad snows and it took me an hour or two to fight my way into work. Who could do that every day for years and still live a fruitful life? Not me.</li>
<li>I had a friend who lived in New Jersey and worked in New York City. It took him 2-3 hours (depending on traffic) EACH WAY, EVERY DAY to get to and from work. And he did this for YEARS. I about broke down crying when he told me what he had done for all that time. He left the house at 5 am and got home around 8 pm every night &#8212; if he was lucky. Ugh.</li>
<li>I&#8217;m wondering if commuting was a big issue in the Great Resignation. My guess is that it was. People saw they could be as effective by working at home so they simply said &#8220;no, thank you&#8221; to the nasty commute. They then got jobs where it wasn&#8217;t needed. As stated above, people would be willing to trade a lot of money to eliminate their commute.</li>
<li>This is one of the best things about being retired &#8212; no daily commute &#8212; especially during bad weather. Every time we have a snow storm in Colorado Springs (or used to have them &#8212; now we&#8217;re in Florida for most of them. Hahahaha), I think about my poor friends fighting their way into work and/or back home again &#8212; worried about whether they can make it or not, their safety, etc. I simply walk over to the gym (yes, I walk in cold weather &#8212; I lived in Michigan for 14 years so it&#8217;s no big deal). And no one is at the gym because they are all stressed out going into work. Of course this was pre-2022 as our trips to The Villages makes this a thing of the past (except for those once-a-year two-day snowstorms in May).</li>
<li>My last employer was THE WORST about snow days. We would have a big snow storm and our boss (the owner) would still want people to come in. At first, our policy was that &#8220;when company X closed, we closed.&#8221; Except Company X actually cared for their employees so they would close when it was bad, something our boss didn&#8217;t want to do. So we abandoned that and basically went to an &#8220;everyone comes in no matter what unless the world is ending&#8221; policy. This forced people to risk a lot by driving in bad weather and be stressed just to get into work when the rest of the city was shut down. And this was usually only for a few hours as the office then closed early. Of course the boss &#8220;worked from home&#8221; so he didn&#8217;t have to deal with the weather. It was one of the main reasons I decided to retire &#8212; I couldn&#8217;t take this crap.</li>
<li>&#8220;Americans spend more than two weeks of the year commuting more than their typical annual vacation time.&#8221; That is simply a brutal, brutal statement. Unfortunately it&#8217;s not (by far) the biggest time suck (as we&#8217;ll see in a moment) though it is the most hated (as we&#8217;ll also see in a moment).</li>
<li>&#8220;Taking a job that requires an hour-long commute each way has a negative effect on happiness similar in magnitude to not having a job at all.&#8221; I know how stressed people are when they are unemployed. So being as bad as not having a job is a terrible thing.</li>
<li>I always lived in cities where you had to drive to work (for the most part) as the public transportation wasn&#8217;t great. There were a couple exceptions to this. First, when I was an intern in D.C., I took the metro which was not bad at all. It&#8217;s true that riding is better than driving as you eliminate much of the stress and you can actually get something done while doing it. Second, I took the bus on and off for a year when we lived in Pittsburgh. Let me just say that taking a big city bus was not my cup of tea in any way, shape, or form. It was early in my career and I did it to save money, but it made my life worse. The exception was on snow days when someone else could worry about the driving.</li>
<li>There is a way to redeem some of the commuting time &#8212; make it fun and/or educational with audio books. Listening to a great novel or a new book on business can be a great way to take unproductive time and turn it into something worthwhile. I did this for most of my career and learned a lot in the car (probably got my second, third, and fourth MBAs via audio) as well as had great times with the likes of Harry Potter and The Hunger Games &#8212; things I would never have read otherwise. Plus I probably got the equivalent of a another master&#8217;s degree or two in personal finance and writing based on the books and podcasts I listened to.</li>
</ul>
<h4><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>Big Time Suck 2: Television</strong></span></h4>
<p>Let&#8217;s move on to the next time killer &#8212; television:</p>
<p style="padding-left: 40px;"><em><strong>In addition to spending two weeks per year commuting, the average American spends the equivalent of two months per year watching television. In many countries, people spend almost as much time watching TV as they do working.</strong></em></p>
<p style="padding-left: 40px;"><em><strong>If our choices reveal what we like best, TV must be pretty much the most super-terrific thing ever. And yet, study after study shows that people experience less pleasure while watching TV than while engaging in more active forms of leisure, including walking the dog. More than any other activity, television appears responsible for the failure of the U-index to budge over the past four decades.</strong></em></p>
<p style="padding-left: 40px;"><em><strong>Although people today spend less time doing unpleasant activities such as household chores, television has sucked up much of this newly available time while providing little emotional payoff. In a sample of over one hundred thousand people from thirty-two European countries, individuals who watched more than thirty minutes of television per day were less satisfied with their lives than people who watched TV for under half an hour.</strong></em></p>
<p style="padding-left: 40px;"><em><strong>Watching the occasional TV show may be genuinely enjoyable, but devoting two months of the year to the tube is too much.</strong></em></p>
<p style="padding-left: 40px;"><em><strong>To be fair, watching TV has one big advantage: it&#8217;s cheap. Replacing some of the time you spend watching TV with other, more engaging activities (like going out for dinner with friends or taking an art class) will cost you money. But it is money well spent.</strong></em></p>
<p>Ok, let&#8217;s get to my thoughts:</p>
<ul>
<li>TWO MONTHS PER YEAR? As Bugs Bunny said once, &#8220;<a href="https://youtu.be/Cy1SyXuWBt8">Oooooooooooooo, I&#8217;m dying</a>!!!!&#8221; But seriously&#8230;that&#8217;s brutal. I was a big TV watcher at times, but never as big as most were (as we&#8217;ll see) &#8212; and certainly not as much time as I spent working. How is that even possible?</li>
<li>My dad is a great example of the TV versus active lifestyle difference. In Iowa after my mom died, he watched 8-10 hours of TV a day and was pretty miserable (he would say it and we could hear it in his voice). Then, down in <a href="https://esimoney.com/review-of-the-villages-florida-part-1/">The Villages</a>, we could see him come to life with all the activities. So when he bought a place there we were thrilled! And after a month or so of getting his new life set up (which is when I&#8217;m writing this), he&#8217;s now back at the activity smorgasbord at The Villages and loving it!</li>
<li>Thirty minutes a day seems to be the breaking point where TV goes from adding value to life to sucking value from life. Which is way lower than what people actually do&#8230;</li>
<li>Most people watch more than 30 minutes of TV a day. <a href="https://www.statista.com/statistics/186833/average-television-use-per-person-in-the-us-since-2002/">The AVERAGE time spent watching TV per American per day is about three hours</a>. Ugh. This is a KILLER!</li>
<li>The worst part of watching TV three hours a day IMO is wasted time. Here&#8217;s a quote I found that I&#8217;ve shared previously: &#8220;If you’re broke you should cancel Netflix. Not to save $15 per month but to save 40 hours per month.&#8221; The top excuse I get from people who don&#8217;t have a side hustle is &#8220;I don&#8217;t have the time for it.&#8221; Well, I&#8217;ve found your time. Cut your TV viewing down to &#8220;only&#8221; 1.5 hours per day and spend the other 1.5 hours on a <a href="https://esimoney.com/side-hustle-business-can-get-financial-independence-10-years/">side hustle that can get you to financial independence in 10 years or less</a>.</li>
<li>Even in retirement when I have &#8220;all the time in the world&#8221;, the most I watch TV is a couple hours a day &#8212; and some of that is while I&#8217;m eating dinner (so at least I&#8217;m accomplishing something else). I&#8217;m not sure what I&#8217;d do if I had to watch three hours a day every day (and remember, this is average &#8212; which means many people are OVER 3 hours a day). Is there really enough good stuff on TV anyway to suck up that much time?</li>
</ul>
<p>Ok, I&#8217;m beating a dead horse here so let&#8217;s move on&#8230;</p>
<h4><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>Big Time Suck 3: Time with Family and Friends</strong></span></h4>
<p>Now we go in the opposite direction &#8212; something you should do more of &#8212; spend time with family and friends:</p>
<p style="padding-left: 40px;"><em><strong>If you awaken happiness researchers in the middle of the night and ask them to tell you (quick! what matters most for human well-being), you&#8217;ll get the same response: get the hell out of my house. After they calm down, though, we&#8217;re pretty sure they&#8217;ll agree on the answer: social relationships. People experience the most positive moods of the day while spending time with family and friends.</strong></em></p>
<p style="padding-left: 40px;"><em><strong>In the past decade, the emotional benefits of parenthood have been much maligned, with media outlets from New York magazine to Slate featuring headlines such as WHY PARENTS HATE PARENTING and PARENTS ARE JUNKIES. Yet a recent study with a nationally representative sample of Americans revealed that playing with children produced more positive feelings than almost any other common daily activity.</strong></em></p>
<p style="padding-left: 40px;"><em><strong>There&#8217;s a time trap that buying stuff springs on us. Our purchases can undermine the amount of time we have available to spend with friends and family, by compelling us to work more to afford the purchases we make to try to improve our family life. In a 2003 poll, over 80 percent of Americans–with and without children&#8211;reported wishing they had more time to spend with their families.</strong></em></p>
<p style="padding-left: 40px;"><em><strong>A substantial minority said they would be willing to accept a pay cut to have more time with family. But many respondents indicated that they couldn&#8217;t afford to do so, often citing the high costs of housing as the barrier. Yet, as we saw earlier, people who spend more money on housing reap few benefits in terms of happiness. Working long hours to earn more money to provide your children with fancier homes and shinier toys may represent a bad happiness trade-off- especially when doing so comes at the cost of actually spending time playing with them.</strong></em></p>
<p>Thoughts on this:</p>
<ul>
<li>Not much new news on this. I think we all know that spending time with family ranks high on the happiness scale for most people.</li>
<li>This is one reason we live where we do &#8212; our kids are here. And we see them at least a couple times a week. If they moved somewhere else, we&#8217;d probably cash out of Colorado and move to Florida (where my dad lives). But that&#8217;s a story for a different day.</li>
<li>We also spend almost every vacation with our kids. It makes the vacation even better. Our last one was when we all went to The Villages together (and worked in Disney, trips to the beach, etc.) They are planning on coming down next winter as well. And by the time this posts, my daughter and I will have attended the Financial Blogger Conference in Orlando for a small, mini-vacation. Of course we live in Colorado, so the summers here are like one big vacation. <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/14.0.0/72x72/1f609.png" alt="😉" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></li>
<li>I&#8217;m just going to leave this here as I&#8217;m sure someone needs to read it again: &#8220;Working long hours to earn more money to provide your children with fancier homes and shinier toys may represent a bad happiness trade-off- especially when doing so comes at the cost of actually spending time playing with them.&#8221;</li>
</ul>
<p>Let&#8217;s move on&#8230;</p>
<h4><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>A Couple Key Thoughts</strong></span></h4>
<p>Before we leave this subject (and chapter of the book), I want to share a couple quotes which were too good to let pass by.</p>
<p>Here&#8217;s the first:</p>
<p style="padding-left: 40px;"><em><strong>Aside from commuting, working is the only activity that produces unpleasant moods more than 25 percent of the time among both French and American women.</strong></em></p>
<p>Hahaha. Commuting is hated activity #1 and working is #2. Notice how they are both associated with holding a job? No wonder people are generally unhappy with their jobs and want to retire asap.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s probably much better now given that working from home has become more common, but it&#8217;s still a huge issue for those back in the office who have to fight their way through traffic every day just to get to work.</p>
<p>Here&#8217;s the second &#8212; which is a fitting quote to end this subject on IMO:</p>
<p style="padding-left: 40px;"><em><strong>Transforming decisions about money into decisions about time has a surprising benefit. Thinking about time rather than money spurs people to engage in activities that promote well-being, like socializing and volunteering.</strong></em></p>
<p>That&#8217;s what I&#8217;ll leave you with today &#8212; the challenge to think a bit more about time and how you&#8217;re spending it and a bit less about money.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s something I wish I had done earlier in life because I think it would have made me even happier along the journey to financial freedom.</p>
<p>To read the next post in this series and see what millionaires think about this topic, check out <a href="https://esimoney.com/millionaire-thoughts-on-buying-time/">Millionaire Thoughts on Buying Time</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://esimoney.com/be-happier-by-buying-time/">Be Happier by Buying Time</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://esimoney.com">ESI Money</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://esimoney.com/be-happier-by-buying-time/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>5</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
