<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<rdf:RDF
 xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
 xmlns="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/"
 xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
 xmlns:taxo="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/taxonomy/"
 xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
 xmlns:syn="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
 xmlns:admin="http://webns.net/mvcb/"
>

<channel rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/">
<title>cond-mat.dis-nn updates on arXiv.org</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">Condensed Matter -- Disordered Systems and Neural Networks (cond-mat.dis-nn) updates on the arXiv.org e-print archive</description>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:date>2022-11-03T20:30:00-05:00</dc:date>
<dc:publisher>help@arxiv.org</dc:publisher>
<dc:subject>Condensed Matter -- Disordered Systems and Neural Networks</dc:subject>
<syn:updateBase>1901-01-01T00:00+00:00</syn:updateBase>
<syn:updateFrequency>1</syn:updateFrequency>
<syn:updatePeriod>daily</syn:updatePeriod>
<items>
 <rdf:Seq>
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01490" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01552" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01741" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01802" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01870" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01904" />
 </rdf:Seq>
</items>
<image rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif" />
</channel>
<image rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif">
<title>arXiv.org</title>
<url>http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif</url>
<link>http://arxiv.org/</link>
</image>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01490">
<title>Deep Learning Hamiltonians from Disordered Image Data in Quantum Materials. (arXiv:2211.01490v1 [cond-mat.str-el])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01490</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The capabilities of image probe experiments are rapidly expanding, providing
new information about quantum materials on unprecedented length and time
scales. Many such materials feature inhomogeneous electronic properties with
intricate pattern formation on the observable surface. This rich spatial
structure contains information about interactions, dimensionality, and disorder
-- a spatial encoding of the Hamiltonian driving the pattern formation. Image
recognition techniques from machine learning are an excellent tool for
interpreting information encoded in the spatial relationships in such images.
Here, we develop a deep learning framework for using the rich information
available in these spatial correlations in order to discover the underlying
Hamiltonian driving the patterns. We first vet the method on a known case,
scanning near-field optical microscopy on a thin film of VO2. We then apply our
trained convolutional neural network architecture to new optical microscope
images of a different VO2 film as it goes through the metal-insulator
transition. We find that a two-dimensional Hamiltonian with both interactions
and random field disorder is required to explain the intricate, fractal
intertwining of metal and insulator domains during the transition. This
detailed knowledge about the underlying Hamiltonian paves the way to using the
model to control the pattern formation via, e.g., tailored hysteresis
protocols. We also introduce a distribution-based confidence measure on the
results of a multi-label classifier, which does not rely on adversarial
training. In addition, we propose a new machine learning based criterion for
diagnosing a physical system&apos;s proximity to criticality.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Basak_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;S. Basak&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Banguero_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;M. Alzate Banguero&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Burzawa_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;L. Burzawa&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Simmons_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;F. Simmons&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Salev_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;P. Salev&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Aigouy_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;L. Aigouy&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Qazilbash_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;M. M. Qazilbash&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Schuller_I/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;I. K. Schuller&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Basov_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;D. N. Basov&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Zimmers_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;A. Zimmers&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Carlson_E/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;E. W. Carlson&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01552">
<title>Mobility edges and critical regions in periodically kicked incommensurate optical Raman lattice. (arXiv:2211.01552v1 [cond-mat.dis-nn])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01552</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Conventionally the mobility edge (ME) separating extended states from
localized ones is a central concept in understanding Anderson localization
transition. The critical state, being delocalized and non-ergodic, is a third
type of fundamental state that is different from both the extended and
localized states. Here we study the localization phenomena in a one dimensional
periodically kicked quasiperiodic optical Raman lattice by using fractal
dimensions. We show a rich phase diagram including the pure extended, critical
and localized phases in the high frequency regime, the MEs separating the
critical regions from the extended (localized) regions, and the coexisting
phase of extended, critical and localized regions with increasing the kicked
period. We also find the fragility of phase boundaries, which are more
susceptible to the dynamical kick, and the phenomenon of the reentrant
localization transition. Finally, we demonstrate how the studied model can be
realized based on current cold atom experiments and how to detect the rich
physics by the expansion dynamics. Our results provide insight into studying
and detecting the novel critical phases, MEs, coexisting quantum phases, and
some other physics phenomena in the periodically kicked systems.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Wang_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yucheng Wang&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01741">
<title>On the relation between disorder and homogeneity in an amorphous metal. (arXiv:2211.01741v1 [cond-mat.dis-nn])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01741</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Disorder and homogeneity are two concepts that refer to spatial variation of
the system potential. In condensed-matter systems disorder is typically divided
into two types; those with local parameters varying from site to site (diagonal
disorder) and those characterized by random transfer-integral values
(off-diagonal disorder). Amorphous systems in particular exhibit off-diagonal
disorder due to random positions of their constituents. In real systems
diagonal and off-diagonal disorder may be interconnected. The formal depiction
of disorder as local deviations from a common value focuses attention on the
short-range components of the potential-landscape. However, long range
potential fluctuation are quite common in real systems. In this work we seek to
find a correlation between disorder and homogeneity using amorphous
indium-oxide films with different carrier-concentrations and with different
degree of disorder. Thermal treatment is used as a means of fine tuning the
system disorder. In this process the resistance of the sample decreases while
its amorphous structure and chemical composition is preserved. The reduced
resistivity affects the Ioffe-Regel parameter that is taken as a relative
measure of disorder in a given sample. The homogeneity of the system was
monitored using inelastic light-scattering. This is based on collecting the
Raman signal from micron-size spots across the sample. The statistics of these
low-energy data are compared with the sample disorder independently estimated
from transport measurements. The analysis establishes that heterogeneity and
disorder are correlated.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Ovadyahu_Z/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Z. Ovadyahu&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01802">
<title>From the replica trick to the replica symmetry breaking technique. (arXiv:2211.01802v1 [physics.hist-ph])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01802</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Among the various remarkable contributions of Giorgio Parisi to physics, his
formulation of the replica symmetry breaking solution for the
Sherrington-Kirkpatrick model stands out. In this article, different historical
sources are used to reconstruct the scientific and professional contexts of
this prodigious advance.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Charbonneau_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Patrick Charbonneau&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01870">
<title>Many-body quantum boomerang effect. (arXiv:2211.01870v1 [cond-mat.dis-nn])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01870</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We study numerically the impact of many-body interactions on the quantum
boomerang effect. We consider various cases: weakly interacting bosons, the
Tonks-Girardeau gas, and strongly interacting bosons (which may be mapped onto
weakly interacting fermions). Numerical simulations are performed using the
time-evolving block decimation algorithm, a quasi-exact method based on matrix
product states. In the case of weakly interacting bosons, we find a partial
destruction of the quantum boomerang effect, in agreement with the earlier
mean-field study [Phys. Rev. A \textbf{102}, 013303 (2020)]. For the
Tonks-Girardeau gas, we show the presence of the full quantum boomerang effect.
For strongly interacting bosons, we observe a partial boomerang effect. We show
that the destruction of the quantum boomerang effect is universal and does not
depend on the details of the interaction between particles.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Janarek_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jakub Janarek&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Zakrzewski_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jakub Zakrzewski&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Delande_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Dominique Delande&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01904">
<title>Dimensionality reduction of local structure in glassy binary mixtures. (arXiv:2211.01904v1 [cond-mat.stat-mech])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01904</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We consider unsupervised learning methods for characterizing the disordered
microscopic structure of supercooled liquids and glasses. Specifically, we
perform dimensionality reduction of smooth structural descriptors that describe
radial and bond-orientational correlations, and assess the ability of the
method to grasp the essential structural features of glassy binary mixtures. In
several cases, a few collective variables account for the bulk of the
structural fluctuations within the first coordination shell and also display a
clear connection with the fluctuations of particle mobility. Fine-grained
descriptors that characterize the radial dependence of bond-orientational order
better capture the structural fluctuations relevant for particle mobility, but
are also more difficult to parametrize and to interpret. We also find that
principal component analysis of bond-orientational order parameters provides
identical results to neural network autoencoders, while having the advantage of
being easily interpretable. Overall, our results indicate that glassy binary
mixtures have a broad spectrum of structural features. In the temperature range
we investigate, some mixtures display well-defined locally favored structures,
which are reflected in bimodal distributions of the structural variables
identified by dimensionality reduction.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Coslovich_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Daniele Coslovich&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Jack_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Robert L. Jack&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Paret_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Joris Paret&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
</rdf:RDF>