<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:foaf="http://xmlns.com/foaf/0.1/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#" xmlns:rdfs="http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#" xmlns:schema="http://schema.org/" xmlns:sioc="http://rdfs.org/sioc/ns#" xmlns:sioct="http://rdfs.org/sioc/types#" xmlns:skos="http://www.w3.org/2004/02/skos/core#" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#" version="2.0" xml:base="https://www.sec.gov/">
  <channel>
    <title>Press Releases</title>
    <link>https://www.sec.gov/</link>
    <description>Official announcements highlighting recent actions taken by the SEC and other newsworthy information.</description>
    <language>en</language>
    
    
<item>
  <title>SEC Charges Creator of Global Crypto Ponzi Scheme and Three US Promoters in Connection with $295 Million Fraud</title>
  <link>https://www.sec.gov/news/press-release/2022-201</link>
  <description>The Securities and Exchange Commission today announced charges against Douver Torres Braga, Joff Paradise, Keleionalani Akana Taylor, and Jonathan Tetreault for their roles in Trade Coin Club, a fraudulent crypto Ponzi scheme that raised more than 82,000…</description>
  <pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2022 12:50:00 -0400</pubDate>
    <dc:creator> </dc:creator>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">4a53976e-1cf8-4410-a49c-06f40bca35ef</guid>
    </item>

<item>
  <title>SEC Charges Halal Capital Founder with Multimillion Dollar Fraudulent Scheme That Targeted Muslim Community</title>
  <link>https://www.sec.gov/news/press-release/2022-200</link>
  <description>The Securities and Exchange Commission today charged Jebara Igbara, the founder of Halal Capital LLC, in connection with a more than $8 million scheme that targeted investors from the New York metropolitan area’s Muslim community.

According to the SEC’s…</description>
  <pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2022 15:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
    <dc:creator> </dc:creator>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">bf06257f-eeaa-4de5-8420-eb1d791bbb91</guid>
    </item>

<item>
  <title>SEC Proposes Enhancements to Open-End Fund Liquidity Framework</title>
  <link>https://www.sec.gov/news/press-release/2022-199</link>
  <description>The Securities and Exchange Commission today voted to propose amendments to better prepare open-end funds for stressed conditions and to mitigate dilution of shareholders’ interests. The rule and form amendments would enhance how funds manage their…</description>
  <pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2022 12:05:00 -0400</pubDate>
    <dc:creator> </dc:creator>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">02e20c1b-fc8d-4b2d-8731-311096a40834</guid>
    </item>

<item>
  <title>SEC Adopts Rules to Enhance Proxy Voting Disclosure by Registered Investment Funds and Require Disclosure of “Say-on-Pay” Votes for Institutional Investment Managers</title>
  <link>https://www.sec.gov/news/press-release/2022-198</link>
  <description>The Securities and Exchange Commission today adopted amendments to Form N-PX to enhance the information mutual funds, exchange-traded funds, and certain other registered funds report about their proxy votes. The amendments will make these funds’ proxy…</description>
  <pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2022 11:15:00 -0400</pubDate>
    <dc:creator> </dc:creator>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">708cc046-c416-4093-ba63-1dfd46eae276</guid>
    </item>

<item>
  <title>SEC Charges Incarcerated Felon and Five Friends in $2 Million Fraud Scheme</title>
  <link>https://www.sec.gov/news/press-release/2022-197</link>
  <description>The Securities and Exchange Commission today charged six individuals, including a federal inmate, for conducting a freeriding scheme that defrauded multiple broker-dealers.

The SEC’s complaint alleges that from May 2019 to early January 2021, Syed Arham…</description>
  <pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2022 11:01:00 -0400</pubDate>
    <dc:creator> </dc:creator>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">0354a49b-59e1-4514-95d8-35abb59edc56</guid>
    </item>

<item>
  <title>SEC Awards More Than $10 Million to Whistleblower</title>
  <link>https://www.sec.gov/news/press-release/2022-196</link>
  <description>The Securities and Exchange Commission today announced an award of more than $10 million to a whistleblower who provided information and assistance that significantly contributed to a successful SEC enforcement action. 

The whistleblower provided…</description>
  <pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2022 10:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
    <dc:creator> </dc:creator>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">4bc26e9b-8f75-42cd-a2af-7e17e42fb4c9</guid>
    </item>

<item>
  <title>SEC Updates List of Firms Using Inaccurate Information to Solicit Investors</title>
  <link>https://www.sec.gov/news/press-release/2022-195</link>
  <description>The Securities and Exchange Commission today announced that it updated its list of unregistered entities that use misleading information to solicit primarily non-U.S. investors, adding 35 soliciting entities, four impersonators of genuine firms, and four…</description>
  <pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2022 08:51:56 -0400</pubDate>
    <dc:creator> </dc:creator>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">bc873420-b4f2-4756-b3ec-209280450968</guid>
    </item>

<item>
  <title>SEC Proposes New Oversight Requirements for Certain Services Outsourced by Investment Advisers</title>
  <link>https://www.sec.gov/news/press-release/2022-194</link>
  <description>The Securities and Exchange Commission today proposed a new rule and rule amendments under the Investment Advisers Act of 1940 to prohibit registered investment advisers from outsourcing certain services and functions without conducting due diligence and…</description>
  <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 12:50:00 -0400</pubDate>
    <dc:creator> </dc:creator>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">d096cc17-e5e0-4273-ae52-909d6a68b650</guid>
    </item>

<item>
  <title>SEC Adopts Amendments to Modernize Fund Shareholder Reports and Promote Transparent Fee- and Expense-Related Information in Fund Advertisements</title>
  <link>https://www.sec.gov/news/press-release/2022-193</link>
  <description>The Securities and Exchange Commission voted today to adopt rule and form amendments to require mutual funds and exchange-traded funds to transmit concise and visually engaging shareholder reports and to promote transparent and balanced presentations of…</description>
  <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 11:55:00 -0400</pubDate>
    <dc:creator> </dc:creator>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">c9090139-032a-48e7-8ce3-663e1067f549</guid>
    </item>

<item>
  <title>SEC Adopts Compensation Recovery Listing Standards and Disclosure Rules</title>
  <link>https://www.sec.gov/news/press-release/2022-192</link>
  <description>The Securities and Exchange Commission today adopted rules to require securities exchanges to adopt listing standards that require issuers to develop and implement a policy providing for the recovery of erroneously awarded incentive-based compensation…</description>
  <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 11:20:00 -0400</pubDate>
    <dc:creator> </dc:creator>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">67b07af0-317f-4033-9301-cc0eedd18484</guid>
    </item>

<item>
  <title>SEC Charges Canadian Cannabis Company and Former Senior Executive with Accounting Fraud</title>
  <link>https://www.sec.gov/news/press-release/2022-191</link>
  <description>The Securities and Exchange Commission today charged Cronos Group Inc., a Nasdaq-listed cannabis company based in Toronto, for improperly accounting for millions of dollars of revenue and for other accounting misconduct in multiple reporting periods. The…</description>
  <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 16:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
    <dc:creator> </dc:creator>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">228cf144-1f4f-4536-a92b-cabc7595631e</guid>
    </item>

<item>
  <title>SEC Names Jason J. Burt as Regional Director of the Denver Office</title>
  <link>https://www.sec.gov/news/press-release/2022-190</link>
  <description>The Securities and Exchange Commission today announced that Jason J. Burt has been named Regional Director of the Denver Office, where he has served as Acting Co-Director since July.

“I am pleased that Jason will head the Denver Regional Office after an…</description>
  <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 11:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
    <dc:creator> </dc:creator>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">b532bc0e-bdaf-46a5-98f2-5accf7966bde</guid>
    </item>

<item>
  <title>SEC Charges Mattel with Financial Misstatements and Former PwC Audit Partner with Improper Professional Conduct</title>
  <link>https://www.sec.gov/news/press-release/2022-189</link>
  <description>The Securities and Exchange Commission today announced that California-based Mattel Inc. has agreed to pay $3.5 million to settle charges relating to misstatements in its third and fourth quarter 2017 financial statements. Separately, the SEC is…</description>
  <pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2022 16:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
    <dc:creator> </dc:creator>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">bfae1535-6a77-4697-962a-11029947de29</guid>
    </item>

<item>
  <title>New Jersey Real Estate Development Firm and Four Executives Charged With $600 Million Ponzi-like Fraud</title>
  <link>https://www.sec.gov/news/press-release/2022-188</link>
  <description>The Securities and Exchange Commission today charged New Jersey-based National Realty Investment Advisors LLC (NRIA) and four of its former executives with running a Ponzi-like scheme that raised approximately $600 million from about 2,000 investors.…</description>
  <pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2022 10:11:23 -0400</pubDate>
    <dc:creator> </dc:creator>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">c5a9f7c4-5b26-466f-8225-e2f1f0f01a31</guid>
    </item>

<item>
  <title>SEC Adopts Rule Amendments to Modernize How Broker-Dealers Preserve Electronic Records and Enhance the Electronic Recordkeeping Requirements for Security-Based Swap Entities</title>
  <link>https://www.sec.gov/news/press-release/2022-187</link>
  <description>The Securities and Exchange Commission today voted to adopt amendments to the electronic recordkeeping, prompt production of records, and third-party recordkeeping service requirements applicable to broker-dealers, security-based swap dealers (SBSDs),…</description>
  <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2022 11:15:00 -0400</pubDate>
    <dc:creator> </dc:creator>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">5c51b921-48c5-47a6-9c10-fd14ee024d9b</guid>
    </item>

<item>
  <title>SEC Reopens Comment Periods for Several Rulemaking Releases Due to Technological Error in Receiving Certain Comments</title>
  <link>https://www.sec.gov/news/press-release/2022-186</link>
  <description>The Securities and Exchange Commission today reopened the public comment periods for 11 Commission rulemaking releases and one request for comment due to a technological error that resulted in a number of public comments submitted through the Commission’…</description>
  <pubDate>Fri, 07 Oct 2022 14:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
    <dc:creator> </dc:creator>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">cf8a7170-5864-4275-8870-df0180968f3f</guid>
    </item>

<item>
  <title>Small Business Advisory Committee to Host Meeting to Discuss Entrepreneurship Hubs and the IPO Market</title>
  <link>https://www.sec.gov/news/press-release/2022-185</link>
  <description>The Securities and Exchange Commission’s Small Business Capital Formation Advisory Committee today released the agenda for its meeting on Thursday, Oct. 13, which will address entrepreneurship hubs and recent trends in taking a company public.…</description>
  <pubDate>Thu, 06 Oct 2022 17:00:31 -0400</pubDate>
    <dc:creator> </dc:creator>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">8d59720f-4d6e-4e30-a395-530f1af018c9</guid>
    </item>

<item>
  <title>SEC to Spotlight Financial Planning and Resilience during World Investor Week 2022</title>
  <link>https://www.sec.gov/news/press-release/2022-184</link>
  <description>The Securities and Exchange Commission today announced that it will highlight the importance of long-term planning and investor resilience during World Investor Week (WIW) 2022, which takes place October 3-9. Planning for life’s unexpected…</description>
  <pubDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2022 10:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
    <dc:creator> </dc:creator>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">8704bef6-4952-47d2-9c5d-88b781ffbb31</guid>
    </item>

<item>
  <title>SEC Charges Kim Kardashian for Unlawfully Touting Crypto Security</title>
  <link>https://www.sec.gov/news/press-release/2022-183</link>
  <description>The Securities and Exchange Commission today announced charges against Kim Kardashian for touting on social media a crypto asset security offered and sold by EthereumMax without disclosing the payment she received for the promotion. Kardashian agreed to…</description>
  <pubDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2022 07:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
    <dc:creator> </dc:creator>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">8c74d22d-f131-464c-9cb7-119d8dc8c2e3</guid>
    </item>

<item>
  <title>SEC Charges Eight in Scheme to Fraudulently Promote Securities Offerings</title>
  <link>https://www.sec.gov/news/press-release/2022-182</link>
  <description>The Securities and Exchange Commission today announced charges against six individuals and two companies for their involvement in a fraudulent scheme to promote the securities of issuers that were conducting (or purporting to conduct) offerings pursuant…</description>
  <pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2022 14:49:35 -0400</pubDate>
    <dc:creator> </dc:creator>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">1dd61120-f7f9-4474-aac0-bcdfaf1c28ec</guid>
    </item>

<item>
  <title>SEC Charges Two Canadian Software Engineers with Insider Trading</title>
  <link>https://www.sec.gov/news/press-release/2022-181</link>
  <description>The Securities and Exchange Commission today announced insider trading charges against two Canadian software engineers who made $1.6 million by trading ahead of non-public, market-moving financial information.

According to the SEC’s complaint, from at…</description>
  <pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2022 09:02:39 -0400</pubDate>
    <dc:creator> </dc:creator>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">cb3db0ca-a59e-4a2f-8f38-68e4bd5daead</guid>
    </item>

<item>
  <title>SEC Charges Audit Firm RSM and Three Senior-Level Employees with Failure to Properly Conduct Client Audits</title>
  <link>https://www.sec.gov/news/press-release/2022-180</link>
  <description>The Securities and Exchange Commission today charged audit firm RSM US LLP and three senior-level employees with improper professional conduct for failing to properly audit Revolution Lighting Technologies Inc.’s (“Revolution”) financial statements over…</description>
  <pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2022 08:36:02 -0400</pubDate>
    <dc:creator> </dc:creator>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">95058fc6-0edb-43ac-b6f8-d961f4fb988b</guid>
    </item>

<item>
  <title>Barclays Agrees to a $361 Million Settlement to Resolve SEC Charges Relating to Over-Issuances of Securities</title>
  <link>https://www.sec.gov/news/press-release/2022-179</link>
  <description>The Securities and Exchange Commission today charged Barclays PLC and Barclays Bank PLC (BBPLC) in connection with the unregistered offer and sale of an unprecedented amount of securities due to a failure to implement any internal control to track such…</description>
  <pubDate>Thu, 29 Sep 2022 14:36:39 -0400</pubDate>
    <dc:creator> </dc:creator>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">5dc68529-0409-4af0-a5a1-12358e9029d2</guid>
    </item>

<item>
  <title>SEC Charges Man for Defrauding Investors out of Millions of Dollars by Posing as Hedge Fund Billionaire</title>
  <link>https://www.sec.gov/news/press-release/2022-178</link>
  <description>The Securities and Exchange Commission today charged Justin Costello for using a false persona, as a Harvard-educated military veteran and hedge fund billionaire, to defraud investors out of millions of dollars. The SEC also charged Costello and David…</description>
  <pubDate>Thu, 29 Sep 2022 11:38:21 -0400</pubDate>
    <dc:creator> </dc:creator>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">6717bfb3-988b-4d1a-9dbe-8a5f5e6d9946</guid>
    </item>

<item>
  <title>SEC Monitoring Impact of Hurricanes Ian and Fiona on Capital Markets</title>
  <link>https://www.sec.gov/news/press-release/2022-177</link>
  <description>SEC Chair Gary Gensler has directed the staff to carefully monitor developments as a result of Hurricanes Ian and Fiona. While the safety of local residents is the highest priority, the SEC invites inquiries from any person with obligations under the…</description>
  <pubDate>Thu, 29 Sep 2022 11:27:51 -0400</pubDate>
    <dc:creator> </dc:creator>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">91ca9835-ef57-4bde-9797-e1d2230770a5</guid>
    </item>

  </channel>
</rss>
