<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns:yt="http://www.youtube.com/xml/schemas/2015" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
 <link rel="self" href="http://www.youtube.com/feeds/videos.xml?channel_id=UCBH5VZE_Y4F3CMcPIzPEB5A"/>
 <id>yt:channel:UCBH5VZE_Y4F3CMcPIzPEB5A</id>
 <yt:channelId>UCBH5VZE_Y4F3CMcPIzPEB5A</yt:channelId>
 <title>Real Vision Finance</title>
 <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCBH5VZE_Y4F3CMcPIzPEB5A"/>
 <author>
  <name>Real Vision Finance</name>
  <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCBH5VZE_Y4F3CMcPIzPEB5A</uri>
 </author>
 <published>2015-01-22T22:18:27+00:00</published>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:SqmXabBNrMM</id>
  <yt:videoId>SqmXabBNrMM</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCBH5VZE_Y4F3CMcPIzPEB5A</yt:channelId>
  <title>Is High-Yield Spreads a Reliable Economic Indicator?</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=SqmXabBNrMM"/>
  <author>
   <name>Real Vision Finance</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCBH5VZE_Y4F3CMcPIzPEB5A</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-11-04T21:55:10+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-11-04T22:53:58+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Is High-Yield Spreads a Reliable Economic Indicator?</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/SqmXabBNrMM?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i4.ytimg.com/vi/SqmXabBNrMM/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>Which economic indicator is the most reliable for confirming we’re in a crisis? According to Verdad Capital founder and portfolio manager Dan Rasmussen, it’s high-yield spreads. 

Identifying the key relationships across the globe isn’t hard. Formulating an approach that surfaces alpha when spreads spike is where it gets difficult. 

Per Rasmussen, the best way to act in such environments is through small-value equities. Rasmussen explains why it makes sense and how to time the trade in a captivating episode of The Next Big Trade.

👉 Do you want even more content like this? And to see this video before we release it here? Become a member of Real Vision -- get started here: https://rvtv.io/membership 

Thanks for watching Real Vision Finance!

#smallcapstocks  #tradingstrategy  #stockstowatch 

About Real Vision™:
Real Vision™ is where you can gain an understanding of the complex world of finance, business, and the global economy with real in-depth analysis from real experts. 

🔥 𝗚𝗘𝗧 𝟳 𝗗𝗔𝗬𝗦 of Real Vision’s insights for only $𝟭 (seriously!) https://rvtv.io/RVfor1dollar
 
🚀 Want to become a better investor or start from scratch?  👉 Join the Real Investing course now! https://rvtv.io/RVAcademy 

Connect with Real Vision™ Online:
RV Crypto: http://rvtv.io/RealVisionCrypto
Twitter: https://rvtv.io/twitter
Instagram: https://rvtv.io/instagram
Facebook: https://rvtv.io/facebook
Linkedin: https://rvtv.io/linkedin​​​​​​​​​​​​​​​​

#Macro #finance #macroeconomy #markets #financialmarkets #bonds #stocks #oil #gas #commodities #equities #gold

Disclaimer:
This is pretty obvious, but we should probably say it anyway so there is no confusion…The material in REAL VISION GROUP video programs and publications {collectively referred to as “RV RELEASES”} is provided for informational purposes only and is NOT investment advice. The information in RV RELEASES has been obtained from sources believed to be reliable, but Real Vision and its contributors, distributors and/or publisher, licensors, and their respective employees, contractors, agents, suppliers, and vendors { collectively, “Affiliated Parties”} make no representation or warranty as to the accuracy, timeliness or completeness of the content in RV RELEASES. Any data included in RV RELEASES are illustrative only and not for investment purposes. Any opinion or recommendation expressed in RV RELEASES is subject to change without notice. RV Releases do not recommend, explicitly nor implicitly, nor suggest or recommend any investment strategy. Real Vision Group and its Affiliated Parties disclaim all liability for any loss that may arise (whether direct indirect, consequential, incidental, punitive, or otherwise) from any use of the information in RV RELEASES. Real Vision Group and its Affiliated Parties do not have regard for any individual, group of individuals, or entity’s specific investment objectives, financial situation, or circumstance. RV RELEASES do not express any opinion on the future value of any security, currency, or other investment instruments. You should seek expert financial and other advice regarding the appropriateness of the material discussed or recommended in RV RELEASES and should note that investment values may fall, you may receive less back than originally invested and past performances are not necessarily reflective of future performances. Well, that was pretty intense! We hope you got all of that – now stop reading the small print and go and enjoy Real Vision.</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="113" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="2920"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:VJ372iHsExM</id>
  <yt:videoId>VJ372iHsExM</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCBH5VZE_Y4F3CMcPIzPEB5A</yt:channelId>
  <title>The Labor Market Is Still Intact</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VJ372iHsExM"/>
  <author>
   <name>Real Vision Finance</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCBH5VZE_Y4F3CMcPIzPEB5A</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-11-04T20:42:19+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-11-05T11:30:58+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>The Labor Market Is Still Intact</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/VJ372iHsExM?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i3.ytimg.com/vi/VJ372iHsExM/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>U.S. stocks opened higher but drifted lower through the trading day, digesting an October nonfarm payrolls report that showed a still-strong labor market in the aftermath of Federal Reserve Chair Jerome Powell’s forceful rejection of “pivot” talk earlier this week and ahead of crucial midterm elections next week. Traders are now pricing in a 5.25% peak policy rate via the June 2023 swap contract. “I don’t think this changes anything in the Fed’s calculation,” noted Peter Boockvar in response to the jobs report, “but I do believe the trend in the unemployment rate is now going higher and will be 4%-plus soon.” Boockvar, the chief investment officer of Bleakly Advisory Group, joins Andreas Steno Larsen for today’s Daily Briefing to talk about  when the Fed might finally change, or at least pause, its current policy path and the implications of Tuesday’s voting in the U.S. We also hear from Alexander Stahel about why U.S. immunity to the global energy crisis is an illusion. Watch the full conversation featuring Alexander Stahel and Andreas Steno Larsen here: https://rvtv.io/3WzREk0. And we want to hear from you too – please share your questions, comments, and suggestions!

Editor’s Note: Our live chat feature will be unavailable for four to six weeks as we upgrade our video player technology. We apologize for the temporary loss of function. But we assure you the upgrade will more than justify the wait. In the meantime, we will be monitoring the comments section. So, in addition to conversing with your fellow community members, please share your questions there.



Thanks for watching The Daily Briefing. Sign up here with your email address to have every episode delivered to your inbox Monday-Friday: http://rvtv.io/DailyBriefEmail

About Real Vision™:
Real Vision™ is where you can gain an understanding of the complex world of finance, business and the global economy with real in-depth analysis from real experts. 

Connect with Real Vision™ Online:
Twitter: https://rvtv.io/twitter
Instagram: https://rvtv.io/instagram
Facebook: https://rvtv.io/facebook
Linkedin: https://rvtv.io/linkedin 

The Labor Market Is Still Intact

Disclaimer:
This is pretty obvious, but we should probably say it anyway so that there is absolutely no confusion…The material in REAL VISION GROUP video programs and publications {collectively referred to as “RV RELEASES”} is provided for informational purposes only and is NOT investment advice. The information in RV RELEASES has been obtained from sources believed to be reliable, but Real Vision and its contributors, distributors and/or publisher, licensors, and their respective employees, contractors , agents, suppliers and vendors { collectively, “Affiliated Parties”} make no representation or warranty as to the accuracy, timeliness or completeness of the content in RV RELEASES. Any data included in RV RELEASES are illustrative only and not for investment purposes. Any opinion or recommendation expressed in RV RELEASES is subject to change without notice. RV Releases do not recommend, explicitly nor implicitly, nor suggest or recommend any investment strategy. Real Vision Group and its Affiliated Parties disclaim all liability for any loss that may arise (whether direct indirect, consequential, incidental, punitive or otherwise) from any use of the information in RV RELEASES. Real Vision Group and its Affiliated Parties do not have regard to any individual’s, group of individuals’ or entity’s specific investment objectives, financial situation or circumstance. RV RELEASES do not express any opinion on the future value of any security, currency or other investment instrument. You should seek expert financial and other advice regarding the appropriateness of the material discussed or recommended in RV RELEASES and should note that investment values may fall, you may receive less back than originally invested and past performances is not necessarily reflective of future performances. Well that was pretty intense! We hope you got all of that – now stop reading the small print and go and enjoy Real Vision.</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="358" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="8880"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:fyZiYNmWDVc</id>
  <yt:videoId>fyZiYNmWDVc</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCBH5VZE_Y4F3CMcPIzPEB5A</yt:channelId>
  <title>What'll Break First? The Real Economy or the Markets?</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fyZiYNmWDVc"/>
  <author>
   <name>Real Vision Finance</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCBH5VZE_Y4F3CMcPIzPEB5A</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-11-04T16:12:07+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-11-04T16:24:40+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>What'll Break First? The Real Economy or the Markets?</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/fyZiYNmWDVc?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i3.ytimg.com/vi/fyZiYNmWDVc/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>The Federal Reserve is dealing with a complex set of fundamental factors – including elements that could make inflation “quite persistent” – as it tries to re-establish price stability in a U.S. economy perhaps forever altered by the COVID-19 pandemic and its aftermath. 

That’s according to Dennis Lockhart, who served 10 years as the president of the Federal Reserve Bank of Atlanta. 

Lockhart joins Harry Melandri of MI2 Partners for a comprehensive discussion of inflation and unemployment, the economic outlook and financial stability, the global energy market and geopolitics, and how the trajectory of Fed policy will impact all of the foregoing. 

“The future,” Lockhart notes, “is not only problematic but also biased toward either inflation or biased toward weak growth.” Given the alternatives, though, he’s still inclined to go long the United States. Recorded on October 24, 2022.

👉 Do you want even more content like this? And to see this video before we release it here? Become a member of Real Vision -- get started here: https://rvtv.io/membership 

Thanks for watching Real Vision Finance!

#financialmarkets  #fed  #federalreserve 

About Real Vision™:
Real Vision™ is where you can gain an understanding of the complex world of finance, business, and the global economy with real in-depth analysis from real experts. 

🔥 𝗚𝗘𝗧 𝟳 𝗗𝗔𝗬𝗦 of Real Vision’s insights for only $𝟭 (seriously!) https://rvtv.io/RVfor1dollar
 
🚀 Want to become a better investor or start from scratch?  👉 Join the Real Investing course now! https://rvtv.io/RVAcademy 

Connect with Real Vision™ Online:
RV Crypto: http://rvtv.io/RealVisionCrypto
Twitter: https://rvtv.io/twitter
Instagram: https://rvtv.io/instagram
Facebook: https://rvtv.io/facebook
Linkedin: https://rvtv.io/linkedin​​​​​​​​​​​​​​​​

#Macro #finance #macroeconomy #markets #financialmarkets #bonds #stocks #oil #gas #commodities #equities #gold

Disclaimer:
This is pretty obvious, but we should probably say it anyway so there is no confusion…The material in REAL VISION GROUP video programs and publications {collectively referred to as “RV RELEASES”} is provided for informational purposes only and is NOT investment advice. The information in RV RELEASES has been obtained from sources believed to be reliable, but Real Vision and its contributors, distributors and/or publisher, licensors, and their respective employees, contractors, agents, suppliers, and vendors { collectively, “Affiliated Parties”} make no representation or warranty as to the accuracy, timeliness or completeness of the content in RV RELEASES. Any data included in RV RELEASES are illustrative only and not for investment purposes. Any opinion or recommendation expressed in RV RELEASES is subject to change without notice. RV Releases do not recommend, explicitly nor implicitly, nor suggest or recommend any investment strategy. Real Vision Group and its Affiliated Parties disclaim all liability for any loss that may arise (whether direct indirect, consequential, incidental, punitive, or otherwise) from any use of the information in RV RELEASES. Real Vision Group and its Affiliated Parties do not have regard for any individual, group of individuals, or entity’s specific investment objectives, financial situation, or circumstance. RV RELEASES do not express any opinion on the future value of any security, currency, or other investment instruments. You should seek expert financial and other advice regarding the appropriateness of the material discussed or recommended in RV RELEASES and should note that investment values may fall, you may receive less back than originally invested and past performances are not necessarily reflective of future performances. Well, that was pretty intense! We hope you got all of that – now stop reading the small print and go and enjoy Real Vision.</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="129" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="2971"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:Tv0hyhD6x-s</id>
  <yt:videoId>Tv0hyhD6x-s</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCBH5VZE_Y4F3CMcPIzPEB5A</yt:channelId>
  <title>Europe is Safe for the Next 3 Months (PART 2)</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Tv0hyhD6x-s"/>
  <author>
   <name>Real Vision Finance</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCBH5VZE_Y4F3CMcPIzPEB5A</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-11-04T15:59:05+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-11-05T08:19:43+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Europe is Safe for the Next 3 Months (PART 2)</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/Tv0hyhD6x-s?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i1.ytimg.com/vi/Tv0hyhD6x-s/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description></media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="32" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="1174"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:7pwuCe0gLh8</id>
  <yt:videoId>7pwuCe0gLh8</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCBH5VZE_Y4F3CMcPIzPEB5A</yt:channelId>
  <title>Europe is Safe for the Next 3 Months (PART 1)</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7pwuCe0gLh8"/>
  <author>
   <name>Real Vision Finance</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCBH5VZE_Y4F3CMcPIzPEB5A</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-11-04T15:36:16+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-11-05T07:59:35+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Europe is Safe for the Next 3 Months (PART 1)</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/7pwuCe0gLh8?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i4.ytimg.com/vi/7pwuCe0gLh8/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description></media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="31" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="1259"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:2qlNnTYnaRI</id>
  <yt:videoId>2qlNnTYnaRI</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCBH5VZE_Y4F3CMcPIzPEB5A</yt:channelId>
  <title>AI Can Play Chess &amp; StarCraft 🤯</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2qlNnTYnaRI"/>
  <author>
   <name>Real Vision Finance</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCBH5VZE_Y4F3CMcPIzPEB5A</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-11-04T03:49:20+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-11-04T15:59:43+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>AI Can Play Chess &amp; StarCraft 🤯</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/2qlNnTYnaRI?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i3.ytimg.com/vi/2qlNnTYnaRI/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description></media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="50" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="1781"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:r16GkxG61Kw</id>
  <yt:videoId>r16GkxG61Kw</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCBH5VZE_Y4F3CMcPIzPEB5A</yt:channelId>
  <title>Easy Money Has Hard Consequences</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=r16GkxG61Kw"/>
  <author>
   <name>Real Vision Finance</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCBH5VZE_Y4F3CMcPIzPEB5A</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-11-03T20:36:33+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-11-04T18:53:58+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Easy Money Has Hard Consequences</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/r16GkxG61Kw?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i3.ytimg.com/vi/r16GkxG61Kw/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>Yesterday, the Federal Reserve announced a fourth consecutive 75-basis-point rate hike, and Chair Jerome Powell aggressively pushed back against any thoughts of a “pivot.” Today, the Bank of England followed the Fed with its own 75-basis-point rate hike, even as it warned what would be the country’s longest recession ever has already started and will continue through 2023 and into 2024. The dollar is strengthening against the pound again, though the prospect of a “soft landing” stateside seems to be growing more and more remote. “The world is confronted with many new threats,” writes Vincent Deluard in his most recent newsletter, “and the next twelve months feel abnormally uncertain.” Deluard, the Director of Global Macro Strategy at Stone X, joins Ash Bennington for today’s Daily Briefing to talk about recent moves by central banks, his 2023 outlook, and his “Holy Trinity” picks for this market. We also hear from Andreas Steno Larsen about the natural gas supply situation in Europe this heating season and, more importantly, next winter. Watch the complete conversation between Andreas Steno Larsen and Maggie Lake here: https://rvtv.io/3DCRpvQ. And we want to hear from you too – please share your questions, comments, and suggestions!

#money #monetarypolicy #financialmarkets 

Editor’s Note: Our live chat feature will be unavailable for four to six weeks as we upgrade our video player technology. We apologize for the temporary loss of function. But we assure you the upgrade will more than justify the wait. In the meantime, we will be monitoring the comments section. So, in addition to conversing with your fellow community members, please share your questions there.



Thanks for watching The Daily Briefing. Sign up here with your email address to have every episode delivered to your inbox Monday-Friday: http://rvtv.io/DailyBriefEmail

About Real Vision™:
Real Vision™ is where you can gain an understanding of the complex world of finance, business and the global economy with real in-depth analysis from real experts. 

Connect with Real Vision™ Online:
Twitter: https://rvtv.io/twitter
Instagram: https://rvtv.io/instagram
Facebook: https://rvtv.io/facebook
Linkedin: https://rvtv.io/linkedin 

Easy Money Has Hard Consequences

Disclaimer:
This is pretty obvious, but we should probably say it anyway so that there is absolutely no confusion…The material in REAL VISION GROUP video programs and publications {collectively referred to as “RV RELEASES”} is provided for informational purposes only and is NOT investment advice. The information in RV RELEASES has been obtained from sources believed to be reliable, but Real Vision and its contributors, distributors and/or publisher, licensors, and their respective employees, contractors , agents, suppliers and vendors { collectively, “Affiliated Parties”} make no representation or warranty as to the accuracy, timeliness or completeness of the content in RV RELEASES. Any data included in RV RELEASES are illustrative only and not for investment purposes. Any opinion or recommendation expressed in RV RELEASES is subject to change without notice. RV Releases do not recommend, explicitly nor implicitly, nor suggest or recommend any investment strategy. Real Vision Group and its Affiliated Parties disclaim all liability for any loss that may arise (whether direct indirect, consequential, incidental, punitive or otherwise) from any use of the information in RV RELEASES. Real Vision Group and its Affiliated Parties do not have regard to any individual’s, group of individuals’ or entity’s specific investment objectives, financial situation or circumstance. RV RELEASES do not express any opinion on the future value of any security, currency or other investment instrument. You should seek expert financial and other advice regarding the appropriateness of the material discussed or recommended in RV RELEASES and should note that investment values may fall, you may receive less back than originally invested and past performances is not necessarily reflective of future performances. Well that was pretty intense! We hope you got all of that – now stop reading the small print and go and enjoy Real Vision.</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="316" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="9782"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:v4ioIwAM-So</id>
  <yt:videoId>v4ioIwAM-So</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCBH5VZE_Y4F3CMcPIzPEB5A</yt:channelId>
  <title>The Chinese Government Likes Its Surveillance Policies</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=v4ioIwAM-So"/>
  <author>
   <name>Real Vision Finance</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCBH5VZE_Y4F3CMcPIzPEB5A</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-11-03T19:44:31+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-11-04T08:27:55+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>The Chinese Government Likes Its Surveillance Policies</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/v4ioIwAM-So?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i3.ytimg.com/vi/v4ioIwAM-So/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description></media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="48" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="1749"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:bjkSI2lxyyI</id>
  <yt:videoId>bjkSI2lxyyI</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCBH5VZE_Y4F3CMcPIzPEB5A</yt:channelId>
  <title>Can China Continue to Grow Without Foreign Investment?</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=bjkSI2lxyyI"/>
  <author>
   <name>Real Vision Finance</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCBH5VZE_Y4F3CMcPIzPEB5A</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-11-03T17:11:10+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-11-04T08:47:03+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Can China Continue to Grow Without Foreign Investment?</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/bjkSI2lxyyI?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i3.ytimg.com/vi/bjkSI2lxyyI/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>A crackdown on its tech companies, the collapse of its real estate sector, and enforcement of “zero Covid” have combined to profoundly impact China’s economy, with outside observers emboldened to question the durability of the current regime. 

The 20th National Congress of the Chinese Communist Party was once seen to be a celebration for Xi Jinping, highlighted by his coronation for an unprecedented third term as president. As ever, though, as economist George Magnus recently tweeted, “The Congress represents continuity and consolidation.” 

Magnus, a research associate at the China Centre at Oxford University, joins Maggie Lake for a conversation about the Middle Kingdom and its direction, noting that the economy and the private sector serve the interests of the CCP above all else. Recorded on September 28, 2022.

👉 Do you want even more content like this? And to see this video before we release it here? Become a member of Real Vision -- get started here: https://rvtv.io/membership 

TIMESTAMPS:
1 Overview of the Current State of China 01:15
2 Will Xi Jinping Ease Zero Covid Policies After He Secures Another Term? 06:38
3 What Should We Expect to Come Out of the 20th Party Congress? 0:10:56
4 China's Strategy to Recalibrate Their Industrial Sector 0:24:07
5 Digging Deeper into China's Data 0:38:39
6 Can China Continue to Grow Without Foreign Investment? 0:46:46
7 Will China Make a Move on Taiwan? 0:53:46
8 What Do Investors Risk Getting Wrong About China? 0:56:16
9 The Takeaways 01:04:02

Thanks for watching Real Vision Finance!

#China #chinaeconomy  #chinanews 

About Real Vision™:
Real Vision™ is where you can gain an understanding of the complex world of finance, business, and the global economy with real in-depth analysis from real experts. 

🔥 𝗚𝗘𝗧 𝟳 𝗗𝗔𝗬𝗦 of Real Vision’s insights for only $𝟭 (seriously!) https://rvtv.io/RVfor1dollar
 
🚀 Want to become a better investor or start from scratch?  👉 Join the Real Investing course now! https://rvtv.io/RVAcademy 

Connect with Real Vision™ Online:
RV Crypto: http://rvtv.io/RealVisionCrypto
Twitter: https://rvtv.io/twitter
Instagram: https://rvtv.io/instagram
Facebook: https://rvtv.io/facebook
Linkedin: https://rvtv.io/linkedin​​​​​​​​​​​​​​​​

#Macro #finance #macroeconomy #markets #financialmarkets #bonds #stocks #oil #gas #commodities #equities #gold

Disclaimer:
This is pretty obvious, but we should probably say it anyway so there is no confusion…The material in REAL VISION GROUP video programs and publications {collectively referred to as “RV RELEASES”} is provided for informational purposes only and is NOT investment advice. The information in RV RELEASES has been obtained from sources believed to be reliable, but Real Vision and its contributors, distributors and/or publisher, licensors, and their respective employees, contractors, agents, suppliers, and vendors { collectively, “Affiliated Parties”} make no representation or warranty as to the accuracy, timeliness or completeness of the content in RV RELEASES. Any data included in RV RELEASES are illustrative only and not for investment purposes. Any opinion or recommendation expressed in RV RELEASES is subject to change without notice. RV Releases do not recommend, explicitly nor implicitly, nor suggest or recommend any investment strategy. Real Vision Group and its Affiliated Parties disclaim all liability for any loss that may arise (whether direct indirect, consequential, incidental, punitive, or otherwise) from any use of the information in RV RELEASES. Real Vision Group and its Affiliated Parties do not have regard for any individual, group of individuals, or entity’s specific investment objectives, financial situation, or circumstance. RV RELEASES do not express any opinion on the future value of any security, currency, or other investment instruments. You should seek expert financial and other advice regarding the appropriateness of the material discussed or recommended in RV RELEASES and should note that investment values may fall, you may receive less back than originally invested and past performances are not necessarily reflective of future performances. Well, that was pretty intense! We hope you got all of that – now stop reading the small print and go and enjoy Real Vision.</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="235" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="8696"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:FzVXmhRTRzk</id>
  <yt:videoId>FzVXmhRTRzk</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCBH5VZE_Y4F3CMcPIzPEB5A</yt:channelId>
  <title>Can Unemployment Help the Fed? | The Big Conversation | Refinitiv</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=FzVXmhRTRzk"/>
  <author>
   <name>Real Vision Finance</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCBH5VZE_Y4F3CMcPIzPEB5A</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-11-03T13:00:17+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-11-03T13:00:17+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Can Unemployment Help the Fed? | The Big Conversation | Refinitiv</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/FzVXmhRTRzk?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i3.ytimg.com/vi/FzVXmhRTRzk/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>This week Real Vision’s Roger Hirst uses best in class data to look at the outlook for employment and its implications for both recessions and equity markets. Equity markets usually make a major bottom during recessions and recessions go hand in hand with higher unemployment. Currently, unemployment is close to record lows. That could change, but will it be swift enough to allow the Fed to reverse course on rates? In the Chatter, Real Vision’s Roger Hirst talks to Kelvin Tay, Regional Chief Investment Officer at UBS Wealth Management in Singapore, about the likelihood of a recession in the US.

See the full series and access expert data-driven insights and news from Refinitiv: https://refini.tv/2Tq42o2  


Subscribe now for more videos like this one: https://rvtv.io/2OW3mqu   

Become a member of Real Vision -- get started for 7 days for only $1: https://rvtv.io/membership  

 

About Refinitiv: For new insights on artificial intelligence (AI), digitalization, big data, risk management, compliance, fighting financial crime and the future of trading and investing, visit our insights hub - http://refinitiv.com/perspectives. Refinitiv is one of the world’s largest providers of financial markets data and infrastructure, serving over 40,000 institutions in approximately 190 countries. It provides leading data and insights, trading platforms, and open data and technology platforms that connect a thriving global financial markets community – driving performance in trading, investment, wealth management, regulatory compliance, market data management, enterprise risk and fighting financial crime. https://www.refinitiv.com We invite you to join Refinitiv's social media communities: http://linkedin.com/company/refinitiv http://twitter.com/refinitiv http://www.instagram.com/refinitiv http://www.facebook.com/refinitiv   

 

 

About Real Vision™:  

Real Vision™ is the destination for the world’s most successful investors to share their thoughts about what’s happening in today’s markets. (Think of it like TED Talks for Finance.). Understand the complex world of finance, business and the global economy with real in-depth analysis from real experts. 

 

Disclaimer:  

The content and information (“Content”) in the video programs (“Video Programs”) is provided for informational purposes only and not investment advice. You should not construe any such Content, information or other material as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other professional advice nor does any such information constitute a comprehensive or complete statement of the matters discussed. None of the Content constitutes a solicitation, recommendation, endorsement, or offer by Refinitiv or any third party service provider to buy or sell any securities or other financial instruments in this or in in any other jurisdiction in which such solicitation or offer would be unlawful under the securities laws of such jurisdiction. All Content is information of a general nature, is illustrative only and does not address the circumstances of any particular individual or entity. Refinitiv is not a fiduciary by virtue of any person’s use of or access to the Video Programs or Content. You alone assume the sole responsibility of evaluating the merits and risks associated with the use of any information or other Content in the Video Programs before making any decisions based on such information or other Content. In exchange for accessing and viewing the Video Programs and Content, you agree not to hold Refinitiv, its affiliates or any third party service provider liable for any possible claim for damages arising from any decision you make based on information or other Content made available to you through the Video Programs. The Content and information in the Video Programs has been obtained from sources believed to be reliable, but Refinitiv makes no representation or warranty as to the accuracy, timeliness or completeness of the Content. Any opinion or recommendation expressed in the Video Programs is subject to change without notice. Refinitiv does not recommend, explicitly nor implicitly, nor suggest or recommend any investment strategy. Refinitiv disclaims all liability for any loss that may arise (whether direct, indirect, consequential, incidental, punitive or otherwise) from any use of the information in Video Programs. Refinitiv does not have regard to any individual’s, group of individuals’ or entity’s specific investment objectives, financial situation or circumstances. Refinitiv does not express any opinion on the future value of any security, currency or other investment instrument. You should seek expert financial and other advice regarding the appropriateness of the material discussed or recommended in the Video Programs and should note that investment values may fall, you may receive back less than originally invested and past performance is not necessarily reflective of future performance.</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="178" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="3361"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:cXIM0r_u60o</id>
  <yt:videoId>cXIM0r_u60o</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCBH5VZE_Y4F3CMcPIzPEB5A</yt:channelId>
  <title>What Kind of a Hike Was It?</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=cXIM0r_u60o"/>
  <author>
   <name>Real Vision Finance</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCBH5VZE_Y4F3CMcPIzPEB5A</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-11-02T20:34:31+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-11-04T18:08:17+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>What Kind of a Hike Was It?</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/cXIM0r_u60o?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i4.ytimg.com/vi/cXIM0r_u60o/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>The Federal Open Market Committee added a couple of interesting phrases to its policy statement announcing a fourth consecutive 75-basis-point interest-rate increase, noting that it will take into account time lags and the impact of cumulative tightening during future meetings. In his post-FOMC-meeting press conference, Fed Chair Jerome Powell emphasized the centrality of price stability to sustained economic growth, acknowledged data indicating the U.S. economy is slowing, and noted the continuing strength of a still “out-of-balance” labor market. George Goncalves, the head of U.S. macro strategy at MUFG, joins Maggie Lake for today’s Daily Briefing to talk about whether the FOMC statement was neutral, hawkish, or dovish, overall liquidity heading into the end of the year, and why we need to keep an eye on overseas markets. We also hear from Jesse Felder, the author of The Felder Report, about why we face a period of elevated inflation and what investments will work in such an environment. Watch the full interview between Jesse Felder and Maggie Lake here: https://www.realvision.com/shows/make-or-break-inflation/videos/there-wont-be-a-crash-but-drpj?tab=details. And we want to hear from you too – please share your questions, comments, and suggestions!

Editor’s Note: Our live chat feature will be unavailable for four to six weeks as we upgrade our video player technology. We apologize for the temporary loss of function. But we assure you the upgrade will more than justify the wait. In the meantime, we will be monitoring the comments section. So, in addition to conversing with your fellow community members, please share your questions there.



Thanks for watching The Daily Briefing. Sign up here with your email address to have every episode delivered to your inbox Monday-Friday: http://rvtv.io/DailyBriefEmail

About Real Vision™:
Real Vision™ is where you can gain an understanding of the complex world of finance, business and the global economy with real in-depth analysis from real experts. 

Connect with Real Vision™ Online:
Twitter: https://rvtv.io/twitter
Instagram: https://rvtv.io/instagram
Facebook: https://rvtv.io/facebook
Linkedin: https://rvtv.io/linkedin 

What Kind of a Hike Was It?

Disclaimer:
This is pretty obvious, but we should probably say it anyway so that there is absolutely no confusion…The material in REAL VISION GROUP video programs and publications {collectively referred to as “RV RELEASES”} is provided for informational purposes only and is NOT investment advice. The information in RV RELEASES has been obtained from sources believed to be reliable, but Real Vision and its contributors, distributors and/or publisher, licensors, and their respective employees, contractors , agents, suppliers and vendors { collectively, “Affiliated Parties”} make no representation or warranty as to the accuracy, timeliness or completeness of the content in RV RELEASES. Any data included in RV RELEASES are illustrative only and not for investment purposes. Any opinion or recommendation expressed in RV RELEASES is subject to change without notice. RV Releases do not recommend, explicitly nor implicitly, nor suggest or recommend any investment strategy. Real Vision Group and its Affiliated Parties disclaim all liability for any loss that may arise (whether direct indirect, consequential, incidental, punitive or otherwise) from any use of the information in RV RELEASES. Real Vision Group and its Affiliated Parties do not have regard to any individual’s, group of individuals’ or entity’s specific investment objectives, financial situation or circumstance. RV RELEASES do not express any opinion on the future value of any security, currency or other investment instrument. You should seek expert financial and other advice regarding the appropriateness of the material discussed or recommended in RV RELEASES and should note that investment values may fall, you may receive less back than originally invested and past performances is not necessarily reflective of future performances. Well that was pretty intense! We hope you got all of that – now stop reading the small print and go and enjoy Real Vision.</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="695" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="19373"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:9D72usi69d8</id>
  <yt:videoId>9D72usi69d8</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCBH5VZE_Y4F3CMcPIzPEB5A</yt:channelId>
  <title>What Will China Do?</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9D72usi69d8"/>
  <author>
   <name>Real Vision Finance</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCBH5VZE_Y4F3CMcPIzPEB5A</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-11-01T20:37:04+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-11-02T16:02:00+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>What Will China Do?</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/9D72usi69d8?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i2.ytimg.com/vi/9D72usi69d8/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>Chinese stocks and the yuan rallied on unconfirmed reports authorities have formed a committee to reconsider China’s “COVID zero” restrictions on economic activity. There was no follow-through in the U.S., though, as investors remain focused on Wednesday and the Federal Open Market Committee’s monetary policy decision. Tony Greer, the founder of TG Macro and the editor of the Morning Navigator, joins Andreas Steno Larsen for today’s Daily Briefing to talk about what impact a reopening of the Chinese economy China will have on global commodity markets and how to position for potential upside. We also hear from Jesse Felder, author of The Felder Report, about how changing investment patterns will impact the technology and energy sectors. Watch the full interview between Jesse Felder and Maggie Lake here: https://www.realvision.com/shows/make-or-break-inflation/videos/there-wont-be-a-crash-but-drpj?tab=details. And we want to hear from you too – please share your questions, comments, and suggestions!

Editor’s Note: Our live chat feature will be unavailable for four to six weeks as we upgrade our video player technology. We apologize for the temporary loss of function. But we assure you the upgrade will more than justify the wait. In the meantime, we will be monitoring the comments section. So, in addition to conversing with your fellow community members, please share your questions there.



Thanks for watching The Daily Briefing. Sign up here with your email address to have every episode delivered to your inbox Monday-Friday: http://rvtv.io/DailyBriefEmail

About Real Vision™:
Real Vision™ is where you can gain an understanding of the complex world of finance, business and the global economy with real in-depth analysis from real experts. 

Connect with Real Vision™ Online:
Twitter: https://rvtv.io/twitter
Instagram: https://rvtv.io/instagram
Facebook: https://rvtv.io/facebook
Linkedin: https://rvtv.io/linkedin 

What Will China Do?

Disclaimer:
This is pretty obvious, but we should probably say it anyway so that there is absolutely no confusion…The material in REAL VISION GROUP video programs and publications {collectively referred to as “RV RELEASES”} is provided for informational purposes only and is NOT investment advice. The information in RV RELEASES has been obtained from sources believed to be reliable, but Real Vision and its contributors, distributors and/or publisher, licensors, and their respective employees, contractors , agents, suppliers and vendors { collectively, “Affiliated Parties”} make no representation or warranty as to the accuracy, timeliness or completeness of the content in RV RELEASES. Any data included in RV RELEASES are illustrative only and not for investment purposes. Any opinion or recommendation expressed in RV RELEASES is subject to change without notice. RV Releases do not recommend, explicitly nor implicitly, nor suggest or recommend any investment strategy. Real Vision Group and its Affiliated Parties disclaim all liability for any loss that may arise (whether direct indirect, consequential, incidental, punitive or otherwise) from any use of the information in RV RELEASES. Real Vision Group and its Affiliated Parties do not have regard to any individual’s, group of individuals’ or entity’s specific investment objectives, financial situation or circumstance. RV RELEASES do not express any opinion on the future value of any security, currency or other investment instrument. You should seek expert financial and other advice regarding the appropriateness of the material discussed or recommended in RV RELEASES and should note that investment values may fall, you may receive less back than originally invested and past performances is not necessarily reflective of future performances. Well that was pretty intense! We hope you got all of that – now stop reading the small print and go and enjoy Real Vision.</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="728" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="21495"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:ccmC4ZKPKLw</id>
  <yt:videoId>ccmC4ZKPKLw</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCBH5VZE_Y4F3CMcPIzPEB5A</yt:channelId>
  <title>These Gold Stocks Could Outperform in the Next Decade</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ccmC4ZKPKLw"/>
  <author>
   <name>Real Vision Finance</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCBH5VZE_Y4F3CMcPIzPEB5A</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-11-01T16:14:09+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-11-02T08:53:45+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>These Gold Stocks Could Outperform in the Next Decade</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/ccmC4ZKPKLw?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i4.ytimg.com/vi/ccmC4ZKPKLw/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>In our new show, 3 Ideas, an expert will share three suggestions about where to put your money right now. 

This is not advice but rather a launching point for you to do your own due diligence and to make decisions that suit your risk tolerance and your objectives. 

We begin with precious metals investor Lawrence Lepard, the founder and managing partner of gold-and-silver-focused Equity Management Associates. In the inaugural episode of 3 Ideas, Larry goes deep on three mining stocks at the top of his current watch list – and, because he thinks it’s important to be diversified within the space, he names a bunch more potential outperformers too. Recorded on September 22, 2022. 

Disclosure: Larry Lepard and his firm own all of the stocks discussed in this interview. His fund holds a roughly 2% stake in Guanajuato Silver Co.

👉 Do you want even more content like this? And to see this video before we release it here? Become a member of Real Vision -- get started here: https://rvtv.io/membership 

Thanks for watching Real Vision Finance!

#gold  #goldmarket  #preciousmetals 

About Real Vision™:
Real Vision™ is where you can gain an understanding of the complex world of finance, business, and the global economy with real in-depth analysis from real experts. 

🔥 𝗚𝗘𝗧 𝟳 𝗗𝗔𝗬𝗦 of Real Vision’s insights for only $𝟭 (seriously!) https://rvtv.io/RVfor1dollar
 
🚀 Want to become a better investor or start from scratch?  👉 Join the Real Investing course now! https://rvtv.io/RVAcademy 

Connect with Real Vision™ Online:
RV Crypto: http://rvtv.io/RealVisionCrypto
Twitter: https://rvtv.io/twitter
Instagram: https://rvtv.io/instagram
Facebook: https://rvtv.io/facebook
Linkedin: https://rvtv.io/linkedin​​​​​​​​​​​​​​​​

#Macro #finance #macroeconomy #markets #financialmarkets #bonds #stocks #oil #gas #commodities #equities #gold

Disclaimer:
This is pretty obvious, but we should probably say it anyway so there is no confusion…The material in REAL VISION GROUP video programs and publications {collectively referred to as “RV RELEASES”} is provided for informational purposes only and is NOT investment advice. The information in RV RELEASES has been obtained from sources believed to be reliable, but Real Vision and its contributors, distributors and/or publisher, licensors, and their respective employees, contractors, agents, suppliers, and vendors { collectively, “Affiliated Parties”} make no representation or warranty as to the accuracy, timeliness or completeness of the content in RV RELEASES. Any data included in RV RELEASES are illustrative only and not for investment purposes. Any opinion or recommendation expressed in RV RELEASES is subject to change without notice. RV Releases do not recommend, explicitly nor implicitly, nor suggest or recommend any investment strategy. Real Vision Group and its Affiliated Parties disclaim all liability for any loss that may arise (whether direct indirect, consequential, incidental, punitive, or otherwise) from any use of the information in RV RELEASES. Real Vision Group and its Affiliated Parties do not have regard for any individual, group of individuals, or entity’s specific investment objectives, financial situation, or circumstance. RV RELEASES do not express any opinion on the future value of any security, currency, or other investment instruments. You should seek expert financial and other advice regarding the appropriateness of the material discussed or recommended in RV RELEASES and should note that investment values may fall, you may receive less back than originally invested and past performances are not necessarily reflective of future performances. Well, that was pretty intense! We hope you got all of that – now stop reading the small print and go and enjoy Real Vision.</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="192" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="4588"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:7SJpLX7sEPQ</id>
  <yt:videoId>7SJpLX7sEPQ</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCBH5VZE_Y4F3CMcPIzPEB5A</yt:channelId>
  <title>How To Be a Calculated Risk-Taker w/ Jeff Dorman</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7SJpLX7sEPQ"/>
  <author>
   <name>Real Vision Finance</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCBH5VZE_Y4F3CMcPIzPEB5A</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-10-31T21:55:08+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-11-01T07:02:25+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>How To Be a Calculated Risk-Taker w/ Jeff Dorman</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/7SJpLX7sEPQ?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i4.ytimg.com/vi/7SJpLX7sEPQ/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>In this episode of My Life in Four Trades, Jeff Dorman, a co-founder, and the chief investment officer of Arca, gets personal with Maggie Lake. 

Jeff explains why he quit traditional finance, shares the lessons he had to learn and unlearn after years of working on Wall Street, and talks about how he’s become a calculated risk-taker. 

After trading at leading TradFi firms such as Lehman Brothers, Merrill Lynch, and Citadel, Jeff moved to Los Angeles for a new blockchain-powered career and to find a work-life balance.

👉 Do you want even more content like this? And to see this video before we release it here? Become a member of Real Vision -- get started here: https://rvtv.io/membership 

Thanks for watching Real Vision Finance!

#tradingstrategy  #tradingeducation  #youtubepodcast 

About Real Vision™:
Real Vision™ is where you can gain an understanding of the complex world of finance, business, and the global economy with real in-depth analysis from real experts. 

🔥 𝗚𝗘𝗧 𝟳 𝗗𝗔𝗬𝗦 of Real Vision’s insights for only $𝟭 (seriously!) https://rvtv.io/RVfor1dollar
 
🚀 Want to become a better investor or start from scratch?  👉 Join the Real Investing course now! https://rvtv.io/RVAcademy 

Connect with Real Vision™ Online:
RV Crypto: http://rvtv.io/RealVisionCrypto
Twitter: https://rvtv.io/twitter
Instagram: https://rvtv.io/instagram
Facebook: https://rvtv.io/facebook
Linkedin: https://rvtv.io/linkedin​​​​​​​​​​​​​​​​

#Macro #finance #macroeconomy #markets #financialmarkets #bonds #stocks #oil #gas #commodities #equities #gold

Disclaimer:
This is pretty obvious, but we should probably say it anyway so there is no confusion…The material in REAL VISION GROUP video programs and publications {collectively referred to as “RV RELEASES”} is provided for informational purposes only and is NOT investment advice. The information in RV RELEASES has been obtained from sources believed to be reliable, but Real Vision and its contributors, distributors and/or publisher, licensors, and their respective employees, contractors, agents, suppliers, and vendors { collectively, “Affiliated Parties”} make no representation or warranty as to the accuracy, timeliness or completeness of the content in RV RELEASES. Any data included in RV RELEASES are illustrative only and not for investment purposes. Any opinion or recommendation expressed in RV RELEASES is subject to change without notice. RV Releases do not recommend, explicitly nor implicitly, nor suggest or recommend any investment strategy. Real Vision Group and its Affiliated Parties disclaim all liability for any loss that may arise (whether direct indirect, consequential, incidental, punitive, or otherwise) from any use of the information in RV RELEASES. Real Vision Group and its Affiliated Parties do not have regard for any individual, group of individuals, or entity’s specific investment objectives, financial situation, or circumstance. RV RELEASES do not express any opinion on the future value of any security, currency, or other investment instruments. You should seek expert financial and other advice regarding the appropriateness of the material discussed or recommended in RV RELEASES and should note that investment values may fall, you may receive less back than originally invested and past performances are not necessarily reflective of future performances. Well, that was pretty intense! We hope you got all of that – now stop reading the small print and go and enjoy Real Vision.</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="130" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="3791"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:rzucANvHlvc</id>
  <yt:videoId>rzucANvHlvc</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCBH5VZE_Y4F3CMcPIzPEB5A</yt:channelId>
  <title>Energy Crisis Dos and Don'ts With Doomberg</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=rzucANvHlvc"/>
  <author>
   <name>Real Vision Finance</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCBH5VZE_Y4F3CMcPIzPEB5A</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-10-31T20:42:10+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-11-01T19:13:26+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Energy Crisis Dos and Don'ts With Doomberg</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/rzucANvHlvc?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i3.ytimg.com/vi/rzucANvHlvc/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>“This should be fun,” tweeted Doomberg amid reports President Joe Biden will propose a “windfall tax” on profits of oil and gas producers, as political leaders continue to pose against the global energy problem. Andreas Steno Larsen welcomes the congenitally acerbic and always insightful Green Chicken for today’s Daily Briefing to talk about realistic solutions to a situation that only seems to be growing worse by the day – with inflation yet to peak and still more resource-scarcity promised by Russia’s withdrawal from the Black Sea Grain Initiative. We also hear from White Tundra Investments CEO Shubham Garg, who shares his reasoning for exponential growth in global oil demand. Watch Shubham Garg’s complete presentation here: https://www.realvision.com/shows/3-ideas/videos/where-to-pick-in-canadas-energy-patch-LwzQ?tab=details. We want to hear from you too – please share your comments, questions, and suggestions.



Thanks for watching The Daily Briefing. Sign up here with your email address to have every episode delivered to your inbox Monday-Friday: http://rvtv.io/DailyBriefEmail

About Real Vision™:
Real Vision™ is where you can gain an understanding of the complex world of finance, business and the global economy with real in-depth analysis from real experts. 

Connect with Real Vision™ Online:
Twitter: https://rvtv.io/twitter
Instagram: https://rvtv.io/instagram
Facebook: https://rvtv.io/facebook
Linkedin: https://rvtv.io/linkedin 

Energy Crisis Dos and Don'ts With Doomberg.

Disclaimer:
This is pretty obvious, but we should probably say it anyway so that there is absolutely no confusion…The material in REAL VISION GROUP video programs and publications {collectively referred to as “RV RELEASES”} is provided for informational purposes only and is NOT investment advice. The information in RV RELEASES has been obtained from sources believed to be reliable, but Real Vision and its contributors, distributors and/or publisher, licensors, and their respective employees, contractors , agents, suppliers and vendors { collectively, “Affiliated Parties”} make no representation or warranty as to the accuracy, timeliness or completeness of the content in RV RELEASES. Any data included in RV RELEASES are illustrative only and not for investment purposes. Any opinion or recommendation expressed in RV RELEASES is subject to change without notice. RV Releases do not recommend, explicitly nor implicitly, nor suggest or recommend any investment strategy. Real Vision Group and its Affiliated Parties disclaim all liability for any loss that may arise (whether direct indirect, consequential, incidental, punitive or otherwise) from any use of the information in RV RELEASES. Real Vision Group and its Affiliated Parties do not have regard to any individual’s, group of individuals’ or entity’s specific investment objectives, financial situation or circumstance. RV RELEASES do not express any opinion on the future value of any security, currency or other investment instrument. You should seek expert financial and other advice regarding the appropriateness of the material discussed or recommended in RV RELEASES and should note that investment values may fall, you may receive less back than originally invested and past performances is not necessarily reflective of future performances. Well that was pretty intense! We hope you got all of that – now stop reading the small print and go and enjoy Real Vision.</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="871" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="24181"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
</feed>
