<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<rdf:RDF
 xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
 xmlns="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/"
 xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
 xmlns:taxo="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/taxonomy/"
 xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
 xmlns:syn="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
 xmlns:admin="http://webns.net/mvcb/"
>

<channel rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/">
<title>q-bio.GN updates on arXiv.org</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">Quantitative Biology -- Genomics (q-bio.GN) updates on the arXiv.org e-print archive</description>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:date>2022-11-03T20:30:00-05:00</dc:date>
<dc:publisher>help@arxiv.org</dc:publisher>
<dc:subject>Quantitative Biology -- Genomics</dc:subject>
<syn:updateBase>1901-01-01T00:00+00:00</syn:updateBase>
<syn:updateFrequency>1</syn:updateFrequency>
<syn:updatePeriod>daily</syn:updatePeriod>
<items>
 <rdf:Seq>
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01603" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2102.02649" />
 </rdf:Seq>
</items>
<image rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif" />
</channel>
<image rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif">
<title>arXiv.org</title>
<url>http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif</url>
<link>http://arxiv.org/</link>
</image>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01603">
<title>Using Signal Processing in Tandem With Adapted Mixture Models for Classifying Genomic Signals. (arXiv:2211.01603v1 [q-bio.GN])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01603</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Genomic signal processing has been used successfully in bioinformatics to
analyze biomolecular sequences and gain varied insights into DNA structure,
gene organization, protein binding, sequence evolution, etc. But challenges
remain in finding the appropriate spectral representation of a biomolecular
sequence, especially when multiple variable-length sequences need to be handled
consistently. In this study, we address this challenge in the context of the
well-studied problem of classifying genomic sequences into different taxonomic
units (strain, phyla, order, etc.). We propose a novel technique that employs
signal processing in tandem with Gaussian mixture models to improve the
spectral representation of a sequence and subsequently the taxonomic
classification accuracies. The sequences are first transformed into spectra,
and projected to a subspace, where sequences belonging to different taxons are
better distinguishable. Our method outperforms a similar state-of-the-art
method on established benchmark datasets by an absolute margin of 6.06%
accuracy.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/q-bio/1/au:+Jaiswal_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Saish Jaiswal&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/q-bio/1/au:+Nema_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Shreya Nema&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/q-bio/1/au:+Murthy_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Hema A Murthy&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/q-bio/1/au:+Narayanan_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Manikandan Narayanan&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2102.02649">
<title>A step towards a reinforcement learning de novo genome assembler. (arXiv:2102.02649v3 [q-bio.GN] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2102.02649</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The use of reinforcement learning has proven to be very promising for solving
complex activities without human supervision during their learning process.
However, their successful applications are predominantly focused on fictional
and entertainment problems - such as games. Based on the above, this work aims
to shed light on the application of reinforcement learning to solve this
relevant real-world problem, the genome assembly. By expanding the only
approach found in the literature that addresses this problem, we carefully
explored the aspects of intelligent agent learning, performed by the Q-learning
algorithm, to understand its suitability to be applied in scenarios whose
characteristics are more similar to those faced by real genome projects. The
improvements proposed here include changing the previously proposed reward
system and including state space exploration optimization strategies based on
dynamic pruning and mutual collaboration with evolutionary computing. These
investigations were tried on 23 new environments with larger inputs than those
used previously. All these environments are freely available on the internet
for the evolution of this research by the scientific community. The results
suggest consistent performance progress using the proposed improvements,
however, they also demonstrate the limitations of them, especially related to
the high dimensionality of state and action spaces. We also present, later, the
paths that can be traced to tackle genome assembly efficiently in real
scenarios considering recent, successfully reinforcement learning applications
- including deep reinforcement learning - from other domains dealing with
high-dimensional inputs.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/q-bio/1/au:+Padovani_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Kleber Padovani&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/q-bio/1/au:+Xavier_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Roberto Xavier&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/q-bio/1/au:+Carvalho_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Andre Carvalho&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/q-bio/1/au:+Reali_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Anna Reali&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/q-bio/1/au:+Chateau_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Annie Chateau&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/q-bio/1/au:+Alves_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ronnie Alves&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
</rdf:RDF>