<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
<title>Page One Economics®</title>
<description>Page One Economics®</description>
<link>https://research.stlouisfed.org/publications/page1-econ/</link>
<atom:link href="https://research.stlouisfed.org/publications/page1-econ/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2022 11:47:21 -0500</pubDate>
<item>
<title>Beyond the Hype: An Introduction to Crypto Assets</title>
<link>https://research.stlouisfed.org/publications/page1-econ/2022/10/03/beyond-the-hype-an-introduction-to-crypto-assets</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[Crypto assets have increasingly occupied news headlines and the minds of many consumers. While initially introduced as a payment system, crypto assets are seen by many as an enticing investment opportunity. This issue of&nbsp;Page One Economics®&nbsp;introduces crypto assets, blockchain technology, and the emerging crypto universe.
]]>
</description>
<pubDate>2022-10-03</pubDate>
<guid>https://research.stlouisfed.org/publications/page1-econ/2022/10/03/beyond-the-hype-an-introduction-to-crypto-assets</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Income and Wealth Inequality</title>
<link>https://research.stlouisfed.org/publications/page1-econ/2022/09/01/income-and-wealth-inequality</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[Income and wealth are becoming more unequal over time. The September 2022 issue of&nbsp;Page One Economics® discusses how income and wealth inequality are measured, what drives differences among individuals and households, and how growing inequality may affect the overall economy.
]]>
</description>
<pubDate>2022-09-01</pubDate>
<guid>https://research.stlouisfed.org/publications/page1-econ/2022/09/01/income-and-wealth-inequality</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Data Revisions with FRED®</title>
<link>https://research.stlouisfed.org/publications/page1-econ/2022/08/01/data-revisions-with-fred</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[This&nbsp;Page One Economics&nbsp;Data Primer describes the reasons data are revised and updated.&nbsp;More accurate data facilitate better decisionmaking.&nbsp;
]]>
</description>
<pubDate>2022-08-01</pubDate>
<guid>https://research.stlouisfed.org/publications/page1-econ/2022/08/01/data-revisions-with-fred</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>How Does the Fed Use Its Monetary Policy Tools to Influence the Economy?</title>
<link>https://research.stlouisfed.org/publications/page1-econ/2022/05/02/how-does-the-fed-use-its-monetary-policy-tools-to-influence-the-economy</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[The Federal Reserve has a congressional mandate to promote maximum employment and price stability. This issue of&nbsp;Page One Economics® explains how the FOMC conducts monetary policy by setting the target range for the federal funds rate and how the Fed uses its policy tools to steer the federal funds rate into the FOMC’s target range.&nbsp;
]]>
</description>
<pubDate>2022-05-02</pubDate>
<guid>https://research.stlouisfed.org/publications/page1-econ/2022/05/02/how-does-the-fed-use-its-monetary-policy-tools-to-influence-the-economy</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Endowment Effect</title>
<link>https://research.stlouisfed.org/publications/page1-econ/2022/04/01/the-endowment-effect</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[Shopping for and owning things are exciting and emotional experiences. We take time and energy thinking about what to buy and the role it will play in our lives. In this&nbsp;Page One Economics®: Focus on Finance&nbsp;article, we look at the endowment effect&mdash;how we place more value on items we own than on items we don’t. &nbsp;&nbsp;]]>
</description>
<pubDate>2022-04-01</pubDate>
<guid>https://research.stlouisfed.org/publications/page1-econ/2022/04/01/the-endowment-effect</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Examining Racial Wealth Inequality</title>
<link>https://research.stlouisfed.org/publications/page1-econ/2022/03/01/examining-racial-wealth-inequality</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[This issue of Page One Economics® covers the topics of income and wealth through the lens of racial inequality. Learn the difference between income and wealth, how the racial wealth gap has endured over time, and the reasons that certain groups have been limited in their wealth-building potential.]]>
</description>
<pubDate>2022-03-01</pubDate>
<guid>https://research.stlouisfed.org/publications/page1-econ/2022/03/01/examining-racial-wealth-inequality</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>On the Move: Mortgage Basics</title>
<link>https://research.stlouisfed.org/publications/page1-econ/2022/02/01/on-the-move-mortgage-basics</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[Buying a home is a major financial decision, and for young people in particular the entire process can seem overwhelming. Learn about mortgages and the steps people can take early in life to prepare themselves financially to buy a home, in this February 2022 issue of&nbsp;Page One Economics: Focus on Finance.
]]>
</description>
<pubDate>2022-02-01</pubDate>
<guid>https://research.stlouisfed.org/publications/page1-econ/2022/02/01/on-the-move-mortgage-basics</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Importance of Diverse Perspectives: Strategies for Supporting Women in Economics</title>
<link>https://research.stlouisfed.org/publications/page1-econ/2022/01/14/the-importance-of-diverse-perspectives-strategies-for-supporting-women-in-economics</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[There is a lack of diversity in the field on economics, which limits the range of perspectives during research and policy discussions. Without diverse perspectives, economists are in danger of not identifying key parts of a problem and not considering a full array of solutions.&nbsp;This Women in Economics special issue of&nbsp;Page One Economics&nbsp;presents the case that diversity among economists is needed to gain a wider perspective during economic research and policy development.
]]>
</description>
<pubDate>2022-01-14</pubDate>
<guid>https://research.stlouisfed.org/publications/page1-econ/2022/01/14/the-importance-of-diverse-perspectives-strategies-for-supporting-women-in-economics</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Gender and Labor Markets</title>
<link>https://research.stlouisfed.org/publications/page1-econ/2022/01/03/gender-and-labor-markets</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[Interactions between employers and employees in the labor market underpin all production activities. The January 2022 issue of&nbsp;Page One Economics® discusses how gender influences workers’ experiences in the labor market, including their decisions to participate in the market, the types of jobs they hold, their decisions to exit the market, and ultimately their earnings.]]>
</description>
<pubDate>2022-01-03</pubDate>
<guid>https://research.stlouisfed.org/publications/page1-econ/2022/01/03/gender-and-labor-markets</guid>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>