<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns:yt="http://www.youtube.com/xml/schemas/2015" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
 <link rel="self" href="http://www.youtube.com/feeds/videos.xml?channel_id=UC9K5PLkj0N_b9JTPdSRwPkg"/>
 <id>yt:channel:UC9K5PLkj0N_b9JTPdSRwPkg</id>
 <yt:channelId>UC9K5PLkj0N_b9JTPdSRwPkg</yt:channelId>
 <title>New Discourses</title>
 <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC9K5PLkj0N_b9JTPdSRwPkg"/>
 <author>
  <name>New Discourses</name>
  <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC9K5PLkj0N_b9JTPdSRwPkg</uri>
 </author>
 <published>2019-07-03T19:05:08+00:00</published>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:oWEB31FMsno</id>
  <yt:videoId>oWEB31FMsno</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UC9K5PLkj0N_b9JTPdSRwPkg</yt:channelId>
  <title>&quot;Groomer Schools&quot; | James Lindsay</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=oWEB31FMsno"/>
  <author>
   <name>New Discourses</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC9K5PLkj0N_b9JTPdSRwPkg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-11-03T15:51:05+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-11-04T15:02:24+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>&quot;Groomer Schools&quot; | James Lindsay</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/oWEB31FMsno?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i4.ytimg.com/vi/oWEB31FMsno/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>The Marxification of Education Workshop, Session 3 

The word of the year in education and regarding our children has been &quot;groomer,&quot; which is widely banned across social media now as a result (along with James Lindsay from Twitter for calling this problem out). In the Marxification of education, which is its remaking into a system of Marxist conscientization, schools can be said to have been transformed into groomer schools. Specifically, while the terms &quot;thought reform&quot; and &quot;brainwashing&quot; have been used in the past to describe this process, the term &quot;grooming&quot; is even more applicable given the nature of the process of conscientization, including its specific subject matter. It's a tremendous problem that demands understanding and a solution. Here, New Discourses Founder James Lindsay summarizes what he means by the term &quot;Groomer Schools&quot; in this third of four presentations on the Marxification of Education delivered in late July 2022 in Arlington, Virginia, on location in the now-famous Loudoun County, ground zero for the fight for America's schools. 

As a result of the research that produced this lecture series, Lindsay has written a detailed and accessible book on the issue titled The Marxification of Education, which is available for preorder now: https://amzn.to/3RYZ0tY #ad 

Session 1: https://newdiscourses.com/2022/10/the-critical-turn-in-education/
Session 2: https://newdiscourses.com/2022/10/paulo-freires-critical-method-of-education/

Support New Discourses: https://newdiscourses.com/support

Subscribe to New Discourses on other platforms: https://newdiscourses.com/subscribe

Follow James Lindsay: https://linktr.ee/conceptualjames

© 2022 New Discourses. All rights reserved.</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="820" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="10748"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:oI1MaaTKfRc</id>
  <yt:videoId>oI1MaaTKfRc</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UC9K5PLkj0N_b9JTPdSRwPkg</yt:channelId>
  <title>Totalitarianism and the Progressive Impulse</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=oI1MaaTKfRc"/>
  <author>
   <name>New Discourses</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC9K5PLkj0N_b9JTPdSRwPkg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-11-02T17:26:54+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-11-03T09:50:06+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Totalitarianism and the Progressive Impulse</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/oI1MaaTKfRc?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i4.ytimg.com/vi/oI1MaaTKfRc/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>New Discourses Bullets, Ep. 25 

With the possible exception of our would-be overlords, we all know Nazis were bad. Fewer of us, especially in the younger generations, understand that Communists are also bad. Do you understand these two movements and how they're actually both bad because they're actually both part of the same current of thought? That current of thought is progressivism, especially of the collectivist-socialist kind, which is more broadly an actionable manifestation of the Romantic counter-Enlightenment movement. While different in important ways, what these two evil movements share in common is profound. Join host James Lindsay in this longer episode of New Discourses Bullets to see them both, as well as our present circumstances, more clearly.

Support New Discourses: https://newdiscourses.com/support

Subscribe to New Discourses on other platforms: https://newdiscourses.com/subscribe

Follow James Lindsay: https://linktr.ee/conceptualjames

© 2022 New Discourses. All rights reserved.</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="636" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="8156"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:SukzKzs_OSQ</id>
  <yt:videoId>SukzKzs_OSQ</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UC9K5PLkj0N_b9JTPdSRwPkg</yt:channelId>
  <title>Paulo Freire's &quot;Critical&quot; Method of Education | James Lindsay</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=SukzKzs_OSQ"/>
  <author>
   <name>New Discourses</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC9K5PLkj0N_b9JTPdSRwPkg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-10-31T18:45:34+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-11-04T15:02:39+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Paulo Freire's &quot;Critical&quot; Method of Education | James Lindsay</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/SukzKzs_OSQ?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i4.ytimg.com/vi/SukzKzs_OSQ/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>The Marxification of Education Workshop, Session 2 

How on Earth did education get so messed up and stolen from our society and our kids? While the critical turn in education enabled this &quot;transformation&quot; of our education system, the crucial piece that allowed it to happen is the work of a Brazilian Marxist by the name of Paulo Freire. Paulo Freire completely transformed education, not least by Marxifying it. That is, in addition to creating the conditions to swap out actual education for political education, Freire structured his understanding of education and knowledge itself as a Marxist Theory of knowing and being educated. Treating these as a special kind of bourgeois private property, Freire paved the way to abolish education entirely and to reimagine it as a system of brainwashing learners into critical Marxist consciousness. Here, New Discourses Founder James Lindsay summarizes this transformation of education itself in this second of four presentations on the Marxification of Education delivered in late July 2022 in Arlington, Virginia, on location in the now-famous Loudoun County, ground zero for the fight for America's schools. 

As a result of the research that produced this lecture series, and this lecture in particular, Lindsay has written a detailed and accessible book expanding on these themes considerably, titled The Marxification of Education, which is available for preorder now: https://amzn.to/3RYZ0tY #ad

Session 1: https://newdiscourses.com/2022/10/the-critical-turn-in-education/
Session 3: https://newdiscourses.com/2022/11/groomer-schools/

Support New Discourses: https://newdiscourses.com/support

Subscribe to New Discourses on other platforms: https://newdiscourses.com/subscribe

Follow James Lindsay: https://linktr.ee/conceptualjames

© 2022 New Discourses. All rights reserved.</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="665" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="12026"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:TEk4vMaNzeo</id>
  <yt:videoId>TEk4vMaNzeo</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UC9K5PLkj0N_b9JTPdSRwPkg</yt:channelId>
  <title>Systemic Trauma and Harm</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=TEk4vMaNzeo"/>
  <author>
   <name>New Discourses</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC9K5PLkj0N_b9JTPdSRwPkg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-10-27T12:26:39+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-10-28T10:29:12+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Systemic Trauma and Harm</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/TEk4vMaNzeo?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i1.ytimg.com/vi/TEk4vMaNzeo/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>New Discourses Bullets, Ep. 24

Trauma and harm. Trauma and harm. Harm and trauma. It seems virtually everything Woke these days is justified on the back of some obviously nonsense appeal to &quot;trauma&quot; or &quot;harm.&quot; Schools are arranged as being &quot;safe and welcoming&quot; and &quot;places where everyone feels like they belong&quot; in response to the pervasive &quot;trauma&quot; and &quot;harm&quot; of everything else in society. What's going on? In Woke Marxism, like everything else, trauma and harm are understood systemically. They're the result of oppression, which is the result of systemic power, which is the result of the structural stratification of society, which is how Marxists read everything in the world. In this episode of New Discourses Bullets, host James Lindsay breaks down how &quot;systemic trauma and harm&quot; are nothing more than the same old Marxist religious impulse (to undo the Marxist Fall of Man) and latest excuse for seizing power over everything.

Support New Discourses: https://newdiscourses.com/support

Subscribe to New Discourses on other platforms: https://newdiscourses.com/subscribe

Follow James Lindsay: https://linktr.ee/conceptualjames

© 2022 New Discourses. All rights reserved.</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="557" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="6985"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:HAQdYE8rQPI</id>
  <yt:videoId>HAQdYE8rQPI</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UC9K5PLkj0N_b9JTPdSRwPkg</yt:channelId>
  <title>The Critical Turn in Education | James Lindsay</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=HAQdYE8rQPI"/>
  <author>
   <name>New Discourses</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC9K5PLkj0N_b9JTPdSRwPkg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-10-20T18:15:13+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-11-04T15:01:47+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>The Critical Turn in Education | James Lindsay</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/HAQdYE8rQPI?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i1.ytimg.com/vi/HAQdYE8rQPI/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>The Marxification of Education Workshop, Session 1 

Education has been stolen from us and from our children. Yes, stolen. It was deliberately transformed from within into something that is barely education at all anymore. Instead, it's a systematic program of thought reform (brainwashing) into neo-Marxist belief and activism. How has this been accomplished? The formal name for the transformation is &quot;the critical turn in education,&quot; which &quot;turned&quot; education from traditional models of pedagogy to &quot;Critical Pedagogy,&quot; the application and teaching of Critical Theory to and through the education system. Its purpose: to overcome what Marxists refer to as &quot;the problem of reproduction,&quot; by which stable societies reproduce themselves from one generation to the next, especially through institutions involving children like religion, family, media, and especially education. Here, New Discourses Founder James Lindsay summarizes this &quot;turn&quot; in this first of four presentations on the Marxification of Education delivered in late July 2022 in Arlington, Virginia, on location in the now-famous Loudoun County, ground zero for the fight for America's schools. 

As a result of the research that produced this lecture series, Lindsay has written a detailed and accessible book on the issue titled The Marxification of Education, which is available for preorder now: https://amzn.to/3RYZ0tY #ad

Session 2: https://newdiscourses.com/2022/10/paulo-freires-critical-method-of-education/
Session 3: https://newdiscourses.com/2022/11/groomer-schools/

Support New Discourses: https://newdiscourses.com/support

Subscribe to New Discourses on other platforms: https://newdiscourses.com/subscribe

Follow James Lindsay: https://linktr.ee/conceptualjames

© 2022 New Discourses. All rights reserved.</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="2085" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="36735"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:5Uxt6J8Jg0w</id>
  <yt:videoId>5Uxt6J8Jg0w</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UC9K5PLkj0N_b9JTPdSRwPkg</yt:channelId>
  <title>What Does It Mean to Be Freirean?</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=5Uxt6J8Jg0w"/>
  <author>
   <name>New Discourses</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC9K5PLkj0N_b9JTPdSRwPkg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-10-17T18:00:06+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-10-17T19:44:00+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>What Does It Mean to Be Freirean?</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/5Uxt6J8Jg0w?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i2.ytimg.com/vi/5Uxt6J8Jg0w/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>The New Discourses Podcast with James Lindsay, Episode 97 

We have devoted a lot of time on the New Discourses Podcast to breaking down the work of the Brazilian Marxist &quot;educator&quot; Paulo Freire, who proved to be a pivotal figure in the history of Marxism in several ways at once. This work needs to continue, so it will continue. In this episode of the New Discourses Podcast, host James Lindsay offers a summary of what it means to be &quot;Freirean&quot; in education, following from his detailed explanation on the Social Justice Encyclopedia, Translations from the Wokish (https://newdiscourses.com/tftw-freirean/). Join him to understand what it means to be Freirean in even greater clarity and detail.

Support New Discourses: https://newdiscourses.com/support

Subscribe to New Discourses on other platforms: https://newdiscourses.com/subscribe

Follow James Lindsay: https://linktr.ee/conceptualjames

© 2022 New Discourses. All rights reserved.</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="615" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="12129"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:Wnjo5tOl338</id>
  <yt:videoId>Wnjo5tOl338</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UC9K5PLkj0N_b9JTPdSRwPkg</yt:channelId>
  <title>Data is the New Oil</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Wnjo5tOl338"/>
  <author>
   <name>New Discourses</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC9K5PLkj0N_b9JTPdSRwPkg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-10-13T16:33:23+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-11-04T18:05:53+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Data is the New Oil</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/Wnjo5tOl338?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i4.ytimg.com/vi/Wnjo5tOl338/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>New Discourses Bullets, Ep. 23 

You have probably heard the quip: &quot;data is the new oil.&quot; What does that mean, and what does it imply? In this episode of New Discourses Bullets, host James Lindsay walks you through the concept, making it clear that data, like oil and gold before it, are not just extremely valuable commodities but can also serve as the basis for the next iteration of our currency. This has profound implications for life in the coming digital era if we don't get ahead of it now by passing robust data privacy, ownership, and protection legislation. This is truly an issue of global importance!

Support New Discourses: https://newdiscourses.com/support

Subscribe to New Discourses on other platforms: https://newdiscourses.com/subscribe

Follow James Lindsay: https://linktr.ee/conceptualjames

© 2022 New Discourses. All rights reserved.</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="701" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="8043"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:Lp0ewPsfghw</id>
  <yt:videoId>Lp0ewPsfghw</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UC9K5PLkj0N_b9JTPdSRwPkg</yt:channelId>
  <title>The Strange Death of the University, Part 2: A New Sensibility</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Lp0ewPsfghw"/>
  <author>
   <name>New Discourses</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC9K5PLkj0N_b9JTPdSRwPkg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-10-10T18:00:08+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-10-27T23:50:06+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>The Strange Death of the University, Part 2: A New Sensibility</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/Lp0ewPsfghw?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i1.ytimg.com/vi/Lp0ewPsfghw/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>The New Discourses Podcast with James Lindsay, Episode 96 

We all know academia is in trouble. In fact, we're not even sure it can be saved. To put it simply, the university is dying. To be sure, it's a strange death, however, because the university is in some sense going back to its roots, returning to being theological seminaries, though in a completely new religion. That religion is the transformative religion of Dialectical Leftism, and its materialist watchword in the 21st century is &quot;Sustainability.&quot; In this New Discourses Podcast series, host James Lindsay takes the listener through a 2022 UNESCO book, Knowledge-driven Actions: Transforming Higher Education for Global Sustainability (https://unesdoc.unesco.org/ark:/48223/pf0000380519/), that calls upon all &quot;higher education institutions&quot; to transform themselves so that they align, promote, and help complete the United Nations 17 Sustainable Development Goals as a part of the 2030 Agenda. 

In this episode of the series, host James Lindsay takes the listener through the first chapter, the introduction, to this manipulative UNESCO document. Sustainability is made out clearly to be a cult-religious concept, a new theological object to bind and orient the university so that the Neo-Communist agenda can be accomplished through it. Sustainability will come to guide how institutions think, operate, research, and teach, and they will serve as beacons for this new faith to the communities around them. Sustainability is to become our &quot;New Sensibility,&quot; just like Herbert Marcuse called for in the second chapter of his 1969 Essay on Liberation (https://www.marxists.org/reference/archive/marcuse/works/1969/essay-liberation.htm/). Sustainability as the tyranny of the 21st century (https://newdiscourses.com/2021/10/sustainability-tyranny-21st-century/) is to become the mode and model for all institutions of higher education, including colleges, universities, seminaries, and more. Join James to hear about how the universities are to be transformed into the cathedrals of this new backwards cult religion.

Support New Discourses: https://newdiscourses.com/support

Subscribe to New Discourses on other platforms: https://newdiscourses.com/subscribe

Follow James Lindsay: https://linktr.ee/conceptualjames

© 2022 New Discourses. All rights reserved.</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="652" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="12552"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:e2DxUYNm4u0</id>
  <yt:videoId>e2DxUYNm4u0</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UC9K5PLkj0N_b9JTPdSRwPkg</yt:channelId>
  <title>&quot;Lived Experience,&quot; Explained</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=e2DxUYNm4u0"/>
  <author>
   <name>New Discourses</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC9K5PLkj0N_b9JTPdSRwPkg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-10-06T16:49:31+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-10-21T21:55:51+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>&quot;Lived Experience,&quot; Explained</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/e2DxUYNm4u0?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i2.ytimg.com/vi/e2DxUYNm4u0/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>New Discourses Bullets, Ep. 22 

We've all heard it and done everything we can to avoid rolling our eyes now. &quot;It's my lived experience!&quot; as though that's evidence or, actually, even better than evidence. &quot;Lived experience&quot; is a particular result of Leftist dialectical thought, however, that allows them to convince people that whatever they say is right and whatever anyone else says is dumb or bad. It is, in fact, the dialectical synthesis of evidence and the Leftist phenomenological interpretation of the circumstances in which that evidence presents. It's even better than evidence, then, because while evidence is objective, &quot;lived experience&quot; is both objective and subjective at the same time, with the subjectivity coming from a place of higher consciousness. Join host James Lindsay for this episode of New Discourses Bullets in which he breaks it down.

Support New Discourses: https://newdiscourses.com/support

Subscribe to New Discourses on other platforms: https://newdiscourses.com/subscribe

Follow James Lindsay: https://linktr.ee/conceptualjames

© 2022 New Discourses. All rights reserved.</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="897" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="11814"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:Ndl6NrMPeyc</id>
  <yt:videoId>Ndl6NrMPeyc</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UC9K5PLkj0N_b9JTPdSRwPkg</yt:channelId>
  <title>The Strange Death of the University, Part 1: The Red Thread</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Ndl6NrMPeyc"/>
  <author>
   <name>New Discourses</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC9K5PLkj0N_b9JTPdSRwPkg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-10-03T18:00:11+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-10-06T06:33:09+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>The Strange Death of the University, Part 1: The Red Thread</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/Ndl6NrMPeyc?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i3.ytimg.com/vi/Ndl6NrMPeyc/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>The New Discourses Podcast with James Lindsay, Episode 95

We all know academia is in trouble. In fact, we're not even sure it can be saved. To put it simply, the university is dying. To be sure, it's a strange death, however, because the university is in some sense going back to its roots, returning to being theological seminaries, though in a completely new religion. That religion is the transformative religion of Dialectical Leftism, and its materialist watchword in the 21st century is &quot;Sustainability.&quot; In this New Discourses Podcast series, host James Lindsay takes the listener through a 2022 UNESCO book, Knowledge-driven Actions: Transforming Higher Education for Global Sustainability (https://unesdoc.unesco.org/ark:/48223/pf0000380519/), that calls upon all &quot;higher education institutions&quot; to transform themselves so that they align, promote, and help complete the United Nations 17 Sustainable Development Goals as a part of the 2030 Agenda. 

In this first episode of the series, Lindsay goes through the preliminary materials, including a foreword that explicitly grounds the entire purpose of the document in the work of the Critical Marxist Herbert Marcuse. &quot;Transformation is the red thread running through all the Sustainable Development Goals,&quot; we're told in the first sentence of the foreword. The goal in this executive summary is clear. The university must be transformed. It must be made into a think tank that services the UN 2030 Agenda and the Sustainable Development Goals meant to achieve it. All institutions of higher education, colleges, universities, seminaries, and beyond, must be bound and oriented in this one particular Neo-Communist direction. They must abandon their missions and take up the core value of sustainability, on the UN's agenda-driven terms. They must install &quot;sustainability officers&quot; and refuse to engage in any activity that supports &quot;non-sustainable&quot; practices. Join James and be shocked at what the United Nations thinks it can coerce the world's colleges into doing.

Support New Discourses: https://newdiscourses.com/support

Subscribe to New Discourses on other platforms: https://newdiscourses.com/subscribe

Follow James Lindsay: https://linktr.ee/conceptualjames

© 2022 New Discourses. All rights reserved.</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="1194" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="21990"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:njKVFFMe_C0</id>
  <yt:videoId>njKVFFMe_C0</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UC9K5PLkj0N_b9JTPdSRwPkg</yt:channelId>
  <title>Understanding the Dialectic</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=njKVFFMe_C0"/>
  <author>
   <name>New Discourses</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC9K5PLkj0N_b9JTPdSRwPkg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-09-29T16:08:53+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-10-05T21:04:04+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Understanding the Dialectic</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/njKVFFMe_C0?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i3.ytimg.com/vi/njKVFFMe_C0/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>New Discourses Bullets, Ep. 21 

Leftist thought for at least the past 250 years has taken a particular form that is not the usual form of thinking and understanding we know and love. It's something completely different. The Left, perhaps since Rousseau and definitely since Hegel, has been dialectical in its thinking. It is the Dialectical Left. What is the dialectic, though? What is dialectical thinking? In short, it's the fusion of opposites in a way that understands them from a higher-level perspective, which is necessarily synthetic. In this slightly longer episode of New Discourses Bullets, host James Lindsay explains the dialectic and dialectical thought in some detail with a considerable number of examples to help you understand this synthetic approach to thought and why it's always going to be a catastrophe in the making.

Support New Discourses: https://newdiscourses.com/support

Subscribe to New Discourses on other platforms: https://newdiscourses.com/subscribe

Follow James Lindsay: https://linktr.ee/conceptualjames

© 2022 New Discourses. All rights reserved.</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="893" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="13663"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:DiQ4nrR-iUU</id>
  <yt:videoId>DiQ4nrR-iUU</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UC9K5PLkj0N_b9JTPdSRwPkg</yt:channelId>
  <title>How Paulo Freire Made Marxism Stupid</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=DiQ4nrR-iUU"/>
  <author>
   <name>New Discourses</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC9K5PLkj0N_b9JTPdSRwPkg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-09-26T18:00:10+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-09-28T09:10:43+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>How Paulo Freire Made Marxism Stupid</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/DiQ4nrR-iUU?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i1.ytimg.com/vi/DiQ4nrR-iUU/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>The New Discourses Podcast with James Lindsay, Episode 94 

Paulo Freire is a Brazilian Marxist who is responsible for &quot;Marxifying&quot; education (https://newdiscourses.com/2022/05/paulo-freires-marxification-of-education/), thereby ruining it. In effect, what he did was created a Marxist Theory of being educated (https://newdiscourses.com/2022/05/paulo-freires-schools-new-discourses-bullets-ep-7/), and what this did, in turn, was create a Marxist Theory of knowledge and knowing. Who gets to be considered a knower? On what grounds? To whose benefit? Who decides? All of these questions are to be answered on (Critical) Marxist grounds. One result of this transition, in addition to his approach to education (https://newdiscourses.com/2022/08/paulo-freire-and-the-critical-theft-of-education/), is that he opened the door to a true Marxism of stupidity. You see, as a result of Freire's arguments, &quot;excluded knowledges&quot; have to be included, which includes the stupid. Speaking of how anti-intellectual and stupid this allowed Marxism to be, it allows for any idiot with a &quot;Critical&quot; disposition to create a Marxist Theory of anything by asking and answering the sorts of questions listed above about the knowledge base of anything they want. Thus, we end up with Marxist analyses of every academic subject, every facet of society, every hobby, every everything, in an interminable cascade of irritating stupidity we refer to as &quot;being Woke.&quot; In this episode of the New Discourses Podcast, host James Lindsay explains the phenomenon through a number of examples that make it absolutely clear how cheap and stupid &quot;Marxist&quot; analysis has become as a result of going &quot;Woke.&quot;

Support New Discourses: https://newdiscourses.com/support

Subscribe to New Discourses on other platforms: https://newdiscourses.com/subscribe

Follow James Lindsay: https://linktr.ee/conceptualjames

© 2022 New Discourses. All rights reserved.</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="1720" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="23230"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:d5KAq91WwbM</id>
  <yt:videoId>d5KAq91WwbM</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UC9K5PLkj0N_b9JTPdSRwPkg</yt:channelId>
  <title>The Dialectic of Global Citizenship</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=d5KAq91WwbM"/>
  <author>
   <name>New Discourses</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC9K5PLkj0N_b9JTPdSRwPkg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-09-22T14:14:58+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-09-30T22:00:06+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>The Dialectic of Global Citizenship</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/d5KAq91WwbM?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i1.ytimg.com/vi/d5KAq91WwbM/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>New Discourses Bullets, Ep. 20

There are certain advantages to understanding not just how the Dialectical Left (including Marxists and Wokeness) think but how their thought evolves over time. Theirs is a wholly Leftist religion that operates through a completely dialectical faith. In this episode of New Discourses Bullets, host James Lindsay spends a few minutes unpacking the dialectic and how it works. He then uses this information to trace the development of Leftist thought over the last 260 years and offers a cogent explanation for how it will develop over the next thirty, progressing through Woke Marxism into Sustainable Capitalism and pushing onward into &quot;global citizenship&quot; and a basis for a global administrative state.

Support New Discourses: https://newdiscourses.com/support

Subscribe to New Discourses on other platforms: https://newdiscourses.com/subscribe

Follow James Lindsay: https://linktr.ee/conceptualjames

© 2022 New Discourses. All rights reserved.</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="1012" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="12342"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:ehuWcpJmOc8</id>
  <yt:videoId>ehuWcpJmOc8</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UC9K5PLkj0N_b9JTPdSRwPkg</yt:channelId>
  <title>Critique and the Linguistic Transformation of Society</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ehuWcpJmOc8"/>
  <author>
   <name>New Discourses</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC9K5PLkj0N_b9JTPdSRwPkg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-09-19T18:00:11+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-09-24T17:38:26+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Critique and the Linguistic Transformation of Society</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/ehuWcpJmOc8?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i2.ytimg.com/vi/ehuWcpJmOc8/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>The New Discourses Podcast with James Lindsay, Episode 93 

Redefine the words; redefine the society. That's the basic idea of &quot;critique&quot; and the way so much of Marxist activism proceeds. Recently, James Lindsay explained this phenomenon in an essay (https://newdiscourses.com/2022/09/three-terms-communists-redefined-to-subvert-society/) on New Discourses with relation to three key terms that allow a subversion of society: &quot;inclusion,&quot; &quot;democracy,&quot; and, most concerningly, &quot;citizenship.&quot; In this episode of the New Discourses Podcast, host James Lindsay reads through and elaborates on his own essay on this topic. Join him to understand this important maneuver.

Support New Discourses: https://newdiscourses.com/support

Subscribe to New Discourses on other platforms: https://newdiscourses.com/subscribe

Follow James Lindsay: https://linktr.ee/conceptualjames

© 2022 New Discourses. All rights reserved.</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="1087" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="20544"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:_AcOgyVBnNY</id>
  <yt:videoId>_AcOgyVBnNY</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UC9K5PLkj0N_b9JTPdSRwPkg</yt:channelId>
  <title>On Individual, Corporate, and Social Buying</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_AcOgyVBnNY"/>
  <author>
   <name>New Discourses</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC9K5PLkj0N_b9JTPdSRwPkg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-09-15T16:44:39+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-09-23T10:25:35+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>On Individual, Corporate, and Social Buying</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/_AcOgyVBnNY?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i4.ytimg.com/vi/_AcOgyVBnNY/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>New Discourses Bullets, Ep. 19 

Apparently a lot of young people believe not only in something nonsensical but also specifically in socialism. I recently heard an example of a young woman talking about how all the necessities of life both &quot;should be free&quot; and &quot;should be paid for by the government.&quot; Obviously, if they're paid for, they're not free, but she means that they're free for her and paid for by everyone, thus partly her, through the intermediary of the State. This is a terrible idea. To better understand why, it's best to understand a basic fact of economic decision-making, which are the differences between first-, second-, and third-person purchasing decisions and why government purchasing, which is always third-person, is always least likely to do well by the cost/quality tradeoff. Join host James Lindsay in this episode of New Discourses Bullets as he breaks it down.

Support New Discourses: https://newdiscourses.com/support

Subscribe to New Discourses on other platforms: https://newdiscourses.com/subscribe

Follow James Lindsay: https://linktr.ee/conceptualjames

© 2022 New Discourses. All rights reserved.</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="476" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="5396"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
</feed>
