<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<rdf:RDF
 xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
 xmlns="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/"
 xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
 xmlns:taxo="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/taxonomy/"
 xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
 xmlns:syn="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
 xmlns:admin="http://webns.net/mvcb/"
>

<channel rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/">
<title>eess.SY updates on arXiv.org</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">Electrical Engineering and Systems Science -- Systems and Control (eess.SY) updates on the arXiv.org e-print archive</description>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:date>2022-11-03T20:30:00-05:00</dc:date>
<dc:publisher>help@arxiv.org</dc:publisher>
<dc:subject>Electrical Engineering and Systems Science -- Systems and Control</dc:subject>
<syn:updateBase>1901-01-01T00:00+00:00</syn:updateBase>
<syn:updateFrequency>1</syn:updateFrequency>
<syn:updatePeriod>daily</syn:updatePeriod>
<items>
 <rdf:Seq>
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01442" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01481" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01487" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01527" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01539" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01595" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01601" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01661" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01676" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01706" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01720" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01793" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01801" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01812" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01813" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01822" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01833" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01860" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01958" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2007.15390" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2108.02003" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2111.03699" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2204.03471" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2206.07811" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2208.10933" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.16695" />
 </rdf:Seq>
</items>
<image rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif" />
</channel>
<image rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif">
<title>arXiv.org</title>
<url>http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif</url>
<link>http://arxiv.org/</link>
</image>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01442">
<title>Towards Statistical Methods for Minimizing Effects of Failure Cascades. (arXiv:2211.01442v1 [eess.SY])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01442</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;This paper concerns the potential of corrective actions, such as generation
and load dispatch on minimizing the effects of transmission line failures in
electric power systems. Three loss functions (grid-centric, consumer-centric,
and influence localization) are used to statistically evaluate the criticality
of initial contingent failures. A learning scheme for both AC and DC grid
models combine a Monte Carlo approach with a convex dynamic programming
formulation and introduces an adaptive selection process, illustrated on the
IEEE-30 bus system.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/eess/1/au:+Liu_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Siyu Liu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/eess/1/au:+Ilic_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Marija Ilic&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01481">
<title>Physics-inspired machine learning for power grid frequency modelling. (arXiv:2211.01481v1 [eess.SY])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01481</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The operation of power systems is affected by diverse technical, economic and
social factors. Social behaviour determines load patterns, electricity markets
regulate the generation and weather-dependent renewables introduce power
fluctuations. Thus, power system dynamics must be regarded as a non-autonomous
system whose parameters vary strongly with time. However, the external driving
factors are usually only available on coarse scales and the actual dependencies
of the dynamic system parameters are generally unknown. Here, we propose a
physics-inspired machine learning model that bridges the gap between
large-scale drivers and short-term dynamics of the power system. Integrating
stochastic differential equations and artificial neural networks, we construct
a probabilistic model of the power grid frequency dynamics in Continental
Europe. Its probabilistic prediction outperforms the daily average profile,
which is an important benchmark. Using the integrated model, we identify and
explain the parameters of the dynamical system from the data, which reveals
their strong time-dependence and their relation to external drivers such as
wind power feed-in and fast generation ramps. Finally, we generate synthetic
time series from the model, which successfully reproduce central
characteristics of the grid frequency such as their heavy-tailed distribution.
All in all, our work emphasises the importance of modelling power system
dynamics as a stochastic non-autonomous system with both intrinsic dynamics and
external drivers.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/eess/1/au:+Kruse_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Johannes Kruse&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/eess/1/au:+Cramer_E/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Eike Cramer&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/eess/1/au:+Schafer_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Benjamin Sch&amp;#xe4;fer&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/eess/1/au:+Witthaut_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Dirk Witthaut&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01487">
<title>Multi-vehicle Conflict Resolution in Highly Constrained Spaces by Merging Optimal Control and Reinforcement Learning. (arXiv:2211.01487v1 [cs.RO])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01487</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We present a novel method in this work to address the problem of
multi-vehicle conflict resolution in highly constrained spaces. A high-fidelity
optimal control problem is formulated to incorporate nonlinear, non-holonomic
vehicle dynamics and exact collision avoidance constraints. Despite being
high-dimensional and non-convex, we can obtain an optimal solution by learning
configuration strategies with reinforcement learning (RL) in a simplified
discrete environment and approaching high-quality initial guesses
progressively. The simulation results show that our method can explore
efficient actions to resolve conflicts in confined space and generate dexterous
maneuvers that are both collision-free and kinematically feasible.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Shen_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xu Shen&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Borrelli_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Francesco Borrelli&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01527">
<title>Sensor Control for Information Gain in Dynamic, Sparse and Partially Observed Environments. (arXiv:2211.01527v1 [cs.AI])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01527</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We present an approach for autonomous sensor control for information
gathering under partially observable, dynamic and sparsely sampled
environments. We consider the problem of controlling a sensor that makes
partial observations in some space of interest such that it maximizes
information about entities present in that space. We describe our approach for
the task of Radio-Frequency (RF) spectrum monitoring, where the goal is to
search for and track unknown, dynamic signals in the environment. To this end,
we develop and demonstrate enhancements of the Deep Anticipatory Network (DAN)
Reinforcement Learning (RL) framework that uses prediction and information-gain
rewards to learn information-maximization policies in reward-sparse
environments. We also extend this problem to situations in which taking samples
from the actual RF spectrum/field is limited and expensive, and propose a
model-based version of the original RL algorithm that fine-tunes the controller
using a model of the environment that is iteratively improved from limited
samples taken from the RF field. Our approach was thoroughly validated by
testing against baseline expert-designed controllers in simulated RF
environments of different complexity, using different rewards schemes and
evaluation metrics. The results show that our system outperforms the standard
DAN architecture and is more flexible and robust than several hand-coded
agents. We also show that our approach is adaptable to non-stationary
environments where the agent has to learn to adapt to changes from the emitting
sources.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Burns_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;J. Brian Burns&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Sundaresan_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Aravind Sundaresan&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Sequeira_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Pedro Sequeira&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Sadhu_V/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Vidyasagar Sadhu&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01539">
<title>Conformal Prediction for STL Runtime Verification. (arXiv:2211.01539v1 [eess.SY])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01539</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We are interested in predicting failures of cyber-physical systems during
their operation. Particularly, we consider stochastic systems and signal
temporal logic specifications, and we want to calculate the probability that
the current system trajectory violates the specification. The paper presents
two predictive runtime verification algorithms that predict future system
states from the current observed system trajectory. As these predictions may
not be accurate, we construct prediction regions that quantify prediction
uncertainty by using conformal prediction, a statistical tool for uncertainty
quantification. Our first algorithm directly constructs a prediction region for
the satisfaction measure of the specification so that we can predict
specification violations with a desired confidence. The second algorithm
constructs prediction regions for future system states first, and uses these to
obtain a prediction region for the satisfaction measure. To the best of our
knowledge, these are the first formal guarantees for a predictive runtime
verification algorithm that applies to widely used trajectory predictors such
as RNNs and LSTMs, while being computationally simple and making no assumptions
on the underlying distribution. We present numerical experiments of an F-16
aircraft and a self-driving car.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/eess/1/au:+Lindemann_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Lars Lindemann&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/eess/1/au:+Qin_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xin Qin&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/eess/1/au:+Deshmukh_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jyotirmoy V. Deshmukh&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/eess/1/au:+Pappas_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;George J. Pappas&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01595">
<title>Reinforcement Learning in Non-Markovian Environments. (arXiv:2211.01595v1 [eess.SY])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01595</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Following the novel paradigm developed by Van Roy and coauthors for
reinforcement learning in arbitrary non-Markovian environments, we propose a
related formulation inspired by classical stochastic control that reduces the
problem to recursive computation of approximate sufficient statistics.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/eess/1/au:+Chandak_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Siddharth Chandak&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/eess/1/au:+Borkar_V/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Vivek S Borkar&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/eess/1/au:+Dodhia_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Parth Dodhia&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01601">
<title>A Fast Solution Method for Large-scale Unit Commitment Based on Lagrangian Relaxation and Dynamic Programming. (arXiv:2211.01601v1 [math.OC])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01601</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The unit commitment problem (UC) is crucial for the operation and market
mechanism of power systems. With the development of modern electricity, the
scale of power systems is expanding, and solving the UC problem is also
becoming more and more difficult. To this end, this paper proposes a new fast
solution method based on Lagrangian relaxation and dynamic program-ming.
Firstly, the UC solution is estimated to be an initial trial UC solution by a
fast method based on Lagrangian relaxation. This initial trial UC solution
fully considers the system-wide con-straints. Secondly, a dynamic programming
module is introduced to adjust the trial UC solution to make it satisfy the
unit-wise constraints. Thirdly, a method for constructing a feasible UC
solution is proposed based on the adjusted trial UC solution. Specifically, a
feasibility-testing model and an updating strategy for the trial UC solution
are established in this part. Numerical tests are implemented on IEEE 24-bus,
IEEE 118-bus, Polish 2383-bus, and French 6468-bus systems, which verify the
effec-tiveness and efficiency of the proposed method.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Hou_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jiangwei Hou&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Zhai_Q/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Qiaozhu Zhai&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Zhou_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yuzhou Zhou&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Guan_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xiaohong Guan&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01661">
<title>Pairing optimization via statistics: Algebraic structure in pairing problems and its application to performance enhancement. (arXiv:2211.01661v1 [cs.DS])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01661</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Fully pairing all elements of a set while attempting to maximize the total
benefit is a combinatorically difficult problem. Such pairing problems
naturally appear in various situations in science, technology, economics, and
other fields. In our previous study, we proposed an efficient method to infer
the underlying compatibilities among the entities, under the constraint that
only the total compatibility is observable. Furthermore, by transforming the
pairing problem into a traveling salesman problem with a multi-layer
architecture, a pairing optimization algorithm was successfully demonstrated to
derive a high-total-compatibility pairing. However, there is substantial room
for further performance enhancement by further exploiting the underlying
mathematical properties. In this study, we prove the existence of algebraic
structures in the pairing problem. We transform the initially estimated
compatibility information into an equivalent form where the variance of the
individual compatibilities is minimized. We then demonstrate that the total
compatibility obtained when using the heuristic pairing algorithm on the
transformed problem is significantly higher compared to the previous method.
With this improved perspective on the pairing problem using fundamental
mathematical properties, we can contribute to practical applications such as
wireless communications beyond 5G, where efficient pairing is of critical
importance.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Fujita_N/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Naoki Fujita&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Rohm_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Andr&amp;#xe9; R&amp;#xf6;hm&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Mihana_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Takatomo Mihana&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Horisaki_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ryoichi Horisaki&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Li_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Aohan Li&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Hasegawa_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Mikio Hasegawa&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Naruse_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Makoto Naruse&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01676">
<title>Repeatable random permutation set. (arXiv:2211.01676v1 [cs.AI])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01676</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Based on Dempster-Shafer evidence theory (DST), random permutation set (RPS)
is proposed by replacing combinatorial number with permutation number and
therefore incorporating order information. Besides, RPS could take DST as a
special case when all items occur in the same order. However, the repetition of
items is not allowed in RPS. To address this issue, we propose repeatable
random permutation set (R2PS) which takes the repetition of items into
consideration. The right and left junctional sum combination rules are proposed
and their properties including consistency, pseudo-Matthew effect and
associativity are researched. Based on these properties, a decision support
system application is simulated to show the effectiveness of R2PS.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Yang_W/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Wenran Yang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Deng_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yong Deng&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01706">
<title>Minimum-Time Escape from a Circular Region for a Dubins Car. (arXiv:2211.01706v1 [eess.SY])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01706</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We investigate the problem of finding paths that enable a robot modeled as a
Dubins car (i.e., a constant-speed finite-turn-rate unicycle) to escape from a
circular region of space in minimum time. This minimum-time escape problem
arises in marine, aerial, and ground robotics in situations where a safety
region has been violated and must be exited before a potential negative
consequence occurs (e.g., a collision). Using the tools of nonlinear optimal
control theory, we show that a surprisingly simple closed-form feedback control
law solves this minimum-time escape problem, and that the minimum-time paths
have an elegant geometric interpretation.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/eess/1/au:+Molloy_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Timothy L. Molloy&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/eess/1/au:+Shames_I/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Iman Shames&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01720">
<title>Response Times Parametric Estimation of Real-Time Systems. (arXiv:2211.01720v1 [eess.SY])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01720</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Real-time systems are a set of programs, a scheduling policy and a system
architecture, constrained by timing requirements. Most of daily embedded
devices are real-time systems, e.g. airplanes, cars, trains, spatial probes,
etc. The time required by a program for its end-to-end execution is called its
response time. Usually, upper-bounds of response times are computed in order to
provide safe deadline miss probabilities. In this paper, we propose a suited
re-parametrization of the inverse Gaussian mixture distribution adapted to
response times of real-time systems and the estimation of deadline miss
probabilities. The parameters and their associated deadline miss probabilities
are estimated with an adapted Expectation-Maximization algorithm.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/eess/1/au:+Zagalo_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Kevin Zagalo&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/eess/1/au:+Verbytska_O/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Olena Verbytska&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/eess/1/au:+Cucu_Grosjean_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Liliana Cucu-Grosjean&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/eess/1/au:+Bar_Hen_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Avner Bar-Hen&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01793">
<title>Data-driven Abstractions for Verification of Deterministic Systems. (arXiv:2211.01793v1 [eess.SY])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01793</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;A common technique to verify complex logic specifications for dynamical
systems is the construction of symbolic abstractions: simpler, finite-state
models whose behaviour mimics the one of the systems of interest. Typically,
abstractions are constructed exploiting an accurate knowledge of the underlying
model: in real-life applications, this may be a costly assumption. By sampling
random $\ell$-step trajectories of an unknown system, we build an abstraction
based on the notion of $\ell$-completeness. We newly define the notion of
probabilistic behavioural inclusion, and provide probably approximately correct
(PAC) guarantees that this abstraction includes all behaviours of the concrete
system, for finite and infinite time horizon, leveraging the scenario theory
for non convex problems. Our method is then tested on several numerical
benchmarks.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/eess/1/au:+Coppola_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Rudi Coppola&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/eess/1/au:+Peruffo_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Andrea Peruffo&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/eess/1/au:+Mazo_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Manuel Mazo Jr&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01801">
<title>DECISIVE Test Methods Handbook: Test Methods for Evaluating sUAS in Subterranean and Constrained Indoor Environments, Version 1.1. (arXiv:2211.01801v1 [cs.RO])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01801</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;This handbook outlines all test methods developed under the Development and
Execution of Comprehensive and Integrated Subterranean Intelligent Vehicle
Evaluations (DECISIVE) project by the University of Massachusetts Lowell for
evaluating small unmanned aerial systems (sUAS) performance in subterranean and
constrained indoor environments, spanning communications, field readiness,
interface, obstacle avoidance, navigation, mapping, autonomy, trust, and
situation awareness. For sUAS deployment in subterranean and constrained indoor
environments, this puts forth two assumptions about applicable sUAS to be
evaluated using these test methods: (1) able to operate without access to GPS
signal, and (2) width from prop top to prop tip does not exceed 91 cm (36 in)
wide (i.e., can physically fit through a typical doorway, although successful
navigation through is not guaranteed). All test methods are specified using a
common format: Purpose, Summary of Test Method, Apparatus and Artifacts,
Equipment, Metrics, Procedure, and Example Data. All test methods are designed
to be run in real-world environments (e.g., MOUT sites) or using fabricated
apparatuses (e.g., test bays built from wood, or contained inside of one or
more shipping containers).
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Norton_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Adam Norton&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Ahmadzadeh_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Reza Ahmadzadeh&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Jerath_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Kshitij Jerath&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Robinette_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Paul Robinette&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Weitzen_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jay Weitzen&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Wickramarathne_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Thanuka Wickramarathne&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Yanco_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Holly Yanco&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Choi_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Minseop Choi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Donald_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ryan Donald&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Donoghue_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Brendan Donoghue&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Dumas_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Christian Dumas&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Gavriel_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Peter Gavriel&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Giedraitis_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Alden Giedraitis&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Hertel_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Brendan Hertel&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Houle_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jack Houle&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Letteri_N/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Nathan Letteri&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Meriaux_E/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Edwin Meriaux&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Rezaei_Z/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Zahra Rezaei&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Singh_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Rakshith Singh&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Willcox_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Gregg Willcox&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Yoni_N/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Naye Yoni&lt;/a&gt; (University of Massachusetts Lowell)</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01812">
<title>Benchmarking local motion planners for navigation of mobile manipulators. (arXiv:2211.01812v1 [cs.RO])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01812</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;There are various trajectory planners for mobile manipulators. It is often
challenging to compare their performance under similar circumstances due to
differences in hardware, dissimilarity of tasks and objectives, as well as
uncertainties in measurements and operating environments. In this paper, we
propose a simulation framework to evaluate the performance of the local
trajectory planners to generate smooth, and dynamically and kinematically
feasible trajectories for mobile manipulators in the same environment. We focus
on local planners as they are key components that provide smooth trajectories
while carrying a load, react to dynamic obstacles, and avoid collisions. We
evaluate two prominent local trajectory planners, Dynamic-Window Approach (DWA)
and Time Elastic Band (TEB) using the metrics that we introduce. Moreover, our
software solution is applicable to any other local planners used in the Robot
Operating System (ROS) framework, without additional programming effort.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Tafnakaji_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Sevag Tafnakaji&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Hajieghrary_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Hadi Hajieghrary&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Teixeira_Q/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Quentin Teixeira&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Bekiroglu_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yasemin Bekiroglu&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01813">
<title>Developing Modular Autonomous Capabilities for sUAS Operations. (arXiv:2211.01813v1 [cs.RO])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01813</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Small teams in the field can benefit from the capabilities provided by small
Uncrewed Aerial Systems (sUAS) for missions such as reconnaissance, hostile
attribution, remote emplacement, and search and rescue. The mobility,
communications, and flexible payload capacity of sUAS can offer teams new
levels of situational awareness and enable more highly coordinated missions
than previously possible. However, piloting such aircraft for specific missions
draws personnel away from other mission-critical tasks, increasing the load on
remaining personnel while also increasing complexity of operations. For wider
adoption and use of sUAS for security and humanitarian missions, safe and
robust autonomy must be employed to reduce this burden on small teams. In this
paper, we present the development of the Collaborative-UAS for Hostile
Attribution, Surveillance, Emplacement, and Reconnaissance (CHASER) testbed,
for rapidly prototyping capabilities that will reduce strain on small teams
through sensor-guided autonomous control. We attempt to address autonomy needs
unfilled by commercial sUAS platforms by creating and testing a series of
composable modules that can be configured to support multiple missions. Methods
implemented and presented here include radar track correlation, on-board
computer vision target detection, target position estimation, closed-loop
relative position control, and efficient search of a 3D volume for target
acquisition. We configure and test a series of these modules in an example
mission, executing a fully autonomous chase of an intruding sUAS in live
flight, and demonstrating the success of the modularized autonomy approach. We
present performance results from simulation or live flight tests for each
module. Lastly, we describe the software architecture that we have developed
for flexible controls and comment on how the capabilities presented may enable
additional missions.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Quigley_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Keegan Quigley&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Goodwin_V/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Virginia Goodwin&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Alvarez_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Luis Alvarez&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Yao_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Justin Yao&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Maclara_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yousef Salaman Maclara&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01822">
<title>Dead-zone compensation via passivity-based control for a class of mechanical systems. (arXiv:2211.01822v1 [eess.SY])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01822</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;This manuscript introduces a passivity-based control methodology for
fully-actuated mechanical systems with symmetric or asymmetric dead-zones. To
this end, we find a smooth approximation of the inverse of the function that
describes such a nonlinearity. Then, we propose an energy and damping injection
approach - based on the PI-PBC technique - that compensates for the dead-zone.
Moreover, we provide an analysis of the performance of the proposed controller
near the equilibrium. We conclude this paper by experimentally validating the
results on a two degrees-of-freedom planar manipulator.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/eess/1/au:+Chan_Zheng_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Carmen Chan-Zheng&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/eess/1/au:+Borja_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Pablo Borja&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/eess/1/au:+Scherpen_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jacquelien M.A Scherpen&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01833">
<title>Basis Function feedforward for Position-Dependent Systems. (arXiv:2211.01833v1 [eess.SY])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01833</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Feedforward for motion systems is getting increasingly more important to
achieve performance requirements. This leads to a situation where
position-dependent effects cannot be neglected anymore.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/eess/1/au:+Haren_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Max van Haren&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/eess/1/au:+Blanken_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Lennart Blanken&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/eess/1/au:+Oomen_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Tom Oomen&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01860">
<title>Learning safety in model-based Reinforcement Learning using MPC and Gaussian Processes. (arXiv:2211.01860v1 [eess.SY])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01860</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;In this work, we propose a method to encourage safety in a Model Predictive
Control (MPC)-based Reinforcement Learning (RL) agent via Gaussian Process (GP)
regression. This framework consists of 1) a parametric MPC scheme that is
employed as model-based controller with approximate knowledge on the real
system&apos;s dynamics, 2) an episodic RL algorithm tasked with adjusting the MPC
parametrization in order to increase its performance, and lastly, 3) GP
regressors used to estimate, directly from data, constraints on the MPC
parameters capable of predicting, up to some probability, whether the
parametrization is likely to yield a safe or unsafe policy. These constraints
are then enforced onto the RL updates in an effort to enhance the learning
method with a probabilistic safety mechanism. Compared to other recent
publications combining safe RL with MPC, our method does not require further
assumptions on, e.g., the prediction model in order to retain computational
tractability. We illustrate the results of our method in a numerical example on
the control of a quadrotor drone in a safety-critical environment.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/eess/1/au:+Airaldi_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Filippo Airaldi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/eess/1/au:+Schutter_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Bart De Schutter&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/eess/1/au:+Dabiri_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Azita Dabiri&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01958">
<title>An Efficient Approach with Dynamic Multi-Swarm of UAVs for Forest Firefighting. (arXiv:2211.01958v1 [cs.MA])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01958</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;In this paper, the Multi-Swarm Cooperative Information-driven search and
Divide and Conquer mitigation control (MSCIDC) approach is proposed for faster
detection and mitigation of forest fire by reducing the loss of biodiversity,
nutrients, soil moisture, and other intangible benefits. A swarm is a
cooperative group of Unmanned Aerial Vehicles (UAVs) that fly together to
search and quench the fire effectively. The multi-swarm cooperative
information-driven search uses a multi-level search comprising cooperative
information-driven exploration and exploitation for quick/accurate detection of
fire location. The search level is selected based on the thermal sensor
information about the potential fire area. The dynamicity of swarms, aided by
global regulative repulsion and merging between swarms, reduces the detection
and mitigation time compared to the existing methods. The local attraction
among the members of the swarm helps the non-detector members to reach the fire
location faster, and divide-and-conquer mitigation control ensures a
non-overlapping fire sector allocation for all members quenching the fire. The
performance of MSCIDC has been compared with different multi-UAV methods using
a simulated environment of pine forest. The performance clearly shows that
MSCIDC mitigates fire much faster than the multi-UAV methods. The Monte-Carlo
simulation results indicate that the proposed method reduces the average forest
area burnt by $65\%$ and mission time by $60\%$ compared to the best result
case of the multi-UAV approaches, guaranteeing a faster and successful mission.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+John_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Josy John&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Harikumar_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;K. Harikumar&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Senthilnath_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;J. Senthilnath&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Sundaram_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Suresh Sundaram&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2007.15390">
<title>Sampling-based 3-D Line-of-Sight PWA Model Predictive Control for Autonomous Rendezvous and Docking with a Tumbling Target. (arXiv:2007.15390v3 [eess.SY] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2007.15390</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;In this paper, a model predictive control (MPC) framework is employed to
realize autonomous rendezvous and docking (AR&amp;amp;D) with a tumbling target, using
the piecewise affine (PWA) model of the 3-D line-of-sight (LOS) dynamics and
Euler attitude dynamics. Consider the error between the predictions obtained by
the approximate linear model and the actual states of nonlinear dynamics, a
sampling-based PWA MPC is proposed to sample the predictions in the closer
neighborhood of the actual states. Besides, novel constructions of constraints
are presented to reduce the on-board computation cost and time-delay.
Furthermore, a singularity-free strategy is provided to realize crossing the
singularity of angle states smoothly. Then, the mission is achieved by
continuous 6-DOF pose (position and attitude) tracking of the target&apos;s docking
port, with the coupling between the position and attitude of the target&apos;s
docking port is taken into account. Finally, numerical results are presented to
demonstrate the above theories.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/eess/1/au:+Li_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Dongting Li&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/eess/1/au:+Dong_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Rui-Qi Dong&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/eess/1/au:+Guo_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yanning Guo&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/eess/1/au:+Ran_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Guangtao Ran&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/eess/1/au:+Li_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Dongyu Li&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2108.02003">
<title>Robust direct acoustic impedance control using two microphones for mixed feedforward-feedback controller. (arXiv:2108.02003v3 [eess.SY] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2108.02003</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;This paper presents an acoustic impedance control architecture for an
electroacoustic absorber combining both a feedforward and a feedback
microphone-based strategies on a current-driven loudspeaker. Feedforward
systems enable good performance for direct impedance control. However,
inaccuracies in the required actuator model can lead to a loss of passivity,
which can cause unstable behaviors. The feedback contribution allows the
absorber to better handle model errors and still achieve an accurate impedance,
preserving passivity. Numerical and experimental studies were conducted to
compare this new architecture against a state-of-the-art feedforward control
method.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/eess/1/au:+Volery_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Maxime Volery&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/eess/1/au:+Guo_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xinxin Guo&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/eess/1/au:+Lissek_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Herv&amp;#xe9; Lissek&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2111.03699">
<title>A space of goals: the cognitive geometry of informationally bounded agents. (arXiv:2111.03699v2 [cs.AI] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2111.03699</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Traditionally, Euclidean geometry is treated by scientists as a priori and
objective. However, when we take the position of an agent, the problem of
selecting a best route should also factor in the abilities of the agent, its
embodiment and particularly its cognitive effort. In this paper we consider
geometry in terms of travel between states within a world by incorporating
information processing costs with the appropriate spatial distances. This
induces a geometry that increasingly differs from the original geometry of the
given world as information costs become increasingly important. We visualise
this &quot;cognitive geometry&quot; by projecting it onto 2- and 3-dimensional spaces
showing distinct distortions reflecting the emergence of epistemic and
information-saving strategies as well as pivot states. The analogies between
traditional cost-based geometries and those induced by additional informational
costs invite a generalisation of the notion of geodesics as cheapest routes
towards the notion of infodesics. In this perspective, the concept of
infodesics is inspired by the property of geodesics that, travelling from a
given start location to a given goal location along a geodesic, not only the
goal, but all points along the way are visited at optimal cost from the start.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Archer_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Karen Archer&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Volpi_N/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Nicola Catenacci Volpi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Broker_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Franziska Br&amp;#xf6;ker&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Polani_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Daniel Polani&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2204.03471">
<title>DynLight: Realize dynamic phase duration with multi-level traffic signal control. (arXiv:2204.03471v3 [cs.AI] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2204.03471</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Adopting reinforcement learning (RL) for traffic signal control (TSC) is
increasingly popular, and RL has become a promising solution for traffic signal
control. However, several challenges still need to be overcome. Firstly, most
RL methods use fixed action duration and select the green phase for the next
state, which makes the phase duration less dynamic and flexible. Secondly, the
phase sequence of RL methods can be arbitrary, affecting the real-world
deployment which may require a cyclical phase structure. Lastly, the average
travel time and throughput are not fair metrics to evaluate TSC performance. To
address these challenges, we propose a multi-level traffic signal control
framework, DynLight, which uses an optimization method Max-QueueLength (M-QL)
to determine the phase and uses a deep Q-network to determine the duration of
the corresponding phase. Based on DynLight, we further propose DynLight-C which
adopts a well-trained deep Q-network of DynLight and replace M-QL with a
cyclical control policy that actuates a set of phases in fixed cyclical order
to realize cyclical phase structure. Comprehensive experiments on multiple
real-world datasets demonstrate that DynLight achieves a new state-of-the-art.
Furthermore, the deep Q-network of DynLight can learn well on determining the
phase duration and DynLight-C demonstrates high performance for deployment.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zhang_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Liang Zhang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Xie_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Shubin Xie&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Deng_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jianming Deng&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2206.07811">
<title>Safety Guarantees for Neural Network Dynamic Systems via Stochastic Barrier Functions. (arXiv:2206.07811v3 [eess.SY] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2206.07811</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Neural Networks (NNs) have been successfully employed to represent the state
evolution of complex dynamical systems. Such models, referred to as NN dynamic
models (NNDMs), use iterative noisy predictions of NN to estimate a
distribution of system trajectories over time. Despite their accuracy, safety
analysis of NNDMs is known to be a challenging problem and remains largely
unexplored. To address this issue, in this paper, we introduce a method of
providing safety guarantees for NNDMs. Our approach is based on stochastic
barrier functions, whose relation with safety are analogous to that of Lyapunov
functions with stability. We first show a method of synthesizing stochastic
barrier functions for NNDMs via a convex optimization problem, which in turn
provides a lower bound on the system&apos;s safety probability. A key step in our
method is the employment of the recent convex approximation results for NNs to
find piece-wise linear bounds, which allow the formulation of the barrier
function synthesis problem as a sum-of-squares optimization program. If the
obtained safety probability is above the desired threshold, the system is
certified. Otherwise, we introduce a method of generating controls for the
system that robustly maximizes the safety probability in a minimally-invasive
manner. We exploit the convexity property of the barrier function to formulate
the optimal control synthesis problem as a linear program. Experimental results
illustrate the efficacy of the method. Namely, they show that the method can
scale to multi-dimensional NNDMs with multiple layers and hundreds of neurons
per layer, and that the controller can significantly improve the safety
probability.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/eess/1/au:+Mazouz_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Rayan Mazouz&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/eess/1/au:+Muvvala_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Karan Muvvala&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/eess/1/au:+Ratheesh_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Akash Ratheesh&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/eess/1/au:+Laurenti_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Luca Laurenti&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/eess/1/au:+Lahijanian_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Morteza Lahijanian&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2208.10933">
<title>Large-Scale Integrated Flexible Tactile Sensor Array for Sensitive Smart Robotic Touch. (arXiv:2208.10933v2 [cond-mat.mtrl-sci] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2208.10933</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;In the long pursuit of smart robotics, it has been envisioned to empower
robots with human-like senses, especially vision and touch. While tremendous
progress has been made in image sensors and computer vision over the past
decades, the tactile sense abilities are lagging behind due to the lack of
large-scale flexible tactile sensor array with high sensitivity, high spatial
resolution, and fast response. In this work, we have demonstrated a 64x64
flexible tactile sensor array with a record-high spatial resolution of 0.9 mm
(equivalently 28.2 pixels per inch), by integrating a high-performance
piezoresistive film (PRF) with a large-area active matrix of carbon nanotube
thin-film transistors. PRF with self-formed microstructures exhibited high
pressure-sensitivity of ~385 kPa-1 for MWCNTs concentration of 6%, while the
14% one exhibited fast response time of ~3 ms, good linearity, broad detection
range beyond 1400 kPa, and excellent cyclability over 3000 cycles. Using this
fully integrated tactile sensor array, the footprint maps of an artificial
honeybee were clearly identified. Furthermore, we hardware-implemented a smart
tactile system by integrating the PRF-based sensor array with a memristor-based
computing-in-memory chip to record and recognize handwritten digits and Chinese
calligraphy, achieving high classification accuracies of 98.8% and 97.3% in
hardware, respectively. The integration of sensor networks with deep learning
hardware may enable edge or near-sensor computing with significantly reduced
power consumption and latency. Our work could pave the road to building
large-scale intelligent sensor networks for next-generation smart robotics.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Zhao_Z/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Zhenxuan Zhao&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Tang_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jianshi Tang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Yuan_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jian Yuan&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Li_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yijun Li&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Dai_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yuan Dai&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Yao_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jian Yao&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Zhang_Q/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Qingtian Zhang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Ding_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Sanchuan Ding&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Li_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Tingyu Li&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Zhang_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ruirui Zhang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Zheng_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yu Zheng&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Zhang_Z/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Zhengyou Zhang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Qiu_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Song Qiu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Li_Q/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Qingwen Li&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Gao_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Bin Gao&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Deng_N/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ning Deng&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Qian_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;He Qian&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Xing_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Fei Xing&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+You_Z/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Zheng You&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Wu_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Huaqiang Wu&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.16695">
<title>Impact of Reconfigurable Intelligent Surface Geometry on Communication Performance. (arXiv:2210.16695v2 [eess.SY] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.16695</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;When beamforming is applied at the transmitter, only part of reconfigurable
intelligent surfaces (RISs) will be active, and it becomes indispensable to
study the impact of RIS geometry. This letter aims at evaluating RIS geometry,
ranging from linear (1D), and planar (2D), to cylindrical (3D) structures. We
first derive the effective illuminated surface of different RIS topologies and
determine the resulting signal-to-noise ratio (SNR) and outage probability.
Then, we investigate the optimal RIS location to trade off active area versus
received power considering near-field propagation. Numerical results quantify
the benefit of RIS geometric compactness and provide their applicable ranges.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/eess/1/au:+Cui_Z/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Zhuangzhuang Cui&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/eess/1/au:+Pollin_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Sofie Pollin&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
</rdf:RDF>