<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:foaf="http://xmlns.com/foaf/0.1/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#" xmlns:rdfs="http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#" xmlns:schema="http://schema.org/" xmlns:sioc="http://rdfs.org/sioc/ns#" xmlns:sioct="http://rdfs.org/sioc/types#" xmlns:skos="http://www.w3.org/2004/02/skos/core#" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#" version="2.0" xml:base="https://www.sec.gov/">
  <channel>
    <title>Investor Alerts and Bulletins</title>
    <link>https://www.sec.gov/</link>
    <description>The SEC’s Office of Investor Education and Advocacy provides a variety of services and tools to address problems you may face as an investor. Investor Alerts, focused on recent investment frauds and scams, and Investor Bulletins, focused on topical issues including recent Commission actions, are provided as a service to investors. They are neither legal interpretations nor statements of SEC policy. If you have questions concerning the meaning or application of a particular law or rule, please consult with an attorney who specializes in securities law. Subscribe to get Investor Alerts and Bulletins by email.</description>
    <language>en</language>
    
    
<item>
  <title>Updated Investor Bulletin: Investing in an IPO</title>
  <link>https://www.sec.gov/oiea/investor-alerts-and-bulletins/updated-investor-bulletin-investing-ipo</link>
  <description/>
  <pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 12:10:33 -0400</pubDate>
    <dc:creator> </dc:creator>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">d311b292-605d-4c1c-aa2b-673e8fc1dbff</guid>
    </item>

<item>
  <title>Updated Investor Bulletin: Regulation Crowdfunding for Investors</title>
  <link>https://www.sec.gov/oiea/investor-alerts-bulletins/ib_crowdfunding-.html</link>
  <description>The SEC’s Office of Investor Education and Advocacy is issuing this Investor Bulletin to educate investors about a new investing   opportunity in the form of securities-based crowdfunding.</description>
  <pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 05:47:37 -0400</pubDate>
    <dc:creator> </dc:creator>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">ca0a8dc8-fdce-46de-959f-7c33b9193c4b</guid>
    </item>

<item>
  <title>Investor Resilience – World Investor Week 2022: Investor Bulletin</title>
  <link>https://www.sec.gov/oiea/investor-alerts-and-bulletins/investor-resilience-world-investor-week-2022-investor-bulletin</link>
  <description/>
  <pubDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2022 15:19:44 -0400</pubDate>
    <dc:creator> </dc:creator>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">47dcbae2-1683-4ae1-93da-5e962dcfc4b0</guid>
    </item>

<item>
  <title>Investor Bulletin: Performance Claims</title>
  <link>https://www.sec.gov/oiea/investor-alerts-bulletins/ib_performance</link>
  <description>The SEC’s Office of Investor Education and Advocacy is issuing this Investor Bulletin to educate investors about investment performance claims.  If you are in the market for an investment, you will likely come across sales and marketing materials that describe an investment’s performance.  You should know that performance information can be presented in many different ways.  Before making a decision, always make sure you understand how any performance claim is calculated and presented – and whether or not the claim is reliable and applies to your particular circumstances.  Here are a few things to consider.</description>
  <pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2022 06:18:55 -0400</pubDate>
    <dc:creator> </dc:creator>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">9b5ed946-f59b-4cb0-9ec5-8571ba253e29</guid>
    </item>

<item>
  <title>Social Media and Investment Fraud – Investor Alert</title>
  <link>https://www.sec.gov/oiea/investor-alerts-and-bulletins/social-media-and-investment-fraud-investor-alert</link>
  <description>Fraudsters often use social media to scam investors.  The SEC’s Office of Investor Education and Advocacy encourages you to be skeptical and never make investment decisions based solely on information from social media platforms or apps.</description>
  <pubDate>Mon, 29 Aug 2022 13:34:12 -0400</pubDate>
    <dc:creator> </dc:creator>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">178c524a-5a73-4d57-9710-12c2818c98fd</guid>
    </item>

<item>
  <title>Private Placements under Regulation D – Investor Bulletin</title>
  <link>https://www.sec.gov/oiea/investor-alerts-and-bulletins/private-placements-under-regulation-d-investor-bulletin</link>
  <description/>
  <pubDate>Wed, 17 Aug 2022 14:34:48 -0400</pubDate>
    <dc:creator> </dc:creator>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">66e6d76e-3582-4ae2-90ac-e222ba91ba10</guid>
    </item>

<item>
  <title>Trading Prohibitions on Foreign Companies Under the HFCAA: Investor Bulletin</title>
  <link>https://www.sec.gov/oiea/investor-alerts-and-bulletins/trading-prohibitions-foreign-companies-under-hfcaa-investor</link>
  <description/>
  <pubDate>Wed, 03 Aug 2022 10:07:00 -0400</pubDate>
    <dc:creator> </dc:creator>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">79bf520a-2afd-435f-afd8-bd22916e0cb3</guid>
    </item>

<item>
  <title>Tips for Teachers: Investing for Retirement -- Updated Investor Bulletin</title>
  <link>https://www.sec.gov/oiea/investor-alerts-and-bulletins/tips-teachers-investing-retirement-investor-bulletin</link>
  <description/>
  <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2022 09:33:20 -0400</pubDate>
    <dc:creator> </dc:creator>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">97f8e369-bf85-43fa-aae5-0b86e50e7c9a</guid>
    </item>

<item>
  <title>Broker-Dealer/Customer Arbitration: Investor Bulletin</title>
  <link>https://www.sec.gov/oiea/investor-alerts-and-bulletins/broker-dealercustomer-arbitration-investor-bulletin</link>
  <description>The SEC’s Office of Investor Education and Advocacy is issuing this Investor Bulletin to help educate investors about the arbitration and mediation processes involving a customer dispute with a broker-dealer. </description>
  <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2022 07:07:07 -0400</pubDate>
    <dc:creator> </dc:creator>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">e61c19a8-f0c6-45ad-9acc-33f42c870285</guid>
    </item>

<item>
  <title>Extended-Hours Trading: Investor Bulletin</title>
  <link>https://www.sec.gov/oiea/investor-alerts-and-bulletins/extended-hours-trading-investor-bulletin</link>
  <description>The SEC’s Office of Investor Education and Advocacy is issuing this Investor Bulletin to help educate investors about extended-hours trading for stocks. Extended-hours trading, refers to trading that occurs outside of regular trading hours. Regular trading hours for stocks traded on exchanges and certain other markets are from 9:30 a.m. to 4:00 p.m. Eastern Time. Extended-hours trading sessions may occur before or after regular trading hours. The duration of extended-hours trading sessions varies between markets and trading venues. Investors should contact their brokerage firms to determine if and when extended-hours trading sessions are available.</description>
  <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2022 14:28:48 -0400</pubDate>
    <dc:creator> </dc:creator>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">f6b96d02-5b49-4f63-8b4e-4fd81660a172</guid>
    </item>

<item>
  <title>Watch Out for Fake COVID-19 Claims When Investing -- Investor Alert</title>
  <link>https://www.sec.gov/oiea/investor-alerts-and-bulletins/watch-out-fake-covid-19-claims-when-investing-investor-alert</link>
  <description>Investors should be aware that false statements may be made -- including in company press releases, promotional materials, and social media posts -- about a company offering or developing products that prevent, detect, or treat COVID-19, in order to inflate the value of a company’s stock.  Fraudulent stock promotions of these companies also may be made through “research reports” that make predictions of a specific “target price.”  Never invest in a company based solely on information in a press release or stock promotion.  If claims about the company’s products are inaccurate or unreliable, you may lose a lot of the money you invest.</description>
  <pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2022 11:34:08 -0400</pubDate>
    <dc:creator> </dc:creator>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">a41bcd88-58f7-4f9b-a90e-e1a16de65b3f</guid>
    </item>

<item>
  <title>Investor Bulletin – Top 10 Investment Tips for College Students</title>
  <link>https://www.sec.gov/oiea/investor-alerts-and-bulletins/investor-bulletin-top-10-investment-tips-college-students</link>
  <description>One of the best ways to build wealth is by saving and investing over a long period of time. The earlier you start, the easier it is for your money to grow. Opening your first investment account is a key step in beginning your investment journey. As a college student, you may receive offers to open an investment account. These offers could come from your bank, from someone you or your family know, or even at a campus coffee shop. They also can include incentives, like free stock or cash to invest, as a way to entice you to sign up. Here are ten important investment tips from the SEC’s Office of Investor Education and Advocacy to consider when opening any investment account.</description>
  <pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2022 10:26:03 -0400</pubDate>
    <dc:creator> </dc:creator>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">2583572e-60d8-49d9-aa2a-9f9f48da3e91</guid>
    </item>

<item>
  <title>Investor Bulletin: Interested in Margin? Understand Interest.</title>
  <link>https://www.sec.gov/oiea/investor-alerts-and-bulletins/investor-bulletin-interested-margin-understand-interest</link>
  <description/>
  <pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2022 15:12:55 -0400</pubDate>
    <dc:creator> </dc:creator>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">48c01c72-06f1-4fb0-9c5f-f11d6c5b3377</guid>
    </item>

<item>
  <title>Investor Bulletin: Crypto Asset Interest-bearing Accounts</title>
  <link>https://www.sec.gov/oiea/investor-alerts-and-bulletins/investor-bulletin-crypto-asset-interest-bearing-accounts</link>
  <description/>
  <pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2022 11:07:02 -0500</pubDate>
    <dc:creator> </dc:creator>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">0a8f3826-6320-4d2e-a053-2c1cf32c161b</guid>
    </item>

<item>
  <title>Investor Bulletin: Fund Liquidation</title>
  <link>https://www.sec.gov/oiea/investor-alerts-and-bulletins/investor-bulletin-fund-liquidation</link>
  <description/>
  <pubDate>Fri, 17 Dec 2021 13:18:43 -0500</pubDate>
    <dc:creator> </dc:creator>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">e3c427dc-10b1-488c-846a-d8d675fe8b12</guid>
    </item>

<item>
  <title>Investor Bulletin: Trading Suspensions</title>
  <link>https://www.sec.gov/oiea/investor-alerts-and-bulletins/investor-bulletin-trading-suspensions</link>
  <description/>
  <pubDate>Tue, 14 Dec 2021 16:19:46 -0500</pubDate>
    <dc:creator> </dc:creator>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">f96045a8-44b0-407f-ae9a-f4113ee46e83</guid>
    </item>

<item>
  <title>Beware of Communications Falsely Appearing to Come from the SEC – Investor Alert</title>
  <link>https://www.sec.gov/oiea/investor-alerts-and-bulletins/beware-communications-falsely-appearing-come-sec-investor-alert</link>
  <description/>
  <pubDate>Fri, 19 Nov 2021 16:24:30 -0500</pubDate>
    <dc:creator> </dc:creator>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">df44d55f-c07e-4376-aef2-4f8d3e594c49</guid>
    </item>

<item>
  <title>Key Topics for World Investor Week 2021: Investor Bulletin</title>
  <link>https://www.sec.gov/oiea/investor-alerts-and-bulletins/key-topics-world-investor-week-2021-investor-bulletin</link>
  <description/>
  <pubDate>Mon, 04 Oct 2021 13:18:36 -0400</pubDate>
    <dc:creator> </dc:creator>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">ae15cb5b-fe4a-4815-a801-95bbad8c1487</guid>
    </item>

<item>
  <title>Investor Bulletin:  U.S.-Listed Companies Operating Chinese Businesses Through a VIE Structure</title>
  <link>https://www.sec.gov/oiea/investor-alerts-and-bulletins/investor-bulletin-us-listed-companies-operating-chinese</link>
  <description/>
  <pubDate>Mon, 20 Sep 2021 11:23:32 -0400</pubDate>
    <dc:creator> </dc:creator>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">8917aaee-edbc-4da4-9f4e-e5bc45636d9d</guid>
    </item>

<item>
  <title>Be on the Lookout for Investment Scams Related to Hurricane Ida</title>
  <link>https://www.sec.gov/oiea/investor-alerts-and-bulletins/be-lookout-investment-scams-related-hurricane-ida</link>
  <description/>
  <pubDate>Fri, 03 Sep 2021 09:39:42 -0400</pubDate>
    <dc:creator> </dc:creator>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">09acc5c6-e8ac-472a-94fc-c65058beda2c</guid>
    </item>

<item>
  <title>Digital Asset and “Crypto” Investment Scams – Investor Alert</title>
  <link>https://www.sec.gov/oiea/investor-alerts-and-bulletins/digital-asset-and-crypto-investment-scams-investor-alert</link>
  <description/>
  <pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2021 09:39:13 -0400</pubDate>
    <dc:creator> </dc:creator>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">6b9e92f0-5697-4417-bec3-c1ff38560c51</guid>
    </item>

<item>
  <title>Fraudsters Posing as Brokers or Investment Advisers – Investor Alert</title>
  <link>https://www.sec.gov/oiea/investor-alerts-and-bulletins/fraudsters-posing-brokers-or-investment-advisers-investor-alert</link>
  <description/>
  <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jul 2021 14:44:57 -0400</pubDate>
    <dc:creator> </dc:creator>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">92252e74-b19f-460b-89e2-e6f2c50beceb</guid>
    </item>

<item>
  <title>Funds Trading in Bitcoin Futures – Investor Bulletin</title>
  <link>https://www.sec.gov/oiea/investor-alerts-and-bulletins/ib_fundstrading</link>
  <description>The Securities and Exchange Commission’s (SEC’s) Office of Investor Education and Advocacy (OIEA) and the Commodity Futures Trading Commission’s (CFTC’s) Office of Customer Education and Outreach (OCEO) urge investors considering a fund with exposure to the Bitcoin futures market to weigh carefully the potential risks and benefits of the investment. Among other things, investors should understand that Bitcoin, including gaining exposure through the Bitcoin futures market, is a highly speculative investment. As such, investors should consider the volatility of Bitcoin and the Bitcoin futures market, as well as the lack of regulation and potential for fraud or manipulation in the underlying Bitcoin market.</description>
  <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jun 2021 17:09:21 -0400</pubDate>
    <dc:creator> </dc:creator>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">1bb76ad5-deca-4bbe-b88b-40181642480d</guid>
    </item>

<item>
  <title>Investor Bulletin: How to Open a Brokerage Account</title>
  <link>https://www.sec.gov/oiea/investor-alerts-and-bulletins/ib_openbrokerageaccount</link>
  <description>The SEC's Office of Investor Education and Advocacy is updating this Investor Bulletin to help you understand what to expect when opening a brokerage account, including what information you will need to provide, what decisions you will be asked to make, and what questions you should ask your broker.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Brokerage accounts differ from investment advisory accounts, which generally are governed by different rules and regulations.  For information on opening an advisory account, please see our bulletin: Opening an Investment Advisory Account.  For additional information on working with broker-dealers and investment advisers, please see Investor.gov’s Working with Brokers and Investment Advisers.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Before opening an account with any broker, you should always remember to read the firm’s relationship summary (Form CRS) and check the broker's background and disciplinary history. For guidance in finding a broker's background or disciplinary history, as well as other tips to consider when selecting a broker, please read our bulletin How to Select an Investment Professional.</description>
  <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jun 2021 17:00:34 -0400</pubDate>
    <dc:creator> </dc:creator>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">906c4e66-b200-4de0-8edc-ca0b36b8b2b6</guid>
    </item>

<item>
  <title>Investor Bulletin: Understanding Margin Accounts</title>
  <link>https://www.sec.gov/oiea/investor-alerts-and-bulletins/ib_marginaccount</link>
  <description>The SEC’s Office of Investor Education and Advocacy is issuing this Investor Bulletin to educate investors about the use of margin accounts to buy securities and their related risks.</description>
  <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jun 2021 16:34:58 -0400</pubDate>
    <dc:creator> </dc:creator>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">5f6c9a17-bb9d-4312-b6a1-b1b7cbc16a3b</guid>
    </item>

  </channel>
</rss>
