<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:rdau="http://rdaregistry.info/Elements/u/#" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:swpo="http://sw-portal.deri.org/ontologies/swportal#" xmlns:identifiers="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/identifiers/" xmlns:ebucore="http://www.ebu.ch/metadata/ontologies/ebucore/ebucore#">
<channel>
<title>Federal Reserve Bank of San Francisco publications</title>
<description>Economic research and commentary from Federal Reserve Bank of San Francisco</description>
<link>https://fedinprint.org/search?facets[]=provider_literal_array:Federal+Reserve+Bank+of+San+Francisco</link>
<atom:link href="https://fedinprint.org/search?facets[]=provider_literal_array:Federal+Reserve+Bank+of+San+Francisco" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2022 16:45:29 +0000</pubDate>
<item>
<title>In Conversation: Mary C. Daly with UC Berkeley’s Fisher Center for Real Estate &amp; Urban Economics</title>
<link>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedfsp/94964</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[Presentation at UC Berkeley’s Fisher Center for Real Estate & Urban Economics, Berkeley, California, October 21, 2022, by Mary C. Daly, President and Chief Executive Officer, Federal Reserve Bank of San Francisco.]]>
</description>
<guid>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedfsp/94964</guid>
<dc:creator>Daly, Mary C.</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2022-10-21</dc:date>
<dc:subject>inflation; federal reserve; Federal Open Market Committee (FOMC); dual mandate; housing markets</dc:subject>
<bibo:series>Speech</bibo:series>
</item>
<item>
<title>“Bouncing Forward” from Disasters on Hawaiʻi’s Big Island: Lessons for Equitable Recovery and Future Resilience</title>
<link>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedfcb/94939</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[Recovery planning and implementation on the island of Hawaiʻi following a federally declared disaster provides an example of equitable, forward-looking disaster preparation and resilience. Community development professionals in other geographies can learn from the way planners and nonprofits used a regional equity approach to improving household and community resilience, broke down silos to have flexible funding from multiple sources ready for future disasters, and worked to build community through “resilience hubs” that provide disaster-related and ongoing services that help promote economic participation. These efforts also provide lessons for potential future Community Reinvestment Act (CRA) activity that helps prepare communities for disasters.]]>
</description>
<guid>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedfcb/94939</guid>
<dc:creator>McElvain, Beki; Mattiuzzi, Elizabeth</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2022-10-19</dc:date>
<rdau:hasExtent>27</rdau:hasExtent>
<dc:subject>natural disasters; resilience; equity; economic participation; Hawaii</dc:subject>
<bibo:volume>2022</bibo:volume>
<bibo:issue>05</bibo:issue>
<identifiers:doi>10.24148/cdrb2022-05</identifiers:doi>
<bibo:series>Community Development Research Brief</bibo:series>
</item>
<item>
<title>Comparing Measures of Housing Inflation</title>
<link>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedfel/94921</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[Measuring the price of shelter for homeowners is difficult, even when housing markets are stable. A new measure of shelter price inflation uses mortgage, tax, and insurance payments, rather than the implied rental value of homes used in the consumer price index (CPI). The payments method suggests year-over-year shelter price inflation rose 4.3% nationally in July, compared with the CPI’s 5.8% estimate. Conditions in rental markets likely explain this difference. Comparing the varying results nationally and across regions highlights the challenge of accurately measuring the shelter inflation that homeowners face.]]>
</description>
<guid>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedfel/94921</guid>
<dc:creator>Bengali, Leila</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2022-10-17</dc:date>
<rdau:hasExtent>6</rdau:hasExtent>
<dc:subject>house prices; homeowners; consumer price index (CPI); owners’ equivalent rent</dc:subject>
<bibo:volume>2022</bibo:volume>
<bibo:issue>29</bibo:issue>
<bibo:series>FRBSF Economic Letter</bibo:series>
</item>
<item>
<title>What If? Monetary Policy in Hindsight</title>
<link>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedfel/94904</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[If the Federal Reserve had expected the upcoming inflation surge back in March 2021, would it have acted differently? A new method to tackle such “what if” questions suggests that it may have been preferable to only moderately raise the federal funds rate during 2021, even with perfect foresight. In that case, inflation would have been about 1 percentage point lower as of June 2022, while unemployment would be about 2 percentage points higher. This result reflects the importance of the Fed’s dual mandate of price stability and maximum employment.]]>
</description>
<guid>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedfel/94904</guid>
<dc:creator>Barnichon, Regis</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2022-10-11</dc:date>
<rdau:hasExtent>6</rdau:hasExtent>
<dc:subject>monetary policy; inflation; unemployment; federal funds rate</dc:subject>
<bibo:volume>2022</bibo:volume>
<bibo:issue>28</bibo:issue>
<bibo:series>FRBSF Economic Letter</bibo:series>
</item>
<item>
<title>Understanding Climate Damages: Consumption versus Investment</title>
<link>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedfwp/94890/original</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[Existing climate-economy models use aggregate damage functions to model the effects of climate change. This approach assumes climate change has equal impacts on the productivity of firms that produce consumption and investment goods or services. We show the split between damage to consumption and investment productivity matters for the dynamic consequences of climate change. Drawing on the structural transformation literature, we develop a framework that incorporates heterogeneous climate damages. When investment is more vulnerable to climate, we find short-run consumption losses will be smaller than leading models with aggregate damage functions suggest, but long-run consumption losses will be larger. We quantify these effects for the climate damage from heat stress and find that accounting for heterogeneous damages increases the welfare cost of climate change by approximately 4 to 24 percent, depending on the discount factor.]]>
</description>
<guid>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedfwp/94890/original</guid>
<dc:creator>Casey, Gregory; Fried, Stephie; Gibson, Matthew</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2022-10-04</dc:date>
<rdau:hasExtent>61</rdau:hasExtent>
<dc:subject>climate change; productivity; consumption; investments; structural changes; growth</dc:subject>
<swpo:hasNumber>2022-21</swpo:hasNumber>
<identifiers:doi>10.24148/wp2022-21</identifiers:doi>
<bibo:series>Working Paper Series</bibo:series>
</item>
<item>
<title>Projecting the Impact of Rising Temperatures: The Role of Macroeconomic Dynamics</title>
<link>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedfwp/94889/original</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[We use theory and empirics to distinguish between the impact of temperature on transition (temporary) and steady state (permanent) growth in output per capita. Standard economic theory suggests that the long-run growth rate of output per capita is determined entirely by the growth rate of total factor productivity (TFP). We find evidence suggesting that the level of temperature affects the level of TFP, but not the growth rate of TFP. This implies that a change in temperature will have a temporary, but not a permanent, impact on growth in output per capita. To highlight the quantitative importance of distinguishing between permanent and temporary changes in economic growth, we use our empirical estimates and theoretical framework to project the impacts of future increases in temperature from climate change. We find losses that are substantial, but smaller than those in the existing empirical literature that assumes a change in temperature permanently affects economic growth.]]>
</description>
<guid>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedfwp/94889/original</guid>
<dc:creator>Casey, Gregory; Fried, Stephie; Goode, Ethan</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2022-08-18</dc:date>
<rdau:hasExtent>57</rdau:hasExtent>
<dc:subject>temperature; climate; macroeconomics; growth rates</dc:subject>
<swpo:hasNumber>2022-20</swpo:hasNumber>
<identifiers:doi>10.24148/wp2022-20</identifiers:doi>
<bibo:series>Working Paper Series</bibo:series>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Singularity of the Dual Mandate</title>
<link>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedfsp/94862</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[Presentation at Boise State University, Boise, Idaho, September 29, 2022, by Mary C. Daly, President and Chief Executive Officer, Federal Reserve Bank of San Francisco.]]>
</description>
<guid>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedfsp/94862</guid>
<dc:creator>Daly, Mary C.</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2022-09-29</dc:date>
<rdau:hasExtent>11</rdau:hasExtent>
<dc:subject>dual mandate; jobs; price stability</dc:subject>
<bibo:series>Speech</bibo:series>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Singularity of the Dual Mandate</title>
<link>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedfel/94861</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[Economic security depends on both jobs and stable prices. Together, these two congressionally mandated goals constitute the Fed’s dual mandate. This mandate is not a choice between two desirable things. It is a balance meant to deliver on a singular goal—a sustainable and expanding economy that works for everyone.]]>
</description>
<guid>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedfel/94861</guid>
<dc:creator>Daly, Mary C.</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2022-10-03</dc:date>
<rdau:hasExtent>8</rdau:hasExtent>
<dc:subject>jobs; price stability; dual mandate</dc:subject>
<bibo:volume>2022</bibo:volume>
<bibo:issue>27</bibo:issue>
<bibo:series>FRBSF Economic Letter</bibo:series>
</item>
<item>
<title>Remote Work and Housing Demand</title>
<link>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedfel/94838</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[The COVID-19 pandemic reshaped the way households work. Nearly a third of employees still worked from home part time or full time as of August 2022. This has significantly increased housing demand and is a key factor explaining why U.S. house prices grew 24% between November 2019 and November 2021. Analysis shows that the shift to remote work may account for more than half of overall house price increases and similar increases in rents. This fundamental evolution in work-related housing demand may be important for future house prices.]]>
</description>
<guid>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedfel/94838</guid>
<dc:creator>Wieland, Johannes F.; Mondragon, John; Kmetz, Augustus</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2022-09-26</dc:date>
<rdau:hasExtent>5</rdau:hasExtent>
<dc:subject>covid19; remote work; house prices; housing demand</dc:subject>
<bibo:volume>2022</bibo:volume>
<bibo:issue>26</bibo:issue>
<bibo:series>FRBSF Economic Letter</bibo:series>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Impact of COVID on Productivity and Potential Output</title>
<link>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedfwp/94837/original</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[The U.S. economy came into the pandemic, and looks likely to leave it, on a slow-growth path. The near- term level of potential output has fallen because of shortfalls in labor that should reverse over time. Labor productivity, to a surprising degree, has followed an accelerated version of its Great Recession path with initially strong growth followed by weak growth. But, as of mid-2022, it appears that the overall level of labor and total factor productivity are only modestly affected. The sign of the effect depends on whether we use the strong income-side measures of pandemic output growth or the much weaker expenditure-side measures. There is considerable heterogeneity across industries. We can explain some but not all of the heterogeneity through industry differences in cyclical utilization and off-the-clock hours worked. After accounting for these factors, industries where it is easy to work from home have grown somewhat faster than they did pre-pandemic. In contrast, industries where it is hard to work from home have performed extremely poorly.]]>
</description>
<guid>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedfwp/94837/original</guid>
<dc:creator>Fernald, John G.; Li, Huiyu</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2022-09-15</dc:date>
<rdau:hasExtent>52</rdau:hasExtent>
<dc:subject>growth accounting; productivity; potential output</dc:subject>
<swpo:hasNumber>2022-19</swpo:hasNumber>
<identifiers:doi>10.24148/wp2022-19</identifiers:doi>
<bibo:series>Working Paper Series</bibo:series>
</item>
<item>
<title>Decomposing Supply and Demand Driven Inflation</title>
<link>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedfwp/94836/original</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[The extent to which either supply or demand factors drive inflation has important implications for economic policy. I propose a framework to decompose inflation into supply- and demand-driven components. I generate two new data series, the supply and demand-driven contributions to personal consumption expenditures (PCE) inflation, which quantify the degree to which either demand or supply is driving inflation in a current month. The series show expected time-series patterns. The demand-driven contribution tends to decline during recessions, while the supply-driven contribution tends to follow food and energy prices. Monetary policy tightening acts to reduce the demand-driven contribution of inflation. Oil-supply shocks act to increase the supply driven contribution, but decrease the demand-driven contribution of inflation. The decompositions can be used to test theory or by policymakers and practitioners to track inflation drivers in real time.]]>
</description>
<guid>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedfwp/94836/original</guid>
<dc:creator>Shapiro, Adam Hale</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2022-09-22</dc:date>
<rdau:hasExtent>35</rdau:hasExtent>
<dc:subject>supply and demand; inflation; decomposition</dc:subject>
<swpo:hasNumber>2022-18</swpo:hasNumber>
<identifiers:doi>10.24148/wp2022-18</identifiers:doi>
<bibo:series>Working Paper Series</bibo:series>
</item>
<item>
<title>Inflation and Wage Growth Since the Pandemic</title>
<link>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedfwp/94747/original</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[Following the worst of the COVID-19 pandemic, inflation has surged to 1980s levels in advanced economies. Motivated by vast differences in pandemic support across countries, we investigate the subsequent response of inflation and the feedback to wages. We exploit these differences to identify the effect these programs had on inflation and to examine the link between wages and inflation. Our empirical approach is based on a novel dynamic difference-in differences method based on local projections. Our estimates suggest that an increase of 5% in direct transfers (relative to trend) peaked at about an average 3 percentage points boost to the rate of inflation and wage growth after one year the support measures are introduced, with their effect waning by the second year. Moreover, since the pandemic and under a high-inflation environment, the role of inflation expectations on wage-setting dynamics have increased and become longer lasting.]]>
</description>
<guid>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedfwp/94747/original</guid>
<dc:creator>Nechio, Fernanda; Jordà, Òscar</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2022-09-06</dc:date>
<rdau:hasExtent>28</rdau:hasExtent>
<dc:subject>inflation; wages; fiscal transfers; covid19</dc:subject>
<swpo:hasNumber>2022-17</swpo:hasNumber>
<identifiers:doi>10.24148/wp2022-17</identifiers:doi>
<bibo:series>Working Paper Series</bibo:series>
</item>
<item>
<title>House Price Responses to Monetary Policy Surprises: Evidence from the U.S. Listings Data</title>
<link>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedfwp/94745/original</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[Existing literature documents that house prices respond to monetary policy surprises with a significant delay, taking years to reach their peak response. We present new evidence of a much faster response. We exploit information contained in listings for the residential properties for sale in the United States between 2001 and 2019 from the CoreLogic Multiple Listing Service Dataset. Using high-frequency measures of monetary policy shocks, we document that a one standard-deviation contractionary monetary policy surprise lowers housing list prices by 0.2–0.3 percent within two weeks—a magnitude on par with the effect on stock prices. House prices respond stronger to the surprises to future rates as compared to the surprise changes in the federal funds rate. Sale prices are mostly pre-determined by list prices and do not independently respond to monetary policy surprises.]]>
</description>
<guid>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedfwp/94745/original</guid>
<dc:creator>Gorea, Denis; Kudlyak, Marianna; Kryvtsov, Oleksiy</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2022-08-05</dc:date>
<rdau:hasExtent>36</rdau:hasExtent>
<dc:subject>house prices; monetary policy; monetary policy transmission; house sales</dc:subject>
<swpo:hasNumber>2022-16</swpo:hasNumber>
<identifiers:doi>10.24148/wp2022-16</identifiers:doi>
<bibo:series>Working Paper Series</bibo:series>
</item>
<item>
<title>Wage Growth When Inflation Is High</title>
<link>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedfel/94744</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[In a tight labor market, workers are able to respond to price increases by bargaining for higher wages. Analyzing conditions since the pandemic shows that, in the recent environment of elevated inflation and low unemployment, wages have become much more sensitive to expected price inflation than in the past. The impact of inflation expectations on wages also appears to have become longer lasting.]]>
</description>
<guid>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedfel/94744</guid>
<dc:creator>Jordà, Òscar; Rivera-Reyes, Fabián; Liu, Celeste; Nechio, Fernanda</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2022-09-06</dc:date>
<rdau:hasExtent>6</rdau:hasExtent>
<dc:subject>wage growth; price inflation; inflation expectations; unemployment; covid19</dc:subject>
<bibo:volume>2022</bibo:volume>
<bibo:issue>25</bibo:issue>
<bibo:series>FRBSF Economic Letter</bibo:series>
</item>
<item>
<title>Finding a Soft Landing along the Beveridge Curve</title>
<link>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedfer/94743</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[As U.S. economic growth slows this year, a key question is whether job openings can fall from historical highs without a substantial rise in unemployment. Analyzing the current Beveridge curve relationship between unemployment and job openings presents a meaningful possibility that labor market pressures can ease and achieve a “soft landing” with only a limited increase in unemployment. This view is supported by high rates of job matching in the U.S. labor market in 2022, despite ongoing employment reallocation across industries.]]>
</description>
<guid>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedfer/94743</guid>
<dc:creator>Petrosky-Nadeau, Nicolas; Bok, Brandyn; Yilma, Mary; Valletta, Robert G.</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2022-08-29</dc:date>
<rdau:hasExtent>6</rdau:hasExtent>
<dc:subject>economic growth; Beveridge curve; unemployment; Job openings; job matching process</dc:subject>
<bibo:volume>2022</bibo:volume>
<bibo:issue>24</bibo:issue>
<bibo:series>Economic Review</bibo:series>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Impact of Weather on Retail Sales</title>
<link>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedfel/94663</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[Variation in weather could cause greater disruptions to a range of economic outcomes as severe weather events become more frequent or more extreme. Analyzing daily sales at a national apparel and sporting goods brand’s stores reveals that weather effects on store sales are surprisingly persistent, even after accounting for shoppers simply changing when and where they make their purchases. Moreover, sales at stores that have more experience with adverse weather events have a lower response, suggesting that adaptation may reduce the negative impact of increasingly severe weather on sales.]]>
</description>
<guid>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedfel/94663</guid>
<dc:creator>Roth Tran, Brigitte</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2022-08-22</dc:date>
<rdau:hasExtent>5</rdau:hasExtent>
<dc:subject>weather; economic activity; store sales</dc:subject>
<bibo:volume>2022</bibo:volume>
<bibo:issue>23</bibo:issue>
<bibo:series>FRBSF Economic Letter</bibo:series>
</item>
<item>
<title>Two Years into COVID, What’s the State of U.S. Businesses?</title>
<link>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedfel/94631</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[More than two years after the outbreak of COVID-19, concerns remain that U.S. businesses are substantially more vulnerable and less productive than in the past. Using extensive data on private and public firms allows for a detailed assessment of these concerns. According to a number of performance measures, businesses borrowing from large U.S. banks appear relatively healthy, increased leverage is concentrated among safer companies rather than riskier ones, and probabilities of default are close to pre-crisis levels.]]>
</description>
<guid>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedfel/94631</guid>
<dc:creator>Paul, Pascal</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2022-08-15</dc:date>
<rdau:hasExtent>6</rdau:hasExtent>
<dc:subject>covid19; borrowing; leverage; default; economic conditions</dc:subject>
<bibo:volume>2022</bibo:volume>
<bibo:issue>22</bibo:issue>
<bibo:series>FRBSF Economic Letter</bibo:series>
</item>
<item>
<title>Will Workers Demand Cost-of-Living Adjustments?</title>
<link>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedfel/94630</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[Households are currently expecting inflation to run high in the short run but to remain muted over the more distant future. Given this divergence, what role do short-run and long-run household inflation expectations play in determining what workers expect for future wages? Data show that wage inflation is sensitive to movements in household short-run inflation expectations but not to those over longer horizons. This points to an upside risk for inflation, as workers negotiate higher wages that businesses could pass on to consumers by raising prices.]]>
</description>
<guid>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedfel/94630</guid>
<dc:creator>Pepper, Mollie; Leduc, Sylvain; Glick, Reuven</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2022-08-08</dc:date>
<rdau:hasExtent>6</rdau:hasExtent>
<dc:subject>inflation; inflation expectations; wages; prices; COLA; cost-of-living adjustment; pandemic; covid19</dc:subject>
<bibo:volume>2022</bibo:volume>
<bibo:issue>21</bibo:issue>
<bibo:series>FRBSF Economic Letter</bibo:series>
</item>
<item>
<title>A Sufficient Statistics Approach for Macro Policy Evaluation</title>
<link>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedfwp/94570/original</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[The evaluation of macroeconomic policy decisions has traditionally relied on the formulation of a specific economic model. In this work, we show that two statistics are sufficient to detect, often even correct, non-optimal policies, i.e., policies that do not minimize the loss function. The two sufficient statistics are (i) the effects of policy shocks on the policy objectives, and (ii) forecasts for the policy objectives conditional on the policy decision. Both statistics can be estimated without relying on a specific model. We illustrate the method by studying US monetary policy decisions.]]>
</description>
<guid>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedfwp/94570/original</guid>
<dc:creator>Mesters, Geert; Barnichon, Regis</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2022-04-27</dc:date>
<rdau:hasExtent>15</rdau:hasExtent>
<dc:subject>optimal policy; impulse responses; forecasting</dc:subject>
<swpo:hasNumber>2022</swpo:hasNumber>
<identifiers:doi>10.24148/wp2022-15</identifiers:doi>
<bibo:series>Working Paper Series</bibo:series>
</item>
<item>
<title>Evergreening</title>
<link>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedfwp/94569/original</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[We develop a simple model of relationship lending where lenders have incentives for evergreening loans by offering better terms to less productive and more indebted firms. We detect such lending behavior using loan-level supervisory data for the United States. Low-capitalized banks systematically distort firms’ risk assessments to window-dress their balance sheets. To avoid further reductions in their capital ratios, such banks extend relatively more credit to underreported borrowers. We incorporate the theoretical mechanism into a dynamic heterogeneous-firm model to show that evergreening affects aggregate outcomes, resulting in lower interest rates, higher levels of debt, and lower productivity.]]>
</description>
<guid>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedfwp/94569/original</guid>
<dc:creator>Faria-e-Castro, Miguel; Paul, Pascal; Sanchez, Juan M.</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2022-07-31</dc:date>
<rdau:hasExtent>70</rdau:hasExtent>
<dc:subject>evergreening; zombie firms; bank lending; misallocation</dc:subject>
<swpo:hasNumber>2022-14</swpo:hasNumber>
<identifiers:doi>10.24148/wp2022-14</identifiers:doi>
<bibo:series>Working Paper Series</bibo:series>
</item>
<item>
<title>COVID-19 Fiscal Expansion and Inflation Expectations in Japan</title>
<link>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedfel/94546</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[The Japanese government’s strong response to the economic fallout from COVID-19 presents an opportunity to examine whether expansionary fiscal policies raise long-term inflation expectations. Analyzing market-based estimates of long-term inflation expectations in Japan shows that announcements of government fiscal stimulus under COVID-19 had no meaningful impact on investors’ long-term inflation expectations. This illustrates the challenge of moving long-term expectations after they become anchored below a central bank’s inflation target, as they have been in Japan.]]>
</description>
<guid>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedfel/94546</guid>
<dc:creator>Spiegel, Mark M.; Christensen, Jens H. E.</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2022-08-03</dc:date>
<rdau:hasExtent>5</rdau:hasExtent>
<dc:subject>covid19; inflation expectations; fiscal expansion; Japan</dc:subject>
<bibo:volume>2022</bibo:volume>
<bibo:issue>20</bibo:issue>
<bibo:series>FRBSF Economic Letter</bibo:series>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Unequal Effect of Interest Rates by Race, Gender</title>
<link>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedfel/94539</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[Household spending typically falls as interest rates rise, but the responses vary by race and gender. Data show that households with mortgages headed by white women cut their spending on durable goods about a quarter percentage point in the three years following a 1 percentage point increase in interest rates. This is a much larger reduction than for households with mortgages headed by white men or Black men or women. The differences highlight the challenge of understanding how policy interest rate changes affect a diverse population.]]>
</description>
<guid>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedfel/94539</guid>
<dc:creator>Puig, Aina</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2022-08-01</dc:date>
<rdau:hasExtent>5</rdau:hasExtent>
<dc:subject>interest rates; race; gender; household spending; durable goods; diversity; white men; white women; black men; black women</dc:subject>
<bibo:volume>2022</bibo:volume>
<bibo:issue>19</bibo:issue>
<bibo:series>FRBSF Economic Letter</bibo:series>
</item>
<item>
<title>Dynastic Home Equity</title>
<link>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedfwp/94494/original</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[Using a nationally representative panel of consumer credit records for the US from 1999 to 2021, we document a positive correlation between child and parent homeownership. We propose a new causal mechanism behind this relationship based on parents extracting home equity to help finance their child's home purchase and quantify this mechanism in several ways. First, controlling for cohort, zip code, age, and the creditworthiness of parents and children, we find that children whose parents extract equity are 60% more likely to become a homeowner than children whose homeowner-parents do not extract equity. Second, using an event study approach, we find that the increase in child homeownership occurs almost entirely in the year when parents extract equity. Third, using variation in equity extraction induced by households near leverage constraints, we find parental equity extraction increases the child's probability of becoming a homeowner by about five times. Our results highlight the importance of familial wealth for household wealth accumulation and housing wealth in particular. A back-of-the-envelope calculation suggests that dynastic home equity increases housing wealth inequality among young adults by 20%.]]>
</description>
<guid>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedfwp/94494/original</guid>
<dc:creator>Mondragon, John; Kudlyak, Marianna; Benetton, Matteo</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2022-07-09</dc:date>
<rdau:hasExtent>57</rdau:hasExtent>
<dc:subject>home equity; intergenerational wealth; inequality; mortgages; housing; household finance</dc:subject>
<swpo:hasNumber>2022-13</swpo:hasNumber>
<identifiers:doi>10.24148/wp2022-13</identifiers:doi>
<bibo:series>Working Paper Series</bibo:series>
</item>
<item>
<title>Residential Instability in the Bay Area through the COVID-19 Pandemic</title>
<link>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedfcb/94470</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[This report draws on a unique, longitudinal dataset of over 250,000 San Francisco Bay Area residents to examine residential instability—including moving, crowding, and financial health—in the Bay Area during the pandemic. Our research finds a substantial decrease in moving during the pandemic, particularly for residents of extremely low socioeconomic status (SES). At the same time, we report a concerning rise in residents living in crowded conditions and experiencing declining credit scores. These trends suggest that COVID-19 rent relief programs and eviction moratoria may be successful in reducing displacement; however, alternative strategies may be necessary to address other forms of residential instability, like crowding, especially in Black and low-income neighborhoods. This report concludes with recommendations to address residential instability in the Bay Area.]]>
</description>
<guid>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedfcb/94470</guid>
<dc:creator>Kumar, Vasudha; Liang, Becky; Vargo, Jason; Hwang, Jackelyn</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2022-07-11</dc:date>
<rdau:hasExtent>37</rdau:hasExtent>
<dc:subject>covid19; residential instability; rent relief; eviction moratoria; Bay Area</dc:subject>
<bibo:volume>2022</bibo:volume>
<bibo:issue>04</bibo:issue>
<identifiers:doi>10.24148/cdrb2022-4</identifiers:doi>
<bibo:series>Community Development Research Brief</bibo:series>
</item>
<item>
<title>Making Sense of Negative Nominal Interest Rates</title>
<link>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedfwp/94465/original</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[Several advanced economies implemented negative nominal interest rates in the middle of the last decade, seeking to provide further monetary accommodation once cuts in positive territory had been exhausted. Negative rates affect banks in novel ways, mostly because during times of negative policy rates the interest rate that banks pay households on their deposits usually remains close to zero. In this review, we analyze the large literature that studies the impact of negative nominal interest rates, proceeding in four steps. First, we explain the theoretical channels through which negative rates affect banks. Second, we discuss the empirical findings about bank outcomes under negative rates. Third, we describe the aggregate transmission channels that influence the macroeconomic implications of a policy rate cut in negative territory. Finally, we compare the general-equilibrium models that have been used to quantify the effectiveness of negative rates and highlight why they have obtained mixed results. We conclude that, if properly implemented, negative rates are a valuable tool that central banks should not discard outright. However, negative rates can have quantifiable costs for the financial sector, and their effectiveness is likely to decline if implemented for long periods.]]>
</description>
<guid>https://fedinprint.org/item/fedfwp/94465/original</guid>
<dc:creator>Koby, Yann; Balloch, Cynthia; Ulate, Mauricio</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2022-06-23</dc:date>
<rdau:hasExtent>49</rdau:hasExtent>
<dc:subject>negative nominal interest rates; Negative Interest Rates; ZLB; ELB; Monetary Policy; Bank Profitability; Central Banking</dc:subject>
<swpo:hasNumber>2022-12</swpo:hasNumber>
<identifiers:doi>10.24148/wp2022-12</identifiers:doi>
<bibo:series>Working Paper Series</bibo:series>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>