<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<rdf:RDF
 xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
 xmlns="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/"
 xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
 xmlns:taxo="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/taxonomy/"
 xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
 xmlns:syn="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
 xmlns:admin="http://webns.net/mvcb/"
>

<channel rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/">
<title>astro-ph.CO updates on arXiv.org</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">Astrophysics -- Cosmology and Nongalactic Astrophysics (astro-ph.CO) updates on the arXiv.org e-print archive</description>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:date>2022-11-03T20:30:00-05:00</dc:date>
<dc:publisher>help@arxiv.org</dc:publisher>
<dc:subject>Astrophysics -- Cosmology and Nongalactic Astrophysics</dc:subject>
<syn:updateBase>1901-01-01T00:00+00:00</syn:updateBase>
<syn:updateFrequency>1</syn:updateFrequency>
<syn:updatePeriod>daily</syn:updatePeriod>
<items>
 <rdf:Seq>
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01382" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01393" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01402" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01405" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01493" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01523" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01546" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01652" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01728" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01729" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01744" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01854" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01901" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01935" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01949" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.02025" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.02028" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.02045" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2201.00809" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2201.09016" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2201.10480" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2203.13340" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2209.08215" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.00746" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.02431" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.14890" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.00940" />
 </rdf:Seq>
</items>
<image rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif" />
</channel>
<image rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif">
<title>arXiv.org</title>
<url>http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif</url>
<link>http://arxiv.org/</link>
</image>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01382">
<title>The Mass-Metallicity Relation of Dwarf Galaxies at the Cosmic Noon in the JWST Era. (arXiv:2211.01382v1 [astro-ph.GA])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01382</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We present the mass-metallicity relation (MZR) at $z=2-3$ in the stellar mass
range of $M_\star\approx 10^{6.5}-10^{9.5}M_\odot$ using 55 dwarf galaxies in
the Abell 2744 and SMACS J0723-3732 galaxy cluster fields. These dwarf galaxies
are identified and confirmed by deep JWST/NIRISS imaging and slitless grism
spectroscopic observations. Taking advantage of the gravitational lensing
effect, we extend the previous MZR relation at $z=2-3$ to a much lower mass
regime by more than 2.5 orders of magnitude compared with previous studies. We
find that the MZR has a shallower slope at the low-mass end
($M_\star&amp;lt;10^{9}M_\odot$) compared to that at the high-mass end
($M_\star&amp;gt;10^{9}M_\odot$), with a slope turnover point at around the stellar
mass of $10^9 M_\odot$. This implies that dominating feedback processes in
dwarf galaxies may be different from that in galaxies with higher mass. From
$z=3$ to $z=2$, the metallicity of the dwarf galaxies is enhanced by
$\approx0.1$ dex for a given stellar mass, consistent with the mild evolution
found in galaxies with higher mass. Further, we confirm the existence of a 3D
relation between the gas-phase metallicity, stellar mass, and star formation
rate, i.e., fundamental metallicity relation (FMR), in dwarf galaxies at
$z=2-3$. Our derived FMR, which has no significant redshift evolution, can be
used as a benchmark to understand the origin of the anti-correlation between
SFR and metallicity of dwarf galaxies in the high-redshift Universe.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Li_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Mingyu Li&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Cai_Z/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Zheng Cai&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Bian_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Fuyan Bian&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Lin_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xiaojing Lin&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Li_Z/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Zihao Li&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Wu_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yunjing Wu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Sun_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Fengwu Sun&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Zhang_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Shiwu Zhang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Zou_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Siwei Zou&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Fan_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xiaohui Fan&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Egami_E/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Eiichi Egami&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Charlot_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Stephane Charlot&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Bruzual_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Gustavo Bruzual&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Chevallard_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jacopo Chevallard&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01393">
<title>Exploring diffuse radio emission in galaxy clusters and groups with the uGMRT and the SKA. (arXiv:2211.01393v1 [astro-ph.CO])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01393</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Diffuse radio emission has been detected in a considerable number of galaxy
clusters and groups, revealing the presence of pervasive cosmic magnetic
fields, and of relativistic particles in the large-scale structure (LSS) of the
Universe. Since cluster radio emission is faint and steep spectrum, its
observations are largely limited by the instrument sensitivity and frequency of
observation, leading to a dearth of information, more so for lower-mass
systems. The unprecedented sensitivity of recently commissioned low-frequency
radio telescope arrays, aided by the development of advanced calibration and
imaging techniques, have helped in achieving unparalleled image quality. At the
same time, the development of sophisticated numerical simulations and the
availability of supercomputing facilities have paved the way for
high-resolution numerical modeling of radio emission, and the structure of the
cosmic magnetic fields in LSS, leading to predictions matching the capabilities
of observational facilities. In view of these rapidly-evolving scenerio in
modeling and observations, in this review, we summarise the role of the new
telescope arrays and the development of advanced imaging techniques and discuss
the detections of various kinds of cluster radio sources. In particular, we
discuss observations of the cosmic web in the form of supercluster filaments,
studies of emission in poor clusters and groups of galaxies, and of ultra-steep
spectrum sources. We also review the current theoretical understanding of
various diffuse cluster radio sources and the associated magnetic field and
polarization. As the statistics of detections improve along with our
theoretical understanding, we update the source classification schemes based on
their intrinsic properties. We conclude by summarising the role of the upgraded
GMRT and our expectations from the upcoming Square Kilometre Array (SKA)
observatories.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Paul_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Surajit Paul&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Kale_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ruta Kale&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Datta_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Abhirup Datta&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Basu_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Aritra Basu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Sur_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Sharanya Sur&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Parekh_V/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Viral Parekh&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Gupta_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Prateek Gupta&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Chatterjee_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Swarna Chatterjee&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Salunkhe_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Sameer Salunkhe&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Iqbal_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Asif Iqbal&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Pandey_Pommier_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Mamta Pandey-Pommier&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Raja_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ramij Raja&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Rahaman_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Majidul Rahaman&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Raychaudhury_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Somak Raychaudhury&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Nath_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Biman B. Nath&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Majumdar_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Subhabrata Majumdar&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01402">
<title>Flashlights: An Off-Caustic Lensed Star at Redshift $z$ = 1.26 in Abell 370. (arXiv:2211.01402v1 [astro-ph.CO])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01402</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We report the discovery of a transient seen in a strongly lensed arc at
redshift $z_{\rm s}=1.2567$ in \emph{Hubble Space Telescope} imaging of the
Abell 370 galaxy cluster. The transient is detected at $29.51\pm0.14$ AB mag in
a WFC3/UVIS F200LP difference image made using observations from two different
epochs, obtained in the framework of the \emph{Flashlights} program, and is
also visible in the F350LP band ($m_{\rm F350LP}\sim30.53$ AB). The transient
is observed on the negative-parity side of the critical curve at a distance of
$\sim 0.6&apos;&apos;$ from it, greater than previous examples of lensed stars. The large
distance from the critical curve yields a significantly smaller
macro-magnification, but our simulations show that bright, O/B-type supergiants
can reach sufficiently high magnifications to be seen at the observed position
and magnitude. In addition, the observed transient image is a trailing image
with an observer-frame time delay of $\sim+0.8$ days from its expected
counterpart, so that any transient lasting for longer than that should have
also been seen on the minima side and is thus excluded. This, together with the
blue color we measure for the transient ($m_{\rm F200LP} - m_{\rm F350LP} \sim
[-0.7,-1]$ AB mag), rules out most other transient candidates such as
(kilo)novae, for example, and makes a lensed star the prime candidate. Assuming
the transient is indeed a lensed star as suggested, many more such events
should be detected in the near future in cluster surveys with the \emph{Hubble
Space Telescope} and \emph{James Webb Space Telescope}.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Meena_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ashish Kumar Meena&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Chen_W/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Wenlei Chen&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Zitrin_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Adi Zitrin&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Kelly_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Patrick L. Kelly&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Golubchik_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Miriam Golubchik&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Zhou_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Rui Zhou&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Alfred_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Amruth Alfred&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Broadhurst_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Tom Broadhurst&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Diego_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jose M. Diego&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Oguri_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Masamune Oguri&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Williams_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Liliya L. R. Williams&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Filippenko_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Alexei V. Filippenko&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Li_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Sung Kei Li&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01405">
<title>Gravitational wave stochastic background in reduced Horndeski theories. (arXiv:2211.01405v1 [gr-qc])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01405</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We generalize to reduced Horndeski theories of gravity, where gravitational
waves (GWs) travel at the speed of light, the expression of a statistically
homogeneous and unpolarized stochastic gravitational wave background (SGWB)
signal measured as the correlation between the individual signals detected by
two interferometers in arbitrary configurations. We also discuss some results
found in the literature regarding cosmological distances in modified theories,
namely, the simultaneous validity of a duality distance relation for GW signals
and of the coincidence between the gravitational wave luminosity distance,
based on the energy flux, and the distance inferred from the wave amplitude.
This discussion allows us to conclude that the spectral energy density per unit
solid angle of an astrophysical SGWB signal has the same functional dependency
with the luminosity of each emitting source as in General Relativity (GR).
Using the generalized expression of the GW energy-momentum tensor and the
modified propagation law for the tensor modes, we conclude that the energy
density of a SGWB maintains the same functional relation with the scale factor
as in GR, provided that the modified theory coincides with GR in a given
hypersurface of constant time. However, the relation between the detected
signal and the spectral energy density is changed by the global factor
$G_4(\varphi(t_0))$, thus potentially serving as a probe for modified gravity
theories.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Lobato_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jo&amp;#xe3;o C. Lobato&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Matos_I/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Isabela S. Matos&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Calvao_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Maur&amp;#xed;cio O. Calv&amp;#xe3;o&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Waga_I/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ioav Waga&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01493">
<title>Magnetic fields and relativistic electrons fill entire galaxy cluster. (arXiv:2211.01493v1 [astro-ph.CO])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01493</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The hot plasma within merging galaxy clusters is predicted to be filled with
shocks and turbulence that may convert part of their kinetic energy into
relativistic electrons and magnetic fields generating synchrotron radiation.
Analyzing Low Frequency Array (LOFAR) observations of the galaxy cluster Abell
2255, we show evidence of radio synchrotron emission distributed over very
large scales of at least 5 megaparsec. The pervasive radio emission witnesses
that shocks and turbulence efficiently transfer kinetic energy into
relativistic particles and magnetic fields in a region that extends up to the
cluster outskirts. The strength of the emission requires a magnetic field
energy density at least 100 times higher than expected from a simple
compression of primordial fields, presumably implying that dynamo operates
efficiently also in the cluster periphery. It also suggests that nonthermal
components may contribute substantially to the pressure of the intracluster
medium in the cluster periphery.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Botteon_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;A. Botteon&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Weeren_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;R. J. van Weeren&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Brunetti_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;G. Brunetti&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Vazza_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;F. Vazza&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Shimwell_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;T. W. Shimwell&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Bruggen_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;M. Br&amp;#xfc;ggen&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Rottgering_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;H. J. A. R&amp;#xf6;ttgering&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Gasperin_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;F. de Gasperin&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Akamatsu_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;H. Akamatsu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Bonafede_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;A. Bonafede&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Cassano_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;R. Cassano&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Cuciti_V/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;V. Cuciti&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Dallacasa_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;D. Dallacasa&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Gennaro_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;G. Di Gennaro&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Gastaldello_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;F. Gastaldello&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01523">
<title>A weak lensing perspective on nonlinear structure formation with fuzzy dark matter. (arXiv:2211.01523v1 [astro-ph.CO])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01523</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We investigate nonlinear structure formation in the fuzzy dark matter (FDM)
model in comparison to cold dark matter (CDM) models from a weak lensing
perspective using perturbative methods. We use Eulerian perturbation theory up
to fourth order to compute the tree-level matter trispectrum and the one-loop
matter spectrum and bispectrum from consistently chosen initial conditions. We
go on to derive the respective lensing spectra, bispectra and trispectra in CDM
and FDM in the context of a Euclid-like weak lensing survey. Finally, we
compute the attainable cumulative signal-to-noise ratios and an estimate of the
attainable $\chi^2$-functionals for distinguishing FDM from CDM at particle
masses $m=10^{-21}$ eV, $m = 10^{-22}$ eV and $m = 10^{-23}$ eV. We find that a
weak lensing survey can potentially be used to distinguish between the FDM and
CDM cases up to a mass of $m = 10^{-22}$ eV.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Kunkel_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Alexander Kunkel&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Chiueh_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Tzihong Chiueh&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Schafer_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Bj&amp;#xf6;rn Malte Sch&amp;#xe4;fer&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01546">
<title>On the superstring-inspired quantum correction to the Starobinsky model of inflation. (arXiv:2211.01546v1 [gr-qc])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01546</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Superstring/M-theory is the theory of quantum gravity that can provide the
UV-completion to viable inflation models. We modify the Starobinsky inflation
model by adding the Bel-Robinson tensor $T^{\mu\nu\lambda\rho}$ squared term
proposed as the leading quantum correction inspired by superstring theory. The
$(R+\frac{1}{6m^2}R^2 -\frac{\beta}{8m^6}T^2)$ model under consideration has
two parameters: the inflaton mass $m$ and the string-inspired positive
parameter $\beta$. We derive the equations of motion in the
Friedmann-Lemaitre-Robertson-Walker universe and investigate its solutions. We
find the physical bounds on the value of the parameter $\beta$ by demanding the
absence of ghosts and consistency of the derived inflationary observables with
the measurements of the cosmic microwave background radiation.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Ketov_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Sergei V. Ketov&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Pozdeeva_E/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ekaterina O. Pozdeeva&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Vernov_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Sergey Yu. Vernov&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01652">
<title>Viscous attenuation of gravitational waves propagating through an inhomogeneous background. (arXiv:2211.01652v1 [gr-qc])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01652</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We consider the propagation of gravitational waves in the late-time Universe,
in the presence of structure, and we also consider the cosmic fluid to be
viscous. In this work, we investigate the cumulative effect of inhomogeneities
and viscosity of the cosmic-fluid, on the observables associated with the
sources of the gravitational waves. Employing Buchert&apos;s averaging procedure in
the backreaction framework, we consider a model of inhomogeneous spacetime.
Using the modified redshift versus distance relation, through the averaging
process in the context of the model, we study the variation of the
redshift-dependent part of the observed gravitational wave amplitude for
different combinations of our model parameters, while simultaneously
considering damping of the gravitational wave amplitude due to viscosity of the
cosmic-fluid. Then, we investigate the differences occurring in the variation
of the redshift-dependent part of the observed gravitational wave amplitude,
due to consideration of viscous attenuation. We show that there are significant
deviations after the inclusion of viscous attenuation in our analysis,
depending on the chosen value of the coefficient of viscosity. Our result
signifies the importance of the effect of viscosity, within the model of an
inhomogeneous Universe, on precision measurements of parameters of
compact-binary sources of gravitational waves.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Pandey_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Shashank Shekhar Pandey&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Sarkar_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Arnab Sarkar&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Ali_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Amna Ali&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Majumdar_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;A. S. Majumdar&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01728">
<title>Primordial non-gaussianity up to all orders: theoretical aspects and implications for primordial black hole models. (arXiv:2211.01728v1 [astro-ph.CO])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01728</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We develop an exact formalism for the computation of the abundance of
primordial black holes (PBHs) in the presence of local non-gaussianity (NG) in
the curvature perturbation field. For the first time, we include NG going
beyond the widely used quadratic and cubic approximations, and consider a
completely generic functional form. Adopting threshold statistics of the
compaction function, we address the computation of the abundance both for
narrow and broad power spectra. While our formulas are generic, we discuss
explicit examples of phenomenological relevance considering the physics case of
the curvaton field. We carefully assess under which conditions the conventional
perturbative approach can be trusted. In the case of a narrow power spectrum,
this happens only if the perturbative expansion is pushed beyond the quadratic
order (with the optimal order of truncation that depends on the width of the
spectrum). Most importantly, we demonstrate that the perturbative approach is
intrinsically flawed when considering broad spectra, in which case only the
non-perturbative computation captures the correct result. Finally, we describe
the phenomenological relevance of our results for the connection between the
abundance of PBHs and the stochastic gravitational wave (GW) background related
to their formation. As NGs modify the amplitude of perturbations necessary to
produce a given PBHs abundance and boost PBHs production at large scales for
broad spectra, modelling these effects is crucial to connect the PBH scenario
to its signatures at current and future GWs experiments.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Ferrante_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Giacomo Ferrante&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Franciolini_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Gabriele Franciolini&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Iovino_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Antonio Junior Iovino&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Urbano_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Alfredo Urbano&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01729">
<title>A seesaw model for large neutrino masses in concordance with cosmology. (arXiv:2211.01729v1 [hep-ph])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01729</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Cosmological constraints on the sum of the neutrino masses can be relaxed if
the number density of active neutrinos is reduced compared to the standard
scenario, while at the same time keeping the effective number of neutrino
species $N_{\rm eff}\approx 3$ by introducing a new component of dark
radiation. We discuss a UV complete model to realise this idea, which
simultaneously provides neutrino masses via the seesaw mechanism. It is based
on a $U(1)$ symmetry in the dark sector, which can be either gauged or global.
In addition to heavy seesaw neutrinos, we need to introduce $\mathcal{O}(10)$
generations of massless sterile neutrinos providing the dark radiation. Then we
can accommodate active neutrino masses with $\sum m_\nu \sim 1$ eV, in the
sensitivity range of the KATRIN experiment. We discuss the phenomenology of the
model and identify the allowed parameter space. We argue that the gauged
version of the model is preferred, and in this case the typical energy scale of
the model is in the 10 MeV to few GeV range.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Escudero_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Miguel Escudero&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Schwetz_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Thomas Schwetz&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Terol_Calvo_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jorge Terol-Calvo&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01744">
<title>The galaxy formation origin of the lensing is low problem. (arXiv:2211.01744v1 [astro-ph.CO])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01744</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;It is now well-established that $\Lambda$CDM predictions overestimate
gravitational lensing measurements around massive galaxies by about 30%, the
so-called lensing is low problem. Using a state-of-the-art hydrodynamical
simulation, we show that this discrepancy reflects shortcomings in standard
structure formation models rather than tensions within the $\Lambda$CDM
paradigm itself. Specifically, this problem results from ignoring a variety of
galaxy formation effects in simple models, including assembly bias, segregation
of satellite galaxies relative to dark matter, and baryonic effects on the
matter distribution. Each of these contributes towards overestimating
gravitational lensing and, when combined, these explain the amplitude and scale
dependence of the lensing is low problem. We conclude that simplistic structure
formation models are inadequate to interpret lensing and clustering together,
and that it is crucial to employ more sophisticated models for the upcoming
generation of large-scale surveys.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Chaves_Montero_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jonas Chaves-Montero&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Angulo_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Raul E. Angulo&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Contreras_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Sergio Contreras&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01854">
<title>Ultralight dark matter searches at the sub-Hz frontier with atom multi-gradiometry. (arXiv:2211.01854v1 [hep-ph])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01854</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Single-photon atom gradiometry is a powerful experimental technique that can
be employed to search for the oscillation of atomic transition energies induced
by ultralight scalar dark matter (ULDM). In the sub-Hz regime the background is
expected to be dominated by gravity gradient noise (GGN), which arises as a
result of mass fluctuations around the experiment. In this work we model the
GGN as surface Rayleigh waves and construct a likelihood-based analysis that
consistently folds GGN into the sensitivity estimates of vertical atom
gradiometers in the frequency window between 1 mHz and 1 Hz. We show that in
certain geological settings GGN can be significantly mitigated when operating a
multi-gradiometer configuration, which consists of three or more atom
interferometers in the same baseline. Multi-gradiometer experiments, such as
future versions of AION and MAGIS-100, have the potential to probe regions of
scalar ULDM parameter space in the sub-Hz regime that have not been excluded by
existing experiments.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Badurina_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Leonardo Badurina&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Gibson_V/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Valerie Gibson&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+McCabe_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Christopher McCabe&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Mitchell_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jeremiah Mitchell&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01901">
<title>Augmenting photometric redshift estimates using spectroscopic nearest neighbours. (arXiv:2211.01901v1 [astro-ph.CO])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01901</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;As a consequence of galaxy clustering, close galaxies observed on the plane
of the sky should be spatially correlated with a probability inversely
proportional to their angular separation. In principle, this information can be
used to improve photometric redshift estimates when spectroscopic redshifts are
available for some of the neighbouring objects. Depending on the depth of the
survey, however, such angular correlation is reduced by chance projections. In
this work, we implement a deep learning model to distinguish between apparent
and real angular neighbours by solving a classification task. We adopt a graph
neural network architecture to tie together the photometry, the spectroscopy
and the spatial information between neighbouring galaxies. We train and
validate the algorithm on the data of the VIPERS galaxy survey, for which
SED-fitting based photometric redshifts are also available. The model yields a
confidence level for a pair of galaxies to be real angular neighbours, enabling
us to disentangle chance superpositions in a probabilistic way. When objects
for which no physical companion can be identified are excluded, all photometric
redshifts&apos; quality metrics improve significantly, confirming that their
estimates were of lower quality. For our typical test configuration, the
algorithm identifies a subset containing ~75% of high-quality photometric
redshifts, for which the dispersion is reduced by as much as 50% (from 0.08 to
0.04), while the fraction of outliers reduces from 3% to 0.8%. Moreover, we
show that the spectroscopic redshift of the angular neighbour with the highest
detection probability provides an excellent estimate of the redshift of the
target galaxy, comparable or even better than the corresponding template
fitting estimate.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Tosone_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;F. Tosone&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Cagliari_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;M.S. Cagliari&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Guzzo_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;L. Guzzo&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Granett_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;B.R. Granett&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Crespi_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;A. Crespi&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01935">
<title>Discovering a new well: Decaying dark matter with profile likelihoods. (arXiv:2211.01935v1 [astro-ph.CO])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01935</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;A large number of studies, all using Bayesian parameter inference from Markov
Chain Monte Carlo methods, have constrained the presence of a decaying dark
matter component. All such studies find a strong preference for either very
long-lived or very short-lived dark matter. However, in this letter, we
demonstrate that this preference is due to parameter volume effects that drive
the model towards the standard $\Lambda$CDM model, which is known to provide a
good fit to most observational data.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using profile likelihoods, which are free from volume effects, we instead
find that the best-fitting parameters are associated with an intermediate
regime where around $3 \%$ of cold dark matter decays just prior to
recombination. With two additional parameters, the model yields an overall
preference over the $\Lambda$CDM model of $\Delta \chi^2 \approx -2.8$ with
\textit{Planck} and BAO and $\Delta \chi^2 \approx -7.8$ with the SH0ES $H_0$
measurement, while only slightly alleviating the $H_0$ tension. Ultimately, our
results reveal that decaying dark matter is more viable than previously
assumed, and illustrate the dangers of relying exclusively on Bayesian
parameter inference when analysing extensions to the $\Lambda$CDM model.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Holm_E/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Emil Brinch Holm&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Herold_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Laura Herold&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Hannestad_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Steen Hannestad&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Nygaard_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Andreas Nygaard&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Tram_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Thomas Tram&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01949">
<title>Impact of multiple modes on the evolution of self-interacting axion condensate around rotating black holes. (arXiv:2211.01949v1 [gr-qc])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01949</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Ultra-light particles, such as axions, form a macroscopic condensate around a
highly spinning black hole by the superradiant instability. Due to its
macroscopic nature, the condensate opens the possibility of detecting the axion
through gravitational wave observations. However, the precise evolution of the
condensate must be known for the actual detection. For future observation, we
numerically study the influence of the self-interaction, especially interaction
between different modes, on the evolution of the condensate in detail. First,
we focus on the case when condensate starts with the smallest possible angular
quantum number. For this case, we perform the non-linear calculation and show
that the dissipation induced by the mode interaction is strong enough to
saturate the superradiant instability, even if the secondary cloud starts with
quantum fluctuations. Our result indicates that explosive phenomena such as
bosenova do not occur in this case. We also show that the condensate settles to
a quasi-stationary state mainly composed of two modes, one with the smallest
angular quantum number for which the superradiant instability occurs and the
other with the adjacent higher angular quantum number. We also study the case
when the condensate starts with the dominance of the higher angular quantum
number. We show that the dissipation process induced by the mode coupling does
not occur for small gravitational coupling. Therefore, bosenova might occur in
this case.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Omiya_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Hidetoshi Omiya&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Takahashi_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Takuya Takahashi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Tanaka_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Takahiro Tanaka&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Yoshino_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Hirotaka Yoshino&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.02025">
<title>The quantum character of the Scalar Field Dark Matter. (arXiv:2211.02025v1 [astro-ph.CO])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.02025</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The Scalar Field Dark Matter (SFDM) model, also called Fuzzy, Wave,
Bose-Einstein, Ultra-light Dark Matter, has received a lot of attention because
it has been able to provide simpler and more natural explanations for various
features of galaxies, such as the number of satellite galaxies and the
cusp-core problem. We recently showed that this model is able to explain the
vast polar orbits of satellite galaxies around their host, the so-called VPO,
and to explain the X-ray and gamma-ray emissions in the vacuum regions of our
galaxy, that is, the Fermi Bubbles. In all these phenomena the quantum
character of SFDM has been crucial. In this work we study the quantum effects
of SFDM at the cosmological level, to see these effects not only at the
galactic scale, but also at the cosmological scale. Using a convenient ansatz,
we were able to integrate the perturbed equations to show that the shape of the
SFDM halos resembling atoms is a generic result. The main conclusion of this
work is that quantum mechanics, the successful microworld theory, could also
explain the dark side of the cosmos.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Matos_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Tonatiuh Matos&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.02028">
<title>Neutrino Origin of LHAASO&apos;s 18 TeV GRB221009A Photon. (arXiv:2211.02028v1 [hep-ph])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.02028</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;LHAASO collaboration detected photons with energy above 10 TeV from the most
recent gamma-ray burst (GRB), GRB221009A. Given the redshift of this event,
$z\sim 0.15$, photons of such energy are expected to interact with the diffuse
extragalactic background light (EBL) well before reaching Earth. In this paper
we provide the first neutrino-related explanation of the most energetic 18 TeV
event reported by LHAASO. We find that the minimal viable scenario involves
both mixing and transition magnetic moment portal between light and sterile
neutrinos. The production of sterile neutrinos occurs efficiently via mixing
while the transition magnetic moment portal governs the decay rate in the
parameter space where tree-level decays via mixing to non-photon final states
are suppressed. Our explanation of this event, while being consistent with the
terrestrial constraints, points to the non-standard cosmology.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Brdar_V/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Vedran Brdar&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Li_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ying-Ying Li&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.02045">
<title>Fast and robust Bayesian Inference using Gaussian Processes with GPry. (arXiv:2211.02045v1 [astro-ph.CO])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.02045</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We present the GPry algorithm for fast Bayesian inference of general
(non-Gaussian) posteriors with a moderate number of parameters. GPry does not
need any pre-training, special hardware such as GPUs, and is intended as a
drop-in replacement for traditional Monte Carlo methods for Bayesian inference.
Our algorithm is based on generating a Gaussian Process surrogate model of the
log-posterior, aided by a Support Vector Machine classifier that excludes
extreme or non-finite values. An active learning scheme allows us to reduce the
number of required posterior evaluations by two orders of magnitude compared to
traditional Monte Carlo inference. Our algorithm allows for parallel
evaluations of the posterior at optimal locations, further reducing wall-clock
times. We significantly improve performance using properties of the posterior
in our active learning scheme and for the definition of the GP prior. In
particular we account for the expected dynamical range of the posterior in
different dimensionalities. We test our model against a number of synthetic and
cosmological examples. GPry outperforms traditional Monte Carlo methods when
the evaluation time of the likelihood (or the calculation of theoretical
observables) is of the order of seconds; for evaluation times of over a minute
it can perform inference in days that would take months using traditional
methods. GPry is distributed as an open source Python package (pip install
gpry) and can also be found at https://github.com/jonaselgammal/GPry.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Gammal_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jonas El Gammal&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Schoneberg_N/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Nils Sch&amp;#xf6;neberg&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Torrado_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jes&amp;#xfa;s Torrado&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Fidler_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Christian Fidler&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2201.00809">
<title>A Wheeler-DeWitt Equation with Time. (arXiv:2201.00809v4 [gr-qc] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2201.00809</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The equation for canonical gravity produced by Wheeler and DeWitt in the late
1960s still presents difficulties both in terms of its mathematical solution
and its physical interpretation. One of these issues is, notoriously, the
absence of an explicit time. In this short note, we suggest one simple and
straightforward way to avoid this occurrence. We go back to the classical
equation that inspired Wheeler and DeWitt (namely, the
Hamilton--Jacobi--Einstein equation) and make explicit, before quantization,
the presence of a known, classically meaningful notion of time. We do this by
allowing Hamilton&apos;s principal function to be explicitly dependent on this time
locally. This choice results in a Wheeler--DeWitt equation with time. A working
solution for the de Sitter minisuperspace is shown.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Rotondo_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Marcello Rotondo&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2201.09016">
<title>A minimal self tuning model to solve the cosmological constant problem. (arXiv:2201.09016v2 [astro-ph.CO] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2201.09016</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The expansion of the Universe is observed to be accelerating, with the
simplest solution being a classical cosmological constant. However, this
receives contributions from the quantum vacuum, which are predicted to be many
orders of magnitude larger than observations, and suffers from radiative
instabilities requiring repeated fine tuning. In this paper we present a
minimal, self tuning scalar field model that can dynamically cancel a large
quantum vacuum energy, avoiding Weinberg&apos;s No Go Theorem, and produce
accelerated de Sitter expansion at a lower energy scale as a solution to the
problem. Our minimal model, which contains a non canonical kinetic energy and a
linear potential, belongs to the Kinetic Gravity Braiding subclass of Horndeski
theory which is not observationally excluded, and lies outside of the known Fab
Four or Well Tempered models. We find analytic solutions in the limits of slow
roll and fast roll, and numerically solve the equations of motion to illustrate
our model. We show that the model allows for a matter dominated era, and that
the attractor solution is stable under a phase transition in the vacuum energy
density. We also consider the energy scales required to match observations. Our
model shows the existence of a wider class of successful self tuning models
than previously assumed.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Khan_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Arnaz Khan&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Taylor_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Andy Taylor&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2201.10480">
<title>Galaxy and Mass Assembly (GAMA): Mid-infrared properties as tracers of galaxy environment. (arXiv:2201.10480v2 [astro-ph.GA] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2201.10480</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We investigate how different mid-infrared (mid-IR) properties of galaxies
trace the environment in which the galaxies are located. For this purpose, we
first study the dependence of galaxy clustering on the absolute magnitude at
3.4 $\mu$m and redshift. Then, we look into the environmental dependence of
mid-IR luminosities and the galaxy properties derived from these luminosities.
We also explore how various infrared galaxy luminosity selections influence the
galaxy clustering measurements. We use a set of W1 (3.4 $\mu$m) absolute
magnitude ($M_\text{W1}$) selected samples from the Galaxy and Mass Assembly
(GAMA) survey matched with mid-IR properties from the Wide-field Infrared
Survey Explorer (WISE) in the redshift range $0.07 \leq z &amp;lt; 0.43$. We compute
the galaxy two-point correlation function (2pCF) and compare the clustering
lengths between subsamples binned in $M_\text{W1}$ and in redshift. We also
measure the marked correlation functions (MCFs) using the luminosities in the
WISE W1 to W4 (3.4 to 22 $\mu$m) bands as marks. Additionally, we compare the
measurements of MCFs with different estimates of stellar mass and star
formation rate used as marks. Finally, we check how different selections
applied to the sample affect the clustering measurements. We show strong
clustering dependence on the W1 absolute magnitude: galaxies brighter in the W1
band are more strongly clustered than their fainter counterparts. We also
observe a lack of significant redshift dependence of clustering in the redshift
range $0.07 \leq z &amp;lt; 0.43$. We show that although W1 and W2 bands are direct
indicators of stellar mass, a galaxy sample selected based on W1 or W2 bands
does not perfectly show the clustering behaviour of a stellar mass selected
sample. Similar is the case with the proxy relation between W3 and W4 bands and
star formation rate.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Sureshkumar_U/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;U. Sureshkumar&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Durkalec_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;A. Durkalec&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Pollo_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;A. Pollo&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Bilicki_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;M. Bilicki&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Cluver_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;M. E. Cluver&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Bellstedt_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;S. Bellstedt&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Farrow_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;D. J. Farrow&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Loveday_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;J. Loveday&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Taylor_E/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;E. N. Taylor&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Bland_Hawthorn_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;J. Bland-Hawthorn&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2203.13340">
<title>Heating of the intracluster medium by buoyant bubbles and sound waves. (arXiv:2203.13340v2 [astro-ph.CO] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2203.13340</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Active galactic nuclei (AGN) powered by the central Super-Massive Black Holes
(SMBHs) play a major role in modifying the thermal properties of the
intracluster medium (ICM). In this work, we implement two AGN heating models:
(i) by buoyant cavities rising through stratified ICM (effervescent model) and,
(ii) by viscous and conductive dissipation of sound waves (acoustic model). Our
aim is to determine whether these heating models are consistent with ICM
observables and if one is preferred over the other. We assume an initial
entropy profile of ICM that is expected from the purely gravitational infall of
the gas in the potential of the dark matter halo. We then incorporate heating,
radiative cooling, and thermal conduction to study the evolution of ICM over
the age of the clusters. Our results are: (i) Both the heating processes can
produce comparable thermal profiles of the ICM with some tuning of relevant
parameters. (ii) Thermal conduction is crucially important, even at the level
of 10\% of the Spitzer values, in transferring the injected energy beyond the
central regions, and without which the temperature/entropy profiles are
unrealistically high. (iii) The required injected AGN power scales with cluster
mass as $M_{\rm vir}^{1.5}$ for both models. (iv) The required AGN luminosity
is comparable with the observed radio jet power, reinforcing the idea that AGNs
are the dominant heating source in clusters. (v) Finally, we estimate that the
fraction of the total AGN luminosity available as the AGN mechanical luminosity
at $0.02r_{500}$ is less than 0.05\%.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Iqbal_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Asif Iqbal&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Majumdar_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Subhabrata Majumdar&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Nath_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Biman B. Nath&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Roychowdhury_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Suparna Roychowdhury&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2209.08215">
<title>Report of the Topical Group on Cosmic Probes of Dark Matter for Snowmass 2021. (arXiv:2209.08215v2 [hep-ph] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2209.08215</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Cosmological and astrophysical observations currently provide the the only
robust, positive evidence for dark matter. Cosmic probes of dark matter, which
seek to determine the fundamental properties of dark matter through
observations of the cosmos, have emerged as a promising means to reveal the
nature of dark matter. This report summarizes the current status and future
potential of cosmic probes to inform our understanding of the fundamental
nature of dark matter in the coming decade.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Drlica_Wagner_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Alex Drlica-Wagner&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Prescod_Weinstein_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Chanda Prescod-Weinstein&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Yu_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Hai-Bo Yu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Albert_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Andrea Albert&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Banerjee_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Arka Banerjee&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Baryakhtar_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Masha Baryakhtar&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Bechtol_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Keith Bechtol&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Bird_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Simeon Bird&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Birrer_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Simon Birrer&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Bringmann_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Torsten Bringmann&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Caputo_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Regina Caputo&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Chakrabarti_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Sukanya Chakrabarti&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Chen_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Thomas Y. Chen&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Croon_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Djuna Croon&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Cyr_Racine_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Francis-Yan Cyr-Racine&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Dawson_W/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;William A. Dawson&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Dvorkin_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Cora Dvorkin&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Gluscevic_V/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Vera Gluscevic&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Gilman_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Daniel Gilman&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Grin_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Daniel Grin&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Hlozek_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ren&amp;#xe9;e Hlo&amp;#x17e;ek&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Leane_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Rebecca K. Leane&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Li_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ting S. Li&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Mao_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yao-Yuan Mao&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Meyers_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Joel Meyers&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Mishra_Sharma_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Siddharth Mishra-Sharma&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Munoz_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Julian B. Mu&amp;#xf1;oz&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Munshi_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ferah Munshi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Nadler_E/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ethan O. Nadler&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Parikh_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Aditya Parikh&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Perez_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Kerstin Perez&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Peter_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Annika H. G. Peter&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Profumo_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Stefano Profumo&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Schutz_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Katelin Schutz&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Sehgal_N/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Neelima Sehgal&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Simon_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Joshua D. Simon&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Sinha_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Kuver Sinha&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Valluri_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Monica Valluri&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Wechsler_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Risa H. Wechsler&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.00746">
<title>Constraints on Cosmological Parameters with a Sample of Type Ia Supernovae from JWST. (arXiv:2210.00746v2 [astro-ph.CO] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.00746</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We investigate the potential of using a sample of very high-redshift
($2\lesssim z \lesssim6$) (VHZ) Type Ia supernovae (SNe~Ia) attainable by the
James Webb Space Telescope (JWST) on constraining cosmological parameters. At
such high redshifts, the age of the universe is young enough that the VHZ SNIa
sample comprises the very first SNe~Ia of the universe, with progenitors among
the very first generation of low mass stars that the universe has made. We show
that the VHZ SNe~Ia can be used to disentangle systematic effects due to the
luminosity distance evolution with redshifts intrinsic to SNIa standardization.
Assuming that the systematic evolution can be described by a linear or
logarithmic formula, we found that the coefficients of this dependence can be
determined accurately and decoupled from cosmological models. Systematic
evolution as large as 0.15 mag and 0.45 mag out to $z=5$ can be robustly
separated from popular cosmological models for the linear and logarithmic
evolution, respectively. The VHZ SNe~Ia will lay the foundation for quantifying
the systematic redshift evolution of SNIa luminosity distance scales. When
combined with SNIa surveys at comparatively lower redshifts, the VHZ SNe~Ia
allow for a precise measurement of the history of the expansion of the universe
from $z\sim 0$ to the epoch approaching reionization.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Lu_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jia Lu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Wang_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Lifan Wang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Chen_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xingzhuo Chen&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Rubin_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;David Rubin&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Perlmutter_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Saul Perlmutter&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Baade_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Dietrich Baade&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Mould_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jeremy Mould&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Vinko_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jozsef Vinko&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Regos_E/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Eniko Regos&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Koekemoer_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Anton M. Koekemoer&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.02431">
<title>Black hole thermodynamics from logotropic fluids. (arXiv:2210.02431v2 [gr-qc] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.02431</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We show that Einstein&apos;s field equations with a negative cosmological constant
can admit black hole solutions whose thermodynamics coincides with that of
logotropic fluids, recently investigated to heal some cosmological and
astrophysical issues. For this purpose, we adopt the Anton-Schmidt equation of
state, which represents a generalized version of logotropic fluids. We thus
propose a general treatment to obtain an asymptotic anti-de Sitter metric,
reproducing the thermodynamic properties of both Anton-Schmidt and logotropic
fluids. Hence, we explore how to construct suitable spacetime functions,
invoking an event horizon and fulfilling the null, weak, strong and dominant
energy conditions. We further relax the strong energy condition to search for
possible additional solutions. Finally, we discuss the optical properties
related to a specific class of metrics and show how to construct an effective
refractive index depending on the spacetime functions and the thermodynamic
quantities of the fluid under study. We also explore possible departures with
respect to the case without the fluid.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Capozziello_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Salvatore Capozziello&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+DAgostino_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Rocco D&amp;#x27;Agostino&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Lapponi_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Alessio Lapponi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/gr-qc/1/au:+Luongo_O/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Orlando Luongo&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.14890">
<title>The deconvolved distribution estimator: enhancing reionisation-era CO line-intensity mapping analyses with a cross-correlation analogue for one-point statistics. (arXiv:2210.14890v2 [astro-ph.CO] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.14890</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We present the deconvolved distribution estimator (DDE), an extension of the
voxel intensity distribution (VID), in the context of future observations
proposed as part of the CO Mapping Array Project (COMAP). The DDE exploits the
fact that the observed VID is a convolution of correlated signal intensity
distributions and uncorrelated noise or interloper intensity distributions. By
deconvolving the individual VID of two observables away from their joint VID in
a Fourier-space operation, the DDE suppresses sensitivity to interloper
emission while maintaining sensitivity to correlated components. The DDE thus
improves upon the VID by rejecting uncorrelated noise and interloper biases,
which is useful in the context of COMAP observations that observe different
rotational transitions of CO from the same comoving volume in different
observing frequency bands. Fisher forecasts suggest that the theoretical
sensitivity in the DDE allows significant improvements in constraining power
compared to either the cross power spectrum or the individual VID data, and
matches the constraining power of the combination of all other one- and
two-point summary statistics. Future work should further investigate the
covariance and model-dependent behaviour of this novel one-point
cross-correlation statistic.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Chung_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Dongwoo T. Chung&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Bangari_I/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ishika Bangari&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Breysse_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Patrick C. Breysse&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Ihle_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;H&amp;#xe5;vard T. Ihle&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Bond_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;J. Richard Bond&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Dunne_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Delaney A. Dunne&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Padmanabhan_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Hamsa Padmanabhan&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Philip_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Liju Philip&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Rennie_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Thomas J. Rennie&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Viero_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Marco P. Viero&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.00940">
<title>Continuous gravitational wave detection to understand the generation mechanism of fast radio bursts. (arXiv:2211.00940v1 [astro-ph.HE] CROSS LISTED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.00940</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Since the unexpected discovery of fast radio bursts (FRBs), researchers have
proposed varied theories and models to explain their phenomena. One such model
that has recently been developed incorporates the so-called
Gertsenshtein-Zel&apos;dovich (GZ) effect, which states that when gravitational
waves traverse the pulsar magnetosphere, a portion of their gravitational
radiation is transformed into electromagnetic (EM) radiation. The observed
properties of FRBs are consistent with the properties of this EM radiation,
implying, remarkably, that the GZ effect can account for both repeating and
non-repeating FRBs. If this model is correct, the pulsar&apos;s properties should
not change over time, and it would continue to emit both EM dipole and
gravitational quadrupole radiation for a long period of time. This article
targets the gravitational radiation produced by the pulsar mechanism and shows
that several proposed gravitational wave detectors can detect these
gravitational waves. If such detections are performed in the future from the
positions of FRBs, it will validate the GZ process for FRB production and can
rule out several other FRB theories.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Kalita_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Surajit Kalita&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/astro-ph/1/au:+Weltman_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Amanda Weltman&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
</rdf:RDF>