<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<rdf:RDF
 xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
 xmlns="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/"
 xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
 xmlns:taxo="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/taxonomy/"
 xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
 xmlns:syn="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
 xmlns:admin="http://webns.net/mvcb/"
>

<channel rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/">
<title>cond-mat.str-el updates on arXiv.org</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">Condensed Matter -- Strongly Correlated Electrons (cond-mat.str-el) updates on the arXiv.org e-print archive</description>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:date>2022-11-03T20:30:00-05:00</dc:date>
<dc:publisher>help@arxiv.org</dc:publisher>
<dc:subject>Condensed Matter -- Strongly Correlated Electrons</dc:subject>
<syn:updateBase>1901-01-01T00:00+00:00</syn:updateBase>
<syn:updateFrequency>1</syn:updateFrequency>
<syn:updatePeriod>daily</syn:updatePeriod>
<items>
 <rdf:Seq>
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01376" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01380" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01381" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01388" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01390" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01400" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01483" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01490" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01501" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01650" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01663" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01709" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01714" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01735" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01771" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01780" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01820" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01884" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01919" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.02002" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.02031" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2011.08638" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2201.10580" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2205.15676" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.00173" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01360" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.00679" />
 </rdf:Seq>
</items>
<image rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif" />
</channel>
<image rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif">
<title>arXiv.org</title>
<url>http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif</url>
<link>http://arxiv.org/</link>
</image>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01376">
<title>Higgs Condensates are Symmetry-Protected Topological Phases: I. Discrete Symmetries. (arXiv:2211.01376v1 [cond-mat.str-el])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01376</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Where in the landscape of many-body phases of matter do we place the Higgs
condensate of a gauge theory? On the one hand, the Higgs phase is gapped, has
no local order parameter, and for fundamental Higgs fields is adiabatically
connected to the confined phase. On the other hand, Higgs phases such as
superconductors display rich phenomenology. In this work, we propose a minimal
description of the Higgs phase as a symmetry-protected topological (SPT) phase,
utilizing conventional and higher-form symmetries. In this first part, we focus
on 2+1D $\mathbb Z_2$ gauge theory and find that the Higgs phase is protected
by a higher-form magnetic symmetry and a matter symmetry, whose meaning depends
on the physical context. While this proposal captures known properties of Higgs
phases, it also predicts that the Higgs phase of the Fradkin-Shenker model has
SPT edge modes in the symmetric part of the phase diagram, which we confirm
analytically. In addition, we argue that this SPT property is remarkably robust
upon explicitly breaking the magnetic symmetry. Although the Higgs and confined
phases are then connected without a bulk transition, they are separated by a
boundary phase transition, which we confirm with tensor network simulations.
More generally, the boundary anomaly of the Higgs SPT phase coincides with the
emergent anomaly of symmetry-breaking phases, making precise the relation
between Higgs phases and symmetry breaking. The SPT nature of the Higgs phase
can also manifest in the bulk, e.g., at transitions between distinct Higgs
condensates. Finally, we extract insights which are applicable to general SPT
phases, such as a &apos;bulk-defect correspondence&apos; generalizing discrete gauge
group analogs of Superconductor-Insulator-Superconductor (SIS) junctions. The
sequel to this work will generalize &apos;Higgs=SPT&apos; to continuous symmetries,
interpreting superconductivity as an SPT property.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Verresen_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ruben Verresen&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Borla_U/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Umberto Borla&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Vishwanath_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ashvin Vishwanath&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Moroz_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Sergej Moroz&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Thorngren_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ryan Thorngren&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01380">
<title>Large-Scale $2+1$D $\mathrm{U}(1)$ Gauge Theory with Dynamical Matter in a Cold-Atom Quantum Simulator. (arXiv:2211.01380v1 [cond-mat.quant-gas])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01380</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;A major driver of quantum-simulator technology is the prospect of probing
high-energy phenomena in synthetic quantum matter setups at a high level of
control and tunability, thereby offering a venue complementary to dedicated
particle colliders. Here, we propose an experimentally feasible realization of
a large-scale $2+1$D $\mathrm{U}(1)$ gauge theory with dynamical matter and
gauge fields in a cold-atom quantum simulator with spinless bosons. We present
the full mapping of the corresponding Gauss&apos;s law onto the bosonic
computational basis. We then show that the target gauge theory can be
faithfully realized and stabilized by an emergent gauge protection term in a
two-dimensional single-species Bose--Hubbard optical Lieb superlattice with two
spatial periods along either direction, thereby requiring only moderate
experimental resources already available in current cold-atom setups. Using
infinite matrix product states, we calculate numerical benchmarks for adiabatic
sweeps and global quench dynamics that further confirm the fidelity of the
mapping. Our work brings quantum simulators of gauge theories a significant
step forward in terms of investigating particle physics in higher spatial
dimensions, and is readily implementable in existing cold-atom platforms.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Osborne_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jesse Osborne&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+McCulloch_I/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ian P. McCulloch&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Yang_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Bing Yang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Hauke_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Philipp Hauke&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Halimeh_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jad C. Halimeh&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01381">
<title>Quantum Spin Puddles and Lakes: NISQ-Era Spin Liquids from Non-Equilibrium Dynamics. (arXiv:2211.01381v1 [cond-mat.str-el])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01381</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;While many-body systems can host long-ranged entangled quantum spin liquids
(QSLs), the ingredients for realizing these as ground states can be
prohibitively difficult. In many circumstances, one requires (i) a constrained
Hilbert space and (ii) an extensive quantum superposition. The paradigmatic
example is the toric code, or $\mathbb{Z}_2$ spin liquid, which is a
superposition of closed loop states. We show how non-equilibrium Hamiltonian
dynamics can provide a streamlined route toward creating such QSLs. Rather than
cooling into the ground state of a Hamiltonian, we show how a simple parameter
sweep can dynamically project a family of initial product states into the
constrained space, giving rise to a QSL. For the toric code, this is achieved
in systems with a separation in energy scales between the $e$- and $m$-anyons,
where one can sweep in a way that is adiabatic (sudden) with respect to the
former (latter). Although this separation of scales does not extend to the
thermodynamic limit, we analytically and numerically show that this method
efficiently prepares a spin liquid in finite-sized regions, which we brand
``quantum spin lakes.&apos;&apos; This mechanism elucidates recent experimental and
numerical observations of the dynamical state preparation of the ruby lattice
spin liquid in Rydberg atom arrays. In fact, the slow dynamics of $m$-anyons
suggest that we can capture spin lake preparation by simulating the dynamics on
tree lattices, which we confirm with tensor network simulations. Finally, we
use this mechanism to propose new experiments, e.g., for preparing a
finite-sized $U(1)$ spin liquid as a honeycomb Rokhsar-Kivelson dimer model
using Rydberg atoms -- which is remarkable given its equilibrium counterpart is
unstable in $2 + 1$D. Our work opens up a new avenue in the study of
non-equilibrium physics, as well as the exploration of exotic states of finite
extent in NISQ devices.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Sahay_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Rahul Sahay&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Vishwanath_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ashvin Vishwanath&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Verresen_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ruben Verresen&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01388">
<title>Sublattice Interference promotes Pair Density Wave order in Kagome Metals. (arXiv:2211.01388v1 [cond-mat.str-el])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01388</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Motivated by the observation of a pair density wave (PDW) in the kagome metal
CsV${}_3$Sb${}_5$, we consider the fate of electrons near a p-type van Hove
singularity (vHS) in the presence of local repulsive interactions. We study the
effect of such interactions on Fermi surface &quot;patches&quot; at the vHS. We show how
a feature unique to the Kagome lattice known as sublattice interference
crucially affects the form of the interactions among the patches. The RG flow
of such interactions results in a regime where nearest neighbor interactions
exceed onsite repulsion. We identify this condition as being favorable for the
formation of CDW and PDW orders. We conclude that in the weak-coupling limit,
CDW order is the dominant order, whereas PDW order sets in at intermediate
coupling.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Wu_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yi-Ming Wu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Thomale_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ronny Thomale&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Raghu_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;S. Raghu&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01390">
<title>Strange-metal behavior in a Fermi liquid with strange scatterers. (arXiv:2211.01390v1 [cond-mat.str-el])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01390</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;A variety of low-temperature, normal-state properties of optimally and
overdoped cuprate superconductors, including the DC and optical transport
responses, are sufficiently anomalous that they might seem to be inconsistent
with any quasiparticle description. However, we show by explicit construction
that the most salient phenomena can be accounted for in a system with localized
&quot;strange scatterers&quot; embedded into a Fermi liquid with a conventional
quasiparticle description. Such scatterers could originate from &quot;two-level
systems&quot; associated with an electronic glassy state with short-range
charge-order correlations.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Berg_E/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Erez Berg&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Grissonnanche_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ga&amp;#xeb;l Grissonnanche&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Kivelson_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Steven A. Kivelson&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Murthy_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Chaitanya Murthy&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Pandey_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Akshat Pandey&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Ramshaw_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;B. J. Ramshaw&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Spivak_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Boris Z. Spivak&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01400">
<title>Improved effective vertices in the multi-orbital Two-Particle Self-Consistent method from Dynamical Mean-Field Theory. (arXiv:2211.01400v1 [cond-mat.str-el])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01400</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;In this work we present a multi-orbital form of the Two-Particle
Self-Consistent approach (TPSC), here the effective local and static
irreducible interaction vertices are determined by means of the Dynamical
Mean-Field Theory (DMFT). This approach replaces the approximate ansatz
equations for the double occupations $\langle
n^{}_{\alpha,\sigma}n^{}_{\beta,\sigma&apos;}\rangle$ by sampling them directly for
the same model using DMFT. Compared to the usual Hartree-Fock like ansatz, this
leads to more accurate local vertices in the weakly correlated regime, and
provides access to stronger correlated systems that were previously out of
reach. This approach is extended by replacing the local component of the TPSC
self-energy by the DMFT impurity self-energy, which results in an improved
self-energy that incorporates strong local correlations but retains a
non-trivial momentum-dependence. We find that this combination of TPSC and DMFT
provides a significant improvement over the multi-orbital formulation of
multi-orbital TPSC, as it allows to determine the components of the spin vertex
without artificial symmetry assumptions, and opens the possibility to include
the transversal particle-hole channel. The new approach is also able to remove
unphysical divergences in the charge vertices in TPSC. We find a general trend
that lower temperatures can be accessed in the calculation. Benchmarking
single-particle quantities such as the local spectral function with other
many-body methods we find significant improvement in the more strongly
correlated regime.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Zantout_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Karim Zantout&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Backes_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Steffen Backes&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Razpopov_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Aleksandar Razpopov&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Lessnich_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Dominik Lessnich&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Valenti_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Roser Valenti&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01483">
<title>Unravelling the origin of the peculiar transition in the magnetically ordered phase of the Weyl semimetal Co3Sn2S2. (arXiv:2211.01483v1 [cond-mat.str-el])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01483</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Recent discovery of topologically non-trivial behavior in Co3Sn2S2 stimulated
a notable interest in this itinerant ferromagnet (Tc = 174 K). The exact
magnetic state remains ambiguous, with several reports indicating the existence
of a second transition in the range 125 -- 130 K, with antiferromagnetic and
glassy phases proposed to coexist with the ferromagnetic phase. Using detailed
angle-dependent DC and AC magnetization measurements on large, high-quality
single crystals we reveal a highly anisotropic behavior of both static and
dynamic response of Co3Sn2S2. It is established that many observations related
to sharp magnetization changes when B || c are influenced by the
demagnetization factor of a sample. On the other hand, a genuine transition has
been found at Tp = 128 K, with the magnetic response being strictly
perpendicular to the c-axis and several orders of magnitude smaller than for B
|| c. Calculations using density-functional theory indicate that the ground
state magnetic structure consist of magnetic moments canted away from the
c-axis by a small angle (~ 1.5deg). We argue that the second transition
originates from a small additional canting of moments within the kagome plane,
with two equivalent orientations for each spin.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Zivkovic_I/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ivica Zivkovic&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Yadav_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ravi Yadav&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Soh_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jian-Rui Soh&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Yi_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;ChangJiang Yi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Shi_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;YouGuo Shi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Yazyev_O/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Oleg V. Yazyev&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Ronnow_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Henrik M. Ronnow&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01490">
<title>Deep Learning Hamiltonians from Disordered Image Data in Quantum Materials. (arXiv:2211.01490v1 [cond-mat.str-el])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01490</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The capabilities of image probe experiments are rapidly expanding, providing
new information about quantum materials on unprecedented length and time
scales. Many such materials feature inhomogeneous electronic properties with
intricate pattern formation on the observable surface. This rich spatial
structure contains information about interactions, dimensionality, and disorder
-- a spatial encoding of the Hamiltonian driving the pattern formation. Image
recognition techniques from machine learning are an excellent tool for
interpreting information encoded in the spatial relationships in such images.
Here, we develop a deep learning framework for using the rich information
available in these spatial correlations in order to discover the underlying
Hamiltonian driving the patterns. We first vet the method on a known case,
scanning near-field optical microscopy on a thin film of VO2. We then apply our
trained convolutional neural network architecture to new optical microscope
images of a different VO2 film as it goes through the metal-insulator
transition. We find that a two-dimensional Hamiltonian with both interactions
and random field disorder is required to explain the intricate, fractal
intertwining of metal and insulator domains during the transition. This
detailed knowledge about the underlying Hamiltonian paves the way to using the
model to control the pattern formation via, e.g., tailored hysteresis
protocols. We also introduce a distribution-based confidence measure on the
results of a multi-label classifier, which does not rely on adversarial
training. In addition, we propose a new machine learning based criterion for
diagnosing a physical system&apos;s proximity to criticality.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Basak_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;S. Basak&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Banguero_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;M. Alzate Banguero&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Burzawa_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;L. Burzawa&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Simmons_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;F. Simmons&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Salev_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;P. Salev&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Aigouy_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;L. Aigouy&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Qazilbash_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;M. M. Qazilbash&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Schuller_I/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;I. K. Schuller&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Basov_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;D. N. Basov&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Zimmers_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;A. Zimmers&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Carlson_E/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;E. W. Carlson&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01501">
<title>A light-induced Weyl semiconductor-to-metal transition mediated by Peierls instability. (arXiv:2211.01501v1 [cond-mat.str-el])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01501</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Elemental tellurium is a strongly spin-orbit coupled Peierls-distorted
semiconductor whose band structure features topologically protected Weyl nodes.
Using time-dependent density functional theory calculations, we show that
impulsive optical excitation can be used to transiently control the amplitude
of the Peierls distortion, realizing a mechanism to switch tellurium between
three states: Weyl semiconductor, Weyl metal and non-Weyl metal. Further, we
present experimental evidence of this inverse-Peierls distortion using
time-resolved optical second harmonic generation measurements. These results
provide a pathway to multifunctional ultrafast Weyl devices and introduce
Peierls systems as viable hosts of light-induced topological transitions.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Ning_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;H. Ning&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Mehio_O/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;O. Mehio&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Lian_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;C. Lian&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Li_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;X. Li&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Zoghlin_E/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;E. Zoghlin&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Zhou_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;P. Zhou&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Cheng_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;B. Cheng&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Wilson_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;S. D. Wilson&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Wong_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;B. M. Wong&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Hsieh_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;D. Hsieh&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01650">
<title>Universality and its limits in non-Hermitian many-body quantum chaos using the Sachdev-Ye-Kitaev model. (arXiv:2211.01650v1 [hep-th])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01650</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Spectral rigidity in Hermitian quantum chaotic systems signals the presence
of dynamical universal features at time scales that can be much shorter than
the Heisenberg time. We study the analogue of this time scale in many-body
non-Hermitian quantum chaos by a detailed analysis of long-range spectral
correlators. For that purpose, we investigate the number variance and the
spectral form factor of a non-Hermitian $q$-body Sachdev-Ye-Kitaev (nHSYK)
model, which describes $N$ fermions in zero spatial dimensions. After an
analytical and numerical analysis of these spectral observables for
non-Hermitian random matrices, and a careful unfolding, we find good agreement
with the nHSYK model for $q &amp;gt; 2$ starting at a time scale that decreases
sharply with $q$. The source of deviation from universality, identified
analytically, is ensemble fluctuations not related to the quantum dynamics. For
fixed $q$ and large enough $N$, these fluctuations become dominant up until
after the Heisenberg time, so that the spectral form factor is no longer useful
for the study of quantum chaos. In all cases, our results point to a weakened
or vanishing spectral rigidity that effectively delays the observation of full
quantum ergodicity. We also show that the number variance displays
non-stationary spectral correlations for both the nHSYK model and random
matrices. This non-stationarity, also not related to the quantum dynamics,
points to intrinsic limitations of these observables to describe the quantum
chaotic motion. On the other hand, we introduce the local spectral form factor,
which is shown to be stationary and not affected by collective fluctuations,
and propose it as an effective diagnostic of non-Hermitian quantum chaos. For
$q = 2$, we find saturation to Poisson statistics at a time scale of $\log D$,
compared to a scale of $\sqrt D$ for $ q&amp;gt;2$, with $D $ the total number of
states.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Garcia_Garcia_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Antonio M. Garc&amp;#xed;a-Garc&amp;#xed;a&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Sa_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Lucas S&amp;#xe1;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Verbaarschot_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jacobus J. M. Verbaarschot&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01663">
<title>Static magnetic and ESR spectroscopic properties of the dimer-chain antiferromagnet BiCoPO$_5$. (arXiv:2211.01663v1 [cond-mat.str-el])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01663</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We report a comprehensive study of the static susceptibility, high-field
magnetization and high-frequency/high-magnetic field electron spin resonance
(HF-ESR) spectroscopy of polycrystalline samples of the bismuth cobalt
oxy-phosphate BiCoPO$_5$. This compound features a peculiar spin system that
can be considered as antiferromagnetic (AFM) chains built of pairs of
ferromagnetically coupled Co spins and interconnected in all three spatial
directions. It was previously shown that BiCoPO$_5$ orders
antiferromagnetically at $T_{\rm N} \approx 10$ K and this order can be
continuously suppressed by magnetic field towards the critical value
$\mu_0H_{\rm c} \approx 15$ T. In our experiments we find strongly enhanced
magnetic moments and spectroscopic $g$ factors as compared to the expected
spin-only values, suggesting a strong contribution of orbital magnetism for the
Co$^{2+}$ ions. This is quantitatively confirmed by ab initio quantum chemical
calculations. Within the AFM ordered phase, we observe a distinct field-induced
magnetic phase transition. Its critical field rises to $\sim 6$ T at $T \ll
T_{\rm N}$. The HF-ESR spectra recorded at $T\ll T_{\rm N}$ are very rich
comprising up to six resonance modes possibly of the multimagnonic nature that
soften towards the critical region around 6 T. Interestingly, we find that the
Co moments are not yet fully polarized at $H_{\rm c}$ which supports a
theoretical proposal identifying $H_{\rm c}$ as the quantum critical point for
the transition of the spin system in BiCoPO$_5$ to the quantum disordered state
at stronger fields.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Iakovleva_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;M. Iakovleva&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Petersen_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;T. Petersen&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Alfonsov_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;A. Alfonsov&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Skourski_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Y. Skourski&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Grafe_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;H.-J. Grafe&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Vavilova_E/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;E. Vavilova&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Nath_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;R. Nath&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Hozoi_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;L. Hozoi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Kataev_V/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;V. Kataev&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01709">
<title>Dynamic phase transitions on the kagome Ising ferromagnet. (arXiv:2211.01709v1 [cond-mat.stat-mech])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01709</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We perform extensive Monte Carlo simulations to investigate the dynamic phase
transition properties of the two-dimensional kinetic Ising model on the kagome
lattice in the presence of square-wave oscillating magnetic field. Through
detailed finite-size scaling analysis, we study universality aspects of the
non-equilibrium phase transition. Obtained critical exponents indicate that the
two-dimensional kagome-lattice kinetic Ising model belongs to the same
universality class with the corresponding Ising model in equilibrium. Moreover,
dynamic critical exponent of the local moves used in simulations is determined
with high precision. Our numerical results are compatible with the previous
ones on kinetic Ising models.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Vatansever_Z/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Zeynep Demir Vatansever&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01714">
<title>Skyrmion Jellyfish in Driven Chiral Magnets. (arXiv:2211.01714v1 [cond-mat.mes-hall])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01714</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Chiral magnets can host topological particles known as skyrmions which carry
an exactly quantised topological charge $Q=-1$. In the presence of an
oscillating magnetic field ${\bf B}_1(t)$, a single skyrmion embedded in a
ferromagnetic background will start to move with constant velocity ${\bf
v}_{\text{trans}}$. The mechanism behind this motion is similar to the one used
by a jellyfish when it swims through water. We show that the skyrmion&apos;s motion
is a universal phenomenon, arising in any magnetic system with translational
modes. By projecting the equation of motion onto the skyrmion&apos;s translational
modes and going to quadratic order in ${\bf B}_1(t)$ we obtain an analytical
expression for ${\bf v}_{\text{trans}}$ as a function of the system&apos;s linear
response. The linear response and consequently ${\bf v}_{\text{trans}}$ are
influenced by the skyrmion&apos;s internal modes and scattering states, as well as
by the ferromagnetic background&apos;s Kittel mode. The direction and speed of ${\bf
v}_{\text{trans}}$ can be controlled by changing the polarisation, frequency
and phase of the driving field ${\bf B}_1(t)$. For systems with small Gilbert
damping parameter $\alpha$, we identify two distinct physical mechanisms used
by the skyrmion to move. At low driving frequencies, the skyrmion&apos;s motion is
driven by friction, and $v_{\text{trans}}\sim\alpha$, whereas at higher
frequencies above the ferromagnetic gap the skyrmion moves by magnon emission
and $v_{\text{trans}}$ becomes independent of $\alpha$.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Ser_N/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Nina del Ser&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Lohani_V/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Vivek Lohani&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01735">
<title>Electronic Coherent Control of an Insulator-to-Metal Mott Transition. (arXiv:2211.01735v1 [cond-mat.str-el])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01735</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Managing light-matter interaction on timescales faster than the loss of
electronic coherence is key for achieving the full quantum control of final
products in solid-solid transformations. In this work, we demonstrate coherent
electronic control of the photoinduced insulator-to-metal transition in the
prototypical Mott insulator V$_2$O$_3$. Selective excitation of a specific
interband transition with two phase-locked light pulses manipulates the orbital
occupation of the correlated bands in a way that depends on the coherent
evolution of the photoinduced superposition of states. Comparison between
experimental results and numerical solutions of the optical Bloch equations
provides an electronic coherence time on the order of 5 fs. Temperature
dependent experiments suggest that the electronic coherence time is enhanced in
the vicinity of the insulator-to-metal transition critical temperature, thus
highlighting the role of fluctuations in determining the electronic coherence.
These results open new routes to selectively switch functionalities of quantum
materials and coherently control solid-solid electronic transformations.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Franceschini_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Paolo Franceschini&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Policht_V/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Veronica R.Policht&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Milloch_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Alessandra Milloch&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Ronchi_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Andrea Ronchi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Mor_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Selene Mor&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Mellaerts_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Simon Mellaerts&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Hsu_W/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Wei-Fan Hsu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Pagliara_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Stefania Pagliara&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Ferrini_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Gabriele Ferrini&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Banfi_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Francesco Banfi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Fabrizio_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Michele Fabrizio&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Menghini_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Mariela Menghini&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Locquet_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jean-Pierre Locquet&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Conte_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Stefano Dal Conte&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Cerullo_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Giulio Cerullo&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Giannetti_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Claudio Giannetti&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01771">
<title>The competition between antiferromagnetism and superconductivity in a doped Hubbard model with anisotropic interaction. (arXiv:2211.01771v1 [cond-mat.str-el])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01771</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The competition between antiferromagnetism and superconductivity is one of
the central questions in the research of strong correlated systems. In this
work, we utilize a double layer model containing Hubbard interaction and
interlayer Heisenberg interaction to reveal their competitions. This model is
free of sign problem at certain conditions, and we perform projector quantum
Monte Carlo simulations to extract the ground state correlations of magnetism
and superconductivity. Our results shows that the superconductivity emerges
when the antiferromagnetism is suppressed by tuning the filling or the
anisotropy of the interlayer Heisenberg interaction. This model can be seen as
an analogue of unconventional superconductors and may help us to understand the
transition from an antiferromagnetic insulator to a superconductor.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Ma_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Runyu Ma&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Ma_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Tianxing Ma&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01780">
<title>Controlling charge density order in 2H-TaSe$_{2}$ using a van Hove singularity. (arXiv:2211.01780v1 [cond-mat.str-el])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01780</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We report on the interplay between a van Hove singularity and a charge
density wave state in 2H-TaSe$_{2}$. We use angle-resolved photoemission
spectroscopy to investigate changes in the Fermi surface of this material under
surface doping with potassium. At high doping, we observe modifications which
imply the disappearance of the $(3\times 3)$ charge density wave and formation
of a different correlated state. Using a tight-binding-based approach as well
as an effective model, we explain our observations as a consequence of coupling
between the single-particle Lifshitz transition during which the Fermi level
passes a van Hove singularity and the charge density order. The high electronic
density of states associated with the van Hove singularity induces a change in
the periodicity of the charge density wave from the known $(3\times 3)$ to a
new $(2\times 2)$ superlattice.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Luckin_W/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;William R. B. Luckin&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Li_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yiwei Li&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Jiang_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Juan Jiang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Gunasekera_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Surani M. Gunasekera&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Prabhakaran_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Dharmalingam Prabhakaran&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Flicker_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Felix Flicker&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Chen_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yulin Chen&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Mucha_Kruczynski_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Marcin Mucha-Kruczynski&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01820">
<title>Dual density waves with neutral and charged dipolar excitons of GaAs bilayers. (arXiv:2211.01820v1 [cond-mat.str-el])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01820</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Strongly correlated quantum particles in lattice potentials are the building
blocks for a large variety of quantum insulators, for instance Mott phases and
density waves breaking the lattice symmetry. Such collective states are
accessible to bosonic and fermionic systems. To expand further the spectrum of
accessible quantum matter phases, mixing both species is theoretically
appealing, since density order then competes with phase separation. Here we
manipulate such Bose-Fermi mixture by confining neutral (boson-like) and
charged (fermion-like) dipolar excitons in an artificial square lattice of a
GaAs bilayer. At unitary lattice filling, strong inter- and intra-species
interactions stabilise insulating phases when the fraction of charged excitons
is around (1/3, 1/2, 2/3). We evidence that dual Bose-Fermi density waves are
then realised, with species ordered in alternating stripes. Our observations
highlight that dipolar excitons allow for controlled implementations of
Bose-Fermi Hubbard models extended by off-site interactions.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Lagoin_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Camille Lagoin&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Suffit_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Stephan Suffit&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Baldwin_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Kirk Baldwin&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Pfeiffer_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Loren Pfeiffer&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Dubin_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Francois Dubin&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01884">
<title>Orbital liquid in the $e_g$ orbital Hubbard model in $d=\infty$ dimensions. (arXiv:2211.01884v1 [cond-mat.str-el])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01884</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We demonstrate that the three-dimensional $e_g$ orbital Hubbard model can be
generalized to arbitrary dimension $d$, and that the form of the result is
determined uniquely by the requirements that
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(i) the two-fold degeneracy of the $e_g$ orbital be retained, and (ii) the
cubic lattice be turned into a hypercubic lattice. While the local Coulomb
interaction $U$ is invariant for each basis of orthogonal orbitals, the form of
the kinetic energy depends on the orbital basis and takes the most symmetric
form for the so-called complex-orbital basis. Characteristically, with respect
to this basis, the model has two hopping channels, one that is orbital-flavor
conserving, and a second one that is orbital-flavor non-conserving. We show
that the noninteracting electronic structure consists of two nondegenerate
bands of plane-wave real-orbital single-particle states for which the orbital
depends on the wave vector. Due to the latter feature each band is unpolarized
at any filling, and has a non-Gaussian density of states at $d=\infty$. The
\textit{orbital liquid} state is obtained by filling these two bands up to the
same Fermi energy. We investigate the $e_g$ orbital Hubbard model in the limit
$d\to\infty$, treating the on-site Coulomb interaction $U$ within the
Gutzwiller approximation, thus determining the correlation energy of the
orbital liquid and the (disordered) para-orbital states. (...) We show that the
orbital liquid is the ground state everywhere in the $(n,U)$ phase diagram
except close to half-filling at sufficiently large $U$, where ferro-orbital
order with real orbitals occupied is favored. The latter feature is shown to be
specific for $d=\infty$, being of mathematical nature due to the exponential
tails in the density of states.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Feiner_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Louis Felix Feiner&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Oles_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Andrzej M. Ole&amp;#x15b;&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01919">
<title>Non-local corrections to dynamical mean-field theory from the two-particle self-consistent method. (arXiv:2211.01919v1 [cond-mat.str-el])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01919</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Theoretical methods that are accurate for both short-distance observables and
long-wavelength collective modes are still being developed for the Hubbard
model. Here, we benchmark against published diagrammatic quantum Monte Carlo
results an approach that combines local observables from dynamical mean-field
theory (DMFT) with the two-particle self-consistent theory (TPSC). This method
(TPSC+DMFT) is relevant for weak to intermediate interaction, satisfies the
local Pauli principle and allows us to compute a spin susceptibility that
satisfies the Mermin-Wagner theorem. The DMFT double occupancy determines the
spin and charge vertices through local spin and charge sum rules. The TPSC
self-energy is also improved by replacing its local part with the local DMFT
self-energy. With this method, we find improvements for both spin and charge
fluctuations and for the self-energy. We also find that the accuracy check
developed for TPSC is a good predictor of deviations from benchmarks. TPSC+DMFT
can be used in regimes where quantum Monte Carlo is inaccessible. In addition,
this method paves the way to multi-band generalizations of TPSC that could be
used in advanced electronic structure codes that include DMFT.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Martin_N/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;N. Martin&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Gauvin_Ndiaye_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;C. Gauvin-Ndiaye&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Tremblay_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;A.-M. S. Tremblay&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.02002">
<title>Emergence of Competing Orders and Possible Quantum Spin Liquid in SU(N) Fermions. (arXiv:2211.02002v1 [cond-mat.str-el])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.02002</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;In the past decades, tremendous efforts have been made towards understanding
the exotic physics emerging from competition between various ordering
tendencies in strongly correlated systems. Employing state-of-the-art quantum
Monte-Carlo simulation, we investigate an interacting SU($N$) fermionic model
with varying interaction strength and value of $N$, and unveil the ground-state
phase diagram of the model exhibiting a plethora of exotic phases. For small
value of $N$, namely $N=2,3$, the ground state is antiferromagnetic (AFM)
phase, whereas in the large-$N$ limit, valence bound solid (VBS) order is
dominant. For the intermediate value of $N$ such as $N=4$, remarkably, our
study reveals distinct VBS orders appear in the weak and strong coupling
regimes. More fantastically, the competition between staggered and columnar VBS
ordering tendencies gives rise to a Mott insulating phase without spontaneously
symmetry breaking (SSB), existing in a large interacting parameter regime,
which is consistent with a gapped quantum spin liquid. Our study not only
provides a platform to investigate the fundamental physics of quantum many-body
systems, but also offers a novel route towards searching for exotic states of
matter such as quantum spin liquid in realistic quantum materials.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Yu_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xue-Jia Yu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Shi_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Shao-Hang Shi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Xu_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Limei Xu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Li_Z/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Zi-Xiang Li&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.02031">
<title>Spectral properties of 1D extended Hubbard model from bosonization and time-dependent variational principle: applications to 1D cuprate. (arXiv:2211.02031v1 [cond-mat.str-el])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.02031</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Recent ARPES experiments on doped 1D cuprates revealed the importance of
effective near-neighbor (NN) attractions in explaining certain features in
spectral functions. Here we investigate spectral properties of the extended
Hubbard model with the on-site repulsion $U$ and NN interaction $V$, by
employing bosonization analysis and the high-precision time-dependent
variational principle (TDVP) calculations of the model on 1D chain with up to
300 sites. From state-of-the-art TDVP calculations, we find that the spectral
weights of the holon-folding and $3k_F$ branches evolve oppositely as a
function of $V$. This peculiar dichotomy may be explained in bosonization
analysis from the opposite dependence of exponent that determines the spectral
weights on Luttinger parameter $K_{\rho}$. Moreover, our TDVP calculations of
models with fixed $U=8t$ and different $V$ show that $V\approx -1.7t$ may fit
the experimental results best, indicating a moderate effective NN attraction in
1D cuprates that might provide some hints towards understanding
superconductivity in 2D cuprates.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Wang_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Hao-Xin Wang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Wu_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yi-Ming Wu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Jiang_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yi-Fan Jiang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Yao_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Hong Yao&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2011.08638">
<title>Adiabatic theory of the polaron spectral function. (arXiv:2011.08638v2 [cond-mat.str-el] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2011.08638</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;An analytic theory for the spectral function for electrons coupled with
phonons is formulated in the adiabatic limit. In the case when the chemical
potential is large and negative $\mu \to -\infty$ the ground state does not
have the adiabatic deformation and the spectral function is defined by the
standard perturbation theory. In this limit we present the spectral function
calculated up to fourth order in the electron-phonon coupling constant which
satisfies the sum rules up to the 5th moment. In the case when the chemical
potential is pinned at the polaron binding energy the spectral function is
defined by the ground state with a nonzero adiabatic deformation. We calculate
the spectral function with the finite polaron density in the adiabatic limit.
We also demonstrate how the sum rules for higher moments may be evaluated in
the adiabatic limit. Contrary to the case of zero polaron density the spectral
function with the finite polaron concentration has some contributions which are
characteristic for polarons.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Kabanov_V/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;V.V. Kabanov&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2201.10580">
<title>Krein-unitary Schrieffer-Wolff transformation and band touchings in bosonic Bogoliubov-de Gennes and other Krein-Hermitian Hamiltonians. (arXiv:2201.10580v2 [cond-mat.str-el] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2201.10580</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Krein-Hermitian Hamiltonians, i.e., Hamiltonians Hermitian with respect to an
indefinite inner product, have emerged as an important class of non-Hermitian
Hamiltonians in physics, encompassing both single-particle bosonic
Bogoliubov-de Gennes (BdG) Hamiltonians and so-called &quot;$PT$-symmetric&quot;
non-Hermitian Hamiltonians. In particular, they have attracted considerable
scrutiny owing to the recent surge in interest for boson topology. Motivated by
these developments, we formulate a perturbative Krein-unitary Schrieffer-Wolff
transformation for finite-size dynamically stable Krein-Hermitian Hamiltonians,
yielding an effective Hamiltonian for a subspace of interest. The effective
Hamiltonian is Krein Hermitian and, for sufficiently small perturbations, also
dynamically stable. As an application, we use this transformation to justify
codimension-based analyses of band touchings in bosonic BdG Hamiltonians, which
complement topological characterization. We use this simple approach based on
symmetry and codimension to revisit known topological magnon band touchings in
several materials of recent interest.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Massarelli_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Geremia Massarelli&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Khait_I/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ilia Khait&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Paramekanti_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Arun Paramekanti&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2205.15676">
<title>Quantum phase transition in skewed ladders: an entanglement entropy and fidelity study. (arXiv:2205.15676v3 [cond-mat.str-el] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2205.15676</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Entanglement entropy (EE) of a state is a measure of correlation or
entanglement between two parts of a composite system and it may show
appreciable change when the ground state (GS) undergoes a qualitative change in
a quantum phase transition (QPT). Therefore, the EE has been extensively used
to characterise the QPT in various correlated Hamiltonians. Similarly fidelity
also shows sharp changes at a QPT. We characterized the QPT of frustrated
antiferromagnetic Heisenberg spin-1/2 systems on 3/4, 3/5 and 5/7 skewed
ladders using the EE and fidelity analysis. It is noted that all the
non-magnetic to magnetic QPT boundary in these systems can be accurately
determined using the EE and fidelity, and the EE exhibits a discontinuous
change, whereas fidelity shows a sharp dip at the transition points. It is also
noted that in case of the degenerate GS, the unsymmetrized calculations show
wild fluctuations in the EE and fidelity even without actual phase transition,
however, this problem is resolved by calculating the EE and the fidelity in the
lowest energy state of the symmetry subspaces, to which the degenerate states
belong.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Das_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Sambunath Das&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Dey_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Dayasindhu Dey&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Ramasesha_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;S. Ramasesha&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Kumar_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Manoranjan Kumar&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.00173">
<title>Density Matrix Renormalization Group for Transcorrelated Hamiltonians: Ground and Excited States in \emph{ab initio} Systems. (arXiv:2211.00173v2 [physics.chem-ph] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.00173</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We present the theory of a density matrix renormalization group (DMRG)
algorithm which can solve for both the ground and excited states of
non-Hermitian transcorrelated Hamiltonians, and show applications in \emph{ab
initio} molecular systems. Transcorrelation (TC) accelerates the basis set
convergence rate by including known physics (such as, but not limited to, the
electron-electron cusp) in the Jastrow factor used for the similarity
transformation. It also improves the accuracy of approximate methods such as
coupled cluster singles and doubles (CCSD) as shown by some recent studies.
However, the non-Hermiticity of the TC Hamiltonians poses challenges for
variational methods like DMRG. Imaginary-time evolution on the matrix product
state (MPS) in the DMRG framework has been proposed to circumvent this problem;
but this is currently limited to treating the ground state, and has lower
efficiency than the time-independent DMRG (TI-DMRG), due to the need to
eliminate Trotter errors. In this work, we show that with minimal changes to
the existing TI-DMRG algorithm, namely replacing the original Davidson solver
with the general Davidson solver to solve the non-Hermitian effective
Hamiltonians at each site for a few low-lying right eigenstates, and following
the rest of the original DMRG recipe, one can find the ground and excited
states with improved efficiency compared to the original DMRG when
extrapolating to the infinite bond dimension limit in the same basis set.
Accelerated basis set convergence rate is also observed, as expected, within
the TC framework.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Liao_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ke Liao&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Zhai_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Huanchen Zhai&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Christlmaier_E/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Evelin Martine Christlmaier&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Schraivogel_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Thomas Schraivogel&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Rios_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Pablo L&amp;#xf3;pez R&amp;#xed;os&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Kats_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Daniel Kats&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Alavi_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ali Alavi&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01360">
<title>High-field quantum spin liquid transitions and angle-field phase diagram of Kitaev magnet $\alpha$-RuCl$_3$. (arXiv:2211.01360v2 [cond-mat.str-el] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01360</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The pursuit of quantum spin liquid (QSL) in the Kitaev honeycomb magnets has
drawn intensive attention recently. In particular, $\alpha$-RuCl$_3$ has been
widely recognized as a promising candidate for the Kitaev QSL. Although the
compound exhibits an antiferromagnetic order under zero field, it is believed
to be endowed with fractionalized excitations, and can be driven to the QSL
phase by magnetic fields. Here, based on a realistic $K$-$J$-$\Gamma$-$\Gamma&apos;$
model for $\alpha$-RuCl$_3$ [1], we exploit the exponential tensor
renormalization group approach to explore the phase diagram of the compound
under magnetic fields. We calculate the thermodynamic quantities, including the
specific heat, Gr\&quot;uneisen parameter, magnetic torque, and the magnetotropic
susceptibility, etc, under a magnetic field with a tilting angle $\theta$ to
the $c^*$-axis perpendicular to the honeycomb plane. We find an extended QSL in
the angle-field phase diagram determined with thermodynamic responses. The
gapless nature of such field-induced QSL is identified from the specific heat
and entropy data computed down to very low temperatures. The present study
provides guidance for future high-field experiments for the QSL in
$\alpha$-RuCl$_3$ and other candidate Kitaev magnets.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Li_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Han Li&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Li_W/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Wei Li&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Su_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Gang Su&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.00679">
<title>Quantum phase transitions in non-Hermitian $\mathcal{P}\mathcal{T}$-symmetric transverse-field Ising spin chains. (arXiv:2211.00679v1 [quant-ph] CROSS LISTED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.00679</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We present a theoretical study of quantum phases and quantum phase
transitions occurring in non-Hermitian $\mathcal{P}\mathcal{T}$-symmetric
superconducting qubits chains described by a transverse-field Ising spin model.
A non-Hermitian part of the Hamiltonian is implemented via imaginary staggered
\textit{longitudinal } magnetic field, which corresponds to a local staggered
gain and loss terms. By making use of a direct numerical diagonalization of the
Hamiltonian for spin chains of a finite size $N$, we explore the dependencies
of the energy spectrum, including the energy difference between the first
excited and the ground states, the spatial correlation function of local
polarization ($z$-component of local magnetization) on the adjacent spins
interaction strength $J$ and the local gain (loss) parameter $\gamma$. A
scaling procedure for the coherence length $\xi$ allows us to establish a
complete quantum phase diagram of the system. We obtain two quantum phases for
$J&amp;lt;0$, namely, $\mathcal{P}\mathcal{T}$-symmetry broken antiferromagnetic state
and $\mathcal{P}\mathcal{T}$-symmetry preserved paramagnetic state, and the
quantum phase transition line between them is the line of exception points. For
$J&amp;gt;0$ the $\mathcal{P}\mathcal{T}$-symmetry of the ground state is retained in
a whole region of parameter space of $J$ and $\gamma$, and a system shows
\textit{two} intriguing quantum phase transitions between ferromagnetic and
paramagnetic states for a fixed parameter $\gamma &amp;gt; 1$. We also provide the
qualitative quantum phase diagram $\gamma-J$ derived in the framework of the
Bethe-Peierls approximation that is in a good accord with numerically obtained
results.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Starkov_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Grigory A. Starkov&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Fistoul_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Mikhail V. Fistoul&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Eremin_I/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ilya M. Eremin&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
</rdf:RDF>