<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
    <rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
        <channel>
            <title><![CDATA[OPEC Flash News]]></title>
            <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/news.rss]]></link>
            <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
            <copyright><![CDATA[© ]]></copyright>
            <ttl>180</ttl>
            <atom:link href="http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/news.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />



            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC daily basket price stood at $93.51 a barrel Thursday, 3 November 2022]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6758.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6758.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Fri, 4 Nov 2022 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC to host the Fourth OPEC-OPEC Fund Annual Legal Workshop on regulatory issues related to the energy transition, access and security]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[Vienna, Austria, 17&nbsp;October 2022--The OPEC Secretariat will host the Fourth OPEC-OPEC Fund Annual Legal Workshop on regulatory issues related to the energy transition, along with energy access and security, on Monday, 24 October 2022.]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/7035.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/7035.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC and the City of Vienna to host the Vienna Energy Scholar Programme 2022]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[Vienna, Austria, 8 September 2022--The OPEC Secretariat and the City of Vienna will host the Second Vienna Energy Scholar Programme (VESP) from 19 to 23 September 2022 at the OPEC Headquarters.]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/7005.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/7005.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Thu, 8 Sep 2022 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC takes part in Nigeria Oil and Gas Conference and Exhibition 2022]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[Abuja, Nigeria, 5 July 2022--The Organization of the Petroleum Exporting Countries (OPEC) participated in the 21st edition of Nigeria Oil and Gas (NOG) Conference and Exhibition, which is taking place in Abuja.]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6958.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6958.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Tue, 5 Jul 2022 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[You have indeed been a worthy ambassador of our country, President Buhari tells Barkindo, outgoing OPEC Secretary General]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[Abuja, Nigeria, 5 July 2022--President Muhammadu Buhari Tuesday in Abuja expressed the nation’s gratitude to the outgoing Secretary General of the Organization of the Petroleum Exporting Countries (OPEC), Mohammed Barkindo, describing him as a worthy ambassador of the country.]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6960.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6960.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Tue, 5 Jul 2022 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC Secretary General congratulates Minister Al-Rumhy on the completion of his tenure]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[Vienna, Austria, 17 June 2022--OPEC Secretary General, HE Mohammad Sanusi Barkindo, congratulated HE Dr Mohammed Bin Hamad Al-Rumhy on completing his tenure as Minister of Energy and Minerals of the Sultanate of Oman.]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6906.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6906.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2022 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC’s 21st Coordination Meeting on Climate Change takes place]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[Vienna, Austria, 31 May 2022--The Organization of the Petroleum Exporting Countries (OPEC) held the 21st Coordination Meeting on Climate Change via videoconference.]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6873.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6873.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2022 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC holds special workshop on climate change]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[Vienna, Austria, 30 May 2022--The Organization of the Petroleum Exporting Countries (OPEC) hosted the Fifth Technical Workshop on Climate Change under the theme “The first global stocktake under the Paris Agreement: challenges and opportunities for energy-exporting developing countries.”]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6870.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6870.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[Barkindo bestowed with Venezuela’s Highest Civilian Honour]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[Vienna, Austria, 13 May 2022--OPEC Secretary General, HE Mohammad Sanusi Barkindo, was received by the President of the Bolivarian Republic of Venezuela, HE Nicolas Maduro Moros, at the Miraflores Palace, Caracas. They held a working meeting to discuss ongoing developments in the oil market.&nbsp;]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6866.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6866.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[DoC technical committee convenes to review oil market developments]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[Vienna, Austria, 4 May 2022--The Joint Technical Committee (JTC) of the Declaration of Cooperation (DoC) today held its 62nd Meeting via videoconference to examine the conditions and emerging trends in the global oil market.]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6854.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6854.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Wed, 4 May 2022 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[DoC technical body convenes to review oil market developments]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[Vienna, Austria, 30 March 2022--The Joint Technical Committee (JTC) of the Declaration of Cooperation (DoC) held its 61st Meeting to examine the oil market situation and relevant trends.]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6841.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6841.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2022 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC Secretary General takes part in the Global Energy Forum in Dubai]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[Dubai, United Arab Emirates, 28 March 2022--OPEC Secretary General, HE Mohammad Sanusi Barkindo, today participated in the Atlantic Council’s Global Energy Forum (GEF) 2022 in Dubai, UAE.]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6837.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6837.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2022 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[The Joint Technical Committee meets to review oil market conditions]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[Vienna, Austria, 1 March 2022--The Joint Technical Committee (JTC) of the Declaration of Cooperation (DoC) held its 60th Meeting today via videoconference to examine the latest developments in the global oil market.]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6827.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6827.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Tue, 1 Mar 2022 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC Secretary General participates in Nigeria International Energy Summit]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[Vienna, Austria, 28 February 2022--OPEC Secretary General, HE Mohammad Sanusi Barkindo, participated virtually in the 2022 edition of Nigeria International Energy Summit (NIES), which is being held in Abuja between 27 February and 3 March.]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6824.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6824.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2022 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC Secretary General discusses OPEC’s role in the energy transition in Vienna’s Diplomatic Academy]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[Vienna, Austria, 3 February 2022--OPEC Secretary General, HE Mohammad Sanusi Barkindo, delivered a public lecture, hosted by the Diplomatic Academy of Vienna, to discuss the role of the Organization in the energy transition.]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6798.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6798.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Thu, 3 Feb 2022 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[DoC technical body meets to examine oil market conditions]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[Vienna, Austria, 1 February 2022--The Joint Technical Committee (JTC) of the Declaration of Cooperation (DoC) convened today for its 59th Meeting to examine the developments in the global oil market and emerging trends.]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6794.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6794.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Tue, 1 Feb 2022 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC congratulates the OPEC Fund on its 46th Anniversary]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[Vienna, Austria, 28 January 2022--OPEC Secretary General, HE Mohammad Sanusi Barkindo, extended his sincere congratulations to the OPEC Fund for International Development on the occasion of its 46th Anniversary.]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6789.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6789.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jan 2022 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[President Nicol&aacute;s Maduro congratulates OPEC Secretary General Mohammad Sanusi Barkindo]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[Vienna, Austria, 20 January 2022--President Nicol&aacute;s Maduro of the Bolivarian Republic of Venezuela paid glowing tribute to OPEC Secretary General, HE Mohammad Sanusi Barkindo, for a very successful two-term tenure which comes to an end in August 2022. The President was addressing the nation’s Parliament during the State of the Nation address in Caracas on Wednesday, 19 January 2022.]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6785.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6785.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2022 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[In pilgrimage tour, OPEC Secretary General visits the city of Ur in Iraq]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[Ur, Nasiriya, Iraq, 9 January 2022--OPEC Secretary General, HE Mohammad Sanusi Barkindo, and an accompanying delegation visited the ancient city of Ur in Nasiriya in the south of Iraq.]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6778.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6778.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Sun, 9 Jan 2022 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[Secretary General of OPEC commences mission to Iraq]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[Baghdad, Iraq, 6 January 2022--OPEC Secretary General, HE Mohammad Sanusi Barkindo, arrived today, 6 January 2022, in the Iraqi capital of Baghdad, following the gracious invitation of HE Ihsan Abdul Jabbar Ismaael, the country’s Minister of Oil and Head of its Delegation to the Organization.]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6768.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6768.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Thu, 6 Jan 2022 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC Secretary General visits the historic Al-Shaab Hall in Baghdad]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[Baghdad, Iraq, 6 January 2022--OPEC Secretary General, HE Mohammad Sanusi Barkindo, today visited the Al-Shaab Hall in the Bab Al-Muaatham district in Baghdad during his mission to Iraq.]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6772.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6772.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Thu, 6 Jan 2022 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[DoC Joint Technical Committee convenes to examine oil market developments]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[Vienna, Austria, 3 January 2022--The Joint Technical Committee (JTC) of the Declaration of Cooperation (DoC) held today its 58th Meeting via videoconference to review the conditions of the global oil market.]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6759.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6759.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Mon, 3 Jan 2022 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[DoC Joint Technical Committee meets to review oil market conditions]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[Vienna, Austria, 1 December 2021--The Joint Technical Committee (JTC) of the Declaration of Cooperation (DoC) convened today via videoconference for its 57th Meeting to examine the latest developments in the global oil market.]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6738.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6738.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Wed, 1 Dec 2021 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC, non-OPEC DoC participants convene for 10th Technical Meeting]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[Vienna, Austria, 25 November 2021--The 10th Technical Meeting of OPEC and non-OPEC oil producing countries participating in the Declaration of Cooperation (DoC) was held today via videoconference.]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6728.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6728.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Thu, 25 Nov 2021 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC extends its condolences on the passing of Abdullah Ismail]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[Vienna, Austria, 24 November 2021 2021--It is with great sadness that OPEC learned of the passing of Abdullah Ismail, who had been present at the ‘Baghdad Conference’ when the Organization of the Petroleum Exporting Countries (OPEC) was founded on September 14, 1960. The OPEC Secretariat extends its deepest and heartfelt condolences to his family and friends.]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6726.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6726.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[The 136th Meeting of OPEC’s Economic Commission Board commences]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[Vienna, Austria, 23 November 2021--The Organization of the Petroleum Exporting Countries (OPEC) today held the opening session of the 136th Meeting of the Economic Commission Board (ECB) via videoconference.]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6721.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6721.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Tue, 23 Nov 2021 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC Secretary General holds an interactive session with students at ADIPEC 2021]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[Abu Dhabi, United Arab Emirates, 17 November 2021--OPEC Secretary General, HE Mohammad Sanusi Barkindo, today hosted a special interactive session to engage with young students as part of the Organization’s participation at ADIPEC 2021 in Abu Dhabi, United Arab Emirates (UAE).]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6717.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6717.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Wed, 17 Nov 2021 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC presents its World Oil Outlook 2021 at ADIPEC]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[Abu Dhabi, United Arab Emirates, 16 November 2021--The Organization of the Petroleum Exporting Countries (OPEC) today held a special session to present the 15th edition of its World Oil Outlook (WOO), as part of the Organization’s participation at ADIPEC 2021 in Abu Dhabi, United Arab Emirates (UAE).]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6712.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6712.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Tue, 16 Nov 2021 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC attends ADIPEC 2021’s opening, participates in high-level discussions]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[Abu Dhabi, United Arab Emirates, 15 November 2021--OPEC Secretary General, HE Mohammad Sanusi Barkindo, attended the opening ceremony of the 2021 edition of the Abu Dhabi International Petroleum Exhibition and Conference (ADIPEC) in Abu Dhabi, United Arab Emirates (UAE).]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6708.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6708.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Mon, 15 Nov 2021 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC participates in African Energy Week 2021]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[Cape Town, South Africa, 9 November 2021--OPEC Secretary General, HE Mohammad Sanusi Barkindo, participated in the 2021 edition of African Energy Week (AEW) that is taking place in Cape Town, South Africa, from 9 to 12 November 2021, under the theme “Making energy poverty history by 2030.”]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6701.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6701.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Tue, 9 Nov 2021 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC to hold technical meeting on Asian energy and oil outlook]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[Vienna, Austria, 4 November 2021--The Organization of the Petroleum Exporting Countries (OPEC) will host the Seventh Technical Meeting on Asian Energy and Oil Outlook on Monday, 8 November 2021, via videoconference.]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6692.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6692.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Thu, 4 Nov 2021 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[DoC Joint Technical Committee convenes for its 56th Meeting]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[Vienna, Austria, 28 October 2021--The 56th Meeting of the Joint Technical Committee (JTC) was held today, 28 October 2021, via videoconference to review oil market developments.]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6682.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6682.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Thu, 28 Oct 2021 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC hosts coordination meeting on climate change]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[Vienna, Austria, 20 October 2021--OPEC hosted the 20th Coordination Meeting on Climate Change via videoconference.]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6663.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6663.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Wed, 20 Oct 2021 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC, IEA, IEF to hold 8th Joint Workshop on the Interactions between Physical and Financial Energy Markets]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[Vienna, Austria, 20 October 2021--The Organization of the Petroleum Exporting Countries (OPEC), the International Energy Agency (IEA) and the International Energy Forum (IEF) will together host the eighth workshop on the interactions between physical and financial energy markets on Thursday, 21 October 2021, via videoconference.]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6669.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6669.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Wed, 20 Oct 2021 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC takes part in India Energy Forum by CERAWeek]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[Vienna, Austria, 20 October 2021--OPEC Secretary General, HE Mohammad Sanusi Barkindo, participated via videoconference in the 2021 edition of the India Energy Forum by CERAWeek.]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6666.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6666.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Wed, 20 Oct 2021 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC, ECS, OPEC Fund holds third joint annual legal workshop]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[Vienna, Austria, 18 October 2021--The OPEC Secretariat, the Energy Charter Secretariat (ECS) and the OPEC Fund for International Development jointly hosted the third annual legal workshop via videoconference.]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6660.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6660.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Mon, 18 Oct 2021 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC to host special workshop with energy companies]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[Vienna, Austria, 7 October 2021--The OPEC Secretariat will hold the First Technical Workshop with Energy Companies on Monday, 11 October 2021, via videoconference.]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6650.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6650.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Thu, 7 Oct 2021 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC, ECS, OPEC Fund to hold 3rd annual legal workshop on national climate laws]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[Vienna, Austria, 5 October 2021--The OPEC Secretariat will host jointly with the Energy Charter Secretariat (ECS) and the OPEC Fund for International Development the Third Annual Legal Workshop on Monday, 18 October 2021, via videoconference to address national climate laws and jurisprudence evolution, with a focus on emissions reduction and energy access.]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6649.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6649.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Tue, 5 Oct 2021 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC congratulates China on the 72nd Anniversary since foundation]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[Vienna, Austria, 1 October 2021--OPEC Secretary General, HE Mohammad Sanusi Barkindo, extended his sincere congratulations to the People’s Republic of China on the occasion of the country’s National Day.]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6646.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6646.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Fri, 1 Oct 2021 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC marks five years since the historic ‘Algiers Accord’]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[Vienna, Austria, 29 September 2021--OPEC has marked the fifth anniversary of the pivotal decisions taken in Algiers, Algeria, on 28 September 2016 that would culminate in the signing of the Declaration of Cooperation (DoC) later that year.]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6627.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6627.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Wed, 29 Sep 2021 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[DoC Joint Technical Committee discusses oil market developments]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[Vienna, Austria, 29 September 2021--The Joint Technical Committee (JTC) convened for its 55th meeting via videoconference to examine oil market developments.]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6624.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6624.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Wed, 29 Sep 2021 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC congratulates Saudi Arabia on its national day]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[Vienna, Austria, 23 September 2021--OPEC Secretary General, HE Mohammad Sanusi Barkindo, extended his sincere congratulations to the leaders and people of the Kingdom of Saudi Arabia on the occasion of its national day.]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6608.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6608.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Thu, 23 Sep 2021 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC Secretary General visits the Emirate of Fujairah, meets its Ruler]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[Fujairah, United Arab Emirates, 22 September 2021--OPEC Secretary General, HE Mohammad Sanusi Barkindo, visited the Emirate of Fujairah as part of his mission to the United Arab Emirates (UAE).]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6604.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6604.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Wed, 22 Sep 2021 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC Secretary General participates in the opening session of Gastech 2021 in Dubai]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[Dubai, United Arab Emirates, 21 September 2021--OPEC Secretary General, HE Mohammad Sanusi Barkindo, took part in the opening ceremony of Gastech 2021 held in Dubai, United Arab Emirates.]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6600.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6600.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Tue, 21 Sep 2021 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC conveys its condolences on the passing of Algeria’s former President Bouteflika]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[Vienna, Austria, 20 September 2021--OPEC Secretary General, HE Mohammad Sanusi Barkindo, extended his condolences to HE Mohamed Arkab, Algeria’s Minister of Energy and Mines and Head of its Delegation to OPEC, on the passing of HE Abdelaziz Bouteflika, the county’s former President.]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6597.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6597.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Mon, 20 Sep 2021 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC Secretary General visits Venezuela, meets President Maduro]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[Caracas, Venezuela, 16 September 2021--OPEC Secretary General, HE Mohammad Sanusi Barkindo, has visited the Bolivarian Republic of Venezuela at the gracious invitation of its government to celebrate OPEC’s 61st Anniversary. Venezuela is a Founder Member of OPEC.]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6592.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6592.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Thu, 16 Sep 2021 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[Indian Oil Corporation congratulates OPEC on its 61st Anniversary]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[Vienna, Austria, 14 September 2021--The Chairman of Indian Oil Corporation, S. M. Vaidya, extended his congratulations to OPEC Secretary General, HE Mohammad Sanusi Barkindo, on the occasion of the Organization’s 61st Anniversary.]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6590.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6590.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Tue, 14 Sep 2021 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[Venezuela has played a crucial role in OPEC’s history]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[Vienna, Austria, 14 September 2021--Article by HE Mohammad Sanusi Barkindo, OPEC Secretary General, on the occasion of the Organization’s 61st Anniversary.]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6591.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6591.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Tue, 14 Sep 2021 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[The 21st Special Meeting of the ECB concludes]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[Vienna, Austria, 13 September 2021--The 21st Special Meeting of the Economic Commission Board (ECB), held via videoconference, concluded today, Monday, 13 September 2021.]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6581.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6581.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Mon, 13 Sep 2021 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC’s ECB meets for its 21st Special Meeting]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[Vienna, Austria, 7 September 2021--The 21st Special Meeting of OPEC’s Economic Commission Board (ECB) commenced via videoconference.]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6577.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6577.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Tue, 7 Sep 2021 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC congratulates Malaysia on its Independence Day]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[Vienna, Austria, 31 August 2021--OPEC Secretary General, HE Mohammad Sanusi Barkindo, extended his sincere congratulations to the Government and People of Malaysia on the occasion of its Independence Day.]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6566.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6566.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Tue, 31 Aug 2021 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC Secretary General concludes mission to Congo by visiting Pointe-Noire]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[Pointe-Noire, the Republic of the Congo, 25 August 2021--OPEC Secretary General, HE Mohammad Sanusi Barkindo, concluded his mission to the Republic of the Congo by visiting the coastal city and port of Pointe-Noire.]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6560.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6560.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Wed, 25 Aug 2021 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC Secretary General meets with Congo’s National Assembly President and Members of Parliament]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[Brazzaville, the Republic of the Congo, 24 August 2021--OPEC Secretary General, HE Mohammad Sanusi Barkindo, accompanied by HE Bruno Jean-Richard Itoua, Minister of Hydrocarbon of the Republic of the Congo, held a meeting with HE Isidore Mvouba, President de L’Assemble Nationale, in Brazzaville.]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6552.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6552.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Tue, 24 Aug 2021 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC Secretary General visits APPO’s Headquarters in Brazzaville]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[Brazzaville, the Republic of the Congo, 24 August 2021--OPEC Secretary General, HE Mohammad Sanusi Barkindo, accompanied by HE Bruno Jean-Richard Itoua, Minister of Hydrocarbons of the Republic of the Congo, met with Dr Omar Farouk Ibrahim, Secretary General of the African Petroleum Producers’ Organization (APPO), during a visit to the Organization’s headquarters in Brazzaville.]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6556.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6556.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Tue, 24 Aug 2021 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC Secretary General commences mission to Congo by meeting Minister Itoua]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[Brazzaville, the Republic of the Congo, 23 August 2021--OPEC Secretary General, HE Mohammad Sanusi Barkindo, began his mission to the Republic of the Congo by holding a bilateral meeting with HE Bruno Jean-Richard Itoua, Congo’s Minister of Hydrocarbons and Head of Delegation to the Organization, in Brazzaville.]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6537.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6537.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Mon, 23 Aug 2021 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC Secretary General visits Congo’s national oil company]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[Brazzaville, the Republic of the Congo, 23 August 2021--OPEC Secretary General, HE Mohammad Sanusi Barkindo, accompanied by HE Bruno Jean-Richard Itoua, Minister of Hydrocarbons of the Republic of the Congo, met with Maixent Raoul Ominga, Director General of the Soci&eacute;t&eacute; Nationale des P&eacute;troles du Congo (SNPC), Congo’s national company, during a visit to the company’s headquarters.]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6548.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6548.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Mon, 23 Aug 2021 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC Secretary General meets with Congo’s Prime Minister]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[Brazzaville, the Republic of the Congo, 23 August 2021--OPEC Secretary General, HE Mohammad Sanusi Barkindo, and an accompanying OPEC delegation were received by HE Anatole Collinet Makosso, Prime Minister of the Republic of the Congo, at his office in Brazzaville.]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6544.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6544.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Mon, 23 Aug 2021 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC congratulates President Buhari of Nigeria on ratifying the Petroleum Industry Bill]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[Vienna, Austria, 16 August 2021--OPEC Secretary General, HE Mohammad Sanusi Barkindo, extended his sincere congratulations in a letter to HE Muhammadu Buhari, President of Nigeria, on signing the Petroleum Industry Bill (PIB) into law.]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6535.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6535.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Mon, 16 Aug 2021 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC Secretary General meets with HE Zanganeh, Iranian Petroleum Minister]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[Tehran, IR Iran, 6 August 2021--Ahead of the first meeting of IR Iran’s President Ebrahim Raisi with OPEC Secretary General, Mohammad Sanusi Barkindo, later in the afternoon, the outgoing Petroleum Minister, HE Bijan Zanganeh, hosted the Secretary General at a working lunch.]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6525.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6525.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Fri, 6 Aug 2021 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC Secretary General meets with HE Raisi, new Iranian President]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[Tehran, IR Iran, 6 August 2021--OPEC Secretary General, HE Mohammad Sanusi Barkindo, today held a bilateral meeting in Tehran with HE Ebrahim Raisi, the new President of IR Iran.]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6531.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6531.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Fri, 6 Aug 2021 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC Secretary General attends inauguration ceremony of HE Raisi, holds high-level bilateral meetings]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[Tehran, IR Iran, 5 August 2021--OPEC Secretary General, HE Mohammad Sanusi Barkindo, attended the inauguration ceremony of the new Iranian President, HE Ebrahim Raisi, in Tehran, IR Iran.]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6521.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6521.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Thu, 5 Aug 2021 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC Secretary General meets with IR Iran Ambassador to Nigeria]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[Abuja, Nigeria, 2 August 2021--OPEC Secretary General, HE Mohammad Sanusi Barkindo, today held a bilateral meeting in Abuja with HE Mohammad Ali Bak, Ambassador of IR Iran.]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6519.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6519.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Mon, 2 Aug 2021 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC extends its condolences to the people of Iraq following fire at the Imam Hussein Teaching Hospital]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[Vienna, Austria, 16 July 2021--OPEC Secretary General, HE Mohammad Sanusi Barkindo, has conveyed his deep and sincere condolences to HE Ihsan Abdul Jabbar Ismaael, Iraq’s Minister of Oil and Head of its Delegation to OPEC, on the loss of life following a fire at the Imam Hussein Teaching Hospital in the city of Nasiriya, Iraq.]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6509.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6509.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jul 2021 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC participates in Nigeria’s Valuechain Annual Lecture and Awards 2021]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[Vienna, Austria, 12 July 2021--OPEC Secretary General, HE Mohammad Sanusi Barkindo, participated in the fourth iteration of the Valuechain Annual Lecture and Awards via videoconference.]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6505.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6505.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[Barkindo congratulates Nigeria’s leadership on its 50th Anniversary in OPEC]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[Vienna, Austria, 12 July 2021--OPEC Secretary General, HE Mohammad Sanusi Barkindo, conveyed his profound and heartfelt congratulations to the leaders and people of Nigeria on the occasion of its golden anniversary since becoming an OPEC Member Country.]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6506.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6506.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC hosts 19th Coordination Meeting on Climate Change]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[Vienna, Austria, 8 July 2021--The OPEC Secretariat hosts the 19th Coordination Meeting on Climate Change via videoconference.]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6501.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6501.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Thu, 8 Jul 2021 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[Fourth Technical Workshop on Climate Change held via videoconference]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[Vienna, Austria, 7 July 2021--The OPEC Secretariat today hosted the fourth reiteration of the Technical Workshop on Climate Change via videoconference.]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6494.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6494.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Wed, 7 Jul 2021 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[JTC reviews oil market developments]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[Vienna, Austria, 29 June 2021--The Joint Technical Committee (JTC) of the Declaration of Cooperation (DoC) of OPEC and non-OPEC oil producing countries held its 53rd Meeting via videoconference to review the latest oil market developments and discuss future prospects.]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6473.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6473.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jun 2021 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC and India hold high-level bilateral consultation]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[Vienna, Austria, 24 June 2021--OPEC Secretary General, HE Mohammad Sanusi Barkindo, met with HE Dharmendra Pradhan, India’s Minister of Petroleum and Natural Gas and Minister of Steel, to discuss oil market developments.]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6469.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6469.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jun 2021 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC’s Economic Commission Board continues its deliberations]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[Vienna, Austria, 23 June 2021--The 135th Meeting of the Economic Commission Board (ECB) of OPEC continued its deliberations today, Wednesday, 23 June 2021, via videoconference.]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6466.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6466.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jun 2021 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[DoC participating countries hold 9th Technical Meeting]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[Vienna, Austria, 17 June 2021--The Ninth Technical Meeting of the OPEC and non-OPEC Countries participating in the Declaration of Cooperation (DoC) was held via videoconference.]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6461.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6461.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jun 2021 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC’s Economic Commission Board convenes for its 135th Meeting]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[Vienna, Austria, 15 June 2021--The 135th Meeting of the Economic Commission Board (ECB) of OPEC has commenced via videoconference. The Board is the economic and technical think-tank of the Organization.]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6458.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6458.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2021 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC to host the First Vienna Energy Scholar Programme]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[Vienna, Austria, 9 June 2021--The OPEC Secretariat and the City of Vienna will jointly host the First Vienna Energy Scholar Programme (VESP) from 4 to 8 October 2021.]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6456.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6456.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Wed, 9 Jun 2021 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC-Africa Energy Dialogue to commence on 2 June]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[Vienna, Austria, 1 June 2021--The inaugural High-Level Meeting of the OPEC-Africa Energy Dialogue will be held on Wednesday, 2 June 2021, via videoconference.]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6451.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6451.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Tue, 1 Jun 2021 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[DoC Joint Technical Committee discusses oil market developments]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[Vienna, Austria, 31 May 2021--The Joint Technical Committee (JTC) convened for its 52nd Meeting via videoconference to review the conditions and emerging trends in the global oil market.]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6444.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6444.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Mon, 31 May 2021 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC’s 20th Annual Statistical Meeting begins]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[Vienna, Austria, 17 May 2021--The 20th Annual Statistical Meeting (ASM) of the Organization of the Petroleum Exporting Countries (OPEC) has started via videoconference.]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6437.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6437.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Mon, 17 May 2021 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[IEA-IEF-OPEC Symposium discusses COVID-19 recovery, post-pandemic prospects]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[Vienna, Austria, 28 April 2021--The International Energy Agency (IEA), the International Energy Forum (IEF) and the Organization of the Petroleum Exporting Countries (OPEC) today held the Fifth IEA-IEF-OPEC Symposium on Coal and Gas Market Outlooks via videoconference.]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6431.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6431.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Wed, 28 Apr 2021 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC Secretary General conveys his condolences to the people of Iraq following tragic fire at Ibn Al-Khatib Hospital]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[Vienna, Austria,&nbsp;26 April 2021--HE Mohammad Sanusi Barkindo, OPEC Secretary General, in a letter to HE Ihsan Abdul Jabbar Ismaael, Iraq’s Minister of Oil and Head of its Delegation to OPEC, extended his deep and sincere condolences to the Government and People of Iraq on the tragic loss of life following a fire in Ibn Al-Khatib Hospital in Baghdad, Iraq on Saturday, 24 April 2021.]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6428.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6428.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Mon, 26 Apr 2021 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[DoC JTC meets to review oil market developments]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[Vienna, Austria, 26 April 2021--The Joint Technical Committee (JTC) held its 51st meeting via videoconference to review oil market conditions in preparation for the 29th Meeting of the Joint Ministerial Monitoring Committee (JMMC) and the 16th OPEC and non-OPEC Ministerial Meeting (ONOMM) scheduled for Wednesday, 28 April 2021.]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6425.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6425.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Mon, 26 Apr 2021 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC Secretary General congratulates Professor Bordoff of Columbia University on his new assignment]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[Vienna, Austria, 23 April 2021--HE Mohammad Sanusi Barkindo, OPEC Secretary General, in a letter extended his congratulations to Professor Jason Bordoff, Founding Director of the Center on Global Energy Policy, on his new role as Co-Founding Dean of the Columbia Climate School.]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6424.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6424.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Fri, 23 Apr 2021 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[The Fifth IEA-IEF-OPEC Symposium on Coal and Gas Market Outlooks to be held on 28 April]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[Vienna, Austria, 23 April 2021--The International Energy Agency (IEA), the International Energy Forum (IEF) and the Organization of the Petroleum Exporting Countries (OPEC) will hold the Fifth Symposium on Coal and Gas Market Outlooks on Wednesday, 28 April 2021, via videoconference.]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6423.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6423.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Fri, 23 Apr 2021 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC to hold special workshop on energy and information technology]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[Vienna, Austria, 15 April 2021--The OPEC Secretariat will host the Third Workshop on Energy and Information Technology on Wednesday, 26 May 2021, via videoconference.]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6418.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6418.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Thu, 15 Apr 2021 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC participates in the International Monetary and Financial Committee Meeting]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[Vienna, Austria, 8 April 2021--OPEC Secretary General, HE Mohammad Sanusi Barkindo, took part in the International Monetary and Financial Committee Meeting, which is part of the spring meetings of the International Monetary Fund and the World Bank Group’s Board of Governors.]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6414.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6414.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Thu, 8 Apr 2021 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[DoC Joint Technical Committee convenes its 50th meeting]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[Vienna, Austria, 30 March 2021--The Joint Technical Committee (JTC) held its 50th meeting via videoconference to examine oil market developments and related trends.]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6397.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6397.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[DoC JTC discusses oil market developments]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[Vienna, Austria, 2 March 2021--The Joint Technical Committee (JTC) held its 49th meeting via videoconference in preparation for the 27th Meeting of the Joint Ministerial Monitoring Committee (JMMC) and the 14th OPEC and non-OPEC Ministerial Meeting (ONOMM) scheduled for Wednesday, 3 March 2021, and Thursday, 4 March 2021, respectively.]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6371.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6371.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Tue, 2 Mar 2021 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[Sheikh Ahmed Zaki Yamani: an OPEC and oil industry pioneer]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[It is with great sadness that OPEC has learnt of the passing of one of the Organization’s and the petroleum industry’s most respected and legendary leaders, Sheikh Ahmed Zaki Yamani, at the age of 90. The OPEC Secretariat extends its deepest and heartfelt condolences to the family and friends of Sheikh Yamani and to the Kingdom of Saudi Arabia.]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6368.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6368.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[DoC Joint Technical Committee convenes via videoconference]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[Vienna, Austria, 2 February 2021--The Joint Technical Committee (JTC) held its 48th meeting to assess oil market conditions and examine its developments and trends. The videoconference took place ahead of the 26th Meeting of the Joint Ministerial Monitoring Committee (JMMC) scheduled for tomorrow, Wednesday, 3 February 2021.]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6341.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6341.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Tue, 2 Feb 2021 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC congratulates the OPEC Fund on its 45th Anniversary]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[Vienna, Austria, 28 January 2021--HE Mohammad Sanusi Barkindo, OPEC Secretary General, in a letter extended his congratulations to HE Dr Abdulhamid Alkhalifa, Director-General of the OPEC Fund for International Development, on its 45th Anniversary.]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6339.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6339.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2021 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC Secretary General participates in Platt’s Americas Petroleum and Energy Virtual Conference]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[Vienna, Austria, 27 January 2021--HE Mohammad Sanusi Barkindo, OPEC Secretary General, participated via videoconference in the Americas Petroleum and Energy Conference organized by S&amp;P Global Platts. He focused on the importance of multilateralism in guiding the global energy transition.]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6333.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6333.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC and WEF discuss enhancing cooperation]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[Vienna, Austria, 25 January 2021--The Organization of the Petroleum Export Countries (OPEC) and the World Economic Forum (WEF) today held a bilateral meeting to explore possible avenues of cooperation and strengthen dialogue between the two Organizations.]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6323.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6323.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2021 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[Secretary General participates in Atlantic Council Global Energy Forum discussion]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[Vienna, Austria, 19 January 2021--OPEC’s Secretary General, HE Mohammad Sanusi Barkindo, participated in the Atlantic Council Global Energy Forum via videoconference.]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6320.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6320.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2021 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC participates in the 11th Gulf Intelligence ‘Global’ UAE Energy Forum]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[Vienna, Austria, 13 January 2021--OPEC Secretary General, Mohammad Sanusi Barkindo, participated via videoconference in the 11th ‘Global’ UAE Energy Forum, which focused on the 2021 oil and energy outlook.]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6314.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6314.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2021 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[The DoC’s Joint Technical Committee holds its 47th meeting]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[Vienna, Austria, 3 January 2021--The Joint Technical Committee (JTC) has convened for its 47th meeting via videoconference, in advance of the 25th Meeting of the Joint Ministerial Monitoring Committee (JMMC) and the 13th OPEC and non-OPEC Ministerial Meeting scheduled for Monday, 4 January 2021.]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6292.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6292.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Sun, 3 Jan 2021 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC offers it condolences on the sad passing of Francisco R. Parra]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[Vienna, Austria, 18 December 2020--It was with great sadness that OPEC has learnt of the passing of one of the Organization’s and the petroleum industry’s most respected leaders and scholars, HE Dr. Francisco R. Parra from Venezuela. The OPEC Secretariat extends its deepest and heartfelt condolences to his family and friends.]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6278.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6278.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Fri, 18 Dec 2020 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC participates in the Energy Charter Conference 2020]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[Vienna, Austria, 17 December 2020--HE Mohammad Sanusi Barkindo, OPEC Secretary General, participated in the 31st Meeting of the Energy Charter Conference under the theme “Energy efficiency for all: Innovations and investments.”]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6271.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6271.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2020 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC receives a letter of appreciation from UN Secretary General]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[Vienna, Austria, 17 December 2020--OPEC Secretary General, HE Mohammad Sanusi Barkindo, received a letter of appreciation from the Secretary General of the United Nations (UN), HE Antonio Guterres, in a response to a congratulatory letter sent by Secretary General Barkindo on the occasion of the 75th anniversary since the UN Charter entered into force in 1945.]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6276.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6276.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2020 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC conveys its condolences on the passing of Dr Abderrahman Khene]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[Vienna, Austria, 15 December 2020--OPEC Secretary General, HE Mohammad Sanusi Barkindo, and staff members of the Secretariat have offered their deep and sincere condolences following the sad passing of former OPEC Secretary General, HE Dr Abderrahman Khene of Algeria, aged 89.]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6269.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6269.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2020 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC Secretary General participates in Nigeria Oil and Gas Conference]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[Vienna, Austria, 8 December 2020--OPEC Secretary General, HE Mohammad Sanusi Barkindo, participated in the 2020 edition of the Nigeria Oil and Gas Conference via videoconference.]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6265.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6265.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Tue, 8 Dec 2020 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC, non-OPEC participants hold 8th Technical Meeting]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[Vienna, Austria, 27 November 2020--The 8th Technical Meeting of the OPEC and non-OPEC countries of the Declaration of Cooperation (DoC) has commenced via videoconference.]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6247.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6247.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Fri, 27 Nov 2020 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC’s Economic Commission Board holds its 134th meeting]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[Vienna, Austria, 25 November 2020--The OPEC Economic Commission Board (ECB) has convened for its 134th meeting via videoconference.]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6241.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6241.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Wed, 25 Nov 2020 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[The 46th Meeting of the Joint Technical Committee holds via videoconference]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[Vienna, Austria, 16 November 2020--The Joint Technical Committee (JTC) convened for its 46th meeting via videoconference, in preparation for the 24th Meeting of the Joint Ministerial Meeting (JMMC) scheduled for Tuesday, 17 November 2020.]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6229.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6229.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Mon, 16 Nov 2020 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC Secretary General attends 22nd GECF Ministerial Meeting]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[Vienna, Austria, 12 November 2020--OPEC Secretary General, Mohammad Sanusi Barkindo, today participated in the 22nd Meeting of the GECF Ministerial via videoconference.]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6225.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6225.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2020 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC participates in GECF Ministerial Roundtable on Natural Gas]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[Vienna, Austria,11 November 2020--OPEC Secretary General, Mohammad Sanusi Barkindo, participated today in a ministerial roundtable hosted by the Gas Exporting Countries Forum (GECF) to discuss natural gas and its key role as an energy source in a post-COVID world.]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6223.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6223.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2020 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC Secretary General participates in inaugural IEF podcast ]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[Vienna, Austria, 2 November 2020--Mohammad Sanusi Barkindo, OPEC Secretary General, and Joseph McMonigle, IEF Secretary General, today discussed a range of energy-related issues in the IEF’s inaugural podcast.]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6196.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6196.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Mon, 2 Nov 2020 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[The Joint Technical Committee convenes for its 45th meeting]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[Vienna, Austria, 15 October 2020--The 45th Meeting of the Joint Technical Committee (JTC) was held via videoconference, in preparation for the 23rd Meeting of the Joint Ministerial Meeting (JMMC) planned for 19 October 2020.]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6166.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6166.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Thu, 15 Oct 2020 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC-ECS-OPEC Fund hold second annual legal workshop]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[Vienna, Austria, 13 October 2020--The OPEC Secretariat held the Second annual OPEC legal workshop, in cooperation with the Energy Charter Secretariat (ECS) and the OPEC Fund for International Development, under the theme “The Law of the Energy Transition,” via videoconference.]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6160.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6160.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Tue, 13 Oct 2020 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC hosts the First OPEC-AFREC Technical Meeting ]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[Vienna, Austria, 6 October 2020--The OPEC Secretariat today held the first technical workshop of OPEC and the African Energy Commission (AFREC) via videoconference.]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6141.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6141.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Tue, 6 Oct 2020 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC to hold the second OPEC-ECS-OPEC Fund Annual Legal Workshop on the Law of the Energy Transition]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[The OPEC Secretariat will host the Second OPEC-ECS-OPEC Fund Annual Legal Workshop on the Law of the Energy Transition, on Tuesday 13&nbsp;October 2020, via videoconference]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6139.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6139.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Mon, 5 Oct 2020 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[Global oil demand and non-OPEC supply forecasting workshop concluded today]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[Vienna, Austria, 2 October 2020--The Technical Workshop with agencies forecasting global oil demand and non-OPEC supply concluded today, 2 October 2020.]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6135.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6135.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Fri, 2 Oct 2020 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC holds special workshop on forecasting global oil demand and non-OPEC supply]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[Vienna, Austria, 1 October 2020--The OPEC Secretariat hosted today a technical workshop via videoconference to discuss global oil demand and non-OPEC supply forecasting.]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6130.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6130.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Thu, 1 Oct 2020 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC holds coordination meeting on climate change]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[Vienna, Austria, 30 September 2020--The OPEC Secretariat held today the 18th Coordination Meeting on Climate Change via videoconference.]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6127.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6127.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2020 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC holds special workshop on climate change]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[Vienna, Austria, 29 September 2020--The OPEC Secretariat held today a technical workshop on climate response measures, as a key climate change issue with a far-reaching effect, via videoconference.]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6121.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6121.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Tue, 29 Sep 2020 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC’s ECB convenes for its 20th Special Meeting]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[Vienna, Austria, 22 September 2020--The Economic Commission Board (ECB) of OPEC has commenced its 20th Special Meeting via videoconference.]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6108.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6108.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Tue, 22 Sep 2020 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC to hold special workshop on energy and information technology]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[Vienna, Austria, 27 August 2020--The OPEC Secretariat will host the Second Workshop on Energy and Information Technology on Monday, 21 September 2020, via videoconference.]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6080.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6080.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2020 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC holds special workshop on secondary sources for oil data]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[Vienna, Austria, 9 July 2020--The OPEC Secretariat today held a technical workshop via videoconference with industry experts from select agencies that provide data from secondary sources to OPEC. The exchange aimed to share valuable insights and views among stakeholders on current oil market developments.]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6039.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6039.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Thu, 9 Jul 2020 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[IHS Markit interviews OPEC Secretary General on oil market developments]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[Vienna, Austria, 9 July 2020--OPEC Secretary General, HE Mohammad Sanusi Barkindo, was interviewed by Carlos Pascual, Senior Vice President at IHS Markit, to discuss the conditions and recent developments in the global oil market.]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6042.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6042.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Thu, 9 Jul 2020 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC Secretary General welcomes new OPEC President]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[Vienna, Austria, 6 July 2020--OPEC Secretary General, HE Mohammad Sanusi Barkindo, today held an online meeting with HE Abdelmadjid Attar, Algeria’s newly appointed Minister of Energy and President of the OPEC Conference, to discuss global oil market developments and the progress made in implementing the recent decisions of the OPEC Conference and the OPEC and non-OPEC Ministerial Meetings.]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6034.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6034.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Mon, 6 Jul 2020 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC Secretary General participates in high-level roundtable on Africa’s energy sector]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[Vienna, Austria, 30 June 2020--OPEC Secretary General, Mohammad Sanusi Barkindo, today participated in an African Ministerial Roundtable to discuss the impacts of the COVID-19 pandemic on Africa’s energy sector, as well as emerging challenges and opportunities. The roundtable was co-hosted by Senegal’s Ministry of Petroleum and the International Energy Agency (IEA).]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6027.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6027.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[HE Barkindo participates in a webinar hosted by the Canada-UAE Business Council]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[Vienna, Austria, 29 June 2020--OPEC Secretary General, HE Mohammad Sanusi Barkindo, together with HE Suhail Mohamed Al Mazrouei, UAE’s Minister of Energy and Industry, and HE Jason Kenney, Premier of Alberta, Canada, participated in a webinar dialogue session hosted by the Canada-UAE Business Council to discuss the ‘Energy issues in the post-COVID-19 world’.]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6024.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6024.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2020 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC Secretary General holds video meeting with Brazil’s Minister of Energy]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[Vienna, Austria, 22 June 2020--OPEC Secretary General, Mohammad Sanusi Barkindo, today met with Bento Albuquerque, Minister of Energy of Brazil, via videoconference to discuss recent oil market developments and the landmark decisions reached at the recent OPEC and non-OPEC Ministerial Meetings, as well as the outcome of the Emergency Meeting of the G20 Energy Ministers.]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6020.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6020.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jun 2020 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC to host special technical workshop “OPEC at 60”]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[Vienna, Austria, 17 June 2020-- The OPEC Secretariat will kick off the commemoration of its diamond anniversary by hosting a special technical workshop, titled “OPEC at 60”, on Tuesday, 23 June 2020, via videoconference.]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6007.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6007.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2020 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC Secretary General welcomes new Iraqi Oil Minister]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[Vienna, Austria, 17 June 2020--OPEC Secretary General, HE Mohammad Sanusi Barkindo, held a webinar meeting with Iraq’s new Oil Minister, HE Ihsan Abdul Jabbar Ismaael, to welcome the Minister to OPEC and discuss oil market developments and the outcome of the June Ministerial Meetings.]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6003.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/6003.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2020 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC’s Secretary General holds video meeting with Colombia’s Mines and Energy Minister]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[Vienna, Austria, 15 June 2020--OPEC Secretary General, HE Mohammad Sanusi Barkindo, held a bilateral webinar meeting today with HE Mar&iacute;a Fernanda Su&aacute;rez Londo&ntilde;o, Minister of Mines and Energy of Colombia.]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/5999.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/5999.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2020 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC Secretary General holds video meeting with Norway’s Minister of Petroleum and Energy]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[Vienna, Austria, 15 June 2020-- HE Mohammad Sanusi Barkindo, OPEC Secretary General, held a bilateral meeting via webinar with HE Tina Bru, Norway’s Minister of Petroleum and Energy. Topics include COVID-19’s impact on the global economy and oil market, the G20 Extraordinary Energy Ministers Meeting, and recent OPEC/non-OPEC Ministerial Meetings. Norway is a key non-OPEC producing country that has had a long and outstanding relationship with OPEC.]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/5995.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/5995.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2020 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC Secretary General holds video meeting with Alberta’s Energy Minister]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[Vienna, Austria, 10 June 2020--OPEC Secretary General, HE Mohammad Sanusi Barkindo, held a bilateral meeting with HE Sonya Savage, Minister of Energy for Alberta, Canada, via videoconference to discuss oil market developments and the historic decisions reached at the 11th OPEC and non-OPEC Ministerial Meeting held on 6 June 2020.]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/5986.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/5986.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[New Oil Minister confirms Iraq’s full commitment to OPEC and non-OPEC decisions]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[Vienna, Austria, 9 June 2020--Iraq’s new Minister of Oil, HE Ihsan Abdul Jabbar Ismaael, confirmed in a phone call with HRH Prince Abdul Aziz Bin Salman, Saudi Arabia’s Minister of Energy and Chairman of the OPEC and non-OPEC Ministerial Meeting, his country’s full commitment to the decisions taken at the 11th OPEC and non-OPEC Ministerial Meeting held on Saturday, 6 June 2020.]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/5982.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/5982.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Tue, 9 Jun 2020 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[Iraq renews its full commitment to OPEC+ decisions]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[Vienna, Austria, 6 June 2020--Iraq has renewed its full commitment to the oil production adjustments decisions reached in April 2020 by OPEC Members Countries and non-OPEC oil producing countries participating in the Declaration of Cooperation, noting the importance of team spirit and joint efforts to achieve stability and balance in the global oil market.]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/5962.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/5962.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Sat, 6 Jun 2020 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[The 7th Technical Meeting of OPEC and non-OPEC Countries of the DoC convenes via videoconference]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[Vienna, Austria, 4 June 2020--The Technical Meeting of OPEC and non-OPEC Countries participating under the Declaration of Cooperation (DoC) is convening for the 7th time, via videoconference in Vienna.]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/5956.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/5956.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Thu, 4 Jun 2020 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC Secretary General holds a bilateral meeting with India’s Minister for Petroleum and Natural Gas]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[Vienna, Austria, 3 June 2020--HE Mohammad Sanusi Barkindo, OPEC Secretary General, held a bilateral meeting with HE Dharmendra Pradhan, India’s Minister for Petroleum and Natural Gas, via videoconference to discuss the importance of the OPEC-India partnership and further ways to strengthen dialogue in the face of current challenges.]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/5948.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/5948.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Wed, 3 Jun 2020 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[The 133rd Meeting of the Economic Commission Board convenes via webinar]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[Vienna, Austria, 3 June 2020--The 133rd Economic Commission Board (ECB) of OPEC has convened by Webinar in Vienna. The ECB is the economic and technical statutory think-tank of the Organization. It meets routinely before the ordinary Ministerial Conference held biannually in June and December. The Board comprises of the Secretary General as the Chairman and National Representatives as members.]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/5945.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/5945.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Wed, 3 Jun 2020 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[Energy Minister: Alberta reduces oil production by around 1 mb/d, praises OPEC+ agreement]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[Vienna, Austria, 27 May 2020--The Minister of Energy for Alberta, Canada, HE Sonya Savage, supported the OPEC+ production adjustment agreement in April to battle COVID-19 demand destruction, and added that her province has reduced oil output by about 1 mb/d due to market forces.]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/5934.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/5934.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2020 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC Secretary General welcomes new Venezuelan Minister]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[Vienna, Austria, 27 May 2020--OPEC Secretary General, HE Mohammad Sanusi Barkindo, and HE Tareck El Aissami, Venezuela’s People's Minister of Petroleum, held a videoconference meeting today to welcome the minister to OPEC and discuss recent oil market developments and the upcoming June ministerial meetings.]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/5936.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/5936.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2020 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[Texas Railroad Commissioner: DoC adjustments bring stability to an energy market ‘in drastic need of it’]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[Vienna, Austria, 26 May 2020--Ryan Sitton, the Texas Railroad Commissioner who urged his state to adjust oil production, has praised the ‘Declaration of Cooperation’ (DoC) participating countries for their swift efforts to stabilize the global oil market.]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/5932.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/5932.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Tue, 26 May 2020 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[Equatorial Guinea fully implements voluntary production adjustment commitments]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[Vienna, Austria, 18 May 2020--Equatorial Guinea announced that it has fully adjusted its oil production in accordance with its commitment to oil market stability and the agreements reached at the 9th and 10th (Extraordinary) OPEC and non-OPEC Ministerial Meetings held on 9 and 12 April respectively, via videoconference.]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/5931.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/5931.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Mon, 18 May 2020 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[Letter of condolence on the passing of IR Iran’s OPEC Governor]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[Vienna, Austria, 16 May 2020--OPEC Secretary General, Mohammad Sanusi Barkindo, today sent a letter of condolence to HE Eng. Bijan Namdar Zanganeh, Minister of Petroleum of the Islamic Republic of Iran, following the passing away of Hossein Kazempour Ardebili, the country’s veteran representative to the OPEC Board of Governors.]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/5929.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/5929.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Sat, 16 May 2020 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[Algeria fully implements the voluntary adjustment agreement reached in April]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[Vienna, Austria, 15 May 2020--Algeria has confirmed that it has fully adjusted its oil production as part of its commitment to oil market stability and the agreements reached at the 9th and 10th (Extraordinary) OPEC and non-OPEC Ministerial Meetings held on 9 and 12 April respectively via videoconference.]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/5927.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/5927.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2020 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[Iraq is committed to the production adjustment agreement reached in April – Acting Oil Minister]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[Vienna, Austria, 14 May 2020--Iraq’s Minister of Finance and Acting Oil Minister, Dr Ali Alawi, emphasised in a statement Iraq’s commitment to the voluntary production adjustment agreement reached at the 9th and 10th (Extraordinary) OPEC and non-OPEC Ministerial Meetings held on 9 and 12 April respectively via videoconference.]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/5921.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/5921.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Thu, 14 May 2020 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[Energy Ministers of Saudi Arabia and the Russian Federation discuss oil market developments]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[Vienna, Austria, 13 May 2020--HRH Prince Abdul Aziz Bin Salman, Minister of Energy of the Kingdom of Saudi Arabia, and HE Alexander Novak, Minister of Energy of the Russian Federation, held a phone call as part of their regular consultations on oil market developments and issued a joint statement.]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/5919.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/5919.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Wed, 13 May 2020 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[Azerbaijan announces major oil production adjustments]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[Vienna, Austria, 1 May 2020--Azerbaijan’s state oil company SOCAR announces&nbsp; major oil production adjustment plans for 2020, 2021 and 2022 as part of Azerbaijan’s commitments to the voluntary production adjustment agreement reached at the 9th and 10th (Extraordinary) OPEC and non-OPEC Ministerial Meetings held on the 9th and 12th of April respectively via videoconference.]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/5915.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/5915.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Fri, 1 May 2020 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC President calls for full implementation of production adjustment agreement reached in April]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[Vienna, Austria, 1 May 2020--HE Mohamed Arkab, Algeria’s Minister of Energy and President of the OPEC Conference, has called on OPEC Members and non-OPEC oil producing countries participating in the Declaration of Cooperation to fully implement the agreements reached at the 9th and 10th (Extraordinary) OPEC and non-OPEC Ministerial Meetings held on 9 and 12 April respectively via videoconference.]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/5916.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/5916.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Fri, 1 May 2020 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[KPC informs customers of a new reduction in crude oil contractual volumes  ]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[Vienna, Austria, 30 April 2020--Kuwait Petroleum Corporation has informed its customers of a 22% reduction in their crude oil contractual volumes from July until December 2020, following reductions already made for May and June 2020, according to a letter sent by KPC to its customers.]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/5913.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/5913.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC hosts series of energy round table with reputable international institutions]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[The OPEC Secretariat has been hosting a series of energy round tables with select experts from international institutions, the oil industry and the financial community following two Extraordinary OPEC and non-OPEC Ministerial Meetings held via videoconference on 9 and 12 April.]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/5909.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/5909.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[ADNOC informs its customers of its production adjustment plans for May and June 2020]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[Vienna, Austria, 30 April 2020--Abu Dhabi National Oil Company (ADNOC) has notified its customers in a letter of its plans to voluntarily adjust its crude oil production in May and June 2020.]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/5914.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/5914.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[Norway adjusts its oil production to support oil market stability]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[Vienna, Austria, 30 April 2020--Norway has announced its plans to voluntarily adjust its production of crude oil to accelerate the stabilisation process in the global oil market, in light of the outbreak of COVID-19 and its impact on the global economy and oil demand.]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/5912.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/5912.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[Oman announces its oil production adjustment plans effective 1 May 2020]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[Vienna, Austria, 27 April 2020—HE Dr Mohammed Bin Hamad Al-Rumhy, Minister of Oil and Gas of the Sultanate of Oman, notified HE Mohammad Sanusi Barkindo, OPEC Secretary General, of the Sultanate's plans to voluntarily adjust oil production as part of its commitment to the Declaration of Cooperation.]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/5904.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/5904.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2020 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[Kuwait starts adjusting its oil production before May 1]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[HE Dr Khaled Ali Al-Fadhel, Kuwait’s Minister of Oil, Minister of Electricity and Water, and Chairman of the Board of Kuwait Petroleum Corporation (KPC), confirmed that the State of Kuwait has begun adjusting its oil production as part of its commitment in the Declaration of Cooperation to support the stability of the global oil market.]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/5902.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/5902.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Thu, 23 Apr 2020 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC Secretary General extends his condolences to President Buhari]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[OPEC Secretary General, HE Mohammad Sanusi Barkindo, extended his deepest condolences to HE Muhammadu Buhari, President of Nigeria, and its people for the tragic death of HE Mallam Abba Kyari, Nigeria's Chief of Staff, in a letter.]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/5901.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/5901.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2020 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[Saudi Aramco supplies 8.5 million bpd of oil as of May 1]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[Saudi Aramco will supply its customers with 8.5 million barrels per day of crude oil as of May 1, the company said in a statement.]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/5900.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/5900.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Fri, 17 Apr 2020 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[Ministers of Energy of Saudi Arabia and the Russian Federation discuss the oil market situation]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[HRH Prince Abdul Aziz Bin Salman, Minister of Energy of the Kingdom of Saudi Arabia, and HE Alexander Novak, Minister of Energy of the Russian Federation, held a constructive phone call as part of their regular consultations on the oil market situation and issued a joint statement.]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/5895.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/5895.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Thu, 16 Apr 2020 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[Dr. Fadhil J. Chalabi: a distinguished OPEC diplomat]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[TRIBUTE to Dr. Fadhil J. Chalabi]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/5778.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/5778.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Mon, 2 Dec 2019 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[Our commitment to OPEC-Non-OPEC agreement is total says Sylva as Nigeria meets OPEC target]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[Nigeria has given assurance of its total commitment to the full implementation of the Agreement entered into by OPEC and 10 Non-OPEC Member States also known as the OPEC plus or the Declaration of Cooperation (DoC) Countries.]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/5776.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/5776.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Sun, 1 Dec 2019 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[Goodwill Message to the Gas Exporting Countries Forum]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[Goodwill Message to the Gas Exporting Countries Forum on the occasion of the 5th Gas Summit of the GECF, 29 November 2019, Malabo, Equatorial Guinea.]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/5774.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/5774.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2019 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC Secretary General interviewed by Bloomberg in London]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/5697.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/5697.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2019 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[Bill Gates tells FT divestment from fossil fuels is not the answer]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/5672.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/5672.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2019 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[Saudi Energy Minister interviewed by CNN]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/5655.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/5655.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC Secretary General congratulates staff on the New Islamic Year]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[OPEC Secretary General, HE Mohammad Sanusi Barkindo, congratulated the Organization’s staff on the New Islamic Year - the Hijri year.]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/5653.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/5653.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2019 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[Iraq’s Minister of Oil: Cooperation will enhance market stability and investment potential]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/5621.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/5621.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2019 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC highlights its 2020 oil market forecast in the July Monthly Oil Market Report (MOMR), released today]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/5620.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/5620.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2019 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC Secretary General interviewed by Bloomberg in Baku, Azerbaijan]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/5444.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/5444.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2019 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC Secretary General interviewed by Bhushan Bahree, senior director of Energy at IHS Markit]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/5430.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/5430.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2019 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC Secretary General holds a Press Briefing at CERA Week 2019]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/5432.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/5432.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2019 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC Secretary General interviewed by CNBC at CERAWeek 2019]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/5419.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/5419.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2019 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC Secretary General congratulates Nigerian President Muhammadu Buhari on his reelection]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/5398.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/5398.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Wed, 27 Feb 2019 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC Secretary General congratulates President Vladimir Putin on his birthday anniversary]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/5172.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/5172.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Sun, 7 Oct 2018 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC to launch 2018 Annual Statistical Bulletin]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/5006.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/5006.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Wed, 6 Jun 2018 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[In pilgrimage tour, OPEC’s Secretary General visits India’s historic Digboi Refinery, first oil well]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/4949.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/4949.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Sat, 14 Apr 2018 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC’s Secretary General meets with India’s Petroleum and Natural Gas Minister ]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/4937.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/4937.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Tue, 10 Apr 2018 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC Secretary General meets Ambassador of the Russian Federation]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/4931.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/4931.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Mon, 9 Apr 2018 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC Secretary General meets with Iraqi Prime Minister]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/4912.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/4912.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Thu, 29 Mar 2018 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC Secretary General speaks at 4th Iraq Energy Forum]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/4908.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/4908.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Wed, 28 Mar 2018 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC Secretary General meets with Speaker of Iraq’s Parliament ]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/4904.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/4904.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Wed, 28 Mar 2018 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC Secretary General meets with Iraqi President]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/4899.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/4899.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Mon, 26 Mar 2018 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC Secretary General meets with Iraqi Oil Minister]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/4901.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/4901.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Mon, 26 Mar 2018 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC Secretary General meets with Azerbaijani President and Energy Minister]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/4893.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/4893.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Wed, 21 Mar 2018 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC Secretary General congratulates Chancellor Angela Merkel on her reelection]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/4891.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/4891.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Tue, 20 Mar 2018 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC Secretary General congratulates Russian President Vladimir Putin on his reelection]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/4886.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/4886.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Mon, 19 Mar 2018 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[Ministerial plenary at CERAWeek ]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/4869.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/4869.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Wed, 7 Mar 2018 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC Secretary General interviewed by CNBC at CERAWeek 2018]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/4872.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/4872.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Wed, 7 Mar 2018 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC and IEA share the stage at CERAWeek]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/4864.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/4864.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Tue, 6 Mar 2018 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC Secretary General congratulates HE Khalid A. Al-Falih on ’International Oil Diplomacy of the Year 2017’ Award]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/4843.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/4843.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2018 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC Secretary General meets with Nigerian Ambassador to Saudi Arabia]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/4841.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/4841.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2018 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC Secretary General delivers keynote speech at Egypt Petroleum Show 2018]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/4835.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/4835.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Tue, 13 Feb 2018 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC Secretary General participates in Egypt Petroleum Show 2018]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/4830.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/4830.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Mon, 12 Feb 2018 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC Secretary General meets with President of Ecuador and Minister of Hydrocarbons in Quito]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[Quito, Ecuador, 7 February 2018--HE Len&iacute;n Moreno, the President of Ecuador, yesterday received HE Mohammad Sanusi Barkindo, Secretary General of the Organization of the Petroleum Exporting Countries (OPEC), in Quito, Ecuador.]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/4819.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/4819.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Wed, 7 Feb 2018 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC Secretary General meets with Venezuela’s President, Petroleum Minister]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[Caracas, Venezuela, 6 February 2018--OPEC Secretary General, HE Mohammad Sanusi Barkindo, met with HE Nicol&aacute;s Maduro Moros, the President of Venezuela, in Caracas, where they discussed various issues related to energy and the oil markets.]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/4816.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/4816.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Tue, 6 Feb 2018 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC Secretary General meets with President of Azerbaijan]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/4808.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/4808.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jan 2018 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC Secretary General meets with Vice President of Nigeria]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/4812.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/4812.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jan 2018 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC Secretary General meets with Prime Minister of Denmark]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/4810.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/4810.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jan 2018 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC holds 2nd Technical Meeting of OPEC, Non-OPEC Participating Countries]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/4665.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/4665.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2017 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC Secretary General interviewed by Bloomberg at the Oil &amp; Money Conference]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/4586.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/4586.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Fri, 20 Oct 2017 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC Secretary General interviewed by Bloomberg TV at Russia Energy Week]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/4563.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/4563.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Fri, 6 Oct 2017 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC Secretary General interviewed by Russia Today in Moscow]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/4565.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/4565.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Fri, 6 Oct 2017 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[Russian Energy Week Forum plenary session]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/4562.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/4562.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Thu, 5 Oct 2017 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC Secretary General receives Ambassador of Kazakhstan, HE Kairat Sarybay]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/4428.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/4428.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2017 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC Secretary General attends the World Petroleum Congress in Istanbul]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/4400.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/4400.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jul 2017 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC Secretary General receives Nigerian Minister of Finance HE Kemi Adeosun]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/4392.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/4392.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Fri, 7 Jul 2017 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC Secretary General receives Minister of Finance of Ecuador, HE Carlos de la Torre]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/4396.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/4396.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Fri, 7 Jul 2017 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC and KAPSARC meet in Vienna]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[As a follow-up to discussions held in February this year between OPEC and the King Abdullah Petroleum Studies and Research Center (KAPSARC), a technical working session between the respective organizations was held at the OPEC Secretariat on 12 June 2017.]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/4375.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/4375.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2017 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC Participates in the Astana Expo 2017]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[The Organization of the Petroleum Exporting Countries (OPEC) is participating in the International Specialized Exhibition, Expo 2017, which opened in Astana, Kazakhstan, on 10 June and will run until 10 September 2017.]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/4363.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/4363.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jun 2017 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC Secretary General receives Mexican Deputy Secretary of Energy]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/4291.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/4291.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2017 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[Turkmenistan Ambassador visits OPEC Secretary General]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/4272.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/4272.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2017 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC Participates in Tehran’s Oil and Gas Exhibition ]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/4267.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/4267.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Fri, 12 May 2017 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[Angolan Ambassador visits OPEC Secretary General]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/4262.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/4262.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Thu, 4 May 2017 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC Secretary General meets with Dr. Chalabi]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/4223.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/4223.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2017 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC Secretary General discusses expanding cooperation with IEF Head]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/4178.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/4178.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Thu, 16 Mar 2017 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC Secretary General meets with Energy Charter Head]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/4164.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/4164.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2017 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC Secretary General interviewed by Daniel Yergin for CERAWeek Live]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/4144.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/4144.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Tue, 7 Mar 2017 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[The need for a stable world oil market ]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/4113.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/4113.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2017 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[&quot;OPEC and the future&quot; - An interview with the OPEC Secretary General]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/4082.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/4082.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Fri, 3 Feb 2017 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC Secretary General brings OPEC perspective to World Economic Forum talks]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/4076.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/4076.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2017 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC Secretary General named ‘Man of the Year’]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/4018.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/4018.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Thu, 5 Jan 2017 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC Secretary General Congratulates El-Badri on Platts Award]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/3998.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/3998.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2016 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[APPA pledges support for OPEC’s initiatives]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/3931.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/3931.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Fri, 2 Dec 2016 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC Secretary General receives Japanese State Minister of Economy, Trade and Industry]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/3932.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/3932.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Fri, 2 Dec 2016 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC Secretary General meets Heads of Delegation on eve of Conference]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/3910.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/3910.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2016 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[Mayor of Vienna receives OPEC Secretary General]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/3901.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/3901.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Thu, 24 Nov 2016 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC Secretary General participates in ADIPEC 2016 ]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/3860.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/3860.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2016 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[Austrian Federal Chancellor receives OPEC Secretary General]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/3862.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/3862.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2016 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[“Significant progress” made since Algiers Accord - Barkindo]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/3828.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/3828.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Tue, 1 Nov 2016 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC Secretary General meets with Azerbaijan’s Energy Minister]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/3816.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/3816.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Sat, 29 Oct 2016 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC Secretary General speaks at Oil &amp; Money conference in London]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/3786.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/3786.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2016 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC Secretary General visits the Center for Strategic and International Studies, Washington D.C.]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/3745.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/3745.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2016 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC Ministers, Secretary General hold oil talks in Istanbul]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/3752.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/3752.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2016 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC Secretary General in panel debate at World Energy Congress]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/3757.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/3757.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2016 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC Secretary General attends Presidential Plenary and follow-up sessions at the World Energy Congress]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/3747.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/3747.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2016 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC Secretary General to attend annual meetings of the IMF and the World Bank Group]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/3744.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/3744.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Fri, 7 Oct 2016 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC Secretary General attends opening of 15th IEF Ministerial]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/3681.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/3681.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2016 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC Secretary General receives Director General of OFID]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/3680.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/3680.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2016 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[Conference President, other dignitaries meet OPEC Secretary General in Algiers]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/3664.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/3664.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2016 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[Nigeria hopeful crude oil price will rise to its true value soon]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/3662.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/3662.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Fri, 23 Sep 2016 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC Secretary General receives Nigerian community leaders]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/3646.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/3646.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2016 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[UAE Ambassador visits OPEC Secretary General]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/3644.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/3644.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2016 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC Secretary General receives Venezuelan Ambassador]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/3631.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/3631.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Fri, 2 Sep 2016 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC Secretary General meets Nigerian Ambassador]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/3627.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/3627.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Tue, 30 Aug 2016 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC Secretary General visits OFID Director General]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/3625.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/3625.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Tue, 30 Aug 2016 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC Secretary General receives Ambassador of the Russian Federation]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/3623.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/3623.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2016 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC Secretary General receives Ambassador of Indonesia]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/3613.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/3613.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2016 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC Secretary General receives Libyan Ambassador]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/3621.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/3621.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2016 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC Secretary General meets Algerian Ambassador in Vienna ]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/3610.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/3610.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Tue, 23 Aug 2016 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC Secretary General receives Iraqi Ambassador]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/3603.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/3603.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Tue, 23 Aug 2016 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC Secretary General receives Qatari Ambassador]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/3597.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/3597.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2016 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[Moroccan Ambassador discusses COP 22 with OPEC Secretary General]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/3592.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/3592.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Fri, 19 Aug 2016 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC Secretary General receives IR Iran’s Ambassador to international organizations]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/3588.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/3588.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Fri, 12 Aug 2016 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC saddened at news of Robert Mabro’s passing away]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/3579.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/3579.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Mon, 8 Aug 2016 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC Secretary General receives first official visit at OPEC Secretariat]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/3566.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/3566.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Mon, 8 Aug 2016 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[OPEC Secretariat sends condolences to Ecuador]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/3461.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/3461.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2016 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[Member Country professionals attend training on OPEC and the oil market]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/3440.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/3440.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Thu, 3 Mar 2016 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[Equitable energy ambitions - OPEC Secretary General]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[The world’s leading economies must strike a balance between renewables development and providing access to energy for those currently living without, ensuring that modern energy services are a realistic and attainable goal for all, writes Abdalla Salem El-Badri, Secretary General, OPEC.]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/3164.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/3164.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Thu, 5 Nov 2015 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[Students express appreciation for “unique” OPEC Seminar experience]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[Vienna, Austria, 17 June 2015--A group of students that attended the 6th OPEC International Seminar in Vienna on June 3-4 has written to the Organization, thanking it for providing them with a “unique” experience and for “promoting the youth of our countries”.]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/3064.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/3064.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2015 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[Security of energy supplies inextricably linked with demand - El-Badri]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[Vienna, Austria, 8 May 2015--An Article by OPEC Secretary General, HE Abdalla Salem El-Badri, for the publication produced for the 41st G7 Summit, which will be held in Schloss Elmau, Bavaria, Germany on June 7–8, 2015.]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/3013.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/3013.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Fri, 8 May 2015 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>






            <item>
                <title><![CDATA[Interview by OPEC&#39;s Director of Research Division]]></title>
                <description><![CDATA[Vienna, Austria, 7 May 2015--The Director of Research Division at the OPEC Secretariat, Dr. Omar S. Abdul-Hamid, gave an interview to Siemens magazine "Pictures of the Future". ]]></description>
                <link><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/3011.htm]]></link>
                <guid><![CDATA[http://www.opec.org/opec_web/en/3011.htm]]></guid>
                <pubDate>Thu, 7 May 2015 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
            </item>




    </channel>
</rss>