<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<rdf:RDF
 xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
 xmlns="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/"
 xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
 xmlns:taxo="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/taxonomy/"
 xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
 xmlns:syn="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
 xmlns:admin="http://webns.net/mvcb/"
>

<channel rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/">
<title>physics.med-ph updates on arXiv.org</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">Physics -- Medical Physics (physics.med-ph) updates on the arXiv.org e-print archive</description>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:date>2022-11-03T20:30:00-05:00</dc:date>
<dc:publisher>help@arxiv.org</dc:publisher>
<dc:subject>Physics -- Medical Physics</dc:subject>
<syn:updateBase>1901-01-01T00:00+00:00</syn:updateBase>
<syn:updateFrequency>1</syn:updateFrequency>
<syn:updatePeriod>daily</syn:updatePeriod>
<items>
 <rdf:Seq>
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01372" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01375" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01626" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01892" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.02024" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.02035" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2204.08249" />
 </rdf:Seq>
</items>
<image rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif" />
</channel>
<image rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif">
<title>arXiv.org</title>
<url>http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif</url>
<link>http://arxiv.org/</link>
</image>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01372">
<title>Investigating the robustness of a learning-based method for quantitative phase retrieval from propagation-based x-ray phase contrast measurements under laboratory conditions. (arXiv:2211.01372v1 [physics.med-ph])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01372</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Quantitative phase retrieval (QPR) in propagation-based x-ray phase contrast
imaging of heterogeneous and structurally complicated objects is challenging
under laboratory conditions due to partial spatial coherence and
polychromaticity. A learning-based method (LBM) provides a non-linear approach
to this problem while not being constrained by restrictive assumptions about
object properties and beam coherence. In this work, a LBM was assessed for its
applicability under practical scenarios by evaluating its robustness and
generalizability under typical experimental variations. Towards this end, an
end-to-end LBM was employed for QPR under laboratory conditions and its
robustness was investigated across various system and object conditions. The
robustness of the method was tested via varying propagation distances and its
generalizability with respect to object structure and experimental data was
also tested. Although the LBM was stable under the studied variations, its
successful deployment was found to be affected by choices pertaining to data
pre-processing, network training considerations and system modeling. To our
knowledge, we demonstrated for the first time, the potential applicability of
an end-to-end learning-based quantitative phase retrieval method, trained on
simulated data, to experimental propagation-based x-ray phase contrast
measurements acquired under laboratory conditions. We considered conditions of
polychromaticity, partial spatial coherence, and high noise levels, typical to
laboratory conditions. This work further explored the robustness of this method
to practical variations in propagation distances and object structure with the
goal of assessing its potential for experimental use. Such an exploration of
any LBM (irrespective of its network architecture) before practical deployment
provides an understanding of its potential behavior under experimental
settings.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Deshpande_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Rucha Deshpande&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Avachat_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ashish Avachat&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Brooks_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Frank J. Brooks&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Anastasio_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Mark A. Anastasio&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01375">
<title>High-speed processing of X-ray wavefront marking data with the Unified Modulated Pattern Analysis (UMPA) model. (arXiv:2211.01375v1 [physics.med-ph])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01375</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Wavefront-marking X-ray imaging techniques use e.g., sandpaper or a grating
to generate intensity fluctuations, and analyze their distortion by the sample
in order to retrieve attenuation, phase-contrast, and dark-field information.
Phase contrast yields an improved visibility of soft-tissue specimens, while
dark-field reveals small-angle scatter from sub-resolution structures. Both
have found many biomedical and engineering applications. The previously
developed Unified Modulated Pattern Analysis (UMPA) model extracts these
modalities from wavefront-marking data. We here present a new UMPA
implementation, capable of rapidly processing large datasets and featuring
capabilities to greatly extend the field of view. We also discuss possible
artifacts and additional new features.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Marco_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Fabio De Marco&lt;/a&gt; (1,2), &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Savatovic_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Sara Savatovi&amp;#x107;&lt;/a&gt; (1,2), &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Smith_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ronan Smith&lt;/a&gt; (3), &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Trapani_V/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Vittorio Di Trapani&lt;/a&gt; (1,2), &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Margini_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Marco Margini&lt;/a&gt; (1,2), &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Lautizi_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ginevra Lautizi&lt;/a&gt; (1,2), &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Thibault_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Pierre Thibault&lt;/a&gt; (1,2) ((1) Department of Physics, University of Trieste, (2) Elettra-Sincrotrone Trieste, (3) Department of Physics, University of Southampton)</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01626">
<title>FEniCS implementation of the Virtual Fields Method (VFM) for nonhomogeneous hyperelastic identification. (arXiv:2211.01626v1 [physics.med-ph])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01626</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;It is of great significance to identify the nonhomogeneous distribution of
material properties in human tissues for different clinical and medical
applications. This leads to the requirement of solving an inverse problem in
elasticity. The virtual fields method (VFM) is a rather recent inverse method
with remarkable computational efficiency compared with the optimization-based
methods. In this study, we aim to identify nonhomogeneous hyperelastic material
properties using the VFM. We propose two novel algorithms, RE-VFM and NO-VFM.
In RE-VFM, the solid is partitioned in different regions and the elastic
properties of each region are determined. In NO-VFM, 2 the distribution of
elastic properties is completely reconstructed through the inverse problem
without partitioning the solid. As the VFM requires to use virtual fields, we
proposed an efficient way to construct them and implemented the approach in the
FEniCS package. We validated the proposed methods on several examples,
including a bilayer structure, a lamina cribosa (LC) model and a cube model
embedded with a spherical inclusion. The numerical examples illustrate the
feasibility of both RE-VFM and NO-VFM. Notably, the spatial variations of the
Young&apos;s modulus distribution can be recovered accurately within only 5
iterations. The obtained results reveal the potential of the proposed methods
for future clinical applications such as estimating the risk of vision loss
related to glaucoma and detecting tumors.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Deng_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jianwei Deng&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Guo_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xu Guo&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Mei_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yue Mei&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Avril_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Stephane Avril&lt;/a&gt; (SAINBIOSE-ENSMSE)</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01892">
<title>Deep meta-learning for the selection of accurate ultrasound based breast mass classifier. (arXiv:2211.01892v1 [eess.IV])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01892</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Standard classification methods based on handcrafted morphological and
texture features have achieved good performance in breast mass differentiation
in ultrasound (US). In comparison to deep neural networks, commonly perceived
as &quot;black-box&quot; models, classical techniques are based on features that have
well-understood medical and physical interpretation. However, classifiers based
on morphological features commonly underperform in the presence of the
shadowing artifact and ill-defined mass borders, while texture based
classifiers may fail when the US image is too noisy. Therefore, in practice it
would be beneficial to select the classification method based on the appearance
of the particular US image. In this work, we develop a deep meta-network that
can automatically process input breast mass US images and recommend whether to
apply the shape or texture based classifier for the breast mass
differentiation. Our preliminary results demonstrate that meta-learning
techniques can be used to improve the performance of the standard classifiers
based on handcrafted features. With the proposed meta-learning based approach,
we achieved the area under the receiver operating characteristic curve of 0.95
and accuracy of 0.91.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/eess/1/au:+Byra_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Michal Byra&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/eess/1/au:+Karwat_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Piotr Karwat&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/eess/1/au:+Ryzhankow_I/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ivan Ryzhankow&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/eess/1/au:+Komorowski_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Piotr Komorowski&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/eess/1/au:+Klimonda_Z/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ziemowit Klimonda&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/eess/1/au:+Fura_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Lukasz Fura&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/eess/1/au:+Pawlowska_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Anna Pawlowska&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/eess/1/au:+Zolek_N/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Norbert Zolek&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/eess/1/au:+Litniewski_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jerzy Litniewski&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.02024">
<title>fMRI from EEG is only Deep Learning away: the use of interpretable DL to unravel EEG-fMRI relationships. (arXiv:2211.02024v1 [physics.med-ph])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.02024</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The access to activity of subcortical structures offers unique opportunity
for building intention dependent brain-computer interfaces, renders abundant
options for exploring a broad range of cognitive phenomena in the realm of
affective neuroscience including complex decision making processes and the
eternal free-will dilemma and facilitates diagnostics of a range of
neurological deceases. So far this was possible only using bulky, expensive and
immobile fMRI equipment. Here we present an interpretable domain grounded
solution to recover the activity of several subcortical regions from the
multichannel EEG data and demonstrate up to 60% correlation between the actual
subcortical blood oxygenation level dependent sBOLD signal and its EEG-derived
twin. Then, using the novel and theoretically justified weight interpretation
methodology we recover individual spatial and time-frequency patterns of scalp
EEG predictive of the hemodynamic signal in the subcortical nuclei. The
described results not only pave the road towards wearable subcortical activity
scanners but also showcase an automatic knowledge discovery process facilitated
by deep learning technology in combination with an interpretable domain
constrained architecture and the appropriate downstream task.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Kovalev_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Alexander Kovalev&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Mikheev_I/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ilia Mikheev&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Ossadtchi_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Alexei Ossadtchi&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.02035">
<title>A Retrospective Study on the Investigation of Potential Clinical Benefits of Online Adaptive Proton Therapy for Head and Neck Cancer. (arXiv:2211.02035v1 [physics.med-ph])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.02035</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Online adaptive proton therapy (APT) is an ideal solution theoretically,
which however is challenging to proton clinics. Although multiple groups have
been endeavoring to develop online APT technology, there is a concern in the
radiotherapy community about the necessity of online APT because of its unknown
impact on treatment outcomes. Hence, we have performed a retrospective study to
investigate the potential clinical effects of online APT for HN cancer patients
in relative to the current offline APT via simulations. To mimic an online APT
treatment course, we have recalculated and evaluated the actual dose of the
current treatment plan on patient actual treatment anatomy captured by cone
beam CT for each fraction. The cumulative dose of simulated online APT courses
was compared to actual offline APT courses and the initially designed treatment
plan dose. For patients 1 and 2, the simulated online ART course maintained a
relatively higher CTV dose coverages than the offline ART course, particularly
for CTV-Low, which led to an improvement of 2.66% and 4.52% in TCP of CTV-Low.
For patients 3 and 4, with clinically comparable CTV dose coverages, the
simulated online ART course achieved better OAR sparing than the offline ART
course. The mean doses of right parotid and oral cavity were decreased from
29.52 Gy relative biological effectiveness (RBE) and 41.89 Gy RBE to 22.16 Gy
RBE and 34.61 Gy RBE for patient 3, leading to a reduce of 1.67% and 3.40% in
NTCP for the two organs. Compared to the current clinical practice, the
retrospective study indicated that online APT tended to spare more normal
tissues by achieving the clinical goal with merely half of the positional
uncertainty margin. Future studies are needed to help identify the patients
with large potential benefits prior to treatment to conserve scarce clinical
resources.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Chang_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Chih-Wei Chang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Bohannon_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Duncan Bohannon&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Tian_Z/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Zhen Tian&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Wang_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yinan Wang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Mcdonald_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Mark W. Mcdonald&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Yu_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;David S. Yu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Liu_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Tian Liu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Zhou_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jun Zhou&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Yang_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xiaofeng Yang&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2204.08249">
<title>Label-free metabolic imaging of non-alcoholic-fatty-liver-disease (NAFLD) liver by volumetric dynamic optical coherence tomography. (arXiv:2204.08249v2 [physics.med-ph] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2204.08249</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Label-free metabolic imaging of non-alcoholic fatty liver disease (NAFLD)
mouse liver is demonstrated ex vivo by dynamic optical coherence tomography
(OCT). The NAFLD mouse is a methionine choline-deficient (MCD)-diet model, and
two mice fed MCD diet for 1 and 2 weeks are involved in addition to a
normal-diet mouse. The dynamic OCT is based on repeating raster scan and
logarithmic intensity variance (LIV) analysis which enables volumetric
metabolic imaging with a standard-speed (50,000 A-lines/s) OCT system.
Metabolic domains associated with lipid droplet accumulation and inflammation
are clearly visualized three-dimensionally. Particularly, the normal-diet liver
exhibits highly metabolic vessel-like structures of peri-vascular hepatic
zones. The 1-week MCD-diet liver shows ring-shaped highly metabolic structures
formed with lipid droplets. The 2-week MCD-diet liver exhibits fragmented
vessel-like structures associated with inflammation. These results imply that
volumetric LIV imaging is useful for visualizing and assessing NAFLD
abnormalities.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Mukherjee_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Pradipta Mukherjee&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Fukuda_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Shinichi Fukuda&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Lukmanto_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Donny Lukmanto&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Yamashita_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Toshiharu Yamashita&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Okada_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Kosuke Okada&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Makita_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Shuichi Makita&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+El_Sadek_I/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ibrahim Abd El-Sadek&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Miyazawa_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Arata Miyazawa&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Zhu_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Lida Zhu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Morishita_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Rion Morishita&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Lichtenegger_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Antonia Lichtenegger&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Oshika_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Tetsuro Oshika&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Yasuno_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yoshiaki Yasuno&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
</rdf:RDF>