<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<rdf:RDF
 xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
 xmlns="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/"
 xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
 xmlns:taxo="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/taxonomy/"
 xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
 xmlns:syn="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
 xmlns:admin="http://webns.net/mvcb/"
>

<channel rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/">
<title>cond-mat.other updates on arXiv.org</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">Condensed Matter -- Other Condensed Matter (cond-mat.other) updates on the arXiv.org e-print archive</description>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:date>2022-11-03T20:30:00-05:00</dc:date>
<dc:publisher>help@arxiv.org</dc:publisher>
<dc:subject>Condensed Matter -- Other Condensed Matter</dc:subject>
<syn:updateBase>1901-01-01T00:00+00:00</syn:updateBase>
<syn:updateFrequency>1</syn:updateFrequency>
<syn:updatePeriod>daily</syn:updatePeriod>
<items>
 <rdf:Seq>
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01560" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01857" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2208.13858" />
 </rdf:Seq>
</items>
<image rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif" />
</channel>
<image rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif">
<title>arXiv.org</title>
<url>http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif</url>
<link>http://arxiv.org/</link>
</image>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01560">
<title>Imaging the decay of quantized vortex rings to decipher quantum dissipation. (arXiv:2211.01560v1 [cond-mat.quant-gas])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01560</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Like many quantum fluids, superfluid helium-4 (He II) can be considered as a
mixture of two miscible fluid components: an inviscid superfluid and a viscous
normal fluid consisting of thermal quasiparticles [1]. A mutual friction
between the two fluids can emerge due to quasiparticles scattering off
quantized vortex lines in the superfluid [2]. This quantum dissipation
mechanism is the key for understanding various fascinating behaviors of the
two-fluid system [3,4]. However, due to the lack of experimental data for
guidance, modeling the mutual friction between individual vortices and the
normal fluid remains an unsettled topic despite decades of research [5-10].
Here we report an experiment where we visualize the motion of quantized vortex
rings in He II by decorating them with solidified deuterium tracer particles.
By examining how the rings spontaneously shrink and accelerate, we provide
unequivocal evidences showing that only a recent theory [9] which accounts for
the coupled motion of the two fluids with a self-consistent local friction can
reproduce the observed ring dynamics. Our work eliminates long-standing
ambiguities in our theoretical description of the vortex dynamics in He II,
which will have a far-reaching impact since similar mutual friction concept has
been adopted for a wide variety of quantum two-fluid systems, including atomic
Bose-Einstein condensates (BECs) [11,12], superfluid neutron stars [13-15], and
gravity-mapped holographic superfluid [16,17].
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Tang_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yuan Tang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Guo_W/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Wei Guo&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Kobayashi_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Hiromichi Kobayashi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Yui_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Satoshi Yui&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Tsubota_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Makoto Tsubota&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Kanai_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Toshiaki Kanai&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01857">
<title>Algebra of the spinor invariants and the relativistic hydrogen atom. (arXiv:2211.01857v1 [quant-ph])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01857</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;It is shown that the Dirac equation with the Coulomb potential can be solved
using the algebra of the three spinor invariants of the Dirac equation without
the involvement of the methods of supersymmetric quantum mechanics. The Dirac
Hamiltonian is invariant with respect to the rotation transformation, which
indicates the dynamical (hidden) symmetry $ SU(2) $ of the Dirac equation. The
total symmetry of the Dirac equation is the symmetry $ SO(3) \otimes SU(2) $.
The generator of the $ SO(3) $ symmetry group is given by the total momentum
operator, and the generator of $ SU(2) $ group is given by the rotation of the
vector-states in the spinor space, determined by the Dirac, Johnson-Lippmann,
and the new spinor invariants. It is shown that using algebraic approach to the
Dirac problem allows one to calculate the eigenstates and eigenenergies of the
relativistic hydrogen atom and reveals the fundamental role of the principal
quantum number as an independent number, even though it is represented as the
combination of other quantum numbers.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Eremko_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;A.A. Eremko&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Brizhik_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;L.S. Brizhik&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Loktev_V/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;V.M. Loktev&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2208.13858">
<title>Unitary evolution for a two-level quantum system in fractional-time scenario. (arXiv:2208.13858v2 [quant-ph] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2208.13858</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The time-evolution operator obtained from the fractional-time Schr\&quot;{o}dinger
equation (FTSE) is said to be non-unitary since it does not preserve the norm
of the vector state in time. As done in the time-dependent non-Hermitian
quantum formalism, for a traceless non-Hermitian two-level quantum system, we
demonstrate that it is possible to map the non-unitary time-evolution operator
in a unitary one. It is done by considering a dynamical Hilbert space with a
time-dependent metric operator, constructed from a Hermitian time-dependent
Dyson map, in respect to which the system evolves in a unitary way, and the
standard quantum mechanics interpretation can be made properly. To elucidate
our approach, we consider three examples of Hamiltonian operators and their
corresponding unitary dynamics obtained from the solutions of FTSE, and the
respective Dyson maps.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Cius_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;D. Cius&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Menon_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;L. Menon Jr.&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Santos_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;M. A. F. dos Santos&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Castro_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;A. S. M. de Castro&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Andrade_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;F. M. Andrade&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
</rdf:RDF>