<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<rdf:RDF
 xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
 xmlns="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/"
 xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
 xmlns:taxo="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/taxonomy/"
 xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
 xmlns:syn="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
 xmlns:admin="http://webns.net/mvcb/"
>

<channel rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/">
<title>cs.DL updates on arXiv.org</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">Computer Science -- Digital Libraries (cs.DL) updates on the arXiv.org e-print archive</description>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:date>2022-11-03T20:30:00-05:00</dc:date>
<dc:publisher>help@arxiv.org</dc:publisher>
<dc:subject>Computer Science -- Digital Libraries</dc:subject>
<syn:updateBase>1901-01-01T00:00+00:00</syn:updateBase>
<syn:updateFrequency>1</syn:updateFrequency>
<syn:updatePeriod>daily</syn:updatePeriod>
<items>
 <rdf:Seq>
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01936" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/1909.08191" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2103.11909" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2103.12450" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2204.03383" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2204.13384" />
 </rdf:Seq>
</items>
<image rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif" />
</channel>
<image rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif">
<title>arXiv.org</title>
<url>http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif</url>
<link>http://arxiv.org/</link>
</image>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01936">
<title>Differences in collaboration structures and impact among prominent researchers in Europe and North America. (arXiv:2211.01936v1 [physics.soc-ph])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01936</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Scientists collaborate through intricate networks, which impact the quality
and scope of their research. At the same time, funding and institutional
arrangements, as well as scientific and political cultures, affect the
structure of collaboration networks. Since such arrangements and cultures
differ across regions in the world in systematic ways, we surmise that
collaboration networks and impact should also differ systematically across
regions. To test this, we compare the structure of collaboration networks among
prominent researchers in North America and Europe. We find that prominent
researchers in Europe establish denser collaboration networks, whereas those in
North-America establish more decentralized networks. We also find that the
impact of the publications of prominent researchers in North America is
significantly higher than for those in Europe, both when they collaborate with
other prominent researchers and when they do not. Although Europeans
collaborate with other prominent researchers more often, which increases their
impact, we also find that repeated collaboration among prominent researchers
decreases the synergistic effect of collaborating.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Danus_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Lluis Danus&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Muntaner_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Carles Muntaner&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Krauss_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Alexander Krauss&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Sales_Pardo_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Marta Sales-Pardo&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Guimera_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Roger Guimera&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/1909.08191">
<title>Exploring Scholarly Data by Semantic Query on Knowledge Graph Embedding Space. (arXiv:1909.08191v2 [cs.AI] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/1909.08191</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The trends of open science have enabled several open scholarly datasets which
include millions of papers and authors. Managing, exploring, and utilizing such
large and complicated datasets effectively are challenging. In recent years,
the knowledge graph has emerged as a universal data format for representing
knowledge about heterogeneous entities and their relationships. The knowledge
graph can be modeled by knowledge graph embedding methods, which represent
entities and relations as embedding vectors in semantic space, then model the
interactions between these embedding vectors. However, the semantic structures
in the knowledge graph embedding space are not well-studied, thus knowledge
graph embedding methods are usually only used for knowledge graph completion
but not data representation and analysis. In this paper, we propose to analyze
these semantic structures based on the well-studied word embedding space and
use them to support data exploration. We also define the semantic queries,
which are algebraic operations between the embedding vectors in the knowledge
graph embedding space, to solve queries such as similarity and analogy between
the entities on the original datasets. We then design a general framework for
data exploration by semantic queries and discuss the solution to some
traditional scholarly data exploration tasks. We also propose some new
interesting tasks that can be solved based on the uncanny semantic structures
of the embedding space.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Tran_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Hung Nghiep Tran&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Takasu_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Atsuhiro Takasu&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2103.11909">
<title>Identifying Machine-Paraphrased Plagiarism. (arXiv:2103.11909v5 [cs.CL] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2103.11909</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Employing paraphrasing tools to conceal plagiarized text is a severe threat
to academic integrity. To enable the detection of machine-paraphrased text, we
evaluate the effectiveness of five pre-trained word embedding models combined
with machine learning classifiers and state-of-the-art neural language models.
We analyze preprints of research papers, graduation theses, and Wikipedia
articles, which we paraphrased using different configurations of the tools
SpinBot and SpinnerChief. The best performing technique, Longformer, achieved
an average F1 score of 80.99% (F1=99.68% for SpinBot and F1=71.64% for
SpinnerChief cases), while human evaluators achieved F1=78.4% for SpinBot and
F1=65.6% for SpinnerChief cases. We show that the automated classification
alleviates shortcomings of widely-used text-matching systems, such as Turnitin
and PlagScan. To facilitate future research, all data, code, and two web
applications showcasing our contributions are openly available.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Wahle_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jan Philip Wahle&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Ruas_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Terry Ruas&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Foltynek_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Tom&amp;#xe1;&amp;#x161; Folt&amp;#xfd;nek&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Meuschke_N/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Norman Meuschke&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Gipp_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Bela Gipp&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2103.12450">
<title>Are Neural Language Models Good Plagiarists? A Benchmark for Neural Paraphrase Detection. (arXiv:2103.12450v4 [cs.CL] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2103.12450</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The rise of language models such as BERT allows for high-quality text
paraphrasing. This is a problem to academic integrity, as it is difficult to
differentiate between original and machine-generated content. We propose a
benchmark consisting of paraphrased articles using recent language models
relying on the Transformer architecture. Our contribution fosters future
research of paraphrase detection systems as it offers a large collection of
aligned original and paraphrased documents, a study regarding its structure,
classification experiments with state-of-the-art systems, and we make our
findings publicly available.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Wahle_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jan Philip Wahle&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Ruas_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Terry Ruas&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Meuschke_N/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Norman Meuschke&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Gipp_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Bela Gipp&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2204.03383">
<title>Overlay journals: a study of the current landscape. (arXiv:2204.03383v3 [cs.DL] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2204.03383</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Overlay journals are characterised by their articles being published on open
access repositories, often already starting in their initial preprint form as a
prerequisite for submission to the journal prior to initiating the peer-review
process. In this study we aimed to identify currently active overlay journals
and examine their characteristics. We utilised an explorative web search and
contacted key service providers for additional information. The final sample
consisted of 34 overlay journals. While the results show that new overlay
journals have been actively established within recent years, the current
presence of overlay journals remains diminutive compared to the overall number
of open access journals. Most overlay journals publish articles in natural
sciences, mathematics or computer sciences, and are commonly published by
groups of academics rather than formal organisations. They may also rank highly
within the traditional journal citation metrics. None of the investigated
journals required fees from authors, which is likely related to the
cost-effective aspects of the overlay publishing model. Both the growth in
adoption of open access preprint repositories and researchers&apos; willingness to
publish in overlay journals will determine the model&apos;s wider impact on
scholarly publishing.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Rousi_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Antti Mikael Rousi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Laakso_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Mikael Laakso&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2204.13384">
<title>D3: A Massive Dataset of Scholarly Metadata for Analyzing the State of Computer Science Research. (arXiv:2204.13384v3 [cs.DL] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2204.13384</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;DBLP is the largest open-access repository of scientific articles on computer
science and provides metadata associated with publications, authors, and
venues. We retrieved more than 6 million publications from DBLP and extracted
pertinent metadata (e.g., abstracts, author affiliations, citations) from the
publication texts to create the DBLP Discovery Dataset (D3). D3 can be used to
identify trends in research activity, productivity, focus, bias, accessibility,
and impact of computer science research. We present an initial analysis focused
on the volume of computer science research (e.g., number of papers, authors,
research activity), trends in topics of interest, and citation patterns. Our
findings show that computer science is a growing research field (approx. 15%
annually), with an active and collaborative researcher community. While papers
in recent years present more bibliographical entries in comparison to previous
decades, the average number of citations has been declining. Investigating
papers&apos; abstracts reveals that recent topic trends are clearly reflected in D3.
Finally, we list further applications of D3 and pose supplemental research
questions. The D3 dataset, our findings, and source code are publicly available
for research purposes.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Wahle_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jan Philip Wahle&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Ruas_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Terry Ruas&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Mohammad_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Saif M. Mohammad&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Gipp_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Bela Gipp&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
</rdf:RDF>