<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <ttl>60</ttl>
    <copyright>Copyright 2022 Minnesota Public Radio</copyright>
    <link>https://www.dontasktig.org/</link>
    <title>Don't Ask Tig</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[Need advice? Comedian Tig Notaro doesn’t have all the answers, but that won't stop her from fielding your questions on life's many challenges. With the help of her friends and the occasional expert, Tig gives her best inexpert guidance on everything from lost love to giving yourself a haircut with toddler scissors. We're warning you now: Don't Ask Tig.]]>
    </description>
    <itunes:author>American Public Media</itunes:author>
    <itunes:type>episodic</itunes:type>
    <itunes:complete>No</itunes:complete>
    <itunes:explicit>yes</itunes:explicit>
    <atom:link rel="self" type="application/rss+builder" href="https://feeds.publicradio.org/public_feeds/dont-ask-tig/itunes/rss.rss"/>
    <itunes:owner>
      <itunes:name>American Public Media</itunes:name>
      <itunes:email>podcasts@americanpublicmedia.org</itunes:email>
    </itunes:owner>
    <itunes:image href="https://img.apmcdn.org/a8fd250a751bc3f101884348524dd2a38885fde0/uncropped/697bdf-20210901-don-t-ask-tig-apm-studios-podcast-art-2000.jpg"/>
    <image>
      <url>https://img.apmcdn.org/a8fd250a751bc3f101884348524dd2a38885fde0/uncropped/697bdf-20210901-don-t-ask-tig-apm-studios-podcast-art-2000.jpg</url>
      <title>Don't Ask Tig</title>
      <link>https://www.dontasktig.org/</link>
    </image>
    <itunes:category text="Comedy">
      <itunes:category text="Comedy Interviews"/>
    </itunes:category>
    <item>
      <title>Sheng Wang</title>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">01GGTCB7AWBYWTHK1YJFFNZP9R</guid>
      <itunes:author>American Public Media</itunes:author>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>Tig and Sheng Wang, comedian and writer on ABC’s “Fresh Off the Boat,” trade stories about their childhoods in Houston, post-apocalyptic hairstyles, and pickleball moves. Then Tig and Sheng advise a runner whose partner would rather go to a comedy show than watch her run her first marathon, and they counsel a single woman who has the unbelievable “problem” of finding too many good matches on a dating app. </p>
<p>This episode is sponsored by BetterHelp (go to Betterhelp.com/TIG for 10% off the first month of online therapy), Shopify (go to Shopify.com/TIG for a free trial), Rocket Money (go to Rocket Money.com/tig and start canceling unwanted subscriptions today), Indeed (go to Indeed.com/TIG to start hiring now; terms and conditions apply), and WealthFront (go to WealthFront.com/TIG to get your first $5,000 managed for free).</p>
<p>Need advice? Submit your question for Tig at dontasktig.org/contact.</p>
]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure length="20914304" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://play.podtrac.com/APM-DontAskTig/chrt.fm/track/3G835/pdst.fm/e/traffic.megaphone.fm/CAD7610810011.mp3"/>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2022 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <itunes:duration>00:43:29</itunes:duration>
      <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mae Martin</title>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">01GG8F7XYARY2J5XD9FD5RNX0G</guid>
      <itunes:author>American Public Media</itunes:author>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>Actor, comedian, and writer Mae Martin, who co-wrote and stars in the award-winning Netflix dramedy series ‘Feel Good,’ talks about getting into comedy at the age of 13 and what they wish they knew back then. Tig and Mae give guidance to a Texan who can’t decide if she wants to live in the UK or America, help a recently promoted manager with an office dress-code dilemma and come up with great gift ideas for a guy in his 30s. </p>
<p>This episode is sponsored by BetterHelp (go to Betterhelp.com/TIG for 10% off the first month of online therapy), Shopify (go to Shopify.com/TIG for a free trial), Rocket Money (go to Rocket Money.com/tig and start canceling unwanted subscriptions today), Indeed (go to Indeed.com/TIG to start hiring now; terms and conditions apply), Zocdoc (go to Zocdoc.com/TIG to download the Zocdoc app for free), and WealthFront (go to WealthFront.com/TIG to get your first $5,000 managed for free).</p>
<p>Need advice? Submit your question for Tig at dontasktig.org/contact.  </p>
]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure length="17379456" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://play.podtrac.com/APM-DontAskTig/chrt.fm/track/3G835/pdst.fm/e/traffic.megaphone.fm/CAD6001622177.mp3"/>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 08:02:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <itunes:duration>00:36:07</itunes:duration>
      <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sheryl Lee Ralph</title>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">01GFP7A1YXXKRTWP9RX657XMHX</guid>
      <itunes:author>American Public Media</itunes:author>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>Award-winning actress Sheryl Lee Ralph and Tig reminisce about working together on the TV series ‘One Mississippi;’ then Sheryl talks about her amazing Emmy acceptance speech that electrified the ceremony and went viral across social media, and about what inspired her drive to succeed. Sheryl and Tig have some stern advice for a teacher who has a crush on a senior colleague and prescribe pickleball and treading water to a man with a troubling problem.</p>
<p>This episode is sponsored by BetterHelp (go to Betterhelp.com/TIG for 10% off the first month of online therapy), Shopify (go to Shopify.com/tig for a free trial), Rocket Money (Go to RocketMoney.com/tig and start canceling unwanted subscriptions today), Indeed (go to Indeed.com/TIG to start hiring now; terms and conditions apply; cost per application pricing not available to everyone), Zocdoc (go to Zocdoc.com/TIG to download the Zocdoc app for free), and WealthFront (go to WealthFront.com/TIG to get your first $5,000 managed for free).</p>
<p>Need advice? Submit your question for Tig at dontasktig.org/contact.</p>
]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure length="20170880" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://play.podtrac.com/APM-DontAskTig/chrt.fm/track/3G835/pdst.fm/e/traffic.megaphone.fm/CAD9618129894.mp3"/>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <itunes:duration>00:41:56</itunes:duration>
      <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kristen Bell</title>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">01GF40BH83Y3W69G3XT4TKXPWV</guid>
      <itunes:author>American Public Media</itunes:author>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>Tig is back! She kicks off season 3 with one of her BFFs, actress Kristen Bell, acclaimed for so many roles on TV (The Good Place, Veronica Mars and more) and in movies (Anna in Frozen, Forgetting Sarah Marshall). Kristen talks about road-tripping with her famous actor/podcast host husband, Dax Shepard, and their kids. Tig and Kristen also offer some hilarious advice about neighborhood party invitations, dealing with jealous wives and how to get a colleague to stop playing the song “Let It Go.”</p>
<p>This episode is sponsored by BetterHelp (go to Betterhelp.com/TIG for 10% off the first month of online therapy), Shopify (go to Shopify.com/TIG for a free trial),  Rocket Money (Go to RocketMoney.com/tig and start canceling unwanted subscriptions today), and WealthFront (go to WealthFront.com/TIG to get your first $5,000 managed for free).</p>
<p>Need advice? Submit your question for Tig at dontasktig.org/contact.</p>
]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure length="21508224" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://play.podtrac.com/APM-DontAskTig/chrt.fm/track/3G835/pdst.fm/e/traffic.megaphone.fm/CAD6484221968.mp3"/>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2022 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <itunes:duration>00:44:43</itunes:duration>
      <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Season 3 Trailer</title>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">01GEJB8SBRZHJRBGSYGCHXG8G2</guid>
      <itunes:author>American Public Media</itunes:author>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>Every week, comedian Tig Notaro and a rotating cast of guests field audience questions on love, loss, and life’s other indignities. Season 3 coming October 12th.</p>
<p>Need advice? <a href="https://mpr.tfaforms.net/92" class="default">Submit your question for Tig here</a>.</p>
<p>Follow us on <a href="http://twitter.com/dontasktig" class="default">Twitter</a>, <a href="http://facebook.com/dontasktig" class="default">Facebook</a>, and <a href="http://instagram.com/dontasktig" class="default">Instagram</a> at @DontAskTig.</p>
]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure length="618624" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://play.podtrac.com/APM-DontAskTig/chrt.fm/track/3G835/pdst.fm/e/traffic.megaphone.fm/CAD8784315272.mp3"/>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2022 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <itunes:duration>00:01:12</itunes:duration>
      <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Karen Kilgariff</title>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">01G5FWJCVRNFR392Q8Q6MFZPS5</guid>
      <itunes:author>American Public Media</itunes:author>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>Karen Kilgariff, comedian and co-host of the wildly popular podcast My Favorite Murder, talks to her pal Tig about what she thinks fuels true crime obsession, and they trade stories on lessons their mothers taught them that they fully believe continue to save their lives to this day. Tig and Karen also advise a listener at the end of their rope because their partner ignores any recommendations they share about books and entertainment, and together they brainstorm snappy comebacks for a pioneer reality tv star whose onscreen past keeps coming back to haunt them. </p>
<p>This episode is sponsored by Betterhelp (go to Betterhelp.com/TIG for 10% off the first month of online therapy), Shopify (go to Shopify.com/TIG for a free 14-day trial and full access to Shopify’s suite of features), Macys (go to Macys.com/purpose to celebrate Pride month), Truebill (go to Truebill.com/TIG and start canceling today), and eHarmony (go to eHarmony.com to start free today). </p>
<p>Need advice? Submit your question for Tig at dontasktig.org/contact.</p>
]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure length="20732032" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://play.podtrac.com/APM-DontAskTig/chrt.fm/track/3G835/pdst.fm/e/traffic.megaphone.fm/CAD7894303162.mp3"/>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2022 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <itunes:duration>00:43:06</itunes:duration>
      <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lauren Lapkus</title>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">01G4ZYE7R1SYJWDXEAKZB99NP0</guid>
      <itunes:author>American Public Media</itunes:author>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>Tig’s guest is comedian and Emmy-nominated actor Lauren Lapkus, star of the Netflix movie The Wrong Missy, and known for her role as corrections officer Susan Fischer on Orange is the New Black. Lauren and Tig give suggestions to a listener wondering what to wear on a blind date, advise a woman whose long-time boyfriend never says “I love you” and help a mom upset because her six-year-old calls her by her first name instead of “mommy.” </p>
<p>This episode is sponsored by Betterhelp (go to Betterhelp.com/TIG for 10% off the first month of online therapy), Indeed (go to Indeed.com/TIG for a $75 sponsored job credit to upgrade your job posting, offer good for a limited time), Shopify (go to Shopify.com/TIG for a free 14-day trial and full access to Shopify’s suite of features),  Netsuite (go to Netsuite.com/TIG for a one-of-a-kind financing offer), Macys (go to Macys.com/purpose to celebrate Pride month), Truebill (go to Truebill.com/TIG and start canceling today), and Netflix’s The Hall: Honoring the Greats of Stand Up | Accompanying Podcast. </p>
<p>Need advice? Submit your question for Tig at dontasktig.org/contact.</p>
]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure length="20115584" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://play.podtrac.com/APM-DontAskTig/chrt.fm/track/3G835/pdst.fm/e/traffic.megaphone.fm/CAD8531168183.mp3"/>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2022 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <itunes:duration>00:41:49</itunes:duration>
      <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rufus Wainwright</title>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">01G4DQ0EXTJZEZJ15A476BF04V</guid>
      <itunes:author>American Public Media</itunes:author>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>Afraid it’s too late to pursue a career in music? Have a rude relative who is also cold toward your four-year-old kid? Songwriter, composer and Grammy-nominated singer Rufus Wainwright helps Tig weigh in on these problems as well as the debate over whether it’s socially acceptable to pee in the shower. Plus, Rufus gets candid on what he thinks the biggest problem is with today’s pop stars, balancing indulgence with better judgment, and the best advice he’s ever heard in the lyrics of a song. </p>
<p>This episode is sponsored by Betterhelp (go to Betterhelp.com/TIG for 10% off the first month of online therapy), Shopify (go to Shopify.com/TIG for a free 14-day trial and full access to Shopify’s suite of features),  Netsuite (go to Netsuite.com/TIG for a one-of-a-kind financing offer), Zocdoc (go to Zocdoc.com/TIG to download the Zocdoc app for FREE), Macys (go to Macys.com/purpose to celebrate Pride month), Truebill (go to Truebill.com/TIG and start canceling today), Wealthfront (go to Wealthfront.com/TIG to start building your wealth and get your first $5,000 managed for FREE, for life), and Netflix’s The Hall: Honoring the Greats of Stand Up | Accompanying Podcast. </p>
<p>Need advice? Submit your question for Tig at dontasktig.org/contact.</p>
]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure length="15816832" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://play.podtrac.com/APM-DontAskTig/chrt.fm/track/3G835/pdst.fm/e/traffic.megaphone.fm/CAD1485371599.mp3"/>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2022 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <itunes:duration>00:32:51</itunes:duration>
      <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Michael McKean</title>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">01G3VQP646RHQXYAMXB8SSCRCV</guid>
      <itunes:author>American Public Media</itunes:author>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>Actor Michael McKean, beloved for his roles as Chuck McGill in “Better Call Saul” and David St. Hubbins in the classic rock-umentary “This Is Spinal Tap”, tells Tig all about some surprising backstage memories he has of playing Lenny of the Lenny and Squiggy duo in the classic 1970’s sitcom “Laverne &amp; Shirley”. Michael also helps Tig advise a mom who is judgmental about her toddler’s “dud” friends,  and counsels a listener whose buddy can’t stop yawning when they talk on the phone.</p>
<p>This episode is sponsored by Betterhelp (go to Betterhelp.com/TIG for 10% off the first month of online therapy),  Indeed (go to Indeed.com/TIG for a $75 sponsored job credit to upgrade your job posting, offer good for a limited time), Shopify (go to Shopify.com/TIG for a free 14-day trial and full access to Shopify’s suite of features), Netsuite (go to Netsuite.com/TIG for a one-of-a-kind financing offer), Zocdoc (go to Zocdoc.com/TIG to download the Zocdoc app for free), and Netflix’s The Hall: Honoring the Greats of Stand Up | Accompanying Podcast. </p>
<p>Need advice? Submit your question for Tig at dontasktig.org/contact.</p>
]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure length="20322432" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://play.podtrac.com/APM-DontAskTig/chrt.fm/track/3G835/pdst.fm/e/traffic.megaphone.fm/CAD3678376608.mp3"/>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2022 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <itunes:duration>00:42:15</itunes:duration>
      <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chloé Zhao</title>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">01G3AHBHK4F9YZ4QPB61RVZMZK</guid>
      <itunes:author>American Public Media</itunes:author>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>Chloé Zhao, who won the 2021 Best Director Oscar for “Nomadland,” talks to Tig about what that means for her personally and professionally. She and Tig discover a surprising secret weapon they share to stay sane and successful. They also advise a listener on whether to try writing a novel or a screenplay, and give some perspective to a mother bothered by snide comments that her kid obviously behaves like an only child.</p>
<p>This episode is sponsored by Betterhelp (go to Betterhelp.com/TIG for 10% off the first month of online therapy), Shopify (go to Shopify.com/TIG for a free 14-day trial and full access to Shopify’s suite of features), Netsuite (go to Netsuite.com/TIG for a one-of-a-kind financing offer), and Netflix’s <a href="https://podcasts.apple.com/us/podcast/the-hall-honoring-the-greats-of-stand/id1513670059">The Hall: Honoring the Greats of Stand Up | Accompanying Podcast</a>. </p>
<p>Need advice? Submit your question for Tig at dontasktig.org/contact.</p>
]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure length="22130816" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://play.podtrac.com/APM-DontAskTig/chrt.fm/track/3G835/pdst.fm/e/traffic.megaphone.fm/CAD5650151142.mp3"/>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2022 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <itunes:duration>00:46:01</itunes:duration>
      <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Alex Kurtzman</title>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">01G2QPTHRXX8R9TGNWZZP82DR6</guid>
      <itunes:author>American Public Media</itunes:author>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>Suffering from hand sanitizer dry hands? Need inspiration to finally confess those romantic feelings you’ve kept hidden from a long-distance flame? Who better to ask than master of the Star Trek universe — filmmaker Alex Kurtzman. He joins Tig and together they have some expert tips on how to be an effective manager. Alex also talks about how he knew Tig would be a perfect Starship captain, divulges the secret to being a brilliant director and reveals who one of his personal heroes is.</p>
<p>This episode is sponsored by Betterhelp (go to Betterhelp.com/TIG for 10% off the first month of online therapy), Indeed (go to Indeed.com/TIG for a $75 sponsored job credit), Shopify (go to Shopify.com/TIG for a free 14-day trial and full access to Shopify’s suite of features), Netsuite (go to Netsuite.com/TIG for a one-of-a-kind financing offer), and Wealthfront (go to Wealthfront.com/TIG to get your first $5,000 managed for FREE, for life). </p>
<p>Need advice? Submit your question for Tig at dontasktig.org/contact.</p>
]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure length="19042432" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://play.podtrac.com/APM-DontAskTig/chrt.fm/track/3G835/pdst.fm/e/traffic.megaphone.fm/CAD7154092159.mp3"/>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2022 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <itunes:duration>00:39:35</itunes:duration>
      <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Paul Rudd</title>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">01G260B86J7R5Z7WJKKCVDJABH</guid>
      <itunes:author>American Public Media</itunes:author>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>Tig talks with one of America&#39;s favorite leading men, Paul Rudd, star of the Ant-Man movies, the TV series The Shrink Next Door, and so much more. Paul discusses fascinating facts about real ants, and talks about owning a candy store in a small town. Paul and Tig discuss why he was named sexiest man alive and how he stacks up against CNN correspondent Sanjay Gupta for the title. Together, Tig and Paul advise a listener on how to find friends in a new city, help another decide whether to fly across the country for a birthday bash, and they find a new name for a librarian whose boss wants her to change her name at work.</p>
<p>This episode is sponsored by Betterhelp (go to Betterhelp.com/TIG for 10% off the first month of online therapy), Shopify (go to Shopify.com/TIG for a free 14-day trial and full access to Shopify’s suite of features), and Netsuite (go to Netsuite.com/TIG for a one-of-a-kind financing offer).</p>
<p>Need advice? Submit your question for Tig at dontasktig.org/contact.</p>
]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure length="20914304" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://play.podtrac.com/APM-DontAskTig/chrt.fm/track/3G835/pdst.fm/e/traffic.megaphone.fm/CAD6219869522.mp3"/>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2022 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <itunes:duration>00:43:28</itunes:duration>
      <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ben Schwartz</title>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">01G1M6NMR7Y00V88F58JCZ0VCV</guid>
      <itunes:author>American Public Media</itunes:author>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>Tig catches up with comedian and veteran improv performer Ben Schwartz, who talks about his process for voicing the superpowered hedgehog in the “Sonic the Hedgehog” movies, what it was like growing up as the son of a social worker and teacher, and the kinds of letters he still writes on his prized collection of vintage typewriters. Ben and Tig advise a listener concerned that his neighbor is overfeeding his cat, and a Finnish immigrant worried that he doesn&#39;t know how to &quot;socialize like an American.&quot;</p>
<p>This episode is sponsored by Betterhelp (go to Betterhelp.com/TIG for 10% off the first month of online therapy), Indeed (go to Indeed.com/TIG for a $75 sponsored job credit), Shopify (go to Shopify.com/TIG for a free 14-day trial and full access to Shopify’s suite of features), and Netsuite (go to Netsuite.com/TIG for a one-of-a-kind financing offer).</p>
<p>Need advice? Submit your question for Tig at dontasktig.org/contact.</p>
]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure length="21467264" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://play.podtrac.com/APM-DontAskTig/chrt.fm/track/3G835/pdst.fm/e/traffic.megaphone.fm/CAD2701876699.mp3"/>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2022 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <itunes:duration>00:44:38</itunes:duration>
      <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Phoebe Bridgers</title>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">01G11EA0EGN5ZV383MD5XMSFHW</guid>
      <itunes:author>American Public Media</itunes:author>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>Indie pop rock sensation and Grammy nominee Phoebe Bridgers talks about life as the child of a standup comedian, the origins of her ghoul-inspired style and the worst advice she recently gave a friend. Then Phoebe and Tig help a listener who feels guilty about a past romantic affair and counsel a father who doesn’t like to punish his young daughter who can’t seem to stop misbehaving.</p>
<p>This episode is sponsored by Betterhelp (go to Betterhelp.com/TIG for 10% off the first month of online therapy),  Netsuite (go to Netsuite.com/TIG for a one-of-a-kind financing offer), Zocdoc (go to Zocdoc.com/TIG to download the app for free), and Wealthfront (go to Wealthfront.com/TIG to get $5,000 managed for free when opening an investment account). </p>
<p>Need advice? Submit your question for Tig at dontasktig.org/contact.</p>
]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure length="19986560" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://play.podtrac.com/APM-DontAskTig/chrt.fm/track/3G835/pdst.fm/e/traffic.megaphone.fm/CAD8983098612.mp3"/>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2022 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <itunes:duration>00:41:33</itunes:duration>
      <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Conan O'Brien</title>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">01FYT1MMXWNBKB1NA63KZP3378</guid>
      <itunes:author>American Public Media</itunes:author>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>Tig&#39;s old pal, the one and only Conan O&#39;Brien, discusses the people he turns to for advice and why the storied prankster himself doesn&#39;t actually like pranks. The legendary late-night host helps Tig counsel a grandmother magician on how to handle six-year-old hecklers, criticizes an overzealous office whistleblower and reflects on advice he&#39;s given to college graduates in commencement speeches he delivered over the past two decades.   </p>
<p>This episode is sponsored by Betterhelp (go to Betterhelp.com/TIG for 10% off the first month of online therapy),  Indeed (go to Indeed.com/TIG for a $75 sponsored job credit), Headspace (go to headspace.com/TIG for one month of free access to their entire mindfulness library), Ethos (go to Ethoslife.com – to get your free personalized quote today) and Netsuite (go to Netsuite.com/TIG for a one-of-a-kind financing offer). </p>
<p>Need advice? Submit your question for Tig at dontasktig.org/contact.</p>
]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure length="19757184" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://play.podtrac.com/APM-DontAskTig/chrt.fm/track/3G835/pdst.fm/e/traffic.megaphone.fm/CAD5088254248.mp3"/>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2022 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <itunes:duration>00:41:04</itunes:duration>
      <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ian Harvie</title>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">01FY7GKJ26Y4HRZ396XEH8J6BE</guid>
      <itunes:author>American Public Media</itunes:author>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>You’ve seen actor Ian Harvie as Dale on Transparent, and as Bud on Will and Grace. In this episode, Ian and Tig talk about doing stand up while sober. Then, Ian helps Tig brainstorm ideas for chores a five-year-old can do to make spending money and advise a listener on how to be proud of their body.</p>
<p>This episode is sponsored by Betterhelp (go to Betterhelp.com/TIG for 10% off the first month of online therapy), Shopify (go to Shopify.com/TIG  for a free 14 day trial and full access to Shopify’s suite of features), Novo ( go to Novo.co/TIG – to sign up for a free business checking account and access to over $5,000 in perks and discounts),  Netsuite (go to Netsuite.com/TIG for a one-of-a-kind financing offer), Ethos (go to Ethoslife.com – to get your free personalized quote today) and Zocdoc (go to Zocdoc.com/TIG to download the app for free).</p>
<p>Need advice? Submit your question for Tig at dontasktig.org/contact.</p>
]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure length="20146304" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://play.podtrac.com/APM-DontAskTig/chrt.fm/track/3G835/pdst.fm/e/traffic.megaphone.fm/CAD4663390421.mp3"/>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2022 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <itunes:duration>00:41:53</itunes:duration>
      <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kathleen Madigan</title>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">01FXNQSDXQ1FC4VY4PWPJ6YSGJ</guid>
      <itunes:author>American Public Media</itunes:author>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>Hilarious standup comedian Kathleen Madigan talks about her very short basketball &quot;career&quot; and why she left LA for Nashville. Then, she and Tig advise a remorseful heckler about apologizing to a comedian and help a listener start off on the right foot at a new job, plus they discuss the best way to &quot;break up&quot; with an old friend.</p>
<p>This episode is sponsored by Betterhelp (go to Betterhelp.com/TIG for 10% off the first month of online therapy), Indeed (go to Indeed.com/TIG for a $75 sponsored job credit), and Headspace (go to headspace.com/TIG) - for one month free access to their entire mindfulness library</p>
<p>Need advice? Submit your question for Tig at dontasktig.org/contact.</p>
]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure length="16994432" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://play.podtrac.com/APM-DontAskTig/chrt.fm/track/3G835/pdst.fm/e/traffic.megaphone.fm/CAD3734444917.mp3"/>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2022 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <itunes:duration>00:35:19</itunes:duration>
      <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deepak Chopra</title>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">01FX1DTB021GK6KZ088TQT8TJR</guid>
      <itunes:author>American Public Media</itunes:author>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>Bestselling author and personal transformation pioneer Deepak Chopra reveals his pick for the greatest jokester of all time. He and Tig give advice about karma, home remodeling and the best ways to goof around, plus they discuss Oprah and glitter bombs. It all becomes clear in this episode of Don’t Ask Tig.</p>
<p>This episode is sponsored by Betterhelp (go to Betterhelp.com/TIG for 10% off the first month of online therapy) and Netsuite (go to Netsuite.com/TIG for a one-of-a-kind financing offer).</p>
<p>Need advice? Submit your question for Tig at dontasktig.org/contact.</p>
]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure length="16111744" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://play.podtrac.com/APM-DontAskTig/chrt.fm/track/3G835/pdst.fm/e/traffic.megaphone.fm/CAD8581872907.mp3"/>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2022 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <itunes:duration>00:33:28</itunes:duration>
      <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lena Waithe</title>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">01FWHVW1XB2HTN87A1QQTD73PY</guid>
      <itunes:author>American Public Media</itunes:author>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>Lena Waithe, the trailblazing producer, actor, and Emmy-winning screenwriter of Netflix’s “Master of None” and creator of BET&#39;s &quot;Twenties,&quot; trades stories with Tig about their early days as assistants in Hollywood, and how to be a great mentor. Tig and Lena offer advice to a retiree struggling with boredom, a long-distance girlfriend who wants to spice up her Zoom dates, and a woman about to become a grandmother who wants to be called something more hip than ‘grandma.’</p>
<p>This episode is sponsored by Betterhelp (go to Betterhelp.com/TIG for 10% off the first month of online therapy), Indeed (go to Indeed.com/TIG for a $75 sponsored job credit), and Zocdoc (go to Zocdoc.com/TIG to download the app for free).</p>
<p>Need advice? Submit your question for Tig at dontasktig.org/contact.</p>
]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure length="20123776" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://play.podtrac.com/APM-DontAskTig/chrt.fm/track/3G835/pdst.fm/e/traffic.megaphone.fm/CAD9858304855.mp3"/>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Feb 2022 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <itunes:duration>00:41:50</itunes:duration>
      <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deon Cole</title>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">01FVZBVN9MTGM1Y7QZBFRVZJFX</guid>
      <itunes:author>American Public Media</itunes:author>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>Actor and comedian Deon Cole, a regular on Black-ish and Grown-ish, stops by Don&#39;t Ask Tig to talk privacy, positivity and how to be uniquely yourself.  He and Tig give advice to a mom who can&#39;t get her smelly teenager to shower, and they can&#39;t stop laughing about Dear Abby&#39;s suggestions to a newlywed husband who&#39;s bothered that his wife sleeps, eats and even cooks in the nude!  </p>
<p>This episode is sponsored by Betterhelp (go to Betterhelp.com/TIG for 10% off the first month of online therapy), Shopify (go to Shopify.com/TIG  for a free 14 day trial and full access to Shopify’s suite of features), and Zocdoc (go to Zocdoc.com/TIG to download the app for free).</p>
<p>Need advice? Submit your question for Tig at dontasktig.org/contact.</p>
]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure length="19867776" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://play.podtrac.com/APM-DontAskTig/chrt.fm/track/3G835/pdst.fm/e/traffic.megaphone.fm/CAD4049367680.mp3"/>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Feb 2022 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <itunes:duration>00:41:18</itunes:duration>
      <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Patti Harrison</title>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">01FVBGP80SDKEFAD4JMSV3SH0E</guid>
      <itunes:author>American Public Media</itunes:author>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>Feeling pressure to engage more on social media and want guidance on how often to post? Wondering what questions to ask if you&#39;re thinking about having a baby via surrogate? Well, Tig&#39;s twins came into the world via surrogate, and &quot;Shrill&quot; actor/comedian Patti Harrison played a surrogate in the indie movie sensation &quot;Together Together.&quot; They share their experiences with these topics and a few others, then round up some motivating and a few absurd quotes to inspire a listener to level up their workout. </p>
<p>This episode is sponsored by Betterhelp (go to Betterhelp.com/TIG for 10% off the first month of online therapy) and Indeed (go to Indeed.com/TIG for a $75 sponsored job credit). </p>
<p>Need advice? Submit your question for Tig at dontasktig.org/contact.</p>
]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure length="18970752" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://play.podtrac.com/APM-DontAskTig/chrt.fm/track/3G835/pdst.fm/e/traffic.megaphone.fm/CAD1695836046.mp3"/>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Feb 2022 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <itunes:duration>00:39:26</itunes:duration>
      <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lucy Lawless</title>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">01FTVQJPGVSBM5Y1GJWR1KGAQ7</guid>
      <itunes:author>American Public Media</itunes:author>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>Kiwi actor and singer Lucy Lawless stars in Acorn TV&#39;s My Life Is Murder and is beloved as Xena: Warrior Princess from the 90&#39;s TV series and more. She and Tig reminisce about their history that goes way back and their shared experience as lesbian icons. They give advice to a mom annoyed by her daughter&#39;s cell phone addiction and counsel a woman on how to fend off a family of huggers.</p>
<p>This episode is sponsored by Betterhelp (go to Betterhelp.com/TIG for 10% off the first month of online therapy), and EthosLife.com. </p>
<p>Need advice? Submit your question for Tig at dontasktig.org/contact.</p>
]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure length="16771200" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://play.podtrac.com/APM-DontAskTig/chrt.fm/track/3G835/pdst.fm/e/traffic.megaphone.fm/CAD3580265073.mp3"/>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2022 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <itunes:duration>00:34:51</itunes:duration>
      <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fortune Feimster</title>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">01FT6Q7DP4Y00JZTGC14AN3G96</guid>
      <itunes:author>American Public Media</itunes:author>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>Comedian, writer, and actor Fortune Feimster — now starring in the hit TV series Kenan — joins Tig to swap hilarious stories about debutante balls and newlywed life. They also weigh in on creative compliments for ugly dogs and the pros and cons of steady romance versus intense first love.</p>
<p>This episode is sponsored by Betterhelp (go to Betterhelp.com/TIG for 10% off the first month of online therapy), Headspace (go to headspace.com/TIG) - for one month free access to their entire mindfulness library), and Indeed (go to Indeed.com/TIG  for a $75 sponsored job credit).</p>
<p>Need advice? Submit your question for Tig at dontasktig.org/contact.</p>
]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure length="21459072" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://play.podtrac.com/APM-DontAskTig/chrt.fm/track/3G835/pdst.fm/e/traffic.megaphone.fm/CAD5227303549.mp3"/>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jan 2022 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <itunes:duration>00:44:37</itunes:duration>
      <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jimmy Carr</title>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">01FSQATR2RQ3QQYN8GBS32JM8Y</guid>
      <itunes:author>American Public Media</itunes:author>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>Jimmy Carr, one of the UK&#39;s best loved comedians and game show hosts, is so good at giving advice, he&#39;s written a self-help book. He shares with Tig his “cheat” on what all self-help books have in common.  Jimmy and Tig compare notes on why they may actually appreciate heckling during a standup - and offer advice about a woman worried she&#39;s getting marriage proposals only because she&#39;s rich.</p>
<p>This episode is sponsored by Betterhelp (go to Betterhelp.com/TIG for 10% off the first month of online therapy) and Zocdoc (go to Zocdoc.com/TIG  to download the app and sign up for free).</p>
<p>Need advice? Submit your question for Tig at dontasktig.org/contact.</p>
]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure length="20220032" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://play.podtrac.com/APM-DontAskTig/chrt.fm/track/3G835/pdst.fm/e/traffic.megaphone.fm/CAD5130309653.mp3"/>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jan 2022 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <itunes:duration>00:42:02</itunes:duration>
      <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sasheer Zamata</title>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">01FS37BEPX0YF83C7KD4HG2PF7</guid>
      <itunes:author>American Public Media</itunes:author>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>Craving a best friend, but unsure how to make that connection as an adult? Actor and former SNL cast member Sasheer Zamata tells Tig how she found her later-in-life bestie — none other than fellow comedian Nicole Byer — now her co-host on the podcast Best Friends. Sasheer and Tig give advice on how to keep kids from binging on granola bars first thing in the morning and brainstorm about how humor can rescue someone from a sticky situation. Sasheer, who stars in the Hulu series Woke, gives her take on the word &quot;woke&quot; and dishes about her first crush — hint: he&#39;s out of this world!</p>
<p>This episode is sponsored by Betterhelp (go to Betterhelp.com/TIG for 10% off the first month of online therapy). </p>
<p>Need advice? Submit your question for Tig at dontasktig.org/contact.</p>
]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure length="18915456" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://play.podtrac.com/APM-DontAskTig/chrt.fm/track/3G835/pdst.fm/e/traffic.megaphone.fm/CAD4423597842.mp3"/>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2022 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <itunes:duration>00:39:19</itunes:duration>
      <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rosie O'Donnell</title>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">01FRK2NTV3QMGN314XB4PF0MM1</guid>
      <itunes:author>American Public Media</itunes:author>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>From her award winning The Rosie O&#39;Donnell show to being a moderator on The View to her role in the upcoming reboot of American Gigolo, there&#39;s nothing Rosie has not done in movies or TV.  This week the actor, comedian, host, and producer tells Tig why she prefers working on Broadway over Hollywood, and how she learned to conduct a great interview from Johnny Carson. Then she and Tig give advice to a budding entrepreneur who wants to save the world and a friend of a dog owner who insists on bringing her pooch everywhere. </p>
<p>This episode is sponsored by Shopify (Go to Shopify.com/tig for a free fourteen-day trial and full access to Shopify’s entire suite of features), Betterhelp (go to Betterhelp.com/TIG for 10% off the first month of online therapy), Indeed (go to Indeed.com/TIG  for a $75 sponsored job credit), and Wealthfront (go to Wealthfront.com/TIG to have your first $5,000 managed for free). </p>
<p>Need advice? Submit your question for Tig at dontasktig.org/contact.</p>
]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure length="15835264" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://play.podtrac.com/APM-DontAskTig/chrt.fm/track/3G835/pdst.fm/e/traffic.megaphone.fm/CAD6228183640.mp3"/>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jan 2022 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <itunes:duration>00:32:54</itunes:duration>
      <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rainn Wilson</title>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">01FPX822PDBDF75NGBCXVH3ZJZ</guid>
      <itunes:author>American Public Media</itunes:author>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>This week Tig is joined by actor, comedian, and podcast host Rainn Wilson, best known for playing the iconic and quirky Dwight in The Office for nearly a decade. Rainn talks about how he applies one of Dwight&#39;s most quotable pieces of advice in real life. Rainn also discusses the greatest lesson he learned from his own father. Together he and Tig encourage a self-professed oddball to let her freak flag fly, and advise an engaged couple on how to dis-invite guests to their wedding that has been postponed by COVID so long they&#39;re barely friends anymore. </p>
<p>This episode is sponsored by Betterhelp (go to Betterhelp.com/TIG for 10% off the first month of online therapy),  and Sakara (go to sakara.com/dontask for 20% off your first order) and Truebill (Truebill.com/tig). </p>
<p>Need advice? Submit your question for Tig at dontasktig.org/contact.</p>
]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure length="18444416" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://play.podtrac.com/APM-DontAskTig/chrt.fm/track/3G835/pdst.fm/e/traffic.megaphone.fm/CAD2822472404.mp3"/>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Dec 2021 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <itunes:duration>00:38:20</itunes:duration>
      <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gary Gulman</title>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">01FPB21XRWV082G8XG006MWTV6</guid>
      <itunes:author>American Public Media</itunes:author>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>Standup comedian Gary Gulman has been in the comedy biz for over 20 years. He’s a regular on the late night circuit and has his own HBO special called “The Great Depresh.” In this episode of Don&#39;t Ask Tig, Tig and Gary break down some myths surrounding the relationship between comedians and depression. Gary offers a strategy for battling procrastination that he derives from a Jewish tradition, and shares what his college therapist taught him about understanding the opposite sex. He and Tig help a college athlete struggling to maintain good grades and they advise a concerned mom whose young child is bullied by her friend’s daughter.</p>
<p>This episode is sponsored by Betterhelp (go to Betterhelp.com/TIG for 10% off the first month of online therapy) and Indeed (go to Indeed.com/TIG for a $75 sponsored job credit).</p>
<p>Need advice? Submit your question for Tig at dontasktig.org/contact.</p>
]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure length="19366016" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://play.podtrac.com/APM-DontAskTig/chrt.fm/track/3G835/pdst.fm/e/traffic.megaphone.fm/CAD7433441318.mp3"/>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Dec 2021 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <itunes:duration>00:40:15</itunes:duration>
      <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Aparna Nancherla</title>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">01FNSCM77SHE0SX3V7XX1MH20N</guid>
      <itunes:author>American Public Media</itunes:author>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>The delightful and hilarious actor Aparna Nancherla reunites with her good friend Tig on Zoom. Who can forget Aparna from shows like Netflix&#39;s BoJack Horseman, Comedy Central&#39;s Corporate, and Fox&#39;s The Great North? In this episode, Tig and Aparna talk about how the pandemic has us all dropping longtime friends, but maybe not forever. Aparna asks for Tig&#39;s advice on the daunting task of writing her first book. Together they give guidance to a  woman who wants to give her partner the best Christmas ever before he deploys for military service and try to help a son whose senior-citizen mom keeps falling for online dating scammers.  </p>
<p>This episode is sponsored by Betterhelp (go to Betterhelp.com/TIG for 10% off the first month) and Sakara (go to sakara.com/dontask  for 20% off your first order).</p>
<p>Need advice? Submit your question for Tig at dontasktig.org/contact.</p>
]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure length="20191360" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://play.podtrac.com/APM-DontAskTig/chrt.fm/track/3G835/pdst.fm/e/traffic.megaphone.fm/CAD2666231242.mp3"/>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2021 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <itunes:duration>00:41:58</itunes:duration>
      <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nick Kroll</title>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">01FMMXWEVTVJ4NKBJFNM4AV3JB</guid>
      <itunes:author>American Public Media</itunes:author>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>This episode is excerpted from a live-over-Zoom Don&#39;t Ask Tig show with comedian, actor, producer, and Tig’s longtime pal Nick Kroll. You know Nick from the Emmy-Nominated animated series “Big Mouth,” and as the voice of Uncle Fester in “The Addams Family 2.” Nick and Tig take a stroll down memory lane to reminisce about their careers before they hit it big. They also give advice to a mother whose 9-year-old keeps cursing in public and to a woman who is continually upstaged by a friend&#39;s dog on her birthday. Speaking of pups, Tig and Nick also solve the mystery of a runaway Chihuahua destined to be a Broadway star. </p>
<p>This episode is sponsored by Betterhelp (go to Betterhelp.com/TIG for 10% off the first month), Postmates (new customers can use code “DONTASK” to receive 50% off their first 5 orders of $50 or more. Max savings of $100 per order), and Tor Books&#39; A Bathroom Book for People Not Pooping or Peeing But Using the Bathroom As An Escape, available now wherever books are sold.</p>
<p>Need advice? Submit your question for Tig at dontasktig.org/contact.</p>
]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure length="16666752" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://play.podtrac.com/APM-DontAskTig/chrt.fm/track/3G835/pdst.fm/e/traffic.megaphone.fm/CAD7811562532.mp3"/>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Nov 2021 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <itunes:duration>00:34:38</itunes:duration>
      <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mayim Bialik</title>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">01FM34AZ39MK89PVA6W38X05GG</guid>
      <itunes:author>American Public Media</itunes:author>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>Actress Mayim Bialik, known for starring in &quot;The Big Bang Theory,&quot; &quot;Blossom&quot; and more, talks to Tig about why she thinks she&#39;d be a good host for Jeopardy and why that&#39;s created such controversy.  She and Tig help a single, 30-something decide if they should have children and how that could change their life.  And they give advice on how to know if you&#39;re a &#39;people pleaser&#39; and what to do about that.</p>
<p>This episode is sponsored by Betterhelp (go to Betterhelp.com/TIG for 10% off the first month) and Indeed (go to Indeed.com/TIG for a $75 sponsored job credit).</p>
<p>Need advice? Submit your question for Tig at dontasktig.org/contact.</p>
]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure length="19146880" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://play.podtrac.com/APM-DontAskTig/chrt.fm/track/3G835/pdst.fm/e/traffic.megaphone.fm/CAD2876384501.mp3"/>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Nov 2021 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <itunes:duration>00:39:48</itunes:duration>
      <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Taylor Dayne</title>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">01FKH845RTWABM7XBS0B2BRFM8</guid>
      <itunes:author>American Public Media</itunes:author>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>Who better to be Tig&#39;s guest on her 50th episode than actress Taylor Dayne —  one of her favorite singers — with the real story behind how their fun and serendipitous friendship got started. Taylor also reveals her reaction to being the subject of one of Tig&#39;s popular standup stories. Together they share parenting advice, offer guidance on how to not get nervous if you&#39;re invited to sing at a best friend&#39;s wedding. And together they help a caller decide if she should contact the biological father she never knew, but has discovered on an ancestry website.</p>
<p>This episode is sponsored by Betterhelp (go to Betterhelp.com/TIG for 10% off the first month of online therapy) and Sakara (go to Sakara.com/dontask for 20% off your first order).</p>
<p>Need advice? Submit your question for Tig at dontasktig.org/contact.</p>
]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure length="16171136" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://play.podtrac.com/APM-DontAskTig/chrt.fm/track/3G835/pdst.fm/e/traffic.megaphone.fm/CAD4043913137.mp3"/>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Nov 2021 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <itunes:duration>00:33:36</itunes:duration>
      <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Patton Oswalt and Meredith Salenger</title>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">01FJZFQGH9M7CTS4F772JX44P1</guid>
      <itunes:author>American Public Media</itunes:author>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>Tig talks with comedian and voice actor Patton Oswalt and his wife, actor and voice-over artist Meredith Salenger, about how they manage to keep the spark in their marriage while working together professionally. Meredith reveals how Patton&#39;s young daughter held the key to whether their courtship would be a success and they all give advice on what to do about endless family text strings with updates on people you don&#39;t even know. </p>
<p>This episode is sponsored by Betterhelp (go to Betterhelp.com/TIG for 10% off the first month).</p>
<p>Need advice? Submit your question for Tig at dontasktig.org/contact.</p>
]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure length="21584000" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://play.podtrac.com/APM-DontAskTig/chrt.fm/track/3G835/pdst.fm/e/traffic.megaphone.fm/CAD3884388729.mp3"/>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2021 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <itunes:duration>00:44:52</itunes:duration>
      <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jon Lovett</title>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">01FJCZ8CKBKS5K8YSZDHN7TS2E</guid>
      <itunes:author>American Public Media</itunes:author>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>How can you tell if your schoolboy crush likes you too?  Should you name a child after a moose?  Those are just a couple of the pressing questions Tig discusses with comedian, host of Pod Save America, and former presidential speechwriter Jon Lovett.  Lovett also talks about the most embarrassing line he wrote for President Obama, and how he and his partner Ronan Farrow balance their busy bi-coastal lives and careers.</p>
<p>This episode is sponsored by Betterhelp (go to Betterhelp.com/TIG for 10% off the first month) and Sakara (go to Sakara.com/dontask for 20% off your first order).</p>
<p>Need advice? Submit your question for Tig at dontasktig.org/contact.</p>
]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure length="17195136" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://play.podtrac.com/APM-DontAskTig/chrt.fm/track/3G835/pdst.fm/e/traffic.megaphone.fm/CAD5828713344.mp3"/>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Oct 2021 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <itunes:duration>00:35:43</itunes:duration>
      <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ron Funches</title>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">01FHTXAVAVVDQBWSSMB8QWSJA8</guid>
      <itunes:author>American Public Media</itunes:author>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>Need some insider tourist tips about where to visit on a trip to L.A.?  Tig and actor/comedian Ron Funches have some off the beaten path ideas you won&#39;t find in any guidebooks.  Ron, the voice behind Cooper on the animated hit Trolls and on Bob’s Burgers and Adventure Time, also talks about his online dating experiences, why Lucille Ball is his inspiration and he and Tig offer advice to a jokester whose friends are offended by his humor.</p>
<p>This episode is sponsored by Betterhelp (go to Betterhelp.com/TIG for 10% off the first month) and Indeed (go to Indeed.com/tig for a $75 sponsored job credit). </p>
<p>Need advice? Submit your question for Tig at dontasktig.org/contact.</p>
]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure length="20594816" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://play.podtrac.com/APM-DontAskTig/chrt.fm/track/3G835/pdst.fm/e/traffic.megaphone.fm/CAD4490597353.mp3"/>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2021 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <itunes:duration>00:42:49</itunes:duration>
      <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Seth Rogen</title>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">01FH8GMDKBMJGXXHMR1YERC9VV</guid>
      <itunes:author>American Public Media</itunes:author>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>Comedian, actor, producer Seth Rogen is not going to sugarcoat things for you, so when he and Tig meet for the first time over Zoom, he delivers his unfiltered two cents on issues like what to say if your mother asks you for sex advice and what to do about old material that just isn&#39;t funny anymore. They also talk about their favorite comedic role models and ideas for how to tell that someone special you&#39;ve been &quot;around the block&quot; with other guys before.  <br><br><strong>OUR SPONSORS:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Betterhelp</strong> - <a href="http://betterhelp.com/tig">betterhelp.com/tig</a> </p>
<p>Need advice? Submit your question for Tig at <a href="https://www.dontasktig.org/contact">dontasktig.org/contact</a>.</p>
<p><br></p>
]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure length="17186944" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://play.podtrac.com/APM-DontAskTig/chrt.fm/track/3G835/pdst.fm/e/traffic.megaphone.fm/CAD8859738484.mp3"/>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Oct 2021 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <itunes:duration>00:35:43</itunes:duration>
      <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Phoebe Robinson</title>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">01FGMRS83RHBGDPT911N924BTS</guid>
      <itunes:author>American Public Media</itunes:author>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>How do you get your man to say he loves you?  Tig and comedian Phoebe Robinson team up to answer that question and find themselves at odds with an old-time advice columnist who thinks women should not go looking for love.  Phoebe, who is also the host of her own Comedy Central series “Doing the Most with Phoebe Robinson” and of the podcast turned HBO special “Two Dope Queens” and Tig share a laugh over forgetting what they&#39;re talking about right in the middle of their conversation.  And they have some fun advice for a listener with a cranky grandma and another one with a parrot interfering in his owner&#39;s love life.<br><br><strong>OUR SPONSORS:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Betterhelp</strong> - <a href="http://betterhelp.com/tig">betterhelp.com/tig</a> </p>
<p><strong>Sakara</strong> - <a href="http://sakara.com/dontask">sakara.com/dontask</a> and use code: <strong>dontask20</strong></p>
<p>Need advice? Submit your question for Tig at <a href="https://www.dontasktig.org/contact">dontasktig.org/contact</a>.</p>
]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure length="21115008" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://play.podtrac.com/APM-DontAskTig/chrt.fm/track/3G835/pdst.fm/e/traffic.megaphone.fm/CAD5725414337.mp3"/>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Sep 2021 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <itunes:duration>00:43:53</itunes:duration>
      <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sanjay Gupta</title>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">01FG2KK4YW4EQVE4W0X2CTE1Q1</guid>
      <itunes:author>American Public Media</itunes:author>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>This is your chance to hear advice on careers, love and COVID from one of America&#39;s best-known doctors, Sanjay Gupta!  Dr. Gupta is not only an Emmy-award winning CNN medical correspondent, he&#39;s also a neurosurgeon and was once listed on People Magazine&#39;s sexiest people alive.  So, it&#39;s safe to say,  he&#39;s overqualified to join Tig as they offer guidance to a high school student on how to break it to her mother that she wants to be a TV journalist instead of a doctor. They also help a listener decide whether to stay in their marriage or pursue a crush. And he and Tig discuss the pros and cons about being considered a sex symbol.</p>
<p></p>
<p><br><strong>OUR SPONSORS:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Betterhelp</strong> - <a href="http://betterhelp.com/tig">betterhelp.com/tig</a> </p>
<p><strong>Wealthfront</strong> - <a href="https://invest.wealthfront.com/TIG?utm_medium=podcast&utm_source=dontasktig&utm_campaign=podcast_invest_q32021" class="default">wealthfront.com/tig</a></p>
<p><strong>Nutrafol</strong> - <a href="https://nutrafol.com/" class="default">nutrafol.com</a> and use code “TIG”</p>
<p>Need advice? Submit your question for Tig at <a href="https://www.dontasktig.org/contact">dontasktig.org/contact</a>.</p>
]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure length="17404032" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://play.podtrac.com/APM-DontAskTig/chrt.fm/track/3G835/pdst.fm/e/traffic.megaphone.fm/CAD3153154593.mp3"/>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Sep 2021 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <itunes:duration>00:36:10</itunes:duration>
      <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Samantha Bee</title>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">01FFK8QHXYKZCHY3ZCBJJCCYWV</guid>
      <itunes:author>American Public Media</itunes:author>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>No one speaks their mind quite like comedian, TV host Samantha Bee, and this time she&#39;s upfront and personal with Tig. Together they advise a listener on how to snap out of a crush on their therapist and tackle the tough issue of figuring out if someone actually likes you or is just being polite. Then Tig and Samantha bond over how and when they each had that &quot;birds and bees talk&quot; with their own kids and also how they personally cope with grieving a lost loved one. </p>
<p>This episode is sponsored by Betterhelp Online Counseling (betterhelp.com/tig) and Indeed (indeed.com/tig). </p>
<p>Need advice? Submit your question for Tig at dontasktig.org/contact</p>
]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure length="22126720" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://play.podtrac.com/APM-DontAskTig/chrt.fm/track/3G835/pdst.fm/e/traffic.megaphone.fm/CAD9993930034.mp3"/>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Sep 2021 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <itunes:duration>00:45:49</itunes:duration>
      <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Margaret Cho</title>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">01FD7FSW8C767YJAMYWMEZHNC5</guid>
      <itunes:author>American Public Media</itunes:author>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>Back in the dating scene and contemplating whether it would help to delete all traces of all exes from your social media? Feeling guilty about leaving your dog home alone now that there are safer ways to gather outside socially? Comedian and actress Margaret Cho steps in to advise Tig’s listeners with pearls from her personal history. Tig and Margaret bond over their love for country music and offer up some frank talk about how best to remove yourself from a draining relationship. </p>
<p>This episode is sponsored by Betterhelp Online Counseling (betterhelp.com/tig), Brooklinen (brooklinen.com and use promo code: Tig) and Ned (ned.com/tig).</p>
]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure length="16527488" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://play.podtrac.com/APM-DontAskTig/chrt.fm/track/3G835/pdst.fm/e/traffic.megaphone.fm/CAD9385908713.mp3"/>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Aug 2021 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <itunes:duration>00:34:09</itunes:duration>
      <itunes:explicit>yes</itunes:explicit>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Janet Varney</title>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">01FCPE1XQV042CRA739A8AWVMF</guid>
      <itunes:author>American Public Media</itunes:author>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>Need some new ideas for how to fend off creepy guys at work?  Should you reveal how you tricked a former teacher now that you&#39;re going to be his colleague?  Actor and co-founder of SF Sketchfest Janet Varney joins Tig to give advice on those questions, and even tackle the tricky issue of how much to tip waiters in a foreign country... which brings up one of Tig&#39;s most embarrassing and funny memories.</p>
<p>This episode is sponsored by Betterhelp Online Counseling (betterhelp.com/tig), Indeed (indeed.com/tig), and Wealthfront (wealthfront.com/tig).</p>
<p>Need advice? Submit your question for Tig at dontasktig.org/contact.</p>
]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure length="20639872" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://play.podtrac.com/APM-DontAskTig/chrt.fm/track/3G835/pdst.fm/e/traffic.megaphone.fm/CAD4398442671.mp3"/>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Aug 2021 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <itunes:duration>00:42:43</itunes:duration>
      <itunes:explicit>yes</itunes:explicit>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LeVar Burton</title>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">01FC6ZNY4FTNHZ7MMCCRJXGF78</guid>
      <itunes:author>American Public Media</itunes:author>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>Don’t know how to deal with romantic feelings for a coworker that’s already in a relationship? Still, feeling guilty from that illegal left turn you made decades ago that potentially caused a multi-vehicle pileup? Well, actor and television host LeVar Burton drops by Don’t Ask Tig to help you out. LeVar, who played Lieutenant Commander Geordi La Forge in “Star Trek: The Next Generation,” gives Tig some well-needed advice, commander to commander, about the joys and overwhelm that comes with being a part of the iconic franchise. </p>
<p>This episode is sponsored by Betterhelp Online Counseling (betterhelp.com/Tig), Ned (ned.com/tig), and Brooklinen (brooklinen.com and use promo code: Tig). </p>
<p>Need advice? Submit your question for Tig at dontasktig.org/contact.</p>
<p><br></p>
]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure length="16343168" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://play.podtrac.com/APM-DontAskTig/chrt.fm/track/3G835/pdst.fm/e/traffic.megaphone.fm/CAD2111402214.mp3"/>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2021 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <itunes:duration>00:33:46</itunes:duration>
      <itunes:explicit>yes</itunes:explicit>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Martha Beck</title>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">01FBMJHKDNB4P3PKXEQ4NNTNF1</guid>
      <itunes:author>American Public Media</itunes:author>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>Find yourself confused about the difference between a life coach and a therapist? Well, highly sought-after life coach and New York Times bestselling author Martha Beck pays Tig a visit to explain. Together, the two help a recently single woman work through the anger of getting dumped out of the blue. Martha and Tig also advise a Quaker minister on what to do now that his congregation -- which is filled with people who hate each other -- is returning to in-person service.  </p>
<p>This episode is sponsored by Betterhelp Online Counseling (betterhelp.com/Tig), Ned (ned.com/tig), and Wealthfront (wealthfront.com/tig).</p>
<p>Need advice? Submit your question for Tig at dontasktig.org/contact.</p>
<p><br></p>
]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure length="18110592" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://play.podtrac.com/APM-DontAskTig/chrt.fm/track/3G835/pdst.fm/e/traffic.megaphone.fm/CAD4492849496.mp3"/>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jul 2021 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <itunes:duration>00:37:27</itunes:duration>
      <itunes:explicit>yes</itunes:explicit>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mike Birbiglia</title>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">01FB34MJZKZV138RDVEFH8GBQ5</guid>
      <itunes:author>American Public Media</itunes:author>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>Need to perform a DIY exorcism to rid an inheritance of bad energy? Did someone from your past write an unflattering song about you in their first EP? Tig and comedian/actor Mike Birbiglia have some answers to navigate these situations and more. Mike also explains why “maybe quit” is a part of his advice to creatives aspiring to make it in Hollywood.</p>
<p>This episode is sponsored by Betterhelp Online Counseling (www.betterhelp.com/Tig),  the “Happier with Gretchen Rubin” podcast (listen wherever you get podcasts), and Bambee (www.bambee.com/tig).<br></p>
<p>Need advice?  Submit your question for Tig at www.dontasktig.org/contact.</p>
<p><br></p>
]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure length="17598592" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://play.podtrac.com/APM-DontAskTig/chrt.fm/track/3G835/pdst.fm/e/traffic.megaphone.fm/CAD5224521400.mp3"/>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2021 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <itunes:duration>00:36:23</itunes:duration>
      <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Esther Perel</title>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">01FAGZW2C0PDMCAN15B5NM0D4Z</guid>
      <itunes:author>American Public Media</itunes:author>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>How do you choose between staying with your boyfriend or pursuing his best friend who is so hot you’re dreaming about him at night?  Is there a way to get those sexual sparks back if your partner’s body changes to the point where you no longer feel attracted to them? Who better to ask than relationship expert Esther Perel who joins Tig in person to talk sex, love and intimacy? The world-renowned therapist also discusses new emotional patterns she sees as Americans emerge from pandemic lockdowns and how we can use play, like her new game &quot;Where Should We Begin - A Game of Stories,&quot; to ease back into life. Learn more at <a href="http://www.Estherperel.com/thegame" class="default">Estherperel.com/thegame</a></p>
<p>This episode is sponsored by Betterhelp Online Counseling (betterhelp.com/Tig), Brooklinen (brooklinen.com and use promo code: Tig), and Indeed (indeed.com/tig). </p>
<p>Need advice?  Submit your question for Tig at dontasktig.org/contact. </p>
<p><br></p>
]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure length="22399104" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://play.podtrac.com/APM-DontAskTig/chrt.fm/track/3G835/pdst.fm/e/traffic.megaphone.fm/CAD3526713710.mp3"/>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <itunes:duration>00:46:23</itunes:duration>
      <itunes:explicit>yes</itunes:explicit>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cyndi Lauper</title>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">01F74PKM3R3PEQ60Q6643YCKRG</guid>
      <itunes:author>American Public Media</itunes:author>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>What should you do if your daughter just wants to have fun-- hanging out at her wealthy boyfriend&#39;s house instead of yours?  Music icon Cyndi Lauper and Tig answer that,  plus give advice to a woman who lost her mother&#39;s diamond decades ago and wonders if she should confess now. Cyndi also admits she sometimes pretends she&#39;s someone else when spotted by a fan in public, and Tig tries to help Cyndi figure out which celebrities are in her cell phone under coded initials.</p>
<p>This episode is sponsored by Betterhelp Online Counseling (betterhelp.com/Tig), Indeed (indeed.com/tig), Storyblocks (storyblocks.com/tig), and Sakara (sakara.com/dontask and use code: dontask20).</p>
<p>Need advice?  Submit your question for Tig at dontasktig.org/contact.</p>
<p><br></p>
]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure length="16609408" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://play.podtrac.com/APM-DontAskTig/chrt.fm/track/3G835/pdst.fm/e/traffic.megaphone.fm/CAD2799198815.mp3"/>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2021 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <itunes:duration>00:34:19</itunes:duration>
      <itunes:explicit>yes</itunes:explicit>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jane Velez-Mitchell</title>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">01F6JG2EGNVVTT7G9TB1SQHYWA</guid>
      <itunes:author>American Public Media</itunes:author>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>What should you do if your dog eats a friend&#39;s $12-hundred dollar shoes? How about if your kid wants to be vegan?  And why you should kick a vaping habit? Outspoken journalist, author, activist Jane Velez-Mitchell joins Tig to dispense no-nonsense advice on those and other issues like telling the world you&#39;re a lesbian later in life and how to stop a friend from opening a bakery when they&#39;re a terrible baker!</p>
<p>This episode is sponsored by Betterhelp Online Counseling (betterhelp.com/Tig), Sakara (sakara.com/dontask and use code: dontask20), and Tor Books&#39; The Invisible Life of Addie LaRue, available now wherever books are sold.</p>
<p>Need advice?  Submit your question for Tig at <a href="http://dontasktig.org/contact" class="default">dontasktig.org/contact</a>.  </p>
<p><br></p>
]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure length="21710976" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://play.podtrac.com/APM-DontAskTig/chrt.fm/track/3G835/pdst.fm/e/traffic.megaphone.fm/CAD8313657519.mp3"/>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 May 2021 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <itunes:duration>00:44:56</itunes:duration>
      <itunes:explicit>yes</itunes:explicit>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Zack Snyder</title>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">01F60RG41DHJJBPQJYTERDFGXV</guid>
      <itunes:author>American Public Media</itunes:author>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>What does it take to replace one key actor in a feature film after it&#39;s edited?  The director of “Superman” and “Justice League,” Zack Snyder, explains how his team inserted Tig into hours of footage with green screens and other tricks, while Tig reveals her acting techniques on Zack&#39;s latest film “Army of the Dead.” Plus, Tig and Zack offer advice on how to tactfully get rid of all that artwork your kids bring home from school and suggest the most thoughtful ways to tell your partner they really need a shower— especially when they&#39;ve lost their sense of smell.</p>
<p>This episode is sponsored by Betterhelp Online Counseling (betterhelp.com/Tig), Sakara (sakara.com/dontask and use code: dontask20), and Bambee (bambee.com/tig). </p>
<p>Need advice?  Submit your question for Tig at dontasktig.org/contact.  </p>
]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure length="18364544" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://play.podtrac.com/APM-DontAskTig/chrt.fm/track/3G835/pdst.fm/e/traffic.megaphone.fm/CAD1785313393.mp3"/>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 May 2021 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <itunes:duration>00:37:58</itunes:duration>
      <itunes:explicit>yes</itunes:explicit>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sunny Hostin</title>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">01F5EF4GDG9EQ1ZECPZT21TNVM</guid>
      <itunes:author>American Public Media</itunes:author>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>Want advice on how to ask the cashier at your local Trader Joe’s for a date? Unsure how to handle your grandma, who&#39;s apparently developed a habit of forging autographs? How about needing help naming your beehive?  Get answers to those and other pressing questions when Tig chats with TV host, journalist, and lawyer Sunny Hostin, who also tells all about how Whoopie Goldberg&#39;s shoes created a blood sport behind the scenes on &quot;The View.&quot; </p>
<p>This episode is sponsored by Betterhelp Online Counseling (betterhelp.com/Tig), Indeed (indeed.com/tig), and Storyblocks (storyblocks.com/tig).</p>
<p>Need advice?  Submit your question for Tig at dontasktig.org/contact.  </p>
<p><br></p>
]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure length="20523136" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://play.podtrac.com/APM-DontAskTig/chrt.fm/track/3G835/pdst.fm/e/traffic.megaphone.fm/CAD1784119947.mp3"/>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <itunes:duration>00:42:28</itunes:duration>
      <itunes:explicit>yes</itunes:explicit>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ed Helms</title>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">01F4WEWDPE54T2T4RFVGVF5H91</guid>
      <itunes:author>American Public Media</itunes:author>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p> Comedian and actor Ed Helms, star of The Office and Hangover movies, discloses how he handles awkward fans who yell at him across airports, and how to deliver an inspiring commencement speech. Then Tig and Ed help listeners navigate annoying office hygiene issues and working with an eccentric billionaire.</p>
<p>This episode is sponsored by Betterhelp Online Counseling (betterhelp.com/Tig) and Sakara (sakara.com/dontask and use code: dontask20).</p>
<p>Need advice?  Submit your question for Tig at dontasktig.org/contact.  </p>
<p><br></p>
]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure length="19746944" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://play.podtrac.com/APM-DontAskTig/chrt.fm/track/3G835/pdst.fm/e/traffic.megaphone.fm/CAD7446418822.mp3"/>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 May 2021 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <itunes:duration>00:40:51</itunes:duration>
      <itunes:explicit>yes</itunes:explicit>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fran Lebowitz</title>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">01F47PS1F1ERDPE7FDYWXM8FGD</guid>
      <itunes:author>American Public Media</itunes:author>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p> Contemplating a trip to Mars? ... how about if it&#39;s only one way? Wondering how you can learn to be funnier? Writer and social commentator Fran Lebowitz responds to listener questions and explains why she believes that a density of &quot;angry homosexuals&quot; is good for a city. Plus, Fran tells Tig what she wishes she could ask her late friend, novelist and Nobel Laureate, Toni Morrison.</p>
<p>This episode is sponsored by Betterhelp Online Counseling (betterhelp.com/Tig), Sakara (sakara.com/dontask, use code: dontask20), and the podcast Back From Broken.</p>
<p>Need advice?  Submit your question for Tig at dontasktig.org/contact.  </p>
<p><br></p>
]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure length="14360704" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://play.podtrac.com/APM-DontAskTig/chrt.fm/track/3G835/pdst.fm/e/traffic.megaphone.fm/CAD8013186483.mp3"/>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Apr 2021 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <itunes:duration>00:29:38</itunes:duration>
      <itunes:explicit>yes</itunes:explicit>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lilly Singh</title>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">01F3RX9HVY71EHR8H8KS7R9ZA8</guid>
      <itunes:author>American Public Media</itunes:author>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>NBC host and comedian Lilly Singh dishes about the best advice she ever received from her mentor Dwayne &quot;The Rock&quot; Johnson and why producing her talk show, &quot;A Little Late With Lilly Singh,&quot; is more fun the second time around. Then, Tig and Lilly give their takes on texting etiquette, responses to unwanted comments about your body, and what to do if your mother says she wants to move in with you.</p>
<p>This episode is sponsored by Betterhelp Online Counseling (betterhelp.com/Tig) and Sakara (sakara.com/dontask and use code: dontask20).</p>
<p>Need advice?  Submit your question for Tig at dontasktig.org/contact.</p>
]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure length="19832960" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://play.podtrac.com/APM-DontAskTig/chrt.fm/track/3G835/pdst.fm/e/traffic.megaphone.fm/CAD8097477194.mp3"/>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Apr 2021 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <itunes:duration>00:41:02</itunes:duration>
      <itunes:explicit>yes</itunes:explicit>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Paula Poundstone</title>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">01F36FM0EV9X573CHP265E1KGM</guid>
      <itunes:author>American Public Media</itunes:author>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>Having trouble getting your kids to read books? Got an uncomfortable secret you need to share with a friend before they walk down the aisle? Comedian Paula Poundstone and Tig are here to help. Plus, Paula discusses interacting with her stand-up audiences and how she carries on conversations during dates.</p>
<p>This episode is sponsored by Betterhelp Online Counseling (betterhelp.com/Tig), Sakara (sakara.com/dontask, use code: dontask20), and the podcast Back From Broken.</p>
<p>Need advice?  Submit your question for Tig at dontasktig.org/contact.  </p>
<p><br></p>
]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure length="24277120" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://play.podtrac.com/APM-DontAskTig/chrt.fm/track/3G835/pdst.fm/e/traffic.megaphone.fm/CAD3796742645.mp3"/>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Apr 2021 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <itunes:duration>00:50:17</itunes:duration>
      <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Andrew Yang</title>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">01F2M5F93MF3T4NAG89799K1BF</guid>
      <itunes:author>American Public Media</itunes:author>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>Is it possible to have a successful run for public office even if you don’t end up winning? Andrew Yang looks back on his 2020 presidential bid and looks forward to his bid for mayor of New York City. Andrew also helps Tig advise listeners on setting boundaries if you’re an introvert, and how to gently let someone know that they’ve been calling you by the wrong name for a really long time.</p>
<p>Get tickets to <em>Don’t Ask Tig: Live!</em> with Nick Kroll on April 8th at <a href="http://www.dontasktig.org/tickets">dontasktig.org/tickets</a>! It helps support this public radio podcast!</p>
<p>This episode is sponsored by Betterhelp Online Counseling (betterhelp.com/Tig).</p>
<p>Need advice?  Submit your question for Tig at dontasktig.org/contact.  </p>
]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure length="18133120" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://play.podtrac.com/APM-DontAskTig/chrt.fm/track/3G835/pdst.fm/e/traffic.megaphone.fm/CAD7067547421.mp3"/>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Apr 2021 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <itunes:duration>00:37:29</itunes:duration>
      <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Judd Apatow </title>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">01F21XB4YACVKB0EKD5F3P8XA9</guid>
      <itunes:author>American Public Media</itunes:author>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>Recorded live last December, Judd Apatow gets candid about mentorship and the ways that his personal life end up in his films. Tig and Judd give advice about initiating a breakup, motivating an unmotivated retiree to spice up his life, and getting an odorous co-worker to use deodorant. Want to check out video of the event? </p>
<p>Get tickets to <em>Don’t Ask Tig: Live!</em> with Nick Kroll on April 8th at <a href="http://www.dontasktig.org/tickets">dontasktig.org/tickets</a>! It helps support this public radio podcast!</p>
<p>This episode is sponsored by Betterhelp Online Counseling (<a href="http://betterhelp.com/Tig">betterhelp.com/Tig</a>) and Sakara (<a href="http://sakara.com/dontask">sakara.com/dontask</a> and use code: dontask20). </p>
<p>Need advice?  Submit your question for Tig at dontasktig.org/contact. </p>
<p><br></p>
]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure length="16586880" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://play.podtrac.com/APM-DontAskTig/chrt.fm/track/3G835/pdst.fm/e/traffic.megaphone.fm/CAD5074579838.mp3"/>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Mar 2021 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <itunes:duration>00:34:16</itunes:duration>
      <itunes:explicit>yes</itunes:explicit>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rebecca Walker </title>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">01F1GMSXYXDE3KP4541HREVVCN</guid>
      <itunes:author>American Public Media</itunes:author>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>Rebecca Walker shares her experience writing for Tig’s Amazon Prime series “One Mississippi” and what it was like growing up with a larger-than-life mother. Tig and Rebecca offer up their pearls of wisdom about teaching sexual boundaries to teens, de-scandalizing your child’s wedding music playlist, and how to stop unnecessarily apologizing. </p>
<p>Get tickets to <em>Don’t Ask Tig: Live!</em> with Nick Kroll on April 8th at <a href="http://www.dontasktig.org/tickets" class="default">dontasktig.org/tickets</a>!</p>
<p>This episode is sponsored by Betterhelp Online Counseling (betterhelp.com/Tig).  </p>
<p>Need advice?  Submit your question for Tig at dontasktig.org/contact.  </p>
]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure length="21311616" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://play.podtrac.com/APM-DontAskTig/chrt.fm/track/3G835/pdst.fm/e/traffic.megaphone.fm/CAD3069447762.mp3"/>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2021 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <itunes:duration>00:44:07</itunes:duration>
      <itunes:explicit>yes</itunes:explicit>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Molly Ringwald</title>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">01F0YD6R37WWBAFH2QTX6ZXF5X</guid>
      <itunes:author>American Public Media</itunes:author>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>We&#39;re back! Molly Ringwald admits that she&#39;s terrible at giving teenagers advice (despite being a teen movie icon). Molly and Tig advise on dealing with lottery-winning family members, finding your life&#39;s purpose, and what to do with old love letters.  </p>
<p>This episode is sponsored by Betterhelp Online Counseling (betterhelp.com/Tig) and Indeed (Indeed.com/Tig).  </p>
<p>Need advice? Submit your question for Tig at dontasktig.org/contact.</p>
]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure length="20846720" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://play.podtrac.com/APM-DontAskTig/chrt.fm/track/3G835/pdst.fm/e/traffic.megaphone.fm/CAD1408430614.mp3"/>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Mar 2021 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <itunes:duration>00:43:09</itunes:duration>
      <itunes:explicit>yes</itunes:explicit>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sarah Paulson</title>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">01EX0V3RYAGZ5Y6VJCEKHNKJ36</guid>
      <itunes:author>American Public Media</itunes:author>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>Tig and Sarah Paulson give advice on receiving sub-par baked goods and correcting someone’s word usage. They also name a car and auction off a gavel!</p>
<p>Don’t Ask Tig returns with new episodes March 10.</p>
<p>This episode is sponsored by Betterhelp Online Counseling (<a href="http://betterhelp.com/Tig" class="default">betterhelp.com/Tig</a>) and Indeed (I<a href="http://indeed.com/Tig" class="default">ndeed.com/Tig</a>)</p>
<p>Need advice? Submit your question for Tig at <a href="http://dontasktig.org/contact" class="default">dontasktig.org/contact</a>.</p>
<p>Follow us on <a href="http://twitter.com/dontasktig">Twitter</a>, <a href="http://facebook.com/dontasktig">Facebook</a>, and <a href="http://instagram.com/dontasktig">Instagram</a> at @DontAskTig.<br></p>
]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure length="21055616" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://play.podtrac.com/APM-DontAskTig/chrt.fm/track/3G835/pdst.fm/e/traffic.megaphone.fm/CAD2611977377.mp3"/>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <itunes:duration>00:43:35</itunes:duration>
      <itunes:explicit>yes</itunes:explicit>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nora McInerny</title>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">01EWEZ8NNRT06AHN5K84DVTS3Z</guid>
      <itunes:author>American Public Media</itunes:author>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.noraborealis.com/" class="default">Nora McInerny</a> of <em><a href="http://ttfa.org" class="default">Terrible, Thanks For Asking</a></em> joins Tig to give advice on hard times, old friends, skater boys, and Cheap Johnnies. </p>
<p>This episode is sponsored by BetterHelp Online Counseling (<a href="https://www.betterhelp.com/start/?go=true&transaction_id=102442413cc58e3f362d4b7f659058&utm_source=podcast&utm_campaign=1093&utm_medium=Mac+OS+X&utm_content=&utm_term=tig&not_found=1&gor=start">betterhelp.com/Tig</a>) and by Sakara (<a href="https://www.sakara.com/pages/dont-ask-tig">sakara.com/DontAsk</a>)</p>
<p>Need advice? Submit your question for Tig at dontasktig.org/contact.</p>
<p>Follow us on <a href="http://twitter.com/dontasktig">Twitter</a>, <a href="http://facebook.com/dontasktig">Facebook</a>, and <a href="http://instagram.com/dontasktig">Instagram</a> at @DontAskTig.<br></p>
]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure length="18231424" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://play.podtrac.com/APM-DontAskTig/chrt.fm/track/3G835/pdst.fm/e/traffic.megaphone.fm/CAD5223824730.mp3"/>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2021 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <itunes:duration>00:37:42</itunes:duration>
      <itunes:explicit>yes</itunes:explicit>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Robin Roberts</title>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">01EVWJM826WQ8HH49QP6DWDXMH</guid>
      <itunes:author>American Public Media</itunes:author>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>Robin Roberts and Tig catch up on growing up in Mississippi in this chat from December. Plus, Tig and Robin advise on recreational space travel and making career choices, and they name a cat from Jersey!</p>
<p>This episode is sponsored by Indeed (<a href="http://indeed.com/tig" class="c-link">indeed.com/tig</a>) and Betterhelp (<a href="http://betterhelp.com/tig" class="c-link">betterhelp.com/tig</a> discount code tig)<br><br>Need advice? Submit your question for Tig at dontasktig.org/contact.</p>
<p>Follow us on <a href="http://twitter.com/dontasktig">Twitter</a>, <a href="http://facebook.com/dontasktig">Facebook</a>, and <a href="http://instagram.com/dontasktig">Instagram</a> at @DontAskTig.<br></p>
]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure length="19038336" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://play.podtrac.com/APM-DontAskTig/chrt.fm/track/3G835/pdst.fm/e/traffic.megaphone.fm/CAD2061026034.mp3"/>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2021 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <itunes:duration>00:39:23</itunes:duration>
      <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title> Jameela Jamil</title>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">01EVA4659KJC1RSQNNG6PZH444</guid>
      <itunes:author>American Public Media</itunes:author>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>Jameela Jamil has the advice you need in the new year, whether you’re facing your nemesis or your own insecurities. Jameela and Tig talk bad kissers, loud roommates and how to stand up for yourself in all situations.<br><br>This episode is sponsored by BetterHelp Online Counseling (<a href="https://www.betterhelp.com/start/?go=true&transaction_id=102442413cc58e3f362d4b7f659058&utm_source=podcast&utm_campaign=1093&utm_medium=Mac+OS+X&utm_content=&utm_term=tig&not_found=1&gor=start">betterhelp.com/Tig</a>) and by Sakara (<a href="https://www.sakara.com/pages/dont-ask-tig">sakara.com/DontAsk</a>).<br><br>Need advice? Submit your question for Tig at dontasktig.org/contact.</p>
<p></p>
<p>Follow us on <a href="http://twitter.com/dontasktig">Twitter</a>, <a href="http://facebook.com/dontasktig">Facebook</a>, and <a href="http://instagram.com/dontasktig">Instagram</a> at @DontAskTig.</p>
]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure length="19503232" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://play.podtrac.com/APM-DontAskTig/chrt.fm/track/3G835/pdst.fm/e/traffic.megaphone.fm/CAD9999591737.mp3"/>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2021 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <itunes:duration>00:40:21</itunes:duration>
      <itunes:explicit>yes</itunes:explicit>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reese Witherspoon</title>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">01ESMKP9YP6PYFGPGB0CWW21HH</guid>
      <itunes:author>American Public Media</itunes:author>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>Reese Witherspoon drops in with her signature advice style: “super proper meets kinda country.” Reese and Tig advise on true love, trying to find friends, and how many gifts are too many gifts. Plus, they have some shoe recommendations for you. </p>
<p>Get tickets to <em>Don’t Ask Tig: Live!</em> with Judd Apatow on December 17th at <a href="http://www.dontasktig.org/tickets" class="default">dontasktig.org/tickets</a>!</p>
<p>This episode is sponsored by Headspace (<a href="https://www.headspace.com/tig">headspace.com/tig</a>) and BetterHelp Online Counseling (<a href="https://www.betterhelp.com/start/?go=true&transaction_id=102442413cc58e3f362d4b7f659058&utm_source=podcast&utm_campaign=1093&utm_medium=Mac+OS+X&utm_content=&utm_term=tig&not_found=1&gor=start">betterhelp.com/Tig</a>).</p>
<p>Need advice? Submit your question for Tig at dontasktig.org/contact.</p>
<p>Follow us on <a href="http://twitter.com/dontasktig">Twitter</a>, <a href="http://facebook.com/dontasktig">Facebook</a>, and <a href="http://instagram.com/dontasktig">Instagram</a> at @DontAskTig.</p>
]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure length="20527232" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://play.podtrac.com/APM-DontAskTig/chrt.fm/track/3G835/pdst.fm/e/traffic.megaphone.fm/CAD9093149892.mp3"/>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2020 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <itunes:duration>00:42:29</itunes:duration>
      <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Roxane Gay</title>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">01ES1SNV3YE04MST54AT1Q7382</guid>
      <itunes:author>American Public Media</itunes:author>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>Roxane Gay joins Tig to share her thoughts on gossip (good), cats (sometimes evil) and being social (it takes work!). Plus, Tig and Roxane trade advice for a girl stuck with a date who is “dull as tarnished silver.”</p>
<p>Get tickets to <em>Don’t Ask Tig: Live!</em> with Judd Apatow on December 17th at <a href="http://www.dontasktig.org/tickets" class="default">dontasktig.org/tickets</a></p>
<p>This episode is sponsored by BetterHelp Online Counseling (<a href="https://www.betterhelp.com/start/?go=true&transaction_id=102442413cc58e3f362d4b7f659058&utm_source=podcast&utm_campaign=1093&utm_medium=Mac+OS+X&utm_content=&utm_term=tig%C2%AC_found=1&gor=start">betterhelp.com/Tig</a>).</p>
<p>Need advice? Submit your question for Tig at dontasktig.org/contact.</p>
<p>Follow us on <a href="http://twitter.com/dontasktig">Twitter</a>, <a href="http://facebook.com/dontasktig">Facebook</a>, and <a href="http://instagram.com/dontasktig">Instagram</a> at @DontAskTig.</p>
]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure length="15696000" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://play.podtrac.com/APM-DontAskTig/chrt.fm/track/3G835/pdst.fm/e/traffic.megaphone.fm/CAD7932988906.mp3"/>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Dec 2020 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <itunes:duration>00:32:25</itunes:duration>
      <itunes:explicit>yes</itunes:explicit>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Atsuko Okatsuka</title>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">01ERGRF99NXN2QW676G736RGJ8</guid>
      <itunes:author>American Public Media</itunes:author>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>What if you accidentally broke up with your soulmate? Comedian Atsuko Okatsuka of “<a href="http://www.atsukookatsuka.com/lets-go-atsuko.html" class="default">Let’s Go, Atsuko!</a>” joins Tig to talk unrequited love, game shows gone wrong and mismatched hiking abilities.</p>
<p>Get tickets to Don’t Ask Tig: Live! on December 17th at <a href="http://www.dontasktig.org/tickets" class="default">dontasktig.org/tickets</a></p>
<p>This episode is sponsored by BetterHelp Online Counseling (<a href="https://www.betterhelp.com/start/?go=true&transaction_id=102442413cc58e3f362d4b7f659058&utm_source=podcast&utm_campaign=1093&utm_medium=Mac+OS+X&utm_content=&utm_term=tig&not_found=1&gor=start">betterhelp.com/Tig</a>).</p>
<p>Need advice? Submit your question for Tig at dontasktig.org/contact.</p>
<p>Follow us on <a href="http://twitter.com/dontasktig">Twitter</a>, <a href="http://facebook.com/dontasktig">Facebook</a>, and <a href="http://instagram.com/dontasktig">Instagram</a> at @DontAskTig.</p>
<p></p>
]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure length="13590656" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://play.podtrac.com/APM-DontAskTig/chrt.fm/track/3G835/pdst.fm/e/traffic.megaphone.fm/CAD1121372374.mp3"/>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2020 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <itunes:duration>00:28:02</itunes:duration>
      <itunes:explicit>yes</itunes:explicit>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stephen Colbert</title>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">01EQYCSQPMFGR0T25J2QM5044T</guid>
      <itunes:author>American Public Media</itunes:author>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p><strong> </strong>Stephen Colbert flies in with some special holiday advice, complete with catty pilgrims and vegan eggnog. </p>
<p>This episode is sponsored by Sakara (<a href="http://sakara.com/dontaskearlyaccess">sakara.com/DontAskEarlyAccess</a>) and BetterHelp Online Counseling (<a href="https://www.betterhelp.com/start/?go=true&transaction_id=102442413cc58e3f362d4b7f659058&utm_source=podcast&utm_campaign=1093&utm_medium=Mac+OS+X&utm_content=&utm_term=tig&not_found=1&gor=start">betterhelp.com/Tig</a>).<br><br>Need advice? Submit your question for Tig at dontasktig.org/contact.</p>
<p>Follow us on <a href="http://twitter.com/dontasktig">Twitter</a>, <a href="http://facebook.com/dontasktig">Facebook</a>, and <a href="http://instagram.com/dontasktig">Instagram</a> at @DontAskTig.</p>
<p><br></p>
]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure length="18903168" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://play.podtrac.com/APM-DontAskTig/chrt.fm/track/3G835/pdst.fm/e/traffic.megaphone.fm/CAD5843976467.mp3"/>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Nov 2020 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <itunes:duration>00:39:06</itunes:duration>
      <itunes:explicit>yes</itunes:explicit>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>David Sedaris</title>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">01EQCRB8T6H7DK183Z7XC1GF9J</guid>
      <itunes:author>American Public Media</itunes:author>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>Did you know wine can expire? David Sedaris and Tig tackle questions about terrible gift-givers and what happens when the pandemic quashes your dreams. </p>
<p>Get Don&#39;t Ask Tig masks and T-shirts at <a href="http://dontasktig.org/shop" class="default">dontasktig.org/shop</a>!</p>
<p>This episode is sponsored by BetterHelp Online Counseling (<a href="https://www.betterhelp.com/start/?go=true&transaction_id=102442413cc58e3f362d4b7f659058&utm_source=podcast&utm_campaign=1093&utm_medium=Mac+OS+X&utm_content=&utm_term=tig&not_found=1&gor=start">betterhelp.com/Tig</a>).<br><br>Need advice? Submit your question for Tig at dontasktig.org/contact.</p>
<p>Follow us on <a href="http://twitter.com/dontasktig">Twitter</a>, <a href="http://facebook.com/dontasktig">Facebook</a>, and <a href="http://instagram.com/dontasktig">Instagram</a> at @DontAskTig.</p>
<p><br></p>
]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure length="17750144" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://play.podtrac.com/APM-DontAskTig/chrt.fm/track/3G835/pdst.fm/e/traffic.megaphone.fm/CAD1042836866.mp3"/>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2020 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <itunes:duration>00:36:42</itunes:duration>
      <itunes:explicit>yes</itunes:explicit>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Aisha Tyler</title>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">01EPTR7Q87HXEYVEN54Q0W1RPT</guid>
      <itunes:author>American Public Media</itunes:author>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>Aisha Tyler and Tig met over 20 years ago doing stand-up, and now they’re here to swap advice on downsizing, dealing with parents who only watch Fox News, and the country mouse vs. city mouse divide. </p>
<p>Get Don&#39;t Ask Tig masks and T-shirts at <a href="http://dontasktig.org/shop" class="default">dontasktig.org/shop</a>!</p>
<p>This episode is sponsored by BetterHelp Online Counseling (<a href="https://www.betterhelp.com/start/?go=true&transaction_id=102442413cc58e3f362d4b7f659058&utm_source=podcast&utm_campaign=1093&utm_medium=Mac+OS+X&utm_content=&utm_term=tig&not_found=1&gor=start">betterhelp.com/Tig</a>).</p>
<p>Need advice? Submit your question for Tig at dontasktig.org/contact.</p>
<p>Follow us on <a href="http://twitter.com/dontasktig">Twitter</a>, <a href="http://facebook.com/dontasktig">Facebook</a>, and <a href="http://instagram.com/dontasktig">Instagram</a> at @DontAskTig.</p>
<p><br></p>
]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure length="18925696" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://play.podtrac.com/APM-DontAskTig/chrt.fm/track/3G835/pdst.fm/e/traffic.megaphone.fm/CAD6172553307.mp3"/>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2020 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <itunes:duration>00:39:09</itunes:duration>
      <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oscar Nuñez</title>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">01EP81KCP4NQEH77CB0QDECFDZ</guid>
      <itunes:author>American Public Media</itunes:author>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>Oscar Nuñez from &quot;The Office&quot; is here with advice on critical co-workers, dating while broke and drunk declarations of love.<br><br>This episode is sponsored by BetterHelp Online Counseling (<a href="https://www.betterhelp.com/start/?go=true&transaction_id=102442413cc58e3f362d4b7f659058&utm_source=podcast&utm_campaign=1093&utm_medium=Mac+OS+X&utm_content=&utm_term=tig&not_found=1&gor=start">betterhelp.com/Tig</a>) and by Sakara (<a href="https://www.sakara.com/pages/dont-ask-tig">sakara.com/DontAsk</a>).</p>
<p>Check out merch at our shop: <a href="https://bit.ly/DontAskTigShop" class="default">https://bit.ly/DontAskTigShop</a><br><br>Need advice? Submit your question for Tig at dontasktig.org/contact.<br></p>
<p>Follow us on <a href="http://twitter.com/dontasktig">Twitter</a>, <a href="http://facebook.com/dontasktig">Facebook</a>, and <a href="http://instagram.com/dontasktig">Instagram</a> at @DontAskTig.</p>
<p><br></p>
]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure length="14710912" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://play.podtrac.com/APM-DontAskTig/chrt.fm/track/3G835/pdst.fm/e/traffic.megaphone.fm/CAD8767713723.mp3"/>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Nov 2020 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <itunes:duration>00:30:22</itunes:duration>
      <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kate Moennig and Leisha Hailey</title>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">01ENPDKZWCZQFDGJ501QAPKXP6</guid>
      <itunes:author>American Public Media</itunes:author>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p><strong> </strong>Do you need a best friend? Kate Moennig and Leisha Hailey of the “The L Word” join Tig to give advice on long-lasting friendships, confronting cheaters and when a hickey goes too far. </p>
<p>Check out Kate and Leisha’s <em><a href="https://podcasts.apple.com/us/podcast/pants-with-kate-and-leisha/id1514861303" class="default">PANTS</a></em><a href="https://podcasts.apple.com/us/podcast/pants-with-kate-and-leisha/id1514861303" class="default"> podcast</a>.<br></p>
<p>This episode is sponsored by BetterHelp Online Counseling (<a href="https://www.betterhelp.com/start/?go=true&transaction_id=102442413cc58e3f362d4b7f659058&utm_source=podcast&utm_campaign=1093&utm_medium=Mac+OS+X&utm_content=&utm_term=tig&not_found=1&gor=start">betterhelp.com/Tig</a>).<br><br><br>Need advice? Submit your question for Tig at dontasktig.org/contact.<br></p>
<p>Follow us on <a href="http://twitter.com/dontasktig">Twitter</a>, <a href="http://facebook.com/dontasktig">Facebook</a>, and <a href="http://instagram.com/dontasktig">Instagram</a> at @DontAskTig.<br></p>
]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure length="15542400" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://play.podtrac.com/APM-DontAskTig/chrt.fm/track/3G835/pdst.fm/e/traffic.megaphone.fm/CAD3774508319.mp3"/>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2020 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <itunes:duration>00:32:06</itunes:duration>
      <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Indigo Girls</title>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">01EM0FHHH2EYESR83YX790YCNM</guid>
      <itunes:author>American Public Media</itunes:author>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>Tig and the Indigo Girls are here to offer you advice...or are they? Topics they might cover include honing your craft, healthy partnerships and how to get off the phone.</p>
<p>This episode is sponsored by Sakara (<a href="https://www.sakara.com/pages/dont-ask-tig">sakara.com/DontAsk</a>), BetterHelp Online Counseling (<a href="https://www.betterhelp.com/start/?go=true&transaction_id=102442413cc58e3f362d4b7f659058&utm_source=podcast&utm_campaign=1093&utm_medium=Mac+OS+X&utm_content=&utm_term=tig&not_found=1&gor=start">betterhelp.com/Tig</a>) and Indeed (indeed.com/Tig).</p>
<p>Need advice? Submit your question for Tig at dontasktig.org/contact.</p>
<p>Follow us on <a href="http://twitter.com/dontasktig">Twitter</a>, <a href="http://facebook.com/dontasktig">Facebook</a>, and <a href="http://instagram.com/dontasktig">Instagram</a> at @DontAskTig.</p>
<p><br></p>
]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure length="18622592" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://play.podtrac.com/APM-DontAskTig/chrt.fm/track/3G835/pdst.fm/e/traffic.megaphone.fm/CAD4530443876.mp3"/>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2020 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <itunes:duration>00:38:31</itunes:duration>
      <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Olivia Munn</title>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">01EKEC2MQEXR5KXW24QMBHY49V</guid>
      <itunes:author>American Public Media</itunes:author>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>If you’re walking down a dark alley, take Olivia Munn with you. Olivia and Tig talk about combating self-doubt, coming clean for karma and why you should consider martial arts. </p>
<p>This episode is sponsored by Sakara (<a href="https://www.sakara.com/pages/dont-ask-tig">sakara.com/DontAsk</a>) and BetterHelp Online Counseling (<a href="https://www.betterhelp.com/start/?go=true&transaction_id=102442413cc58e3f362d4b7f659058&utm_source=podcast&utm_campaign=1093&utm_medium=Mac+OS+X&utm_content=&utm_term=tig&not_found=1&gor=start">betterhelp.com/Tig</a>).</p>
<p>Need advice? Submit your question for Tig at dontasktig.org/contact.</p>
<p>Follow us on <a href="http://twitter.com/dontasktig">Twitter</a>, <a href="http://facebook.com/dontasktig">Facebook</a>, and <a href="http://instagram.com/dontasktig">Instagram</a> at @DontAskTig.</p>
<p><br></p>
]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure length="15358080" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://play.podtrac.com/APM-DontAskTig/chrt.fm/track/3G835/pdst.fm/e/traffic.megaphone.fm/CAD5453197943.mp3"/>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2020 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <itunes:duration>00:31:43</itunes:duration>
      <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stephanie Allynne</title>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">01EJWKA5RQT2B2DZ3G602FN0Q9</guid>
      <itunes:author>American Public Media</itunes:author>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>The advice is coming from inside the house! Tig is joined by her wife, actress and writer Stephanie Allynne, as they try to give tips on finding true love and monitoring kids’ screen time. Plus, what happens if you don’t think your partner is funny? <br></p>
<p>This episode is sponsored by Talk Space (<a href="https://www.talkspace.com/">talkspace.com</a>, code: DON’T ASK) and by the podcast True Crime Obsessed (<a href="https://www.truecrimeobsessed.com">truecrimeobsessed.com</a>).</p>
<p></p>
<p>Need advice? Submit your question for Tig at dontasktig.org/contact.</p>
<p>Follow us on <a href="http://twitter.com/dontasktig">Twitter</a>, <a href="http://facebook.com/dontasktig">Facebook</a>, and <a href="http://instagram.com/dontasktig">Instagram</a> at @DontAskTig.</p>
<p><br></p>
]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure length="16629888" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://play.podtrac.com/APM-DontAskTig/chrt.fm/track/3G835/pdst.fm/e/traffic.megaphone.fm/CAD8302545890.mp3"/>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2020 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <itunes:duration>00:34:22</itunes:duration>
      <itunes:explicit>yes</itunes:explicit>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cheryl Hines</title>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">01EJAKHWZSBCP3CTVP4736QD98</guid>
      <itunes:author>American Public Media</itunes:author>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>Sometimes you should just say no — and run away. Cheryl Hines and Tig share this and other timeless advice for speaking the truth and following your acting dreams. Plus, Tig debuts a brand new segment: Name That Thang.</p>
<p>This episode is sponsored by Indeed (<a href="http://indeed.com/Podcast">indeed.com/Podcast</a>) and BetterHelp Online Counseling (<a href="https://www.betterhelp.com/start/?go=true&transaction_id=102442413cc58e3f362d4b7f659058&utm_source=podcast&utm_campaign=1093&utm_medium=Mac+OS+X&utm_content=&utm_term=tig&not_found=1&gor=start">betterhelp.com/Tig</a>).</p>
<p>Need advice? Submit your question for Tig at dontasktig.org/contact.</p>
<p>Follow us on <a href="http://twitter.com/dontasktig">Twitter</a>, <a href="http://facebook.com/dontasktig">Facebook</a>, and <a href="http://instagram.com/dontasktig">Instagram</a> at @DontAskTig.</p>
]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure length="16431232" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://play.podtrac.com/APM-DontAskTig/chrt.fm/track/3G835/pdst.fm/e/traffic.megaphone.fm/CAD4833957160.mp3"/>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2020 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <itunes:duration>00:33:57</itunes:duration>
      <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reggie Watts</title>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">01EHDEABDSAHCV3CKH6K48XGQ8</guid>
      <itunes:author>American Public Media</itunes:author>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>Reggie Watts brings out his musical stylings in an attempt to solve your problems. Reggie and Tig dispense advice on changing careers, overly affectionate cats (no such thing!) and how to respond to that text you’ve been avoiding. Plus, we unveil our Worst Advice Hall of Fame. </p>
<p>This episode is sponsored by Sakara (<a href="https://www.sakara.com/pages/dont-ask-tig">sakara.com/DontAsk</a>) and BetterHelp Online Counseling (<a href="https://www.betterhelp.com/start/?go=true&transaction_id=102442413cc58e3f362d4b7f659058&utm_source=podcast&utm_campaign=1093&utm_medium=Mac+OS+X&utm_content=&utm_term=tig&not_found=1&gor=start">betterhelp.com/Tig</a>).</p>
<p>Need advice? Submit your question for Tig at <a href="http://dontasktig.org/contact" class="default">dontasktig.org/contact</a>.</p>
<p>Follow us on <a href="http://twitter.com/dontasktig">Twitter</a>, <a href="http://facebook.com/dontasktig">Facebook</a>, and <a href="http://instagram.com/dontasktig">Instagram</a> at @DontAskTig.<br></p>
]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure length="18559104" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://play.podtrac.com/APM-DontAskTig/chrt.fm/track/3G835/pdst.fm/e/traffic.megaphone.fm/CAD2579348204.mp3"/>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2020 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <itunes:duration>00:38:23</itunes:duration>
      <itunes:explicit>yes</itunes:explicit>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sean Hayes</title>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">01EH6FQF7X0Z8Y2ADRX93XMARR</guid>
      <itunes:author>American Public Media</itunes:author>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p><br>Is a big wedding worth it? Should you get that degree? Sean Hayes and Tig are here to offer some conflicting advice on topics of all kinds. Plus: Tig needs your help with a problem of her own.</p>
<p>This episode is sponsored by BetterHelp Online Counseling (<a href="https://www.betterhelp.com/start/?go=true&transaction_id=102442413cc58e3f362d4b7f659058&utm_source=podcast&utm_campaign=1093&utm_medium=Mac+OS+X&utm_content=&utm_term=tig&not_found=1&gor=start">betterhelp.com/Tig</a>) and Indeed (<a href="http://www.Indeed.com/Tig" class="default">Indeed.com/Tig</a>).</p>
<p>Need advice? Submit your question for Tig at <a href="http://dontasktig.org/contact" class="default">dontasktig.org/contact</a>.</p>
<p>Follow us on <a href="http://twitter.com/dontasktig">Twitter</a>, <a href="http://facebook.com/dontasktig">Facebook</a>, and <a href="http://instagram.com/dontasktig">Instagram</a> at @DontAskTig.</p>
<p></p>
]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure length="19101824" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://play.podtrac.com/APM-DontAskTig/chrt.fm/track/3G835/pdst.fm/e/traffic.megaphone.fm/CAD9797313911.mp3"/>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2020 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <itunes:duration>00:39:31</itunes:duration>
      <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Michelle Buteau</title>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">01EGKQRWPQ737CD30C7MRHVHPW</guid>
      <itunes:author>American Public Media</itunes:author>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p><strong> </strong>Tig and Michelle Buteau get breaking news while doling out advice! They talk DNA tests, asking for help and what songs you absolutely should not play at your wedding. </p>
<p>This episode is sponsored by Talkspace (<a href="https://www.talkspace.com">talkspace.com</a>, code: DONTASK) and by the podcast Obsessed With: Disappeared (<a href="http://disappearedpod.com/" class="default">disappearedpod.com</a>)</p>
<p>Need advice? Submit your question for Tig at dontasktig.org/contact.</p>
<p>Follow us on <a href="http://twitter.com/dontasktig">Twitter</a>, <a href="http://facebook.com/dontasktig">Facebook</a>, and <a href="http://instagram.com/dontasktig">Instagram</a> at @DontAskTig.</p>
<p><br></p>
]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure length="17070208" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://play.podtrac.com/APM-DontAskTig/chrt.fm/track/3G835/pdst.fm/e/traffic.megaphone.fm/CAD7286274075.mp3"/>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2020 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <itunes:duration>00:35:16</itunes:duration>
      <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ira Glass</title>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">01EG2G9391V2297T3NW2H001EG</guid>
      <itunes:author>American Public Media</itunes:author>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>Ira Glass of “This American Life” brings his podcast wisdom to the show. Ira and Tig discuss falling for roommates, trouble in the laboratory and deodorant etiquette in the wilderness.</p>
<p>This episode is sponsored by Sakara (<a href="https://www.sakara.com/pages/dont-ask-tig">sakara.com/DontAsk</a>) and BetterHelp Online Counseling (<a href="https://www.betterhelp.com/start/?go=true&transaction_id=102442413cc58e3f362d4b7f659058&utm_source=podcast&utm_campaign=1093&utm_medium=Mac+OS+X&utm_content=&utm_term=tig&not_found=1&gor=start">betterhelp.com/Tig</a>).</p>
<p>Need advice? Submit your question for Tig at dontasktig.org/contact.</p>
<p>Follow us on <a href="http://twitter.com/dontasktig">Twitter</a>, <a href="http://facebook.com/dontasktig">Facebook</a>, and <a href="http://instagram.com/dontasktig">Instagram</a> at @DontAskTig.</p>
<p><br></p>
]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure length="16230528" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://play.podtrac.com/APM-DontAskTig/chrt.fm/track/3G835/pdst.fm/e/traffic.megaphone.fm/CAD2953459438.mp3"/>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Aug 2020 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <itunes:duration>00:33:32</itunes:duration>
      <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nicole Byer</title>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">01EFG6AK1SYGFS1RTDTZPXBX6W</guid>
      <itunes:author>American Public Media</itunes:author>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>Emmy nominee Nicole Byer thinks you should get a hobby! Nicole and Tig dispense advice on how to make friends as an adult and whether you should take that big risk you’ve been dreaming about. </p>
<p>Need advice? Submit your question for Tig at <a href="http://dontasktig.org/contact" class="default">dontasktig.org/contact</a>.</p>
<p>Follow us on <a href="http://twitter.com/dontasktig">Twitter</a>, <a href="http://facebook.com/dontasktig">Facebook</a>, and <a href="http://instagram.com/dontasktig">Instagram</a> at @DontAskTig.</p>
<p><br></p>
]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure length="14823552" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://play.podtrac.com/APM-DontAskTig/chrt.fm/track/3G835/pdst.fm/e/traffic.megaphone.fm/CAD9293123888.mp3"/>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2020 02:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <itunes:duration>00:30:36</itunes:duration>
      <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Glennon Doyle</title>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">01EEXVDFKTN2Z36987H5BNXBZ4</guid>
      <itunes:author>American Public Media</itunes:author>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>Tig connects with writer Glennon Doyle -- a person potentially actually qualified to give advice -- to answer questions about breaking up with friends and negotiating office politics. <br><br>This episode is sponsored by Talk Space (<a href="https://www.talkspace.com/">talkspace.com</a>, code: DON’T ASK) and Latterday Lesbian Podcast (<a href="http://latterdaylesbian.org/index.html">latterdaylesbian.org</a>). <br><br>Need advice? Submit your question for Tig at dontasktig.org/contact.<br><br>Follow us on social:<br><a href="http://twitter.com/dontasktig" class="default">Twitter.com/dontasktig</a><br><a href="http://facebook.com/dontasktig" class="default">Facebook.com/dontasktig</a><br><a href="http://instagram.com/dontasktig" class="default">Instagram.com/dontasktig</a></p>
<p><br></p>
]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure length="16208000" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://play.podtrac.com/APM-DontAskTig/chrt.fm/track/3G835/pdst.fm/e/traffic.megaphone.fm/CAD1515845268.mp3"/>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2020 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <itunes:duration>00:33:29</itunes:duration>
      <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sarah Cooper</title>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">01EECCJPMC1VST9HTRGQ7BNXZY</guid>
      <itunes:author>American Public Media</itunes:author>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>Sarah Cooper entertains the internet by lip syncing to Trump’s most quotable soundbites, and now she’s offering some wisdom of her own. Sarah and Tig spar over advice on vegans, face masks, and how best to explain what happens when you die.</p>
<p>Need advice? Submit your question for Tig at dontasktig.org/contact.</p>
<p>Follow us on <a href="http://twitter.com/dontasktig">Twitter</a>, <a href="http://facebook.com/dontasktig">Facebook</a>, and <a href="http://instagram.com/dontasktig">Instagram</a> at @DontAskTig.</p>
<p><br></p>
]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure length="13848704" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://play.podtrac.com/APM-DontAskTig/chrt.fm/track/3G835/pdst.fm/e/traffic.megaphone.fm/CAD5404888024.mp3"/>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2020 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <itunes:duration>00:28:34</itunes:duration>
      <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Will Ferrell</title>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">01EDSZ466Q8FEC6QKKE9BCAQV1</guid>
      <itunes:author>American Public Media</itunes:author>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>Tig calls on Will Ferrell for advice on romantic proposals, marriage frustrations, and why you should really go to the dentist. Need advice? Submit your question for Tig at dontasktig.org/contact. Follow us on <a href="http://twitter.com/dontasktig">Twitter</a>, <a href="http://facebook.com/dontasktig">Facebook</a>, and <a href="http://instagram.com/dontasktig">Instagram</a> at @DontAskTig.</p>
<p><br></p>
]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure length="18473088" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://play.podtrac.com/APM-DontAskTig/chrt.fm/track/3G835/pdst.fm/e/traffic.megaphone.fm/CAD3580267756.mp3"/>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2020 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <itunes:duration>00:38:12</itunes:duration>
      <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Don’t Ask Tig</title>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">01EC0YKK047GH9X93FAG99V18T</guid>
      <itunes:author>American Public Media</itunes:author>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>Every week, comedian Tig Notaro and a rotating cast of guests field audience questions on love, loss and life’s other indignities. Coming July 22nd.</p>
<p>Need advice? Submit your question for Tig at www.dontasktig.org and click contact.</p>
<p>Follow us on <a href="http://twitter.com/dontasktig" class="default">Twitter</a>, <a href="http://facebook.com/dontasktig" class="default">Facebook</a>, and <a href="http://instagram.com/dontasktig" class="default">Instagram</a> at @DontAskTig.</p>
]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure length="544896" type="audio/mpeg" url="https://play.podtrac.com/APM-DontAskTig/chrt.fm/track/3G835/pdst.fm/e/traffic.megaphone.fm/CAD6198528353.mp3"/>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2020 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <itunes:duration>00:01:08</itunes:duration>
      <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
