<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>CNBC</title>
<link>http://www.cnbc.com/</link>
<description>News feeds provided by Newslookup.com</description>
<language>en</language>
<lastBuildDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2022 16:42:14 +0000</lastBuildDate>
<ttl>10</ttl>
<item>
<title>CNBC Free Feeds at Newslookup.com</title>
<link>http://www.cnbc.com/</link>
</item>
<item>
<title>Newslookup.com Free Access Alert</title>
<link>https://newslookup.com/donate</link>
<description>Newslookup.com is one of the oldest news search engines on the internet yet a very small company. Hosting thousands of feeds through our API, 100,000+ news category pages, a 60+ million news article archive and serving millions of page views a month globally. Providing this service as well as free access of course all comes at a significant expense in hardware, bandwidth and man power hours to maintain. Like any site we cannot exist without funding from advertising, subscriptions or donations. Therefore please consider supporting us through advertising or one of the donation links on our website.  We also accept payment in BTC - 3DTg51MJj54pepcRgT1t9ebB1b3QTcNQQ5, BCH - qqq27yfk3z5c5h59ymtj8yfu86c3ztwt8vdjhdzdzt, ETH - 0xf72AEE7C080337CbB7DDe6CB8e041FE6E000b268, LTC - MJyT1DVXZbuofaJUnJsmZJCBr6EEX1RUFA</description>
</item>
<item>
<title>Newslookup.com API</title>
<link>https://newslookup.com?referrer=rss</link>
<description>Please note a subscription is now required to the Newslookup.com API for automated queries. If you register an account and login, you can manage a free API subscription temporarily prior to your purchase of subscription. More details can be found at these links API Feed Manager, API Search Manager, API Documentation.</description>
</item>
<item>
<title>Twitter co-founder Dorsey apologizes for growing the company &amp;#39;too quickly&amp;#39; in wake of mass layoffs</title>
<link>https://www.cnbc.com/2022/11/05/twitter-co-founder-jack-dorsey-speaks-out-after-mass-layoffs.html</link>
<description>Twitter co-founder Jack Dorsey apologized Saturday for growing the company</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2022 15:34:55 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Kellogg&amp;#39;s just released a boozy, Eggo Waffles-inspired eggnog liqueur&amp;mdash;and I tried it</title>
<link>https://www.cnbc.com/2022/11/05/eggo-nog-eggnog-liqueur-review.html</link>
<description>Eggo decided to tackle the seasonal adult beverage to &amp;#39;give grownups a unique way to L&amp;#39;Eggo of the holiday stress this season.&amp;#39;</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2022 15:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>2 dating red flags&amp;mdash;and a green flag, according to Hinge users</title>
<link>https://www.cnbc.com/2022/11/05/2-dating-red-flagsand-a-green-flag-according-to-hinge-users.html</link>
<description>Finding a long-term match can feel like an overwhelming task, but going on better dates is more manageable. Here&amp;#39;s how.</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2022 15:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Stability in a volatile market? Inside an S&amp;P 500 ETF delivering double-digit percentage dividends</title>
<link>https://www.cnbc.com/2022/11/05/an-sp-500-etf-delivering-double-digit-percentage-dividends.html</link>
<description>The JPMorgan Equity Premium Income ETF seeks to provide the majority of returns associated with the S&amp;P 500 even in times of high market uncertainty.</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2022 15:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Climate activists swarm private jets at Amsterdam airport to protest pollution</title>
<link>https://www.cnbc.com/2022/11/05/climate-protesters-swarm-amsterdams-schiphol-airport-.html</link>
<description>Hundreds of climate activists swarmed a private jet section of Amsterdam&amp;#39;s Schiphol Airport on Saturday as part of a day of demonstrations in and around the airport.</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2022 14:32:50 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>An elite New York restauranteur on why luxury spending isn&amp;#39;t the key to making people happy</title>
<link>https://www.cnbc.com/2022/11/05/elite-nyc-restauranteur-on-why-luxury-spending-wont-make-people-happy.html</link>
<description>Will Guidara, former owner of Eleven Madison Park, learned a valuable lesson about spending and satisfaction with the help of his wife and a Cartier necklace.</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2022 14:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>I talked to 70 parents who raised highly successful adults&amp;mdash;here&amp;#39;s the &amp;#39;rare&amp;#39; skill they all taught their kids</title>
<link>https://www.cnbc.com/2022/11/05/i-talked-to-70-parents-who-raised-highly-successful-adults-heres-the-rare-skill-they-all-taught-their-kids.html</link>
<description>Parenting expert and author Margot Bisnow, who is a mother to two entrepreneurial sons, interviewed 70 families who raised confident and successful kids. Here&amp;#39;s the</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2022 14:04:55 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>The least stressful job that pays over $100K, according to data&amp;mdash;and how to get it</title>
<link>https://www.cnbc.com/2022/11/05/the-least-stressful-job-that-pays-over-100k-according-to-data-environmental-economist.html</link>
<description>Among O*NET&amp;#39;s list of jobs that are comparatively lower stress is environmental economist, in part because it&amp;#39;s less competitive and highly fulfilling.</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2022 14:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>In bankrupt Lebanon, locals mine bitcoin and buy groceries with tether, as $1 is now worth 15 cents</title>
<link>https://www.cnbc.com/2022/11/05/-in-bankrupt-lebanon-locals-mine-bitcoin-and-buy-groceries-with-tether.html</link>
<description>As Lebanon&amp;#39;s economy spirals into hyperinflation, locals explain how cryptocurrency has replaced a financial system that no longer makes sense.</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2022 13:34:55 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Companies still have way too much office space, and they can&amp;#39;t sell it</title>
<link>https://www.cnbc.com/2022/11/05/companies-still-have-way-too-much-office-space-and-they-cant-sell-it.html</link>
<description>Companies are sitting on a record amount of office real estate and this is no time to sell it.</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2022 13:30:01 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>