<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:rdau="http://rdaregistry.info/Elements/u/#" xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/" xmlns:swpo="http://sw-portal.deri.org/ontologies/swportal#" xmlns:identifiers="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/identifiers/" xmlns:ebucore="http://www.ebu.ch/metadata/ontologies/ebucore/ebucore#">
<channel>
<title>Federal Reserve Bank of New York publications</title>
<description>Economic research and commentary from Federal Reserve Bank of New York</description>
<link>https://fedinprint.org/search?facets[]=provider_literal_array:Federal+Reserve+Bank+of+New+York</link>
<atom:link href="https://fedinprint.org/search?facets[]=provider_literal_array:Federal+Reserve+Bank+of+New+York" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2022 15:47:55 +0000</pubDate>
<item>
<title>Should Mothers Work? How Perceptions of the Social Norm Affect Individual Attitudes Toward Work in the U.S.</title>
<link>https://fedinprint.org/item/fednsr/94979</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[We study how peer beliefs shape individual attitudes toward maternal labor supply using realistic hypothetical scenarios that elicit recommendations on the labor supply choices of a mother with a young child and an information treatment embedded within representative surveys. Across the scenarios, we find that individuals systematically overestimate the extent of gender conservativeness among the people around them. Exposure to information on peer beliefs leads to a shift in recommendations, driven largely by information-based belief updating. The information treatment also increases (intended and actual) donations to a nonprofit organization advocating for women in the workplace.]]>
</description>
<guid>https://fedinprint.org/item/fednsr/94979</guid>
<dc:creator>Pan, Jessica; Cortes, Patricia; Koşar, Gizem; Zafar, Basit</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2022-11-01</dc:date>
<rdau:hasExtent>32</rdau:hasExtent>
<dc:subject>expectations; social norms; information treatment</dc:subject>
<swpo:hasNumber>1038</swpo:hasNumber>
<bibo:series>Staff Reports</bibo:series>
</item>
<item>
<title>Things That Have Never Happened Before Happen All the Time</title>
<link>https://fedinprint.org/item/fednsp/94974</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[Remarks at the Central Bank of Nigeria’s Second National Risk Management Conference (delivered via videoconference).]]>
</description>
<guid>https://fedinprint.org/item/fednsp/94974</guid>
<dc:creator>Rosenberg, Joshua V.</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2022-10-27</dc:date>
<dc:subject>risk management</dc:subject>
<bibo:series>Speech</bibo:series>
</item>
<item>
<title>Bridging the Skills Gap</title>
<link>https://fedinprint.org/item/fednsp/94963</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[Remarks at the “Skilling the Gap: Building Local Talent for In-Demand Careers,” Columbia-Greene Community College, Hudson, New York.]]>
</description>
<guid>https://fedinprint.org/item/fednsp/94963</guid>
<dc:creator>Williams, John C.</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2022-10-21</dc:date>
<dc:subject>skills gap; labor shortage; labor supply; occupations</dc:subject>
<bibo:series>Speech</bibo:series>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Curious Case of the Rise in Deflation Expectations</title>
<link>https://fedinprint.org/item/fednsr/94960</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[We study the behavior of U.S. consumers’ inflation expectations during the high inflation period of 2021-22 using data from the Survey of Consumer Expectations. Short- and, to a lesser extent, mediumterm inflation expectations rose as inflation surged in 2021. Disagreement and uncertainty about future inflation increased significantly. Then, in 2022, even as inflation continued to climb, medium- and longerterm inflation expectations unexpectedly fell and medium- and longer-term deflation expectations increased. We find that respondents with deflation expectations tend to expect prices to mean revert and are more optimistic about the economic outlook.]]>
</description>
<guid>https://fedinprint.org/item/fednsr/94960</guid>
<dc:creator>Koşar, Gizem; Van der Klaauw, Wilbert; Armantier, Olivier; Topa, Giorgio; Williams, John C.; Somerville, Jason</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2022-10-01</dc:date>
<rdau:hasExtent>33</rdau:hasExtent>
<dc:subject>inflation; deflation; expectations; consumer surveys</dc:subject>
<swpo:hasNumber>1037</swpo:hasNumber>
<bibo:series>Staff Reports</bibo:series>
</item>
<item>
<title>All-to-All Trading in the U.S. Treasury Market</title>
<link>https://fedinprint.org/item/fednsr/94959</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[While the U.S. Treasury market remains the deepest and most liquid securities market in the world, several episodes of abrupt deterioration in market functioning over recent years have brought the market’s resilience into focus. The adoption of all-to-all trading in the Treasury market could be one avenue to strengthen market resilience. Conceptually, all-to-all trading would allow any market participant to trade directly with any other market participant. This could be particularly helpful in times of stress, when the capacity of traditional intermediaries may be tested. In this paper, we discuss what all-to-all trading would mean for the cash secondary Treasury market, the benefits it might bring, and the conditions that might make adoption of the protocol more likely. We also review several trading protocols operating in the Treasury market that widen the field of trading partners and discuss the challenges to broader adoption of such protocols.]]>
</description>
<guid>https://fedinprint.org/item/fednsr/94959</guid>
<dc:creator>Lee, Kyle; Fleming, Michael J.; Windover, Carolyn; Schwarz, Krista B.; Cox, Caren; Vega, Clara; Keane, Frank M.; Chaboud, Alain P.; Huh, Yesol; Golay, Ellen Correia</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2022-10-01</dc:date>
<rdau:hasExtent>36</rdau:hasExtent>
<dc:subject>Treasury market; market structure; all-to-all</dc:subject>
<swpo:hasNumber>1036</swpo:hasNumber>
<bibo:series>Staff Reports</bibo:series>
</item>
<item>
<title>Long COVID Appears to Have Led to a Surge of the Disabled in the Workplace</title>
<link>https://fedinprint.org/item/fednls/94949</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[Although most of those infected with COVID-19 have recovered relatively quickly, a substantial share has not, and remains symptomatic months or even years later, in what is commonly referred to as long COVID. Data on the incidence of long COVID is scarce, but recent Census Bureau data suggest that sixteen million working age Americans suffer from it. The economic costs of long COVID is estimated to be in the trillions. While many with long COVID have dropped out of the labor force because they can no longer work, many others appear to be working despite having disabilities related to the disease. Indeed, there has been an increase of around 1.7 million disabled persons in the U.S. since the pandemic began, and there are close to one million newly disabled workers. These disabled workers can benefit from workplace accommodations to help them remain productive and stay on the job, particularly as the majority deal with fatigue and brain fog, the hallmarks of long COVID.]]>
</description>
<guid>https://fedinprint.org/item/fednls/94949</guid>
<dc:creator>Deitz, Richard</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2022-10-20</dc:date>
<dc:subject>Long-COVID; remote work; disability; Chronic Fatigue Syndrome (CFS); longer-run balance sheet</dc:subject>
<swpo:hasNumber>20221020b</swpo:hasNumber>
<bibo:series>Liberty Street Economics</bibo:series>
</item>
<item>
<title>How Have Racial and Ethnic Earnings Gaps Changed after COVID-19?</title>
<link>https://fedinprint.org/item/fednls/94948</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[Racial and ethnic earnings disparities have been salient features of the U.S. economy for decades. Between the pandemic-driven recession in 2020 and the rising inflation since 2021, workers’ real and nominal earnings have seen rapid change. To get a sense of how recent economic conditions have affected earnings disparities, we examine real and nominal weekly earnings trends for Asian, Black, Hispanic, and white workers. We find that average real weekly earnings have been declining in the past year, but less so for Black and Hispanic workers than for white and Asian workers. Black and Hispanic workers have also experienced small increases in real earnings since the pre-pandemic period.]]>
</description>
<guid>https://fedinprint.org/item/fednls/94948</guid>
<dc:creator>Chakrabarti, Rajashri; García, Daniel I.; Pinkovskiy, Maxim L.; Chatterji-Len, Kasey</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2022-10-20</dc:date>
<dc:subject>nominal wage; real wage; racial gap; inequality; wages; labor market</dc:subject>
<swpo:hasNumber>20221020a</swpo:hasNumber>
<bibo:series>Liberty Street Economics</bibo:series>
</item>
<item>
<title>What Have Workers Done with the Time Freed up by Commuting Less?</title>
<link>https://fedinprint.org/item/fednls/94923</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[The COVID-19 pandemic has dramatically changed the way Americans spend their time. One of the most enduring shifts has occurred in the workplace, with millions of employees making the switch to work from home. Even as the pandemic has waned, more than 15 percent of full-time employees remain fully remote and an additional 30 percent work in hybrid arrangements (Barrero, Bloom, and Davis). These changes have substantially reduced time spent commuting to work; in the aggregate, Americans now spend 60 million fewer hours traveling to work each day. In this post, we investigate how people spend this saved time on other activities. Using detailed data from the American Time Use Survey (ATUS), we find that employed individuals allocate their saved commute time toward leisure activities and sleeping, while reducing overall work hours.]]>
</description>
<guid>https://fedinprint.org/item/fednls/94923</guid>
<dc:creator>Toner-Rodgers, Aidan; Pilossoph, Laura; Melcangi, Davide; Dam, David</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2022-10-18</dc:date>
<dc:subject>time use; COVID-19; pandemic; commuting</dc:subject>
<swpo:hasNumber>20221018</swpo:hasNumber>
<bibo:series>Liberty Street Economics</bibo:series>
</item>
<item>
<title>What Is the Outlook for China’s External Surplus?</title>
<link>https://fedinprint.org/item/fednls/94922</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[The sharp slowdown in China’s property sector has reignited debate over the country’s future role as a net provider of savings to the global economy. The debate revolves around whether a sustained decline in property investment will spur a long-term increase in China’s current account surplus, given  the country’s high savings rate. However, China’s rapidly aging population presents opposing forces that complicate this story. The shift of a large share of its population from working life to retirement will reduce savings supply even as a shrinking labor force will reduce investment demand. In this post, we focus on the demographic part of the story and find that this force will exert considerable downward pressure on China’s current account surplus in coming years.]]>
</description>
<guid>https://fedinprint.org/item/fednls/94922</guid>
<dc:creator>Clark, Hunter L.; Higgins, Matthew</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2022-10-17</dc:date>
<dc:subject>China; savings; balance of payments; current account; demographics; trade</dc:subject>
<swpo:hasNumber>20221017</swpo:hasNumber>
<bibo:series>Liberty Street Economics</bibo:series>
</item>
<item>
<title>Intermediation Frictions in Debt Relief: Evidence from CARES Act Forbearance</title>
<link>https://fedinprint.org/item/fednsr/94910</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[We study how intermediaries—mortgage servicers—shaped the implementation of mortgage forbearance during the COVID-19 pandemic and use servicer-level variation to trace out the causal effect of forbearance on borrowers. Forbearance provision varied widely across servicers. Small servicers and nonbanks, especially nonbanks with small liquidity buffers, facilitated fewer forbearances and saw a higher incidence of forbearance-related complaints. Easier access to forbearance substantially increased mortgage nonpayment but also reduced delinquencies outside of forbearance. Part of the liquidity from forbearance was used to reduce credit card debt, but most was saved or used for nondurable consumption.]]>
</description>
<guid>https://fedinprint.org/item/fednsr/94910</guid>
<dc:creator>Scharlemann, Tess C.; Lee, Donghoon; Vickery, James; Kim, You Suk</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2022-10-01</dc:date>
<rdau:hasExtent>69</rdau:hasExtent>
<dc:subject>mortgage; forbearance; liquidity; nonbanks; CARES Act; Coronavirus Aid Relief and Economic Security (CARES) Act; COVID 19</dc:subject>
<swpo:hasNumber>1035</swpo:hasNumber>
<bibo:series>Staff Reports</bibo:series>
</item>
<item>
<title>With Abundant Reserves, Do Banks Adjust Reserve Balances to Accommodate Payment Flows?</title>
<link>https://fedinprint.org/item/fednls/94906</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[As a result of the global financial crisis (GFC), the Federal Reserve switched from a regime of scarce reserves to one of abundant reserves. In this post, we explore how banks’ day-to-day management of reserve balances with respect to payment flows changed with this regime switch. We find that bank behavior did not change on average; under both regimes, banks increased their opening balances when they expected higher outgoing payments and, similarly, decreased these balances with expected higher incoming payments. There are substantial differences across banks, however. At the introduction of the abundant-reserves regime, small domestic banks no longer adjusted balances alongside changes in outgoing payments.]]>
</description>
<guid>https://fedinprint.org/item/fednls/94906</guid>
<dc:creator>Kraft, Kailey; Huang, Catherine; Copeland, Adam</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2022-10-12</dc:date>
<dc:subject>quantitative easing (QE); liquidity; reserves; payments; Federal Reserve; banks</dc:subject>
<swpo:hasNumber>20221012</swpo:hasNumber>
<bibo:series>Liberty Street Economics</bibo:series>
</item>
<item>
<title>New SCE Charts Include a Measure of Longer-Term Inflation Expectations</title>
<link>https://fedinprint.org/item/fednls/94896</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[Today, the New York Fed introduces several new data series and interactive charts depicting findings from its Survey of Consumer Expectations (SCE). The SCE is a representative, internet-based monthly survey of a rotating panel of about 1,300 household heads in the United States. Since January 2014, we have been reporting findings from our monthly survey on U.S. households’ views on inflation, household income and spending growth, their expectations about the housing and labor market, and a range of other expectations about the economy and outcomes for their own household. In addition to publishing interactive charts showing national trends as well as trends by demographic groups (such as age, income, education, numeracy, and geography), we also post the underlying microdata online (with a nine-month lag) to make it available for research purposes.  We are adding three new data series to our interactive charts today. The first two concern expectations about future inflation, and the third concerns expectations of future home price growth.]]>
</description>
<guid>https://fedinprint.org/item/fednls/94896</guid>
<dc:creator>Lall, Devon; Van der Klaauw, Wilbert; Koşar, Gizem; Armantier, Olivier; Somerville, Jason; Topa, Giorgio; Aidala, Felix; Boumahdi, Fatima-Ezzahra</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2022-10-11</dc:date>
<dc:subject>inflation expectations; home price expectations</dc:subject>
<swpo:hasNumber>20221011</swpo:hasNumber>
<bibo:series>Liberty Street Economics</bibo:series>
</item>
<item>
<title>Computer Saturation and the Productivity Slowdown</title>
<link>https://fedinprint.org/item/fednls/94888</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[One of the current puzzles in economics is the recent worldwide slowdown in productivity, compared to the late 1990s and early 2000s. This productivity loss is economically large: if productivity growth had stayed at the same level as in 1995-2004, American GDP would have increased by trillions of dollars. In this post, I discuss a new paper that links this productivity slowdown to saturation in electronics adoption across most industries. I show that most of the productivity growth from electronic miniaturization is concentrated between 1985 and 2005.]]>
</description>
<guid>https://fedinprint.org/item/fednls/94888</guid>
<dc:creator>Azar, Pablo</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2022-10-06</dc:date>
<dc:subject>economic growth; Moore's Law</dc:subject>
<swpo:hasNumber>20221006</swpo:hasNumber>
<bibo:series>Liberty Street Economics</bibo:series>
</item>
<item>
<title>Measuring the Ampleness of Reserves</title>
<link>https://fedinprint.org/item/fednls/94887</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[Over the past fifteen years, reserves in the banking system have grown from tens of billions of dollars to several trillion dollars. This extraordinary rise poses a natural question: Are the rates paid in the market for reserves still sensitive to changes in the quantity of reserves when aggregate reserve holdings are so large? In today’s post, we answer this question by estimating the slope of the reserve demand curve from 2010 to 2022, when reserves ranged from $1 trillion to $4 trillion.]]>
</description>
<guid>https://fedinprint.org/item/fednls/94887</guid>
<dc:creator>La Spada, Gabriele; Williams, John C.; Afonso, Gara</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2022-10-05</dc:date>
<dc:subject>reserve demand; federal funds; ample reserves; monetary policy</dc:subject>
<swpo:hasNumber>20221005</swpo:hasNumber>
<bibo:series>Liberty Street Economics</bibo:series>
</item>
<item>
<title>A Bedrock Commitment to Price Stability</title>
<link>https://fedinprint.org/item/fednsp/94885</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[Remarks at the 2022 U.S. Hispanic Chamber of Commerce National Conference, Phoenix, Arizona.]]>
</description>
<guid>https://fedinprint.org/item/fednsp/94885</guid>
<dc:creator>Williams, John C.</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2022-10-03</dc:date>
<dc:subject>inflation; price stability; supply and demand; monetary policy</dc:subject>
<bibo:series>Speech</bibo:series>
</item>
<item>
<title>Eviction Expectations in the Post-Pandemic Housing Market</title>
<link>https://fedinprint.org/item/fednls/94866</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[Housing is the single largest element of the typical household’s budget, and data from the SCE Household Spending Survey show that this is especially true for renters. As the housing market heated up in the latter stages of the pandemic, home prices and rents both began to rise sharply. For renters, some protection from these increases was afforded by national, state, and in some cases local eviction moratoria, which greatly reduced the risk of households losing access to stable housing if they couldn’t afford their rent. Yet many of these protections have expired and additional supports will do so soon. In this post, we draw on data from our SCE Housing Survey to explore how renters perceive their housing risk and find that the answers depend to a large degree on their current and past experiences of the housing market.]]>
</description>
<guid>https://fedinprint.org/item/fednls/94866</guid>
<dc:creator>Lahey, Benjamin; Somerville, Jason; Haughwout, Andrew F.; Hyman, Benjamin</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2022-10-04</dc:date>
<dc:subject>evictions; expectations; renters; housing</dc:subject>
<swpo:hasNumber>20221004</swpo:hasNumber>
<bibo:series>Liberty Street Economics</bibo:series>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Financial Stability Implications of Digital Assets</title>
<link>https://fedinprint.org/item/fednsr/94863</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[The value of assets in the digital ecosystem has grown rapidly amid periods of high volatility. Does the digital financial system create new potential challenges to financial stability? This paper explores this question using the Federal Reserve’s framework for analyzing vulnerabilities in the traditional financial system. The digital asset ecosystem has recently proven itself to be highly fragile. However, adverse digital asset market shocks have had limited spillovers to the traditional financial system. Currently, the digital asset ecosystem does not provide significant financial services outside the ecosystem, and it exhibits limited interconnections with the traditional financial system. The paper describes emerging vulnerabilities that could present risks to financial stability in the future if the digital asset ecosystem becomes more systemic, including run risks among large stablecoins, valuation pressures in crypto-assets, fragilities of DeFi platforms, growing interconnectedness, and a general lack of regulation.]]>
</description>
<guid>https://fedinprint.org/item/fednsr/94863</guid>
<dc:creator>Swem, Nathan; Carapella, Francesca; Werman, Aurite; Vardoulakis, Alexandros; Perez-Sangimino, JP; Gerszten, Jacob; Baughman, Garth; Lubis, Arazi; Scotti, Chiara; Rappoport, David E.; Azar, Pablo</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2022-09-01</dc:date>
<rdau:hasExtent>31</rdau:hasExtent>
<dc:subject>digital assets; stablecoins; DeFi; financial stability; financial vulnerabilities; systemic risk</dc:subject>
<swpo:hasNumber>1034</swpo:hasNumber>
<bibo:series>Staff Reports</bibo:series>
</item>
<item>
<title>Short-Dated Term Premia and the Level of Inflation</title>
<link>https://fedinprint.org/item/fednls/94848</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[Since the advent of derivatives trading on short-term interest rates in the 1980s, financial commentators have often interpreted market prices as directly reflecting the expected path of future interest rates. However, market prices generally embed risk premia (or “term premia” in reference to measures of risk premia over different horizons) reflecting the compensation required to bear the risk of the asset. When term premia are large in magnitude, derivatives prices may differ substantially from investor expectations of future rates. In this post, we assess whether term premia have increased with the recent rise in inflation, given the historically positive relationship between the two series, and what this means for the interpretation of derivatives prices.]]>
</description>
<guid>https://fedinprint.org/item/fednls/94848</guid>
<dc:creator>Van Tassel, Peter; Smith, Charles; Crump, Richard K.</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2022-09-28</dc:date>
<dc:subject>term premia; inflation; monetary policy expectations; Federal Open Market Committee (FOMC)</dc:subject>
<swpo:hasNumber>20220928</swpo:hasNumber>
<bibo:series>Liberty Street Economics</bibo:series>
</item>
<item>
<title>Revisiting Federal Student Loan Forgiveness: An Update Based on the White House Plan</title>
<link>https://fedinprint.org/item/fednls/94843</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[On August 24, 2022, the White House released a plan to cancel federal student loans for most borrowers. In April,  we wrote about the costs and who most benefits from a few hypothetical loan forgiveness proposals using our Consumer Credit Panel, based on Equifax credit report data.  In this post, we update our framework to consider the White House plan now that parameters are known, with estimates for the total amount of forgiven loans and the distribution of who holds federal student loans before and after the proposed debt jubilee.]]>
</description>
<guid>https://fedinprint.org/item/fednls/94843</guid>
<dc:creator>Goss, Jacob; Mangrum, Daniel; Scally, Joelle</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2022-09-27</dc:date>
<dc:subject>student loans; household finance; inequality; fiscal policy</dc:subject>
<swpo:hasNumber>20220927</swpo:hasNumber>
<bibo:series>Liberty Street Economics</bibo:series>
</item>
<item>
<title>Is China Running Out of Policy Space to Navigate Future Economic Challenges?</title>
<link>https://fedinprint.org/item/fednls/94841</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[After making progress slowing the pace of debt accumulation prior to the pandemic, China saw its debt levels surge in 2020 as the government responded to the severe economic slowdown with credit-led stimulus. With China currently in the midst of another sharp decline in economic activity due to its property slump and zero-COVID strategy, Chinese authorities have responded again by pushing out credit to soften the downturn despite already high levels of debt on corporate, household, and  government balance sheets. In this post, we revisit China’s debt buildup and consider the growing constraints on Chinese policymakers’ tools to navigate future economic challenges.]]>
</description>
<guid>https://fedinprint.org/item/fednls/94841</guid>
<dc:creator>Dawson, Jeffrey B.; Clark, Hunter L.</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2022-09-26</dc:date>
<dc:subject>credit; government debt; China</dc:subject>
<swpo:hasNumber>20220926</swpo:hasNumber>
<bibo:series>Liberty Street Economics</bibo:series>
</item>
<item>
<title>Approximating Grouped Fixed Effects Estimation via Fuzzy Clustering Regression</title>
<link>https://fedinprint.org/item/fednsr/94840</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[We propose a new, computationally-efficient way to approximate the “grouped fixed-effects” (GFE) estimator of Bonhomme and Manresa (2015), which estimates grouped patterns of unobserved heterogeneity. To do so, we generalize the fuzzy C-means objective to regression settings. As the regularization parameter m approaches 1, the fuzzy clustering objective converges to the GFE objective; moreover, we recast this objective as a standard Generalized Method of Moments problem. We replicate the empirical results of Bonhomme and Manresa (2015) and show that our estimator delivers almost identical estimates. In simulations, we show that our approach delivers improvements in terms of bias, classification accuracy, and computational speed.]]>
</description>
<guid>https://fedinprint.org/item/fednsr/94840</guid>
<dc:creator>Pilossoph, Laura; Lewis, Daniel J.; Melcangi, Davide; Toner-Rodgers, Aidan</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2022-09-01</dc:date>
<rdau:hasExtent>27</rdau:hasExtent>
<dc:subject>clustering; unobserved heterogeneity; panel data</dc:subject>
<swpo:hasNumber>1033</swpo:hasNumber>
<bibo:series>Staff Reports</bibo:series>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Ample Reserves Framework and Balance Sheet Reduction: Perspective from the Open Market Desk</title>
<link>https://fedinprint.org/item/fednsp/94753</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[Remarks at the Cato Institute’s 40th Annual Monetary Conference (delivered via videoconference).]]>
</description>
<guid>https://fedinprint.org/item/fednsp/94753</guid>
<dc:creator>Zobel, Patricia</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2022-09-08</dc:date>
<dc:subject>Federal funds rate; Federal Open Market Committee; Open market operations; Federal Reserve monetary policy</dc:subject>
<bibo:series>Speech</bibo:series>
</item>
<item>
<title>Risk-Free Rates and Convenience Yields Around the World</title>
<link>https://fedinprint.org/item/fednsr/94750</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[This paper constructs risk-free interest rates implicit in index option prices for ten of the major G11 currencies. We compare these rates to the yields of government bonds to provide international estimates of the convenience yield earned by safe assets. Average convenience yields across countries are highly correlated with the average interest rate in each country, ranging from 2 basis points in low-rate Switzerland to 61 basis points in high-rate Australia, with the moderate-rate United States providing a middling 34 basis points. For each country, a covered interest parity (CIP) deviation constructed from its option-implied rates and those of the United States is negative, with these negative CIP deviations growing sharply in periods of financial distress, including the 2020 COVID crisis when convenience yields themselves remained moderate. We conclude that risk-free discount rates in the United States are especially low due to its central position in the global financial system, particularly during financial crises, but that U.S. safe assets do not earn an unusually large convenience yield in addition.]]>
</description>
<guid>https://fedinprint.org/item/fednsr/94750</guid>
<dc:creator>Van Tassel, Peter; Diamond, William</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2022-09-01</dc:date>
<rdau:hasExtent>52</rdau:hasExtent>
<dc:subject>risk-free rates; convenience yields; Covered interest rate parity; options</dc:subject>
<swpo:hasNumber>1032</swpo:hasNumber>
<bibo:series>Staff Reports</bibo:series>
</item>
<item>
<title>800,000 Years of Climate Risk</title>
<link>https://fedinprint.org/item/fednsr/94741</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[We use a long history of global temperature and atmospheric carbon dioxide (CO2) concentration to estimate the conditional joint evolution of temperature and CO2 at a millennial frequency. We document three basic facts. First, the temperature–CO2 dynamics are non-linear, so that large deviations in either temperature or CO2 concentrations take a long time to correct–on the scale of multiple millennia. Second, the joint dynamics of temperature and CO2 concentrations exhibit multimodality around historical turning points in temperature and concentration cycles, so that prior to the start of cooling periods, there is a noticeable probability that temperature and CO2 concentrations may continue to increase. Finally, evaluating the future evolution of temperature and CO2 concentration conditional on alternative scenarios realizing, we document that, even conditional on the net-zero 2050 scenario, there remains a significant risk of elevated temperatures for at least a further five millennia.]]>
</description>
<guid>https://fedinprint.org/item/fednsr/94741</guid>
<dc:creator>Giannone, Domenico; Adrian, Tobias; Seneviratne, Dulani; Xiao, Yanzhe; Boyarchenko, Nina; Prasad, Ananthakrishnan</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2022-09-01</dc:date>
<rdau:hasExtent>65</rdau:hasExtent>
<dc:subject>climate change; multimodality; Network for Greening the Financial System (NGFS) scenarios</dc:subject>
<swpo:hasNumber>1031</swpo:hasNumber>
<bibo:series>Staff Reports</bibo:series>
</item>
<item>
<title>Activist Manipulation Dynamics</title>
<link>https://fedinprint.org/item/fednsr/94740</link>
<description>
<![CDATA[Two activists with correlated private positions in a firm’s stock, trade sequentially before simultaneously exerting effort that determines the firm’s value. We document the existence of a novel linear equilibrium in which an activist’s trades have positive sensitivity to her block size, but such orders are not zero on average: the leader activist manipulates the price to induce the follower to acquire a larger position and thus add more value. We examine the implications of this equilibrium for market outcomes and discuss its connection with the prominent phenomenon of “wolf-pack” activism—multiple hedge funds engaging in parallel with a target firm. We also explore the possibility of other equilibria where the activists trade against their initial positions.]]>
</description>
<guid>https://fedinprint.org/item/fednsr/94740</guid>
<dc:creator>Viswanathan, S; Cisternas, Gonzalo; Kolb, Aaron; Cetemen, Doruk</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2022-09-01</dc:date>
<rdau:hasExtent>55</rdau:hasExtent>
<dc:subject>activism; insider trading; noisy signaling; price manipulation; hedge funds</dc:subject>
<swpo:hasNumber>1030</swpo:hasNumber>
<bibo:series>Staff Reports</bibo:series>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>