<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<rdf:RDF
 xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
 xmlns="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/"
 xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
 xmlns:taxo="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/taxonomy/"
 xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
 xmlns:syn="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
 xmlns:admin="http://webns.net/mvcb/"
>

<channel rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/">
<title>cond-mat.stat-mech updates on arXiv.org</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">Condensed Matter -- Statistical Mechanics (cond-mat.stat-mech) updates on the arXiv.org e-print archive</description>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:date>2022-11-03T20:30:00-05:00</dc:date>
<dc:publisher>help@arxiv.org</dc:publisher>
<dc:subject>Condensed Matter -- Statistical Mechanics</dc:subject>
<syn:updateBase>1901-01-01T00:00+00:00</syn:updateBase>
<syn:updateFrequency>1</syn:updateFrequency>
<syn:updatePeriod>daily</syn:updatePeriod>
<items>
 <rdf:Seq>
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01392" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01485" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01632" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01650" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01662" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01683" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01709" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01710" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01773" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01869" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01904" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01909" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01923" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01940" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01942" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01975" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2011.09771" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2012.08889" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2110.08304" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2203.09514" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2205.05704" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2206.12924" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2206.14277" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2208.13633" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2208.13772" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.00906" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.01259" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.09457" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01360" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.00679" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01123" />
 </rdf:Seq>
</items>
<image rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif" />
</channel>
<image rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif">
<title>arXiv.org</title>
<url>http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif</url>
<link>http://arxiv.org/</link>
</image>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01392">
<title>R\&apos;enyi Mutual Information in Quantum Field Theory. (arXiv:2211.01392v1 [hep-th])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01392</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We study a proper definition of R\&apos;enyi mutual information (RMI) in quantum
field theory as defined via the Petz R\&apos;enyi relative entropy. Unlike the
standard definition, the RMI we compute is a genuine measure of correlations
between subsystems, as evidenced by its non-negativity and monotonicity under
local operations. Furthermore, the RMI is UV finite and well-defined in the
continuum limit. We develop a replica path integral approach for the RMI in
quantum field theories and evaluate it explicitly in 1+1D conformal field
theory using twist fields. We prove that it bounds connected correlation
functions and check our results against exact numerics in the massless free
fermion theory.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Kudler_Flam_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jonah Kudler-Flam&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01485">
<title>Information compression at the turbulent-phase transition in cold atom gases. (arXiv:2211.01485v1 [cond-mat.quant-gas])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01485</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The statistical properties of physical systems in thermal equilibrium are
blatantly different from their far-from-equilibrium counterparts. In the
latter, fluctuations often dominate the dynamics and might cluster in ordered
patterns in the form of dissipative coherent structures. Here, we study the
transition of a cold atomic cloud, driven close to a sharp electronic
resonance, from a stable to a turbulent phase. From the atomic density
distribution -- measured using a spatially-resolved pump-probe technique -- we
have computed the Shannon entropy on two different basis sets. Information
compression, corresponding to a minimum in the Shannon entropy, has been
observed at criticality, where the system fluctuations organize into high-order
(low-entropy) patterns. Being independent of the representation used, this
feature is a property shared by a vast class of physical systems undergoing
phase transitions.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Giampaoli_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;R. Giampaoli&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Figueiredo_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;J. L. Figueiredo&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Rodrigues_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;J. D. Rodrigues&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Rodrigues_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;J. A. Rodrigues&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Tercas_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;H. Ter&amp;#xe7;as&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Mendonca_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;J. T. Mendon&amp;#xe7;a&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01632">
<title>Equivalence of the modified Villain formulation and the dual Hamiltonian method in the duality of the XY-plaquette model. (arXiv:2211.01632v1 [hep-th])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01632</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Regarding the duality of the XY-placket model in the $2+1d$ system, We
compared and discussed the equivalence and difference between the modified
Villain formulation, recently introduced by Gorantla et al. to study duality in
exotic field theories such as fracton theory, and the standard Villain
formulation and dual Hamiltonian method we introduced in our previous paper to
study duality between Josephson junctions and quantum phase slips in the $1+1d$
system.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Yoneda_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Morishige Yoneda&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01650">
<title>Universality and its limits in non-Hermitian many-body quantum chaos using the Sachdev-Ye-Kitaev model. (arXiv:2211.01650v1 [hep-th])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01650</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Spectral rigidity in Hermitian quantum chaotic systems signals the presence
of dynamical universal features at time scales that can be much shorter than
the Heisenberg time. We study the analogue of this time scale in many-body
non-Hermitian quantum chaos by a detailed analysis of long-range spectral
correlators. For that purpose, we investigate the number variance and the
spectral form factor of a non-Hermitian $q$-body Sachdev-Ye-Kitaev (nHSYK)
model, which describes $N$ fermions in zero spatial dimensions. After an
analytical and numerical analysis of these spectral observables for
non-Hermitian random matrices, and a careful unfolding, we find good agreement
with the nHSYK model for $q &amp;gt; 2$ starting at a time scale that decreases
sharply with $q$. The source of deviation from universality, identified
analytically, is ensemble fluctuations not related to the quantum dynamics. For
fixed $q$ and large enough $N$, these fluctuations become dominant up until
after the Heisenberg time, so that the spectral form factor is no longer useful
for the study of quantum chaos. In all cases, our results point to a weakened
or vanishing spectral rigidity that effectively delays the observation of full
quantum ergodicity. We also show that the number variance displays
non-stationary spectral correlations for both the nHSYK model and random
matrices. This non-stationarity, also not related to the quantum dynamics,
points to intrinsic limitations of these observables to describe the quantum
chaotic motion. On the other hand, we introduce the local spectral form factor,
which is shown to be stationary and not affected by collective fluctuations,
and propose it as an effective diagnostic of non-Hermitian quantum chaos. For
$q = 2$, we find saturation to Poisson statistics at a time scale of $\log D$,
compared to a scale of $\sqrt D$ for $ q&amp;gt;2$, with $D $ the total number of
states.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Garcia_Garcia_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Antonio M. Garc&amp;#xed;a-Garc&amp;#xed;a&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Sa_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Lucas S&amp;#xe1;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Verbaarschot_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jacobus J. M. Verbaarschot&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01662">
<title>Multicomponent gauge-Higgs models with discrete Abelian gauge groups. (arXiv:2211.01662v1 [hep-lat])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01662</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We consider a variant of the charge-Q compact Abelian-Higgs model, in which
an Nf-dimensional complex vector is coupled with an Abelian Z_q gauge field.
For Nf=2 and Q=1 we observe several transition lines that belong to the O(4),
O(3), and O(2) vector universality classes, depending on the symmetry breaking
pattern at the transition. The universality class is independent of $q$ as long
as q&amp;gt;=3. The universality class of the transition is uniquely determined by the
behavior of the scalar fields; gauge fields do not play any role. We also
investigate the system for Nf=15 and Q=2. In the presence of U(1) gauge fields,
the system undergoes transitions associated with charged fixed points of the
Abelian-Higgs field theory. These continuous transitions turn into first-order
ones when the U(1) gauge fields are replaced by the discrete Z_q fields: in the
present compact model charged transitions appear to be very sensitive to the
nature of the gauge fields
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-lat/1/au:+Bracci_Testasecca_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Giacomo Bracci-Testasecca&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-lat/1/au:+Pelissetto_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Andrea Pelissetto&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01683">
<title>Exact physical quantities of a competing spin chain in the thermodynamic limit. (arXiv:2211.01683v1 [math-ph])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01683</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We study the exact physical quantities of a competing spin chain which
contains many interesting and meaningful couplings including the nearest
neighbor, next nearest neighbor, chiral three spins, Dzyloshinsky-Moriya
interactions and unparallel boundary magnetic fields in the thermodynamic
limit. We obtain the density of zero roots, surface energies and elementary
excitations in different regimes of model parameters. Due to the competition of
various interactions, the surface energy and excited spectrum show many
different pictures from those of the Heisenberg spin chain.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math-ph/1/au:+Lu_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Pengcheng Lu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math-ph/1/au:+Qiao_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yi Qiao&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math-ph/1/au:+Cao_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Junpeng Cao&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math-ph/1/au:+Yang_W/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Wen-Li Yang&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01709">
<title>Dynamic phase transitions on the kagome Ising ferromagnet. (arXiv:2211.01709v1 [cond-mat.stat-mech])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01709</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We perform extensive Monte Carlo simulations to investigate the dynamic phase
transition properties of the two-dimensional kinetic Ising model on the kagome
lattice in the presence of square-wave oscillating magnetic field. Through
detailed finite-size scaling analysis, we study universality aspects of the
non-equilibrium phase transition. Obtained critical exponents indicate that the
two-dimensional kagome-lattice kinetic Ising model belongs to the same
universality class with the corresponding Ising model in equilibrium. Moreover,
dynamic critical exponent of the local moves used in simulations is determined
with high precision. Our numerical results are compatible with the previous
ones on kinetic Ising models.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Vatansever_Z/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Zeynep Demir Vatansever&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01710">
<title>Bernoulli variables, classical exclusion processes and free probability. (arXiv:2211.01710v1 [math-ph])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01710</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We present a new description of the known large deviation function of the
classical symmetric simple exclusion process by exploiting its connection with
the quantum symmetric simple exclusion processes and using tools from free
probability. This may seem paradoxal as free probability usually deals with non
commutative probability while the simple exclusion process belongs to the realm
of classical probability. On the way, we give a new formula for the free energy
-- alias the logarithm of the Laplace transform of the probability distribution
-- of correlated Bernoulli variables in terms of the set of their cumulants
with non-coinciding indices. This latter result is obtained either by
developing a combinatorial approach for cumulants of products of random
variables or by borrowing techniques from Feynman graphs.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math-ph/1/au:+Bauer_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Michel Bauer&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math-ph/1/au:+Bernard_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Denis Bernard&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math-ph/1/au:+Biane_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Philippe Biane&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math-ph/1/au:+Hruza_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ludwig Hruza&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01773">
<title>Universal optimization efficiency and bounds of Carnot-like heat engines and refrigerators under shortcuts to isothermality. (arXiv:2211.01773v1 [quant-ph])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01773</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Based on a quantum thermodynamic protocol for shortcut to isothermality that
smoothly modify the system-reservoir interaction can significantly speed up an
isothermal process while keeping the overall dissipation constant [Phys. Rev.
X. 10, 031015 (2020)], we extend the study of optimization performance of
Carnot-like heat engines and refrigerators in a straightforward and unified
way. We derive the universal optimization efficiency of heat engines and the
optimization coefficient of performance of refrigerators under two unified
optimization criterions, i.e., chi criterion and omega criterion. We also
derived the universal lower and upper bounds for heat engines and
refrigerators, and found that these bounds can be reached under extremely
asymmetric cases.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Zhang_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yanchao Zhang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Wang_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Shuang Wang&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01869">
<title>Stochastic resetting in a networked multiparticle system with correlated transitions. (arXiv:2211.01869v1 [cond-mat.stat-mech])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01869</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The state of many physical, biological and socio-technical systems evolves by
combining smooth local transitions and abrupt resetting events to a set of
reference values. The inclusion of the resetting mechanism not only provides
the possibility of modeling a wide variety of realistic systems but also leads
to interesting novel phenomenology not present in reset-free cases. However,
most models where stochastic resetting is studied address the case of a finite
number of uncorrelated variables, commonly a single one, such as the position
of non-interacting random walkers. Here we overcome this limitation by framing
the process of network growth with node deletion as a stochastic resetting
problem where an arbitrarily large number of degrees of freedom are coupled and
influence each other, both in the resetting and non-resetting (growth) events.
We find the exact, full-time solution of the model, and several
out-of-equilibrium properties are characterized as function of the growth and
resetting rates, such as the emergence of a time-dependent percolation-like
phase transition, and first-passage statistics. Coupled multiparticle systems
subjected to resetting are a necessary generalization in the theory of
stochastic resetting, and the model presented herein serves as an illustrative,
natural and solvable example of such a generalization.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Artime_O/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Oriol Artime&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01904">
<title>Dimensionality reduction of local structure in glassy binary mixtures. (arXiv:2211.01904v1 [cond-mat.stat-mech])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01904</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We consider unsupervised learning methods for characterizing the disordered
microscopic structure of supercooled liquids and glasses. Specifically, we
perform dimensionality reduction of smooth structural descriptors that describe
radial and bond-orientational correlations, and assess the ability of the
method to grasp the essential structural features of glassy binary mixtures. In
several cases, a few collective variables account for the bulk of the
structural fluctuations within the first coordination shell and also display a
clear connection with the fluctuations of particle mobility. Fine-grained
descriptors that characterize the radial dependence of bond-orientational order
better capture the structural fluctuations relevant for particle mobility, but
are also more difficult to parametrize and to interpret. We also find that
principal component analysis of bond-orientational order parameters provides
identical results to neural network autoencoders, while having the advantage of
being easily interpretable. Overall, our results indicate that glassy binary
mixtures have a broad spectrum of structural features. In the temperature range
we investigate, some mixtures display well-defined locally favored structures,
which are reflected in bimodal distributions of the structural variables
identified by dimensionality reduction.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Coslovich_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Daniele Coslovich&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Jack_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Robert L. Jack&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Paret_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Joris Paret&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01909">
<title>Stochastic dynamics with multiplicative dichotomic noise: heterogeneous telegrapher&apos;s equation, anomalous crossovers and resetting. (arXiv:2211.01909v1 [cond-mat.stat-mech])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01909</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We analyze diffusion processes with finite propagation speed in a
non-homogeneous medium in terms of the heterogeneous telegrapher&apos;s equation. In
the diffusion limit of infinite-velocity propagation we recover the results for
the heterogeneous diffusion process. The heterogeneous telegrapher&apos;s process
exhibits a rich variety of diffusion regimes including hyperdiffusion,
ballistic motion, superdiffusion, normal diffusion and subdiffusion, and
different crossover dynamics characteristic for complex systems in which
anomalous diffusion is observed. The anomalous diffusion exponent in the short
time limit is twice the exponent in the long time limit, in accordance to the
crossover dynamics from ballistic diffusion to normal diffusion in the standard
telegrapher&apos;s process. We also analyze the finite-velocity heterogeneous
diffusion process in presence of stochastic Poissonian resetting. We show that
the system reaches a non-equilibrium stationary state. The transition to this
non-equilibrium steady state is analysed in terms of the large deviation
function.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Sandev_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Trifce Sandev&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Kocarev_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ljupco Kocarev&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Metzler_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ralf Metzler&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Chechkin_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Aleksei Chechkin&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01923">
<title>Stochastic Representation of the Quantum Quartic Oscillator. (arXiv:2211.01923v1 [quant-ph])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01923</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Recent experimental advances have inspired the development of theoretical
tools to describe the non-equilibrium dynamics of quantum systems. Among them
an exact representation of quantum spin systems in terms of classical
stochastic processes has been proposed. Here we provide first steps towards the
extension of this stochastic approach to bosonic systems by considering the
one-dimensional quantum quartic oscillator. We show how to exactly parameterize
the time evolution of this prototypical model via the dynamics of a set of
classical variables. We interpret these variables as stochastic processes,
which allows us to propose a novel way to numerically simulate the time
evolution of the system. We benchmark our findings by considering analytically
solvable limits and providing alternative derivations of known results.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Tucci_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Gennaro Tucci&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Nicola_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Stefano De Nicola&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Wald_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Sascha Wald&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Gambassi_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Andrea Gambassi&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01940">
<title>Approximate Gibbsian structure in strongly correlated point fields and generalized Gaussian zero ensembles. (arXiv:2211.01940v1 [math.PR])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01940</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Gibbsian structure in random point fields has been a classical tool for
studying their spatial properties. However, exact Gibbs property is available
only in a relatively limited class of models, and it does not adequately
address many random fields with a strongly dependent spatial structure. In this
work, we provide a general framework for approximate Gibbsian structure for
strongly correlated random point fields. These include processes that exhibit
strong spatial rigidity, in particular, a certain one-parameter family of
analytic Gaussian zero point fields, namely the $\alpha$-GAFs. Our framework
entails conditions that may be verified via finite particle approximations to
the process, a phenomenon that we call an approximate Gibbs property. We show
that these enable one to compare the spatial conditional measures in the
infinite volume limit with Gibbs-type densities supported on appropriate
singular manifolds, a phenomenon we refer to as a generalized Gibbs property.
We demonstrate the scope of our approach by showing that a generalized Gibbs
property holds with a logarithmic pair potential for the $\alpha$-GAFs for any
value of $\alpha$. This establishes the level of rigidity of the $\alpha$-GAF
zero process to be exactly $\lfloor \frac{1}{\alpha} \rfloor$, settling in the
affirmative an open question regarding the existence of point processes with
any specified level of rigidity. For processes such as the zeros of
$\alpha$-GAFs, which involve complex, many-body interactions, our results imply
that the local behaviour of the random points still exhibits 2D Coulomb-type
repulsion in the short range. Our techniques can be leveraged to estimate the
relative energies of configurations under local perturbations, with possible
implications for dynamics and stochastic geometry on strongly correlated random
point fields.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Gangopadhyay_U/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ujan Gangopadhyay&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/math/1/au:+Ghosh_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Subhroshekhar Ghosh&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01942">
<title>Quantum Random Walker in Presence of a Moving Detector. (arXiv:2211.01942v1 [quant-ph])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01942</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;In this work, we study the effect of a moving detector on a discrete time one
dimensional Quantum Random Walk where the movement is realized in the form of
hopping/shifts. The occupation probability $f(x,t;n,s)$ is estimated as the
number of detection $n$ and number of shift $s$ vary. It is seen that the
occupation probability at the initial position $x_D$ of the detector is
enhanced when $n$ is small which a quantum mechanical effect but decreases when
$n$ is large. The ratio of occupation probabilities of our walk to that of an
Infinite walk shows a scaling behavior of $\frac{1}{n^2}$. It shows a definite
scaling behavior with number of shifts $s$ also. The limiting behaviours of the
walk are observed when $x_D$ is large, $n$ is large and $s$ is large and the
walker for these cases approach the Infinite Walk, The Semi Infinite Walk and
the Quenched Quantum Walk respectively.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Molla_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Md Aquib Molla&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Goswami_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Sanchari Goswami&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01975">
<title>Dynamical fermionization in one-dimensional spinor gases at finite temperature. (arXiv:2211.01975v1 [cond-mat.stat-mech])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01975</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Following the removal of axial confinement the momentum distribution of a
Tonks-Girardeau gas approaches that of a system of noninteracting spinless
fermions in the initial harmonic trap. This phenomenon, called dynamical
fermionization, has been experimentally confirmed in the case of the
Lieb-Liniger model and theoretically predicted in the case of multicomponent
systems at zero temperature. We prove analytically that for all spinor gases
with strong repulsive contact interactions at finite temperature the momentum
distribution after release from the trap asymptotically approaches that of a
system of spinless fermions at the same temperature but with a renormalized
chemical potential which depends on the number of components of the spinor
system. In the case of the Gaudin-Yang model we check numerically our
analytical predictions using the results obtained from a nonequilibrium
generalization of Lenard&apos;s formula describing the time evolution of the
field-field correlators.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Patu_O/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ovidiu I. Patu&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2011.09771">
<title>A shortcut way to the Fokker-Planck equation for the non-Markovian dynamics. (arXiv:2011.09771v3 [cond-mat.stat-mech] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2011.09771</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Using a shortcut way we have derived the Fokker-Planck equation for the
Langevin dynamics with a generalized frictional memory kernel and
time-dependent force field. Then we have shown that this method is applicable
for the non-Markovian dynamics with additional force from harmonic potential or
magnetic field or both of them. The simplicity of the method in these complex
cases is highly noticeable and it is applicable to derive the Fokker-Planck
equation for any kind of linear Langevin equation of motion which describes
additive colored noise driven non Markovian dynamics with or without frictional
memory kernel. For example, one may apply the method even for the linear system
with an additional colored Gaussian noise which is not related to the damping
strength. With these the present study may get strong attention in the field of
stochastic thermodynamics which is now at early stage to consider the
non-Markovian dynamics.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Das_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Joydip Das&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Biswas_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Mousumi Biswas&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Bag_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Bidhan Chandra Bag&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2012.08889">
<title>Expressive power of complex-valued restricted Boltzmann machines for solving non-stoquastic Hamiltonians. (arXiv:2012.08889v3 [quant-ph] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2012.08889</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Variational Monte Carlo with neural network quantum states has proven to be a
promising avenue for evaluating the ground state energy of spin Hamiltonians.
However, despite continuous efforts the performance of the method on frustrated
Hamiltonians remains significantly worse than those on stoquastic Hamiltonians
that are sign-free. We present a detailed and systematic study of restricted
Boltzmann machine (RBM) based variational Monte Carlo for quantum spin chains,
resolving how relevant stoquasticity is in this setting. We show that in most
cases, when the Hamiltonian is phase connected with a stoquastic point, the
complex RBM state can faithfully represent the ground state, and local
quantities can be evaluated efficiently by sampling. On the other hand, we
identify several new phases that are challenging for the RBM Ansatz, including
non-topological robust non-stoquastic phases as well as stoquastic phases where
sampling is nevertheless inefficient. Furthermore, we find that an accurate
neural network representation of ground states in non-stoquastic phases is
hindered not only by the sign structure but also by their amplitudes.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Park_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Chae-Yeun Park&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Kastoryano_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Michael J. Kastoryano&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2110.08304">
<title>Nonlinear Landauer formula: Nonlinear response theory of disordered and topological materials. (arXiv:2110.08304v2 [cond-mat.mes-hall] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2110.08304</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The Landauer formula provides a general scattering formulation of electrical
conduction. Despite its utility, it has been mainly applied to the
linear-response regime, and a scattering theory of nonlinear response has yet
to be fully developed. Here, we extend the Landauer formula to the
nonlinear-response regime. We show that while the linear conductance is
directly related to the transmission probability, the nonlinear conductance is
given by its derivatives with respect to energy. This sensitivity to the energy
derivatives is shown to produce unique nonlinear transport phenomena of
mesoscopic systems including disordered and topological materials. By way of
illustration, we investigate nonlinear conductance of disordered chains and
identify their universal behavior according to symmetry. In particular, we find
large singular nonlinear conductance for zero modes, including Majorana zero
modes in topological superconductors. We also show the critical behavior of
nonlinear response around the mobility edges due to the Anderson transitions.
Moreover, we study nonlinear response of graphene as a prime example of
topological materials featuring quantum anomaly. Furthermore, considering the
geometry of electronic wave functions, we develop a scattering theory of the
nonlinear Hall effect. We establish a new connection between the nonlinear Hall
response and the nonequilibrium quantum fluctuations. We also discuss the
influence of disorder and Anderson localization on the nonlinear Hall effect.
Our work opens a new avenue in quantum physics beyond the linear-response
regime.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Kawabata_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Kohei Kawabata&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Ueda_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Masahito Ueda&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2203.09514">
<title>Emergence of isotropy and dynamic scaling in 2D wave turbulence in a homogeneous Bose gas. (arXiv:2203.09514v3 [cond-mat.quant-gas] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2203.09514</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We realise a turbulent cascade of wave excitations in a homogeneous 2D Bose
gas, and probe on all relevant time and length scales how it builds up from
small to large momenta, until the system reaches a steady state with matching
energy injection and dissipation. This all-scales view directly reveals the two
theoretically expected cornerstones of turbulence formation -- the emergence of
statistical momentum-space isotropy under anisotropic forcing, and the
spatiotemporal scaling of the momentum distribution at times before any energy
is dissipated.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Galka_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Maciej Ga&amp;#x142;ka&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Christodoulou_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Panagiotis Christodoulou&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Gazo_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Martin Gazo&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Karailiev_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Andrey Karailiev&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Dogra_N/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Nishant Dogra&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Schmitt_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Julian Schmitt&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Hadzibabic_Z/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Zoran Hadzibabic&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2205.05704">
<title>Dynamical quantum ergodicity from energy level statistics. (arXiv:2205.05704v2 [quant-ph] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2205.05704</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Ergodic theory provides a rigorous mathematical description of classical
dynamical systems including a formal definition of the ergodic hierarchy.
Closely related to this hierarchy is a less-known notion of cyclic approximate
periodic transformations [see, e.g., I. Cornfield, S. Fomin, and Y. Sinai,
Ergodic theory (Springer-Verlag New York, 1982)], which maps any &quot;ergodic&quot;
dynamical system to a cyclic permutation on a circle and arguably represents
the most elementary notion of ergodicity. This paper shows that cyclic
ergodicity generalizes to quantum dynamical systems, and this generalization is
proposed here as the basic rigorous definition of quantum ergodicity. It
implies the ability to construct an orthonormal basis, where quantum dynamics
transports an initial basis vector to all other basis vectors one by one, while
maintaining a sufficiently large overlap between the time-evolved initial state
and a given basis state. It is proven that the basis, maximizing the overlap
over all cyclic permutations, is obtained via the discrete Fourier transform of
the energy eigenstates. This relates quantum cyclic ergodicity to level
statistics. We then show that the near-universal Wigner-Dyson level statistics
implies quantum cyclic ergodicity, but the reverse is not necessarily true. For
the latter, we study irrational flows on a 2D torus and prove that both the
classical and quantum flows are cyclic ergodic. However, the corresponding
level statistics is neither Wigner-Dyson nor Poisson. Finally, we use the
cyclic construction to motivate a quantum ergodic hierarchy of operators and
argue that under the additional assumption of Poincare recurrences, cyclic
ergodicity is a necessary condition for such operators to satisfy the
eigenstate thermalization hypothesis. This work provides a general framework
for transplanting some rigorous concepts of ergodic theory to quantum dynamical
systems.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Vikram_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Amit Vikram&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Galitski_V/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Victor Galitski&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2206.12924">
<title>Low-temperature behavior of the $O(N)$ models below two dimensions. (arXiv:2206.12924v2 [cond-mat.stat-mech] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2206.12924</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We investigate the critical behavior and the nature of the low-temperature
phase of the $O(N)$ models treating the number of field components $N$ and the
dimension $d$ as continuous variables with a focus on the $d\leq 2$ and $N\leq
2$ quadrant of the $(d,N)$ plane. We precisely chart a region of the $(d,N)$
plane where the low-temperature phase is characterized by an algebraic
correlation function decay similar to that of the Kosterlitz-Thouless phase but
with a temperature-independent anomalous dimension $\eta$. We revisit the
Cardy-Hamber analysis leading to a prediction concerning the nonanalytic
behavior of the $O(N)$ models&apos; critical exponents and emphasize the previously
not broadly appreciated consequences of this approach in $d&amp;lt;2$. In particular,
we discuss how this framework leads to destabilization of the long-range order
in favour of the quasi long-range order in systems with $d&amp;lt;2$ and $N&amp;lt;2$.
Subsequently, within a scheme of the nonperturbative renormalization group we
identify the low-temperature fixed points controlling the quasi long-range
ordered phase and demonstrate a collision between the critical and the
low-temperature fixed points upon approaching the lower critical dimension. We
evaluate the critical exponents $\eta(d,N)$ and $\nu^{-1}(d,N)$ and demonstrate
a very good agreement between the predictions of the Cardy-Hamber type analysis
and the nonperturbative renormalization group in $d&amp;lt;2$.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Chlebicki_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Andrzej Chlebicki&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Jakubczyk_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Pawe&amp;#x142; Jakubczyk&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2206.14277">
<title>Integrable Floquet systems related to logarithmic conformal field theory. (arXiv:2206.14277v2 [quant-ph] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2206.14277</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We study an integrable Floquet quantum system related to lattice statistical
systems in the universality class of dense polymers. These systems are
described by a particular non-unitary representation of the Temperley-Lieb
algebra. We find a simple Lie algebra structure for the elements of
Temperley-Lieb algebra which are invariant under shift by two lattice sites,
and show how the local Floquet conserved charges and the Floquet Hamiltonian
are expressed in terms of this algebra. The system has a phase transition
between local and non-local phases of the Floquet Hamiltonian. We provide a
strong indication that in the scaling limit this non-equilibrium system is
described by the logarithmic conformal field theory.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Yashin_V/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Vsevolod I. Yashin&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Kurlov_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Denis V. Kurlov&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Fedorov_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Aleksey K. Fedorov&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Gritsev_V/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Vladimir Gritsev&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2208.13633">
<title>Liquid-liquid transition in water from first principles. (arXiv:2208.13633v2 [cond-mat.stat-mech] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2208.13633</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;A longstanding question in water research is the possibility that supercooled
liquid water can undergo a liquid-liquid phase transition (LLT) into high- and
low-density liquids. We used several complementary molecular simulation
techniques to evaluate the possibility of an LLT in an ab initio neural network
model of water trained on density functional theory calculations with the SCAN
exchange correlation functional. We conclusively show the existence of a
first-order LLT and an associated critical point in the SCAN description of
water, representing the first definitive computational evidence for an LLT in
water from first principles.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Gartner_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Thomas E. Gartner III&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Piaggi_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Pablo M. Piaggi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Car_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Roberto Car&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Panagiotopoulos_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Athanassios Z. Panagiotopoulos&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Debenedetti_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Pablo G. Debenedetti&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2208.13772">
<title>Computing committors via Mahalanobis diffusion maps with enhanced sampling data. (arXiv:2208.13772v2 [physics.comp-ph] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2208.13772</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The study of phenomena such as protein folding and conformational changes in
molecules is a central theme in chemical physics. Molecular dynamics (MD)
simulation is the primary tool for the study of transition processes in
biomolecules, but it is hampered by a huge timescale gap between the processes
of interest and atomic vibrations which dictate the time step size. Therefore,
it is imperative to combine MD simulations with other techniques in order to
quantify the transition processes taking place on large timescales. In this
work, the diffusion map with Mahalanobis kernel, a meshless approach for
approximating the Backward Kolmogorov Operator (BKO) in collective variables,
is upgraded to incorporate standard enhanced sampling techniques such as
metadynamics. The resulting algorithm, which we call the &quot;target measure
Mahalanobis diffusion map&quot; (tm-mmap), is suitable for a moderate number of
collective variables in which one can approximate the diffusion tensor and free
energy. Imposing appropriate boundary conditions allows use of the approximated
BKO to solve for the committor function and utilization of transition path
theory to find the reactive current delineating the transition channels and the
transition rate. The proposed algorithm, tm-mmap, is tested on the
two-dimensional Moro-Cardin two-well system with position-dependent diffusion
coefficient and on alanine dipeptide in two collective variables where the
committor, the reactive current, and the transition rate are compared to those
computed by the finite element method (FEM). Finally, tm-mmap is applied to
alanine dipeptide in four collective variables where the use of finite elements
is infeasible.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Evans_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Luke Evans&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Cameron_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Maria K. Cameron&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Tiwary_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Pratyush Tiwary&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.00906">
<title>Correspondence from renormalized frequency to heat capacity caused by anharmonic oscillations in diatomic molecules. (arXiv:2210.00906v3 [cond-mat.stat-mech] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.00906</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Anharmonicity plays important roles in distant areas, in classical mechanics
in which it exhibits renormalization of the bare frequency, and in statistical
mechanics in which the simplest situation is that it causes a correction to the
vibrational contribution of the heat capacity of an ideal gas composed of
diatomic molecules, and in $ {\phi}^4 $ model in quantum field theory and
various anharmonic effects in condensed matter physics, etc. A novel two-to-one
correspondence is identified from the renormalized frequencies of anharmonic
oscillations in diatomic molecules to the heat capacity corrections for an
ideal gas of the diatomic molecules. When the frequency and the heat capacity
are expressed in perturbative series, respective, in terms of the
characteristic quantities in mechanics and thermal physics, the expansion
coefficients are essentially defined by the renormalization of the bare
frequency, and two expansion coefficients in former corresponds to one in the
latter.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Liu_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Y. T. Liu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Zhong_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Y. Zhong&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Zhang_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;J. H. Zhang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Liu_Q/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Q. H. Liu&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.01259">
<title>A perspective on microscopic pressure (stress) tensor: history, current understanding, and future challenges. (arXiv:2210.01259v2 [physics.chem-ph] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.01259</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The pressure tensor (equivalent to the negative stress tensor) at both
microscopic and macroscopic levels is fundamental to many aspects of
engineering and science, including fluid dynamics, solid mechanics, biophysics,
and thermodynamics. In this perspective paper, we review methods to calculate
the microscopic pressure tensor. Connections between different pressure forms
for equilibrium and non-equilibrium systems are established. We also point out
several challenges in the field, including the historical controversies over
the definition of the microscopic pressure tensor; the difficulties with
many-body and long-range potentials; the insufficiency of software and
computational tools; and the lack of experimental routes to probe the pressure
tensor at the nanoscale. Possible future directions are suggested.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Shi_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Kaihang Shi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Smith_E/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Edward Smith&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Santiso_E/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Erik E. Santiso&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Gubbins_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Keith E. Gubbins&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.09457">
<title>Pseudo Entropy in dS/CFT and Time-like Entanglement Entropy. (arXiv:2210.09457v2 [hep-th] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.09457</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We study holographic entanglement entropy in dS/CFT and introduce time-like
entanglement entropy in CFTs. Both of them take complex values in general and
are related with each other via an analytical continuation. We argue that they
are correctly understood as pseudo entropy. We find that the imaginary part of
pseudo entropy implies an emergence of time in dS/CFT.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Doi_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Kazuki Doi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Harper_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jonathan Harper&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Mollabashi_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ali Mollabashi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Takayanagi_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Tadashi Takayanagi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Taki_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yusuke Taki&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01360">
<title>High-field quantum spin liquid transitions and angle-field phase diagram of Kitaev magnet $\alpha$-RuCl$_3$. (arXiv:2211.01360v2 [cond-mat.str-el] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01360</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The pursuit of quantum spin liquid (QSL) in the Kitaev honeycomb magnets has
drawn intensive attention recently. In particular, $\alpha$-RuCl$_3$ has been
widely recognized as a promising candidate for the Kitaev QSL. Although the
compound exhibits an antiferromagnetic order under zero field, it is believed
to be endowed with fractionalized excitations, and can be driven to the QSL
phase by magnetic fields. Here, based on a realistic $K$-$J$-$\Gamma$-$\Gamma&apos;$
model for $\alpha$-RuCl$_3$ [1], we exploit the exponential tensor
renormalization group approach to explore the phase diagram of the compound
under magnetic fields. We calculate the thermodynamic quantities, including the
specific heat, Gr\&quot;uneisen parameter, magnetic torque, and the magnetotropic
susceptibility, etc, under a magnetic field with a tilting angle $\theta$ to
the $c^*$-axis perpendicular to the honeycomb plane. We find an extended QSL in
the angle-field phase diagram determined with thermodynamic responses. The
gapless nature of such field-induced QSL is identified from the specific heat
and entropy data computed down to very low temperatures. The present study
provides guidance for future high-field experiments for the QSL in
$\alpha$-RuCl$_3$ and other candidate Kitaev magnets.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Li_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Han Li&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Li_W/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Wei Li&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Su_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Gang Su&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.00679">
<title>Quantum phase transitions in non-Hermitian $\mathcal{P}\mathcal{T}$-symmetric transverse-field Ising spin chains. (arXiv:2211.00679v1 [quant-ph] CROSS LISTED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.00679</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We present a theoretical study of quantum phases and quantum phase
transitions occurring in non-Hermitian $\mathcal{P}\mathcal{T}$-symmetric
superconducting qubits chains described by a transverse-field Ising spin model.
A non-Hermitian part of the Hamiltonian is implemented via imaginary staggered
\textit{longitudinal } magnetic field, which corresponds to a local staggered
gain and loss terms. By making use of a direct numerical diagonalization of the
Hamiltonian for spin chains of a finite size $N$, we explore the dependencies
of the energy spectrum, including the energy difference between the first
excited and the ground states, the spatial correlation function of local
polarization ($z$-component of local magnetization) on the adjacent spins
interaction strength $J$ and the local gain (loss) parameter $\gamma$. A
scaling procedure for the coherence length $\xi$ allows us to establish a
complete quantum phase diagram of the system. We obtain two quantum phases for
$J&amp;lt;0$, namely, $\mathcal{P}\mathcal{T}$-symmetry broken antiferromagnetic state
and $\mathcal{P}\mathcal{T}$-symmetry preserved paramagnetic state, and the
quantum phase transition line between them is the line of exception points. For
$J&amp;gt;0$ the $\mathcal{P}\mathcal{T}$-symmetry of the ground state is retained in
a whole region of parameter space of $J$ and $\gamma$, and a system shows
\textit{two} intriguing quantum phase transitions between ferromagnetic and
paramagnetic states for a fixed parameter $\gamma &amp;gt; 1$. We also provide the
qualitative quantum phase diagram $\gamma-J$ derived in the framework of the
Bethe-Peierls approximation that is in a good accord with numerically obtained
results.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Starkov_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Grigory A. Starkov&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Fistoul_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Mikhail V. Fistoul&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Eremin_I/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ilya M. Eremin&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01123">
<title>Multicriticality in Yang-Lee edge singularity. (arXiv:2211.01123v1 [hep-th] CROSS LISTED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01123</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;In this paper we study the non-unitary deformations of the two-dimensional
Tricritical Ising Model obtained by coupling its two spin \mathbb {Z}_2 odd
operators to imaginary magnetic fields. Varying the strengths of these
imaginary magnetic fields and adjusting correspondingly the coupling constants
of the two spin Z2 even fields, we establish the presence of two universality
classes of infrared fixed points on the critical surface. The first class
corresponds to the familiar Yang-Lee edge singularity, while the second class
to its tricritical version. We argue that these two universality classes are
controlled by the conformal non-unitary minimal models M(2,5) and M(2,7)
respectively, which is supported by considerations based on PT symmetry and the
corresponding extension of Zamolodchikov&apos;s c-theorem, and also verified
numerically using the truncated conformal space approach. Our results are in
agreement with a previous numerical study of the lattice version of the
Tricritical Ising Model [1]. We also conjecture the classes of universality
corresponding to higher non-unitary multicritical points obtained by perturbing
the conformal unitary models with imaginary coupling magnetic fields.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Lencses_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;M&amp;#xe1;t&amp;#xe9; Lencs&amp;#xe9;s&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Miscioscia_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Alessio Miscioscia&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Mussardo_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Giuseppe Mussardo&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-th/1/au:+Takacs_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;G&amp;#xe1;bor Tak&amp;#xe1;cs&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
</rdf:RDF>