<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<rdf:RDF
 xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
 xmlns="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/"
 xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
 xmlns:taxo="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/taxonomy/"
 xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
 xmlns:syn="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
 xmlns:admin="http://webns.net/mvcb/"
>

<channel rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/">
<title>cs.CY updates on arXiv.org</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">Computer Science -- Computers and Society (cs.CY) updates on the arXiv.org e-print archive</description>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:date>2022-11-03T20:30:00-05:00</dc:date>
<dc:publisher>help@arxiv.org</dc:publisher>
<dc:subject>Computer Science -- Computers and Society</dc:subject>
<syn:updateBase>1901-01-01T00:00+00:00</syn:updateBase>
<syn:updateFrequency>1</syn:updateFrequency>
<syn:updatePeriod>daily</syn:updatePeriod>
<items>
 <rdf:Seq>
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01478" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01528" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01545" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01551" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01817" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01998" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/1812.05948" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2201.09130" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2203.17232" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2206.03216" />
 </rdf:Seq>
</items>
<image rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif" />
</channel>
<image rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif">
<title>arXiv.org</title>
<url>http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif</url>
<link>http://arxiv.org/</link>
</image>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01478">
<title>A machine learning model to identify corruption in M\&apos;exico&apos;s public procurement contracts. (arXiv:2211.01478v1 [cs.CY])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01478</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The costs and impacts of government corruption range from impairing a
country&apos;s economic growth to affecting its citizens&apos; well-being and safety.
Public contracting between government dependencies and private sector
instances, referred to as public procurement, is a fertile land of opportunity
for corrupt practices, generating substantial monetary losses worldwide. Thus,
identifying and deterring corrupt activities between the government and the
private sector is paramount. However, due to several factors, corruption in
public procurement is challenging to identify and track, leading to corrupt
practices going unnoticed. This paper proposes a machine learning model based
on an ensemble of random forest classifiers, which we call hyper-forest, to
identify and predict corrupt contracts in M\&apos;exico&apos;s public procurement data.
This method&apos;s results correctly detect most of the corrupt and non-corrupt
contracts evaluated in the dataset. Furthermore, we found that the most
critical predictors considered in the model are those related to the
relationship between buyers and suppliers rather than those related to features
of individual contracts. Also, the method proposed here is general enough to be
trained with data from other countries. Overall, our work presents a tool that
can help in the decision-making process to identify, predict and analyze
corruption in public procurement contracts.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Aldana_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Andr&amp;#xe9;s Aldana&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Falcon_Cortes_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Andrea Falc&amp;#xf3;n-Cort&amp;#xe9;s&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Larralde_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Hern&amp;#xe1;n Larralde&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01528">
<title>Fair and Optimal Classification via Transports to Wasserstein-Barycenter. (arXiv:2211.01528v1 [cs.LG])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01528</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Fairness in automated decision-making systems has gained increasing attention
as their applications expand to real-world high-stakes domains. To facilitate
the design of fair ML systems, it is essential to understand the potential
trade-offs between fairness and predictive power, and the construction of the
optimal predictor under a given fairness constraint. In this paper, for general
classification problems under the group fairness criterion of demographic
parity (DP), we precisely characterize the trade-off between DP and
classification accuracy, referred to as the minimum cost of fairness. Our
insight comes from the key observation that finding the optimal fair classifier
is equivalent to solving a Wasserstein-barycenter problem under $\ell_1$-norm
restricted to the vertices of the probability simplex. Inspired by our
characterization, we provide a construction of an optimal fair classifier
achieving this minimum cost via the composition of the Bayes regressor and
optimal transports from its output distributions to the barycenter. Our
construction naturally leads to an algorithm for post-processing any
pre-trained predictor to satisfy DP fairness, complemented with finite sample
guarantees. Experiments on real-world datasets verify and demonstrate the
effectiveness of our approaches.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Xian_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ruicheng Xian&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Yin_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Lang Yin&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Zhao_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Han Zhao&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01545">
<title>Extracting Spatial Interaction Patterns between Urban Road Networks and Mixed Functions. (arXiv:2211.01545v1 [physics.soc-ph])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01545</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;In the field of urban planning, road network system planning is often the
first step and the main purpose of urban planning is to create a spatial
configuration of different functions such as residence, education, business,
etc. Generally speaking, the more mixed the functions of an area has, the more
possible its vitality may be. Therefore, in this article, we propose a new
framework to study the specific spatial influence patterns of the overall
structure and different sub-structures of road networks on the mixed functions.
Taking road segment as the basic unit, we characterize mixed functions
aggregation of road networks with the number of POIs categories within 100
meters around every road segment. At the same time, on the basis of centrality
measurement in graph theory, we use 4 indexes to reflect the characteristics of
the urban road network structure, including degree, closeness, betweenness, and
length. We conduct our methods and experiments using the road networks and POI
data within the 5th ring road of Beijing. The results demonstrate that urban
road networks inherently influence the aggregation of urban mixed functions in
various patterns and the patterns of road network sub-structures is also quite
different. Our study shows that the higher the degree of the road network
structure has, the more likely it will attract functions&apos; aggregation. It also
reveals that diversified local degree will help gather urban functions. In
addition to those, the analysis as well validates the importance of small-grids
typology of urban road networks and the closeness to the center of cities.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Xiao_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Huidan Xiao&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Yang_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Tao Yang&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01551">
<title>Crime Prediction using Machine Learning with a Novel Crime Dataset. (arXiv:2211.01551v1 [cs.LG])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01551</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Crime is an unlawful act that carries legal repercussions. Bangladesh has a
high crime rate due to poverty, population growth, and many other
socio-economic issues. For law enforcement agencies, understanding crime
patterns is essential for preventing future criminal activity. For this
purpose, these agencies need structured crime database. This paper introduces a
novel crime dataset that contains temporal, geographic, weather, and
demographic data about 6574 crime incidents of Bangladesh. We manually gather
crime news articles of a seven year time span from a daily newspaper archive.
We extract basic features from these raw text. Using these basic features, we
then consult standard service-providers of geo-location and weather data in
order to garner these information related to the collected crime incidents.
Furthermore, we collect demographic information from Bangladesh National Census
data. All these information are combined that results in a standard machine
learning dataset. Together, 36 features are engineered for the crime prediction
task. Five supervised machine learning classification algorithms are then
evaluated on this newly built dataset and satisfactory results are achieved. We
also conduct exploratory analysis on various aspects the dataset. This dataset
is expected to serve as the foundation for crime incidence prediction systems
for Bangladesh and other countries. The findings of this study will help law
enforcement agencies to forecast and contain crime as well as to ensure optimal
resource allocation for crime patrol and prevention.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Shohan_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Faisal Tareque Shohan&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Akash_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Abu Ubaida Akash&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Ibrahim_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Muhammad Ibrahim&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Alam_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Mohammad Shafiul Alam&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01817">
<title>Liability regimes in the age of AI: a use-case driven analysis of the burden of proof. (arXiv:2211.01817v1 [cs.AI])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01817</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;New emerging technologies powered by Artificial Intelligence (AI) have the
potential to disruptively transform our societies for the better. In
particular, data-driven learning approaches (i.e., Machine Learning (ML)) have
been a true revolution in the advancement of multiple technologies in various
application domains. But at the same time there is growing concerns about
certain intrinsic characteristics of these methodologies that carry potential
risks to both safety and fundamental rights. Although there are mechanisms in
the adoption process to minimize these risks (e.g., safety regulations), these
do not exclude the possibility of harm occurring, and if this happens, victims
should be able to seek compensation. Liability regimes will therefore play a
key role in ensuring basic protection for victims using or interacting with
these systems. However, the same characteristics that make AI systems
inherently risky, such as lack of causality, opacity, unpredictability or their
self and continuous learning capabilities, lead to considerable difficulties
when it comes to proving causation. This paper presents three case studies, as
well as the methodology to reach them, that illustrate these difficulties.
Specifically, we address the cases of cleaning robots, delivery drones and
robots in education. The outcome of the proposed analysis suggests the need to
revise liability regimes to alleviate the burden of proof on victims in cases
involving AI technologies.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Llorca_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;David Fern&amp;#xe1;ndez Llorca&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Charisi_V/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Vicky Charisi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Hamon_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ronan Hamon&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Sanchez_I/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ignacio S&amp;#xe1;nchez&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Gomez_E/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Emilia G&amp;#xf3;mez&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01998">
<title>Driving innovation through project based learning: A pre-university STEAM for Social Good initiative. (arXiv:2211.01998v1 [cs.CY])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01998</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The Covid pandemic is a clarion call for increased sensitivity to the
interconnected nature of social problems facing our world today. A
future-oriented education on critical issues, such as those outlined in the
United Nations Sustainable Development Goals (UN SDGs) and designing potential
solutions for such problems is an imperative skill that must be imparted to
children to help them navigate their future in today&apos;s unpredictable world.
Towards this goal, we have been conducting 3.5 month-long mentoring programs
for pre-university students in India to participate in a STEAM for Social Good
innovation challenge conducted annually by the Government of India. Using
digital and physical computing skills, we helped children explore creative
solutions for social problems through a constructionist approach to learning,
wherein they ideated and reflected upon the problems in their communities. The
children learnt the Engineering Design Thinking process and worked in online
groups of two or three, from concept to completion. Despite the constraints
posed by the pandemic, they explored creative ways to think about design and
innovation. They completed a variety of tasks by making, tinkering,
engineering, assembling, and programming to grasp the intricate relationship
between software and hardware. Subsequently, the children showcased their
creative abilities through video storytelling to a panel of domain experts. In
this paper, we present the children&apos;s perspective of their experiences through
this journey, the evaluation metrics based on IEEE design principles, and our
learnings from conducting this initiative as a university-school partnership
model for 84 middle and high school students. The aspirational intent of this
initiative is to make the children better social problem solvers and help them
perceive social problems as opportunities to enhance life for themselves and
their communities.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Manikutty_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Gayathri Manikutty&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Sasidharan_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Sreejith Sasidharan&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Rao_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Bhavani Rao&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/1812.05948">
<title>Characterizing the Global Crowd Workforce: A Cross-Country Comparison of Crowdworker Demographics. (arXiv:1812.05948v2 [cs.CY] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/1812.05948</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Since its emergence roughly a decade ago, microtask crowdsourcing has been
attracting a heterogeneous set of workers from all over the globe. This paper
sets out to explore the characteristics of the international crowd workforce
and offers a cross-national comparison of crowdworker populations from ten
countries. We provide an analysis and comparison of demographic characteristics
and shed light on the significance of microtask income for workers situated in
different national contexts. With over 11,000 individual responses, this study
is the first large-scale country-level analysis of the characteristics of
workers on the platform Appen (formerly CrowdFlower and Figure Eight), one of
the two platforms dominating the microtask market. We find large differences
between the characteristics of the crowd workforces of different countries,
both regarding demography and regarding the importance of microtask income for
workers. Furthermore, we find that the composition of the workforce in the ten
countries was largely stable across samples taken at different points in time.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Posch_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Lisa Posch&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Bleier_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Arnim Bleier&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Flock_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Fabian Fl&amp;#xf6;ck&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Lechner_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Clemens M. Lechner&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Kinder_Kurlanda_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Katharina Kinder-Kurlanda&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Helic_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Denis Helic&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Strohmaier_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Markus Strohmaier&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2201.09130">
<title>Artificial Intelligence for Suicide Assessment using Audiovisual Cues: A Review. (arXiv:2201.09130v2 [cs.AI] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2201.09130</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Death by suicide is the seventh leading death cause worldwide. The recent
advancement in Artificial Intelligence (AI), specifically AI applications in
image and voice processing, has created a promising opportunity to
revolutionize suicide risk assessment. Subsequently, we have witnessed
fast-growing literature of research that applies AI to extract audiovisual
non-verbal cues for mental illness assessment. However, the majority of the
recent works focus on depression, despite the evident difference between
depression symptoms and suicidal behavior and non-verbal cues. This paper
reviews recent works that study suicide ideation and suicide behavior detection
through audiovisual feature analysis, mainly suicidal voice/speech acoustic
features analysis and suicidal visual cues. Automatic suicide assessment is a
promising research direction that is still in the early stages. Accordingly,
there is a lack of large datasets that can be used to train machine learning
and deep learning models proven to be effective in other, similar tasks.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Dhelim_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Sahraoui Dhelim&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Chen_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Liming Chen&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Ning_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Huansheng Ning&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Nugent_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Chris Nugent&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2203.17232">
<title>Performative Power. (arXiv:2203.17232v2 [cs.LG] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2203.17232</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We introduce the notion of performative power, which measures the ability of
a firm operating an algorithmic system, such as a digital content
recommendation platform, to cause change in a population of participants. We
relate performative power to the economic study of competition in digital
economies. Traditional economic concepts struggle with identifying
anti-competitive patterns in digital platforms not least due to the complexity
of market definition. In contrast, performative power is a causal notion that
is identifiable with minimal knowledge of the market, its internals,
participants, products, or prices.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Low performative power implies that a firm can do no better than to optimize
their objective on current data. In contrast, firms of high performative power
stand to benefit from steering the population towards more profitable behavior.
We confirm in a simple theoretical model that monopolies maximize performative
power. A firm&apos;s ability to personalize increases performative power, while
competition and outside options decrease performative power. On the empirical
side, we propose an observational causal design to identify performative power
from discontinuities in how digital platforms display content. This allows to
repurpose causal effects from various studies about digital platforms as lower
bounds on performative power. Finally, we speculate about the role that
performative power might play in competition policy and antitrust enforcement
in digital marketplaces.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Hardt_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Moritz Hardt&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Jagadeesan_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Meena Jagadeesan&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Mendler_Dunner_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Celestine Mendler-D&amp;#xfc;nner&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2206.03216">
<title>Data Governance in the Age of Large-Scale Data-Driven Language Technology. (arXiv:2206.03216v2 [cs.CY] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2206.03216</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The recent emergence and adoption of Machine Learning technology, and
specifically of Large Language Models, has drawn attention to the need for
systematic and transparent management of language data. This work proposes an
approach to global language data governance that attempts to organize data
management amongst stakeholders, values, and rights. Our proposal is informed
by prior work on distributed governance that accounts for human values and
grounded by an international research collaboration that brings together
researchers and practitioners from 60 countries. The framework we present is a
multi-party international governance structure focused on language data, and
incorporating technical and organizational tools needed to support its work.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Jernite_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yacine Jernite&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Nguyen_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Huu Nguyen&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Biderman_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Stella Biderman&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Rogers_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Anna Rogers&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Masoud_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Maraim Masoud&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Danchev_V/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Valentin Danchev&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Tan_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Samson Tan&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Luccioni_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Alexandra Sasha Luccioni&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Subramani_N/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Nishant Subramani&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Dupont_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;G&amp;#xe9;rard Dupont&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Dodge_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jesse Dodge&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Lo_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Kyle Lo&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Talat_Z/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Zeerak Talat&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Johnson_I/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Isaac Johnson&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Radev_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Dragomir Radev&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Nikpoor_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Somaieh Nikpoor&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Frohberg_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;J&amp;#xf6;rg Frohberg&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Gokaslan_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Aaron Gokaslan&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Henderson_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Peter Henderson&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Bommasani_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Rishi Bommasani&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Mitchell_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Margaret Mitchell&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
</rdf:RDF>