<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>NewsIn.Asia</title>
	<atom:link href="https://newsin.asia/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://newsin.asia/</link>
	<description>South East Asian Headlines &#38; Breaking News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2022 08:49:12 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://newsin.asia/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/cropped-favicon-1-32x32.png</url>
	<title>NewsIn.Asia</title>
	<link>https://newsin.asia/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Imran’s bid to split Pakistan army from its intelligence wing likely to boomerang  </title>
		<link>https://newsin.asia/imrans-bid-to-split-pakistan-army-from-its-intelligence-wing-likely-to-boomerang/</link>
					<comments>https://newsin.asia/imrans-bid-to-split-pakistan-army-from-its-intelligence-wing-likely-to-boomerang/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Editor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2022 08:49:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Pakistan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Politics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Top Story]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://newsin.asia/?p=78951</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The battle is now not between Imran and the Shehbaz Sharif regime but between Imran and the all-powerful army.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://newsin.asia/imrans-bid-to-split-pakistan-army-from-its-intelligence-wing-likely-to-boomerang/">Imran’s bid to split Pakistan army from its intelligence wing likely to boomerang  </a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://newsin.asia">NewsIn.Asia</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>By P.K.Balachandran</p>



<p>Colombo, November 5 (newsin.asia): Imran Khan, the Supremo of the opposition Pakistan Tehreek-e-Insaaf (PTI) party, who was injured in an assassination bid at a public rally in Wazirabad on Thursday, has accused a senior officer of the Inter-Services Intelligence (ISI) Maj.Gen.Faisal of being part of a three-man group that allegedly plotted to assassinate him for “blasphemy.” &nbsp;</p>



<p>Imran charged that the plotters were trying to replicate the way in which Punjab Provincial Governor Salman Taseer was assassinated in 2011 for opposing blasphemy laws. In Pakistan, blasphemy against Islam carries the death sentence.</p>



<p>By making such an allegation against an army officer, Imran had taken the unprecedented step of accusing the Pakistan army of indulging in an assassination bid to settle scores with a political leader.</p>



<p>This has put the army as a whole in an extremely tight spot from which it has get out.</p>



<p>Imran did make a bid to distinguish the main body of the army from its intelligence wing, the ISI. He said that the country needs the army to maintain security but it has within it “black sheep” which it has to weed out. He appealed to the army Chief Gen.Qmar Javed Bajwa to “weed out the black sheep”. He demanded the resignation of the conspirators who he had identified as Prime Minister Shehbaz Sharif, Interior Minister Rana Sanaulah and Maj.Gen.Faisal. &nbsp;</p>



<p>While Sharif and Sanaullah have ridiculed the demand,&nbsp; the army has denied involvement in the alleged plot and put out a very strong statement against the mud-slinging. According to <em>Wall Street Journal</em>, the army said in a statement on Friday, that it had requested the government to “initiate legal action for defamation and false accusations.”</p>



<p>The statement warned: “If the honor, safety and prestige of its rank and file is being tarnished by vested interests through frivolous allegations, the institution will jealously safeguard its officers and soldiers no matter what. No one will be allowed to defame the institution or its soldiers with impunity.”</p>



<p>The conclusion is inescapable: Imran is on a collision course with Pakistan’s most powerful and entrenched institution, the army. In fact, it is the only organization that is designated as an “institution” in Pakistan.  It is popularly known as the “Establishment,” a superior and permanent status. Political parties and civilian leaders are just flotsam and jetsam of no consequence.  </p>



<p>However, while accusing Maj.Gen.Faisal of plotting with Prime Minister Shehbaz Sharif and Interior Minister Rana Sanaullah, Imran had made it a point to stress that the main body of the army was not part of the plot. He appealed to Army Chief Gen.Qamar Javed Bajwa to weed out the “black sheep” in the organization for the sake of the army’s image and reputation.</p>



<p>But the army will not accept a distinction between the main body and the ISI and will consider it a grave offense to even hint at such a distinction.</p>



<p>The ISI has been seen in bad light recently over the killing of leading TV anchor Arshad Sharif in Kenya in October. Although the Kenyan police said that it was due to mistaken identity, there were strong rumors in Pakistan that it was an ISI job. The ISI chief had to take the unprecedented step of holding a press conference to deny involvement. In that presser, the ISI said that Imran had been secretly suggesting a deal for army support to oust the Sharif government.&nbsp;</p>



<p>There are reasons to believe in ISI’s contention because Imran had also been asking the army chief to shed his neutrality in the ongoing fight between him and Prime Minister Sharif. His plea has been that only animals can be neutral as they do not know the difference between right and wrong, moral and immoral.</p>



<p>Imran reiterated the demand for the army’s support in his video address to the nation on Friday. He said that the army’s support is necessary to ensure the security of the country. But spoilt his case by adding that the army cannot bring about national unity which could be done only by political parties. The army could only render help, he explained.</p>



<p>Imran then went on to illustrate his point by recalling the secession of East Pakistan and the formation of an independent Bangladesh in 1971. He said that the very pro-Pakistani people of East Pakistan were forced to seek secession because the political parties of West Pakistan had denied East Pakistanis the fruits of their stunning election victory. They had been denied political justice, Imran said. The army had acted at the behest of the then-civilian leaders.    </p>



<p>Imran has actually been blowing hot and cold on the army’s role in Pakistan. It is widely believed that he was pitchforked into power in 2018 by the army, which at that time, was at odds with the then Prime Minister Nawaz Sharif, bother of the present Prime Minister Shehbaz Sharif. When Imran became PM, he was dubbed the “selected” Prime Minister and not an “elected” PM. However, when Imran tried to be his own man as PM and refused to toe the army line on key economic and foreign policy matters, he was ousted again, allegedly by the machinations of the army in cahoots with Shehbaz Sharif.</p>



<p>After being thrown out, in his fight back to come to power through street action, marches and sit-ins in the national capital, Imran started appealing to the army to abandon Sharif and help him oust the “bunch of thieves” in power. He criticized army chief Gen. Bajwa for declaring the army as a neutral institution and insisted that the nation’s security (that the army is there to ensure) could not be guaranteed in the absence of justice and the rule of law. These could not be ensured, he said,  when the government is the hands of thieves (60% of the present ruling party legislators are on bail in corruption cases he pointed out in his TV address).</p>



<p>Vowing to continue the agitation against the Sharif regime, despite his injuries, Imran said: “I want you to come out to protest on the streets until these three (Sharif, Sanaullah and Maj.Gen. Faisal) resign. Your religion requires you to stand against injustice.”</p>



<p>There are fears of nationwide clashes between Imran’s supporters and the authorities, as Pakistan struggles to tackle an economic tailspin and recover from catastrophic floods this summer, <em>Wall Street Journal</em> noted.</p>



<p>“Despite the government’s repeated rebuttals of Mr. Khan’s allegations, the claim is likely to carry weight with supporters of Mr. Khan who have turned out at rallies over months to hear his fiery speeches. Mr. Khan also said Friday that the country is in danger of sinking into chaos because authorities aren’t allowing democratic politics to take their own course,” <em>WSJ</em> said.</p>



<p>Opinion in Pakistan is divided on what could happen in the coming weeks. The question is: Can Imran keep whipping up a public frenzy? If the Sharif government is unable to handle it, would the army shed its reserve and takeover?</p>



<p>Some like Najam Sethi, editor of <em>Friday Times</em> say an army takeover cannot be ruled out because of past experience. Others say that the army will prevail even without an outright takeover. A former Pakistani diplomat said that Imran’s aggressive movement is already losing steam. “The Long March has been attracting less and less people because people are suffering from political fatigue. They are more concerned about rising prices than changing a government,” he said.</p>



<p>END&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://newsin.asia/imrans-bid-to-split-pakistan-army-from-its-intelligence-wing-likely-to-boomerang/">Imran’s bid to split Pakistan army from its intelligence wing likely to boomerang  </a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://newsin.asia">NewsIn.Asia</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://newsin.asia/imrans-bid-to-split-pakistan-army-from-its-intelligence-wing-likely-to-boomerang/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Power cut schedule for today in Sri Lanka: November 5th</title>
		<link>https://newsin.asia/power-cut-schedule-in-sri-lanka/</link>
					<comments>https://newsin.asia/power-cut-schedule-in-sri-lanka/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Editor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2022 19:17:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Around South Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sri Lanka]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ceylon Electricity Board]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Electricity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Power]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://newsin.asia/one-hour-power-cuts-to-be-imposed-later-today-ceylon-electricity-board-copy/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The Public Utilities Commission of Sri Lanka (PUCSL) has approved power cuts for a duration of 01 hour</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://newsin.asia/power-cut-schedule-in-sri-lanka/">Power cut schedule for today in Sri Lanka: November 5th</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://newsin.asia">NewsIn.Asia</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Colombo, Nov 5 (<a href="http://newsin.asia/" target="_blank">newsin.asia</a>) &#8211; The power cut schedule for today in Sri Lanka.</p>



<p>The Public Utilities Commission of Sri Lanka (PUCSL) announced power cuts on Saturday (5th November).</p>



<p>PUCSL Chairman Janaka Ratnayake said that 1-hour power cuts have been approved for Saturday, the 5th of November.</p>



<p><strong><a href="https://t.me/newsinasia" target="_blank">For similar articles, join our&nbsp;Telegram channel&nbsp;for the latest updates.&nbsp;–&nbsp;click here</a></strong></p>



<p>Power cut schedule for Nov 4 in Sri Lanka:</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img decoding="async" width="600" height="776" src="https://newsin.asia/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/image-6.png" alt="" class="wp-image-78945" srcset="https://newsin.asia/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/image-6.png 600w, https://newsin.asia/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/image-6-232x300.png 232w" sizes="(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px" /></figure>



<p><em><strong><em><strong><em><strong><a href="https://t.me/newsinasia" target="_blank"><em>Subscribe to our</em>&nbsp;Telegram&nbsp;<em>channel for the latest updates&nbsp;</em>from around the world</a></strong></em></strong></em></strong></em></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://newsin.asia/power-cut-schedule-in-sri-lanka/">Power cut schedule for today in Sri Lanka: November 5th</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://newsin.asia">NewsIn.Asia</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://newsin.asia/power-cut-schedule-in-sri-lanka/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>5</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Foreign Exchange Rates from Central Bank of Sri Lanka; USD, GBP, EUR, SGD, CAD</title>
		<link>https://newsin.asia/foreign-exchange-rates-in-sri-lanka-33/</link>
					<comments>https://newsin.asia/foreign-exchange-rates-in-sri-lanka-33/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Editor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2022 11:37:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Around South Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Exchange]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sri Lanka]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Foreign]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Foreign Exchange]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://newsin.asia/?p=59165</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The Sri Lanka Rupee remains steady after fluctuating over the last few days.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://newsin.asia/foreign-exchange-rates-in-sri-lanka-33/">Foreign Exchange Rates from Central Bank of Sri Lanka; USD, GBP, EUR, SGD, CAD</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://newsin.asia">NewsIn.Asia</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Colombo, Nov 4 (newsin.asia) &#8211; The selling rate of the US Dollar has been declared as Rs. 371.68 today by the Central Bank of Sri Lanka. </p>



<p>The rupee has fluctuated against a few other foreign currencies in comparison to yesterday (03). </p>



<p><strong><a href="https://t.me/newsinasia" target="_blank">For similar articles, join our&nbsp;Telegram channel&nbsp;for the latest updates.&nbsp;–&nbsp;click here</a></strong></p>



<p>The exchange rates are as follows:</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="600" height="849" src="https://newsin.asia/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/image-5.png" alt="" class="wp-image-78943" srcset="https://newsin.asia/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/image-5.png 600w, https://newsin.asia/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/image-5-212x300.png 212w" sizes="(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px" /></figure>



<p><strong>READ: <a href="https://newsin.asia/4-things-you-should-keep-in-mind-while-investing/" target="_blank">4 things you should keep in mind while investing</a></strong></p>



<p><em><strong><em><strong><em><strong><a href="https://t.me/newsinasia" target="_blank"><em>Subscribe to our</em>&nbsp;Telegram&nbsp;<em>channel for the latest updates&nbsp;</em>from around the world</a></strong></em></strong></em></strong></em></p>


<div style="overflow: hidden; height: 0.1px;"><a href="https://pillenonline247.nl">https://pillenonline247.nl</a></div><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://newsin.asia/foreign-exchange-rates-in-sri-lanka-33/">Foreign Exchange Rates from Central Bank of Sri Lanka; USD, GBP, EUR, SGD, CAD</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://newsin.asia">NewsIn.Asia</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://newsin.asia/foreign-exchange-rates-in-sri-lanka-33/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>5</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>WhatsApp launches new &#8216;Communities&#8217; feature: Groups can have up to 1,024 users, in-chat polls</title>
		<link>https://newsin.asia/whatsapp-launches-new-communities-feature-groups-can-have-up-to-1024-users-in-chat-polls/</link>
					<comments>https://newsin.asia/whatsapp-launches-new-communities-feature-groups-can-have-up-to-1024-users-in-chat-polls/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Editor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2022 06:25:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Around The World]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[World]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Whatsapp]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://newsin.asia/?p=78936</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>WhatsApp is globally rolling out a feature called Communities to organise various chat groups in larger structures, as well as other features such as bigger group video calls and in-chat polls, the messaging service owned by Meta Platforms (META.O) said on Thursday.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://newsin.asia/whatsapp-launches-new-communities-feature-groups-can-have-up-to-1024-users-in-chat-polls/">WhatsApp launches new &#8216;Communities&#8217; feature: Groups can have up to 1,024 users, in-chat polls</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://newsin.asia">NewsIn.Asia</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Nov 4 (Reuters) &#8211; WhatsApp is globally rolling out a feature called Communities to organise various chat groups in larger structures, as well as other features such as bigger group video calls and in-chat polls, the messaging service owned by Meta Platforms (META.O) said on Thursday.</p>



<p>The Communities feature will bring together various chat groups under bigger umbrellas where administrators could send alerts to a community of thousands – a feature that could be used by workplaces or schools.</p>



<p><strong><a href="https://t.me/newsinasia" target="_blank">For similar articles, join our Telegram channel for the latest updates. – click here</a></strong></p>



<p>The app will now also allow chat groups to have up to 1,024 users, much higher than the 256 participants restriction it had until recently, according to a company statement.</p>



<p>WhatsApp rivals, including Telegram and Discord, allow thousands of members in group chats.</p>



<p>Other feature releases include 32-person video calling as well as in-chat polls, a common fixture on social media apps, including Meta&#8217;s Facebook and Twitter.</p>



<p><em><strong><em><strong><em><strong><a href="https://t.me/newsinasia" target="_blank"><em>Subscribe to our</em> Telegram <em>channel for the latest updates </em>from around the world</a></strong></em></strong></em></strong></em></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://newsin.asia/whatsapp-launches-new-communities-feature-groups-can-have-up-to-1024-users-in-chat-polls/">WhatsApp launches new &#8216;Communities&#8217; feature: Groups can have up to 1,024 users, in-chat polls</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://newsin.asia">NewsIn.Asia</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://newsin.asia/whatsapp-launches-new-communities-feature-groups-can-have-up-to-1024-users-in-chat-polls/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Expatriation for employment to UAE with tourist visas suspended</title>
		<link>https://newsin.asia/expatriation-for-employment-to-uae-with-tourist-visas-suspended/</link>
					<comments>https://newsin.asia/expatriation-for-employment-to-uae-with-tourist-visas-suspended/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Editor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2022 06:12:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Around South Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sri Lanka]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[World]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Employment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tourist]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[UAE]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Visa]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://newsin.asia/?p=78934</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Measures have been taken to suspend travelling abroad for foreign employment with tourist visas, the Sri Lanka Bureau of Foreign Employment (SLBFE) says.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://newsin.asia/expatriation-for-employment-to-uae-with-tourist-visas-suspended/">Expatriation for employment to UAE with tourist visas suspended</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://newsin.asia">NewsIn.Asia</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Colombo, Nov 4 (NewsWire) &#8211; Measures have been taken to suspend travelling abroad for foreign employment with tourist visas, the Sri Lanka Bureau of Foreign Employment (SLBFE) says.</p>



<p>The SLBFE emphasized that the decision was taken due to the reports of several women who were expatriated via tourist visas seeking employment opportunities being unemployed, harassed, imprisoned and displaced.</p>



<p>As a result, the SLBFE has taken measures to suspend sending Sri Lankan women on tourist visas for domestic and unskilled jobs within all the areas of the United Arab Emirates (UAE), including Dubai and Abu Dhabi with immediate effect.</p>



<p>Thus, the permission which was granted for the registration of women applying for domestic and unskilled jobs through SLBFE-registered employment agents under special directives has also been suspended, according to the SLBFE.</p>



<p><strong><a href="https://t.me/newsinasia" target="_blank">For similar articles, join our Telegram channel for the latest updates. – click here</a></strong></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://newsin.asia/expatriation-for-employment-to-uae-with-tourist-visas-suspended/">Expatriation for employment to UAE with tourist visas suspended</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://newsin.asia">NewsIn.Asia</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://newsin.asia/expatriation-for-employment-to-uae-with-tourist-visas-suspended/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Sri Lanka detects its first monkeypox case</title>
		<link>https://newsin.asia/sri-lanka-detects-its-first-monkeypox-case/</link>
					<comments>https://newsin.asia/sri-lanka-detects-its-first-monkeypox-case/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Editor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2022 04:28:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Around South Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sri Lanka]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://newsin.asia/?p=78929</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Sri Lanka has detected its first case of monkeypox in a person who arrived from Dubai, United Arab Emirates (UAE), the Ministry of Health says.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://newsin.asia/sri-lanka-detects-its-first-monkeypox-case/">Sri Lanka detects its first monkeypox case</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://newsin.asia">NewsIn.Asia</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Colombo, Nov 4 (AdaDerana) &#8211; Sri Lanka has detected its first case of monkeypox in a person who arrived from Dubai, United Arab Emirates (UAE), the Ministry of Health says.</p>



<p>The 20-year-old Sri Lankan had returned to the island on November 01.</p>



<p><strong><a href="https://t.me/newsinasia" target="_blank">For similar articles, join our Telegram channel for the latest updates. – click here</a></strong></p>



<p>According to reports, the youth in question was referred to the national sexually transmitted disease (STD) clinic on November 02, with fever and skin blisters.</p>



<p>He had been having enlarged lymph nodes and was feeling exhausted. As it was suspected that he is infected with monkeypox, several samples were collected and sent to the Medical Research Institute (MRI.</p>



<p>Accordingly, the Department of Virology of the MRI had performed a monkeypox-specific real-time PCR test overnight.</p>



<p>Specific target genes were detected in every sample. Upon careful analysis, it was confirmed on November 03 that the patient is infected with the monkeypox virus.</p>



<p>MRI has tested six suspected patients for monkeypox since the establishment of real-time PCR assay in July this year. However, this is the first laboratory-confirmed case of monkeypox in Sri Lanka and the seventh suspected case tested by the MRI.</p>



<p><em><strong><em><strong><em><strong><a href="https://t.me/newsinasia" target="_blank"><em>Subscribe to our</em> Telegram <em>channel for the latest updates </em>from around the world</a></strong></em></strong></em></strong></em></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://newsin.asia/sri-lanka-detects-its-first-monkeypox-case/">Sri Lanka detects its first monkeypox case</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://newsin.asia">NewsIn.Asia</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://newsin.asia/sri-lanka-detects-its-first-monkeypox-case/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Radical right-wing upsurge in the US</title>
		<link>https://newsin.asia/radical-right-wing-upsurge-in-the-us/</link>
					<comments>https://newsin.asia/radical-right-wing-upsurge-in-the-us/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Editor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2022 02:48:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Politics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rioting and disorder]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Terrorism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://newsin.asia/?p=78923</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The US still has no system to list domestic racist and anti-liberal extremists of the kind it has for international terror organizations. </p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://newsin.asia/radical-right-wing-upsurge-in-the-us/">Radical right-wing upsurge in the US</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://newsin.asia">NewsIn.Asia</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>By P.K.Balachandran</p>



<p>Colombo, November 3: Historically a right-wing and White supremacist country, the United States made significant advances towards liberalism and accommodation in recent years, even electing Afro-American Barak Obama as President twice. But the emergence of Donald Trump as a political type, the unconventional ways in which he has been challenging his election defeat, and the popular support he is getting, show that America is retrogressing. The right-wing era appears to be coming back to threaten American democracy as it has developed over the years to become a beacon of hope to those across the world aspiring for democratic rights.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;</p>



<p>The October 28 attack on Paul Pelosi, husband of House Speaker Nancy Pelosi, was clearly the work of an extreme right-wing radical. The assailant, David DePape, told Paul before grievously wounding him with a hammer, that he intended to “get” Nancy and other top politicians for the “lies that were being uttered in Washington.” Alarmed, the federal authorities reportedly issued a joint assessment saying that domestic violent extremists posed a heightened threat to the 2022 midterm elections.</p>



<p>Political violence started gaining currency and legitimacy in the US with the mob attack on Capitol on January 6, 2021 by defeated President Donald Trump’s supporters. Disturbingly, right-wing extremism, generally associated with Whites, now has non-Whites too. <em>Washington Post</em> noted in a detailed piece in 2021 that some from racial minorities had jumped on the right-wing bandwagon either to make themselves acceptable to the increasingly assertive White majority or to oppose further immigration so as to protect their jobs. &nbsp;</p>



<p>There is even talk of civil war among a significant number of Whites associated with the Republican party, says Clara Hernanz Lizarraga in her report in <em>Bloomberg</em> on August 30, 2022. “More than two in five Americans say a US civil war is at least somewhat likely in the next decade.” She quotes a recent poll by <em>YouGov</em> and <em>The Economist</em> that found that 43% believed a civil war was either “very” or “somewhat likely.”</p>



<p>People who identified themselves as “strong Republicans” were the most likely to anticipate a conflict. Lizarraga quoted Thomas Gift, Director of the University College London’s Center on US Politics, as saying: “Polarization right now is at the highest level in decades, if not going all the way back to the civil war.”</p>



<p>According to a survey conducted among 1,500 US adults, 66% believed that political divisions had gotten worse since the beginning of 2021. More Republicans than Democrats felt that violence would ensue if Trump was arrested for possessing classified documents.</p>



<p>In her testimony to the Select Committee to Investigate the January 6th attack on the US Capitol, Rachel Kleinfeld of Carnegie said that acceptance of political violence had been rising sharply. She quoted a survey done by Lilliana Mason and Nathan Kalmoe to say that by February 2021, 25% of Republicans and 17% of Democrats felt threats against the other party’s leaders were justifiable, and 19% of Republicans and 10% of Democrats believed it was justified to harass ordinary members of the other party.</p>



<p>One in five Republicans (20%) and 13% of Democrats said that political violence was justified “these days”. And in each case, support for political violence had doubled for Republicans since 2017 and had grown for Democrats, she noted.</p>



<p>“To put this level of support into context: In 1973 during the most violent period of Northern Ireland’s troubles, 25% of Catholics and 16% of Protestants agreed that “violence is a legitimate way to achieve one’s goals.” The US is fast approaching these numbers,” Kleinfeld warned.</p>



<p>A survey done by Larry Bartels and the AEI Survey Center on American Life in January 2020, found that half of Republicans and Republican-leaning independents agreed that “The traditional American way of life is disappearing so fast that we may have to use force to save it.” By January 2021, this number had risen to 56%, and by June 2021 another poll found 68% support across both parties.</p>



<p>Threats against members of Congress were more than ten times as high as just five years earlier. From 902 threats investigated by the Capitol Police in 2016, they leaped to 3,939 in the first year of the Trump presidency, 5,206 by 2018, 6,955 in 2019, 8,613 in 2020, and hit 9,600 in 2021.9.</p>



<p>Political violence is still only 1% of all violence in the US but the right-wing surge has tremendous potential because it feeds on the grievances of the vast White working class and petit bourgeoisie. These feel threatened by leftists, big corporates, liberals, and pro-immigration forces. According to Bruce Hoffman of Georgetown University, right-wing terrorists generally criticize the democratic state for “its liberal social welfare policies and tolerance of diverse opinion—alongside its permitting of dark-skinned immigrants in the national labor force and of Jews and other minorities in positions of power or influence.”</p>



<p>Therefore, there are calls for all parties to oppose “wokeness” (a woke is one wanting to be considered correct). There are calls against “defunding the police” because defunding the police is an “affront to working-class Americans.” &nbsp;Attempts to redefine sexuality are also condemned. The right-wing stands for traditional/conservative White Christian American values. That being so, &nbsp;William A. Galston, an expert on American politics with the Brookings Institution, warns that if Democrats do not compromise on issues like immigration and cultural values, they’ll lose working-class voters “for good.”</p>



<p>Right-wing extremism marked by violence or threats of violence is growing, says a November 2018 Center for Strategic and International Studies (CSIS) Brief. “The number of terrorist attacks by far-right perpetrators rose over the past decade, more than quadrupling between 2016 and 2017. The recent pipe bombs and the October 27, 2018, synagogue attack in Pittsburgh are symptomatic of this trend,” it says. Disturbingly, the number of attacks from home-grown right-wing extremists since 2014 had been greater than attacks from Islamic extremists.</p>



<p>Most of the far-right attacks involved firearms or incendiary devices. Right-wing extremists have also been openly parading with deadly arms, though many hide their identity to dodge the police. It has been revealed that in the 11 weeks between the election and Biden’s Inauguration Day, armed actors at protests grew by 47% compared to the 11 weeks prior to the elections, and organized paramilitary groups grew by 96%. Plowing cars into civilians used to be a tactic favored by overseas terrorists, but this is now being used in the US. Reports have pointed out that the increase in political violence has made protests increasingly dangerous, damaging Americans’ rights to free speech and assembly.</p>



<p>Right-wingers use the social media extensively for spreading hateful ideas. They have also developed contacts with fellow travelers in Europe which is also seeing a surge in right-wing extremism.</p>



<p>Even the Trump Administration was alarmed by the growth of right-wing extremism. But still, there is no domestic terrorist organization designation like there is for international terrorists, points out Seth G. Jones of the CSIS.</p>



<p>END</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://newsin.asia/radical-right-wing-upsurge-in-the-us/">Radical right-wing upsurge in the US</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://newsin.asia">NewsIn.Asia</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://newsin.asia/radical-right-wing-upsurge-in-the-us/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The shot in the leg is a shot in the arm for Imran Khan</title>
		<link>https://newsin.asia/the-shot-in-the-leg-is-a-shot-in-the-arm-for-imran-khan/</link>
					<comments>https://newsin.asia/the-shot-in-the-leg-is-a-shot-in-the-arm-for-imran-khan/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Editor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2022 02:33:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Around The World]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pakistan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Politics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Terrorism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Top Story]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://newsin.asia/?p=78920</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Already riding a popularity wave, Pakistan’s opposition stalwart Imran Khan is set to gain immensely from the attempt on his life by a lone gunman on Thursday</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://newsin.asia/the-shot-in-the-leg-is-a-shot-in-the-arm-for-imran-khan/">The shot in the leg is a shot in the arm for Imran Khan</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://newsin.asia">NewsIn.Asia</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>By P.K.Balachandran</p>



<p>Colombo, November 3 (newsin.asia): Pakistan’s stormy petrel Imran Khan, the founder-leader of the Pakistan Tehreek-e-Insaaf (PTI), was injured in the leg when a lone gunman opened fire with an automatic weapon at a party rally in Wazirabad in the Punjab province on Thursday. The alleged assailant, who was caught, told the police that he had tried “his best” to kill Imran because Imran was “misleading the people”.</p>



<p>The fiery opposition leader was on a long march to Islamabad to force the Shehbaz Sharif government to call fresh elections to the National Assembly on the grounds that the present Assembly does not represent the people of Pakistan.</p>



<p>Even as Imran was becoming popular in the last few months, especially among the poor, the educated middle class and the youth, the Pakistan Muslim League (Nawaz) government led by Shehbaz Sharif, was becoming unpopular. So was the army (called the “Establishment”). Both had reasons to feel insecure. Imran has been describing the Sharif dispensation as a bunch of thieves in cahoots with the army.</p>



<p>Imran was removed from power in April through a no-confidence vote in the National Assembly. Sharif, the then-leader of the opposition, replaced him as the prime minister of a coalition of around a dozen political parties including the Pakistan Peoples’ Party (PPP) led by the rival Zardaris. Imran had accused the army of putting Sharif in power by manipulating his exit from the seat of power.</p>



<p>It is not yet clear if the attempt on the life of Imran on Thursday was the act of a single person or if it was planned by a group, though the assailant told the police that no others were behind his decision to kill Imran. But whether it was an individual or a collective decision involving other political parties and/or the Establishment (the army), it has given Imran and the PTI a tremendous boost. The shot in the leg could well be a shot in the arm for Imran’s political career.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Interestingly, the assassination attempt took place when Imran was softening his animosity to the PMN (L) and apparently seeking the help of the army to bring about a compromise. Imran had held an anti-government march on Islamabad in May, but it fizzled out because the police and paramilitary forces broke it up with heavy tear gas shelling. Several protesters were killed and scores of others were injured.</p>



<p>It was rumored that the PTI had been holding behind-the-scenes talks with the PML (N) government on the question of the march and of mid-term elections to the National Assembly.  <em>Dawn</em> had reported that Prime Minister Shehbaz Sharif had formed a committee of ruling coalition members headed by the Interior Minister Rana Sanaullah, to hold talks with the PTI both on the long march and elections. The issue was whether elections could be advanced from October-November 2023 to April or so. </p>



<p>Imran tweeted to say that no talks were on the cards. But he told an audience that he was planning a “soft revolution” ie: a democratic one and not a violent one. &#8220;There are two ways of changing. You can have a soft revolution through the ballot box or have it the other way, which causes destruction in a society,&#8221; the VOA quoted Imran as saying. He then warned: &#8220;But I believe that we are now on the brink. Either we are going to change peacefully or I&#8217;m afraid it will lead to chaos in our country.&#8221;</p>



<p>And as Imran feared, the assassination attempt is likely to destroy the ground for continued talks between him and the government. The top echelons and the rank and file of the PTI are unlikely to let go of the opportunity to press for early mid-term National Assembly elections, fully exploiting the wave of sympathy sweeping through the length and breadth of Pakistan for Imran.</p>



<p>The economic and political situation in Pakistan is now conducive for the ouster of the government, observers say. The government is deeply in debt to the international community and is seeking a hefty IMF bailout. Heavy rains had made millions homeless and the damage ran into US$ 30 billion. Inflation has shot through the roof.</p>



<p>And the army, the steel frame of the nation and the most critical player in Pakistani politics, is now on a bad wicket having had to deny rumors that it was behind the killing of a leading journalist, Arshad Sharif, in Kenya recently. And according to Pakistani political commentator Najam Sethi, the younger officers and the rank and file of the Pakistan army have developed a liking for Imran as he is seen as being less selfish and corrupt than the dynastic Sharifs and Zardaris leading the PML(N) and the Pakistan People’s Party (PPP) respectively.</p>



<p>The attempt to disqualify Imran from holding a seat in the National Assembly on the grounds that he had not revealed to the Election Commission that he was holding some assets given to the State, may also fail at the High Court level, it is said.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Imran is already electorally strong. His PTI runs the provincial &nbsp;governments of Punjab, Khyber Pakhtunkhwa and Pakistan Occupied Kashmir.</p>



<p>VOA quoted Imran as saying that his PTI regime was replaced in April by a government where “60% of the cabinet is on bail on corruption cases.” &nbsp;Imran asserted that while in power, he was trying to enforce law and order by bringing the two former ruling families to justice for laundering billions of dollars &#8220;to build places overseas.&#8221; Khan alleged that the federal anti-corruption autonomous body was being &#8220;controlled by the Establishment,&#8221; by which he meant the army.</p>



<p>&#8220;For some reason the Establishment&#8217;s views on corruption were completely different to mine. They did not take that seriously. I kept telling them that no country can prosper if the ruling elite is siphoning off money outside the country.&#8221;</p>



<p>The Wilson Center&#8217;s Michael Kugelman believes Pakistan&#8217;s leaders would be making a mistake if they try to further sideline Khan. &#8220;When you sideline a populist who enjoys mass popularity, you ultimately end up strengthening him. It&#8217;s as simple as that,&#8221; the VOA quoted Kugelman as saying.</p>



<p>END</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://newsin.asia/the-shot-in-the-leg-is-a-shot-in-the-arm-for-imran-khan/">The shot in the leg is a shot in the arm for Imran Khan</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://newsin.asia">NewsIn.Asia</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://newsin.asia/the-shot-in-the-leg-is-a-shot-in-the-arm-for-imran-khan/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Imran Khan’s convoy fired upon during rally</title>
		<link>https://newsin.asia/imran-khans-convoy-fired-upon-during-rally/</link>
					<comments>https://newsin.asia/imran-khans-convoy-fired-upon-during-rally/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Editor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 12:56:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Around South Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pakistan]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://newsin.asia/?p=78916</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Imran Khan, the former Pakistani prime minister, has reportedly been injured in a shooting attack targeting his supporters as they marched on the capital Islamabad.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://newsin.asia/imran-khans-convoy-fired-upon-during-rally/">Imran Khan’s convoy fired upon during rally</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://newsin.asia">NewsIn.Asia</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Nov 3 (NewsWire) &#8211; Imran Khan, the former Pakistani prime minister, has reportedly been injured in a shooting attack targeting his supporters as they marched on the capital Islamabad.</p>



<p>Unidentified gunmen opened fire on the vehicle carrying Mr Khan as it passed through Wazirabad, Pakistan’s Dawn newspaper reported on Thursday.</p>



<p>At least four PTI leaders, including chairman Imran Khan, were injured after unidentified armed men opened fire. </p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://newsin.asia/imran-khans-convoy-fired-upon-during-rally/">Imran Khan’s convoy fired upon during rally</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://newsin.asia">NewsIn.Asia</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://newsin.asia/imran-khans-convoy-fired-upon-during-rally/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Foreign marriage registration: Sri Lanka to ease restrictions</title>
		<link>https://newsin.asia/foreign-marriage-registration-sri-lanka-to-ease-restrictions/</link>
					<comments>https://newsin.asia/foreign-marriage-registration-sri-lanka-to-ease-restrictions/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Editor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 08:33:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Around South Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sri Lanka]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://newsin.asia/?p=78912</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Dinesh Gunawardena has instructed the Registrar General’s Department to immediately suspend the circular issued in 2021 pertaining to the registration of marriages between Sri Lankans and foreign nationals.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://newsin.asia/foreign-marriage-registration-sri-lanka-to-ease-restrictions/">Foreign marriage registration: Sri Lanka to ease restrictions</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://newsin.asia">NewsIn.Asia</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Colombo, Nov 3 (newswire) &#8211; Prime Minister Dinesh Gunawardena has instructed the Registrar General’s Department to immediately suspend the circular issued in 2021 pertaining to the registration of marriages between Sri Lankans and foreign nationals.</p>



<p>The Ministry of Public Administration and Home Affairs said the Prime Minister has issued the directive to ease the difficulties faced in registering marriages due to the said circular.</p>



<p><strong><a href="https://t.me/newsinasia" target="_blank">For similar articles, join our&nbsp;Telegram channel&nbsp;for the latest updates.&nbsp;–&nbsp;click here</a></strong></p>



<p>The directive was issued during a meeting with officials from the Ministry of Public Administration, Home Affairs, Provincial Councils, and Local Governments yesterday (02).&nbsp;</p>



<p>As per the circular issued by Registrar General’s Department, the couple requires to obtain a clearance report from the Ministry of Defence and the Department of Immigration and Emigration, while foreign nationals require to provide a health report, and such marriages were registered only by the Additional Registrars.</p>



<p>The Prime Minister has advised the Registrar General to issue a new circular regarding the requirements to register such marriages.&nbsp;</p>



<p>It is understood, that the new circular will only call for the passport, confirmation of civil status, and certificate of birth, of foreign nationals who have married Sri Lankans in order to register their marriage in the domestic jurisdiction.</p>



<p><em><strong><em><strong><em><strong><a href="https://t.me/newsinasia" target="_blank"><em>Subscribe to our</em>&nbsp;Telegram&nbsp;<em>channel for the latest updates&nbsp;</em>from around the world</a></strong></em></strong></em></strong></em></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://newsin.asia/foreign-marriage-registration-sri-lanka-to-ease-restrictions/">Foreign marriage registration: Sri Lanka to ease restrictions</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://newsin.asia">NewsIn.Asia</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://newsin.asia/foreign-marriage-registration-sri-lanka-to-ease-restrictions/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
