<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<rdf:RDF
 xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
 xmlns="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/"
 xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
 xmlns:taxo="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/taxonomy/"
 xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
 xmlns:syn="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
 xmlns:admin="http://webns.net/mvcb/"
>

<channel rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/">
<title>physics.ao-ph updates on arXiv.org</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">Physics -- Atmospheric and Oceanic Physics (physics.ao-ph) updates on the arXiv.org e-print archive</description>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:date>2022-11-03T20:30:00-05:00</dc:date>
<dc:publisher>help@arxiv.org</dc:publisher>
<dc:subject>Physics -- Atmospheric and Oceanic Physics</dc:subject>
<syn:updateBase>1901-01-01T00:00+00:00</syn:updateBase>
<syn:updateFrequency>1</syn:updateFrequency>
<syn:updatePeriod>daily</syn:updatePeriod>
<items>
 <rdf:Seq>
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01613" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01685" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01902" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01908" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01929" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01944" />
 </rdf:Seq>
</items>
<image rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif" />
</channel>
<image rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif">
<title>arXiv.org</title>
<url>http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif</url>
<link>http://arxiv.org/</link>
</image>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01613">
<title>An Unsupervised Learning Perspective on the Dynamic Contribution to Extreme Precipitation Changes. (arXiv:2211.01613v1 [physics.ao-ph])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01613</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Despite the importance of quantifying how the spatial patterns of extreme
precipitation will change with warming, we lack tools to objectively analyze
the storm-scale outputs of modern climate models. To address this gap, we
develop an unsupervised machine learning framework to quantify how storm
dynamics affect precipitation extremes and their changes without sacrificing
spatial information. Over a wide range of precipitation quantiles, we find that
the spatial patterns of extreme precipitation changes are dominated by spatial
shifts in storm regimes rather than intrinsic changes in how these storm
regimes produce precipitation.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Mooers_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Griffin Mooers&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Beucler_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Tom Beucler&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Pritchard_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Mike Pritchard&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Mandt_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Stephan Mandt&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01685">
<title>Generalized topological bulk-edge correspondence in continuous systems with non-Hermitian boundary conditions. (arXiv:2211.01685v1 [cond-mat.mes-hall])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01685</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The bulk-edge correspondence (BEC) is the hallmark of topological systems. In
continuous (non-lattice) Hermitian systems with unbounded wavevector it was
recently shown that the BEC is modified. How would it be further affected in
non-Hermitian systems, experiencing loss and/or gain? In this work we take the
first step in this direction, by studying a Hermitian continuous system with
non-Hermitian boundary conditions. We find in this case that edge modes emerge
at roots of the scattering matrix, as opposed to the Hermitian case, where they
emerge at poles (or, more accurately, coalescence of roots and poles). This
entails a nontrivial modification to the relative Levinson&apos;s theorem. We then
show that the topological structure remains the same as in the Hermitian case,
and the generalized BEC holds, provided one employs appropriate modified
contours in the wavevector plane, so that the scattering matrix phase winding
counts the edge modes correctly. We exemplify all this using a paradigmatic
model of waves in a shallow ocean or active systems in the presence of odd
viscosity, as well as 2D electron gas with Hall viscosity. We use this
opportunity to examine the case of large odd viscosity, where the scattering
matrix becomes $2\times2$, which has not been discussed in previous works on
the Hermitian generalized BEC.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Rapoport_O/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Orr Rapoport&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Goldstein_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Moshe Goldstein&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01902">
<title>Martian Ionosphere Electron Density Prediction Using Bagged Trees. (arXiv:2211.01902v1 [physics.ao-ph])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01902</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The availability of Martian atmospheric data provided by several Martian
missions broadened the opportunity to investigate and study the conditions of
the Martian ionosphere. As such, ionospheric models play a crucial part in
improving our understanding of ionospheric behavior in response to different
spatial, temporal, and space weather conditions. This work represents an
initial attempt to construct an electron density prediction model of the
Martian ionosphere using machine learning. The model targets the ionosphere at
solar zenith ranging from 70 to 90 degrees, and as such only utilizes
observations from the Mars Global Surveyor mission. The performance of
different machine learning methods was compared in terms of root mean square
error, coefficient of determination, and mean absolute error. The bagged
regression trees method performed best out of all the evaluated methods.
Furthermore, the optimized bagged regression trees model outperformed other
Martian ionosphere models from the literature (MIRI and NeMars) in finding the
peak electron density value, and the peak density height in terms of
root-mean-square error and mean absolute error.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Darya_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Abdollah Masoud Darya&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Alameri_N/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Noora Alameri&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Shaikh_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Muhammad Mubasshir Shaikh&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Fernini_I/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ilias Fernini&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01908">
<title>Near-real-time global gridded daily CO$_2$ emissions 2021. (arXiv:2211.01908v1 [physics.ao-ph])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01908</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We present a near-real-time global gridded daily CO$_2$ emissions dataset
(GRACED) throughout 2021. GRACED provides gridded CO$_2$ emissions at a
0.1degree*0.1degree spatial resolution and 1-day temporal resolution from
cement production and fossil fuel combustion over seven sectors, including
industry, power, residential consumption, ground transportation, international
aviation, domestic aviation, and international shipping. GRACED is prepared
from a near-real-time daily national CO$_2$ emissions estimates (Carbon
Monitor), multi-source spatial activity data emissions and satellite NO$_2$
data for time variations of those spatial activity data. GRACED provides the
most timely overview of emissions distribution changes, which enables more
accurate and timely identification of when and where fossil CO$_2$ emissions
have rebounded and decreased. Uncertainty analysis of GRACED gives a grid-level
two-sigma uncertainty of value of 19.9% in 2021, indicating the reliability of
GRACED was not sacrificed for the sake of higher spatiotemporal resolution that
GRACED provides. Continuing to update GRACED in a timely manner could help
policymakers monitor energy and climate policies&apos; effectiveness and make
adjustments quickly.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Dou_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xinyu Dou&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Hong_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jinpyo Hong&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Ciais_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Philippe Ciais&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Chevallier_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Fr&amp;#xe9;d&amp;#xe9;ric Chevallier&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Yan_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Feifan Yan&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Yu_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ying Yu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Hu_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yifan Hu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Huo_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Da Huo&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Sun_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yun Sun&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Wang_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yilong Wang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Davis_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Steven J. Davis&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Crippa_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Monica Crippa&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Janssens_Maenhout_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Greet Janssens-Maenhout&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Guizzardi_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Diego Guizzardi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Solazzo_E/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Efisio Solazzo&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Lin_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xiaojuan Lin&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Song_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xuanren Song&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Zhu_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Biqing Zhu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Cui_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Duo Cui&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Ke_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Piyu Ke&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Wang_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Hengqi Wang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Zhou_W/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Wenwen Zhou&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Huang_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xia Huang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Deng_Z/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Zhu Deng&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Liu_Z/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Zhu Liu&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01929">
<title>Attractors and bifurcation diagrams in complex climate models. (arXiv:2211.01929v1 [physics.ao-ph])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01929</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The climate is a complex non-equilibrium dynamical system that relaxes toward
a steady state under the continuous input of solar radiation and dissipative
mechanisms. The steady state is not necessarily unique. A useful tool to
describe the possible steady states under different forcing is the bifurcation
diagram, that reveals the regions of multi-stability, the position of tipping
points, and the range of stability of each steady state. However, its
construction is highly time consuming in climate models with a dynamical deep
ocean, interactive ice sheets or carbon cycle, where the relaxation time
becomes larger than thousand years. Using a coupled setup of MITgcm, we test
two techniques with complementary advantages. The first is based on the
introduction of random fluctuations in the forcing and permits to explore a
wide part of phase space. The second reconstructs the stable branches and is
more precise in finding the position of tipping points.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Brunetti_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Maura Brunetti&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Ragon_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Charline Ragon&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01944">
<title>Carbon Monitor Europe, near-real-time daily CO$_2$ emissions for 27 EU countries and the United Kingdom. (arXiv:2211.01944v1 [physics.geo-ph])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01944</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;With the urgent need to implement the EU countries pledges and to monitor the
effectiveness of Green Deal plan, Monitoring Reporting and Verification tools
are needed to track how emissions are changing for all the sectors. Current
official inventories only provide annual estimates of national CO$_2$ emissions
with a lag of 1+ year which do not capture the variations of emissions due to
recent shocks including COVID lockdowns and economic rebounds, war in Ukraine.
Here we present a near-real-time country-level dataset of daily fossil fuel and
cement emissions from January 2019 through December 2021 for 27 EU countries
and UK, which called Carbon Monitor Europe. The data are calculated separately
for six sectors: power, industry, ground transportation, domestic aviation,
international aviation and residential. Daily CO$_2$ emissions are estimated
from a large set of activity data compiled from different sources. The goal of
this dataset is to improve the timeliness and temporal resolution of emissions
for European countries, to inform the public and decision makers about current
emissions changes in Europe.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Ke_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Piyu Ke&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Deng_Z/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Zhu Deng&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Zhu_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Biqing Zhu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Zheng_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Bo Zheng&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Wang_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yilong Wang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Boucher_O/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Olivier Boucher&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Arous_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Simon Ben Arous&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Zhou_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Chuanlong Zhou&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Dou_X/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Xinyu Dou&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Sun_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Taochun Sun&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Li_Z/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Zhao Li&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Yan_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Feifan Yan&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Cui_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Duo Cui&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Hu_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yifan Hu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Huo_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Da Huo&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Pierre_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jean Pierre&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Engelen_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Richard Engelen&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Davis_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Steven J. Davis&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Ciais_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Philippe Ciais&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Liu_Z/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Zhu Liu&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
</rdf:RDF>