<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"><channel><title>IEEE Spectrum</title><link>https://spectrum.ieee.org/</link><description>IEEE Spectrum</description><atom:link href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/feeds/topic/aerospace.rss" rel="self"></atom:link><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2022 15:56:38 -0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/eyJ0eXAiOiJKV1QiLCJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJpbWFnZSI6Imh0dHBzOi8vYXNzZXRzLnJibC5tcy8yNjg4NDUyMC9vcmlnaW4ucG5nIiwiZXhwaXJlc19hdCI6MTY5OTk5OTQzOX0.aimbeagNFKGtififsLPFvztNYGr1_NMvLOOT1mPOjEU/image.png?width=210</url><link>https://spectrum.ieee.org/</link><title>IEEE Spectrum</title></image><item><title>Chopper Rocket Chasers Played “Catch Me if You Can”</title><link>https://spectrum.ieee.org/reusable-rockets</link><description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/a-shot-from-overhead-of-a-helicopter-with-its-rotors-spinning-a-large-cylindrical-object-hangs-from-it-on-a-cable.jpg?id=32041805&width=2000&height=1500&coordinates=0%2C0%2C0%2C1"/><br/><br/><p><strong><em>Update 4 Nov. 2:45 p.m. EDT:</em> </strong><em>Rocket Lab says its launch was successful, but booster recovery was not. It says it lost telemetry signals from the descending first stage during reentry. <br/></em></p><p><em>“As standard procedure, we pull the helicopter from the recovery zone if this happens,” a company spokesperson said.</em></p><p><span></span>“If at first you don’t succeed….” <a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/rocket-booster-rocket-lab" target="_self">Rocket Lab</a>, the <a href="https://www.rocketlabusa.com/" target="_blank">space launch company</a> with two launchpads on the New Zealand coast, almost did succeed in May at something very difficult: To make its Electron booster reusable (and therefore far less expensive to fly), it tried catching the used first stage—in midair—with a helicopter as it descended by parachute toward the Pacific Ocean.</p><p>It came oh-so-close. On its first try, Rocket Lab’s helicopter successfully snagged the parachute with a hook at the end of a long cable—a remarkable piece of planning and flying. But the pilot, in the company’s <a href="https://www.rocketlabusa.com/updates/new-blog-post-8/" target="_blank">words</a>, “detected different load characteristics than previously experienced in testing,” and let the rocket fall in the water for a ship to recover it. </p><p>So try, try again. Rocket Lab is now making a new recovery attempt, this time with a rocket carrying an atmospheric-research satellite for the <a href="https://www.rymdstyrelsen.se/en/swedish-space-industry/swedish-satellites/mats/" target="_blank">Swedish National Space Agency</a>. If the helicopter can catch and hold onto the booster, it will fly it back to Rocket Lab’s production complex near Auckland for possible reuse. </p><p>“We’re eager to get the helicopter back out there,” said <a href="https://www.rocketlabusa.com/about/team/" target="_blank">Peter Beck</a>, Rocket Lab’s CEO and founder. </p><p class="shortcode-media shortcode-media-rebelmouse-image">
<img alt=" View looking down from a helicopter as it approached Electron rocket booster, descending by parachute. A yellow cable at left has a large hook at the end." class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="bd50e731d7c11896cf3f44ff9b7d3171" data-rm-shortcode-name="rebelmouse-image" id="fba11" loading="lazy" src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/view-looking-down-from-a-helicopter-as-it-approached-electron-rocket-booster-descending-by-parachute-a-yellow-cable-at-left-h.jpg?id=32041829&width=980"/>
<small class="image-media media-caption" placeholder="Add Photo Caption...">During Rocket Lab’s launch on 2 May 2022, the helicopter was able to catch the Electron rocket booster, but load issues forced the pilot to let the rocket fall to the water.</small><small class="image-media media-photo-credit" placeholder="Add Photo Credit...">Rocket Lab</small></p><p>“No changes since the May recovery,” said <a href="https://www.rocketlabusa.com/about/team/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Morgan Bailey</a> of Rocket Lab in an email to <em>IEEE Spectrum</em>, “but our team has carried out a number of capture rehearsals with test stages in preparation for this launch.”</p><p>Satellite operators are watching closely because, after Elon Musk’s <a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/tag/spacex" target="_blank">SpaceX</a>, Rocket Lab has established itself as a contender in space launches, especially for companies and government agencies with smaller payloads. This is its 32nd Electron launch since 2017. “They’ve become a major player,” said <a href="https://www.spacecapital.com/team" target="_blank">Chad Anderson</a> of Space Capital, a venture capital firm.</p><p>Many of the world’s launch bases have historically been near the ocean for good reason: If rockets failed, open water is a relatively safe place for debris to fall. That’s why the United States uses coastal Florida and California, and the European Space Agency uses Kourou, French Guiana, on the northern coast of South America. Rocket Lab started in New Zealand and is expanding to the Virginia coast. </p><p>The downside is that saltwater and rocket hardware don’t mix very well; the water is corrosive, and cleanup is expensive. SpaceX goes to great lengths to land its boosters on barges or back at Cape Canaveral; Rocket Lab, whose boosters are smaller, can change its commercial space business dramatically if helicopter recoveries become routine. </p><p>The name of the mission for its <a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/rocket-booster-rocket-lab" target="_blank">first booster-recovery attempt</a> was a playful “There and Back Again”; the second, suggested by an American space enthusiast, is “Catch Me if You Can.”</p><p>Here’s the plan: The Electron rocket, 18 meters tall, lifts off over the southern Pacific, aiming to place the satellite in a sun-synchronous orbit 585 kilometers high. The first stage, which made up 80 percent of the vehicle’s mass at launch, burns out after the first 70 km. Two minutes and 32 seconds into the flight, it drops off, following a long arc that, on past flights, would have sent it crashing into the ocean, about 280 km downrange. </p><p class="shortcode-media shortcode-media-rebelmouse-image">
<img alt="Photo-illustration of a helicopter, a booster attached to a parachute and a ship in the distance." class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="6e9d1b29a9c81d8d4764839068465c55" data-rm-shortcode-name="rebelmouse-image" id="5072f" loading="lazy" src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/photo-illustration-of-a-helicopter-a-booster-attached-to-a-parachute-and-a-ship-in-the-distance.jpg?id=32041811&width=980"/>
<small class="image-media media-caption" placeholder="Add Photo Caption...">This artist's conception envisions the helicopter, having successfully snagged the booster's parachute, carrying it back to dry land. A recovery ship is on standby. </small><small class="image-media media-photo-credit" placeholder="Add Photo Credit...">Rocket Lab</small></p><p>But Rocket Lab has equipped it with heat shielding, a guidance computer and control thrusters, protecting and steering it as it falls tailfirst at up to 8,300 kilometers per hour. Temperatures reach 2,400 °C as it’s slowed by the thickening air around it. </p><p>At an altitude of 13 km a small <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Drogue_parachute" target="_blank">drogue parachute</a> is deployed, followed by a main chute less than a minute later. They slow the booster’s descent to about 36 km/h. </p><p>The helicopter, a Sikorsky S-92, is waiting in the landing zone, trailing a grappling hook on a long cable. If all goes well, the helicopter flies over the descending rocket and snags the parachute cables about 2,000 meters above the ocean’s surface. Then it flies back to land with the rocket hanging underneath.</p><p>“The main advantage of air capture is that we’re not cleaning salt water out of it,” said Rocket Lab’s Bailey in an earlier interview. “We’re still in the test phase part of the program, and in terms of time and cost savings, that’ll be determined.” </p><p>But engines recovered from the ocean after previous launches have been refurbished and test-fired successfully, says Rocket Lab. Like many engineering efforts, it’s a step at a time.</p><p>“Being able to refly Electron without too much rework is the aim of the game,” says the company. “If we can achieve high level performance with engine parts recovered from the ocean, imagine what we can do with returned dry engines.”</p>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2022 14:08:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spectrum.ieee.org/reusable-rockets</guid><category>Space flight</category><category>Rockets</category><category>Aerospace</category><category>Satellites</category><category>Business</category><category>Rocket launch</category><dc:creator>Ned Potter</dc:creator><media:content medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/a-shot-from-overhead-of-a-helicopter-with-its-rotors-spinning-a-large-cylindrical-object-hangs-from-it-on-a-cable.jpg?id=32041805&amp;width=980"></media:content></item><item><title>Who Will Fix Hubble and Chandra?</title><link>https://spectrum.ieee.org/elon-musk-spacex-hubble</link><description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/the-hubble-space-telescope-with-clouds-in-the-background-seen-during-a-space-shuttle-servicing-mission-in-2002.jpg?id=31972878&width=2000&height=1500&coordinates=182%2C0%2C182%2C0"/><br/><br/><p>
<a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/spacex-starlink-dish-network" target="_self">Elon Musk</a>, step aside. You may be the richest rich man in the space business, but you’re not first. Musk’s <a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/search/?q=spacex" target="_self">SpaceX</a> corporation is a powerful force, with its weekly launches and visions of colonizing Mars. But if you want a broader view of how wealthy entrepreneurs have shaped space exploration, you might want to look at <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/George_Ellery_Hale" target="_blank">George Ellery Hale</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/James_Lick" target="_blank">James Lick</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/William_Johnson_McDonald" target="_blank">William McDonald</a> or—remember this name—<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/John_Daggett_Hooker" target="_blank">John D. Hooker</a>.
</p><p>
	All this comes up now because SpaceX, joining forces with the billionaire 
	<a href="https://polarisprogram.com/team/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Jared Isaacman</a>, has made what sounds at first like a novel <a href="https://www.nasa.gov/feature/goddard/2022/nasa-spacex-to-study-hubble-telescope-reboost-possibility" target="_blank">proposal</a> to NASA: It would like to see if one of the company’s Dragon spacecraft can be sent to service the fabled, invaluable (and aging) <a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission_pages/hubble/main/index.html" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Hubble Space Telescope</a>, last repaired in 2009.
</p><p>
	Private companies going to the rescue of one of NASA’s crown jewels? NASA’s mantra in recent years has been to let 
	<a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/private-space-stations" target="_self">private enterprise</a> handle the day-to-day of space operations—communications satellites, getting astronauts to the space station, and so forth—while pure science, the stuff that makes history but not necessarily money, remains the province of government. Might that model change?
</p><p>
	“We’re working on crazy ideas all the time,” said 
	<a href="https://science.nasa.gov/about-us/leadership/Thomas-Zurbuchen" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Thomas Zurbuchen</a>, NASA’s space science chief. "Frankly, that’s what we’re supposed to do.”
</p><p>
	It’s only a six-month feasibility study for now; no money will change hands between business and NASA. But Isaacman, who made his fortune in 
	<a href="https://www.shift4.com/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">payment-management software</a> before turning to space, suggested that if a Hubble mission happens, it may lead to other things. “Alongside NASA, exploration is one of many objectives for the commercial space industry,” he said on a media teleconference. “And probably one of the greatest exploration assets of all time is the Hubble Space Telescope.”
</p><p>
	So it’s possible that at some point in the future, there may be a SpaceX Dragon, perhaps with Isaacman as a crew member, setting out to grapple the Hubble, boost it into a higher orbit, maybe even replace some worn-out components to lengthen its life.
</p><p>
	Aerospace companies say privately mounted repair sounds like a good idea. So good that they’ve proposed it already.
</p><p class="shortcode-media shortcode-media-rebelmouse-image rm-resized-container rm-resized-container-25 rm-float-left" data-rm-resized-container="25%" style="float: left;">
<img alt="The Chandra X-ray telescope, photographed by space shuttle astronauts after they deployed it in July 1999." class="rm-shortcode rm-resized-image" data-rm-shortcode-id="9ae81d7d302196c0c852dc9d2f3f7385" data-rm-shortcode-name="rebelmouse-image" id="ecbfc" loading="lazy" src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/the-chandra-x-ray-telescope-photographed-by-space-shuttle-astronauts-after-they-deployed-it-in-july-1999.jpg?id=31972890&width=980" style="max-width: 100%"/>
<small class="image-media media-caption" placeholder="Add Photo Caption..." style="max-width: 100%;">The Chandra X-ray telescope, as photographed by space-shuttle astronauts after they deployed it in July 1999. It is attached to a booster that moved it into an orbit 10,000 by 100,000 kilometers from Earth.</small><small class="image-media media-photo-credit" placeholder="Add Photo Credit..." style="max-width: 100%;">NASA</small>
</p><p>
<a href="https://www.northropgrumman.com/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Northrop Grumman</a>, one of the United States’ largest aerospace contractors, has quietly suggested to NASA that it might service one of the Hubble’s sister telescopes, the <a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission_pages/chandra/main/index.html" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Chandra X-ray Observatory</a>. Chandra was launched into Earth orbit by the space shuttle Columbia in 1999 (Hubble was launched from the shuttle Discovery in 1990), and the two often complement each other, observing the same celestial phenomena at different wavelengths.
</p><p>
	As in the case of the SpaceX/Hubble proposal, Northrop Grumman’s Chandra study is at an early stage. But there are a few major differences. For one, Chandra was assembled by TRW, a company that has since been bought by Northrop Grumman. And another company subsidiary, 
	<a href="https://www.northropgrumman.com/space/space-logistics-services/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">SpaceLogistics</a>, has been sending what it calls <a href="https://www.northropgrumman.com/space/space-logistics-services/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Mission Extension Vehicles</a> (MEVs) to service aging Intelsat communications satellites since 2020. Two of these robotic craft have launched so far. The MEVs act like space tugs, docking with their target satellites to provide them with attitude control and propulsion if their own systems are failing or running out of fuel. SpaceLogistics says it is developing a next-generation rescue craft, which it calls a Mission Robotic Vehicle, equipped with an articulated arm to add, relocate, or possibly repair components on orbit.
</p><p>
	“We want to see if we can apply this to space-science missions,” says 
	<a href="https://materials.ucsb.edu/events/dr-jonathan-w-arenberg-northrop-grumman" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Jon Arenberg</a>, Northrop Grumman’s chief mission architect for science and robotic exploration, who worked on Chandra and, later, the <a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/collections/james-webb-telescope/" target="_self">James Webb Space Telescope</a>. He says a major issue for servicing is the exacting specifications needed for NASA’s major observatories; Chandra, for example, records the extremely short wavelengths of X-ray radiation (0.01–10 nanometers).
</p><p>
	“We need to preserve the scientific integrity of the spacecraft,” he says. “That’s an absolute.”
</p><p>
	But so far, the company says, a mission seems possible. NASA managers have listened receptively. And Northrop Grumman says a servicing mission could be flown for a fraction of the cost of a new telescope.
</p><div class="rm-embed embed-media"><iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/JUnA88PQY3k" title="YouTube video player" width="560">
</iframe></div><p>
	New telescopes need not be government projects. In fact, NASA’s chief economist, 
	<a href="https://www.nasa.gov/about/alex-macdonald-chief-economist-office-of-the-administrator/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Alexander MacDonald</a>, argues that almost all of America’s greatest observatories were privately funded until Cold War politics made government the major player in space exploration. That’s why this story began with names from the 19th and 20th centuries—Hale, Lick, and McDonald—to which we should add <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Charles_Yerkes" target="_blank">Charles Yerkes</a> and, more recently, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/William_Myron_Keck" target="_blank">William Keck</a>. These were arguably the Elon Musks of their times—entrepreneurs who made millions in oil, iron, or real estate before funding the United States’ largest telescopes. (Hale’s father manufactured elevators—highly profitable in the rebuilding after the Great Chicago Fire of 1871.) The most ambitious observatories, MacDonald calculated for his book <em><a href="https://yalebooks.yale.edu/book/9780300219326/the-long-space-age/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">The Long Space Age</a></em>, were about as expensive back then as some of NASA’s modern planetary probes. None of them had very much to do with government.
</p><p>
	To be sure, government will remain a major player in space for a long time. “NASA pays the cost, predominantly, of the development of new commercial crew vehicles, SpaceX’s Dragon being one,” MacDonald says. “And now that those capabilities exist, private individuals can also pay to utilize those capabilities.” Isaacman doesn’t have to build a spacecraft; he can hire one that SpaceX originally built for NASA.
</p><p>“I think that creates a much more diverse and potentially interesting space-exploration future than we have been considering for some time,” MacDonald says.</p><p>
	So put these pieces together: Private enterprise has been a driver of space science since the 1800s. Private companies are already conducting on-orbit satellite rescues. NASA hasn’t said no to the idea of private missions to service its orbiting observatories.
</p><p>
	And why does John D. Hooker’s name matter? In 1906, he agreed to put up US $45,000 (about $1.4 million today) to make the mirror for a 
	<a href="https://www.mtwilson.edu/building-the-100-inch-telescope/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">100-inch reflecting telescope at Mount Wilson, Calif</a>. One astronomer made the Hooker Telescope famous by using it to determine that the universe, full of galaxies, was expanding.
</p><p>
	The astronomer’s name was 
	<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Edwin_Hubble" target="_blank">Edwin Hubble</a>. We’ve come full circle.
</p>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2022 18:06:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spectrum.ieee.org/elon-musk-spacex-hubble</guid><category>Elon musk</category><category>Spacex</category><category>Nasa</category><category>Northrop grumman</category><category>Hubble space telescope</category><category>Chandra x-ray observatory</category><category>Service robotics</category><dc:creator>Ned Potter</dc:creator><media:content medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/the-hubble-space-telescope-with-clouds-in-the-background-seen-during-a-space-shuttle-servicing-mission-in-2002.jpg?id=31972878&amp;width=980"></media:content></item><item><title>How a Dual Curing Adhesive Works</title><link>https://spectrum.ieee.org/master-bond-uv22dc80-1-dual-cure-epoxy</link><description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/a-person-uses-a-brush-to-apply-epoxy-to-a-set-of-lenses.jpg?id=31844049&width=2000&height=1500&coordinates=248%2C0%2C249%2C0"/><br/><br/><p>
<em>This sponsored article is brought to you by <a href="https://www.masterbond.com/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Master Bond</a>.</em>
</p><p>
<a href="https://www.masterbond.com/video/product-spotlight-uv22dc80" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Master Bond UV22DC80-1</a> is a nanosilica filled, dual cure epoxy based system. Nanosilica filled epoxy formulations are designed to further improve performance and processing properties.
</p><p>
	The specific filler will play a crucial role in determining key parameters such as viscosity, flow, aging characteristics, strength, shrinkage, hardness, and exotherm. As a dual curing system, UV22DC80-1 cures readily upon exposure to UV light, and will cross link in shadowed out areas when heat is added.
</p><hr/><h3>See Master Bond's UV22DC80-1 in Action</h3><br/><span class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="9674f9b6e22739e3e15edf2d3fc9d849" style="display:block;position:relative;padding-top:56.25%;"><iframe frameborder="0" height="auto" lazy-loadable="true" scrolling="no" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/nSbU4uhbVrc?rel=0" style="position:absolute;top:0;left:0;width:100%;height:100%;" width="100%"></iframe></span><p>Dual cure systems are effective for rapidly fixturing parts with the UV portion of the cure, and then concluding the process by adding heat. Watch this video to see a dual cured epoxy in action.</p><h3></h3><br/><p>This compound features exceptionally low shrinkage upon cure, outstanding dimensional stability, and resists abrasion. It is not oxygen inhibited. It withstands chemicals such as acids, bases, fuels and solvents. It is electrically insulative with a volume resistivity greater than 10<sup>14</sup> ohm-cm. It is optically clear, with a refractive index of 1.52. </p><p>The low viscosity ranges from 500 cps to 3500 cps. The temperature serviceability extends from -100°F to 300°F. UV22DC80-1 bonds well to metals, ceramics, glass, rubber, and many plastics. It passes NASA low outgassing certification and is used in high tech applications including aerospace, optical and opto-electronics.<span></span></p><p><a href="https://www.masterbond.com/tds/uv22dc80-1" target="_blank">Contact Master Bond to request a technical data sheet or discuss your application.</a></p>]]></description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2022 17:50:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spectrum.ieee.org/master-bond-uv22dc80-1-dual-cure-epoxy</guid><category>Epoxy</category><category>Ultraviolet</category><category>Adhesive</category><category>Master bond</category><category>Nasa</category><dc:creator>Master Bond</dc:creator><media:content medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/a-person-uses-a-brush-to-apply-epoxy-to-a-set-of-lenses.jpg?id=31844049&amp;width=980"></media:content></item><item><title>NASA’s DART Mission Aims to Save the World</title><link>https://spectrum.ieee.org/planetary-protection-nasa-dart</link><description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/a-cubesat-with-2-large-solar-panels-in-front-of-two-grey-asteroids-in-space-with-a-smaller-cubesat-nearby.jpg?id=31804118&width=2000&height=1500&coordinates=0%2C0%2C0%2C0"/><br/><br/><p>Armageddon ruined everything. <a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/nasa-needs-coders-to-help-prevent-asteroid-armageddon" target="_self"><em>Armageddon</em></a>—the 1998 movie, not the mythical battlefield—told the story of an asteroid headed straight for Earth, and a bunch of swaggering roughnecks sent in space shuttles to blow it up with a nuclear weapon.</p><p>“<em>Armageddon</em> is big and noisy and stupid and shameless, and it’s going to be huge at the box office,” <a href="https://www.rottentomatoes.com/m/armageddon/reviews?intcmp=rt-what-to-know_read-critics-reviews" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">wrote</a> Jay Carr of the <a href="https://www.newspapers.com/newspage/441533250/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"><em>Boston Globe</em></a>.</p><p>Carr was right—the film was <a href="https://www.boxofficemojo.com/year/1998/" target="_blank">the year’s second biggest hit</a> (after <em>Titanic</em>)—and ever since, scientists have had to explain, patiently, that cluttering space with radioactive debris may not be the best way to protect ourselves. NASA is now trying a slightly less dramatic approach with a robotic mission called <a href="https://www.nasa.gov/planetarydefense/dart/dart-news" target="_blank">DART</a>—short for Double Asteroid Redirection Test. On Monday at 7:14 p.m. EDT, if all goes well, the little spacecraft will crash into an asteroid called <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dimorphos" target="_blank">Dimorphos</a>, about 11 million kilometers from Earth. Dimorphos is about 160 meters across, and orbits a 780-meter asteroid, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/65803_Didymos" target="_blank">65803 Didymos</a>. NASA TV plans to <a href="https://www.nasa.gov/nasalive" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">cover it live</a>.</p><p>DART’s end will be violent, but not blockbuster-movie-violent. Music won’t swell and girlfriends back on Earth won’t swoon. Mission managers hope the spacecraft, with a mass of about 600 kilograms, hitting at 22,000 km/h, will nudge the asteroid slightly in its orbit, just enough to prove that it’s technologically possible in case a future asteroid has Earth in its crosshairs.</p><p>“Maybe once a century or so, there’ll be an asteroid sizeable enough that we’d like to certainly know, ahead of time, if it was going to impact,” says <a href="https://www.nasa.gov/planetarydefense/organization" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Lindley Johnson</a>, who has the title of planetary defense officer at <a href="https://www.nasa.gov/planetarydefense" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">NASA</a>.</p><p>“If you just take a hair off the orbital velocity, you’ve changed the orbit of the asteroid so that what would have been impact three or four years down the road is now a complete miss.”</p><p>So take that, Hollywood! If DART succeeds, it will show there are better fuels to protect Earth than testosterone.</p><p>The risk of a comet or asteroid that wipes out civilization is really very small, but large enough that policymakers take it seriously. NASA, ordered by the <a href="https://www.congress.gov/bill/109th-congress/senate-bill/1281/text" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">U.S. Congress</a> in 2005 to scan the inner solar system for hazards, <a href="https://cneos.jpl.nasa.gov/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">has found nearly 900</a> so-called NEOs—<a href="https://www.nasa.gov/planetarydefense/did-you-know" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">near-Earth objects</a>—at least a kilometer across, more than 95 percent of all in that size range that probably exist. It has plotted their orbits far into the future, and none of them stand more than a fraction of a percent chance of hitting Earth in this millennium.</p><p class="shortcode-media shortcode-media-rebelmouse-image">
<img alt="An infographic showing the orientation of Didymos,  Dimorphos, DART, and LICIACube." class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="7c5517ee5dbd74e18ecf3b916f814e98" data-rm-shortcode-name="rebelmouse-image" id="bf199" loading="lazy" src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/an-infographic-showing-the-orientation-of-didymos-dimorphos-dart-and-liciacube.jpg?id=31804127&width=980"/>
<small class="image-media media-caption" placeholder="Add Photo Caption...">The DART spacecraft should crash into the asteroid Dimorphos and slow it in its orbit around the larger asteroid Didymos. The LICIACube cubesat will fly in formation to take images of the impact.</small><small class="image-media media-photo-credit" placeholder="Add Photo Credit...">Johns Hopkins APL/NASA</small></p><p>But there are smaller NEOs, perhaps 140 meters or more in diameter, too small to end civilization but large enough to cause mass destruction if they hit a populated area. There may be 25,000 that come within 50 million km of Earth’s orbit, and NASA estimates telescopes have only found about 40 percent of them. That’s why scientists want to expand the search for them and have good ways to deal with them if necessary. DART is the first test.</p><p>NASA takes pains to say this is a low-risk mission. Didymos and Dimorphos never cross Earth’s orbit, and computer simulations show that no matter where or how hard DART hits, it cannot possibly divert either one enough to put Earth in danger. Scientists want to see if DART can alter Dimorphos’s speed by perhaps a few centimeters per second.</p><p>The DART spacecraft, a 1-meter cube with two long solar panels, is elegantly simple, equipped with a telescope called DRACO, hydrazine maneuvering thrusters, a xenon-fueled <a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/hall-effect-sensor" target="_self">ion engine</a> and a navigation system called <a href="https://www.jhuapl.edu/interactive/navigating-double-asteroid-redirection-test-on-its-own" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">SMART Nav</a>. It was <a href="https://blogs.nasa.gov/dart/2021/11/24/nasa-spacex-launch-dart-first-planetary-defense-test-mission/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">launched by a SpaceX rocket</a> in November. About 4 hours and 90,000 km before the hoped-for impact, SMART Nav will take over control of the spacecraft, using optical images from the telescope. Didymos, the larger object, should be a point of light by then; Dimorphos, the intended target, will probably not appear as more than one pixel until about 50 minutes before impact. DART will send one image per second back to Earth, but the spacecraft is autonomous; signals from the ground, 38 light-seconds away, would be useless for steering as the ship races in.</p><p class="shortcode-media shortcode-media-rebelmouse-image">
<img alt="A golden cubesat with a bright light and lines" class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="9c26df105c1880ce4a232d43aff8782b" data-rm-shortcode-name="rebelmouse-image" id="0d793" loading="lazy" src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/a-golden-cubesat-with-a-bright-light-and-lines.jpg?id=31804128&width=980"/>
<small class="image-media media-caption" placeholder="Add Photo Caption...">The DART spacecraft separated from its SpaceX Falcon 9 launch vehicle, 55 minutes after liftoff from Vandenberg Space Force Base, in California, 24 November 2021. In this image from the rocket, the spacecraft had not yet unfurled its solar panels.</small><small class="image-media media-photo-credit" placeholder="Add Photo Credit...">NASA</small></p><p>What’s more, nobody knows the shape or consistency of little Dimorphos. Is it a solid boulder or a loose cluster of rubble? Is it smooth or craggy, round or elongated? “We’re trying to hit the center,” says <a href="https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/author/37088208152" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Evan Smith</a>, the deputy mission systems engineer at the <a href="https://www.jhuapl.edu/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Johns Hopkins Applied Physics Laboratory</a>, which is running DART. “We don’t want to overcorrect for some mountain or crater on one side that’s throwing an odd shadow or something.”</p><p>So on final approach, DART will cover 800 km without any steering. Thruster firings could blur the last images of Dimorphos’s surface, which scientists want to study. Impact should be imaged from about 50 km away by an Italian-made minisatellite, called <a href="https://www.asi.it/en/planets-stars-universe/solar-system-and-beyond/liciacube/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">LICIACube</a>, which DART released two weeks ago.</p><p>“In the minutes following impact, I know everybody is going be high fiving on the engineering side,” said <a href="https://www.nasa.gov/planetarydefense/organization" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Tom Statler</a>, DART’s program scientist at NASA, “but I’m going be imagining all the cool stuff that is actually going on on the asteroid, with a crater being dug and ejecta being blasted off.”</p><p>There is, of course, a possibility that DART will miss, in which case there should be enough fuel on board to allow engineers to go after a backup target. But an advantage of the Didymos-Dimorphos pair is that it should help in calculating how much effect the impact had. Telescopes on Earth (plus the Hubble and Webb space telescopes) may struggle to measure infinitesimal changes in the orbit of Dimorphos around the sun; it should be easier to see how much its orbit around Didymos is affected. The simplest measurement may be of the changing brightness of the double asteroid, as Dimorphos moves in front of or behind its partner, perhaps more quickly or slowly than it did before impact.</p><p>“We are moving an asteroid,” said Statler. “We are changing the motion of a natural celestial body in space. Humanity’s never done that before.”</p>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 23 Sep 2022 15:52:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spectrum.ieee.org/planetary-protection-nasa-dart</guid><category>Asteroids</category><category>Nasa</category><category>Planetary protection</category><dc:creator>Ned Potter</dc:creator><media:content medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/a-cubesat-with-2-large-solar-panels-in-front-of-two-grey-asteroids-in-space-with-a-smaller-cubesat-nearby.jpg?id=31804118&amp;width=980"></media:content></item><item><title>Aligning the Eyes of the Universe Machine</title><link>https://spectrum.ieee.org/james-webb-space-telescope-mirror</link><description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/a-person-on-a-cherry-picker-next-to-the-james-webb-space-telescope.jpg?id=31637785&width=2000&height=1500&coordinates=0%2C0%2C0%2C0"/><br/><br/><p>
	The <a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/collections/james-webb-telescope/" target="_self">James Webb Space Telescope</a>, in just a few months of operation, has begun to change our view of the universe. Its images—more detailed than what was possible before—show space aglow with galaxies, some of them formed very soon after the big bang.
</p><p>
	None of this would be possible without the work of a team led by <a href="https://www.researchgate.net/scientific-contributions/D-Scott-Acton-2005553350" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Scott Acton</a>, the lead <a href="https://webb.nasa.gov/content/about/innovations/wavefront.html" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">wavefront sensing and control</a> scientist for the Webb at <a href="https://www.ball.com/aerospace/programs/astrophysics/webb" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Ball Aerospace & Technologies</a> in Colorado. He and his colleagues <a href="https://citeseerx.ist.psu.edu/viewdoc/download?doi=10.1.1.823.4123&rep=rep1&type=pdf" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">developed</a> <a href="https://www.jwst.nasa.gov/resources/JWSTTech.pdf" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">the systems</a> that align the 18 separate segments of the Webb’s primary mirror with its smaller secondary mirror and science instruments. To produce clear images in the infrared wavelengths the telescope uses, the segments have to be within <a href="https://jwst-docs.stsci.edu/jwst-observatory-hardware/jwst-wavefront-sensing-and-control" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">tens of nanometers</a> of the shape specified in the spacecraft design.
</p><p>
	Acton grew up in Wyoming and spent more than 20 years on the Webb team. <em>IEEE Spectrum</em> spoke with Acton after his team had finished aligning the telescope’s optics in space. This transcript has been edited for clarity and brevity.
</p><p>
<strong>Tell your story. What got you started?</strong>
</p><p>
<strong>Scott Acton:</strong> When I was seven-years-old, my dad brought home a new television. And he gave me the old television to take apart. I was just enthralled by what I saw inside this television. And from that moment on I was defined by electronics. You look inside an old television and there are mechanisms, there are smells and colors and sights and for a seven-year-old kid, it was just the most amazing thing I’d ever seen.
</p><p>
	Fast-forward 25 years and I’m working in the field of adaptive optics. And eventually that led to wavefront sensing and controls, which led to the Webb telescope.
</p><p class="shortcode-media shortcode-media-rebelmouse-image">
<img alt="sky with bright stars and gaseous activity" class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="cf0f79e1e2e89612e8fa9b62102b382e" data-rm-shortcode-name="rebelmouse-image" id="01a79" loading="lazy" src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/sky-with-bright-stars-and-gaseous-activity.jpg?id=31638587&width=980"/>
<small class="image-media media-caption" placeholder="Add Photo Caption...">Called the Cosmic Cliffs, Webb’s seemingly three-dimensional picture looks like craggy mountains on a moonlit evening. In reality, it is the edge of the giant, gaseous cavity within NGC 3324, and the tallest “peaks” in this image are about 7 light-years high.</small><small class="image-media media-photo-credit" placeholder="Add Photo Credit..."> NASA/ESA/CSA/STScI</small>
</p><p>
<strong>Talk about your work getting the telescope ready for flight. You worked on it for more than 20 years.</strong>
</p><p>
<strong>Acton: </strong>Well, we had to invent all of the wavefront sensing and controls. None of that technology really existed in 2001, so we started from the ground up with concepts and simple experiments. Then more complicated, very complicated experiments and eventually something known as TRL 6 technology—Technology Readiness Level 6—which demonstrated that we could do this in a flightlike environment. And then it was a question of taking this technology, algorithms, understanding it and implementing it into very robust procedures, documentation, and software, so that it could then be applied on the flight telescope.
</p><p>
<strong>What was it like finally to launch?</strong>
</p><p>
<strong>Acton:</strong> Well, I’ve got to say, there was a lot of nervousness, at least on my part. I was thinking we had a 70 percent chance of mission success, or something like that. It’s like sending your kid off to college—this instrument that we’d been looking at and thinking about.
</p><p>
	The Ariane 5 vehicle is so reliable. I didn’t think there was going to be any problem with it, but deployment starts, basically, minutes after launch. So, for me, the place to be was at a computer console [at the Space Telescope Science Institute in Baltimore].
</p><p>
<strong>And then there were a lot of things that had to work.</strong>
</p><p>
<strong>Acton:</strong> Yes, right. But there are some things that that are interesting. They have these things called nonexplosive actuators [used to secure the spacecraft during launch]. There are about 130 of them. And you actually can’t test them. You build them and they get used, basically, once. If you do reuse one, well, it’s now a different actuator because you have to solder it back together. So you can’t qualify the part, but what you can do is qualify the process.
</p><p>
	We could have still had a mission if some didn’t fire, but most of them were absolutely necessary for the success of the mission. So just ask yourself, let’s suppose you want to have a 95 percent chance of success. What number raised to the 130th power is equal to 0.95? That number is basically one. These things had to be perfect.
</p><p class="pull-quote">
	I remember walking home one night, talking on the phone to my wife, Heidi, and saying, “If I’m wrong about this I’ve just completely screwed up the telescope.” She said, “Scott, that’s why you’re there.” That was her way of telling me to cowboy up. The responsibility had to come down to somebody and in that moment, it was me.
</p><p>
<strong>I think the public perception was that the Webb was in very good shape and the in-flight setup all went very well. Would you say that’s accurate?</strong>
</p><p>
<strong>Acton: </strong>Early on in the mission there were hiccups, but other than that, I’d say things just went beyond our wildest expectations. Part of that comes down to the fact that my team and I had commissioned the telescope 100 times in simulations. And we always made it a little harder. I think that served us well because when we got to the real telescope, it was quite robust. It just worked.
</p><p>
<strong>Take us through the process of aligning the telescope.</strong>
</p><p>
<strong>Acton: </strong>The first image we got back from the telescope was 2 February, in the middle of the night. Most people had gone home, but I was there, and a lot of other people were too. We just pointed the telescope at the Large Magellanic Cloud, which has lots and lots of stars in it, and took images on the near-infrared cameras. People were really happy to see these images because they were looking basically to make sure that the science instruments worked.
</p><p>
	But some of us were really concerned with that image, because you could see some very significant astigmatism—stronger than we were expecting to see from our simulations. Later we would learn that the telescope’s secondary mirror was off in translation—about 1.5 millimeters along the deployment axis and about a millimeter in the other axis. And the primary mirror segments were clocked a bit from the perfectly aligned state.
</p><p>
<a href="https://jwst.nasa.gov/content/meetTheTeam/people/feinberg.html" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Lee Feinberg</a>, the telescope lead at NASA Goddard, texted me and said, “Scott, why can’t you just simulate this to see if you can get some images that bad?” So that morning I ran a simulation and was able to reproduce almost exactly what we were seeing in these images. We realized that we were not going to have any major problems with the wavefront.
</p><p><strong>Describe the cadence of your work during commissioning. What would a day be like?</strong>
</p><p>
<strong>Acton:</strong> One of the rules we set up very early on was that in terms of wavefront sensing and control, we would always have two people sitting in front of the computers at any given time. Anytime anything significant happened, I always wanted to make sure that I was there, so I got an apartment [near the institute in Baltimore]. From my door to the door of the of the Mission Operations Center was a 7-minute walk.
</p><p class="shortcode-media shortcode-media-rebelmouse-image">
<img alt="sky with bright star in middle with gases" class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="9e7e4d9499e9901a9c1bd852b8b57d33" data-rm-shortcode-name="rebelmouse-image" id="a9903" loading="lazy" src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/sky-with-bright-star-in-middle-with-gases.jpg?id=31638681&width=980"/>
<small class="image-media media-caption" placeholder="Add Photo Caption...">In this mosaic image stretching 340 light-years across, Webb’s Near-Infrared Camera (NIRCam) displays the Tarantula Nebula star-forming region in a new light, including tens of thousands of never-before-seen young stars that were previously shrouded in cosmic dust.</small><small class="image-media media-photo-credit" placeholder="Add Photo Credit...">NASA/ESA/CSA/STScI/Webb ERO Production Team</small>
</p><p>
	There were certainly times during the process where it had a very large pucker factor, if you will. We couldn’t point the telescope reliably at the very beginning. And a lot of our software, for the early steps of commissioning, depended on the immutability of telescope pointing. We wanted to have the telescope repeatedly pointed to within a couple of arc-seconds and it was closer to 20 or 30. Because of that, some of the initial moves to align the telescope had to be calculated, if you will, by hand.
</p><p>
	I remember walking home one night, talking on the phone to my wife, Heidi, and saying, “If I’m wrong about this I’ve just completely screwed up the telescope.” She said, “Scott, that’s why you’re there.” That was her way of telling me to cowboy up. The responsibility had to come down to somebody and in that moment, it was me.
</p><p>
	But when the result came back, we could see the images. We pointed the telescope at a bright isolated star and then we could see, one at a time, 18 spots appearing in the middle of our main science detector. I remember a colleague saying, “I now believe we’re going to completely align the telescope.” He felt in his mind that if we could get past that step, that everything else was downhill.
</p><p>
	You’re trying to piece together the universe. It’s hard to get it right, and very easy to make mistakes. But we did it.
</p><p>
<strong>Building the Webb was, of course, a big, complicated project. Do you think there are any particular lessons to be drawn from it that people in the future might find useful?</strong>
</p><p>
<strong>Acton:</strong> Here are a couple of really big ones that apply to wavefront sensing and control. One is that there are multiple institutions involved—Northrop Grumman, Ball Aerospace, the Goddard Space Flight Center, the Space Telescope Science Institute—and the complication of having all these institutional lines. It could have been very, very difficult to navigate. So very early on we decided not to have any lines. We were a completely badgeless team. Anybody could talk to anybody. If someone said, “No, I think this is wrong, you should do it this way,” even if they didn’t necessarily have contractual responsibility, everybody listened.
</p><p>
	Another big lesson we learned was about the importance of the interplay between experimentation and simulation. We built a one-sixth scale model, a fully functional optical model of the telescope, and it’s still working. It allowed us, very early on, to know what was going to be difficult. Then we could address those issues in simulation. That understanding, the interplay between experimentation and modeling and simulations, was absolutely essential.
</p><p>
<strong>Recognizing of course, that it’s very early, do you yet have a favorite image?</strong>
</p><p>
<strong>Acton:</strong> My favorite image, so far, was one that was taken during the last real wavefront activity that we did as part of commissioning. It was called a thermal slew test. The telescope has a large <a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/james-webb-telescope-sunshield" target="_self">sunshield</a>, but the sunshield can be at different angles with respect to the sun. So to make sure it was stable, we aimed it at a bright star we used as a guide star, put it in one orientation, and stayed there for five or six days. And then we switched to a different orientation for five or six days. It turned out to be quite stable. But how do you know that the telescope wasn’t rolling about the guide star? To check this, we took a series of test images with the redundant fine-guidance sensor. As you can imagine, when you have a 6-1/2 meter telescope at L2 away from any competing light sources that is cooled to 50 kelvins, yes, it is sensitive. Even just one 20-minute exposure is going to just have unbelievable detail regarding the deep universe. Imagine what happens if you take 100 of those images and average them together. We came up with an image of just some random part of the sky.
</p><p class="shortcode-media shortcode-media-rebelmouse-image">
<img alt="james webb telescope image of bright lights against a dark background" class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="d6e5ebd7d02699554f88c146434fd49c" data-rm-shortcode-name="rebelmouse-image" id="5a840" loading="lazy" src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/james-webb-telescope-image-of-bright-lights-against-a-dark-background.jpg?id=31638422&width=980"/>
<small class="image-media media-caption" placeholder="Add Photo Caption...">Scott Acton’s favorite Webb image: A test image of a random part of the sky, shot with the Webb’s fine-guidance sensor. The points with six-pointed diffraction patterns are stars; all other points are galaxies. </small><small class="image-media media-photo-credit" placeholder="Add Photo Credit...">NASA/CSA/FGS</small>
</p><p>
	I sent this image to <a href="https://www.astro.ucla.edu/~larkin/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">James Larkin</a> at UCLA, and he looked at it and estimated that that single image had 15,000 galaxies in it. Every one of those galaxies probably has between 100 [billion] and 200 billion stars.
</p><p>
	I don’t talk about religion too much when it comes to this, but I must have had in my mind a Biblical reference to the stars singing. I pictured all of those galaxies as singing, as if this was a way for the universe to express joy that after all these years, we could finally see them. It was quite an emotional experience for me and for many people.
</p><p>
<strong>You realized that there was so much out there, and you weren’t even really looking for it yet? You were still phasing the telescope?</strong>
</p><p>
<strong>Acton:</strong> That’s right. I guess I I’m not sure what I expected. I figured you’d just see dark sky. Well, there <em>is</em> no dark sky. Dark sky is a myth. Galaxies are everywhere.
</p><p>
	Finally, we got to our first diffraction-limited image [with the telescope calibrated for science observations for the first time]. And that’s the way the telescope is operating now.
</p><p>
	Several days later, about 70 of us got together—astronomers, engineers, and other team members. A member of the team—his name is Anthony Galyer—and I had gone halves several years earlier and purchased a bottle of cognac from 1906, the year that James Webb was born. We toasted James Webb and the telescope that bears his name.
</p>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2022 17:39:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spectrum.ieee.org/james-webb-space-telescope-mirror</guid><category>Jwst</category><category>Telescopes</category><category>Wavefront sensing</category><category>Simulations</category><category>Control systems</category><category>Optics</category><dc:creator>Ned Potter</dc:creator><media:content medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/a-person-on-a-cherry-picker-next-to-the-james-webb-space-telescope.jpg?id=31637785&amp;width=980"></media:content></item><item><title>MOXIE Shows How to Make Oxygen on Mars</title><link>https://spectrum.ieee.org/making-oxygen-on-mars</link><description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/image-of-mars-perseverance-rover-with-scientific-instruments-on-extended-robotic-arm.jpg?id=31612448&width=2000&height=1500&coordinates=0%2C0%2C0%2C0"/><br/><br/><p><sub></sub>Planning for the return journey is an integral part of the preparations for a crewed Mars mission. Astronauts will require a total mass of about 50 tonnes of rocket propellent for the ascent vehicle that will lift them off the planet’s surface, including 31 tonnes of oxygen approximately. The less popular option is for crewed missions to carry the required oxygen themselves. But scientists are optimistic that it could instead be produced from the carbon dioxide–rich Martian atmosphere itself, using a system called <a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/moxie-might-be-the-most-exciting-thing-perseverance-has-brought-to-mars" target="_self"><u>MOXIE</u></a>.</p><p>The <a href="https://mars.nasa.gov/mars2020/spacecraft/instruments/moxie/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"><u>Mars Oxygen ISRU (In-Situ Resource Utilization) Experiment</u></a> is an 18-kilogram unit housed within the Perseverance rover on Mars. The unit is “the size of a toaster,” adds <a href="https://aeroastro.mit.edu/people/jeffrey-a-hoffman/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"><u>Jeffrey Hoffman</u></a>, professor of aerospace engineering at MIT. Its job is to <a href="https://mars.nasa.gov/mars2020/spacecraft/instruments/moxie/for-scientists/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"><u>electrochemically break down carbon dioxide</u></a> collected from the Martian atmosphere into oxygen and carbon monoxide. It also tests the purity of the oxygen. </p><p>Between February 2021, when it arrived on Mars aboard the Perseverance, and the end of the year, MOXIE has had several successful test runs. According to a review of the system by Hoffman and colleagues, published in <a href="https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/sciadv.abp8636" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"><u><em>Science Advances</em></u></a>, it has demonstrated its ability to produce oxygen during both night and day, when temperatures can vary by over 100 ºC. The generation and purity rates of oxygen also meet requirements to produce rocket propellent and for breathing. The authors assert that a scaled-up version of MOXIE could produce the required oxygen for lift-off as well as for the astronauts to breathe.</p><p class="pull-quote">Next question: How to power any oxygen-producing factories that NASA can land on Mars? Perhaps via NASA’s Kilopower fission reactors? </p><p>MOXIE is a first step toward a much larger and more complex system to support the human exploration of Mars. The researchers estimate a required generation rate of 2 to 3 kilograms per hour, compared with the current MOXIE rate of 6 to 8 grams per hour, to produce enough oxygen for lift-off for a crew arriving 26 months later. “So we’re talking about a system that’s a couple of hundred times bigger than MOXIE,” Hoffman says. </p><p>They calculate this rate accounting for eight months to get to Mars, followed by some time to set up the system. “We figure you'd probably have maybe 14 months to make all the oxygen.” Further, he says, the produced oxygen would have to be liquefied to be used a rocket propellant, something the current version of MOXIE doesn’t do.</p><p>MOXIE also currently faces several design constraints because, says Hoffman, a former astronaut, “our only ride to Mars was inside the Perseverance rover.” This limited the amount of power available to operate the unit, the amount of heat they could produce, the volume and the mass. </p><p>“MOXIE does not work nearly as efficiently as a stand-alone system that was specifically designed would,” says Hoffman. Most of the time, it’s turned off. “Every time we want to make oxygen, we have to heat it up to 800 ºC, so most of the energy goes into heating it up and running the compressor, whereas in a well-designed stand-alone system, most of the energy will go into the actual electrolysis, into actually producing the oxygen.”</p><p>However, there are still many kinks to iron out for the scaling-up process. To begin with, any oxygen-producing system will need lots of power. Hoffman thinks nuclear power is the most likely option, maybe NASA’s <a href="https://www.nasa.gov/directorates/spacetech/kilopower" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"><u>Kilopower fission reactors</u></a>. The setup and the cabling would certainly be challenging, he says. “You’re going to have to launch to all of these nuclear reactors, and of course, they’re not going to be in exactly the same place as the [other] units,” he says. "So, robotically, you’re going to have to connect to the electrical cables to bring power to the oxygen-producing unit.”</p><p>Then there is the solid oxide electrolysis units, which Hoffman points out are carefully machined systems. Fortunately, the company that makes them, <a href="https://oxeonenergy.com/solutions/solid-oxide-electrolysis-cells" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"><u>OxEon</u></a>, has already designed, built, and tested a full-scale unit, a hundred times bigger than the one on MOXIE. “Several of those units would be required to produce oxygen at the quantities that we need,” Hoffman says. </p><p>He also adds that at present, there is no redundancy built into MOXIE. If any part fails, the whole system dies. “If you’re counting on a system to produce oxygen for rocket propellant and for breathing, you need very high reliability, which means you’re going to need quite a few redundant units.”</p><p>Moreover, the system has to be pretty much autonomous, Hoffman says. “It has to be able to monitor itself, run itself.” For testing purposes, every time MOXIE is powered up, there is plenty of time to plan. A full-scale MOXIE system, though, would have to run continuously, and for that it has to be able to adjust automatically to changes in the Mars atmosphere, which can vary by a factor of two over a year, and between nighttime and daytime temperature differences.</p>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Sep 2022 15:27:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spectrum.ieee.org/making-oxygen-on-mars</guid><category>Mars exploration</category><category>Space flight</category><category>Space</category><category>Mars</category><dc:creator>Payal Dhar</dc:creator><media:content medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/image-of-mars-perseverance-rover-with-scientific-instruments-on-extended-robotic-arm.jpg?id=31612448&amp;width=980"></media:content></item><item><title>Apple Kicks Off the Cell-Calls-From-Space Race</title><link>https://spectrum.ieee.org/5g-from-space-apple-spacex</link><description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/man-talking-on-apple-smartphone.jpg?id=31529965&width=2000&height=1500&coordinates=0%2C0%2C0%2C0"/><br/><br/><p>The race to deliver cellular calls from space passes two milestones this month and saw one major announcement last month. First, <a href="https://www.apple.com/iphone-14/" target="_blank">Apple will offer emergency satellite messaging on two of its latest iPhone models</a>, the company announced on Wednesday. Second, AST SpaceMobile plans a launch on Saturday, 10 September, of an experimental satellite to test full-fledged satellite 5G service. In addition, T-Mobile USA and SpaceX intend to offer their own messaging and limited data service via the second generation of SpaceX’s Starlink satellite constellation, as <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Qzli-Ww26Qs" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">the two companies announced on 25 August</a>. </p><p>Each contender is taking a different approach to space-based cellular service. The Apple offering <a href="https://www.lightreading.com/5g/globalstars-mystery-deepens/d/d-id/771369https://investors.globalstar.com/node/14431/html" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">uses the existing satellite bandwidth</a> Globalstar once used for messaging offerings, but without the need for a satellite-specific handset. The AST project and another company, <a href="https://lynk.global/" target="_blank">Lynk Global</a>, would use a dedicated network of satellites with larger-than-normal antennas to produce a 4G, 5G, and someday 6G cellular signal compatible with any existing 4G-compatible phone (as detailed in <a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/5g-satellite" target="_blank">other recent <em>IEEE</em> <em>Spectrum</em></a><a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/5g-satellite"> coverage</a> of space-based 5G offerings). Assuming regulatory approval is forthcoming, the technology would work first in equatorial regions and then across more of the planet as these providers expand their satellite constellations. T-Mobile and Starlink’s offering would work in the former PCS band in the United States. SpaceX, like AST and Lynk, would need to negotiate access to spectrum on a country-by-country basis.</p><p>Apple’s competitors are unlikely to see commercial operations before 2024.</p><p class="pull-quote">“Regulators have not decided on the power limits from space, what concerns there are about interference, especially across national borders. There’s a whole bunch of regulatory issues that simply haven’t been thought about to date.”<br/>—Tim Farrar, telecommunications consultant</p><p>The T-Mobile–Starlink announcement is “in some ways an endorsement” of AST and Lynk’s proposition, and “in other ways a great threat,” says telecommunications consultant Tim Farrar of <a href="http://www.tmfassociates.com/Principals.html" target="_blank">Tim Farrar Associates</a> in Menlo Park, Calif. AST and Lynk have so far told investors they expect their national mobile network operator partners to charge per use or per day, but T-Mobile announced that they plan to include satellite messaging in the 1,900-megahertz range in their existing services. Apple said their Emergency SOS via Satellite service would be free the first two years for U.S. and Canadian iPhone 14 buyers, but did not say what it would cost after that. For now, the Globalstar satellites it is using cannot offer the kind of broadband bandwidth AST has promised, but Globalstar has reported to investors orders for new satellites that might offer new capabilities, including new gateways.</p><p>Even under the best conditions—a clear view of the sky—users will need 15 seconds to send a message via Apple’s service. They will also have to follow onscreen guidance to keep the device pointed at the satellites they are using. Light foliage can cause the same message to take more than a minute to send. Ashley Williams, a satellite engineer at Apple who recorded the service’s announcement, also mentioned a data-compression algorithm and a series of rescue-related suggested auto-replies intended to minimize the amount of data that users would need to send during a rescue.</p><p>Meanwhile, AST SpaceMobile says it aims to launch an experimental satellite Saturday, 10 September, to test its cellular broadband offering.</p><p>Last month’s T-Mobile-SpaceX <a href="https://www.t-mobile.com/news/un-carrier/t-mobile-takes-coverage-above-and-beyond-with-spacex" target="_blank">announcement</a> “helped the world focus attention on the huge market opportunity for SpaceMobile, the only planned space-based cellular broadband network. BlueWalker 3, which has a 693 sq ft array, is scheduled for launch within weeks!” <a href="https://twitter.com/AbelAvellan/status/1562987060977614848?s=20&t=0CE866Ew1r_F2YjDQCR77Q" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">tweeted</a> AST SpaceMobile CEO Abel Avellan on 25 August. The size of the array matters because AST SpaceMobile has so far indicated in its applications for experimental satellite licenses that it intends to use lower radio frequencies (700–900 MHz) with less propagation loss but that require antennas much larger than conventional satellites carry.</p><p>The size of the array will also make it more reflective, which has raised concerns among astronomers. The size of Starlink’s planned constellation has already provoked complaints among astronomers because it will interfere with their ability to observe space. <em>Sky & Telescope</em> magazine <a href="https://skyandtelescope.org/astronomy-news/as-bluewalker-satellites-join-a-brightening-sky-heres-how-you-can-help/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">published on 1 September a call</a> for both professional and amateur astronomers to observe the growing constellations of satellites to document the interference. Professional astronomy societies have <a href="https://aas.org/posts/advocacy/2021/08/impacts-large-satellite-constellations-astronomy-live-updates" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">lobbied U.S. government agencies and Congress on the issue and met with SpaceX officials in May to discuss a recent change that brightened satellites by 0.5 visual magnitudes</a>. </p><p>So far government agencies have issued licenses for thousands of low-Earth-orbiting satellites, which have the biggest impact on astronomers. Even with the constellations starting to form, satellite-cellular telecommunications companies are still open to big regulatory risks. “Regulators have not decided on the power limits from space, what concerns there are about interference, especially across national borders. There’s a whole bunch of regulatory issues that simply haven’t been thought about to date,” Farrar says.</p><p>For a hiker with a twisted ankle, a messaging service that takes a while to connect and twinkles in and out of service as satellites fly by may be better than nothing, but early space-based cellular <a href="https://frankrayal.com/2022/08/29/t-mobile-spacex-direct-satellite-to-handset-service-lots-of-hype-and-little-reality/" target="_blank">will not be a seamless way to connect to video calls from out at sea</a>.</p><p>“User cooperation is in my view the single most critical aspect of whether this service will attract mass-market usage or people willing to pay a significant amount for this service,” Farrar says.</p>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Sep 2022 14:18:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spectrum.ieee.org/5g-from-space-apple-spacex</guid><category>5g</category><category>Satellite broadband</category><category>Apple</category><category>Spacex</category><dc:creator>Lucas Laursen</dc:creator><media:content medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/man-talking-on-apple-smartphone.jpg?id=31529965&amp;width=980"></media:content></item><item><title>China’s Moon Missions Shadow NASA Artemis’s Pace</title><link>https://spectrum.ieee.org/china-moon-mission-artemis</link><description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/an-image-showing-the-long-march-5-y5-rocket-at-the-wenchang-spacecraft-launch-site-in-south-china-s-hainan-province.jpg?id=31360306&width=2000&height=1500&coordinates=267%2C0%2C267%2C0"/><br/><br/><p>This past weekend, NASA scrubbed the Artemis I uncrewed mission to the moon and back. <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2022-09-03/nasa-delays-artemis-launch-due-to-hydrogen-leak" target="_blank">Reportedly</a>, the space agency will try again to launch the inaugural moon mission featuring the gargantuan Space Launch System (SLS) at the end of this month or sometime in October. Meanwhile, half a world away, China is progressing on its own step-by-step program to put both robotic and, eventually, crewed spacecraft on the lunar surface and keep pace with NASA-led achievements.</p><p>Asia’s rapidly growing space power has already made a number of impressive lunar leaps but will need to build on these in the coming years. Ambitious sample-return missions, landings at the lunar south pole, testing the ability to 3D print using materials from regolith, and finally sending astronauts on a short-term visit to our celestial neighbor are in the cards before the end of the decade.</p><p>The next step, expected around 2024, is <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chang%27e_6" target="_blank">Chang’e-6</a>: an unprecedented attempt to collect rock samples from the far side of the moon.</p><p>The mission will build on two recent major space achievements. In 2019, China became the first country to safely land a spacecraft on the <a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/china-gears-up-for-ambitious-landing-on-the-moons-far-side" target="_self">far side of the moon</a>, a hemisphere which cannot be seen from Earth—as the moon is <a href="https://www.sciencefocus.com/space/what-is-tidal-locking/" target="_blank">tidally locked</a>. The mission was made possible by a <a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/pioneering-astronomy-experiment-begins-beyond-the-moon" target="_self">relay satellite</a> out beyond the moon at Earth-moon Lagrange point 2, where it can bounce signals between <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chang%27e_4" target="_blank">Chang’e-4</a> and ground stations in China.</p><p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chang%27e_5" target="_blank">Chang’e-5</a> in 2020 performed the first sampling of lunar material in over four decades. The complex, four-spacecraft mission used an orbiter, lander, ascent vehicle, and return capsule to successfully deliver 1.731 grams of lunar rocks to Earth. The automated rendezvous and docking in lunar orbit of the orbiter and ascent spacecraft was also seen as a test of the technology for getting astronauts off the moon and back to Earth.</p><p>Chang’e-6 will again attempt to collect new samples, this time from the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/South_Pole%E2%80%93Aitken_basin" target="_blank">South pole-Aitken basin</a>, a massive and ancient impact crater on the far side of the moon. The science return of such a mission could likewise be huge as its rocks have the potential to answer some significant questions about the moon’s geological past, says planetary scientist <a href="http://directory.manchester.ac.uk/advanced.php?dn=cn%3DKatherine+Joy%2Bumanroleid%3D306901%2Cou%3DDepartment+of+Earth+and+Environmental+Sciences%2Cou%3DSchool+of+Natural+Sciences%2Cou%3DFaculty+of+Science+and+Engineering%2Cou%3DPeople%2Co%3DUniversity+of+Manchester%2Cc%3DGB&employeeType=STAFF&action=read&form_input=Submit" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Katherine Joy</a> of the <a href="https://www.manchester.ac.uk/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">University of Manchester</a>, in England.</p><p>“We think that the basin-formation event was so large that the moon’s mantle could have been excavated from tens of kilometers deep,” says Joy. Fragments of this mantle material originating from deep in the moon would help us to understand how the Moon differentiated early in its history, the nature of its interior, and how volcanism on the far side of the moon is different or similar to that on the nearside.</p><p><a href="http://www.cnsa.gov.cn/english/n6465652/n6465653/c6813273/content.html" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Chang’e-7</a>, also scheduled for 2024, will look at a different set of questions geared toward lunar resources. It will target the lunar south pole, a region where NASA’s Artemis 3 crewed mission is also <a href="https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/nasa-unveils-candidate-landing-sites-for-artemis-astronauts/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">looking to land</a>.</p><p>The mission will involve a flotilla of spacecraft, including a new relay satellite, an orbiter, lander, rover and a small “hopping” spacecraft designed to<a href="https://spacenews.com/china-targets-permanently-shadowed-regions-at-lunar-south-pole/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"> inspect permanently shadowed craters</a> which are thought to <a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/rocket-mining-system-could-blast-ice-from-lunar-craters" target="_self">contain water ice</a> which could be used in the future to provide breathable oxygen, rocket fuel, or drinking water to lunar explorers.</p><p>Following this <a href="https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/planetary/lunar/cnsa_moon_future.html" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Chang’e-8</a> is expected to launch around 2027 to test in situ resource utilization and conduct other experiments and technology tests such as oxygen extraction and 3D printing related to building a permanent lunar base—for both robots and crew—in the 2030s, named the <a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/china-aims-for-a-permanent-moon-base-in-the-2030s" target="_self">International Lunar Research Station</a> (ILRS).</p><p>The upcoming Chang’e-6, 7 and 8 missions are expected to launch on China’s largest current rocket, the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Long_March_5" target="_blank">Long March 5</a>. But, as with NASA and Artemis, China will need its own megarockets to make human lunar exploration and ultimately, perhaps, crewed lunar bases a reality.</p><p>In part in reaction to the achievements of SpaceX, the China Aerospace Science and Technology Corporation (CASC), the country’s main space contractor, is developing a <a href="https://www.globaltimes.cn/page/202208/1273481.shtml" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">new rocket </a>specifically for launching astronauts beyond low Earth orbit.</p><p>The “new generation crew launch vehicle” will essentially bundle three Long March 5 core stages together (which will be no mean feat of engineering) while also improving the performance of its kerosene engines. The result will be a roughly 90-meter-tall rocket resembling a Long March version of SpaceX’s <a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/tag/falcon-heavy" target="_self">Falcon Heavy</a>, capable of sending 27 tonnes of payload into translunar injection.</p><p>Two launches of the rocket will by 2030, according to leading <a href="https://spacenews.com/chinese-crewed-moon-landing-possible-by-2030-says-senior-space-figure/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Chinese space officials</a>, be able to put a pair of astronauts on the moon for a 6-hour stay. Such a mission also requires developing a <a href="https://spacenews.com/china-is-working-on-a-lander-for-human-moon-missions/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">lunar lander</a> and a <a href="https://www.space.com/china-displays-next-generation-spaceship" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">new spacecraft</a> capable of keeping astronauts safe in deep space.</p><p>For building infrastructure on the moon, China is looking to the future <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Long_March_9" target="_blank">Long March 9</a>, an SLS-class rocket capable of sending 50 tonnes into translunar injection. The project will require CASC to make breakthroughs in a number of areas, including manufacturing new, <a href="https://mp.weixin.qq.com/s/cy6N-3JCHE_HFaxG4nXA1Q" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">wider rocket bodies</a> of up to 10 meters in diameter, mastering massive, <a href="http://www.spacechina.com/n25/n2014789/n2014804/c3150470/content.html" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">higher-thrust rocket engines,</a> and building a new launch complex at Wenchang, Hainan island, to handle the monster.</p><p>Once again NASA is leading humanity’s journey to the moon, but China’s steady accumulation of capabilities and long-term ambitions means it will likely not be far behind.</p>]]></description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2022 16:56:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spectrum.ieee.org/china-moon-mission-artemis</guid><category>China space exploration</category><category>Lunar exploration</category><category>Lunar landing</category><category>Lunar base</category><dc:creator>Andrew Jones</dc:creator><media:content medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/an-image-showing-the-long-march-5-y5-rocket-at-the-wenchang-spacecraft-launch-site-in-south-china-s-hainan-province.jpg?id=31360306&amp;width=980"></media:content></item><item><title>NASA’s Artemis I Revives the Moonshot</title><link>https://spectrum.ieee.org/artemis-1-revives-moonshot</link><description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/artemis-i-on-launch-pad-39b-at-kennedy-space-center-at-dawn.jpg?id=31246740&width=2000&height=1500&coordinates=114%2C0%2C114%2C0"/><br/><br/><p><br/></p><p><em><strong>Update 5 Sept.</strong>: For now, NASA’s giant Artemis I remains on the ground after two launch attempts scrubbed by a hydrogen leak and a balky engine sensor. Mission managers say Artemis will fly when everything's ready—but haven't yet specified whether that might be in late September or in mid-October.</em></p><p>“When you look at the rocket, it looks almost retro,” said <a href="https://www.nasa.gov/feature/nasa-administrator-bill-nelson/" target="_blank">Bill Nelson</a>, the administrator of NASA. “Looks like we’re looking back toward the Saturn V. But it’s a totally different, new, highly sophisticated—more sophisticated—rocket, and spacecraft.”</p><p><a href="https://www.nasa.gov/specials/artemis/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Artemis</a>, powered by the <a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/nasas-space-launch-system-will-lift-off" target="_self">Space Launch System</a> rocket, is America’s first attempt to send astronauts to the moon since <a href="https://history.nasa.gov/SP-4029/Apollo_17a_Summary.htm" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Apollo 17</a> in 1972, and technology has taken giant leaps since then. On <a href="https://www.nasa.gov/artemis-1" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Artemis I</a>, the first test flight, mission managers say they are taking the SLS, with its uncrewed <a href="https://www.nasa.gov/exploration/systems/orion/about/index.html" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Orion</a> spacecraft up top, and “stressing it beyond what it is designed for”—the better to ensure safe flights when astronauts make their first landings, currently targeted to begin with <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Artemis_3" target="_blank">Artemis III</a> in 2025.</p><p>But Nelson is right: The rocket <em>is</em> retro in many ways, borrowing heavily from the space shuttles America flew for 30 years, and from the Apollo-Saturn V.</p><p>Much of Artemis’s hardware is refurbished: Its four main engines, and parts of its two strap-on boosters, all flew before on shuttle missions. The rocket’s apricot color comes from spray-on insulation much like the foam on the shuttle’s external tank. And the large maneuvering engine in Orion’s service module is actually 40 years old—used on 19 space shuttle flights between 1984 and 1992.</p><p class="pull-quote">“I have a name for missions that use too much new technology—failures.”<br/>—John Casani, NASA</p><p>Perhaps more important, the project inherits basic engineering from half a century of spaceflight. Just look at Orion’s crew capsule—a truncated cone, somewhat larger than the Apollo Command Module but conceptually very similar.</p><p>Old, of course, does not mean bad. NASA says there is no need to reinvent things engineers got right the first time.</p><p>“There are certain fundamental aspects of deep-space exploration that are really independent of money,” says <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/jim-geffre-381959225/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Jim Geffre</a>, Orion vehicle-integration manager at the Johnson Space Center in Houston. “The laws of physics haven’t changed since the 1960s. And capsule shapes happen to be really good for coming back into the atmosphere at Mach 32.”</p><p><a href="https://airandspace.si.edu/files/pdf/staff/rlaunius_cv.pdf" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Roger Launius</a>, who served as NASA’s chief historian from 1990 to 2002 and as a curator at the Smithsonian Institution from then until 2017, tells of a conversation he had with <a href="https://www.nae.edu/55569/John-R-Casani" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">John Casani</a>, a veteran NASA engineer who managed the Voyager, Galileo, and Cassini probes to the outer planets.</p><p>“I have a name for missions that use too much new technology,” he recalls Casani saying. “Failures.”</p><p>The Artemis I flight is slated for about six weeks. (<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Apollo_11" target="_blank">Apollo 11</a> lasted eight days.) The ship roughly follows Apollo’s path to the moon’s vicinity, but then puts itself in what NASA calls a distant retrograde orbit. It swoops within 110 kilometers of the lunar surface for a gravity assist, then heads 64,000 km out—taking more than a month but using less fuel than it would in closer orbits. Finally, it comes home, reentering the Earth’s atmosphere at 11 km per second, slowing itself with a heatshield and parachutes, and splashing down in the Pacific not far from San Diego.</p><p class="pull-quote"> If all four, quadruply redundant flight computer modules fail, there is a fifth, entirely separate computer onboard, running different code to get the spacecraft home.</p><p>“That extra time in space,” says Geffre, “allows us to operate the systems, give more time in deep space, and all those things that stress it, like radiation and micrometeoroids, thermal environments.”</p><p>There are, of course, newer technologies on board. Orion is controlled by two vehicle-management computers, each composed of two flight computer modules (FCMs) to handle guidance, navigation, propulsion, communications, and other systems. The flight control system, Geffre points out, is quad-redundant; if at any point one of the four FCMs disagrees with the others, it will take itself offline and, in a 22-second process, reset itself to make sure its outputs are consistent with the others’. If all four FCMs fail, there is a fifth, entirely separate computer running different code to get the spacecraft home.</p><p>Guidance and navigation, too, have advanced since the sextant used on Apollo. Orion uses a star tracker to determine its attitude, imaging stars and comparing them to an onboard database. And an optical navigation camera shoots Earth and the moon so that guidance software can determine their distance and position and keep the spacecraft on course. NASA says it’s there as backup, able to get Orion to a safe splashdown even if all communication with Earth has been lost.</p><p>But even those systems aren’t entirely new. Geffre points out that the guidance system’s architecture is derived from the Boeing 787. Computing power in deep space is limited by cosmic radiation, which can corrupt the output of microprocessors beyond the protection of Earth’s atmosphere and magnetic field.</p><p>Beyond that is the inevitable issue of cost. Artemis is a giant project, years behind schedule, started long before NASA began to buy other launches from companies like <a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/search/?q=spacex" target="_self">SpaceX</a> and <a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/rocket-booster-rocket-lab" target="_self">Rocket Lab</a>. NASA’s inspector general, Paul Martin, <a href="https://science.house.gov/imo/media/doc/Martin%20Testimony4.pdf" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">testified to Congress</a> <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0IhX8OoekwU&t=2018s" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">in March</a> that the first four Artemis missions would cost US $4.1 billion each—“a price tag that strikes us as unsustainable.”</p><p>Launius, for one, rejects the argument that government is inherently wasteful. “Yes, NASA’s had problems in managing programs in the past. Who hasn’t?” he says. He points out that Blue Origin and SpaceX have had plenty of setbacks of their own—they’re just not obliged to be public about them. “I could go on and on. It’s not a government thing per se and it’s not a NASA thing per se.”</p><p>So why return to the moon with—please forgive the pun—such a retro rocket? Partly, say those who watch Artemis closely, because it’s become <a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/gao-warns-of-deteriorating-costs-and-schedules-in-nasas-major-project-portfolio" target="_self">too big to fail</a>, with so much American money and brainpower invested in it. Partly because it turns NASA’s astronauts outward again, <a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/private-space-stations" target="_self">exploring</a> instead of maintaining a space station. Partly because new perspectives could come of it. And partly because <a href="https://aviationweek.com/defense-space/space/opinion-why-nasas-artemis-matters" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">China and Russia</a> have ambitions in space that threaten America’s.</p><p>“Apollo was a demonstration of technological verisimilitude—to the whole world,” says Launius. “And the whole world knew then, as they know today, that the future belongs to the civilization that can master science and technology.”</p><p><em><strong>Update 7 Sept.: </strong>Artemis I has been on launchpad 39B, not 39A as previously reported, at Kennedy Space Center. </em><br/></p>]]></description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Aug 2022 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spectrum.ieee.org/artemis-1-revives-moonshot</guid><category>Space exploration</category><category>Artemis</category><category>Nasa</category><category>Moon exploration</category><category>Moonshot</category><dc:creator>Ned Potter</dc:creator><media:content medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/artemis-i-on-launch-pad-39b-at-kennedy-space-center-at-dawn.jpg?id=31246740&amp;width=980"></media:content></item><item><title>As China’s Quantum-Encrypting Satellites Shrink, Their Networking Abilities Grow</title><link>https://spectrum.ieee.org/satellite-qkd-china</link><description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/a-conceptual-image-showing-a-ground-based-station-connecting-with-satellites.jpg?id=31214800&width=2000&height=1500&coordinates=160%2C0%2C160%2C0"/><br/><br/><p>The orbiting Tiangong-2 space lab has transmitted quantum-encryption keys to four ground stations, researchers <a href="https://opg.optica.org/optica/fulltext.cfm?uri=optica-9-8-933&id=492969" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">reported on 18 August</a>. The same network of ground stations is also able to receive quantum keys from the orbiting Micius satellite, which is in a much higher orbit, using the space station as a repeater. It comes just after the late July launch of Jinan 1, China’s second quantum-encrypting satellite, by the University of Science and Technology of China. USTC told the <a href="https://news.satnews.com/2022/07/31/china-launches-new-satellite-in-important-step-towards-global-quantum-communications-network/" target="_blank">Xinhua News Agency</a> that the new satellite is one-sixth the mass of its 2016 predecessor. </p><p>“The launch is significant,” says physicist <a href="https://physics.illinois.edu/people/directory/profile/kwiat" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Paul Kwiat</a> of the University of Illinois in Urbana-Champaign, because it means the team are starting to build, not just plan, a quantum network. USTC researchers did not reply to <em>IEEE Spectrum’s</em> request for comments. </p><p>In quantum-key distribution (QKD), the quantum states of a single photon, such as polarization, encode and distribute random information that can be used to encrypt a classical message. Because it is impossible to copy the quantum state without changing it, senders and recipients can verify that their transmission got through without tampering or reading by third parties. In some scenarios it involves sending just one well-described photon at a time, but single photons are difficult to produce, and in this case, researchers used an attenuated laser to send small pulses that might also come out a couple of photons at a time, or not at all.</p><p>The USTC research team, led by Jian-Wei Pan, had already <a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/nature23655" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">established quantum-key distribution from Micius to a single ground station</a> in 2017, not long after the 2016 launch of the satellite. The work that Pan and colleagues reported this month, but which took place in 2018 and 2019, is a necessary step for building a constellation of quantum-encryption-compatible satellites across a range of orbits, to ensure more secure long-distance communications.</p><p>Several other research groups have <a href="https://www.optica-opn.org/home/articles/volume_29/february_2018/features/satellite-based_qkd/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">transmitted quantum keys</a>, and others are now building microsatellites for the same purpose. However, the U.S. National Security Agency’s site about QKD lists several technical limitations, such as requiring an initial verification of the counterparty’s identity, the need for special equipment, the cost, and the risk of hardware-based security vulnerabilities. In the absence of fixes, <a href="https://www.nsa.gov/Cybersecurity/Quantum-Key-Distribution-QKD-and-Quantum-Cryptography-QC/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">the NSA does not anticipate approving QKD for national security</a> communications.</p><p>However, attenuated laser pulses are just one way of implementing QKD. Another is to use quantum entanglement, by which a pair of photons will behave the same way, even at a distance, when someone measures one of their quantum properties. In earlier experiments, Pan and colleagues also reported <a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-020-2401-y" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">using quantum entanglement for QKD</a> and mixing satellite and fiber-optic links to establish a <a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-020-03093-8.epdf?sharing_token=1CW5z-80KWF4rgRGti-ZLNRgN0jAjWel9jnR3ZoTv0MNVpe6EvGQLTY7KE8U5lpv1AcqqXD5K2i3SN7zSU9K-dIX_fTfOWh3AkcjO3lLZZQSom5J0UumeoZfz1ZIXNNoNUSoEMYhZmfqWAO_FJy0sAa0ur09z2pHIX00xbdt4Y22R3sPuCz9nadZZORyizjpkFYizVoGYKpYleWnrNiIIG-n2Q-KiOo9HdosHMD_WoM%3D&tracking_referrer=spectrum.ieee.org" target="_blank">mixed-modality QKD network spanning almost 5,000 kilometers</a>. </p><p>“A quantum network with entangled nodes is the thing that would be really interesting, enabling distributed quantum computing and sensing, but  that’s a hard thing to make. Being able to do QKD is a necessary but not sufficient first step,” Kwiat says. The USTC experiments are a chance to establish many technical abilities, such as the precise control of the pulse duration and direction of the lasers involved, or the ability to accurately transfer and measure the quantum signals to the standard necessary for a more complex quantum network. </p><p>That is a step ahead of the many other QKD efforts made so far on laboratory benchtops, over ground-to-ground cables, or aboard balloons or aircraft. “You have to do things very differently if you’re not allowed to fiddle with something once it’s launched into space,” Kwiat says.</p><p>The U.S. CHIPS and Science Act of 2022, signed on 9 August, <a href="https://www.quantum.gov/quantum-in-the-chips-and-science-act-of-2022/" target="_blank">allocated more than US $153 million a year for quantum computing and networks</a>. While that’s unlikely to drive more American work toward an end goal of QKD, Kwiat says, “maybe we do it on the way to these more interesting applications.”</p>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2022 18:37:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spectrum.ieee.org/satellite-qkd-china</guid><category>Qkd</category><category>Satellites</category><category>Networking</category><category>Qkd</category><dc:creator>Lucas Laursen</dc:creator><media:content medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/a-conceptual-image-showing-a-ground-based-station-connecting-with-satellites.jpg?id=31214800&amp;width=980"></media:content></item><item><title>Solar-to-Jet-Fuel System Readies for Takeoff</title><link>https://spectrum.ieee.org/solar-to-jet-fuel-system-readies-for-take-off</link><description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/a-large-outdoor-tower-reflects-sunlight-on-large-mirrors.jpg?id=30458951&width=2000&height=1500&coordinates=0%2C0%2C0%2C0"/><br/><br/><p><sub></sub>As climate change edges from crisis to emergency, the aviation sector looks set <a href="https://apnews.com/article/climate-technology-travel-england-airlines-bc00fe2b83f362f58d4ecbe2d1f7c1d7" target="_blank">to miss its 2050 goal</a> of net-zero emissions. In the five years preceding the pandemic, the top four U.S. airlines—<a href="https://www.aa.com/homePage.do" target="_blank">American</a>, <a href="https://www.delta.com/" target="_blank">Delta</a>, <a href="https://www.southwest.com/" target="_blank">Southwest</a>, and <a href="https://www.united.com/en/us" target="_blank">United</a>—saw a 15 percent increase in the use of jet fuel. Despite continual improvements in engine efficiencies, that number is projected to keep rising.<br/></p><p>A glimmer of hope, however, comes from solar fuels. For the first time, scientists and engineers at the <a href="https://ethz.ch/en.html" target="_blank">Swiss Federal Institute of Technology</a> (ETH) in Zurich have reported a successful demonstration of <a href="https://www.cell.com/joule/fulltext/S2542-4351(22)00286-0" target="_blank">an integrated fuel-production plant for solar kerosene</a>. Using concentrated solar energy, they were able to produce kerosene from water vapor and carbon dioxide directly from air. Fuel thus produced is a drop-in alternative to fossil-derived fuels and can be used with existing storage and distribution infrastructures, and engines.</p><p>Fuels derived from <a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/topics/engineering/syngas" target="_blank">synthesis gas</a> (or syngas)—an intermediate product that is a specific mixture of carbon monoxide and hydrogen—is a known alternative to conventional, fossil-derived fuels. Syngas is produced by <a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/topics/engineering/fischer-tropsch-process" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Fischer-Tropsch (FT) synthesis</a>, in which chemical reactions convert carbon monoxide and water vapor into hydrocarbons. The team of researchers at ETH found that a solar-driven thermochemical method to split water and carbon dioxide using a metal oxide redox cycle can produce renewable syngas. They <a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/rooftop-solar-refinery-produces-carbonneutral-fuels" target="_blank">demonstrated the process</a> in a rooftop solar refinery at the <a href="https://www.ittenbrechbuehl.ch/en/projects/machine-laboratory-eth-zurich/" target="_blank">ETH Machine Laboratory</a> in 2019.</p><p class="shortcode-media shortcode-media-rebelmouse-image">
<img alt="Close-up of a spongy looking material" class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="2a0b09362fae33e4f819e43a52223952" data-rm-shortcode-name="rebelmouse-image" id="2f2cf" loading="lazy" src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/close-up-of-a-spongy-looking-material.jpg?id=30459194&width=980"/>
<small class="image-media media-caption" placeholder="Add Photo Caption...">Reticulated porous structure made of ceria used in the solar reactor to thermochemically split CO2 and H2O and produce syngas, a specific mixture of H2 and CO.</small><small class="image-media media-photo-credit" placeholder="Add Photo Credit...">ETH Zurich</small></p><p>The current pilot-scale solar tower plant was set up at the <a href="https://www.energy.imdea.org/" target="_blank">IMDEA Energy Institute</a> in Spain. It scales up the solar reactor of the 2019 experiment by a factor of 10, says <a href="https://ipe.ethz.ch/people/iepe-professors/Steinfeld.html" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Aldo Steinfeld</a>, an engineering professor at ETH who led the study. The fuel plant brings together three subsystems—the solar tower concentrating facility, solar reactor, and gas-to-liquid unit.</p><p>First, a heliostat field made of mirrors that rotate to follow the sun concentrates solar irradiation into a reactor mounted on top of the tower. The reactor is a cavity receiver lined with reticulated porous ceramic structures made of ceria (or cerium(IV) oxide). Within the reactor, the concentrated sunlight creates a high-temperature environment of about 1,500 °C which is hot enough to split captured carbon dioxide and water from the atmosphere to produce syngas. Finally, the syngas is processed to kerosene in the gas-to-liquid unit. A centralized control room operates the whole system.</p><p>Fuel produced using this method closes the fuel carbon cycle as it only produces as much carbon dioxide as has gone into its manufacture. “The present pilot fuel plant is still a demonstration facility for research purposes,” says Steinfeld, “but it is a fully integrated plant and uses a solar-tower configuration at a scale that is relevant for industrial implementation.”</p><p>“The solar reactor produced syngas with selectivity, purity, and quality suitable for FT synthesis,” the authors noted in their paper. They also reported good material stability for multiple consecutive cycles. They observed a value of 4.1 percent solar-to-syngas energy efficiency, which Steinfeld says is a record value for thermochemical fuel production, even though better efficiencies are required to make the technology economically competitive.</p><p class="shortcode-media shortcode-media-rebelmouse-image">
<img alt="Schematic of the solar tower fuel plant.  " class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="33a694ae31e02b5fac627152ccbe2551" data-rm-shortcode-name="rebelmouse-image" id="ff8ef" loading="lazy" src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/schematic-of-the-solar-tower-fuel-plant.jpg?id=30459216&width=980"/>
<small class="image-media media-caption" placeholder="Add Photo Caption...">A heliostat field concentrates solar radiation onto a solar reactor mounted on top of the solar tower. The solar reactor cosplits water and carbon dioxide and produces a mixture of molecular hydrogen and carbon monoxide, which in turn is processed to drop-in fuels such as kerosene.</small><small class="image-media media-photo-credit" placeholder="Add Photo Credit...">ETH Zurich</small></p><p>“The measured value of energy conversion efficiency was obtained without any implementation of heat recovery,” he says. The heat rejected during the redox cycle of the reactor accounted for more than 50 percent of the solar-energy input. “This fraction can be partially recovered via thermocline heat storage. Thermodynamic analyses indicate that sensible heat recovery could potentially boost the energy efficiency to values exceeding 20 percent.”</p><p>To do so, more work is needed to optimize the ceramic structures lining the reactor, something the ETH team is actively working on, by looking at 3D-printed structures for improved volumetric radiative absorption. “In addition, alternative material compositions, that is, perovskites or aluminates, may yield improved redox capacity, and consequently higher specific fuel output per mass of redox material,” Steinfeld adds.</p><p>The next challenge for the researchers, he says, is the scale-up of their technology for higher solar-radiative power inputs, possibly using an array of solar cavity-receiver modules on top of the solar tower.</p><p>To bring solar kerosene into the market, Steinfeld envisages a quota-based system. “Airlines and airports would be required to have a minimum share of sustainable aviation fuels in the total volume of jet fuel that they put in their aircraft,” he says. This is possible as solar kerosene can be mixed with fossil-based kerosene. This would start out small, as little as 1 or 2 percent, which would raise the total fuel costs at first, though minimally—adding “only a few euros to the cost of a typical flight,” as Steinfeld puts it</p><p>Meanwhile, rising quotas would lead to investment, and to falling costs, eventually replacing fossil-derived kerosene with solar kerosene. “By the time solar jet fuel reaches 10 to 15 percent of the total jet-fuel volume, we ought to see the costs for solar kerosene nearing those of fossil-derived kerosene,” he adds.</p><p>However, we may not have to wait too long for flights to operate solely on solar fuel. A commercial spin-off of Steinfeld’s laboratory, <a href="https://synhelion.com/" target="_blank">Synhelion</a>, is working on commissioning the first industrial-scale solar fuel plant in 2023. The company has also collaborated with the <a href="https://synhelion.com/news/swiss-will-be-the-world-s-first-airline-to-use-synhelion-s-solar-fuels" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">airline SWISS</a> to conduct a flight solely using its solar kerosene.</p>]]></description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Aug 2022 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spectrum.ieee.org/solar-to-jet-fuel-system-readies-for-take-off</guid><category>Jet fuel</category><category>Aviation</category><category>Solar power</category><category>Solar energy</category><dc:creator>Payal Dhar</dc:creator><media:content medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/a-large-outdoor-tower-reflects-sunlight-on-large-mirrors.jpg?id=30458951&amp;width=980"></media:content></item><item><title>X-Rays Could Carry Quantum Signals Across the Stars</title><link>https://spectrum.ieee.org/search-for-extraterrestrial-intelligence</link><description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/colorful-streams-of-light.jpg?id=30142338&width=2000&height=1500&coordinates=0%2C0%2C0%2C0"/><br/><br/><p>
	Quantum signals may possess a number of advantages over regular forms of communication, leading scientists to wonder if humanity was not alone in discovering such benefits. Now a new study suggests that, for hypothetical extraterrestrial civilizations, quantum transmissions using X-rays may be possible across interstellar distances.
</p><p>
	Quantum communication relies on a quantum phenomenon known as 
	<u><a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/what-is-quantum-entanglement" target="_self">entanglement</a></u>. Essentially, two or more particles such as photons that get “linked” via entanglement can, in theory, influence each other instantly no matter how far apart they are.
</p><p>
	Entanglement is essential to 
	<u><a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/quantum-teleportation" target="_self">quantum teleportation</a></u>, in which data can essentially disappear one place and reappear someplace else. Since this information does not travel across the intervening space, there is no chance the information will be lost.
</p><p>
	To accomplish quantum teleportation, one would first entangle two photons. Then, one of the photons—the one to be teleported—is kept at one location while the other is beamed to whatever destination is desired.
</p><p>
	Next, the photon at the destination's quantum state—which defines its key characteristics—is analyzed, an act that also destroys its quantum state. Entanglement will lead the destination photon to prove identical to its partner. For all intents and purposes, the photon at the origin point “teleported” to the destination point—no physical matter moved, but the two photons are physically indistinguishable.
</p><p>
	And to be clear, quantum teleportation cannot send information faster than the speed of light, because the destination photon must still be transmitted via conventional means.
</p><p>
	One weakness of quantum communication is that entanglement is fragile. Still, researchers have successfully transmitted entangled photons that remained stable or “<u><a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/longlasting-qubits" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">coherent</a></u>” enough for quantum teleportation across distances as great as <u><a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/nature23675/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">1,400 kilometers</a></u>.
</p><p>
	Such findings led theoretical physicist 
	<a href="https://www.ph.ed.ac.uk/people/arjun-berera" target="_blank">Arjun Berera</a> at the University of Edinburgh to wonder just how far quantum signals might stay coherent. First, he discovered <u><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2009.00356" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">quantum coherence might survive interstellar distances within our galaxy</a></u>, and then he and his colleagues found <u><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2107.06914" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">quantum coherence might survive intergalactic distances</a></u>.
</p><p>
	“If photons in Earth’s atmosphere don’t decohere to 100 km, then in interstellar space where the medium is much less dense then our atmosphere, photons won’t decohere up to even the size of the galaxy,” Berera says.
</p><p>
	In the new study, the researchers investigated whether and how well quantum communication might survive interstellar distances. Quantum signals might face disruption from a number of factors, such as the gravitational pull of interstellar bodies, they note.
</p><p>
	The scientists discovered the best quantum communication channels for interstellar messages are X-rays. Such frequencies are easier to focus and detect across interstellar distances. (NASA has tested deep-space X-ray communication with its 
	<a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/nasa-wants-to-place-calls-to-deep-space-with-xrays" target="_self">XCOM</a> experiment.) The researchers also found that the optical and microwave bands could enable communication across large distances as well, albeit less effectively than X-rays.
</p><p>
	Although coherence might survive interstellar distances, Berera does note quantum signals might lose fidelity. “This means the quantum state is sustained, but it can have a phase shift, so although the quantum information is preserved in these states, it has been altered by the effect of gravity.” Therefore, it may “take some work at the receiving end to account for these phase shifts and be able to assess the information contained in the original state.”
</p><p>
	Why might an interstellar civilization transmit quantum signals as opposed to regular ones? The researchers note that quantum communication may allow 
	<a href="https://journals.aps.org/pra/abstract/10.1103/PhysRevA.51.2738" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">greater data compression</a> and, in some cases, <a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/quant-ph/0607174" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">exponentially</a> <a href="https://dl.acm.org/doi/10.1145/1007352.1007379" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">faster</a> speeds than classical channels. Such a boost in efficiency might prove very useful for civilizations separated by interstellar distances.
</p><p>
	“It could be that quantum communication is the main communication mode in an extraterrestrial's world, so they just apply what is at hand to send signals into the cosmos,” Berera says.
</p><p>
	The scientists detailed 
	<u><a href="https://journals.aps.org/prd/abstract/10.1103/PhysRevD.105.123033" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">their findings</a></u> online 28 June in the journal <em>Physical Review D</em>.
</p>]]></description><pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2022 15:07:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spectrum.ieee.org/search-for-extraterrestrial-intelligence</guid><category>Extraterrestrial</category><category>Entanglement</category><category>Teleportation</category><category>X-rays</category><category>Coherence</category><category>Decoherence</category><category>Quantum communications</category><dc:creator>Charles Q. Choi</dc:creator><media:content medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/colorful-streams-of-light.jpg?id=30142338&amp;width=980"></media:content></item><item><title>The Webb Space Telescope’s Profound Data Challenges</title><link>https://spectrum.ieee.org/james-webb-telescope-communications</link><description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/two-men-fix-metal-rods-to-a-gold-foiled-satellite-component-in-a-warehouse-clean-room-environment.png?id=30076160&width=2000&height=1500&coordinates=175%2C0%2C175%2C0"/><br/><br/><p class="ieee-editors-note">
<em>For a deep dive into the engineering behind the James Webb Space Telescope, <a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/collections/james-webb-telescope/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">see our collection of posts here</a>.</em>
</p><p>
	When the 
	<a href="https://www.jwst.nasa.gov/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">James Webb Space Telescope</a> (JWST) <a rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"></a><a href="https://www.nasa.gov/feature/goddard/2022/first-images-from-nasa-s-webb-space-telescope-coming-soon" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">reveals its first images</a> on 12 July, they will be the by-product of carefully crafted mirrors and scientific instruments. But all of its data-collecting prowess would be moot without the spacecraft’s communications subsystem.
</p><p>
	The Webb’s comms aren’t flashy. Rather, the data and communication systems are designed to be incredibly, unquestionably dependable and reliable. And while some aspects of them are relatively new—it’s the first mission to use 
	<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ka_band" target="_blank">K<sub>a</sub>-band</a> frequencies for such high data rates so far from Earth, for example—above all else, JWST’s comms provide the foundation upon which JWST’s scientific endeavors sit.
</p><hr/><p>
	As previous articles in this series have noted, JWST is parked at 
	<a href="https://www.nasa.gov/topics/universe/features/webb-l2.html" target="_blank">Lagrange point L2</a>. It’s a point of gravitational equilibrium located about 1.5 million kilometers beyond Earth on a straight line between the planet and the sun. It’s an ideal location for JWST to observe the universe without obstruction and with minimal orbital adjustments.
</p><p>
	Being so far away from Earth, however, means that data has farther to travel to make it back in one piece. It also means the communications subsystem needs to be reliable, because the prospect of a repair mission being sent to address a problem is, for the near term at least, highly unlikely. Given the cost and time involved, says 
	<a href="https://www.jwst.nasa.gov/content/meetTheTeam/people/menzel.html" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Michael Menzel</a>, the mission systems engineer for JWST, “I would not encourage a rendezvous and servicing mission unless something went wildly wrong.”
</p><p>
	According to Menzel, who has worked on JWST in some capacity for over 20 years, the plan has always been to use well-understood K
	<sub>a</sub>-band frequencies for the bulky transmissions of scientific data. Specifically, JWST is transmitting data back to Earth on a 25.9-gigahertz channel at up to 28 megabits per second. The K<sub>a</sub>-band is a portion of the broader <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/K_band_(IEEE)" target="_blank">K-band</a> (another portion, the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ku_band" target="_blank">Ku-band</a>, was also considered).
</p><p class="shortcode-media shortcode-media-rebelmouse-image">
<img alt="An illustration depicting different Lagrange points and where the Webb Telescope is." class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="e917bd84316ffff0c175bcd0bc5611a8" data-rm-shortcode-name="rebelmouse-image" id="80442" loading="lazy" src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/an-illustration-depicting-different-lagrange-points-and-where-the-webb-telescope-is.png?id=30819133&width=980"/>
<small class="image-media media-caption" placeholder="Add Photo Caption...">The Lagrange points are equilibrium locations where competing gravitational tugs on an object net out to zero. JWST is one of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_objects_at_Lagrange_points#L2" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">three craft</a> currently occupying L2 (Shown here at an exaggerated distance from Earth). </small><small class="image-media media-photo-credit" placeholder="Add Photo Credit...">IEEE Spectrum</small>
</p><p>
	Both the data-collection and transmission rates of JWST dwarf those of the older 
	<a href="https://hubblesite.org/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Hubble Space Telescope</a>. Compared to Hubble, which is still active and generates 1 to 2 gigabytes of data daily, JWST can produce up to 57 GB each day (although that amount is dependent on what observations are scheduled).
</p><p>
	Menzel says he first saw the frequency selection proposals for JWST around 2000, when he was working at 
	<a href="https://www.northropgrumman.com/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Northrop Grumman</a>. He became the mission systems engineer in 2004. “I knew where the risks were in this mission. And I wanted to make sure that we didn’t get any new risks,” he says.
</p><p class="shortcode-media shortcode-media-rebelmouse-image rm-resized-container rm-resized-container-25 rm-float-left" data-rm-resized-container="25%" style="float: left;">
<img class="rm-shortcode rm-resized-image" data-rm-shortcode-id="ef72723df77b044205bda548f7515acd" data-rm-shortcode-name="rebelmouse-image" id="54fee" loading="lazy" src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/image.png?id=30076351&width=980" style="max-width: 100%"/>
<small class="image-media media-photo-credit" placeholder="Add Photo Credit..." style="max-width: 100%;">IEEE Spectrum</small>
</p><p>
	Besides, K
	<sub>a</sub>-band frequencies can transmit more data than <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/X_band" target="_blank">X-band</a> (7 to 11.2 GHz) or <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/S_band" target="_blank">S-band</a> (2 to 4 GHz), common choices for craft in deep space. A high data rate is a necessity for the scientific work JWST will be undertaking. In addition, according to <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/carl-hansen-858a1b68" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Carl Hansen</a>, a flight systems engineer at the <a href="https://www.stsci.edu/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Space Telescope Science Institute</a> (the science operations center for JWST), a comparable X-band antenna would be so large that the spacecraft would have trouble remaining steady for imaging.
</p><p>
	Although the 25.9-GHz K
	<sub>a</sub>-band frequency is the telescope’s workhorse communication channel, it also employs two channels in the S-band. One is the 2.09-GHz uplink that ferries future transmission and scientific observation schedules to the telescope at 16 kilobits per second. The other is the 2.27-GHz, 40-kb/s downlink over which the telescope transmits engineering data—including its operational status, systems health, and other information concerning the telescope’s day-to-day activities.
</p><p>
	Any scientific data the JWST collects during its lifetime will need to be stored on board, because the spacecraft doesn’t maintain round-the-clock contact with Earth. Data gathered from its scientific instruments, once collected, is stored within the spacecraft’s 68-GB solid-state drive (3 percent is reserved for engineering and telemetry data). 
	<a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/alex-hunter-3918a111" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Alex Hunter</a>, also a flight systems engineer at the Space Telescope Science Institute, says that by the end of JWST’s 10-year mission life, they expect to be down to about 60 GB because of deep-space radiation and wear and tear.
</p><p>
	The onboard storage is enough to collect data for about 24 hours before it runs out of room. Well before that becomes an issue, JWST will have scheduled opportunities to beam that invaluable data to Earth.
</p><p>
	JWST will stay connected via the 
	<a href="https://www.nasa.gov/directorates/heo/scan/services/networks/deep_space_network/about" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Deep Space Network</a> (DSN)—a <a href="https://eyes.nasa.gov/dsn/dsn.html" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">resource it shares</a> with the <a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/how-the-parker-solar-probe-survives-close-encounters-with-the-sun" target="_self">Parker Solar Probe</a>, <a href="https://www.nasa.gov/tess-transiting-exoplanet-survey-satellite" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Transiting Exoplanet Survey Satellite</a>, the <a href="https://voyager.jpl.nasa.gov/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Voyager probes</a>, and the entire ensemble of <a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/how-nasa-is-adapting-radios-to-a-noisier-mars" target="_self">Mars rovers and orbiters</a>, to name just a few of the other heavyweights. The DSN consists of <a href="https://www.nasa.gov/directorates/heo/scan/services/networks/deep_space_network/complexes" target="_blank">three antenna complexes</a>: Canberra, Australia; Madrid, Spain; and Barstow, Calif. JWST needs to share finite antenna time with plenty of other deep-space missions, each with unique communications needs and schedules.</p><p class="shortcode-media shortcode-media-rebelmouse-image rm-resized-container rm-resized-container-25 rm-float-left" data-rm-resized-container="25%" style="float: left;">
<img class="rm-shortcode rm-resized-image" data-rm-shortcode-id="fedee7e9bbe254af34d3bc428d80b060" data-rm-shortcode-name="rebelmouse-image" id="c5111" loading="lazy" src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/image.png?id=30844323&width=980" style="max-width: 100%"/>
<small class="image-media media-photo-credit" placeholder="Add Photo Credit..." style="max-width: 100%;">IEEE Spectrum</small></p><p>
<a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/sandykwan" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Sandy Kwan</a>, a DSN systems engineer, says that contact windows with spacecraft are scheduled 12 to 20 weeks in advance. JWST had a greater number of scheduled contact windows during its commissioning phase, as instruments were brought on line, checked, and calibrated. Most of that process required real-time communication with Earth.</p><p>All of the communications channels use the 
	<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Reed%E2%80%93Solomon_error_correction" target="_blank">Reed-Solomon</a> <a href="https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/book/5264570" target="_blank">error-correction protocol</a>—the same error-correction standard as used in DVDs and Blu-ray discs as well as QR codes. The lower data-rate S-band channels use <a href="https://technav.ieee.org/topic/binary-phase-shift-keying" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">binary phase-shift key</a> modulation—involving phase shifting of a signal’s carrier wave. The K-band channel, however, uses a quadrature phase-shift key modulation. Quadrature phase-shift keying can double a channel’s data rate, at the cost of more complicated transmitters and receivers.
</p><p>
	JWST’s communications with Earth incorporate an acknowledgement protocol—only after the JWST gets confirmation that a file has been successfully received will it go ahead and delete its copy of the data to clear up space.
	<a href="#_msocom_6" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"></a>
</p><p>
	The communications subsystem was assembled along with the rest of the spacecraft bus by 
	<a href="https://www.northropgrumman.com/space/james-webb-space-telescope/" target="_blank">Northrop Grumman</a>, using off-the-shelf components sourced from multiple manufacturers.
</p><p>
	JWST has had a long and 
	<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Timeline_of_the_James_Webb_Space_Telescope" target="_blank">often-delayed development</a>, but its communications system has always been a bedrock for the rest of the project. Keeping at least one system dependable means it’s one less thing to worry about. Menzel can remember, for instance, ideas for <a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/lunar-pioneers-will-use-lasers-to-phone-home" target="_self">laser-based optical systems</a> that were invariably rejected. “I can count at least two times where I had been approached by people who wanted to experiment with optical communications,” says Menzel. “Each time they came to me, I sent them away with the old ‘Thank you, but I don’t need it. And I don’t want it.’”
</p>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2022 18:03:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spectrum.ieee.org/james-webb-telescope-communications</guid><category>James webb space telescope</category><category>Nasa</category><category>Space telescopes</category><category>Data compression</category><category>Deep space network</category><dc:creator>Michael Koziol</dc:creator><media:content medium="image" type="image/png" url="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/two-men-fix-metal-rods-to-a-gold-foiled-satellite-component-in-a-warehouse-clean-room-environment.png?id=30076160&amp;width=980"></media:content></item><item><title>Inside the Universe Machine: The Webb Space Telescope’s Chilly Sun Shield</title><link>https://spectrum.ieee.org/james-webb-telescope-sunshield</link><description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/rendering-of-james-webb-space-telescope-including-its-18-segmented-primary-mirrors-and-its-five-layered-sun-shade.png?id=30064121&width=2000&height=1500&coordinates=220%2C0%2C221%2C0"/><br/><br/><p class="ieee-editors-note">
<em>For a deep dive into the engineering behind the James Webb Space Telescope, <a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/collections/james-webb-telescope/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">see our collection of posts here</a>.</em>
</p><p>
<strong>When Apollo astronauts</strong> sent back the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Timeline_of_first_images_of_Earth_from_space" target="_blank">first pictures of Earth as a disk in space</a>, the poet <a href="https://archive.nytimes.com/www.nytimes.com/library/national/science/nasa/122568sci-nasa-macleish.html" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Archibald MacLeish</a> wrote of it as “that bright loveliness in the eternal cold.” He was not far off. Deep space has a <a href="https://lambda.gsfc.nasa.gov/product/cobe/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">temperature</a> of 2.7 <a rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">kelvins</a>—just 2.7 degrees above absolute zero.
</p><p>
	If the <a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/at-last-first-light-for-the-james-webb-space-telescope" target="_self">James Webb Space Telescope</a> is to work—looking so far out and therefore so far back in time that it can see the first galaxies forming after the big bang—it will have to image objects so faint that they barely stand out from the cold around them. The world will begin finding out how well the observatory works <a href="https://www.nasa.gov/feature/goddard/2022/first-images-from-nasa-s-webb-space-telescope-coming-soon" target="_blank">as soon as next week</a>, when JWST is expected to release its first trove of scientific images and spectroscopic data.
</p><p>
	So, for argument’s sake, let’s assume <a href="https://www.nasa.gov/feature/join-the-virtual-global-social-for-the-reveal-of-the-james-webb-space-telescopes-first" target="_blank">all indications so far</a> do in fact point to a successful kickoff of the (hopefully long and storied) scientific data-gathering phase of Webb’s mission. How then did the engineers and designers of this massive telescope ever make it possible to cool the telescope down enough—all at a remove of nearly four times the distance from Earth to the moon—to possibly do its job?
</p><p>
	After more than 25 years’ work and technological hurdles beyond counting, the Webb team has launched and stationed its mammoth observatory in solar orbit—and brought its instruments below 40 kelvins (-233 °C), cold enough to see the early universe more than 13.5 billion years ago. Remarkably, most of the cooling has been done passively, by shielding the telescope from the sun and letting physics take care of the rest.
</p><p>
	“Webb is not just the product of a group of people. It’s not the product of some smart astronomers—Webb is truly the product of our entire world’s capability,” says <a href="https://jwst.nasa.gov/content/meetTheTeam/people/parrish.html" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Keith Parrish</a>, a leader on the Webb team at NASA’s <a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission_pages/webb/main/index.html" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Goddard Space Flight Center</a> in Maryland. “Taken as a whole, Webb is truly the result of our entire know-how of how to build complex machines.”
</p><p>
	Parrish joined the project in 1997, ultimately becoming its commissioning manager through the years of design, assembly, testing, delay and, finally, launch on 25 December 2021. He says almost everything about it—its shape and location, the materials from which it’s made—was dictated by the need to have an observatory that would survive for years at supercold temperatures.
</p><p class="shortcode-media shortcode-media-rebelmouse-image">
<img alt="Photo of clean room with five giant foil-like sheets stacked atop one another, with three scientists in the distance, inspecting the sunshield" class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="d704905c49210fdedaaff684f8117968" data-rm-shortcode-name="rebelmouse-image" id="1816e" loading="lazy" src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/photo-of-clean-room-with-five-giant-foil-like-sheets-stacked-atop-one-another-with-three-scientists-in-the-distance-inspecting.jpg?id=30064158&width=980"/>
<small class="image-media media-caption" placeholder="Add Photo Caption...">In this photo, the five-layered JWST sunshield is being unfurled and inspected in a clean room. The layers of coated Kapton E never touch, minimizing the transmission of heat from one layer to the next. </small><small class="image-media media-photo-credit" placeholder="Add Photo Credit...">Alex Evers/Northrop Grumman</small>
</p><p>
	The Webb is an infrared observatory for many reasons, not the least of which is that as the universe expands, the wavelength of light from distant objects is lengthened, causing dramatic redshift. Infrared is also good for seeing through cosmic dust and gas, and for imaging cold things such as comets, Kuiper Belt objects, and perhaps planets orbiting other stars.
</p><p>
	But infrared radiation is often best measured as heat, which is why it’s important for the Webb to be so cold. If, like the <a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/the-hubble-telescope-25-years" target="_self">Hubble Telescope</a>, it were in low Earth orbit, and it had no shielding from the sun, most of its targets would be drowned out by the sun and ground, and by heat in the telescope itself.
</p><p>
	“If my signal is heat—and infrared is heat—then what I can’t have is other heat sources that are noise in the system,” says <a href="https://www.eurekalert.org/news-releases/939245" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Jim Flynn</a>, the sunshield manager at <a href="https://www.northropgrumman.com/space/james-webb-space-telescope/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Northrop Grumman</a>, the prime contractor for the Webb.
</p><p>
	So the Webb has been sent to circle a spot in space called <a href="https://webb.nasa.gov/content/about/orbit.html" target="_blank">L2</a>, 1.5 million kilometers away, opposite the sun, one of the locations known as Lagrange points. These "L" points are where the gravity of Earth and the sun exactly conspire to keep it in a stable and relatively "fixed" orbit with respect to the Earth as it makes its way around its 365.256-day course circling the sun. It’s a good compromise: Earth is distant enough that it doesn’t interfere with observations, but close enough that communication with the spacecraft can be relatively fast. And since the ship isn’t flying from day to night and back on every orbit, its temperature is relatively stable. All it needs is a really, really good sunshade.
</p><p class="pull-quote">
	“Four [layers of sunshield] would have probably done the job. Five gave us a little bit of an insurance policy. I’d like to say it was way more sophisticated than that, but that’s really not what it was at all.”<br/>
	—Keith Parrish, NASA Goddard Space Flight Center
</p><p>
	“The engineering was pushed above and beyond to meet the scientific goals,” says <a href="https://www.stsci.edu/stsci-research/research-directory/alex-lockwood" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Alexandra Lockwood</a>, a project scientist at the <a href="https://www.stsci.edu/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Space Telescope Science Institute</a>, which operates the Webb. “It is specifically designed the way that it is because they wanted to do intensive infrared science.”
</p><p>
	It makes for an ungainly-looking ship in many renderings, with the telescope assembly, intentionally open to space to prevent heat buildup, attached to its silvery sunshield, about 14 meters wide and 21 meters long, with five layers of insulating film to keep the telescope in almost total darkness.
</p><p>
	From its sunlit side the sunshield roughly resembles a kite. The elongated shape, engineers found, would be the most efficient way to keep the Webb’s optics out of the sun. They considered a square or octagon, but the final version covers more area without much more mass.
</p><p>
	“It’s no larger than it needs to be to meet the science field-of-view requirements, and that unique kite shape is the result,” says Parrish. “Any larger than it is now, it just makes everything more complex.”
</p><p>
	The shield’s five layers are made of <a href="https://www.dupont.com/electronic-materials/kapton-polyimide-film.html" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Kapton E</a>, a plastic film first developed by DuPont in the 1960s and used for spacecraft insulation and printed circuits. The layers are coated in aluminum and silicon. Each is thinner than a human hair. But engineers say they are, together, very effective in blocking the sun’s heat. The first layer reduces its strength by about an order of magnitude (or 90 percent), the second layer removes another order of magnitude, and so on. The layers never touch, and they’re slightly flared as one gets away from the center of the shield, so that heat will escape out the sides.
</p><p>
	The result: Temperatures on the sunny side of the shield approach 360 K (87 °C), but on the dark side they’re below that all-important 40 K (-233 °C). <a rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Or, put another way: More than 200 kilowatts of </a><a href="https://directory.eoportal.org/web/eoportal/satellite-missions/j/jwst" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">solar energy</a> fall on the first layer, but only 23 milliwatts make it all the way through the fifth.
</p><h3>The Two Sides of the Webb Telescope</h3><br/><img alt="illustration depicting features of JWST's sunshield" class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="01bd2a751ae5cc318d7e8b3a43e4b820" data-rm-shortcode-name="rebelmouse-image" id="cc1c7" loading="lazy" src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/illustration-depicting-features-of-jwst-s-sunshield.png?id=30818967&width=980"/><p>
	Why five layers? There was a lot of computer modeling, but it was hard to simulate the shield’s thermal behavior before flight. “Four would have probably done the job. Five gave us a little bit of an insurance policy,” says Parrish. “I’d like to say it was way more sophisticated than that, but that’s really not what it was at all.”
</p><p>
	The ability to <a href="https://www.researchgate.net/publication/234251660_Radiatively-cooled_telescopes_for_infrared_space_astronomy" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">cool the telescope naturally</a>, first calculated in the 1980s to be possible, was a major advance. It meant the Webb would not have to rely on a heavy, complex cryogenic apparatus, with refrigerants that could leak and shorten the mission. Of its four main scientific instruments, only one, a midinfrared detector called MIRI, needs to be cooled to 6.7 K. It’s chilled by a multistage cryocooler, which pumps cold helium gas through pulse tubes to draw heat away from the instrument’s sensor. It uses the <a href="https://www.comsol.com/multiphysics/joule-thomson-effect" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Joule-Thomson effect</a>, reducing the temperature of the helium by making it expand after it’s forced through a 1-millimeter valve. Pressure comes from two pistons—the cryocooler system’s only moving parts—facing opposite directions so their movements will cancel each other out and not disturb observations.
</p><p>
	Building the telescope proved immensely complicated; it fell years behind while its budget ballooned toward US $10 billion. The sunshield needed lengthy redesign after testing, when Kapton tore and fasteners came loose.
</p><p>
	“We just bit off way more than we could chew,” Parrish says now. “That’s exactly what NASA should be doing. It should be pushing the envelope. The problem is that eventually Webb got too big to fail.”
</p><p>
	But it’s finally deployed, sending data, and surprising engineers who expected at least some failures as it began to operate. Keith Parrish, his work done, is moving on to other projects at Goddard.
</p><p>
	“I think Webb,” he says, “is just a great product of what it means to be an advanced civilization.”
</p><p><br/></p><p><strong><em>Update: 26 July 2022: </em></strong><em>The story was updated to clarify that the gravity at Lagrange point L2 does not "cancel" (as the story had previously stated) but in fact adds to keep an object at L2 orbiting at the precise same orbital period as, in this case, the Earth—i.e. at 365.256 days.</em><br/></p>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 13:48:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spectrum.ieee.org/james-webb-telescope-sunshield</guid><category>Space telescopes</category><category>Cryogenics</category><category>Cooling</category><category>Nasa</category><category>James webb space telescope</category><dc:creator>Ned Potter</dc:creator><media:content medium="image" type="image/png" url="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/rendering-of-james-webb-space-telescope-including-its-18-segmented-primary-mirrors-and-its-five-layered-sun-shade.png?id=30064121&amp;width=980"></media:content></item><item><title>Inside the Universe Machine: The Webb Space Telescope’s Staggering Vision</title><link>https://spectrum.ieee.org/james-webb-telescope-optics</link><description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/fourteen-technicians-in-clean-room-suits-guide-the-hoisting-of-a-honeycombed-hexagon-mirrored-telescope-inside-a-giant-cleanroo.jpg?id=30063324&width=2000&height=1500&coordinates=422%2C0%2C0%2C0"/><br/><br/><p class="ieee-editors-note">
<em>For a deep dive into the engineering behind the James Webb Space Telescope, <a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/collections/james-webb-telescope/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">see our collection of posts here</a>.</em>
</p><p>
<strong>“Build something</strong> that will absolutely, positively work.” This was the mandate from NASA for designing and building the James Webb Space Telescope—at 6.5 meters wide the largest space telescope in history. Last December, <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7nT7JGZMbtM" target="_blank">JWST launched famously and successfully</a> to its observing station <a href="https://www.nasa.gov/topics/universe/features/webb-l2.html" target="_blank">out beyond the moon</a>. And now according to NASA, as soon as next week, the JWST will at long last<a rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"> begin</a><a href="https://www.nasa.gov/feature/goddard/2022/first-images-from-nasa-s-webb-space-telescope-coming-soon" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"> releasing</a> scientific images and data.
</p><p>
	Mark Kahan, on JWST’s product integrity team, recalls NASA’s engineering challenge as a call to arms for a worldwide team of thousands that set out to create one of the most ambitious scientific instruments in human history. Kahan—chief electro-optical systems engineer at Mountain View, Calif.–based Synopsys—and many others in JWST’s “pit crew” (as he calls the team) drew hard lessons from three decades ago, having helped repair another world-class space telescope with a debilitating case of flawed optics. Of course the Hubble Space Telescope is in low Earth orbit, and so a special space-shuttle mission to install corrective optics (
	<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/STS-61" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">as happened in 1993</a>) was entirely possible.
</p><p>
	Not so with the JWST.
</p><p>
	The meticulous care NASA demanded of JWST’s designers is all the more a necessity because Webb is well out of reach of repair crews. Its mission is to study the infrared universe, and that requires shielding the telescope and its sensors from both the heat of sunlight and the infrared glow of Earth. A good place to do that without getting too far from Earth is an empty patch of interplanetary space 1.5 million kilometers away (well beyond the moon’s orbit) near a spot physicists call the 
	<a href="https://www.nasa.gov/topics/universe/features/webb-l2.html" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">second Lagrange point, or L2</a>.
</p><p>
	The pit crew’s job was “down at the detail level, error checking every critical aspect of the optical design,” says Kahan. Having learned the hard way from Hubble, the crew insisted that every measurement on Webb’s optics be made in at least two different ways that could be checked and cross-checked. Diagnostics were built into the process, Kahan says, so that “you could look at them to see what to kick” to resolve any discrepancies. Their work had to be done on the ground, but their tests had to assess how the telescope would work in deep space at cryogenic temperatures.
</p><h2>
Three New Technologies for the Main Mirror
</h2><p>
	Superficially, Webb follows the design of all large reflecting telescopes. A big mirror collects light from stars, galaxies, nebulae, planets, comets, and other astronomical objects—and then focuses those photons onto a smaller secondary mirror that sends it to a third mirror that then ultimately directs the light to instruments that record images and spectra.
</p><p>
	Webb’s 
	<a href="https://www.jwst.nasa.gov/content/about/faqs/faq.html#mirrortests" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">6.5-meter primary mirror</a> is the first segmented mirror to be launched into space. All the optics had to be made on the ground at room temperature but were deployed in space and operated at 30 to 55 degrees above absolute zero. “We had to develop three new technologies” to make it work, says <a href="https://webb.nasa.gov/content/meetTheTeam/people/feinberg.html" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Lee D. Feinberg</a> of the NASA Goddard Space Flight Center, the optical telescope element manager for Webb for the past 20 years.
</p><p>
	The longest wavelengths that Hubble has to contend with were 2.5 micrometers, whereas 
	<a href="https://www.jwst.nasa.gov/content/about/comparisonWebbVsHubble.html" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Webb is built to observe</a> infrared light that stretches to 28 μm in wavelength. <a href="https://svs.gsfc.nasa.gov/13521" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Compared with Hubble</a>, whose primary mirror is a circle of an area 4.5 square meters, “[Webb’s primary mirror] had to be 25 square meters,” says Feinberg. Webb also “needed segmented mirrors that were lightweight, and its mass was a huge consideration,” he adds. No single-component mirror that could provide the required resolution would have fit on the Ariane 5 rocket that launched JWST. That meant the mirror would have to be made in pieces, assembled, folded, secured to withstand the stress of launch, then unfolded and deployed in space to create a surface that was within tens of nanometers of the shape specified by the designers.
</p><p class="shortcode-media shortcode-media-rebelmouse-image">
<img alt="Images of the James Webb Space Telescope and Hubble Space Telescope to scale, compared to a human figure, who is dwarfed by their size" class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="44f8217f64a3054f4d29e41a965301a3" data-rm-shortcode-name="rebelmouse-image" id="b2811" loading="lazy" src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/images-of-the-james-webb-space-telescope-and-hubble-space-telescope-to-scale-compared-to-a-human-figure-who-is-dwarfed-by-thei.jpg?id=30063396&width=980"/>
<small class="image-media media-caption" placeholder="Add Photo Caption...">The James Webb Space Telescope [left] and the Hubble Space Telescope side by side—with Hubble’s 2.4-meter-diameter mirror versus Webb’s array of hexagonal mirrors making a 6.5-meter-diameter light-collecting area. </small><small class="image-media media-photo-credit" placeholder="Add Photo Credit...">NASA Goddard Space Flight Center</small>
</p><p>
	NASA and the 
	<a href="https://www.af.mil/News/Article-Display/Article/138691/lab-reflects-mirror-technology/" target="_blank">U.S. Air Force, which has its own interests in large lightweight space mirrors for surveillance and focusing laser energy</a>, teamed up to develop the technology. The two agencies narrowed eight submitted proposals down to two approaches for building JWST’s mirrors: one based on low-expansion glass made of <a href="https://www.corning.com/worldwide/en/products/advanced-optics/product-materials/semiconductor-laser-optic-components/ultra-low-expansion-glass.html" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">a mixture of silicon and titanium dioxides</a> similar to that used in Hubble and the other the light but highly toxic metal beryllium. The most crucial issue came down to how well the materials could withstand temperature changes from room temperature on the ground to around 50 K in space. Beryllium won because it could fully release stress after cooling without changing its shape, and it’s not vulnerable to the cracking that can occur in glass. The final beryllium mirror was a 6.5-meter array of 18 hexagonal beryllium mirrors, each weighing about 20 kilograms. The weight per unit area of JWST’s mirror was only <a href="https://jwst.nasa.gov/content/observatory/ote/mirrors/index.html" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">10 percent of that in Hubble</a>. A 100-nanometer layer of pure gold makes the surface reflect 98 percent of incident light from JWST’s main observing band of 0.6 to 28.5 μm. “Pure silver has slightly higher reflectivity than pure gold, but gold is more robust,” says Feinberg. A thin layer of amorphous silica protects the metal film from surface damage.
</p><p>
	In addition, a wavefront-sensing control system keeps mirror segment surfaces 
	<a href="https://jwst-docs.stsci.edu/jwst-observatory-hardware/jwst-wavefront-sensing-and-control" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">aligned to within tens of nanometers</a>. Built on the ground, the system is expected to keep mirror alignment stabilized throughout the telescope’s operational life. A <a href="https://webb.nasa.gov/content/observatory/ote/backplane.html" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">backplane</a> kept at a temperature of 35 K holds all 2.4 tonnes of the telescope and instruments rock-steady to within 32 nm while maintaining them at cryogenic temperatures during observations.
</p><p class="shortcode-media shortcode-media-rebelmouse-image">
<img alt="Metal superstructure of cages and supports stands on a giant platform in a warehouse-sized clean-room. A man in a cleanroom suit watches the operations." class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="5f2636ec033ff78b389bd71d5c19a931" data-rm-shortcode-name="rebelmouse-image" id="05945" loading="lazy" src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/metal-superstructure-of-cages-and-supports-stands-on-a-giant-platform-in-a-warehouse-sized-clean-room-a-man-in-a-cleanroom-suit.jpg?id=30063381&width=980"/>
<small class="image-media media-caption" placeholder="Add Photo Caption...">The JWST backplane, the “spine” that supports the entire hexagonal mirror structure and carries more than 2,400 kg of hardware, is readied for assembly to the rest of the telescope. </small><small class="image-media media-photo-credit" placeholder="Add Photo Credit...">NASA/Chris Gunn</small>
</p><p>
	Hubble’s amazing, long-exposure images of distant galaxies are possible through the use of gyroscopes and reaction wheels. The gyroscopes are used to sense unwanted rotations, and reaction wheels are used to counteract them.
</p><p>
	But the gyroscopes used on Hubble have had a bad track record and have had to be replaced repeatedly. Only three of Hubble’s six gyros remain operational today, and NASA has devised plans for operating with one or two gyros at reduced capability. 
	<a href="https://www.nasa.gov/content/goddard/hubble-space-telescope-pointing-control-system" target="_blank">Hubble also includes reaction wheels and magnetic torquers</a>, used to maintain its orientation when needed or to point at different parts of the sky.<br/>
</p><p>
	Webb uses reaction wheels similarly to turn across the sky, but instead of using mechanical gyros to sense direction, 
	<a href="https://jwst.nasa.gov/content/forScientists/faqScientists.html#gyros" target="_blank">it uses hemispherical resonator gyroscopes</a>, which have no moving parts. Webb also has a small fine-steering mirror in the optical path, which can tilt over an angle of just 5 arc seconds. Those very fine adjustments of the light path into the instruments keep the telescope on target. “It’s a really wonderful way to go,” says Feinberg, adding that it compensates for small amounts of jitter without having to move the whole 6-tonne observatory.
</p><h2>
Instruments
</h2><p>
	Other optics distribute light from the fine-steering mirror among four instruments, two of which can observe simultaneously. Three instruments have sensors that observe wavelengths of 0.6 to 5 μm, which astronomers call the near-infrared. The fourth, called the Mid-InfraRed Instrument (MIRI), observes what astronomers call the mid-infrared spectrum, from 5 to 28.5 μm. Different instruments are needed because sensors and optics have limited wavelength ranges. (Optical engineers may blanch slightly at astronomers’ definitions of what constitutes the near- and mid-infrared wavelength ranges. These two groups simply have differing conventions for labeling the various regimes of the infrared spectrum.)
</p><p>
	Mid-infrared wavelengths are crucial for observing 
	<a href="https://blogs.nasa.gov/webb/2022/04/07/webbs-cool-view-on-how-stars-planets-form/" target="_blank">young stars and planetary systems</a> and <a href="https://asd.gsfc.nasa.gov/blueshift/index.php/2013/09/12/maggies-blog-why-infrared-earliest-galaxies-edition/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">the earliest galaxies</a>, but they also pose some of the biggest engineering challenges. Namely, everything on Earth and planets out to Jupiter glow in the mid-infrared. So for JWST to observe distant astronomical objects, it must avoid recording extraneous mid-infrared noise from all the various sources inside the solar system. “I have spent my whole career building instruments for wavelengths of 5 μm and longer,” says MIRI instrument scientist Alistair Glasse of the <a href="https://www.roe.ac.uk/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Royal Observatory, in Edinburgh</a>. “We’re always struggling against thermal background.”
</p><p>
	Mountaintop telescopes can see the near-infrared, but observing the mid-infrared sky requires telescopes in space. However, the thermal radiation from Earth and its atmosphere can cloud their view, and so can the telescopes themselves unless they are cooled far below room temperature. An ample supply of liquid helium and an orbit far from Earth allowed the 
	<a href="https://www.spitzer.caltech.edu/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Spitzer Space Telescope</a>’s <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Spitzer_Space_Telescope" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">primary observing mission to last</a> for five years, but once the last of the cryogenic fluid evaporated in 2009, its observations were limited to wavelengths shorter than 5 μm.
</p><p>
	Webb has an elaborate solar shield to block sunlight, and an orbit 1.5 million km from Earth that can keep the telescope to below 55 K, but that’s not good enough for low-noise observations at wavelengths longer than 5 μm. The near-infrared instruments operate at 40 K to minimize thermal noise. 
	<a href="https://jwst.nasa.gov/content/about/innovations/cryocooler.html" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">But for observations out to 28.5 μm, MIRI uses a specially developed closed-cycle, helium cryocooler to keep MIRI cooled below 7 K.</a> “We want to have sensitivity limited by the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Shot_noise" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">shot noise</a> of astronomical sources,” says Glasse. (<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Shot_noise" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Shot noise occurs when optical or electrical signals are so feeble that each photon or electron constitutes a detectable peak.</a>) That will make MIRI 1,000 times as sensitive in the mid-infrared as Spitzer.
</p><p>
	Another challenge is the limited transparency of optical materials in the mid-infrared. “We use reflective optics wherever possible,” says Glasse, but they also pose problems, he adds. “Thermal contraction is a big deal,” he says, because the instrument was made at room temperature but is used at 7 K. To keep thermal changes uniform throughout MIRI, they made the whole structure of gold-coated aluminum lest other metals cause warping.
</p><p>
	Detectors are another problem. Webb’s near-infrared sensors use mercury cadmium telluride photodetectors with a resolution of 2,048 x 2,048 pixels. This resolution is widely used at wavelengths below 5 μm, but sensing at
	<a href="https://jwst.nasa.gov/content/about/innovations/infrared.html" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"> MIRI’s longer wavelengths required</a> exotic detectors that are limited to offering only 1,024 x 1,024 pixels.
</p><p>
	Glasse says commissioning “has gone incredibly well.” Although some stray light has been detected, he says, “we are fully expecting to meet all our science goals.”
</p><h2>
NIRCam Aligns the Whole Telescope
</h2><p>
	The near-infrared detectors and optical materials used for observing at wavelengths shorter than 5 μm are much more mature than those for the mid-infrared, so the Near-Infrared Camera (NIRCam) does double duty by both recording images and aligning all the optics in the whole telescope. That alignment was the trickiest part of building the instrument, says NIRCam principal investigator 
	<a href="https://www.as.arizona.edu/people/faculty/marcia-j-rieke" target="_blank">Marcia Rieke</a> of the University of Arizona.
</p><p>
	Alignment means getting all the light collected by the primary mirror to get to the right place in the final image. That’s crucial for Webb, because it has 18 separate segments that have to overlay their images perfectly in the final image, and because all those segments were built on the ground at room temperature but operate at cryogenic temperatures in space at zero gravity. When NASA recorded a test image of a single star after Webb first opened its primary mirror, it showed 18 separate bright spots, one from each segment. 
	<a href="https://www.nasa.gov/press-release/nasa-s-webb-reaches-alignment-milestone-optics-working-successfully" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">When alignment was completed on 11 March, the image from NIRcam showed a single star with six spikes caused by diffraction.</a>
</p><p class="shortcode-media shortcode-media-rebelmouse-image">
<img alt="Image of a star with six-pointed spikes caused by diffraction " class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="900666e39577b81498f3fcd90499ee8b" data-rm-shortcode-name="rebelmouse-image" id="09ba9" loading="lazy" src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/image-of-a-star-with-six-pointed-spikes-caused-by-diffraction.jpg?id=30063386&width=980"/>
<small class="image-media media-caption" placeholder="Add Photo Caption...">Even when performing instrumental calibration tasks, JWST couldn’t help but showcase its stunning sensitivity to the infrared sky. The central star is what telescope technicians used to align JWST’s mirrors. But notice the distant galaxies and stars that photobombed the image too!</small><small class="image-media media-photo-credit" placeholder="Add Photo Credit...">NASA/STScI</small>
</p><p>
	Building a separate alignment system would have added to both the weight and cost of Webb, Rieke realized, and in the original 1995 plan for the telescope she proposed designing NIRCam so it could align the telescope optics once it was up in space as well as record images. “The only real compromise was that it required NIRCam to have exquisite image quality,” says Rieke, wryly. From a scientific point, she adds, using the instrument to align the telescope optics “is great because you know you’re going to have good image quality and it’s going to be aligned with you.” Alignment might be just a tiny bit off for other instruments. In the end, it took a team at Lockheed Martin to develop the computational tools to account for all the elements of thermal expansion.
</p><p>
	Escalating costs and delays had troubled Webb for years. But for Feinberg, “commissioning has been a magical five months.” It began with the sight of sunlight hitting the mirrors. The segmented mirror deployed smoothly, and after the near-infrared cameras cooled, the mirrors focused one star into 18 spots, then aligned them to put the spots on top of each other. “Everything had to work to get it to [focus] that well,” he says. It’s been an intense time, but for Feinberg, a veteran of the Hubble repair mission, commissioning Webb was “a piece of cake.”
</p><p>
<a href="https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/webb-telescopes-giant-mirror-struck-by-micrometeoroid/" target="_blank">NASA announced that between May 23rd and 25th, one segment of the primary mirror had been dinged by a micrometeorite bigger than the agency had expected</a> when it analyzed the potential results of such impacts. “Things do degrade over time,” Feinberg said. But he added that Webb had been engineered to minimize damage, and <a href="https://blogs.nasa.gov/webb/2022/06/08/webb-engineered-to-endure-micrometeoroid-impacts/" target="_blank">NASA said the event had not affected Webb’s operation schedule.</a>
</p><p>
<strong></strong><em> <strong>Corrections 26-28 July 2022: </strong>The story was updated </em><em>a) to reflect the fact that the Lagrange point L2 where Webb now orbits is not that of the "Earth-moon system" (as the story had originally reported) <em>but rather the Earth-sun system </em><br/>
	and b) to correct misstatements in the original posting about Webb's hardware for controlling its orientation.
	</em>
</p><p>
<em><strong>Corrections 12 Aug. 2022: </strong>Alistair Glasse's name was incorrectly spelled in a previous version of this story, as was NIRCam (which we'd spelled as NIRcam); Webb's tertiary mirror (we'd originally reported only its primary and secondary mirrors) was also called out in this version. <br/>
</em>
</p><p>
<em>This article appears in the September 2022 print issue as “Inside the Universe Machine.”</em>
</p>]]></description><pubDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2022 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spectrum.ieee.org/james-webb-telescope-optics</guid><category>James webb space telescope</category><category>Aerospace</category><category>Mirror</category><category>Nasa</category><category>Optics</category><category>Space telescopes</category><category>Type:cover</category><dc:creator>Jeff Hecht</dc:creator><media:content medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/fourteen-technicians-in-clean-room-suits-guide-the-hoisting-of-a-honeycombed-hexagon-mirrored-telescope-inside-a-giant-cleanroo.jpg?id=30063324&amp;width=980"></media:content></item><item><title>Pentagon Aims to Demo a Nuclear Spacecraft Within 5 Years</title><link>https://spectrum.ieee.org/nuclear-spacecraft</link><description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/a-rendering-of-an-apple-next-to-an-exploded-view-diagram-of-a-white-and-grey-sphere-with-a-small-orange-cylinder-at-its-center.jpg?id=29959462&width=2000&height=1500&coordinates=0%2C0%2C0%2C0"/><br/><br/><p>
	In the latest push for nuclear power in space, the Pentagon’s <a href="https://www.diu.mil/" target="_blank">Defense Innovation Unit</a> (DIU) <a href="https://www.diu.mil/latest/powering-the-future-of-space-exploration-diu-launching-next-generation" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">awarded a contract</a> in May to Seattle-based <a href="https://usnc.com/space/" target="_blank">Ultra Safe Nuclear</a> to advance its nuclear power and propulsion concepts. The company is making a soccer ball–size radioisotope battery it calls <a href="https://usnc.com/embercore/" target="_blank">EmberCore</a>. The DIU’s goal is to launch the technology into space for demonstration in 2027.
</p><p>
	Ultra Safe Nuclear’s system is intended to be lightweight, scalable, and usable as both a propulsion source and a power source. It will be specifically designed to give small-to-medium-size military spacecraft the ability to maneuver nimbly in the space between Earth orbit and the moon. The DIU effort is part of the U.S. military’s recently <a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2022/03/12/space-force-moon-pentagon-00016818" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">announced plans</a> to develop a surveillance network in cislunar space.
</p><p>
	Besides speedy space maneuvers, the DIU wants to power sensors and communication systems without having to worry about solar panels pointing in the right direction or batteries having enough charge to work at night, says <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/adam-schilffarth-4958253" target="_blank">Adam Schilffarth</a>, director of strategy at Ultra Safe Nuclear. “Right now, if you are trying to take radar imagery in Ukraine through cloudy skies,” he says, “current platforms can only take a very short image because they draw so much power.”
</p><p>
	Radioisotope power sources are well suited for small, uncrewed spacecraft, adds <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/chris-morrison-51039813" target="_blank">Christopher Morrison</a>, who is leading EmberCore’s development. Such sources rely on the radioactive decay of an element that produces energy, as opposed to nuclear fission, which involves splitting atomic nuclei in a controlled chain reaction to release energy. Heat produced by radioactive decay is converted into electricity using thermoelectric devices.
</p><p>
	Radioisotopes have provided heat and electricity for spacecraft <a href="https://world-nuclear.org/information-library/non-power-nuclear-applications/transport/nuclear-reactors-for-space.aspx" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">since 1961</a>. The <a href="https://mars.nasa.gov/msl/home/" target="_blank">Curiosity</a> and <a href="https://mars.nasa.gov/mars2020/" target="_blank">Perseverance</a> rovers on Mars, and deep-space missions including <a href="https://solarsystem.nasa.gov/missions/cassini/overview/" target="_blank">Cassini</a>, <a href="https://www.nasa.gov/mission_pages/newhorizons/main/index.html" target="_blank">New Horizons</a>, and <a href="https://voyager.jpl.nasa.gov/" target="_blank">Voyager</a> all use radioisotope batteries that rely on the decay of plutonium-238, which is nonfissile—unlike plutonium-239, which is used in weapons and power reactors.
</p><p>
	For EmberCore, Ultra Safe Nuclear has instead turned to medical isotopes such as cobalt-60 that are easier and cheaper to produce. The materials start out inert, and have to be charged with neutrons to become radioactive. The company encapsulates the material in a proprietary ceramic for safety.
</p><p>
	Cobalt-60 has a half-life of five years (compared to plutonium-238’s 90 years), which is enough for the cislunar missions that the DOD and NASA are looking at, Morrison says. He says that EmberCore should be able to provide 10 times as much power as a plutonium-238 system, providing over 1 million kilowatt-hours of energy using just a few pounds of fuel. “This is a technology that is in many ways commercially viable and potentially more scalable than plutonium-238,” he says.
</p><p>
	One downside of the medical isotopes is that they can produce high-energy X-rays in addition to heat. So Ultra Safe Nuclear wraps the fuel with a radiation-absorbing metal shield. But in the future, the EmberCore system could be designed for scientists to use the X-rays for experiments. “They buy this heater and get an X-ray source for free,” says Schilffarth. “We’ve talked with scientists who right now have to haul pieces of lunar or Martian regolith up to their sensor because the X-ray source is so weak. Now we’re talking about a spotlight that could shine down to do science from a distance.”
</p><p>
	Ultra Safe Nuclear’s contract is one of two awarded by the DIU—which aims to speed up the deployment of commercial technology through military use—to develop nuclear power and propulsion for spacecraft. The other contract was awarded to <a href="https://www.avalanche.energy/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Avalanche Energy</a>, which is making a lunchbox-size fusion device it calls an Orbitron. The device will use electrostatic fields to trap high-speed ions in slowly changing orbits around a negatively charged cathode. Collisions between the ions can result in fusion reactions that produce energetic particles.
</p><p>
	Both companies will use nuclear energy to power high-efficiency electric propulsion systems. Electric propulsion technologies such as ion thrusters, which use electromagnetic fields to accelerate ions and generate thrust, are more efficient than chemical rockets, which burn fuel. Solar panels typically power the ion thrusters that satellites use today to change their position and orientation. Schilffarth says that the higher power from EmberCore should give a greater velocity change of 10 kilometers per second in orbit than today’s electric propulsion systems.
</p><p>
	Ultra Safe Nuclear is also one of three companies developing <a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/nuclear-powered-rockets-get-a-second-look-for-travel-to-mars" target="_self">nuclear fission thermal propulsion systems</a> for NASA and the Department of Energy. Meanwhile, the Defense Advanced Research Projects Agency (DARPA) is <a href="https://www.ans.org/news/article-3946/dod-seeks-inspace-demo-of-nuclear-rocket-engine-in-fy-2026/" target="_blank">seeking companies</a> to develop a fission-based nuclear thermal rocket engine, with demonstrations expected in 2026.
</p><p>
<em>This article appears in the August 2022 print issue as “Spacecraft to Run on Radioactive Decay.”</em>
</p>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2022 16:44:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spectrum.ieee.org/nuclear-spacecraft</guid><category>Spacecraft</category><category>Radioactive</category><category>Nuclear fusion</category><category>Nuclear energy</category><dc:creator>Prachi Patel</dc:creator><media:content medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/a-rendering-of-an-apple-next-to-an-exploded-view-diagram-of-a-white-and-grey-sphere-with-a-small-orange-cylinder-at-its-center.jpg?id=29959462&amp;width=980"></media:content></item><item><title>DARPA Wants a Better, Badder Caspian Sea Monster</title><link>https://spectrum.ieee.org/darpa-liberty-lifter</link><description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/a-rendering-of-a-grey-seaplane-with-twin-fuselages-and-backwards-facing-propellers.png?id=29824204&width=2000&height=1500&coordinates=98%2C0%2C99%2C0"/><br/><br/><p>
	Arguably, the primary job of any military organization is moving enormous amounts of stuff from one place to another as quickly and efficiently as possible. Some of that stuff is weaponry, but the vast majority are things that support that weaponry—fuel, spare parts, personnel, and so on. At the moment, the U.S. military has two options when it comes to transporting large amounts of payload. Option one is boats (a sealift), which are efficient, but also slow and require ports. Option two is planes (an airlift), which are faster by a couple of orders of magnitude, but also expensive and require runways.
</p><p>
	To solve this, the Defense Advanced Research Projects Agency (DARPA) wants to combine traditional sealift and airlift with the 
	<a href="https://www.darpa.mil/program/liberty-lifter" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Liberty Lifter program</a><a href="https://www.darpa.mil/program/liberty-lifter" target="_blank"></a>, which aims to “design, build, and flight test an affordable, innovative, and disruptive seaplane” that “enables efficient theater-range transport of large payloads at speeds far exceeding existing sea lift platforms.”
</p><p class="shortcode-media shortcode-media-youtube">
<span class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="df229103923a683aec7b2c6e33175770" style="display:block;position:relative;padding-top:56.25%;"><iframe frameborder="0" height="auto" lazy-loadable="true" scrolling="no" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/IOnLpXVkkTU?rel=0" style="position:absolute;top:0;left:0;width:100%;height:100%;" width="100%"></iframe></span>
<small class="image-media media-photo-credit" placeholder="Add Photo Credit...">DARPA</small>
</p><p>
	DARPA is asking for a design like this to take advantage of ground effect, which occurs when an aircraft’s wing deflects air downward and proximity to the ground generates a cushioning effect due to the compression of air between the bottom of the wing and the ground. This boosts lift and lowers drag to yield a substantial overall improvement in efficiency. Ground effect works on both water and land, but you can take advantage of it for only so long on land before your aircraft runs into something. Which is why oceans are the ideal place for these aircraft—or ships, depending on your perspective.
</p><p>
	During the late 1980s, the Soviets (and later the Russians) leveraged ground effect in the design of a handful of awesomely bizarre ships and aircraft. There’s the 
	<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=H6GE1ZdQTqg" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">VVA-14</a>, which was also an airplane, along with the vehicle shown in DARPA’s video above, the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lun-class_ekranoplan" target="_blank"><em>Lun</em>-class ekranoplan</a>, which operated until the late 1990s. The video clip really does not do this thing justice, so here’s a better picture, taken a couple of years ago:
</p><p class="shortcode-media shortcode-media-rebelmouse-image">
<img alt="Oblique overhead view of a huge grey seaplane on the water" class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="d59abc71824006ab63a4c5806614c412" data-rm-shortcode-name="rebelmouse-image" id="5d206" loading="lazy" src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/oblique-overhead-view-of-a-huge-grey-seaplane-on-the-water.jpg?id=29824197&width=980"/>
<small class="image-media media-photo-credit" placeholder="Add Photo Credit..."><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/CDlqdzpgnpp/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Instagram</a></small>
</p><p>
	The 
	<em>Lun</em> (only one was ever made) had a wingspan of 44 meters and was powered by eight turbojet engines. It flew about 4 meters above the water at speeds of up to 550 kilometers per hour, and could transport almost 100,000 kilograms of cargo for 2,000 km. It was based on an earlier, even larger prototype (the largest aircraft in the world at the time) that the CIA spotted in satellite images in 1967 and which seems to have seriously freaked them out. It was nicknamed the Caspian Sea Monster, and it wasn’t until the 1980s that the West understood what it was and how it worked.
</p><p>
	In the mid 1990s, DARPA itself took a serious look at a stupendously large ground-effect vehicle of its own, the 
	<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Aerocon_Dash_1.6_wingship" target="_blank">Aerocon Dash 1.6 wingship</a>. The concept image below is of a 4.5-million-kg vehicle, 175 meters long with a 100-meter wingspan, powered by 20 (!) jet engines:
</p><p class="shortcode-media shortcode-media-rebelmouse-image">
<img alt="A black and white wireframe drawing of a huge streamlined aircraft" class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="5a2629b227e4874ba22c0e2355f5b37b" data-rm-shortcode-name="rebelmouse-image" id="ff2ed" loading="lazy" src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/a-black-and-white-wireframe-drawing-of-a-huge-streamlined-aircraft.jpg?id=29824198&width=980"/>
<small class="image-media media-photo-credit" placeholder="Add Photo Credit...">Wikipedia</small>
</p><p>
	With a range of almost 20,000 km at over 700 km/h, the wingship could have carried 3,000 passengers or 1.4 million kg of cargo. By 1994, though, DARPA had decided that the potential billion-dollar project to build a wingship like this was too risky, and canceled the whole thing.
</p><p class="shortcode-media shortcode-media-rebelmouse-image rm-resized-container rm-resized-container-25 rm-float-left" data-rm-resized-container="25%" style="float: left;">
<img alt="A concept image of a massive grey seaplane skimming over the ocean" class="rm-shortcode rm-resized-image" data-rm-shortcode-id="b945a1b129f13d09db19e9620082a45b" data-rm-shortcode-name="rebelmouse-image" id="96f42" loading="lazy" src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/a-concept-image-of-a-massive-grey-seaplane-skimming-over-the-ocean.jpg?id=29824201&width=980" style="max-width: 100%"/>
</p><p>
	Less than 10 years later, Boeing’s Phantom Works started exploring an enormous ground-effect aircraft, the 
	<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Boeing_Pelican" target="_blank">Pelican Ultra Large Transport Aircraft</a>. The Pelican would have been even larger than the Aerocon wingship, with a wingspan of 152 meters and a payload of 1.2 million kg—that’s about 178 shipping containers’ worth. Unlike the wingship, the Pelican would take advantage of ground effect to boost efficiency only in transit above water, but would otherwise use runways like a normal aircraft and be able to reach flight altitudes of 7,500 meters. Operating as a traditional aircraft and with an optimal payload, the Pelican would have a range of about 12,000 km. In ground effect, however, the range would have increased to 18,500 km, illustrating the appeal of designs like these. But Boeing dropped the project in 2005 to focus on lower cost, less risky options.
</p><p>
	We’d be remiss if we didn’t at least briefly mention two other massive aircraft: the 
	<a href="https://www.boeing.com/history/products/h-4-flying-boat.page" target="_blank">H-4 Hercules</a>, the cargo seaplane built by Hughes Aircraft Co. in the 1940s, and the <a href="https://www.stratolaunch.com/vehicles/carrier" target="_blank">Stratolaunch carrier aircraft</a>, which features a twin-fuselage configuration that DARPA seems to be favoring in its concept video for some reason.
</p><p>
	From the sound of DARPA’s announcement, they’re looking for something a bit more like the Pelican than the Aerocon Dash or the 
	<em>Lun</em>. DARPA wants the Liberty Lifter to be able to sustain flight out of ground effect if necessary, although it’s expected to spend most of its time over water for efficiency. It won’t use runways on land at all, though, and should be able to stay out on the water for 4 to 6 weeks at a time, operating even in rough seas—a significant challenge for ground-effect aircraft.
</p><p>
	DARPA is looking for an operational range of 7,500 km, with a maximum payload of at least 90,000 kg, including the ability to launch and recover amphibious vehicles. The hardest thing DARPA is asking for could be that, unlike most other X-planes, the Liberty Lifter should incorporate a “low cost design and construction philosophy” inspired by the mass-produced Liberty ships of World War II.
</p><p>
	With US $15 million to be awarded to up to two Liberty Lifter concepts, DARPA is hoping that at least one of those concepts will pass a system-level critical design review in 2025. If everything goes well after that, the first flight of a full-scale prototype vehicle could happen as early as 2027.
</p><p>
<em>This article appears in the September 2022 print issue as “DARPA Reincarnates Soviet-Era Sea Monster.”</em>
</p>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 19 May 2022 19:31:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spectrum.ieee.org/darpa-liberty-lifter</guid><category>Darpa</category><category>X-plane</category><category>Aircraft</category><dc:creator>Evan Ackerman</dc:creator><media:content medium="image" type="image/png" url="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/a-rendering-of-a-grey-seaplane-with-twin-fuselages-and-backwards-facing-propellers.png?id=29824204&amp;width=980"></media:content></item><item><title>Companies Vie to Build NASA’s Next Communications Network</title><link>https://spectrum.ieee.org/nasa-new-network-tdrs</link><description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/a-satellite-with-a-extended-circular-piece-flies-over-earth-s-horizon.jpg?id=29800832&width=2000&height=1500&coordinates=186%2C0%2C186%2C0"/><br/><br/><p>It was a great idea for its time—a network of <a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/search/?q=nasa" target="_self">NASA</a> communications satellites high in geostationary orbit, providing nearly continuous radio contact between controllers on the ground and some of the agency’s highest-profile missions: the <a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/launch-new-spaceship-spacex-nasa-news-history" target="_self">space shuttles</a>, the <a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/private-space-stations" target="_self">International Space Station</a>, the <a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/the-hubble-telescope-25-years" target="_self">Hubble Space Telescope</a>, and dozens of others.</p><p>The satellites were called <a href="https://www.nasa.gov/directorates/heo/scan/services/networks/tdrs_main" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">TDRS</a>—short for Tracking and Data Relay Satellite—and the first was launched in 1983 on the maiden voyage of the space shuttle Challenger. Twelve more would follow, quietly providing a backbone for NASA’s orbital operations. But they’ve gotten old, they’re expensive, and in the 40 years since they began, they’ve been outpaced by commercial satellite networks.</p><p>So what comes next? That’s the 278-million-dollar question—but, importantly, it’s not a multibillion-dollar question.</p><p class="pull-quote">“Now it’ll be just plug and play. They can concentrate on the mission, and they don’t have to worry about comms, because we provide that for them.”<br/>—Craig Miller, Viasat</p><p>NASA, following its mantra to get out of the business of routine space operations, has now awarded US $278.5 million in contracts to six companies: Amazon’s <a href="https://www.aboutamazon.com/news/tag/project-kuiper" target="_blank">Project Kuiper</a>, <a href="https://www.inmarsatgov.com/" target="_blank">Inmarsat Government</a>, <a href="https://ses-gs.com/" target="_blank">SES Government Solutions</a>, <a href="https://www.spacex.com/" target="_blank">SpaceX</a>, <a href="https://www.telesat.com/" target="_blank">Telesat</a>, and <a href="https://www.viasat.com/" target="_blank">Viasat</a>. The agency is asking them to offer services that are reliable, adaptable for all sorts of missions, easy for NASA to use, and—ideally—orders of magnitude less expensive than TDRS.</p><p>“It’s an ambitious wish list,” says <a href="https://www1.grc.nasa.gov/wp-content/uploads/Ka-Band-Conference_-Commercial-Communication-Services-for-NASA-Space-Missions.pdf" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Eli Naffah</a>, communications services project manager at NASA’s Glenn Research Center, in Cleveland. “We’re looking to have industry tell us, based on their capabilities and their business interests, what they would like to provide to us as a service that they would provide to others broadly.”</p><p class="shortcode-media shortcode-media-rebelmouse-image">
<img alt="A satellite  and Earth." class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="b5ddda11009e558ccc17cd5aa7afa4de" data-rm-shortcode-name="rebelmouse-image" id="d14fc" loading="lazy" src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/a-satellite-and-earth.jpg?id=29800909&width=980"/>
<small class="image-media media-caption" placeholder="Add Photo Caption...">Inmarsat now operates a number of geostationary satellites in their GX fleet. The <a href="https://space.skyrocket.de/doc_sdat/inmarsat-7.htm" target="_blank">projected GX7 satellite</a> [left] is expected to launch in 2023.</small><small class="image-media media-photo-credit" placeholder="Add Photo Credit...">Inmarsat Government</small></p><p>Satellite communication is one area that has taken off as a business proposition, independent of NASA’s space efforts. Internet and television transmission, GPS, phone service—all of these have become giant enterprises, ubiquitous in people’s lives. Economy of scale and competition have brought prices down dramatically. (That’s very different from, say, <a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/musk-vs-bezos-the-battle-of-the-space-billionaires-heats-up" target="_self">space tourism</a>, which attracts a lot of attention but for now is still something that only the very wealthy can afford.)</p><p>NASA benefits, in the case of communications, from being a relatively small player, especially if it can get out from under the costs of running something like the TDRS system. The commercial satellite companies take over those costs—which, they say, is fine, since they were spending the money anyway.</p><p>“We love having customers like NASA,” says <a href="https://www.viasat.com/about/who-we-are/Craig-Miller/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Craig Miller</a>, president for government systems at Viasat. “They’re a joy to work with, their mission is in alignment with a lot of our core values, but we make billions of dollars a year selling Internet to other sources.”</p><p>Each of the six companies under the new NASA contract takes a different approach. Inmarsat, SES, and Viasat, for instance, would use large relay satellites, like TDRS, each seeming to hover over a fixed spot on Earth’s equator because, at an altitude of 35,786 kilometers,  one orbit takes precisely 24 hours. Amazon and SpaceX, by contrast, would use swarms of smaller satellites in low Earth orbit, only 3,700 km in altitude. (SpaceX, at last count, had launched more than <a href="https://planet4589.org/space/stats/star/starstats.html" target="_blank">2,200 of its Starlink satellites</a>.) SES and Telesat would offer two-for-one packages, with service both from high and lower orbits. As for radio frequencies, the companies might use <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/C_band_(IEEE)" target="_blank">C band</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ka_band" target="_blank">K<sub>a </sub>band</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/L_band" target="_blank">L band</a>, optical—whatever their existing clients have needed. And so on.</p><p class="shortcode-media shortcode-media-rebelmouse-image">
<img alt="Two rows of stacked objects seen over the background of Earth." class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="4ed4f8de6413908bff16ca14cd552a75" data-rm-shortcode-name="rebelmouse-image" id="5bd00" loading="lazy" src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/two-rows-of-stacked-objects-seen-over-the-background-of-earth.jpg?id=29800895&width=980"/>
<small class="image-media media-caption" placeholder="Add Photo Caption...">Sixty SpaceX Starlink satellites wait for deployment from their launch rocket in low Earth orbit, in this photograph from 2019.</small><small class="image-media media-photo-credit" placeholder="Add Photo Credit...">SpaceX</small></p><p>It may sound like an alphabet soup of ways to solve one basic need—being in contact with its satellites—but engineers say that’s a minor trade-off for NASA if it can piggyback on others’ communications networks. “This allows NASA and our other government users to achieve their missions without the upfront capital expenditure and the full life-cycle cost” of running the TDRS system, said <a href="https://www.inmarsatgov.com/leadership-member/britt-lewis/" target="_blank">Britt Lewis</a>, a senior vice president of Inmarsat Government, in an email to <em>IEEE Spectrum</em>.<br/></p><p>One major advantage to the space agency would be the sheer volume of service available to it. In years past, the TDRS system could handle only so many transmissions at a time; if a particular mission needed to send a large volume of data, it had to book time in advance.</p><p>“Now it’ll be just plug and play,” says Miller at Viasat. “They can concentrate on the mission, and they don’t have to worry about comms, because we provide that for them.”</p><p>NASA says it expects each company will complete technology development and in-space demonstrations by 2025, with the most successful starting to take over operations for the agency by 2030. There will probably be no single winner: “We’re not really looking to have any one particular company be able to provide all the services on our list,” says NASA’s Naffah.</p><p class="shortcode-media shortcode-media-rebelmouse-image rm-resized-container rm-resized-container-25 rm-float-left" data-rm-resized-container="25%" style="float: left;">
<img alt="picture of a satellite in earth orbit" class="rm-shortcode rm-resized-image" data-rm-shortcode-id="c0d355dde26f8c365ff886d9b5e6364a" data-rm-shortcode-name="rebelmouse-image" id="caf09" loading="lazy" src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/picture-of-a-satellite-in-earth-orbit.jpg?id=29800903&width=980" style="max-width: 100%"/>
<small class="image-media media-caption" placeholder="Add Photo Caption...">NASA's <a href="https://www.nasa.gov/feature/tdrs-m-to-continue-vital-communications-link-to-space" target="_blank">TDRS-M</a> communications satellite launched in 2017. </small><small class="image-media media-photo-credit" placeholder="Add Photo Credit...">NASA</small></p><p>The TDRS satellites have proved durable; TDRS-3, launched by the space shuttle Discovery in 1988, is still usable as a spare if newer satellites break down. NASA says it will probably continue to use the system into the 2030s, but it planned no more launches after the last (of TDRS-13 a.k.a. TDRS-M) in 2017.</p><p>If everything works out, says Amazon in an email, “This model would allow organizations like NASA to rely on commercial operators for near-Earth communications while shifting their focus to more ambitious operations, like solving technical challenges for deep space exploration and science missions.”</p><p>At which point the sky's the limit. NASA focuses on the moon, Mars, and other exploration, while it buys routine services from the private sector.</p><p>“We can provide the same kind of broadband capabilities that you’re used to having on Earth,” says Viasat’s Miller. He smiles at this thought. “We can provide Netflix to the ISS.”</p>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 15:28:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spectrum.ieee.org/nasa-new-network-tdrs</guid><category>Nasa</category><category>Spacex</category><category>Amazon</category><category>Space communications</category><dc:creator>Ned Potter</dc:creator><media:content medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/a-satellite-with-a-extended-circular-piece-flies-over-earth-s-horizon.jpg?id=29800832&amp;width=980"></media:content></item><item><title>Take the Lead on Satellite Design Using Digital Engineering</title><link>https://connectlp.keysight.com/Satellite-Digital-Engineering?elqCampaignId=20968&amp;cmpid=ASC-2104798&amp;utm_source=ADSC&amp;utm_medium=ASC&amp;utm_campaign=301</link><description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/image.png?id=27151193&width=980"/><br/><br/><p>Win the race to design and deploy satellite technologies and systems. Learn how new digital engineering techniques can accelerate development and reduce your risk and costs. <a href="https://connectlp.keysight.com/Satellite-Digital-Engineering?elqCampaignId=20968&cmpid=ASC-2104798&utm_source=ADSC&utm_medium=ASC&utm_campaign=301" target="_blank">Download this free whitepaper now!</a></p><p><span></span>Our white paper covers:</p><ul><li>Software-based digital twin models to reduce costly satellite system re-design</li><li>Ways to improve models throughout the product lifecycle, increase confidence, and reduce risks</li></ul>]]></description><pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 18:22:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://connectlp.keysight.com/Satellite-Digital-Engineering?elqCampaignId=20968&amp;cmpid=ASC-2104798&amp;utm_source=ADSC&amp;utm_medium=ASC&amp;utm_campaign=301</guid><category>Keysight</category><category>Satellites</category><category>Software</category><category>Type:whitepaper</category><dc:creator>Keysight</dc:creator><media:content medium="image" type="image/png" url="https://assets.rbl.ms/27151193/origin.png"></media:content></item><item><title>Modern System Level Design for Aerospace &amp; Defense</title><link>https://connectlp.keysight.com/LP=33849?elqCampaignId=20920&amp;cmpid=ASC-2103904&amp;utm_source=ADSC&amp;utm_medium=ASC&amp;utm_campaign=301</link><description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/image.png?id=27151193&width=980"/><br/><br/><p>More than ever, aerospace and defense companies must lower costs, accelerate their R&D, and reduce risk, all while simultaneously maintaining a high level of mission readiness. <a href="https://connectlp.keysight.com/LP=33849?elqCampaignId=20920&cmpid=ASC-2103904&utm_source=ADSC&utm_medium=ASC&utm_campaign=301" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow" target="_blank">Register for this free webinar now!</a></p><p> <a href="https://connectlp.keysight.com/LP=33849?elqCampaignId=20920&cmpid=ASC-2103904&utm_source=ADSC&utm_medium=ASC&utm_campaign=301" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow" target="_blank">Keysight</a> is addressing these design challenges for RF and microwave applications, particularly for aerospace and defense applications. </p><p>In this series of one hour events, we cover the most important aspects of a modern system level design flow for this industry. <br/></p>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2022 13:00:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://connectlp.keysight.com/LP=33849?elqCampaignId=20920&amp;cmpid=ASC-2103904&amp;utm_source=ADSC&amp;utm_medium=ASC&amp;utm_campaign=301</guid><category>Keysight</category><category>Microwaves</category><category>Radio</category><category>Type:webinar</category><category>Microwave</category><dc:creator>Keysight</dc:creator><media:content medium="image" type="image/png" url="https://assets.rbl.ms/27151193/origin.png"></media:content></item><item><title>U.N. Kills Any Plans to Use Mercury as a Rocket Propellant</title><link>https://spectrum.ieee.org/mercury-ion-thruster-banned</link><description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/variously-sized-drops-of-a-silver-liquid-metal-beading-up-on-a-red-background.jpg?id=29686005&width=2000&height=1500&coordinates=0%2C0%2C0%2C0"/><br/><br/><p>A recent United Nations provision has banned the use of mercury in spacecraft propellant. Although no private company has actually used mercury propellant in a launched spacecraft, the possibility was alarming enough—and the dangers extreme enough—that the ban was enacted just a few years after one U.S.-based startup began toying with the idea. Had the company gone through with its intention to sell mercury propellant thrusters to some of the companies building massive satellite constellations over the coming decade, it would have resulted in Earth’s upper atmosphere being laced with mercury.</p><p>Mercury is a neurotoxin. It’s also bio-accumulative, which means it’s absorbed by the body at a faster rate than the body can remove it. The most common way to get mercury poisoning is through eating contaminated seafood. “It’s pretty nasty,” says Michael Bender, the international coordinator of the <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/michael-t-bender-45ab8a1a" target="_blank">Zero Mercury Working Group</a> (ZMWG). “Which is why this is one of the very few instances where the governments of the world came together pretty much unanimously and ratified a treaty.”</p><p>Bender is referring to the 2013 <a href="https://www.mercuryconvention.org/en" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Minamata Convention on Mercury</a>, a U.N. treaty named for a city in Japan <a href="https://news.un.org/en/story/2021/10/1103842" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">whose residents suffered from mercury poisoning</a> from a nearby chemical factory for decades. Because mercury pollutants easily find their way into the oceans and the atmosphere, it’s virtually impossible for one country to prevent mercury poisoning within its borders. “Mercury—it’s an intercontinental pollutant,” Bender says. “So it required a global treaty.”</p><p>Today, the only remaining permitted uses for mercury are in fluorescent lighting and dental amalgams, and even those are being phased out. Mercury is otherwise found as a by-product of other processes, such as the burning of coal. But then a company hit on the idea to use it as a spacecraft propellant.</p><p>In 2018, an employee at Apollo Fusion approached the Public Employees for Environmental Responsibility (PEER), a nonprofit that investigates environmental misconduct in the United States. The employee—who has remained anonymous—alleged that the Mountain View, Calif.–based space startup was planning to build and sell thrusters that used mercury propellant to multiple companies building low Earth orbit (LEO) satellite constellations.</p><p><a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2018-11-19/this-space-startup-could-lace-the-atmosphere-with-toxic-mercury" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Four industry insiders ultimately confirmed</a> that Apollo Fusion was building thrusters that utilized mercury propellant. Apollo Fusion, which <a href="https://astra.com/news/astra-acquires-apollo-fusion-to-reach-new-orbits/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">was acquired by rocket manufacturing startup Astra in June 2021</a>, insisted that the composition of its propellant mixture should be considered <a href="https://fcc.report/ELS/Astro-Digital-US-Inc/0330-EX-CN-2019/228069" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">confidential information</a>. The company withdrew its plans for a mercury propellant in April 2021. Astra declined to respond to a request for comment for this story.</p><p>Apollo Fusion wasn’t the first to consider using mercury as a propellant. NASA originally tested it in the 1960s and 1970s with two <a href="https://www.nasa.gov/centers/glenn/about/history/sert.html" target="_blank">Space Electric Propulsion Tests</a> (SERT), one of which was <a href="https://arc.aiaa.org/doi/abs/10.2514/3.25512?journalCode=jsr" target="_blank">sent into orbit in 1970</a>. Although the tests demonstrated mercury’s effectiveness as a propellant, the same concerns over the element’s toxicity that have seen it banned in many other industries halted its use by the space agency as well.</p><p>“I think it just sort of fell off a lot of folks’ radars,” says <a href="https://peer.org/author/kevin-bell/" target="_blank">Kevin Bell</a>, the staff counsel for PEER. “And then somebody just resurrected the research on it and said, ‘Hey, other than the environmental impact, this was a pretty good idea.’ It would give you a competitive advantage in what I imagine is a pretty tight, competitive market.”</p><p>That’s presumably why Apollo Fusion was keen on using it in their thrusters. Apollo Fusion as a startup emerged more or less simultaneously with the rise of <a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/amazons-project-kuiper-is-more-than-the-companys-response-to-spacex" target="_self">massive LEO constellations</a> that use hundreds or thousands of satellites in orbits below 2,000 kilometers to provide continual low-latency coverage. Finding a slightly cheaper, more efficient propellant for one large geostationary satellite doesn’t move the needle much. But doing the same for thousands of satellites that <a href="https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2017/10/spacex-and-oneweb-broadband-satellites-raise-fears-about-space-debris/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">need to be replaced every several years</a>? That’s a much more noticeable discount.</p><p>Were it not for mercury’s extreme toxicity, it would actually make an extremely attractive propellant. Apollo Fusion wanted to use a type of ion thruster called a Hall-effect thruster. Ion thrusters strip electrons from the atoms that make up a liquid or gaseous propellant, and then an electric field pushes the resultant ions away from the spacecraft, generating a modest thrust in the opposite direction. The physics of rocket engines means that the performance of these engines increases with the mass of the ion that you can accelerate.</p><p>Mercury is heavier than either xenon or krypton, the most commonly used propellants, meaning more thrust per expelled ion. It’s also liquid at room temperature, making it efficient to store and use. And it’s cheap—there’s not a lot of competition with anyone looking to buy mercury.</p><p>Bender says that ZMWG, alongside PEER, caught wind of Apollo Fusion marketing its mercury-based thrusters to at least three companies deploying LEO constellations—One Web, Planet Labs, and SpaceX. Planet Labs, an Earth-imaging company, has <a href="https://www.planet.com/pulse/planets-first-launch-of-2020-26-superdoves-on-a-vega/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">at least 200 CubeSats</a> in low Earth orbit. One Web and SpaceX, both wireless-communication providers, have many more. One Web plans to have <a href="https://oneweb.net/resources/oneweb-secures-investment-softbank-and-hughes-network-systems" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">nearly 650 satellites</a> in orbit by the end of 2022. SpaceX already has nearly 1,500 active satellites aloft in its Starlink constellation, with an eye toward <a href="https://fortune.com/2022/02/10/spacex-starlink-satellites-solar-storm-lost-elon-musk-internet/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">deploying as many as <em>30,000</em> satellites</a> before its constellation is complete. Other constellations, like Amazon’s Kuiper constellation, are also planning to deploy thousands of satellites.</p><p>In 2019, a group of researchers in Italy and the United States <a href="https://iopscience.iop.org/article/10.1088/1748-9326/ab4b75" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">estimated how much of the mercury used in spacecraft propellant</a> might find its way back into Earth’s atmosphere. They figured that a hypothetical LEO constellation of 2,000 satellites, each carrying 100 kilograms of propellant, would emit 20 tonnes of mercury every year over the course of a 10-year life span. Three quarters of that mercury, the researchers suggested, would eventually wind up in the oceans.</p><p>That amounts to 1 percent of global mercury emissions from a constellation only a fraction of the size of the one planned by SpaceX alone. And if multiple constellations adopted the technology, they would represent a significant percentage of global mercury emissions—especially, the researchers warned, as other uses of mercury are phased out as planned in the years ahead.</p><p>Fortunately, it’s unlikely that any mercury propellant thrusters will even get off the ground. Prior to the fourth meeting of the Minamata Convention, Canada, the European Union, and Norway highlighted the dangers of mercury propellant, alongside ZMWG. The provision to ban mercury usage in satellites <a href="https://peer.org/un-bans-mercury-satellite-propellants-under-new-minamata-treaty-provisions/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">was passed on 26 March 2022</a>.</p><p>The question now is enforcement. “Obviously, there aren’t any U.N. peacekeepers going into space to shoot down” mercury-based satellites, says Bell. But the 137 countries, including the United States, who are party to the convention have pledged to adhere to its provisions—including the propellant ban.</p><p>The United States is notable in that list because as Bender explains, it did not ratify the Minamata Convention via the U.S. Senate but instead deposited with the U.N. an instrument of acceptance. In a <a href="https://www.unep.org/news-and-stories/press-release/global-treaty-mercury-pollution-gets-boost-united-states" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">7 November 2013 statement</a> (about one month after the original Minamata Convention was adopted), the U.S. State Department said the country would be able to fulfill its obligations “under existing legislative and regulatory authority.”</p><p>Bender says the difference is “weedy” but that this appears to mean that the U.S. government has agreed to adhere to the Minamata Convention’s provisions because it already has similar laws on the books. Except there is still no existing U.S. law or regulation banning mercury propellant. For Bender, that creates some uncertainty around compliance when the provision goes into force in 2025.</p><p>Still, with a U.S. company being the first startup to toy with mercury propellant, it might be ideal to have a stronger U.S. ratification of the Minamata Convention before another company hits on the same idea. “There will always be market incentives to cut corners and do something more dangerously,” Bell says.</p><p><em>Update 19 April 2022: </em>In an email, a spokesperson for Astra stated that the company's propulsion system, the <a href="https://astra.com/space-products/astra-spacecraft-engine/" target="_blank">Astra Spacecraft Engine</a>, does not use mercury. The spokesperson also stated that Astra has no plans to use mercury propellant and that the company does not have anything in orbit that uses mercury.<br/></p><p><em>Updated 20 April 2022 to clarify that Apollo Fusion was building thrusters that used mercury, not that they had actually used them. </em></p>]]></description><pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2022 18:00:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spectrum.ieee.org/mercury-ion-thruster-banned</guid><category>Spacecraft</category><category>Thruster</category><category>Mercury</category><category>Ion thruster</category><category>Space</category><dc:creator>Michael Koziol</dc:creator><media:content medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/variously-sized-drops-of-a-silver-liquid-metal-beading-up-on-a-red-background.jpg?id=29686005&amp;width=980"></media:content></item><item><title>A Helicopter Will Try to Catch a Rocket Booster in Midair</title><link>https://spectrum.ieee.org/rocket-booster-rocket-lab</link><description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/a-digital-rendering-of-a-spacecraft-booster-falling-back-into-earth-s-atmosphere.jpg?id=29693520&width=2000&height=1500&coordinates=240%2C0%2C240%2C0"/><br/><br/><p>
	The longest journey begins with a single step, and that step gets expensive when you’re in the space business. Take, for example, the Electron booster made by 
	<a href="https://www.rocketlabusa.com/" target="_blank">Rocket Lab</a>, a company with two launch pads on the New Zealand coast and another awaiting use in Virginia. Earth’s gravity is so stubborn that, by necessity, two-thirds of the rocket is its first stage—and it has historically ended up as trash on the ocean floor after less than 3 minutes of flight.<br/>
</p><p>
	Making those boosters reusable—saving them from a saltwater grave, and therefore saving a lot of money—has been a goal of aerospace engineers since the early space age. Elon Musk’s 
	<a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/tag/spacex" target="_self">SpaceX</a> has famously been landing its Falcon 9 boosters on drone ships off the Florida coast—<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=KDK5TF2BOhQ" target="_blank">mind-bending to watch</a> but very hard to pull off.
</p><p>
	Rocket Lab says it has another way. Iits next flight will carry 34 commercial satellites—and instead of being dropped in the Pacific, the spent first stage will be snared in midair by a helicopter as it descends by parachute. It will then be brought back to base, seared by the heat of reentry but inwardly intact, for possible refurbishment and reuse. The team, in its determination to minimize its odds of dropping the ball, so to speak, has pushed back the launch several times in order to wait out inclement weather. They reason that because this isn’t a game of horseshoes, close is not good enough.
</p><p>
	“It’s a very complex thing to do,” says 
	<a href="https://www.rocketlabusa.com/about/team/" target="_blank">Morgan Bailey</a> of Rocket Lab. “You have to position the helicopter in exactly the right spot, you have to know exactly where the stage is going to be coming down, you have to be able to slow it enough,” she says. “We’ve practiced and practiced all of the individual puzzle pieces, and now it’s putting them together. It’s not a foregone conclusion that the first capture attempt will be a success.”
</p><p>
	Still, people in the space business will be watching, since Rocket Lab has established a niche for itself as a viable space company. This will be its 26th Electron launch. The company says it has launched 112 satellites so far, many of them 
	<a data-linked-post="2650275029" href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/the-tricks-to-launching-many-satellites-on-one-rocket" target="_blank">so-called smallsats</a> that are relatively inexpensive to fly. “Right now, there are two companies taking payloads to orbit: SpaceX and Rocket Lab,” says <a href="https://www.spacecapital.com/team" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Chad Anderson</a>, CEO of Space Capital, a firm that funds space startups.
</p><blockquote class="rm-embed twitter-tweet" data-partner="rebelmouse" data-twitter-tweet-id="1511331067629760513">
<div style="margin:1em 0">It\u2019s time\u2026\u2026.Launch - Catch - Launchhttps://twitter.com/RocketLab/status/1511314645138567169\u00a0\u2026</div> — Peter Beck (@Peter Beck)
        <a href="https://twitter.com/Peter_J_Beck/statuses/1511331067629760513">1649164380</a>
</blockquote>
<script async="" charset="utf-8" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js"></script><p>
	Here's the flight profile. The Electron is 18 meters tall; the bottom 12 meters are the first stage. For this mission it will lift off from New Zealand on its way to a sun-synchronous orbit 520 kilometers high. The first stage burns out after the first 70 km. Two minutes and 32 seconds into the flight, it drops off, following a long arc that in the past would have sent it crashing into the ocean, about 280 km downrange.
</p><p>
	But Rocket Lab has now equipped its booster with heat shielding, protecting it as it falls tail-first at up to 8,300 kilometers per hour. Temperatures should reach 2,400 °C as the booster is slowed by the air around it.
</p><p>
	At an altitude of 13 km, a small 
	<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Drogue_parachute" target="_blank">drogue parachute </a>is deployed from the top end of the rocket stage, followed by a main chute at about 6 km, less than a minute later. The parachute slows the rocket substantially, so that it is soon descending at only about 36 km/h.
</p><p class="shortcode-media shortcode-media-rebelmouse-image">
<img alt="Rendering of helicopter after catching the spent Electron rocket first stage in midair." class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="c59981ae92bdc9ad2a889721f5296e59" data-rm-shortcode-name="rebelmouse-image" id="9196e" loading="lazy" src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/rendering-of-helicopter-after-catching-the-spent-electron-rocket-first-stage-in-midair.jpg?id=29693535&width=980"/>
<small class="image-media media-caption" placeholder="Add Photo Caption...">An artist’s conception shows the helicopter after catching the spent Electron rocket’s first stage in midair.</small><small class="image-media media-photo-credit" placeholder="Add Photo Credit...">Rocket Lab</small>
</p><p>
	But even that would make for a hard splashdown—which is why a Sikorsky S-92 helicopter hovers over the landing zone, trailing a grappling hook on a long cable. The plan is for the helicopter to fly over the descending rocket and snag the parachute cables. The rocket never gets wet; the chopper secures it and either lowers it onto a ship or carries it back to land. Meanwhile—let’s not lose sight of the prime mission—the second stage of the rocket should reach orbit about 10 minutes after launch.
</p><p>
	“You have to keep the booster out of the water,” says Anderson. “If they can do that, it’s a big deal.” Many space people will recall NASA’s 
	<a href="https://www.nasa.gov/exploration/systems/sls/fs/solid-rocket-booster.html" target="_blank">solid rocket boosters</a>, which helped launch the space shuttles and then parachuted into the Atlantic; towing them back to port and cleaning them up for reuse was slow and expensive. NASA’s giant <a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/nasas-space-launch-system-will-lift-off" target="_self">SLS rocket</a> uses the same boosters, but there are no plans to recover them.
</p><p>
	So midair recovery is far better, though it’s not new. As long ago as 1960, the U.S. Air Force snagged a returning capsule from a mission called 
	<a href="https://airandspace.si.edu/explore-and-learn/multimedia/detail.cfm?id=4281" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Discoverer 14</a>. But that had nothing to do with economy; the Discoverers were actually <a href="https://airandspace.si.edu/events/techquest/past-missions/eye-in-the-sky/corona.cfm" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Corona</a> reconnaissance satellites, and they were sending back film of the Soviet Union—priceless for Cold War intelligence.
</p><p>
	Rocket Lab tries to sound more playful about its missions: It gives them names like “A Data With Destiny” or “Without Mission a Beat.” This newest flight, with its booster-recovery attempt, is called “There and Back Again.”
</p><p>
	A teenager 
	<a href="https://twitter.com/EmmettReis/status/1512205706342055946" target="_blank">tweeted</a> to CEO Peter Beck: “It would have been cool if the mission was called ‘Catch Me If You Can.’”
</p><p>
	“Oh…that’s good!” Beck 
	<a href="https://twitter.com/Peter_J_Beck/status/1512207819986022429" target="_blank">replied</a>. “Congratulations, you have just named the very next recovery mission.”<br/>
</p><p>
<em>Update 22 April 2022: </em>In a tweet, Rocket Lab announced that due to weather, the planned launch and recovery would be rescheduled <a href="https://twitter.com/RocketLab/status/1517328086345281536" target="_blank">for 27 April at the earliest</a>.<br/>
</p><p>
<em>This article appears in the July 2022 print issue as “Rocket Lab Catches Rocket Booster in Midair.”</em>
</p>]]></description><pubDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2022 18:28:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spectrum.ieee.org/rocket-booster-rocket-lab</guid><category>Rocket launch</category><category>Space flight</category><category>Rockets</category><dc:creator>Ned Potter</dc:creator><media:content medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/a-digital-rendering-of-a-spacecraft-booster-falling-back-into-earth-s-atmosphere.jpg?id=29693520&amp;width=980"></media:content></item><item><title>Applications Guide: 3D Printed Low-Loss Dielectric Structures Addressing Microwave/mmWave Challenges</title><link>https://engineeringresources.spectrum.ieee.org/free/w_defa2421/prgm.cgi</link><description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/applications-guide-3d-printed-low-loss-dielectric-structures-addressing-microwave-mmwave-challenges.gif?id=29673634&width=2000&height=1500&coordinates=76%2C0%2C77%2C0"/><br/><br/><p>Traditional fabrication approaches of Microwave/mmWave dielectrics have material, geometry, tolerance, and/or repeatability challenges. New 3D printable resins with desirable Microwave/mmWave characteristics are enabling 3D DLP manufacturing of low-loss and low-dielectric constant material for prototyping and production. This whitepaper discusses applications of this 3D dielectric structure fabrication process.</p>]]></description><pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2022 22:51:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://engineeringresources.spectrum.ieee.org/free/w_defa2421/prgm.cgi</guid><category>Type:whitepaper</category><dc:creator>Fortify</dc:creator><media:content medium="image" type="image/gif" url="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/applications-guide-3d-printed-low-loss-dielectric-structures-addressing-microwave-mmwave-challenges.gif?id=29673634&amp;width=980"></media:content></item><item><title>Speed Up Device Test and Stretch Your Budget</title><link>https://connectlp.keysight.com/LP=32100?elqCampaignId=19912&amp;cmpid=ASC-2103050&amp;utm_source=ADSC&amp;utm_medium=ASC&amp;utm_campaign=301</link><description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/image.png?id=27151193&width=980"/><br/><br/><p><a href="https://connectlp.keysight.com/LP=32100?elqCampaignId=19912&cmpid=ASC-2103050&utm_source=ADSC&utm_medium=ASC&utm_campaign=301" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow" target="_blank">Download the ebook</a> and learn about four network analyzer capabilities that make next-generation testing more efficient.</p><p>Now you can conduct time-domain analysis, spectrum analysis, and more with a single connection to a network analyzer.<br/>If cash is scarce, stay on track with affordable rentals of Keysight’s latest network analyzers and other RF test instruments.</p><p>Why rent?<br/></p><ul><li>Flexible financial terms: use your operating budget, finance, or purchase over time</li><li>Overnight delivery</li><li>Excellent service and support</li></ul>]]></description><pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2022 13:26:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://connectlp.keysight.com/LP=32100?elqCampaignId=19912&amp;cmpid=ASC-2103050&amp;utm_source=ADSC&amp;utm_medium=ASC&amp;utm_campaign=301</guid><category>Test and measurement</category><category>Keysight</category><category>Type:whitepaper</category><dc:creator>Keysight</dc:creator><media:content medium="image" type="image/png" url="https://assets.rbl.ms/27151193/origin.png"></media:content></item><item><title>Meet the Lunar Gateway’s Robot Caretakers</title><link>https://spectrum.ieee.org/lunar-gateway-robots</link><description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/an-artist-s-concept-of-a-large-robotic-arm-on-the-exterior-of-a-space-station-orbiting-the-moon.jpg?id=29647407&width=2000&height=1500&coordinates=240%2C0%2C240%2C0"/><br/><br/><p>
	An integral part of NASA’s plan to return astronauts to the moon this decade is the 
	<a href="https://www.nasa.gov/gateway" target="_blank">Lunar Gateway</a>, a space station that will be humanity’s first permanent outpost outside of low Earth orbit. Gateway, a partnership between <a href="http://nasa.gov" target="_blank">NASA</a>, the <a href="https://www.asc-csa.gc.ca/eng/astronomy/moon-exploration/lunar-gateway.asp" target="_blank">Canadian Space Agency</a> (CSA), the <a href="https://www.esa.int/Science_Exploration/Human_and_Robotic_Exploration/Exploration/Gateway" target="_blank">European Space Agency</a> (ESA), and the <a href="https://global.jaxa.jp/press/2019/03/20190312b.html" target="_blank">Japan Aerospace Exploration Agency</a> (JAXA), is intended to support operations on the lunar surface while also serving as a staging point for exploration to Mars.
</p><p>
<a data-linked-post="2650278695" href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/nasas-lunar-space-station-is-a-greatterrible-idea" target="_blank">Gateway</a> will be significantly smaller than the <a data-linked-post="2654777916" href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/naukas-troubled-flight-t" target="_blank">International Space Station</a> (ISS), initially consisting of just two modules with additional modules to be added over time. The first pieces of the station to reach lunar orbit will be the <a href="https://www.nasa.gov/feature/glenn/2021/we-are-fired-up-gateway-propulsion-system-passes-first-test" target="_blank">Power and Propulsion Element (PPE)</a> attached to the <a href="https://news.northropgrumman.com/news/releases/northrop-grumman-finalizes-contract-with-nasa-to-complete-first-crew-module-for-artemis-program" target="_blank">Habitation and Logistics Outpost (HALO)</a>, <a href="https://www.nasa.gov/press-release/nasa-awards-contract-to-launch-initial-elements-for-lunar-outpost/" target="_blank">scheduled to launch</a> together on a <a href="https://www.spacex.com/vehicles/falcon-heavy/" target="_blank">SpaceX Falcon Heavy</a> rocket in November 2024. The relatively small size of Gateway is possible because the station won’t be crewed most of the time—astronauts may pass through for a few weeks, but the expectation is that Gateway will spend about 11 months out of the year without anyone on board.
</p><hr/><p>
	This presents some unique challenges for Gateway. On the ISS, astronauts spend a substantial amount of time on station upkeep, but Gateway will have to keep itself functional for extended periods without any direct human assistance.
</p><p>
	“The things that the crew does on the International Space Station will need to be handled by Gateway on its own,” explains 
	<a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/julia-badger-b690094/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Julia Badger</a>, Gateway autonomy system manager at NASA’s Johnson Space Center. “There’s also a big difference in the operational paradigm. Right now, ISS has a mission control that’s full time. With Gateway, we’re eventually expecting to have just 8 hours a week of ground operations.” The hundreds of commands that the ISS receives every day to keep it running will still be necessary on Gateway—they’ll just have to come from Gateway itself, rather than from humans back on Earth.
</p><p class="pull-quote">
	“It’s a new way of thinking compared to ISS. If something breaks on Gateway, we either have to be able to live with it for a certain amount of time, or we’ve got to have the ability to remotely or autonomously fix it.” —<em>Julia Badger, NASA JSC</em>
</p><p>
	To make this happen, NASA is developing a 
	<a href="https://www.nasa.gov/collection-asset/gateway-vehicle-systems-management-demonstration-completed-0" target="_blank">vehicle system manager</a>, or VSM, that will act like the omnipresent computer system found on virtually every science-fiction starship. The VSM will autonomously manage all of Gateway’s functionality, taking care of any problems that come up, to the extent that they can be managed with clever software and occasional input from a distant human. “It’s a new way of thinking compared to ISS,” explains Badger. “If something breaks on Gateway, we either have to be able to live with it for a certain amount of time, or we’ve got to have the ability to remotely or autonomously fix it.”
</p><p>
	While Gateway itself can be thought of as a robot of sorts, there’s a limited amount that can be reasonably and efficiently done through dedicated automated systems, and NASA had to find a compromise between redundancy and both complexity and mass. For example, there was some discussion about whether Gateway’s hatches should open and close on their own, and NASA ultimately decided to leave the hatches manually operated. But that doesn’t necessarily mean that Gateway won’t be able to open its hatches without human assistance; it just means that there will be a need for robotic hands rather than human ones.
</p><p>
	“I hope eventually we have robots up there that can open the hatches,” Badger tells us. She explains that Gateway is being designed with potential intravehicular robots (IVRs) in mind, including things like adding visual markers to important locations, placing convenient charging ports around the station interior, and designing the hatches such that the force required to open them is compatible with the capabilities of robotic limbs. Parts of Gateway’s systems may be modular as well, able to be removed and replaced by robots if necessary. “What we’re trying to do,” Badger says, “is make smart choices about Gateway’s design that don’t add a lot of mass but that will make it easier for a robot to work within the station.”
</p><p class="shortcode-media shortcode-media-rebelmouse-image">
<img alt="A human-sized white humanoid robot with a golden helmet and visor, in front of a task board on the International Space Station" class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="a1be5f40d0caada309af13e9b48ac6c1" data-rm-shortcode-name="rebelmouse-image" id="4f1df" loading="lazy" src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/a-human-sized-white-humanoid-robot-with-a-golden-helmet-and-visor-in-front-of-a-task-board-on-the-international-space-station.jpg?id=29647419&width=980"/>
<small class="image-media media-caption" placeholder="Add Photo Caption...">Robonaut at its test station in front of a manipulation task board on the ISS.</small><small class="image-media media-photo-credit" placeholder="Add Photo Credit...">JSC/NASA</small>
</p><p>
	NASA already has a substantial amount of experience with IVR. 
	<a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/tag/robonaut-2" target="_blank">Robonaut 2</a>, a full-size humanoid robot, spent several years on the International Space Station starting in 2011, learning how to perform tasks that would otherwise have to be done by human astronauts. More recently, a trio of cubical, toaster-size, free-flying robots called <a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/tag/Astrobee?topic=robotics" target="_blank">Astrobees</a> have taken up residence on the ISS, where they’ve been experimenting with autonomous sensing and navigation. A NASA project called <a href="https://www.nasa.gov/directorates/spacetech/game_changing_development/projects/ISAAC" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">ISAAC</a> (Integrated System for Autonomous and Adaptive Caretaking) is currently exploring how robots like Astrobee could be used for a variety of tasks on Gateway, from monitoring station health to autonomously transferring cargo, although at least in the near term, in Badger’s opinion, “maintenance of Gateway, like using robots that can switch out broken components, is going to be more important than logistics types of tasks.”
</p><p>
	Badger believes that a combination of a generalized mobile manipulator like Robonaut 2 and a free flyer like Astrobee make for a good team, and this combination is currently the general concept for Gateway IVR. This is not to say that the intravehicular robots that end up on Gateway will look like the robots that have been working on the ISS, but they’ll be inspired by them, and will leverage all of the experience that NASA has gained with its robots on ISS so far. It might also be useful to have a limited number of specialized robots, Badger says. “For example, if there was a reason to get behind a rack, you may want a snake-type of robot for that.”
</p><p class="shortcode-media shortcode-media-rebelmouse-image">
<img alt="A casually dressed astronaut holds a toaster-sized cubical robot on the International Space Station" class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="4a7cf4b8184f22a5f507df9f08013bfd" data-rm-shortcode-name="rebelmouse-image" id="80d9b" loading="lazy" src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/a-casually-dressed-astronaut-holds-a-toaster-sized-cubical-robot-on-the-international-space-station.jpg?id=29647421&width=980"/>
<small class="image-media media-caption" placeholder="Add Photo Caption...">An Astrobee robot (this one is named Bumble) on the ISS.</small><small class="image-media media-photo-credit" placeholder="Add Photo Credit...">JSC/NASA</small>
</p><p>
	While NASA is actively preparing for intravehicular robots on Gateway, such robots do not yet exist, and the agency may not be building these robots itself, instead relying on industry partners to deliver designs that meet NASA’s requirements. At launch, and likely for the first several years at least, Gateway will have to take care of itself without internal robotic assistants. However, one of the goals of Gateway is to operate itself completely autonomously for up to three weeks without any contact with Earth at all, mimicking the three-week solar conjunction between Earth and Mars where the sun blocks any communications between the two planets. “I think that we will get IVR on board,” Badger says. “If we really want Gateway to be able to take care of itself for 21 days, IVR is going to be a very important part of that. And having a robot is absolutely something that I think is going to be necessary as we move on to Mars.”
	<br/>
</p><p class="pull-quote">
	“Having a robot is absolutely something that I think is going to be necessary as we move on to Mars.” —<em>Julia Badger, NASA JSC</em>
</p><p>
	Intravehicular robots are just half of the robotic team that will be necessary to keep Gateway running autonomously long-term. Space stations rely on complex external infrastructure for power, propulsion, thermal control, and much more. Since 2001, the ISS has been home to Canadarm2, a 17.6-meter robotic arm, which is able to move around the station to grasp and manipulate objects while under human control from either inside the station or from the ground.
</p><p>
	The Canadian Space Agency, in partnership with space technology company MDA, is developing a new robotic-arm system for Gateway, called 
	<a href="https://www.asc-csa.gc.ca/eng/canadarm3/about.asp" target="_blank">Canadarm3</a>, scheduled to launch in 2027. Canadarm3 will include an 8.5-meter-long arm for grappling spacecraft and moving large objects, as well as a smaller, more dexterous robotic arm that can be used for delicate tasks. The smaller arm can even repair the larger arm if necessary. But what really sets Canadarm3 apart from its predecessors is how it’s controlled, according to <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/daniel-rey-214828a2/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Daniel Rey</a>, Gateway chief engineer and systems manager at CSA. “One of the very novel things about Canadarm3 is its ability to operate autonomously, without any crew required,” Rey says. This capability relies on a new generation of software and hardware that gives the arm a sense of touch as well as the ability to react to its environment without direct human supervision.
</p><p class="pull-quote">
	“With Canadarm3, we realize that if we want to get ready for Mars, more autonomy will be required.” —<em>Daniel Rey, CSA</em>
</p><p>
	Even though Gateway will be a thousand times farther away from Earth than the ISS, Rey explains that the added distance (about 400,000 kilometers) isn’t what really necessitates Canadarm3’s added autonomy. “Surprisingly, the location of Gateway in its orbit around the moon has a time delay to Earth that is not all that different from the time delay in low Earth orbit when you factor in various ground stations that signals have to pass through,” says Rey. “With Canadarm3, we realize that if we want to get ready for Mars, where that will no longer be the case, more autonomy will be required.”
</p><p>
	Canadarm3’s autonomous tasks on Gateway will include external inspection, unloading logistics vehicles, deploying science payloads, and repairing Gateway by swapping damaged components with spares. Rey tells us that there will also be a science logistics airlock, with a moving table that can be used to pass equipment in and out of Gateway. “It’ll be possible to deploy external science, or to bring external systems inside for repair, and for future internal robotic systems to cooperate with Canadarm3. I think that’ll be a really exciting thing to see.”
</p><p>
	Even though it’s going to take a couple of extra years for Gateway’s robotic residents to arrive, the station will be operating mostly autonomously (by necessity) as soon as the Power and Propulsion Element and the Habitation and Logistics Outpost begin their journey to lunar orbit in November o2024. Several science payloads will be along for the ride, including heliophysics and space weather experiments.
</p><p>
	Gateway itself, though, is arguably the most important experiment of all. Its autonomous systems, whether embodied in internal and external robots or not, will be undergoing continual testing, and Gateway will need to prove itself before we’re ready to trust its technology to take us into deep space. In addition to being able to operate for 21 days without communications, one of Gateway’s eventual requirements is to be able to function for up to three years without any crew visits. This is the level of autonomy and reliability that we’ll need to be prepared for our exploration of Mars, and beyond.
</p>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2022 18:40:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spectrum.ieee.org/lunar-gateway-robots</guid><category>Space robots</category><category>Autonomy</category><category>Lunar gateway</category><category>Nasa</category><category>Robotics</category><dc:creator>Evan Ackerman</dc:creator><media:content medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/an-artist-s-concept-of-a-large-robotic-arm-on-the-exterior-of-a-space-station-orbiting-the-moon.jpg?id=29647407&amp;width=980"></media:content></item><item><title>Puzzling Out the Drone War Over Ukraine</title><link>https://spectrum.ieee.org/ukraine-drone-war</link><description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/a-man-in-combat-fatigues-pushes-a-military-drone-across-an-airport-tarmac-while-another-man-in-fatigues-walks-away.jpg?id=29590718&width=2000&height=1500&coordinates=66%2C0%2C0%2C0"/><br/><br/><p>In 2014, Ukrainian soldiers fighting in Crimea knew that the sight of Russian drones would soon be followed by a heavy barrage of Russian artillery. During that war, the Russian military <a href="https://www.defenseone.com/ideas/2022/03/where-are-russias-drones/362612/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">integrated drones into tactical missions</a>, using them to hunt for Ukrainian forces, whom they <a href="https://breakingdefense.com/2015/10/russian-drone-threat-army-seeks-ukraine-lessons/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">then pounded with artillery and cannon fire</a>. Russian drones weren’t as advanced as those of their Western counterparts, but the Russian military’s integration of drones into its battlefield tactics was second to none.</p><p>Eight years later, the Russians are again invading Ukraine. And since the earlier incursion, the Russian military has spent approximately US $9 billion to domestically produce an armada of <a href="http://drones.cnas.org/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/A-Perspective-on-Russia-Proliferated-Drones.pdf" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">some 500 drones</a> (a.k.a. unmanned aerial vehicles, or UAVs). But, astonishingly, three weeks into this invasion, the Russians have not had anywhere near their previous level of success with their drones. There are even signs that in the drone war, the Ukrainians have an edge over the Russians.</p><p>How could the drone capabilities of these two militaries have experienced such differing fortunes over the same period? The answer lies in a combination of trade embargoes, tech development, and the rising importance of countermeasures.</p><p class="pull-quote">Since 2014’s invasion of Crimea, Russia’s drone-development efforts have lagged—during a time of dynamic evolution and development across the UAV industry. </p><p>First, some background. Military drones come in a wide variety of sizes, purposes, and capabilities, but they can be grouped into a few categories. On one end of the spectrum are relatively tiny flying bombs, small enough to be carried in a rucksack. On the other end are high-altitude drones, with wingspans up to 25 meters and capable of staying aloft for 30 or 40 hours, of being operated from consoles thousands of kilometers from the battlefield, and of firing air-to-surface missiles with deadly precision. In between are a range of intermediate-size drones used primarily for surveillance and reconnaissance.</p><p>Russia’s fleet of drones includes models in each of these categories. However, sanctions imposed after the 2014 invasion of Crimea blocked the Russian military from procuring some key technologies necessary to stay on the cutting edge of drone development, particularly in <a href="https://www.rand.org/pubs/research_reports/RRA113-1.html" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">optics, lightweight composites, and electronics</a>. With relatively limited capabilities of its own in these areas, Russia’s drone development efforts became somewhat sluggish during a time of dynamic evolution and development elsewhere. </p><p>Current stalwarts in the Russian arsenal include the Zala Kyb, which is a “loitering munition” that can <a href="https://zala-aero.com/en/production/bvs/kyb-uav/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">dive into a target and explode</a>. The most common Russian drones are midsize ones used for surveillance and reconnaissance. These include the Eleron-3SV and the Orlan-10 drones, both of which have been used extensively in Syria and Ukraine. In fact, just last week, an Orlan-10 operator <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/davidhambling/2022/03/16/russian-military-awards-reveal-covert-drone-tactics/?sh=5dac22b76fb8" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">was awarded a military medal</a> for locating a site from which Ukrainian soldiers were ambushing Russian tanks, and also a Ukrainian basing area outside Kyiv containing ten artillery pieces, which were subsequently destroyed. Russia’s only large, missile-firing drone is the Kronshtadt Orion, which is similar to the American MQ-1 Predator and can be used for precision strikes as well as reconnaissance. An Orion was credited with an <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=iK4DBQOxfZo" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">air strike on a command center</a> in Ukraine in early March 2022. </p><p>Meanwhile, since the 2014 Crimea war, when they had no drones at all, the Ukrainians have methodically assembled a modest but highly capable set of drones. The backbone of the fleet, with <a href="https://www.overtdefense.com/2021/05/25/leleka-100-model-uavs-added-to-the-ukrainian-armys-inventory/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">some 300 units fielded</a>, are the A1-SM Fury and the <a href="https://www.overtdefense.com/2021/05/25/leleka-100-model-uavs-added-to-the-ukrainian-armys-inventory/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Leleka-100 reconnaissance drones</a>, both designed and manufactured in Ukraine. The A1-SM Fury entered service in April 2020, and the Leleka-100, in May, 2021.</p><p class="pull-quote">On offense, the Ukrainian and Russian militaries are closely matched in the drone war. The difference is on defense.</p><p>The heavy hitter for Ukraine in this war, though, is the Bayraktar TB2 drone, a combat aerial flyer with a wingspan of 12 meters and an armament of four laser-guided bombs. As of the beginning of March, and after losing two TB2s to Russian-backed separatist forces in Lugansk, Ukraine had a complement of 30 of the drones, which were designed and developed in Turkey. These drones are specifically aimed at destroying tanks and as of 24 March <a href="https://www.oryxspioenkop.com/2022/02/defending-ukraine-listing-russian-army.html" target="_blank">had been credited</a> with destroying 26 vehicles, 10 surface-to-air missile systems, and 3 command posts. Various reports have put the <a href="https://www.ft.com/content/7529a862-7928-4b4e-a4c5-b2f50747d1f6" target="_blank">cost of a TB2</a> at anywhere from $1 million to $10 million. It’s much cheaper than the tens of millions fetched for better-known combat drones, such as the MQ-9 Reaper, the backbone of the U.S. Air Force’s fleet of combat drones.</p><p>The Ukrainian arsenal also includes the Tu-141 reconnaissance drones, which are large, high-altitude Soviet-era drones that <a href="https://www.oryxspioenkop.com/2022/02/attack-on-europe-documenting-equipment.html" target="_blank">have had little success</a> in the war. At the small end of the Ukraine drone complement are 100 Switchblade drones, which were donated by the United States as part of the <a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2022/03/16/us-sends-switchblade-drones-to-ukraine-00017836" target="_blank">$800 million weapons package</a> announced on 16 March. The Switchblades are loitering munitions similar in size and functionality to the Russian Zala Kyb.<br/></p><p> The upshot is that on offense, the Ukrainian and Russian militaries are closely matched in the drone war. The difference is on defense: Ukraine has the advantage when it comes to counter-drone technology. A decade ago, counter-drone technology mostly meant using radar to detect drones and surface-to-air missiles to shoot them down. It quickly proved far too costly and ineffective. Drone technology advanced at a brisk pace over the past decade, so counter-drone technology had to move rapidly to keep up. In Russia, it didn’t. Here, again, the Russian military was hampered by technology embargoes and a domestic industrial base that has been somewhat stagnant and lacking in critical capabilities. For contrast, the combined industrial base of the countries supporting Ukraine in this war is massive and has invested heavily in counter-drone technology.</p><p>Russia has deployed electronic warfare systems to counter enemy drones and have likely been using the <a href="https://www.janes.com/defence-news/news-detail/russia-trials-new-ew-tactics" target="_blank">Borisoglebsk 2 MT-LB and R-330Zh Zhitel</a> systems, which use a combination of jamming and spoofing. These systems fill the air with radio-frequency energy, increasing the noise threshold to such a level that the drone cannot distinguish control signals from the remote pilot. Another standard counterdrone technique is sending false signals to the drone, with the most common being fake (“spoofed”) GPS signals, which disorient the flyer. Jamming and spoofing systems are easy to target because they emit radio-frequency waves at fairly high intensities. In fact, open-source images show that Ukrainian forces have already <a href="https://www.oryxspioenkop.com/2022/02/attack-on-europe-documenting-equipment.html" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">destroyed three of these Russian counterdrone systems</a>.</p><p class="pull-quote">The exact systems that have been provided to the Ukrainians is not publicly known, but it’s possible to make an educated guess from among the many systems available.</p><p>Additionally, some of the newer drones being used by the Ukrainians include features to withstand such electronic attacks. For example, when one of these drones detects a jamming signal, it switches to frequencies that are not being jammed; if it is still unable to reestablish a connection, the drone operates autonomously with a series of preset maneuvers until a connection can be reestablished.</p><p>Meanwhile, Ukraine has access to the wide array of NATO counterdrone technologies. The exact systems that have been provided to the Ukrainians is not publicly known, but it’s possible to make an educated guess from among the many systems available. <a href="https://news.lockheedmartin.com/2019-11-07-ATHENA-Successfully-Defends-Drone-Threat" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">One of the more powerful ones</a>, from Lockheed Martin, repurposes a solid-state, phased-array radar system developed to spot incoming munitions, to detect and identify a drone. The system then tracks the drone and <a href="https://www.lockheedmartin.com/en-us/news/features/2016/webt-laser-swarms-drones.html" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">uses high-energy lasers</a> to shoot it down. Raytheon’s <a href="https://www.raytheonmissilesanddefense.com/what-we-do/counter-uas" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">counterdrone portfolio</a> includes similar capabilities along with drone-killing drones and systems capable of beaming high-power microwaves that disrupt the drone’s electronics.</p><p>While most major Western defense contractors have some sort of counterdrone system, there has also been significant innovation in the commercial sector, given the mass proliferation of commercial drones. While many of these technologies are aimed at smaller drones, some of the technologies, including acoustic sensing and radio-frequency localization, are effective against larger drones as well. Also, a dozen small companies have developed jamming and spoofing systems specifically aimed at <a href="https://www.robinradar.com/press/blog/10-counter-drone-technologies-to-detect-and-stop-drones-today" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">countering modern drones</a>.</p><p>Although we don’t know specifically which counterdrone systems are being deployed by the Ukrainians, the images of the destroyed drones tell a compelling story. In the drone war, many of the flyers on both sides have been captured or destroyed on the ground, but more than half were disabled while in flight. The destroyed Ukrainian drones often show tremendous damage, including burn marks and other signs that they were shot down by a Russian surface-to-air missile. A logical conclusion is that the Russians’ electronic counterdrone systems were not effective. Meanwhile, the downed Russian drones are typically much more intact, showing relatively minor damage consistent with a precision strike from a laser or electromagnetic pulse. This is exactly what you would expect if the drones had been dispatched by one of the newer Western counterdrone systems.</p>In the first three weeks of this conflict, Russian drones have failed to achieve the level of success that they did in 2014. The Ukrainians, on the other hand, have logged multiple victories with drone and counterdrone forces assembled in just 8 years. The Russian drones, primarily domestically sourced, have been foiled repeatedly by NATO counterdrone technology. Meanwhile, the Ukrainian drones, such as the TB2s procured from NATO-member Turkey, have had multiple successes against the Russian counterdrone systems.]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2022 12:26:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spectrum.ieee.org/ukraine-drone-war</guid><category>Uavs</category><category>Ukraine</category><category>Ukraine conflict</category><category>Russia</category><category>Drones</category><dc:creator>Vikram Mittal</dc:creator><media:content medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/a-man-in-combat-fatigues-pushes-a-military-drone-across-an-airport-tarmac-while-another-man-in-fatigues-walks-away.jpg?id=29590718&amp;width=980"></media:content></item><item><title>Starfall: Finding a Meteorite with Drones and AI</title><link>https://spectrum.ieee.org/how-to-find-meteorites</link><description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/a-man-stands-in-the-desert-holding-a-remote-controller-for-a-drone-that-hovers-in-the-air-behind-him-he-is-pointing-to-a-small.jpg?id=29590669&width=2000&height=1500&coordinates=0%2C0%2C0%2C0"/><br/><br/><p>Go outside on a clear night, and if you’re very lucky you will see the sky falling. NASA estimates that 50,000 <a href="https://solarsystem.nasa.gov/asteroids-comets-and-meteors/meteors-and-meteorites/in-depth/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">meteorites</a> from space have been found on Earth.</p><p>The shooting stars or fireballs they form as they enter the atmosphere can be beautiful, but they’re hard to track. Of those 50,000, astronomers have been able to plot the past orbits of only <a href="https://www.meteoriteorbits.info/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">about 40</a>.</p><p>Which is why <a href="https://scholar.google.com/citations?user=2OZ1qikAAAAJ&hl=en" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Seamus Anderson</a> and his colleagues at <a href="https://sstc.curtin.edu.au/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Curtin University</a> in Australia may have made an important first. They <a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2203.01466" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank" title="Link: https://arxiv.org/abs/2203.01466">report they’ve recovered a meteorite</a> in the remote Australian outback—one that once followed an ellipse between the orbits of Venus and Jupiter—and they picked it out of nowhere with two drones and machine learning.</p><p>“It was a semi-surprise,” says Anderson, an American who came to Curtin in 2018 to do his Ph.D. work on technology for meteorite searches. “We weren’t expecting to have that much success the first time.”</p><p>Curtin’s Space Science and Technology Center, in the city of Perth, runs the <a href="https://dfn.gfo.rocks/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Desert Fireball Network</a>, a system of 50 automated cameras that monitor Australia’s night skies for incoming meteors. One night last year, two of the cameras tracked a streak in the sky, and the system calculated that a small rock had probably crashed in the desert scrub of Western Australia, in a region known as the Nullarbor. The observations weren’t ideal—they estimated that the meteorite weighed between 150 and 700 grams and had come down in an area of 5 square kilometers—but Anderson and two colleagues decided to make a field trip. In December, they set out from Perth on a drive of more than 1,000 km looking for a needle in a haystack: one blackened piece of rock on the desert floor, 50 km from the nearest paved road.</p><p>In the past, the trip would have been all but pointless. Meteorite hunters usually search the ground on foot, walking back and forth in a grid pattern and hoping they hit pay dirt. Eighty percent of the time, they fail.</p><p>“It’s been shown that people are just terrible at these kinds of repetitive tasks,” says Anderson. “A major problem is humans just not paying attention.”</p><p class="pull-quote">Through repetition, the machine and the researchers learned to deal with false positives: bottles, cans, desert plant roots, and occasional kangaroo bones.</p><p>That’s where technology came in. They used off-the-shelf hardware—a quadcopter drone with a 44-megapixel camera and a desktop computer with a good video card. The unusual part was the convolutional neural network they ran on it—machine-learning software not often carried by campers in the outback.</p><p>“The holy grail of meteorite hunting right now is a drone that can grid a geographic area, look at the ground, and find meteorites with AI,” says <a href="https://www.amsmeteors.org/author/mike-hankey/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Mike Hankey</a> of the American Meteor Society.</p><p class="shortcode-media shortcode-media-rebelmouse-image">
<img alt="Overhead shot shows 3 people in the desert pointing at the ground." class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="3142d36d8fb9cbedce984e69a035c636" data-rm-shortcode-name="rebelmouse-image" id="78c01" loading="lazy" src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/overhead-shot-shows-3-people-in-the-desert-pointing-at-the-ground.jpg?id=29590700&width=980"/>
<small class="image-media media-caption" placeholder="Add Photo Caption...">Seamus Anderson [right] poses with his two colleagues, both pointing at the meteorite they just found. The photo was taken with the drone they had used to locate the specimen.</small><small class="image-media media-photo-credit" placeholder="Add Photo Credit...">Seamus Anderson/Curtin University</small></p><p>A machine-learning system needs training—data about the world from which it can extrapolate—so the researchers fed it drone images of the Nullarbor terrain. Some of them included meteorite samples borrowed from a local museum and planted on the ground. Those images were given a score of 1—a definite meteorite, even if each appeared only as a black dot. Other images showing random terrain nearby were scored as 0—no meteorite here. Through repetition, the machine and the researchers learned to deal with false positives: bottles, cans, desert plant roots, and occasional kangaroo bones.</p><p>“It’s like training your kid to figure out what a dog looks like,” says Anderson now. “You could show lots of images of nothing but black Labs—and then, when it sees a picture of a German Shepard, it’s maybe going to freak out and not know exactly what it’s supposed to do. So you have to give it many opportunities to know what a meteorite can look like in that background.”</p><p class="shortcode-media shortcode-media-rebelmouse-image">
<img alt="Top satellite image  has insets of a meteor falling and blue lines indicating search zones. Bottom shows an orbital map and a closer satellite of the desert with dots showing searched areas." class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="79f9b3684624dceb53f458f7654574fd" data-rm-shortcode-name="rebelmouse-image" id="b21b1" loading="lazy" src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/top-satellite-image-has-insets-of-a-meteor-falling-and-blue-lines-indicating-search-zones-bottom-shows-an-orbital-map-and-a-cl.jpg?id=29590680&width=980"/>
<small class="image-media media-caption" placeholder="Add Photo Caption...">Top: The incoming meteor and where it landed in Western Australia. Bottom left: The likely orbit of the meteoroid before it hit the Earth. Bottom: The section of desert scientists searched.</small>
<small class="image-media media-photo-credit" placeholder="Add Photo Credit...">
            Seamus Anderson/Curtin University
        </small>
</p><p>They began surveying: 43 drone flights over three days, going back and forth at an altitude of about 20 meters, recording 57,255 images. Back at camp, they began to process their images. From the first four flights alone, the algorithm gave 59,384 objects a score of at least 0.7 on that scale of 0 to 1—a lot of possible specimens. The researchers were quickly able to narrow them down to 259 and then 38, which they reinspected with a second, smaller drone. Soon they were down to four, and set out on foot, guided by GPS, to find them.</p><p>Before we reach the conclusion, it’s worth pausing to ask why meteorites are worth chasing. Space scientists will say that some date from the beginnings of the solar system. Some contain amino acids, those most basic building blocks of life. A few are <a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/chelyabinsklike-impacts-more-common-than-scientists-thought" target="_self">large enough</a> to do harm. Others, Anderson points out, contain rare elements, perhaps valuable for future technologies but hard to mine on Earth.</p><p>So there was a lot to think about in the desert heat—life, the universe, the reliability of their algorithm—as Anderson and his two comrades paced the ground looking for a blackened rock.</p><p>“Then one of my friends on the trip, John Fairweather, said one of the most annoying things you can hear at that moment—like, ‘Hey, is this the meteorite?’” Anderson says. He thought it was a joke. “And I thought, ‘That’s not funny right now, John.’ And I looked over and, literally, he’s got the rock.”</p><p class="shortcode-media shortcode-media-rebelmouse-image">
<img alt="Closeup of the meteorite on the desert floor in Australia, with a pen to show its size." class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="f035f185a238057aaab6020369a0f3a3" data-rm-shortcode-name="rebelmouse-image" id="25f51" loading="lazy" src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/closeup-of-the-meteorite-on-the-desert-floor-in-australia-with-a-pen-to-show-its-size.jpg?id=29590699&width=980"/>
<small class="image-media media-caption" placeholder="Add Photo Caption...">The meteorite, named DFN 09, is shown here with a pen for scale.</small><small class="image-media media-photo-credit" placeholder="Add Photo Credit...">Seamus Anderson/Curtin University</small></p><p>Anderson looked around to be sure the surroundings matched what the overhead drone image had shown. They did. The rock was a chondrite, a common type of iron-rich meteorite. It was 5 centimeters long, about the size of an egg, and weighed 70 grams. Most important to Anderson, the algorithm had given this particular patch of ground a score of 1.0—a perfect match.</p><p>“And I stood there, and I basically just screamed for a minute or two. Yes, it was awesome.”</p>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2022 21:41:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spectrum.ieee.org/how-to-find-meteorites</guid><category>Neural networks</category><category>Drones</category><category>Meteors</category><dc:creator>Ned Potter</dc:creator><media:content medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/a-man-stands-in-the-desert-holding-a-remote-controller-for-a-drone-that-hovers-in-the-air-behind-him-he-is-pointing-to-a-small.jpg?id=29590669&amp;width=980"></media:content></item><item><title>How Flyback Rocket Boosters Got Off the Ground</title><link>https://spectrum.ieee.org/how-flyback-rocket-boosters-got-off-the-ground</link><description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/a-photo-of-a-rocket-booster-landing-on-a-landing-pad.png?id=29571732&width=2000&height=1500&coordinates=0%2C152%2C0%2C153"/><br/><br/><p><strong>In the popular</strong> conception of a technological breakthrough, a flash of genius is followed quickly by commercial or industrial success, public acclaim, and substantial wealth for a small group of inventors and backers. In the real world, it almost never works out that way. </p><p>Advances that seem to appear suddenly are often backed by decades of development. Consider <a href="https://www.thoughtco.com/steam-engines-history-1991933#:~:text=The%20high%2Dpressure%20steam%20expands,creating%20motion%20for%20the%20locomotive." target="_blank">steam engines</a>. Starting in the second quarter of the 19th century they began powering trains, and they soon revolutionized the transportation of people and goods. But steam engines themselves had been invented at the beginning of the <em>18th</em> century. For 125 years they had been used to <a href="https://www.farmanddairy.com/columns/earliest-steam-engines-used-to-pump-water/549187.html" target="_blank">pump water out of mines</a> and then to power the mills of the Industrial Revolution.</p><hr/><p>Lately we’ve become accustomed to seeing rocket boosters return to Earth and then land vertically, on their tails, ready to be serviced and flown again. (Much the same <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=TdSxDNnqRlo" target="_blank">majestic imagery</a> thrilled sci-fi moviegoers in the 1950s.) Today, both SpaceX and Blue Origin are using these techniques, and a third startup, Relativity Space, is on the verge of joining them. Such reusable rocketry is already cutting the cost of access to space and, with other advances yet to come, will help make it possible for humanity to return to the moon and eventually to travel to Mars. </p><p>Vertical landings, too, have a long history, with the same ground being plowed many times by multiple research organizations. From 1993 to 1996 a booster named DCX, for <a href="https://www.nmspacemuseum.org/inductee/experimental-delta-clipper/" target="_blank">Delta Clipper</a> Experimental, took off and landed vertically eight times at White Sands Missile Range. It flew to a height of only 2,500 meters, but it successfully negotiated the very tricky dynamics of landing a vertical cylinder on its end. </p><p>The key innovations that made all this possible happened 50 or more years ago. And those in turn built upon the <a href="https://www.history.com/this-day-in-history/first-liquid-fueled-rocket" target="_blank">invention a century ago of liquid-fueled rockets</a> that can be throttled up or down by pumping more or less fuel into a combustion chamber. </p><p>In August 1954 the Rolls-Royce Thrust Measuring Rig, also known as the “flying bedstead,” took off and landed vertically while carrying a pilot. The <a href="http://www.aviastar.org/air/england/rollsroyce_bedstead.php" target="_blank">ungainly contraption</a> had two downward-pointing Rolls-Royce jet engines with nozzles that allowed the pilot to vector the thrust and control the flight. By 1957 another company, Hawker Siddeley, started work on turning this idea into a vertical take-off and landing (VTOL) fighter jet. It first flew in 1967 and entered service in 1969 as the Harrier Jump Jet, with new Rolls-Royce engines specifically designed for thrust vectoring. Thrust vectoring is a critical component of control for all of today’s reusable rocket boosters. </p><p>During the 1960s another rig, also nicknamed the flying bedstead, was developed in the United States for training astronauts to land on the moon. There was a gimbaled rocket engine that always pointed directly downward, providing thrust equal to five-sixths of the vehicle and the pilot’s weight, simulating lunar gravity. The pilot then controlled the thrust and direction of another rocket engine to land the vehicle safely. </p><p>It was not all smooth flying. Neil Armstrong first flew the trainer in March 1967, but he was nearly killed in May 1968 when <a href="https://youtu.be/tUJDbj9Vp5w" target="_blank">things went awry</a> and he had to use the ejection seat to rocket to safety. The parachute deployed and he hit the ground just 4 seconds later. Rocket-powered vertical descent was harder than it looked. </p><p class="pull-quote">Vertical rocket landings have a long history, with the same ground being plowed many times by multiple research organizations.</p><p>Nevertheless, between 1969 and 1972, Armstrong and then five other astronauts piloted lunar modules to vertical landings on the moon. There were no ejection seats, and these have been the only crewed rocket-powered landings on a spaceflight. All other humans lofted into space have used Earth’s atmosphere to slow down, combining heat shields with either wings or parachutes. </p><p>In the early days of Blue Origin, the company returned to the flying-bedstead approach, and its vehicle took off and landed successfully in March 2005. It was powered by four jet engines, once again from Rolls-Royce, bought secondhand from the South African Air Force. Ten years later, in November 2015, Blue Origin’s New Shepard booster reached an altitude of 100 kilometers and then <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9pillaOxGCo" target="_blank">landed vertically</a>. A month later SpaceX had its first successful vertical landing of a Falcon-9 booster. </p><p>Today’s reusable, or flyback, boosters also use something called grid fins, those honeycombed panels sticking out perpendicularly from the top of a booster that guide the massive cylinder as it falls through the atmosphere unpowered. The fins have an even longer history, as they have been part of every crewed <a href="https://space.stackexchange.com/questions/22425/what-are-the-grid-fins-on-the-soyuz-escape-system-used-for" target="_blank">Soyuz</a> launch since the 1960s. They guide the capsule back to Earth if there’s an abort during the climb to orbit. They were last used in October 2018 when a Soyuz failed at 50 km up. The cosmonaut and astronaut who were aboard landed safely and had a successful launch in another Soyuz five months later. </p><p>The next big accomplishment will be crewed vertical landings, 50 years after mankind's last one, on the moon. It will almost certainly happen before this decade is out. </p><p>I’m less confident that we’ll see general-purpose quantum computers and abundant electricity from nuclear fusion in that time frame. But I’m pretty sure we’ll eventually get there with both. The arc of technology development is often long. And sometimes, the longer it is, the more revolutionary it is in the end.</p><p><em>This article appears in the April 2022 print issue as “The Long Road to Overnight Success .”</em></p>]]></description><pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2022 20:27:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spectrum.ieee.org/how-flyback-rocket-boosters-got-off-the-ground</guid><category>Human space flight</category><category>Reusable rocket boosters</category><category>Spacex</category><category>Blue origin</category><category>Reusable rockets</category><dc:creator>Rodney Brooks</dc:creator><media:content medium="image" type="image/png" url="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/a-photo-of-a-rocket-booster-landing-on-a-landing-pad.png?id=29571732&amp;width=980"></media:content></item><item><title>To Catch a Falling Satellite</title><link>https://spectrum.ieee.org/space-junk-astrobee</link><description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/animation-of-a-square-with-3-axis-arrows-maneuvering-towards-a-spinning-satellite.gif?id=29534835&width=2000&height=1500&coordinates=80%2C0%2C80%2C0"/><br/><br/><p>It is the fate of many a dead satellite to spend its last years tumbling out of control. A fuel line may burst, or solar wind may surge, or there may be drag from the outer reaches of the atmosphere—and unless a spacecraft has been designed in some way that keeps it naturally stable, chances are good that it will begin to turn end over end.<br/></p><p>That’s a problem, because Earth orbit is getting more and more crowded. Engineers would like to corral old pieces of <a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/weve-already-passed-the-tipping-point-for-orbital-debris" target="_self">space junk</a>, but they can’t safely reach them, especially if they’re unstable. The European Space Agency says there are about 30,000 “<a href="https://www.esa.int/Safety_Security/Space_Debris/Space_debris_by_the_numbers" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank" title="Link: https://www.esa.int/Safety_Security/Space_Debris/Space_debris_by_the_numbers">debris objects</a>” now being tracked in Earth orbit—derelict satellites, spent rocket stages, pieces sent flying from collisions in space. There may also be 900,000 smaller bits of orbital debris—everything from loose bolts to flecks of paint to shards of insulation. They may be less than 10 centimeters long, but they can still destroy a healthy satellite if they hit at orbital speeds.</p><p>“With more satellites being launched, we might encounter more situations where we have a defunct satellite that’s occupying a valuable orbit,” says <a href="https://aeroastro.mit.edu/people/richard-linares/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Richard Linares</a>, an assistant professor of aeronautics and astronautics at MIT. He’s part of an American-German project, called <a href="https://news.mit.edu/2022/how-reach-tumbling-target-space-0225" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">TumbleDock/ROAM</a>, researching ways to corral and stabilize tumbling satellites so they can be deorbited or, in some cases, perhaps even refueled or repaired.</p><p>Engineers have put up with orbital debris for decades, but Linares says the picture is changing. For one thing, satellite technology is becoming more and more affordable—just look at SpaceX, which has been launching <a href="https://www.starlink.com/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">40 satellites a week</a> so far this year. For another, he says, the economic benefits those satellites offer—high-speed internet, GPS, climate and crop monitoring and other applications—will be threatened if the risk of impacts keeps growing.</p><p>“I think in the next few years we’ll have the technology to do something about space debris,” says Linares. “And there are economic drivers that will incentivize companies to do this.”</p><p>The TumbleDock/ROAM team has just finished a series of tests in the cabin of the International Space Station, using NASA robots called <a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/astrobee-nasa-gateway" target="_blank">Astrobees</a> to stand in for a tumbling satellite and a “chaser” spacecraft sent to catch it. The goal: to figure out <a href="https://www.frontiersin.org/articles/10.3389/frobt.2021.641338/full" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">algorithms</a> so that a chaser can find its target, determine its tumble rates, and calculate the safest and most efficient approach to it.</p><p class="shortcode-media shortcode-media-youtube">
<span class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="e7214e6d1d9d95267aa3c03e4604d150" style="display:block;position:relative;padding-top:56.25%;"><iframe frameborder="0" height="auto" lazy-loadable="true" scrolling="no" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/IsEpmzFGFh8?rel=0&start=43" style="position:absolute;top:0;left:0;width:100%;height:100%;" width="100%"></iframe></span>
<small class="image-media media-caption" placeholder="Add Photo Caption...">Astrobee robot experiment aboard the ISS to reach a tumbling target in space.</small>
<small class="image-media media-photo-credit" placeholder="Add Photo Credit...">
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=IsEpmzFGFh8&t=43s" target="_blank">www.youtube.com</a>
</small>
</p><p>“There’s a massive amount of large debris out there,” says <a href="https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/author/37086406826" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Keenan Albee</a>, a Ph.D. student on the team at MIT. “Look at some of them, with large solar panels that are ready to whack you if you don’t do the approach correctly.”</p><p>The researchers decided early on that a chase vehicle needs enough autonomy to close in on a disabled satellite on its own. Even the largest satellites are too distant for ground-based tracking stations to track their attitude with any precision. A chaser, perhaps equipped with navigation cameras, lidar, and other sensors, will need to do the job in real time.</p><p>“The tumbling motion of a satellite can be quite complex,” says <a href="https://rmc.dlr.de/rm/de/staff/roberto.lampariello/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Roberto Lampariello</a>, the principal investigator on the project at the German Aerospace Center, or DLR. “And if you want to be sure you are not going to collide with any appendages while approaching the mating point, having an autonomous method of guidance is, I think, very attractive.”</p><p>The Astrobee tests on the space station showed that it can be done, at least in principle. Each Astrobee robot is a cube, about 30 centimeters on a side, with navigation cameras, compressed-air thrusters, and Snapdragon processors much like what you would find in a smartphone. For the latest test, last month, NASA astronaut <a href="https://www.nasa.gov/astronauts/biographies/mark-t-vande-hei" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Mark Vande Hei</a> set up two Astrobees a couple of meters apart. They then took their commands from Albee on the ground. He started the test runs, with one robot tumbling and the other trying to rendezvous with it. There have been glitches; the Astrobees needed help determining their precise location relative to the station walls. But the results of the tests were promising.</p><p>A next step, say the researchers, is to determine how best for a chase spacecraft to grapple its target, which is especially difficult if it’s a piece of debris with no docking mechanism. Other plans over the years have involved big nets or lasers; TumbleDock/ROAM team members say they’re intrigued by grippers that use <a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/watch-astrobees-first-autonomous-flight-on-the-international-space-station" target="_self">van der Waals forces</a> between atoms, the kinds that help a gecko cling to a sheer surface.</p><p>The larger question is how to turn experiments like these into actual solutions to a growing, if lofty, problem. Low Earth orbit has been crowded enough, for long enough, that satellite makers add shielding to their vehicles and space agencies continuously scan the skies to prevent close calls. No space travelers have been killed, and there have only been a few cases in which satellites were actually pulverized. But the problem has become increasingly expensive and, in some cases, dangerous. SpaceX has launched 2,000 <a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/spacex-preps-selfdriving-satellites-for-launch" target="_self">Starlink Internet satellites</a> so far, may launch 30,000 more, and has other companies (<a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/amazons-project-kuiper-is-more-than-the-companys-response-to-spacex" target="_self">like Amazon</a>) racing to keep up. They see profits up there.</p><p>MIT’s Linares says that, in fact, is why it’s worth figuring out the space-junk problem. “There’s a reason why those orbits are valuable,” he says. Companies may spend billions to launch new satellites—and don’t want them threatened by old satellites.</p><p>“If your company’s benefiting from an orbit band,” he says, “then you’d probably better get someone to clean it up for you.”</p>]]></description><pubDate>Mon, 14 Mar 2022 16:55:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spectrum.ieee.org/space-junk-astrobee</guid><category>Space junk</category><category>Astrobee</category><category>Iss</category><category>Esa</category><category>Nasa</category><category>Satellites</category><dc:creator>Ned Potter</dc:creator><media:content medium="image" type="image/gif" url="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/animation-of-a-square-with-3-axis-arrows-maneuvering-towards-a-spinning-satellite.gif?id=29534835&amp;width=980"></media:content></item><item><title>Programmable Blocks Tease Self-Assembling Space Structures</title><link>https://spectrum.ieee.org/self-configurable-electrovoxel</link><description><![CDATA[
<img src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/martin-nisser-of-mit-csail-tests-two-robotic-cubes-ability-to-pivot-in-microgravity.jpg?id=29513645&width=2000&height=1500&coordinates=0%2C0%2C0%2C0"/><br/><br/><p><p>
<em>This article is part of our exclusive <a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/collections/journal-watch/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_self">IEEE Journal Watch series</a> in partnership with IEEE Xplore.</em>
</p></p><p>Self-assembling and self-reconfiguring robots depicted in films like <em>Transformers</em> are becoming closer to reality, thanks to a team of researchers at MIT’s <a href="https://www.csail.mit.edu/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Computer Science and Artificial Intelligence Laboratory</a> (CSAIL). Scientists at CSAIL have created what they call ElectroVoxels, modular robotic cubes that use embedded electromagnets to move. The accompanying <a href="http://groups.csail.mit.edu/hcie/files/research-projects/ElectroVoxel/Nisser_ICRA_22_CamReady_0207.pdf" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">paper</a> will be presented at the IEEE International Conference on Robotics and Automation in May.</p><p>“I originally wanted to call them Transformers because they’re essentially robots that can change their shape,” says <a href="https://www.csail.mit.edu/person/martin-nisser" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Martin Nisser</a>, a Ph.D. student in the human-computer interaction group at MIT CSAIL and lead author on the paper. Due to copyright reasons, however, the team decided against it and settled on combining the term “electromagnet” with “voxel,” a volumetric pixel that’s the 3D equivalent of a pixel. “You can think of ElectroVoxels as voxels with electromagnets embedded in them,” he says.</p><p>An ElectroVoxel cube indeed has an electromagnet—a ferrite core wrapped with copper wire—embedded into each of its 12 edges. “When you send a current through an electromagnet, the polarization depends on the direction in which you send the current,” Nisser says. “It’s like a permanent magnet, except you can change the polarity depending on the direction of the current.”</p><p>ElectroVoxel blocks move by either pivoting to a block it shares an edge with or traversing the face of one block to another. When a pair of electromagnets in a cube are polarized oppositely, they attract each other, creating a hinge. You can then use another pair of electromagnets polarized in the same direction to repel each other and perform a pivoting maneuver. Once that pivoting is complete, you can use two separate pairs of electromagnets to attract each other and hold the faces of the two cubes together.</p><p class="shortcode-media shortcode-media-rebelmouse-image">
<img class="rm-shortcode" data-rm-shortcode-id="b9f29d886deb0a926f8bdaff3550e79d" data-rm-shortcode-name="rebelmouse-image" id="0461e" loading="lazy" src="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/electrovoxels-are-modular-robotic-cubes-that-use-embedded-electromagnets-to-move.jpg?id=29513646&width=980"/>
<small class="image-media media-caption" placeholder="Add Photo Caption...">ElectroVoxels are modular robotic cubes that use embedded electromagnets to move.</small><small class="image-media media-photo-credit" placeholder="Add Photo Credit...">MIT CSAIL/Martin Nisser</small></p><p>The blocks are also programmable. “When you have more than two or three ElectroVoxels, it becomes hard to address each electromagnet individually and predict what will happen,” says Nisser. “So we created a user interface that lets you specify which ElectroVoxel should pivot in what direction. Then all the underlying electromagnet assignments are computed for you, and we can put that directly onto the microcontroller.”</p><p>Unlike other self-assembling robots whose hardware consists of bulky motors or expensive actuators, ElectroVoxels promise scalability. They’re light, with each cube weighing 103 grams; cheaper, with each electromagnet costing around US $0.60; and easy to build, with each cube taking about 80 minutes to construct.</p><p>But ElectroVoxels are not without their limitations, and the team took advantage of a particular one as a perfect vehicle for space applications. “One of the drawbacks of ElectroVoxels is that their force is relatively weak compared to other actuators. Yet we also realized that they can be used effectively in space,” Nisser says. “In a microgravity environment, even very low forces can contribute to significant velocities, so a very small force like the ones we have in ElectroVoxels could contribute to moving large objects. We saw this opportunity to explore reconfigurable robots for space applications, where you want to try to change the inertial properties of spacecraft, or to help build temporary structures that can aid in various activities such as structure inspection by astronauts.”</p><p>To verify their theory and establish reconfiguration in space, the team conducted experiments in a microgravity environment. First, they used an air table, a flat table with holes in it and chutes around it to create pillows of air that simulate microgravity conditions. The ElectroVoxels successfully performed pivots and traversals on the air table. Then, the team flew the cubes aboard a <a href="https://www.nasa.gov/analogs/parabolic-flight" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">parabolic flight</a> to observe pivoting. They encountered some difficulties, but the ElectroVoxels were able to pivot in flight.</p><p>“On a typical flight, an aircraft flies these parabolas about 20 times, and each of the parabolas lasts for around 15 seconds. But the quality of the microgravity inside those parabolas tends to vary a bit,” says Nisser. “What ended up happening is that we only had about 4 seconds of microgravity, so the main challenge was fine-tuning everything to make sure we were as prepared as possible for it to work, because with just 4 seconds, there was no time or capability to update things.”</p><p>While the team has demonstrated the ability of ElectroVoxels for use in space, they hope to do the same in the future for Earth. “We’re looking at trying to optimize ElectroVoxels for torque-to-inertia ratios to be able to pivot against gravity,” Nisser says.</p><p>Another fit-for-Earth application for these reconfigurable robots is recyclable rapid prototyping. “3D printers are typically used to create one-off, low-fidelity prototypes, which aren’t necessarily functional,” says Nisser. “If you can create prototypes with a modular system, then you can create one structure and have it automatically pivot into a second structure, making rapid prototyping more sustainable. You wouldn’t have to discard the plastic after each print—you could just use the same modules to create new structures.”</p>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 11 Mar 2022 16:00:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://spectrum.ieee.org/self-configurable-electrovoxel</guid><category>Aerospace</category><category>Robotics</category><category>Zero-g</category><category>Self-assembly</category><dc:creator>Rina Diane Caballar</dc:creator><media:content medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/martin-nisser-of-mit-csail-tests-two-robotic-cubes-ability-to-pivot-in-microgravity.jpg?id=29513645&amp;width=980"></media:content></item></channel></rss>