<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns:yt="http://www.youtube.com/xml/schemas/2015" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
 <link rel="self" href="http://www.youtube.com/feeds/videos.xml?channel_id=UCMTk_R_Y49jvq-HQXDmKI0Q"/>
 <id>yt:channel:UCMTk_R_Y49jvq-HQXDmKI0Q</id>
 <yt:channelId>UCMTk_R_Y49jvq-HQXDmKI0Q</yt:channelId>
 <title>The Right Opinion</title>
 <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCMTk_R_Y49jvq-HQXDmKI0Q"/>
 <author>
  <name>The Right Opinion</name>
  <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCMTk_R_Y49jvq-HQXDmKI0Q</uri>
 </author>
 <published>2016-03-31T20:28:26+00:00</published>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:cK43gsND4GQ</id>
  <yt:videoId>cK43gsND4GQ</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCMTk_R_Y49jvq-HQXDmKI0Q</yt:channelId>
  <title>The Rise And Fall of Frenemies - Trisha and Ethan's Impossible Podcast | TRO</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=cK43gsND4GQ"/>
  <author>
   <name>The Right Opinion</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCMTk_R_Y49jvq-HQXDmKI0Q</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-10-06T17:00:18+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-10-30T12:04:41+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>The Rise And Fall of Frenemies - Trisha and Ethan's Impossible Podcast | TRO</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/cK43gsND4GQ?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i4.ytimg.com/vi/cK43gsND4GQ/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>Go to https://www.Vance-Global.com and use CODE: RIGHTOPINION for 20% off your order or CODE: RIGHTOPINION30 for 30% off Subscriptions

The Right Opinion: The Rise And Fall of Frenemies - Trisha and Ethan's Impossible Podcast | TRO

0:00- Introduction
14:25 - The Beginning
22:27 - Crash
30:45 - Dynamic
40:07 - Chaos &amp; Control
49:24 - Frenemies
57:08 - Couples Counselling
1:05:04 - Trisha's Counselling
1:15:59 - Resolution
1:23:53 - The Wall
1:33:16 - Penultimatum
1:39:57 - The Final Episode
1:49:11 - Aftermath
1:57:31 - Aftershock
2:13:07 - The Next Episode
2:22:24 - Divergence
2:31:36 - Reconciliation
2:40:44 - Enemies
2:50:08 - Nemeses
3:04:45 - Truth
3:12:14 - Lies
3:22:34 - Who’s Using Who?
3:30:40 - Who’s Using Who, 2
3:41:32 - Five Percent
3:48:46 - Faith
4:04:27 - Frenemies
4:13:26 - Outro &amp; Credits

For me, I guess I’ll always be someone who requires the rehearsed nature of scripts to maximise my full potential, and although I’m not adverse to making appearances on a podcast here and there, I think I need to focus my efforts on my content first and foremost, given how I have regularly failed to do that of recent. However, it is a thought that has taken up residence in my psyche, what if I was to drop everything I was doing now, set up a new channel with the resources I currently possess, and do something that doesn’t require me tearing my hair out. In a way, it’s a decision that Ethan and Hila Klein, also known as h3h3productions made a few years ago, when they decided to launch the h3 podcast, but let’s rewind for just a moment in case anyone here isn’t fully acquainted with the YouTube leviathan that is h3h3productions.

h3h3productions is the YouTube channel run by the aforementioned Klein couple, they established a presence on YouTube for content that often parodied their subjects, usually utilising Ethan’s offbeat sense of humour, alongside editing that put a somewhat amusingly absurdist twist on the content they were lampooning. Nonetheless, many of these videos also had an underlying moral message that resonated with many viewers, often calling out many of the creators of their time for their often shallow exploitation of YouTube culture. 

They’re funny, they’re well made, and many of them are still relevant to this day. They’re videos I grew up with, and will always find a place in my heart for. However, a few years ago, as many of you probably know, they themselves became the centre of attention after one of the subjects of their videos: a gentleman by the name of Matt Hoss, decided to sue them for copyright infringement. It had been regularly debated on how much commentary constituted fair use, and with h3’s videos, there was an uneasy trepidation that maybe, if the ruling went in the favour of the plaintiff, that a new gauntlet would be set down for further lawsuits in this domain.

Fortunately the case was won by our protagonists here, and they triumphantly returned to the platform, cheered on by the platform itself, and many creators whose livelihoods seemed to depend on the verdict. However, you can’t really undo the stress that such a case would cause you, and in the aftermath it seemed difficult to return to that content with the same sort of gusto that they’d previously bore. And it’s hard to blame them, if anything a lawsuit which requires such an investment would inevitably sap the fun out of the content that in many ways served as an escape at one point. So, over time, they seemed to distance themselves further from the formula that they had once been inseparable from, venturing into new pastures, including the one we mentioned earlier: the podcast.

If you got this far and you're still interested, be sure to watch more!</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="56871" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="2017416"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:KyEoKOsU7wg</id>
  <yt:videoId>KyEoKOsU7wg</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCMTk_R_Y49jvq-HQXDmKI0Q</yt:channelId>
  <title>The Curious Case of CreepShow Art - A Question of Character | TRO ft. SisterZio &amp; ItzRooster</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=KyEoKOsU7wg"/>
  <author>
   <name>The Right Opinion</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCMTk_R_Y49jvq-HQXDmKI0Q</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-07-29T19:00:02+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-08-01T15:53:13+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>The Curious Case of CreepShow Art - A Question of Character | TRO ft. SisterZio &amp; ItzRooster</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/KyEoKOsU7wg?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i4.ytimg.com/vi/KyEoKOsU7wg/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>Get Surfshark VPN at https://surfshark.deals/opinion - Enter promo code OPINION for 83% off + 3 months for FREE!

The Right Opinion: The Curious Case of CreepShow Art - A Question of Character | TRO ft. SisterZio &amp; ItzRooster

0:00 - Intro
3:34 - Introduction
9:33 - The Content Cycle
19:11 - Strike 1
26:42 - Strike 2
34:17 - Addressing The Faults
43:37 - This Is Her
51:35 - Hopeless
1:11:51 - Peaches
1:16:56 - Strike 3
1:22:38 - Strike 4?
1:28:43 - The Real Amy
2:09:55 - Shannon's Return
2:19:30 - Emily's Response
2:30:14 - Breadcrumbs
2:37:44 - Moving On

Intro:

Covering drama, isn’t it just the most fun pastime to talk about? 

Well, not always, but as people online have grown more invested in the escapades of online creators, coverage is inevitable. At the same time, reporting can take many different forms, and over the years each audience niche has gradually been filled by their corresponding correspondents, whether that’s to do with breaking the news as it happens with an emphatic tone, or analysing the intricacies of a situation through a more retrospective perspective. What matters to people is that they have a voice relaying to them what’s going on in the world, and that voice is at least somewhat reliable, from there they can construct their own hot takes to share to their social media accounts that permeate their relative platforms.

A lot of content is typically very organised, with attention to production value and a clear structure, even if it may not be the most highbrow. However, this sort of content can also have its disadvantages, my sort of content even, it can feel quite distant to some viewers, and if that audience can’t connect to the creator, then they may not feel an interest in the topic that they’re talking about. Sometimes, organisation is unattractive, as much as it pains me to admit. In those cases, viewers may find solace in a creator with a more casual approach to talking about drama, one that reacts to it in an unedited, and unrestrained way, that reflects our innate human reaction to the discovery of revelations about certain shenanigans, and that’s the genre where the person at the centre of today’s video thrived, a person by the name of CreepShow Art.

Watch more to find out!</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="59056" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="2124848"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:FqwS7wdH2U8</id>
  <yt:videoId>FqwS7wdH2U8</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCMTk_R_Y49jvq-HQXDmKI0Q</yt:channelId>
  <title>How Dream Became A Target - A Reflection On Stan Culture | TRO</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=FqwS7wdH2U8"/>
  <author>
   <name>The Right Opinion</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCMTk_R_Y49jvq-HQXDmKI0Q</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-01-25T21:00:04+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-02-28T23:03:30+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>How Dream Became A Target - A Reflection On Stan Culture | TRO</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/FqwS7wdH2U8?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i3.ytimg.com/vi/FqwS7wdH2U8/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>Get Surfshark VPN at https://surfshark.deals/opinion - Enter promo code OPINION for 83% off and 3 extra months for FREE!

The Right Opinion: How Dream Became A Target - A Reflection On Stan Culture | TRO

0:00 - Surfshark Sponsorship
1:58 - Introduction
8:08 - Fever Dream
14:05 - Parasociety
22:16 - Loyalty
27:56 - Influence
34:02 - Timebomb
41:43 - Countdown
48:29 - $ell Out
54:37 - Running Down A Dream
1:02:40 - Bad Dream
1:11:22 - Rinse and Repeat
1:17:14 - The Mask
1:24:15 - Human
1:30:46 - Intentions
1:36:11 - Provocative
1:46:12 - Stan Culture
1:53:38 - Dream Vs. The World
2:02:20 - Finale
2:09:39 - Conclusion &amp; Credits

Dream is a Minecraft YouTuber, he started his channel in 2014, assuming the moniker of “DreamTraps”, and although it didn’t take him too long to hit 1,000 subs, his channel stagnated after that, and although he’s on record doing a little gaming with his friends, and interacting on Twitter, these few years seem pretty uneventful by a YouTuber’s standard. However, this all changed in 2019, where Minecraft was experiencing a bit of a renaissance amongst online communities, and creators alike.

However, it was also a refreshed sense of interest, not necessarily based in nostalgia, and this created a gap for new creators to rise up and fill the increased demand for Minecraft based content. Dream was one of those eager creators, and he wasn’t just any old chump mooching off its popularity, he was a seasoned and experienced patron of the game, and his skills were regularly showcased in the content he produced, which often revolved around challenges that tested his in-game ability, as well as his rather popular Minecraft Manhunt series. Although he wasn’t regarded as a force of personality, his proficiency with the game at hand was highly admirable, and as more people tuned in, his channel picked up momentum, though I’m not sure anyone could have quite predicted where he would be today. 

You see, in the space of two years, he went from a thousand subscribers or so to over twenty million, which I think is what some would call “blowing up”. He streams with a crew known as the “Dream Team”, which includes old and new friends alike, he uploads on a semi-regular basis, has various successful side hustles. It would be fair to take a glance at his channel and say he’s doing alright for himself, but is it the full story?

Such a great amount of success, in such a short amount of time is certainly a lot to adjust to, alongside the increased sense of influence and responsibility you hold. However, it’s nothing that creators online aren’t used to, is it? 

For more... Watch the video!</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="91615" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="2490188"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:AeuZZuobHEo</id>
  <yt:videoId>AeuZZuobHEo</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCMTk_R_Y49jvq-HQXDmKI0Q</yt:channelId>
  <title>The Problems With Blaire White - Misinformation And &quot;Moderation&quot; | TRO</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=AeuZZuobHEo"/>
  <author>
   <name>The Right Opinion</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCMTk_R_Y49jvq-HQXDmKI0Q</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2021-09-25T22:00:34+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-05-11T15:03:42+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>The Problems With Blaire White - Misinformation And &quot;Moderation&quot; | TRO</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/AeuZZuobHEo?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i2.ytimg.com/vi/AeuZZuobHEo/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>The Problems With Blaire White - Misinformation And &quot;Moderation&quot; | TRO

0:00:00 - Introduction
0:06:20 - Setting The Scene
0:13:50 - The Anti-Feminist
0:21:54 - The Good One
0:29:25 - The Playground
0:37:39 - A New Leaf
0:47:37 - Changes
0:56:42 - One Step Back
1:04:28 - A New Calling
1:13:19 - Ground Hog Day
1:22:23 - God I'm So Done
1:31:38 - The Moderate
1:42:06 - The Hill
1:51:12 - The Fall
2:00:34 - The Apology
2:09:47 - Credibility
2:17:32 - The Blaire White Saga
2:24:39 - It Never Ends
2:32:42 - Moderation
2:46:00 - Conclusion &amp; Credits

Intro: 

I recall back to my Q&amp;A in March, when The Nostradamus Opinion announced that the year seemed to calming down, which in hindsight, was a slightly a misguided forecast, in fact, I’d positively say it was a kiss of death, as the world has careened towards its frankly, well-deserved armageddon. 

Honestly, I’ve not handled it too well personally, to see so much going on often makes me want to curl up into a ball and hibernate, or aestivate if you consider when all this was happening. At the same time, there’s always reason within the chaos, and I’ve always lived by the philosophy that I’d emerge from hardships a wiser man, and a part of me hopes that would be similarly applicable on a macro level as well. However, we’ll never reach that if we can’t have a proper, mature discussion to understand how such discord has arisen, and at times where emotions can run high we often need voices of reason to lead that discourse forward, so that we can all learn from such adversities.

In the past few years in particular, I feel that YouTube has become increasingly integral to that conversation, introducing a new generation to the many complex, and sometimes not as complex matters facing down today’s youth, with online creators engaging audiences through fresh mediums, acquainting them with new ideas and perspectives. Although the nature of my channel can be a little biographical, I hope that people have found value in the viewpoints I have to share. And you know what? I’d say the feedback has been broadly positive. One way that people recognise the work you do is what some regard as “Year end lists”, where people compile a selection of their favourite creators, and post it to their preferred social media site.

At the end of 2019, I was once again honoured by being placed amongst YouTubers who put great effort into their respective hustle, however, one name whose presence I was surprised to see was a commentator by the name of Blaire White.

Want to know more? Watch the video...</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="80656" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="2665831"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:w-537G_cn9U</id>
  <yt:videoId>w-537G_cn9U</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCMTk_R_Y49jvq-HQXDmKI0Q</yt:channelId>
  <title>The Manipulation Of Mini Ladd - A History Of Lies | TRO</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=w-537G_cn9U"/>
  <author>
   <name>The Right Opinion</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCMTk_R_Y49jvq-HQXDmKI0Q</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2021-06-02T22:00:01+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-01-08T03:59:08+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>The Manipulation Of Mini Ladd - A History Of Lies | TRO</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/w-537G_cn9U?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i4.ytimg.com/vi/w-537G_cn9U/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>The Right Opinion: The Manipulation Of Mini Ladd - A History Of Lies  | TRO

00:00 | Part 1 - Intro
~
07:24 | Part 2 - Mini Chadd
14:13 | Part 3 - Mad Ladd
21:58 | Part 4 - Mini Gladd
27:56 | Part 5 - Mini Dadd
35:20 | Part 6 - Mini Cladd
42:28 | Part 7 - Mini Fadd
52:02 | Part 8 - Mini Cadd
1:01:05 | Part 9 - Mini Sadd
1:09:08 | Part 10 - His Apology
1:21:45 | Part 11 - Mini Gadd
1:30:58 | Part 12 - Mini Ladd
~
1:39:23 | Part 13 - Outro &amp; Credits

Hello ladies and gentlemen, and welcome to The Right Opinion, the home of a twat with too much free time, and the past, it’s a strange thing, and one that, in times like these, we probably long for more than ever. 

Although I do relate to this sentiment, more than you can possibly know, I likely wouldn’t take anyone other than the person that I am today, minus the chronic health issues of course. Yes, if we can transpose the current version of ourselves to past scenarios, then that’s the choice that many would probably take, it would have likely saved me, and others, from unnecessary disputes and distress, however, at the same time, without many of those past scenarios, we probably wouldn’t be where we are today. In many ways, it’s a paradoxical conundrum, and the best you can do is be thankful for your present wisdom. 

As internet dwellers we tend not to talk about our possibly tainted backstories too much, because other people have a nature to be quite judgemental, and if that’s not who we are today, then what right do people really have to know. However, it’s almost always important we keep the past in mind, because if not, we may be destined to repeat it, and for many people that’s the last thing we want. With this said, there are some who will repeat it regardless, whether they know it’s wrong or not, and for those individuals, well, we may have to be a bit more vocal in how we reprimand them. This is especially true if those individuals hold a relative amount of influence as say, I don’t know, a YouTuber, with dedicated fans, probably serving as a role model to a fair proportion of them. What about when said drama involves your followers? Well then, let’s discuss today’s topic…

Gamers unite, yes, we are once more heading back to that corner of YouTube to set the backdrop for today’s discourse, and we’ll begin by talking about one of the titans of the gaming community, Vanoss.

Evan Fong, also known as VanossGaming, is a creator who posts montage-style content of him and his friends playing a variety of video games, on paper, it sounds fairly unexceptional, but the editing, and interplay between Fong and his comrades has garnered widespread attention from viewers, establishing his channel as a cornerstone in the YouTube gaming subculture that has flourished in the past decade. On his channel, he would feature a retinue of creators who would aid that back-and-forth energy that buoyed his content, this roster would evolve over the years, but one individual who became a pretty regular fixture on the channel during the mid 2010s was a gentleman by the name of Mini Ladd.</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="158814" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="5568493"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:nSx3Ekx2hTM</id>
  <yt:videoId>nSx3Ekx2hTM</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCMTk_R_Y49jvq-HQXDmKI0Q</yt:channelId>
  <title>How One Game Rocked A Community - The Story Behind Hunt Down The Freeman | TRO</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=nSx3Ekx2hTM"/>
  <author>
   <name>The Right Opinion</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCMTk_R_Y49jvq-HQXDmKI0Q</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2021-01-20T21:59:59+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-06-24T08:37:50+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>How One Game Rocked A Community - The Story Behind Hunt Down The Freeman | TRO</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/nSx3Ekx2hTM?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i3.ytimg.com/vi/nSx3Ekx2hTM/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>The Right Opinion: How One Game Rocked A Community - The Story Behind Hunt Down The Freeman | TRO

0:00 - Hunt Down The Freeman
6:30 - Hunt Down The Backstory
13:39 - Hunt Down The Funding
20:49 - Hunt Down The Release
27:29 - Hunt Down The Response
42:30 - Hunt Down The Refund
52:23 - Hunt Down The Controversy
58:32 - Hunt Down The Berkan
1:05:54 - Hunt Down The Conclusion
1:13:11 - Outro &amp; Credits

Intro:  

Recently, I have been the recipient of shocking allegations, that I, am frankly astounded anyone would suggest, these are of course, the allegations, that I am in fact, not a gamer. 

Fitting reaction of shock

I know my friends, I am as outraged as you are, once again, the pineapple on pizza loving heathens have the audacity to cast doubt on my gamer credentials, needless to say, I would be crying at the club, if it was open. So I guess I will have to debunk these claims by taking on another gamer topic, one which will serve as indisputable evidence for my unflinching gamer status, but for this intro, let’s talk about another curious video game that serves as the backdrop for today’s subject. 

Half-Life, it’s a video game, for gamers, like me, who wish to immerse themselves in a first-person shooter with a bit more depth, with the first being released in 1998, the second in 2004, and further successive instalments being released in 2006 and 2007, as well as some additional expansion packs in between. The first game focuses around an individual by the name of Gordon Freeman, who, like many people, triggers an alien invasion when an experiment that he’s running opens up a dimensional rift in time and space. Obviously, antics ensue, and he finds himself up against a diverse plethora of enemies in his mission to return stability to this facility, and the planet alike. Obviously, my synopsis of these games will remain relatively short so I don’t spoil it for anyone planning to play it themselves, but generally speaking it’s considered by many to be one of the greatest games ever published. This is the same story with Half-Life 2, which follows our good friend Gordon a couple decades on after the events of the first, it incorporates many elements present in its predecessor, while adding new features and improving on existing ones. In spite of their shooter status, the series was characterised by its heightened sense of ambition, with Valve President Gabe Newell stating that “if Half-Life 2 isn't viewed as the best PC game of all time, it's going to completely bum out most of the guys on this team”. But Gabe need not have feared, it was released to universal acclaim from reviewers and audiences alike, and is also regarded by many as one of the greatest games of all time.

After the success of the first two games, the developers decided to further metamorphose their approach, with the plan to release a trilogy of episodes, continuing the story from the lens of our protagonist, and a new non-player character by the name of Alyx Vance, a lovely young lady who was present in the previous game, but was now receiving a more prominent role as a companion to Mr. Freeman here. The first two episodes were released to highly positive reception, however, it wasn’t quite equivalent to the rampant appraisal that the previous games had received, though this did not appear to deter them. Episode 3 should have completed the trilogy, and was planned for release in Christmas 2007, however, was initially postponed, and then cancelled following a sequence of delays and changes to company trajectory. 

Since then there has been a lot of speculation as to when the long anticipated “Half-Life 3” will be released. In fact, as I’m sure many of you know, there is an infamous meme, revolving around people’s rather excitable nature to seek confirmation of the game’s announcement, indulged by many throughout the industry. On Wikipedia, there is a page exclusively dedicated to documenting unreleased Half-Life games, it seems that in spite of their revered status within gamer society, the hype surrounding prospective Half-Life projects precedes them. 

The series have elevated itself to this cult-level status, and wherever there’s a devoted fanbase, there’s typically market potential, combine this with the desire simply for more Half-Life content, yet a significant lack of it in the decade following the uncompleted trilogy, and people were longing for a saviour, holding out for a hero to give them what they wanted, and from the darkness, came an unlikely salvation, but was it the one we needed, or the one we deserved.</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="51648" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="1398287"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:_dvag5i55Yc</id>
  <yt:videoId>_dvag5i55Yc</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCMTk_R_Y49jvq-HQXDmKI0Q</yt:channelId>
  <title>The Real Ellen - The Bitter Truth Behind The Daytime Icon | TRO</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_dvag5i55Yc"/>
  <author>
   <name>The Right Opinion</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCMTk_R_Y49jvq-HQXDmKI0Q</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2020-12-17T00:00:02+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-03-05T15:01:54+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>The Real Ellen - The Bitter Truth Behind The Daytime Icon | TRO</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/_dvag5i55Yc?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i4.ytimg.com/vi/_dvag5i55Yc/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>AdamandEve.com. Code: RIGHT. 50% Off 1 Item + Free Shipping in the US and Canada. *Some exclusions apply*

The Real Ellen - The Bitter Truth Behind The Daytime Icon | TRO

0:00 - Sponsor's Message
0:37 - Introduction
7:50 - Precipitate
14:41 - Kindness
24:25 - Hierarchy
33:17 - Erosion
40:00 - The Hole
47:50 - Digging Deeep
55:02 - Curtains
1:03:28 - The &quot;Real&quot; Ellen
1:17:10 - Outro &amp; Credits</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="124367" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="4354105"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:8dTRx9YsbwA</id>
  <yt:videoId>8dTRx9YsbwA</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCMTk_R_Y49jvq-HQXDmKI0Q</yt:channelId>
  <title>The Family YouTuber Who Gave Away Her Son - Myka Stauffer | TRO</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8dTRx9YsbwA"/>
  <author>
   <name>The Right Opinion</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCMTk_R_Y49jvq-HQXDmKI0Q</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2020-11-05T22:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-06-02T08:29:38+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>The Family YouTuber Who Gave Away Her Son - Myka Stauffer | TRO</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/8dTRx9YsbwA?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i1.ytimg.com/vi/8dTRx9YsbwA/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>Go to https://buyraycon.com/TRO 15% off your order! Brought to you by Raycon

The Right Opinion: The Family YouTuber Who Gave Away Her Son - Myka Stauffer | TRO

0:00 - Intro
9:10 - Brave New World
18:25 - After Many A Summer
25:18 - The Genius and The Goddess
31:28 - Point Counter Point
38:24 - Antic Hay
44:11 - Those Barren Leaves
52:10 - Island
58:47 - Time Must Have A Stop

Intro:

Family. For better and for worse, there is no connection like the one you create with the family, I have discussed this time and time again, so I shan’t go into too much depth on my philosophical thoughts on one’s kinsfolk, but as you are all aware by this point, emotional potential, breeds market potential, and the family channel took its place on the YouTube terrain a long time ago. 

Now, family channels are no stranger to criticism. The extent that some families will go for views, often places some of the channels at odds with the rather rigorous standards that audience members impose for such creators, why do these standards exist? Well, because of the children. If you are a parent, many would assert that you have a responsibility to preserve as idyllic a childhood as possible for your offspring, and that degree of responsibility is only amplified when you’re uploading content of your family onto a public platform.

In spite of this, most criticism is typically confined to parents failing to be adequate role models, not just for their own family, but for others who they are supposed to be educating through their content. Some of these escapades may lead to some asking if they are equipped properly to even have children, however, it is seldom the parents who are asking that question, or even acting on such inclination, this is where today’s subjects appear to be an exception.</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="103978" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="3632632"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:bqalB7NywqU</id>
  <yt:videoId>bqalB7NywqU</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCMTk_R_Y49jvq-HQXDmKI0Q</yt:channelId>
  <title>What Happened To Club Penguin? The End Of A Childhood Gem | TRO (ft. Internet Historian)</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=bqalB7NywqU"/>
  <author>
   <name>The Right Opinion</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCMTk_R_Y49jvq-HQXDmKI0Q</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2020-10-04T22:04:27+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-04-17T02:23:26+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>What Happened To Club Penguin? The End Of A Childhood Gem | TRO (ft. Internet Historian)</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/bqalB7NywqU?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i3.ytimg.com/vi/bqalB7NywqU/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>What Happened To Club Penguin? The End Of A Childhood Gem | TRO (ft. Internet Historian)

0:00 - Intro
8:56 - Disney
15:46 - Cast Away
23:19 - Rewritten
31:17 - Online
41:10 - End Of Days
51:42 - The Fall Of Club Penguin

Today, we are going back to the gaming corner of YouTube, because as I have proven time and time again, I am a gamer, and today we are looking at an online MMO which some would argue is unrivalled in the gamer spirit that it has fostered.

Now, you may have suspected an undertone of irony there, but don’t be fooled my friends, because back in the golden days when The Right Opinion was a young lad, full of zest and zeal, there were three games which shaped his online experience: those being, Runescape, Neopets, and the topic of interest today: Club Penguin. 

I can’t remember which order I played them in exactly, though I could take an educated guess, but I still remember them fondly for being able to capture sentiments of wide-eyed wonder and imagination that seem far beyond my grasp these days, and I know this wasn’t just a personal experience, I’m sure many of you similarly reminisce to a time where such avenues felt like a genuine escape to a different world.

However, as time has progressed, so have we, and such memories fade into the background of a distant past. Nonetheless, I find some consolation in the thought that if I ever wanted to attempt to emulate that escapism again, those sites are, as of right now, ready and waiting to welcome me home… well, all except Club Penguin.

Yes, Club Penguin, an abandoned abode. Their tragic demise seemed intangible to many, for a site which had once boasted over 200 million registered accounts, and 30 million active users, however, its last few years have been plagued by drama and conflict, eventually culminating in a rather cataclysmic fashion. 

For those who are unfamiliar, Club Penguin was an online game in which your character could take the form of a penguin, and participate in various activities all over this online world, full of many other colourful fluffy characters controlled by very real people. As a child it taught you the ropes of online safety, and interpersonal friendship. It had some pretty fun games too, and for the young mind, Club Penguin helped prepare individuals for what the internet was going to throw at us, which is an ever more important learning curve in today’s society. Yet, in spite of its relevance, it no longer plays this part in the online sphere, and today, we’ll be finding out how that happened.

However, to understand its end, we need to go back to the beginning, and maybe provide a little background for anyone who never had the privilege to roleplay online as a virtual bird, unless you’re one of those avians, of course. However, I think it’s time to bring in a friend. Now, if you’re familiar with today’s guest you may have recently seen me pull off a legendary voice performance on one of his newest videos.</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="62356" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="1701980"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:JUJOe2MCJp8</id>
  <yt:videoId>JUJOe2MCJp8</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCMTk_R_Y49jvq-HQXDmKI0Q</yt:channelId>
  <title>How One Comment Can Take You Down A Rabbit Hole - The Truth Behind Logan | TRO</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=JUJOe2MCJp8"/>
  <author>
   <name>The Right Opinion</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCMTk_R_Y49jvq-HQXDmKI0Q</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2020-09-09T23:00:01+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-03-06T12:28:30+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>How One Comment Can Take You Down A Rabbit Hole - The Truth Behind Logan | TRO</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/JUJOe2MCJp8?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i3.ytimg.com/vi/JUJOe2MCJp8/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>The Right Opinion: How One Comment Can Take You Down A Rabbit Hole - The Truth Behind Logan | TRO

0:00 - Intro
6:04 - Red Herring
12:56 - Hackerman
21:30 - Unprotected
38:51 - A Crooked System
47:38 - The Solution

Security online, it’s something that a lot of us value as a personal liberty, for our privacy, and our safety. In the last decade, security online has taken multiple steps forward, but as large platforms are taking steps to protect their users, hackers are never too far behind, always looking for methods to stir up trouble, whether that’s attempting to obtain user data, or merely hijack someone’s account for comedic purposes. Plenty of sites have encountered data breaches, it’s an unfortunate hazard that some are clearly ill-prepared for. However, as much as hackers obtaining user data justifiably causes concern on a macro basis, I think people are much more protective over the possession of their personal accounts.

Our personal accounts, regardless of size, or influence, often pertain great personal value to us, as a platform that represents our thoughts, feelings, and even our creative ventures, it’s a piece of us. That sort of thing can definitely be exemplified with one’s YouTube account, now of course many people create YouTube accounts for the mere purposes of commenting, subscribing, and following content, however for many people, a YouTube account allows us to express ourselves, and even if we’re projecting our content towards a large audience, it’s still a product which feels deeply intimate to us, which is why people care about others when they have their channels unnecessarily terminated or restricted. We like to think that all in all, YouTube, in spite of their flaws have a grip on keeping our accounts secure, however, when you look at their track record, this could be called into contention.

Over the last few years, many creators have reported their channels stolen, and subsequently used for less than dignified purposes, in fact, it seems to be an overwhelmingly common occurrence for many users. Now when you have so many channels on a website like YouTube, it seems inevitable that some accounts will be hacked, or stolen, but today we’re looking at an issue that transcends a few occurrences, and outlines a trend which appears pervasive on the platform, and encompassed by one account, which went by the name of Logan.</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="86993" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="2095704"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:mTn_rmpDCV8</id>
  <yt:videoId>mTn_rmpDCV8</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCMTk_R_Y49jvq-HQXDmKI0Q</yt:channelId>
  <title>The Never-Ending Nightmare Of Nikocado Avocado - From Vegan To Villain | TRO</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=mTn_rmpDCV8"/>
  <author>
   <name>The Right Opinion</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCMTk_R_Y49jvq-HQXDmKI0Q</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2020-08-05T22:00:01+00:00</published>
  <updated>2021-12-17T01:09:20+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>The Never-Ending Nightmare Of Nikocado Avocado - From Vegan To Villain | TRO</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/mTn_rmpDCV8?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i2.ytimg.com/vi/mTn_rmpDCV8/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>Sponsored: Get Surfshark VPN at https://surfshark.deals/opinion and enter promo code OPINION for 85% off and 3 extra months for free!

The Right Opinion: The Never-Ending Nightmare Of Nikocado Avocado - From Vegan To Villain | TRO

0:00 - Intro
10:28 - Origins
17:58 - New Era
27:10 - Devil's Advocado
38:04 - Calculation
46:27 - Worth The Weight
56:39 - Drama Queen
1:08:31 - Enduriance
1:17:19 - Cracked Foundations
1:31:20 - Trisha
1:42:52 - Twisted Reality
1:59:41 - The Joker
2:11:20 - Collecting the W
2:23:39 - The Standard
2:31:37 - Stephanie
2:49:26 - Nick's Retort
2:57:22 - Self-Incrimination
3:12:15 - Playing Yourself
3:39:56 - By The Sword
3:51:50 - Old Dogs
4:06:59 - New Tricks
4:18:33 - Undeniably Nick
4:28:49 - The Never-Ending Nightmare Of Nikocado Avocado

Intro:

Drama. In the world of YouTube, the word “drama” is typically used to refer to a conflict regarding a creator, or multiple creators at that. It’s a pretty central theme to the current content that I make on my channel, and is a focal point for multiple commentators alike. We tend to associate most drama with a more contemporary era of YouTube, originating from the mid 2010s, spearheaded by many commentators, and really popularised by the Content Cop series, but drama has existed since the dawn of YouTube. I remember all the way back in 2012, when I watched a lot of Call of Duty content, because, as always, I am a gamer, and there was a very renowned callout video uploaded which obtained well over a million views, and probably would have obtained many more if it had not been deleted. In an environment like that, that was hugely impressive. 

However, with the constant manifestation of communities, and lack of real culture surrounding the nature of drama, with it more seeming like an unintended side effect, nothing ever seemed mould its way into YouTube history, and we tend to reminisce about the early 2010s on YouTube with the innocent nostalgia that we have since assigned to it. That’s not a facet that can be considered with commentary, and since its rise, every major conflict seems imprinted on this beautiful platform, for better and for worse. 

Yet the sensation that drama provokes ever remains the same. It was still one of the most iconic feelings when that Call of Duty drama in 2012 was transpiring, it was a rush, someone being exposed, conflict within the community. The truth is plain, many creators, and audiences alike, thrive on drama, the appeal of it is indisputable, and as it has grown out of its reputation as a byproduct, and into its own genre, it becomes more powerful, and people feel less afraid to indulge their more dramatic side. On top of this, with the increased mobilisation of online communities, it has been granted additional consequential value that we can observe over the past few years.

One of the most noteworthy outcomes of this is “expose culture”, when a person makes strong or revelatory claims regarding another individual, and their behaviour, typically with the intent of depicting a character that had not been previously shown to the audience. You might find someone sitting quite sternly, glaring at the camera, before going into details of whatever they wish to disclose, or you might just see a neatly posted Twitlonger. The overarching message will tell you, this person isn’t who you thought they were, whether its mere business malpractice or something more sinister, there can be very real ramifications. 

The mid 2010s weren’t just for sewing the seeds of drama, and commentary though. No, in fact many new genres rose to YouTube prominence, one of those being mukbangs. Mukbang is another delightful portmanteau whose literal translation would be eatcast, with such information you can probably take a guess at what I’m referring to.  

Yes, the videos where we have an individual consuming portions of food, often accompanied by them making casual chit-chat with the audience. It originated in South Korea at the end of 2000s, but only really caught fire in 2015, when a few larger channels began to pay attention to it.  Since then we’ve seen a wave of creators all over the spectrum take part, either engaging in it as a side venture, or as their dedicated pursuit.

So we have drama, and mukbang, simultaneously emerging into the limelight… two, seemingly quite distinct genres, but what would you end up with, if you merged the two together…

Ladies and gentlemen, I introduce you to Nikocado Avocado.</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="255809" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="9159256"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:91yro7IPSb4</id>
  <yt:videoId>91yro7IPSb4</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCMTk_R_Y49jvq-HQXDmKI0Q</yt:channelId>
  <title>How One &quot;Man&quot; Fooled Us All - The Strange Story Of Samurai Buyer | TRO</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=91yro7IPSb4"/>
  <author>
   <name>The Right Opinion</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCMTk_R_Y49jvq-HQXDmKI0Q</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2020-06-17T21:59:58+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-02-09T05:52:15+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>How One &quot;Man&quot; Fooled Us All - The Strange Story Of Samurai Buyer | TRO</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/91yro7IPSb4?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i2.ytimg.com/vi/91yro7IPSb4/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>How One &quot;Man&quot; Fooled Us All - The Strange Story Of Samurai Buyer | TRO

0:00 - Intro
5:59 - The Rise Of Samurai Buyer
12:26 - i Dubbbed
19:02 - Cherry Blossom
25:57 - Stormy Weather
33:09 - Collateral
43:39 - Samurai Liar
52:29 - Sayonara

Intro:

Image can be reflected in our demeanour, our actions, our comments, and equally, it will be defined by how people interpret that behaviour. When we encounter people, and other alike entities, we spend a lot of time attempting to paint a mental picture in our head for how we envision them. Now, we cannot look into their minds and read their every intention, but some judgement is always necessary, because when we have to make a decision which may involve bestowing responsibility or trust in certain people, then that mental picture has to be factored in. 

However, this is typically reserved for personal relationships, and although we may hold greater opinions about certain issues, we won’t typically assign a face to it. This is particularly the case with corporations. Now, it’s completely valid to have distaste for companies and their conduct, but it’s also reasonable to accept that most companies are made up of a lot of interacting tiers, and this can lead to them pretty much being separated from the idea of consciousness altogether. Although I wouldn’t actually agree with that, and urge others to keep in mind that a decision will typically have a person behind it, it is often hard to conceptually feel any emotional connection to what a company may do, hell, if we did we’d probably never stop being upset, and we need to look out for our mental well being too you know.

YouTube occupies a weird medium between the world of intimacy and distance, because although we may not feel a connection to a lot of creators on a personal level, their success partly relies on the direct support that we pledge towards them. A lot of celebrities feel a bit beyond our world, and YouTube creates communities that people can be involved in, however, because of that, there is a bit more direct accountability, and a judgement that does feel a little more personal. Therefore, we tend to apply certain standards for creators that we may not give to large multinational corporations, partly because of that connection, and partly because we actually have the power to hold them accountable.

Over the last few years, we’ve witnessed companies attempt to be quote “woke”, and relate to the human condition, yet it never feels particularly real because, although amusing, you receive the impression it’s just another campaign focused towards the demographic of depressed teenagers who occupy the Twitter hellscape. On top of this, the Tweets are never really channeled through the mind of an individual, and therefore we never put a face to the company or develop a personal connection. 

However, in 2015, a business managed to infiltrate a budding YouTube community, through a character who would become almost synonymous with the product that he was offering. Yes, long before BetterHelp would cause many creators to reevaluate how they keep an eye on the sponsors they collaborate with, there was an even more bewildering controversy, surrounding one of the most iconic YouTube sponsors: Samurai Buyer.</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="109637" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="3372465"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:BDGVbiaiJ2M</id>
  <yt:videoId>BDGVbiaiJ2M</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCMTk_R_Y49jvq-HQXDmKI0Q</yt:channelId>
  <title>The Dramatic Decay Of DanPlan - End Of An Animated Era | TRO</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=BDGVbiaiJ2M"/>
  <author>
   <name>The Right Opinion</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCMTk_R_Y49jvq-HQXDmKI0Q</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2020-05-31T21:00:07+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-02-08T00:31:37+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>The Dramatic Decay Of DanPlan - End Of An Animated Era | TRO</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/BDGVbiaiJ2M?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i3.ytimg.com/vi/BDGVbiaiJ2M/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>The Right Opinion: The Dramatic Decay Of DanPlan - End Of An Animated Era | TRO

0:00 - Intro
7:32 - Actually
15:31 - Sharing Is Caring
25:33 - Ownership
37:07 - The Response
48:14 - Dissonance
1:00:20 - Small Change
1:11:47 - The Animators
1:28:05 - Unanswered Questions
1:36:05 - The Answers

Intro:

Now, when someone reached out to me about this situation, I will admit, I was not familiar with DanPlan, and in spite of their approximately 2 million strong fanbase, many of my friends were not familiar with their content either, so I sat down and watched a lot of DanPlan. Now I think I have a decent grasp, I will briefly summarise their origins and content, just so people have a grip on how they created such a significant following. 

DanPlan as a channel was established in July 2014 by their titular creators: Daniel, and his friend Hosuh, with the first upload coming soon after.

This was the first instalment of their “By the way” series, the video consisted of a slightly crudely drawn character discussing a story told by his youth pastor. Now, the audio could be better, and this video only appears to include Dan himself, but you can definitely see the origins of a great channel in the making, a lot of Hosuh’s creative illustrations enhance Dan’s stories on a comedic basis, and Dan’s outgoing nature makes him an effective storyteller, there was definitely potential here.

However, this series didn’t receive much attention following its initial upload. Animation was in a bit of a lull at that point, and thus it was probably not worth putting too many eggs in that basket. After this DanPlan spent just under a couple years dedicated to gaming content, which was much more popular at the time. These gaming videos weren’t the most unique, though they were often presented more like highlight reels, and used character heads to represent different people talking. Dan was the consistent host of these videos, gaming with a varying roster of guests, such as Anna, Billy, Jay, and of course, Hosuh. However, there was one more character to introduce to this story, that person goes by the name of Stephen.

Stephen was introduced on the 5th of September, 2015, in the upload “Yamete, Titan Senpai”, in which he, and of course, Dan, and Hosuh, played the Attack On Titan tribute game. Like Hosuh, and many of their other friends, they were acquainted through school and college, and for these comrades, this was just a regular gaming session which happened to be uploaded onto YouTube. Stephen was not one of the original members, but he quickly became a recurring guest on the channel as other individuals began to appear less. However, these gaming videos, although enjoyable for those who participated, didn’t set the channel on fire, gaining DanPlan only 50 subscribers. So come May 2016, the “By The Way” series was resumed, but this time, with a slightly different format. ..

Watch the rest of the video for more.</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="149496" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="5898953"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:p1Zb90MFf20</id>
  <yt:videoId>p1Zb90MFf20</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCMTk_R_Y49jvq-HQXDmKI0Q</yt:channelId>
  <title>The Turbulent Tale of Yandere Dev - A Six Year Struggle | TRO (ft. Thafnine)</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=p1Zb90MFf20"/>
  <author>
   <name>The Right Opinion</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCMTk_R_Y49jvq-HQXDmKI0Q</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2020-05-04T20:00:02+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-05-18T23:43:31+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>The Turbulent Tale of Yandere Dev - A Six Year Struggle | TRO (ft. Thafnine)</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/p1Zb90MFf20?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i1.ytimg.com/vi/p1Zb90MFf20/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>The Right Opinion: The Turbulent Tale of Yandere Dev - A Six Year Struggle | TRO (ft. Thafnine)

This content is meant to inform, educate, and document, and should be strictly interpreted in that context.

Intro Preview:

Ah anime… my favourite, what do people who like anime say... uwu? I’m gonna level with you guys here, one of my most commonly asked questions is if I watch anime, and although I have seen a couple movies when I was much younger: Spirited Away, Howl's Moving Castle, I haven’t really had the chance to enjoy much of it, although I have heard great things, and I really do respect the art, some of the art is truly beautiful. Now anime has been relatively popular since the early 20th century, it obviously originated in Japan, and often represented the cultural zeitgeist at the time.

The development of digital mediums has allowed the art to flourish and expand into new genres. One of those is of course, the video game genre. There are many anime video games, and it was in the video game heyday of the 1980s that anime inspired video games, and video game inspired anime rose to prominence. Since then, their popularity has continued to extend beyond their borders, with the style attaining international prestige amongst a variety of audiences. I also want to take a moment to talk about manga, which is typically used to refer to comics and graphic novels, often created in the Japanese style, manga precedes anime, and although mangas may be made reflecting an anime style, they are by no means the same. However, there is overlap, that overlap can be demonstrated in many characterisations of individuals, this is where we meet the Yandere. 

Yandere is a portmanteau (which is our word of the day) of the words “Yanderu” and “Deredere”, Yanderu meaning sick, and deredere meaning infatuated, deeply in love. So combined you reach the lovely idea that this person is in love to a sick extent, they will do anything for their senpai, even if that means often less than charitable activities. This personality trait is attributed to manga, however, it has gained popularity in anime as well, with many characters being modelled around that mould. The psychotic behaviour paired with an often cute design seems to be a good contrast that has become quite the rave, and it wasn’t until one very cheeky game developer had a very cheeky idea, how about we make a whole video game from the perspective of a Yandere.

That cheeky game developer was a person by the name of Alex Mahan, currently operating under the very fitting name of Yandere Dev.

Watch more to find out...</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="161950" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="5618800"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:Gef1nihHFYU</id>
  <yt:videoId>Gef1nihHFYU</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCMTk_R_Y49jvq-HQXDmKI0Q</yt:channelId>
  <title>The Failure of 13 Reasons Why | TRO (ft. I Hate Everything)</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Gef1nihHFYU"/>
  <author>
   <name>The Right Opinion</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCMTk_R_Y49jvq-HQXDmKI0Q</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2020-04-08T21:36:20+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-10-12T01:19:22+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>The Failure of 13 Reasons Why | TRO (ft. I Hate Everything)</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/Gef1nihHFYU?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i4.ytimg.com/vi/Gef1nihHFYU/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>The Right Opinion: The Failure of 13 Reasons Why - A Three Season Tragedy (ft. I Hate Everything)

Intro:

V shows, honestly something that I have an interest in, but seldom get around to actually watching.

My biggest problem is how much time they tend to consume, and although I promise you, I have too much free time™, it’s not time that I typically decide to dedicate all towards one TV show, I like to allocate it across various activities to maintain mental well-being, because after all, in this world called YouTube, we can all use that from time to time. I mostly indulge my time in films, which are typically shorter in total (with exceptions), and gaming, because, as I have always asserted, I am a gamer. Nonetheless, recently I have found myself in an interesting predicament because YouTube’s slow monetisation process has basically delayed so many of my videos that I found myself with a week on my hands, and a desire to cover something slightly different. 

So, without further ado, I suggest we tackle that slightly different subject on this glorious, glorious day, and if you have basic reading capabilities you will know that this is 13 Reasons Why.</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="82836" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="2838570"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
</feed>
