<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<rdf:RDF
 xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
 xmlns="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/"
 xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
 xmlns:taxo="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/taxonomy/"
 xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
 xmlns:syn="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
 xmlns:admin="http://webns.net/mvcb/"
>

<channel rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/">
<title>hep-lat updates on arXiv.org</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">High Energy Physics - Lattice (hep-lat) updates on the arXiv.org e-print archive</description>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:date>2022-11-03T20:30:00-05:00</dc:date>
<dc:publisher>www-admin@arxiv.org</dc:publisher>
<dc:subject>High Energy Physics - Lattice</dc:subject>
<syn:updateBase>1901-01-01T00:00+00:00</syn:updateBase>
<syn:updateFrequency>1</syn:updateFrequency>
<syn:updatePeriod>daily</syn:updatePeriod>
<items>
 <rdf:Seq>
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01380" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01662" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01673" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01789" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01846" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2203.16012" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2207.00889" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2209.13409" />
 </rdf:Seq>
</items>
<image rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif" />
</channel>
<image rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif">
<title>arXiv.org</title>
<url>http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif</url>
<link>http://arxiv.org/</link>
</image>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01380">
<title>Large-Scale $2+1$D $\mathrm{U}(1)$ Gauge Theory with Dynamical Matter in a Cold-Atom Quantum Simulator. (arXiv:2211.01380v1 [cond-mat.quant-gas])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01380</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;A major driver of quantum-simulator technology is the prospect of probing
high-energy phenomena in synthetic quantum matter setups at a high level of
control and tunability, thereby offering a venue complementary to dedicated
particle colliders. Here, we propose an experimentally feasible realization of
a large-scale $2+1$D $\mathrm{U}(1)$ gauge theory with dynamical matter and
gauge fields in a cold-atom quantum simulator with spinless bosons. We present
the full mapping of the corresponding Gauss&apos;s law onto the bosonic
computational basis. We then show that the target gauge theory can be
faithfully realized and stabilized by an emergent gauge protection term in a
two-dimensional single-species Bose--Hubbard optical Lieb superlattice with two
spatial periods along either direction, thereby requiring only moderate
experimental resources already available in current cold-atom setups. Using
infinite matrix product states, we calculate numerical benchmarks for adiabatic
sweeps and global quench dynamics that further confirm the fidelity of the
mapping. Our work brings quantum simulators of gauge theories a significant
step forward in terms of investigating particle physics in higher spatial
dimensions, and is readily implementable in existing cold-atom platforms.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Osborne_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jesse Osborne&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+McCulloch_I/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ian P. McCulloch&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Yang_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Bing Yang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Hauke_P/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Philipp Hauke&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Halimeh_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jad C. Halimeh&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01662">
<title>Multicomponent gauge-Higgs models with discrete Abelian gauge groups. (arXiv:2211.01662v1 [hep-lat])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01662</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We consider a variant of the charge-Q compact Abelian-Higgs model, in which
an Nf-dimensional complex vector is coupled with an Abelian Z_q gauge field.
For Nf=2 and Q=1 we observe several transition lines that belong to the O(4),
O(3), and O(2) vector universality classes, depending on the symmetry breaking
pattern at the transition. The universality class is independent of $q$ as long
as q&amp;gt;=3. The universality class of the transition is uniquely determined by the
behavior of the scalar fields; gauge fields do not play any role. We also
investigate the system for Nf=15 and Q=2. In the presence of U(1) gauge fields,
the system undergoes transitions associated with charged fixed points of the
Abelian-Higgs field theory. These continuous transitions turn into first-order
ones when the U(1) gauge fields are replaced by the discrete Z_q fields: in the
present compact model charged transitions appear to be very sensitive to the
nature of the gauge fields
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-lat/1/au:+Bracci_Testasecca_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Giacomo Bracci-Testasecca&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-lat/1/au:+Pelissetto_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Andrea Pelissetto&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01673">
<title>The QCD topological susceptibility at high temperatures via staggered fermions spectral projectors. (arXiv:2211.01673v1 [hep-lat])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01673</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The QCD topological observables are essential inputs to obtain theoretical
predictions about axion phenomenology, which are of utmost importance for
current and future experimental searches for this particle. Among them, we
focus on the topological susceptibility, related to the axion mass. We present
lattice results for the topological susceptibility in QCD at high temperatures
obtained by discretizing this observable via spectral projectors on eigenmodes
of the staggered Dirac operator, and we compare them with those obtained with
the standard gluonic definition. The adoption of the spectral discretization is
motivated by the large lattice artifacts affecting the standard gluonic
susceptibility, related to the choice of non-chiral fermions in the lattice
action.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-lat/1/au:+Athenodorou_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Andreas Athenodorou&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-lat/1/au:+Bonanno_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Claudio Bonanno&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-lat/1/au:+Bonati_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Claudio Bonati&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-lat/1/au:+Clemente_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Giuseppe Clemente&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-lat/1/au:+DAngelo_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Francesco D&amp;#x27;Angelo&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-lat/1/au:+DElia_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Massimo D&amp;#x27;Elia&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-lat/1/au:+Maio_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Lorenzo Maio&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-lat/1/au:+Martinelli_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Guido Martinelli&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-lat/1/au:+Sanfilippo_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Francesco Sanfilippo&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-lat/1/au:+Todaro_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Antonino Todaro&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01789">
<title>Probing hadron mass spectrum in dense two-color QCD with linear sigma model. (arXiv:2211.01789v1 [hep-ph])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01789</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We investigate modifications of hadron masses at finite quark chemical
potential in two-flavor and two-color QCD, of which the data are available from
lattice simulations, within a linear sigma model based on approximate
Pauli-Gursey $SU(4)$ symmetry. The model describes not only ground-state scalar
diquarks and pseudo-scalar mesons but also the excited pseudo-scalar diquarks
and scalar mesons; each ground-state diquark (meson) has the corresponding
excited diquark (hadron) with opposite parity as a chiral partner. Effects of
chiral symmetry breaking and diquark condensates are incorporated by a
mean-field treatment. We show that various mixings among the hadrons, which are
triggered by the breakdown of baryon number conservation in the superfluid
phase, lead to a rich hadron mass spectrum. We discuss the influence of
$U(1)_A$ anomaly on the density dependence of the mass spectrum and also
manifestations of the chiral partner structures as density increases in the
superfluid phase. The predicted hadron masses are expected to provide future
lattice simulations with useful information on such symmetry properties in
dense two-color QCD.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Suenaga_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Daiki Suenaga&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Murakami_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Kotaro Murakami&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Itou_E/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Etsuko Itou&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Iida_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Kei Iida&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01846">
<title>Evidence for the molecular nature of $D_{s0}^*(2317)$ and $D_{s1}(2460)$ and the production yield of $K_{c\bar{c}}(4180)$ as a $D\bar{D}K$ bound state in inclusive $e^+e^-\to c\bar{c}$ collisions. (arXiv:2211.01846v1 [hep-ph])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01846</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Searching for exotic multiquark states and elucidating their nature remains a
central topic in understanding quantum chromo dynamics--the underlying theory
of the strong interaction. Two of the most studied such states are the
charmed-strange states $D_{s0}^*(2317)$ and $D_{s1}(2460)$. In this work, we
show for the first time that their production yields in inclusive $e^+e^-\to
c\bar{c}$ productions near $\sqrt{s}=10.6$ GeV measured by the BaBar
Collaboration can be well explained in the molecular picture, which provide a
highly nontrivial verification of their nature being $DK/D^*K$ molecules. In
addition, we predict the production yield of the $D\bar{D}K$ three-body bound
state, $K_{c\bar{c}}(4180)$, in $e^+e^-\to c\bar{c}$ collisions and find that
it is within the reach of the ongoing Belle II experiment.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Wu_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Tian-Chen Wu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Geng_L/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Li-Sheng Geng&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2203.16012">
<title>Entanglement area law for 1D gauge theories and bosonic systems. (arXiv:2203.16012v2 [quant-ph] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2203.16012</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We prove an entanglement area law for a class of 1D quantum systems involving
infinite-dimensional local Hilbert spaces. This class of quantum systems
include bosonic models such as the Hubbard-Holstein model, and both U(1) and
SU(2) lattice gauge theories in one spatial dimension. Our proof relies on new
results concerning the robustness of the ground state and spectral gap to the
truncation of Hilbert space, applied within the approximate ground state
projector (AGSP) framework from previous work. In establishing this area law,
we develop a system-size independent bound on the expectation value of local
observables for Hamiltonians without translation symmetry, which may be of
separate interest. Our result provides theoretical justification for using
tensor network methods to study the ground state properties of quantum systems
with infinite local degrees of freedom.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Abrahamsen_N/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Nilin Abrahamsen&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Tong_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yu Tong&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Bao_N/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ning Bao&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Su_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yuan Su&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/quant-ph/1/au:+Wiebe_N/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Nathan Wiebe&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2207.00889">
<title>Lattice Fermionic Casimir effect in a Slab Bag and Universality. (arXiv:2207.00889v4 [hep-lat] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2207.00889</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;We apply the physically more appealing MIT Bag boundary conditions to study
the Casimir effect on the lattice. Employing the formalism of &lt;a href=&quot;/abs/2005.10758&quot;&gt;arXiv:2005.10758&lt;/a&gt;
to calculate the Casimir energy for free lattice fermions, we show that the
results for the naive, Wilson and overlap fermions match the continuum
expressions precisely in the zero lattice spacing limit, as expected from
universality. In contrast to &lt;a href=&quot;/abs/2005.10758&quot;&gt;arXiv:2005.10758&lt;/a&gt; where the result for the naive
fermions rapidly oscillates with the lattice size for both, the periodic (P)
and anti-periodic (AP) boundary conditions, no oscillations are observed with
the lattice size. Furthermore, the apparent violation of the universality for
naive fermion in &lt;a href=&quot;/abs/2005.10758&quot;&gt;arXiv:2005.10758&lt;/a&gt; is shown to be cured by applying suitable
series extrapolation techniques, thus demonstrating that the Casimir energy for
the naive fermions with periodic/antiperiodic boundary conditions agrees with
the results for other free lattice fermions, and can as well be used to obtain
the results for the Dirac fermion in the zero limit of the lattice spacing.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-lat/1/au:+Mandlecha_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yash V. Mandlecha&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-lat/1/au:+Gavai_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Rajiv V. Gavai&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2209.13409">
<title>Looking for the effects of New Physics in the $\Lambda_b \longrightarrow \Lambda_c(\to \Lambda \pi) \ell \nu $ decay mode. (arXiv:2209.13409v2 [hep-ph] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2209.13409</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;One of the most pragmatic ways to look for the effects of New Physics at low
energy scales is to study a detailed angular distribution of various decay
modes, and in particular those based on $b\to c\ell\bar \nu_\ell$. In this
paper we focus onto $\Lambda_b \longrightarrow \Lambda_c(\to \Lambda \pi) \ell
\nu$ in a generic effective theory setup in which, besides the Standard Model,
we allow for all the possible covariant dimension-six effective operators
capturing the contributions arising at high energy scales, beyond the Standard
Model. We list a number of observables that could be used as a diagnostic tool
to check for the presence of New Physics and to discriminate among its various
scenarios. We also briefly comment on $\Lambda_c \to \Lambda l\nu$.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Becirevic_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Damir Be&amp;#x10d;irevi&amp;#x107;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/hep-ph/1/au:+Jaffredo_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Florentin Jaffredo&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
</rdf:RDF>