<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns:yt="http://www.youtube.com/xml/schemas/2015" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
 <link rel="self" href="http://www.youtube.com/feeds/videos.xml?channel_id=UCZRoNJu1OszFqABP8AuJIuw"/>
 <id>yt:channel:UCZRoNJu1OszFqABP8AuJIuw</id>
 <yt:channelId>UCZRoNJu1OszFqABP8AuJIuw</yt:channelId>
 <title>Logically Answered</title>
 <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCZRoNJu1OszFqABP8AuJIuw"/>
 <author>
  <name>Logically Answered</name>
  <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCZRoNJu1OszFqABP8AuJIuw</uri>
 </author>
 <published>2012-08-25T22:17:43+00:00</published>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:fTIL8QPYfqs</id>
  <yt:videoId>fTIL8QPYfqs</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCZRoNJu1OszFqABP8AuJIuw</yt:channelId>
  <title>Here's What Happened To Elizabeth Holmes</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fTIL8QPYfqs"/>
  <author>
   <name>Logically Answered</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCZRoNJu1OszFqABP8AuJIuw</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-11-04T19:00:23+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-11-04T19:33:57+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Here's What Happened To Elizabeth Holmes</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/fTIL8QPYfqs?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i3.ytimg.com/vi/fTIL8QPYfqs/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>Elizabeth Holmes is one of the most infamous founders in the world having pulled off the greatest fraud of silicon valley: Theranos. Theranos promised to revolutionize blood testing by reducing the amount of blood required to conduct various tests to just one drop of blood. While this idea was no doubt ingenious and likely would’ve done extraordinarily well in the real world, the problem was the idea simply wasn’t feasible with current technology. So, Theranos turned to handing out unreliable exam results or diluting the blood before using traditional testing machinery. Eventually, the media and regulators caught on which resulted in Theranos testing being banned and eventually shut down. And Elizabeth Holmes has since been charged with 11 counts of criminal felony and convicted of three charges of wire fraud and one charge of conspiracy to commit wire fraud. Today, Elizabeth is waiting to get her sentence which is scheduled to take place on November 18, 2022. While Elizabeth is subject to up to 20 years in prison, experts doubt that she’ll spend even more than 10 years in prison. With that being said though, experts don’t think she’ll be able to completely avoid jail time either. This video explains what happened to Elizabeth Holmes after Theranos was exposed and the potential consequences that she may face. 

Discord Community: 
https://discord.gg/SJUNWNt

Timestamps:
0:00 - D Day
2:03 - Fooling Everyone 
5:25 - The Truth Comes Out
8:20 - The Fallout
11:20 - Fake It Till You Make It

Thumbnail Credit:
Ethan Pines - The Forbes Collection
https://bit.ly/3Dvf8Ov

Resources: 
https://pastebin.com/GSZsw0HD</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="1607" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="43627"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:NqPsdlQDOYQ</id>
  <yt:videoId>NqPsdlQDOYQ</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCZRoNJu1OszFqABP8AuJIuw</yt:channelId>
  <title>5 People Founded Tesla. Only Elon Got Rich.</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=NqPsdlQDOYQ"/>
  <author>
   <name>Logically Answered</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCZRoNJu1OszFqABP8AuJIuw</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-11-02T19:00:08+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-11-02T19:32:56+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>5 People Founded Tesla. Only Elon Got Rich.</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/NqPsdlQDOYQ?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i3.ytimg.com/vi/NqPsdlQDOYQ/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>Elon Musk is usually credited as being the visionary founder of Tesla, and this makes sense given that the early days of Tesla were almost completely funded by himself. Not to mention, he was the main reason that Tesla survived the 2008 financial crisis and the 2018 production hell. But, Tesla actually has 5 founders and Elon is only one of them. The other founders include Martin Eberhard, Mark Tarpenning, JB Straubel, and Ian Wright, but these guys are almost never talked about and they’re nowhere near as rich as Elon Musk. In fact, none of the other founders are currently billionaires, and Elon Musk has daily net worth swings that are worth more than all of their net worth combined. But, how did such a massive discrepancy arise among the founders who presumably all started with a significant stake in Tesla? After all, even a 1% stake in Tesla would be worth several billion dollars today. This video explains why Elon Musk is the only Tesla founder that became stupidly rich and why the other founders all eventually left Tesla. 

Discord Community: 
https://discord.gg/SJUNWNt

Timestamps:
0:00 - Tesla’s Other Founders
1:51 - Money Talks
5:27 - Firing The Founders
8:34 - Agressive CEO Compensation
11:37 - Why Only Elon Is Rich

Thumbnail Credit:
Dimitrios Kambouris - Getty Images
https://abcn.ws/3gZpCyk

Resources: 
https://pastebin.com/2TLxqEYk</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="1118" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="22821"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:5JK-0nlbM7k</id>
  <yt:videoId>5JK-0nlbM7k</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCZRoNJu1OszFqABP8AuJIuw</yt:channelId>
  <title>How Everyday People Have Been Scamming Amazon For Billions</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=5JK-0nlbM7k"/>
  <author>
   <name>Logically Answered</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCZRoNJu1OszFqABP8AuJIuw</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-10-31T19:00:02+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-11-02T19:28:44+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>How Everyday People Have Been Scamming Amazon For Billions</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/5JK-0nlbM7k?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i2.ytimg.com/vi/5JK-0nlbM7k/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>The idea that Amazon has been ripping off its employees has been a popular concept for a long time. Amazon employees are often worked to the bone and paid minimal wages. Not to mention, drivers often have to pee in bottles, and managers squash unions before they even appear. But, have you ever heard of the idea of everyday people scamming Amazon? For years, people have been buying products on Amazon just to claim that they didn’t receive them or return a fake version of the product so that they can get a full refund. While simple, in theory, this is not a small scam by any means. On average, 5 to 15% of Amazon purchases are returned out of which 10% are fraudulent returns. This means that roughly 1% of all purchases on Amazon end up with fraudulent returns. And given that Amazon receives hundreds of billions of dollars worth of sales every year, this scam costs Amazon billions every single year. This video explains the mechanics of the Amazon return scam and how this scam is spreading to other companies and industries as well.

Discord Community: 
https://discord.gg/SJUNWNt

Timestamps:
0:00 - Scamming Amazon
1:54 - Return Scam Explained
4:57 - This Is Messed Up
9:46 - A Spreading Parasite

Thumbnail Credit:
Alex Wong - Getty Images
https://bit.ly/3FuMkIT

Resources:
https://pastebin.com/PgaVq5ug</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="2078" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="36314"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:8_vYHSnv3Js</id>
  <yt:videoId>8_vYHSnv3Js</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCZRoNJu1OszFqABP8AuJIuw</yt:channelId>
  <title>Why 40,000 Cancer Patients Are Suing Johnson &amp; Johnson</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8_vYHSnv3Js"/>
  <author>
   <name>Logically Answered</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCZRoNJu1OszFqABP8AuJIuw</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-10-28T19:00:04+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-11-02T18:43:41+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Why 40,000 Cancer Patients Are Suing Johnson &amp; Johnson</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/8_vYHSnv3Js?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i1.ytimg.com/vi/8_vYHSnv3Js/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>Johnson &amp; Johnson is one of the most recognizable household brands in the world. They sell everything from soap and baby powder to band-aids and medicine. At first glance, the company seems completely harmless in nature, but when you take a closer look, you’ll quickly realize that that’s not exactly true. While the company did have wholesome beginnings as a generous family company, corporate greed has slowly corrupted the company over the decades leading to some of the worst scandals in history. First, we have the baby powder lawsuit. J&amp;J’s baby powder is alleged to have asbestos in them which causes cancer. Furthermore, it is alleged that J&amp;J has known about this since the 1970s and that they decided to just push it under the rug. Another massive scandal that J&amp;J has been caught up in is the opioid epidemic. It turns out that many of the largest pharmaceutical companies have been lobbying and pushing for opioids to be easily accessible to everyday people. This has played a massive role in addiction across the US and has arguably played a role in the deaths of hundreds of thousands of people. This video explains how J&amp;J transitioned from being a kind family business into being a ruthless corporate machine. 

Discord Community: 
https://discord.gg/SJUNWNt

Timestamps:
0:00 - The Monster
2:04 - Wholesome Beginnings
5:36 - Slow Deterioration
9:18 - Becoming The Predator
12:18 - Spread The Word

Thumbnail Credits:
Justin Sullivan - Getty Images
https://bit.ly/3DuyHa3
https://bit.ly/3gJGqsZ 

Resources:
https://pastebin.com/CYU2w3vb</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="7707" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="189965"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:bBhx3jhLNHs</id>
  <yt:videoId>bBhx3jhLNHs</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCZRoNJu1OszFqABP8AuJIuw</yt:channelId>
  <title>Japan Has Been Crashing For 33 Years...It's Not Looking Good...</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=bBhx3jhLNHs"/>
  <author>
   <name>Logically Answered</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCZRoNJu1OszFqABP8AuJIuw</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-10-26T19:00:14+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-10-26T19:00:14+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Japan Has Been Crashing For 33 Years...It's Not Looking Good...</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/bBhx3jhLNHs?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i3.ytimg.com/vi/bBhx3jhLNHs/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>After WW2, Japan was by far the fastest-growing country in the world. They put western countries to shame as they pumped out winner after winner from Toyota and Honda to Sony and Panasonic. But, all of this unprecedented growth abruptly came to an end in 1989 when their stock market peaked. At first, people thought that this was simply a routine bear market that would recover sooner or later. But, the bear market just kept going and going and going. In fact, you could argue that it’s still ongoing given that the Nikkei 225 has yet to put in a new all-time high since 1989. It’s not just the stock market that has gotten crushed either. The real estate market also peaked in 1989 and has yet to recover. When you factor in inflation, this situation just becomes even worse. One of the main reasons for this massive stagnation is that Japan’s assets bubbles simply went so far that it has taken decades for real valuations to catch up. This was simply fueled by the Plaza Accord which loosened economic policies within Japan and tightened policies outside Japan. This video explains why Japan’s economy hasn’t grown in 33 years and whether this is what’s up ahead for the US. 

Discord Community: 
https://discord.gg/SJUNWNt

Timestamps:
0:00 - Japan’s Peak
3:28 - Unprecedented Growth
5:46 - The Plaza Accord
8:01 - Monstrous Valuations
11:06 - The Lost Decades

Resources: 
https://pastebin.com/Rs1Sye7U</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="2019" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="59197"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:2lO_njRbhyA</id>
  <yt:videoId>2lO_njRbhyA</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCZRoNJu1OszFqABP8AuJIuw</yt:channelId>
  <title>How PayPal Became The Scummiest Payment Platform</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2lO_njRbhyA"/>
  <author>
   <name>Logically Answered</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCZRoNJu1OszFqABP8AuJIuw</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-10-24T19:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-10-28T14:36:15+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>How PayPal Became The Scummiest Payment Platform</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/2lO_njRbhyA?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i3.ytimg.com/vi/2lO_njRbhyA/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>PayPal is one of the most useful apps out there. It allows us to easily pay our friends and family, private teachers, third-party sellers, and freelancers. Despite its utility though, PayPal has become one of the most hated payment platforms in the world. It just takes one search on Google or YouTube to understand just how much people despise this company. And when we delve into the root of this distaste, it doesn’t take long to understand where all of this is coming from. First of all, PayPal has become notorious for siding with scammers when there is a disputed transaction. This is because scammers are well aware of PayPal’s dispute criteria and they design their scams to perfectly take advantage of PayPal’s loopholes. And unfortunately, PayPal rarely takes a closer look than just their prescribed criteria which results in PayPal seemingly always siding with scammers. This problem is especially frustrating given how high PayPal’s fees are. And it seems that the root problem for all of this is that PayPal acts like a financial institution, but they’re not subject to many of the rules that are applicable to traditional financial institutions like banks. And this has resulted in subpar consumer protection and service. This video explains the top reasons that people despise PayPal and how PayPal became the scummiest payment platform. 

Discord Community: 
https://discord.gg/SJUNWNt

Timestamps:
0:00 - The Hate For PayPal
2:22 - Siding With Scammers
6:04 - Exorbitant Fees
8:16 - The Financial Institution That’s Not
10:26 - The Future Of PayPal

Resources: 
https://pastebin.com/aVzQXCwa</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="2892" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="76025"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:DVU0sk7kTkg</id>
  <yt:videoId>DVU0sk7kTkg</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCZRoNJu1OszFqABP8AuJIuw</yt:channelId>
  <title>Exactly How Equifax Leaked The SSNs Of 146 Million People</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=DVU0sk7kTkg"/>
  <author>
   <name>Logically Answered</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCZRoNJu1OszFqABP8AuJIuw</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-10-21T19:00:08+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-10-21T20:52:24+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Exactly How Equifax Leaked The SSNs Of 146 Million People</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/DVU0sk7kTkg?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i1.ytimg.com/vi/DVU0sk7kTkg/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>Are you familiar with a company called Equifax? You might’ve come across the company when checking your credit score or applying for a loan. Equifax is one of the three major credit bureaus in the world alongside TransUnion and Experian. Given the nature of their business, it’s not surprising that they deal with sensitive financial data on a regular basis. Considering this, you would expect that Equifax has top-tier security measures in place to prevent this data from being leaked and stolen. However, it doesn’t seem like Equifax did enough because a few years ago, they had one of the largest leaks in history. This leak exposed the date of birth, names, and social security numbers of over 140 million people just in the US. This means that if you were a US adult in 2017 and had some sort of credit file, there’s a higher probability that your data was leaked than your data not being leaked. To make things worse, it seems like Equifax got several indications that its cybersecurity needs to be upgraded. Yet, they didn’t take sufficient action before it was too late. If this was Google or Facebook, people would be up in riots, but since it’s a background company, most people don’t even know about the situation. This video explains the story of how the devastating Equifax data breach transpired and what you may be able to do today to claim damages.  

Discord Community: 
https://discord.gg/SJUNWNt

Timestamps:
0:00 - Leaked SSNS
2:32 - Data Breach
5:21 - Public Backlash
8:42 - The Fallout
11:14 - The Takeaway

Resources: 
https://pastebin.com/1a3aYgdu</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="1129" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="28872"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:l5a9jEtP-vg</id>
  <yt:videoId>l5a9jEtP-vg</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCZRoNJu1OszFqABP8AuJIuw</yt:channelId>
  <title>Even Microsoft Uses Linux, So Why Don't We??</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=l5a9jEtP-vg"/>
  <author>
   <name>Logically Answered</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCZRoNJu1OszFqABP8AuJIuw</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-10-19T19:00:19+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-10-23T13:00:25+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Even Microsoft Uses Linux, So Why Don't We??</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/l5a9jEtP-vg?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i1.ytimg.com/vi/l5a9jEtP-vg/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>I’m sure you’ve all heard of Linux. It’s that one open-source operating system that nerds love talking about. But, Linux isn’t just meant for nerds. In fact, virtually all of the largest tech companies in the world use Linux in one form or other thanks to its superior performance when it comes to back-end development. In fact, even Microsoft has switched over from Windows to Linux for their networks, databases, and cloud infrastructure. But, if Linux is so good, why hasn’t the average person even tried it, especially when it's free? Well, one of the main reasons that Linux never gained that much popularity is because its low cost doesn’t really mean much to the vast majority of customers. The vast majority of people just be prebuilt machines and Windows/macOS comes preinstalled for no extra cost. Also, even if you were building your own PC, Microsoft has made it extremely easy to get an unlicensed version of Windows running permanently. On top of this, Linux is usually not as user-friendly because it doesn’t come preinstalled with much software. Not to mention, you often have to use the command line to accomplish simple tasks. This video explains the top reasons that Linux is not very popular despite its free nature and apparent superiority. 

Discord Community: 
https://discord.gg/SJUNWNt

Timestamps:
0:00 - The State Of Linux
1:45 - Uselessly Free
4:58 - The Command Line
7:58 - Virtually No Need
10:42 - The Truth About Linux

Thumbnail Credit:
Shannon Stapleton - Reuters
https://yhoo.it/3ESFT20

Resources:
https://pastebin.com/sKG8S6mt</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="12888" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="515459"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:c08FwvZk0UM</id>
  <yt:videoId>c08FwvZk0UM</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCZRoNJu1OszFqABP8AuJIuw</yt:channelId>
  <title>Why Microsoft Has Been Hiding From You</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=c08FwvZk0UM"/>
  <author>
   <name>Logically Answered</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCZRoNJu1OszFqABP8AuJIuw</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-10-17T19:00:10+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-10-19T21:49:53+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Why Microsoft Has Been Hiding From You</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/c08FwvZk0UM?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i4.ytimg.com/vi/c08FwvZk0UM/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>Have you noticed that Microsoft is one of the most discrete tech companies in the world? Compared to Facebook, Google, and Apple, interest in Microsoft is virtually non-existent. They’re rarely in the news and even though the average person knows about them, they rarely talk about Micorosft and they don’t really have any strong opinions about Microsoft. At first, this might just seem like a random attribute, but this is actually very much on purpose. You see, Microsoft was very much a public company before the 2000s, and Bill Gates’ reputation was similar to that of Mark Zuckerberg’s today. But, all of this changed when a lawsuit nearly split up Microsoft into two different companies for being a monopoly. Ever since then, Microsoft has been avoiding the spotlight to avoid drawing excessive public criticism, and it seems like it’s working. Almost all of the criticism of big tech goes to Google and Facebook nowadays. This video explains how Microsoft slowly disappeared into the background and diverted attention away from their own monopoly. 

Discord Community: 
https://discord.gg/SJUNWNt

Timestamps:
0:00 - Microsoft’s Profit Margins
2:27 - The Public Monopoly
5:27 - Saving The Monopoly
8:28 - Transition To B2B
11:18 - The New Microsoft

Thumbnail Credits:
John Keatley/Redux/Eyevine
https://bit.ly/3VvGQD9
Lior Patel/Alarmy
https://bit.ly/2NZkzKy

Resources: 
https://pastebin.com/etp9Z1xN</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="5384" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="181486"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:nD2o8bJCDkI</id>
  <yt:videoId>nD2o8bJCDkI</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCZRoNJu1OszFqABP8AuJIuw</yt:channelId>
  <title>Why Does Everyone Suddenly Hate Netflix?</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=nD2o8bJCDkI"/>
  <author>
   <name>Logically Answered</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCZRoNJu1OszFqABP8AuJIuw</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-10-14T19:00:28+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-10-17T19:12:32+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Why Does Everyone Suddenly Hate Netflix?</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/nD2o8bJCDkI?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i3.ytimg.com/vi/nD2o8bJCDkI/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>By now, I’m sure that you’re aware that Netflix stock has been getting crushed. A lot of the selloff can be attributed to the market downturn but not all of it. Fundamental struggles within Netflix have definitely resulted in the stock performing even worse. Usually, the average person is indifferent about such downturns, but with Netflix, it actually seems like the average person is happy. They almost have this attitude of Netflix got what they deserved. The top complaint is usually that Netflix’s content library isn’t that great for how much they're charging. But, it seems like this problem is much more deep-rooted than that. The truth is that there is objectively no streaming service that is better than Netflix. In fact, when surveyed about which platform people would choose if they could only have one, Netflix won by a long shot. So, clearly, content alone is not the problem. Rather the problem seems to be that streaming is no longer the antithesis of cable/satellite television. One of the biggest selling points of Netflix was that it could offer great movies and TVs for a cheaper price with no ads. But, nowadays between all the streaming platforms that you need to get and all the ads you have to watch, it almost feels like we’re back to ground 0. And the service that people blame for this regression is Netflix. This video explains why everyone suddenly hates Netflix and why they’re happy that Netflix is doing badly. 

Discord Community: 
https://discord.gg/SJUNWNt

Timestamps:
0:00 - The State Of Netflix
1:45 - The Case For Netflix
4:57 - What People Really Hate
7:54 - The New Normal
11:01 - The Future Of Netflix

Resources: 
https://pastebin.com/7AkxusAc</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="6450" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="209394"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:fDnHyewnRyU</id>
  <yt:videoId>fDnHyewnRyU</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCZRoNJu1OszFqABP8AuJIuw</yt:channelId>
  <title>Who Will Be The Next CEO Of Apple?</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fDnHyewnRyU"/>
  <author>
   <name>Logically Answered</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCZRoNJu1OszFqABP8AuJIuw</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-10-12T19:00:12+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-10-25T04:47:31+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Who Will Be The Next CEO Of Apple?</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/fDnHyewnRyU?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i3.ytimg.com/vi/fDnHyewnRyU/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>Last year, Tim Cook announced that he probably wouldn’t be at Apple in 10 years' time. While this may have come as a surprise to some, this made sense to most given that he’s already in his 60s and has led Apple for over 10 years now. This isn’t to say that anyone wants him to leave though given Apple’s tremendous performance under his leadership. Since Tim took over, Apple stock has grown over 10X even with the recent selloff. But, it seems like Tim wants to call it a day while things are still going well, and it seems that he just wants to stick around for one more product launch. Naturally, this raises the question of who will be Apple’s next CEO? While the fan favorite is Craig Federighi, there are several other viable choices as well. This list primarily includes Jeff Williams, Eddy Cue, and Greg Joswiak. Given their respective ages though, it’s very possible that Apple decides to go with someone a little young like Craig Federighi or John Ternus. This video discusses the top candidates for the role of Apple’s next CEO and each of their respective pros and cons. 

Discord Community: 
https://discord.gg/SJUNWNt

Timestamps:
0:00 - Tim Cook Retiring
2:16 - Jeff Williams
4:46 - Eddy Cue
7:37 - Greg Joswiak
9:32 - Oddballs
11:53 - Craig Federighi
13:58 - Apple’s Next CEO

Thumbnail Credit:
https://apple.co/3CpCK6K

Resources: 
https://pastebin.com/uAAuHdyw</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="2967" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="99723"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:hIXaUaZc-Vw</id>
  <yt:videoId>hIXaUaZc-Vw</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCZRoNJu1OszFqABP8AuJIuw</yt:channelId>
  <title>Dubai's &quot;Oil Independence&quot; Is A Fairytale</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hIXaUaZc-Vw"/>
  <author>
   <name>Logically Answered</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCZRoNJu1OszFqABP8AuJIuw</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-10-10T19:00:19+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-10-30T08:54:33+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Dubai's &quot;Oil Independence&quot; Is A Fairytale</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/hIXaUaZc-Vw?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i1.ytimg.com/vi/hIXaUaZc-Vw/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>Dubai often likes to portray themselves as someone who has escaped their dependency on oil by cleverly investing in hospitality and tourism. They usually back up this claim by stating that less than 1% of their GDP comes from oil. While this sounds great at first glance, when we take a closer look, we’ll see that this is rather misleading. Even though less than 1% of Dubai’s GDP comes from oil doesn’t mean that oil helps the emirate in other ways. Likely the most obvious way in which oil plays a role in Dubai is through Abu Dhabi. The UAE is actually one of the most oil-rich countries in the world and almost all of that oil is located in Abu Dhabi. So, while Dubai isn’t able to produce their own oil and export it, they do often get loans, investments, and bailouts from Abu Dhabi. A perfect example of this was in 2008 when Abu Dhabhi bailed out Dubai with $10 billion. This bailout was crucial in completing the Burj Khalifa and keeping the emirate afloat. But, Dubai has yet to pay back Abu Dhabi for this bailout. This video explains how Dubai is still dependent on oil revenue through Abu Dhabi and why Dubai’s story of oil independence is nothing more than a fairytale. 

Discord Community: 
https://discord.gg/SJUNWNt

Timestamps:
0:00 - Dubai’s Fairytale
2:10 - Nothing But Poverty
5:14 - Close By No Cigar
8:23 - The Godfather
11:34 - The Ugly Truth

Thumbnail Credit:
Jack Morton
https://bit.ly/3CoijY5

Resources:
https://pastebin.com/AVjsUxnK</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="4191" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="146273"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:qVFyjTfOGgI</id>
  <yt:videoId>qVFyjTfOGgI</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCZRoNJu1OszFqABP8AuJIuw</yt:channelId>
  <title>How Did Chip Profit Margins Become So Obscene?</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=qVFyjTfOGgI"/>
  <author>
   <name>Logically Answered</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCZRoNJu1OszFqABP8AuJIuw</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-10-07T19:00:20+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-10-09T20:32:33+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>How Did Chip Profit Margins Become So Obscene?</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/qVFyjTfOGgI?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i2.ytimg.com/vi/qVFyjTfOGgI/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>By now, I’m sure you’ve heard about the new 4000 series of GPUs from Nvidia. As many of us expected, the 4000 series is not cheap by any means. In fact, it’s actually extremely expensive with the top end 4090 coming in at $1600. But, this raises the question, how much exactly does Nvidia even profit from their GPUs? Well, fortunately for us, Nvidia is a public company meaning that all of their revenue and profit figures and public information. Nvidia’s latest gross margins come in at over 60% and their net margins come in at 26% which is even higher than Apple's. It’s not just Nvidia that has these insane margins though. Virtually all semiconductor companies from AMD and Qualcomm to Intel and Applied Materials have these insane margins. These crazy margins extend to their suppliers as well which mainly include TSMC and ASML. This video explains how the semiconductor industry become so profitable and when semiconductor margins will finally cool down. 

Discord Community: 
https://discord.gg/SJUNWNt

Timestamps:
0:00 - Semiconductor Margins
3:16 - Fundamental Risk
6:30 - Unprecedented Demand
9:57 - The End Is Near

Thumbnail Credit: 
https://bit.ly/3Erd3p1

Resources:
https://pastebin.com/4igEM61A</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="2764" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="77134"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:wFvVlMhSbWA</id>
  <yt:videoId>wFvVlMhSbWA</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCZRoNJu1OszFqABP8AuJIuw</yt:channelId>
  <title>Why Are Pilots Paid So Much?</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wFvVlMhSbWA"/>
  <author>
   <name>Logically Answered</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCZRoNJu1OszFqABP8AuJIuw</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-10-05T19:00:18+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-10-19T08:52:36+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Why Are Pilots Paid So Much?</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/wFvVlMhSbWA?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i4.ytimg.com/vi/wFvVlMhSbWA/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>You might’ve heard that there is currently a pilot shortage, but you’ll never believe how much pilots are actually making. The median salary for an airline pilot itself is $202,000. Meanwhile, the highest-level captains at the legacy carriers are able to make much more thanks to high-paying overtime opportunities. The top captains at Delta are making $526,000 per year. The top captains at Southwest are making $549,000 per year. And the top captains at American Airlines are making over $700,000 per year. On top of this, airlines have some of the most generous 401K plans in the world given that many of them contribute 16% worth of your paycheck to a retirement fund without you even contributing. But, despite these insane perks, the pilot shortage is only getting worse, and it’s expected that the pilot shortage will grow multiple folds within the next decade. This means that pilot salaries will only go up even more and the top pilots will probably be making 7 figures in the imminent future. This video explains why pilots are paid so much and the future of the aviation industry. 

Discord Community: 
https://discord.gg/SJUNWNt

Timestamps: 
0:00 - Pilot Salaries
2:58 - Barrier To Entry
5:50 - Paying Your Dues
9:02 - Pilot Shortage
11:18 - 7 Figure Incomes 

Resources: 
https://pastebin.com/rJCwSWjZ</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="5233" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="294305"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:tOkch_7GrU0</id>
  <yt:videoId>tOkch_7GrU0</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCZRoNJu1OszFqABP8AuJIuw</yt:channelId>
  <title>Why Saudi Arabia Has Destroyed 98% Of Mecca Since 1985</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=tOkch_7GrU0"/>
  <author>
   <name>Logically Answered</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCZRoNJu1OszFqABP8AuJIuw</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-10-03T19:00:17+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-10-04T17:40:41+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Why Saudi Arabia Has Destroyed 98% Of Mecca Since 1985</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/tOkch_7GrU0?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i1.ytimg.com/vi/tOkch_7GrU0/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>Saudi Arabia is not only home to the world’s second-largest oil reserves, but they’re also home to one of the most important religious locations: Mecca. Mecca plays a major role in Islam as it is where Mohammed the Prophet was born. Most Muslims try to pilgrimage to Mecca at least once in their lifetimes through something called the Hajj. Given the importance of this city and the wealth of Saudi Arabia, you would think that Saudi Arabia would try to protect the city as much as possible. Yet, they’ve actually been doing the exact opposite. For centuries, Saudi Arabians, and more specifically the Wahhabis have been constantly taking down relics and destroying various buildings in the city. Their reasoning for this is that they’re trying to prevent people from worshipping relics and monuments, but the truth may have more to do with retaining power and control. This video explains why Saudi Arabia has destroyed 98% of Mecca within just the past few decades alone. 

Discord Community: 
https://discord.gg/SJUNWNt

Timestamps:
0:00 - Mecca’s Destruction
2:12 - Wahhabism
5:18 - Thirst For Power
8:39 - Escalating Resentment
10:47 - State Of Mecca

Thumbnail Credit: 
Prakash Singh
https://bit.ly/3SNd8rc
Barclay Fernandez/Victoria Advocate
https://bit.ly/3Rqxzcd

Resources: 
https://pastebin.com/r2DNJH7R</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="3785" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="136971"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
</feed>
