<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?><?xml-stylesheet href="http://www.blogger.com/styles/atom.css" type="text/css"?><feed xmlns='http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom' xmlns:openSearch='http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/' xmlns:blogger='http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008' xmlns:georss='http://www.georss.org/georss' xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005" xmlns:thr='http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0'><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-6959495683334200101</id><updated>2022-10-30T02:33:46.194-07:00</updated><category term="Connect"/><category term="Create"/><category term="News"/><category term="Learn"/><category term="Promote"/><category term="Product"/><category term="Product Update"/><category term="on the rise"/><category term="Music"/><category term="Revenue"/><category term="youtube"/><category term="youtube creator"/><category term="youtube partner"/><category term="mobile"/><category term="youtube earn money"/><category term="Annotations"/><category term="Bethany Mota"/><category term="Black History Month"/><category term="Cards"/><category term="End Screens"/><category term="Epic Rap Battles of History"/><category term="Next Creator"/><category term="Super Chat"/><category term="YouTube Red"/><category term="YouTube Spaces"/><category term="YouTube Studio"/><category term="YouTube Studio app"/><category term="appeals"/><category term="channels"/><category term="content id"/><category term="copyright"/><category term="cross-promotion"/><category term="dispute"/><category term="education"/><category term="iOS"/><category term="mobile live streaming"/><category term="next chef"/><category term="next trainer"/><category term="next up"/><category term="next vlogger"/><category term="space"/><category term="templates"/><category term="tokyo"/><category term="youtube ads"/><title type='text'>YouTube Creator Blog</title><subtitle type='html'></subtitle><link rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#feed' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://youtube-creators.googleblog.com/feeds/posts/default'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://www.blogger.com/feeds/6959495683334200101/posts/default?redirect=false'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://youtube-creators.googleblog.com/'/><link rel='hub' href='http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/'/><link rel='next' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://www.blogger.com/feeds/6959495683334200101/posts/default?start-index=26&amp;max-results=25&amp;redirect=false'/><author><name>YouTube Creators</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/00450486760991148551</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><generator version='7.00' uri='http://www.blogger.com'>Blogger</generator><openSearch:totalResults>433</openSearch:totalResults><openSearch:startIndex>1</openSearch:startIndex><openSearch:itemsPerPage>25</openSearch:itemsPerPage><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-6959495683334200101.post-2640342815530127430</id><published>2020-05-07T10:00:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2020-05-07T10:00:09.424-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Three steps to keep your YouTube account secure</title><content type='html'>In the spirit of World Password Day, we encourage all creators to bolster the security of their Google accounts. Unfortunately, over the past several months we&#39;ve seen a rise in the hijacking of YouTube channels. We take account security seriously and, in addition to continuously improving our monitoring and systems, want to help creators keep their accounts safe by encouraging them to take these three steps:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;h3&gt;1.  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.blog.google/technology/safety-security/five-things-you-can-do-right-now-to-stay-safer-online/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Create a strong password&lt;/a&gt; and never share it or reuse it on other sites. &lt;/h3&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;A secure password and &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.google.com/accounts/answer/7299973?hl=en&amp;amp;ref_topic=3382255&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;updated recovery information&lt;/a&gt;, like adding your phone number to your Google Account, can help protect it. Also, never enter your password information on any page other than account.google.com since that’s one way passwords are stolen. If you work with a team, do not share your password with them, either. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;h3&gt;2. Enable &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/landing/2step/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;2-Step Verification&lt;/a&gt; on your Google account for extra protection in addition to monitoring who has access to your account. &lt;/h3&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;It&#39;s easier than you think for someone to steal your password, through phishing, malware, data breaches and more. Adding 2-Step Verification means that you’ll protect your account with both your password and additional information — like a prompt on your phone, or a physical device like a security key — to confirm it&#39;s really you.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;For your account to be as secure as possible, you should make sure all Google accounts with access to your channel have 2-Step Verification enabled. This includes everyone listed under the &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.google.com/youtube/answer/6351520?hl=en&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;channel permissions&lt;/a&gt; section in your settings. Also consider using the &lt;a href=&quot;https://landing.google.com/advancedprotection/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Advanced Protection Program&lt;/a&gt; for an extra level of security.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;h3&gt;3. Stay vigilant of phishing and malware scams. &lt;/h3&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Knowing what to look for means you can get ahead of potential scams. Look out for any emails that ask for your account login information — legitimate emails from YouTube about your account will never ask for your login information. If you suspect an email may be a phishing or malware scam, don’t click on any links before verifying they are correct by hovering over them. Ensure the email address and sender names match, and look out for any downloads or attachments — especially ones that are very large or run a program on your computer. These can be malware that when downloaded may cause extensive damage to data and computers or may be used to gain unauthorized access to your network.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;On World Password Day and every day, we want to help you ensure your accounts are secure. Follow these three simple tips and go to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://myaccount.google.com/security-checkup?pli=1&amp;amp;otzr=1&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Google Security checkup&lt;/a&gt; to review and adjust your security settings to help you keep your account secure. </content><link rel='replies' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://youtube-creators.googleblog.com/feeds/2640342815530127430/comments/default' title='Post Comments'/><link rel='replies' type='text/html' href='http://youtube-creators.googleblog.com/2020/05/three-steps-youtube-account-secure.html#comment-form' title='0 Comments'/><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://www.blogger.com/feeds/6959495683334200101/posts/default/2640342815530127430'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://www.blogger.com/feeds/6959495683334200101/posts/default/2640342815530127430'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://youtube-creators.googleblog.com/2020/05/three-steps-youtube-account-secure.html' title='Three steps to keep your YouTube account secure'/><author><name>YouTube Creators</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/00450486760991148551</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><thr:total>0</thr:total></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-6959495683334200101.post-4888878190066699871</id><published>2020-03-16T10:00:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2020-03-16T10:00:03.264-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Protecting our extended workforce and the community</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;Today, as the unprecedented COVID-19 situation continues, Google &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.google/inside-google/company-announcements/update-extended-workforce-covid-19&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;outlined&lt;/a&gt; how it’s reducing the need for people to come into its offices while ensuring that its products continue to operate for everyone.  We are committed to keeping the YouTube community informed about our actions related to COVID-19 in a dedicated location in our &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.google.com/youtube/answer/9777243?p=covid19_updates&amp;amp;visit_id=637194868739116880-4122912225&amp;amp;rd=1&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;help center&lt;/a&gt;. Here is our &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtube-creators.googleblog.com/2020/03/coronavirus-update-on-creator-support.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;update&lt;/a&gt; from last week; below is some more information about the reduction of in-office staffing as it relates to YouTube:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We have teams at YouTube, as well as partner companies, that help us support and protect the YouTube community—from people who respond to user and creator questions, to reviewers who evaluate videos for possible policy violations. These teams and companies are staffed by thousands of people dedicated to helping users and creators. As the coronavirus response evolves, we are taking the steps needed to prioritize the well-being of our employees, our extended workforce, and the communities where they live, including reducing in-office&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Arial; font-size: 11pt; white-space: pre-wrap;&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;staffing in certain sites.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Our Community Guidelines enforcement today is based on a combination of people and technology: Machine learning helps detect potentially harmful content and then sends it to human reviewers for assessment. As a result of the new measures we’re taking, we will temporarily start relying more on technology to help with some of the work normally done by reviewers. This means automated systems will start removing some content without human review, so we can continue to act quickly to remove violative content and protect our ecosystem, while we have workplace protections in place. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;As we do this, users and creators may see increased video removals, including some videos that may not violate policies. We won’t issue strikes on this content except in cases where we have high confidence that it’s violative. If creators think that their content was removed in error, they can &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.google.com/youtube/answer/185111?hl=en&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;appeal the decision&lt;/a&gt; and our teams will take a look. However, note that our workforce precautions will also result in delayed appeal reviews. We’ll also be more cautious about what content gets promoted, including livestreams. In some cases, unreviewed content may not be available via search, on the homepage, or in recommendations. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;All eligible creators will still be able to monetize videos and this does not change the updates on monetization of coronavirus-related videos we &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtube-creators.googleblog.com/2020/03/coronavirus-update-on-creator-support.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;shared&lt;/a&gt; last week. And we’ll continue to enforce our policies regarding coronavirus content, including removing videos that discourage people from seeking medical treatment or claim harmful substances have health benefits. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The situation with coronavirus continues to change day by day, and we’ll continue to take the steps needed to protect our teams and the communities where they live. This may affect additional types of YouTube user and creator support and reviews, such as applications for the YouTube partner program or responses on social media. To stay up-to-date on any changes in our services—and our broader response to the coronavirus—continue to check the &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.google.com/youtube/answer/9777243?p=covid19_updates&amp;amp;visit_id=637194868739116880-4122912225&amp;amp;rd=1&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;help center&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We recognize this may be a disruption for users and creators, but know this is the right thing to do for the people who work to keep YouTube safe and for the broader community. We appreciate everyone’s patience as we take these steps during this challenging time.&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='replies' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://youtube-creators.googleblog.com/feeds/4888878190066699871/comments/default' title='Post Comments'/><link rel='replies' type='text/html' href='http://youtube-creators.googleblog.com/2020/03/protecting-our-extended-workforce-and.html#comment-form' title='0 Comments'/><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://www.blogger.com/feeds/6959495683334200101/posts/default/4888878190066699871'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://www.blogger.com/feeds/6959495683334200101/posts/default/4888878190066699871'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://youtube-creators.googleblog.com/2020/03/protecting-our-extended-workforce-and.html' title='Protecting our extended workforce and the community'/><author><name>YouTube Creators</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/00450486760991148551</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><thr:total>0</thr:total></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-6959495683334200101.post-6327838904048105258</id><published>2020-03-11T09:00:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2020-03-11T09:00:05.170-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Coronavirus: An update on creator support and resources </title><content type='html'>Dear Creators and Artists,&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Over the past several weeks, as we’ve all seen the growing crisis around the coronavirus, we at YouTube have been thinking about how these developments might affect you. We often say that you’re the heart of YouTube, and during this difficult time we wanted to share how &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.blog.google/inside-google/company-announcements/coronavirus-covid19-response/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;we’re working to help&lt;/a&gt; and support you.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Keeping our community informed&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;There’s a lot of uncertainty right now, and we understand the importance of helping people find authoritative sources of news and information. We&#39;re using our homepage to direct users to the World Health Organization (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.who.int/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;WHO&lt;/a&gt;), the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cdc.gov/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;CDC&lt;/a&gt;), and other local authoritative organizations around the world to ensure users can easily find updates. We&#39;re also donating advertising inventory to governments and NGOs in impacted regions, who are using it to spotlight timely, helpful information.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;It remains our top priority to provide information to users in a responsible way. From the very beginning of this outbreak, we’ve worked to prevent misinformation associated with the spread of the virus. We’re also &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtube.googleblog.com/2019/12/the-four-rs-of-responsibility-raise-and-reduce.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;raising up&lt;/a&gt; authoritative sources in search and recommendations and showing &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.google.com/youtube/answer/9004474?hl=en&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;information panels&lt;/a&gt; on relevant videos. YouTube will continue to quickly remove videos that violate our &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.google.com/youtube/answer/2801964&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;policies &lt;/a&gt;when they are flagged, including those that discourage people from seeking medical treatment or claim harmful substances have health benefits. Finding trustworthy content is especially critical as news is breaking, and we’ll continue to make sure YouTube delivers accurate information for our users.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-ep3SFNH_B_A/Xmg98Mq9X0I/AAAAAAAACeA/of4XfP5cp24hjLALUuD_1Q4ljPRYOdeGQCLcBGAsYHQ/s1600/20200306_cv_proudct_youtube_mobile_grey.gif&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;1000&quot; data-original-width=&quot;1000&quot; src=&quot;https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-ep3SFNH_B_A/Xmg98Mq9X0I/AAAAAAAACeA/of4XfP5cp24hjLALUuD_1Q4ljPRYOdeGQCLcBGAsYHQ/s1600/20200306_cv_proudct_youtube_mobile_grey.gif&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Partnering to help others&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The situation is evolving every day, and we&#39;re committed to providing you updates along the way, including any changes that may impact our processes and support systems. Check in &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.google.com/youtube/answer/9777243?p=covid19_updates&amp;amp;visit_id=637194868739116880-4122912225&amp;amp;rd=1&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; to find the latest resources from YouTube.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;People around the world come to YouTube for information, but they’re also looking for something more: to find relief and connect as a community. Creators and artists bring us together, offering entertainment and solace through conversations that help us feel less alone. We’re working to help make those connections possible by meeting the increased demand for &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.google.com/youtube/topic/9257891&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;live streaming&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;as &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.stanford.edu/2020/03/05/events-postponed-canceled-stanford-responds-coronavirus-outbreak/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;university events&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://cloud.withgoogle.com/next/sf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;conferences&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=f5FC_a8yN3k&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;religious services&lt;/a&gt; move their gatherings online.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Supporting creators: updates to monetization for coronavirus-related content&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;YouTube’s policies are designed to support your work on the platform, to protect users, and to give advertisers confidence about where their ads run. We know many of you have had questions about our &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.google.com/youtube/answer/6162278#Controversial_sensitive&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;sensitive events&lt;/a&gt; policy, which currently does not allow monetization if a video includes more than a passing mention of the coronavirus. Our sensitive events policy was designed to apply to short-term events of significant magnitude, like a natural disaster. It’s becoming clear this issue is now an ongoing and important part of everyday conversation, and we want to make sure news organizations and creators can continue producing quality videos in a sustainable way. In the days ahead, we will enable ads for content discussing the coronavirus on a limited number of channels, including creators who accurately &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=bK2xupRNgaU&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;self-certify&lt;/a&gt; and a range of news partners. We’re preparing our policies and enforcement processes to expand monetization to more creators and news organizations in the coming weeks. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;h3&gt;The power of community&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;YouTube creators have shown time and again the difference it makes when we come together. We appreciate everything you do to create positive communities that allow people to turn to each other in times of need. Let’s continue to support each other as we navigate these challenging times.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;i&gt;Susan Wojcicki&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;</content><link rel='replies' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://youtube-creators.googleblog.com/feeds/6327838904048105258/comments/default' title='Post Comments'/><link rel='replies' type='text/html' href='http://youtube-creators.googleblog.com/2020/03/coronavirus-update-on-creator-support.html#comment-form' title='0 Comments'/><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://www.blogger.com/feeds/6959495683334200101/posts/default/6327838904048105258'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://www.blogger.com/feeds/6959495683334200101/posts/default/6327838904048105258'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://youtube-creators.googleblog.com/2020/03/coronavirus-update-on-creator-support.html' title='Coronavirus: An update on creator support and resources '/><author><name>YouTube Creators</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/00450486760991148551</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-ep3SFNH_B_A/Xmg98Mq9X0I/AAAAAAAACeA/of4XfP5cp24hjLALUuD_1Q4ljPRYOdeGQCLcBGAsYHQ/s72-c/20200306_cv_proudct_youtube_mobile_grey.gif" height="72" width="72"/><thr:total>0</thr:total></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-6959495683334200101.post-3694323826192690902</id><published>2020-02-12T09:30:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2020-02-12T09:30:07.315-08:00</updated><title type='text'>How black creators are redefining blackness for themselves on YouTube</title><content type='html'>When the Internet arrived, it brought to the world a buzzy connectivity. People could meet, talk and become friends online. Now, with the majority of young black people spending time in places like YouTube, videos have helped create a digital diaspora. It’s this diaspora that helps us — a people dispersed around the globe — feel like we’re not alone.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Here, in this digital space, no one needs to seek another person’s approval for who they are, or what they’re interested in. This has allowed a generation of creators to redefine blackness for themselves. In honor of Black History Month, we’re spotlighting a handful of creators who’ve done just that:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=QhBnZ6NPOY0&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;King Vader&lt;/a&gt; is a popular black creator known for reinterpreting anime. He uses black actors in a setting that’s more familiar to him and his viewers, such as his neighborhood. His “hood” anime videos (Hood Naruto, Hood Cowboy Bebop) have almost 50 million views. By inserting black actors and cultural indicators into this anime landscape, King Vader creates a black-shared experience within the broader-shared experience of the anime fandom. He’s part of the movement that helped views of videos related to anime more than double in 2019.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Breakout star, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=UG8QnjT57UY&amp;amp;t=8s&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Jennelle Eliana&lt;/a&gt;, burst onto the YouTube scene last July with her first video from her blue van. Within weeks, she gained over 1.5 million subscribers and became 2019’s sixth, most-subscribed new creator. She’s part of the “van life” trend — a community created by people who have traded in a conventional way of life for life on the road.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Late last year, two black guys — separated by the Atlantic Ocean — broke all conventions of the type of music a black person is expected to make. Their break-out song, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=w2Ov5jzm3j8&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;“Old Town Road,”&lt;/a&gt; went on to become one of the top music videos in the world. (It was #1 in the U.S.) Music is another area where black creators continue to innovate.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Black creators&#39; interests and experiences put them at the forefront of every trend. The result is a kaleidoscope of blackness, defined by them and for them. They’re telling the world who they are and what they can be. Through their YouTube wins, they helped make 2019 an especially trend-setting and unforgettable one. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;i&gt;Earnest Pettie, Trends Insights Lead&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/i&gt;</content><link rel='replies' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://youtube-creators.googleblog.com/feeds/3694323826192690902/comments/default' title='Post Comments'/><link rel='replies' type='text/html' href='http://youtube-creators.googleblog.com/2020/02/how-black-creators-are-redefining.html#comment-form' title='0 Comments'/><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://www.blogger.com/feeds/6959495683334200101/posts/default/3694323826192690902'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://www.blogger.com/feeds/6959495683334200101/posts/default/3694323826192690902'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://youtube-creators.googleblog.com/2020/02/how-black-creators-are-redefining.html' title='How black creators are redefining blackness for themselves on YouTube'/><author><name>YouTube Creators</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/00450486760991148551</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><thr:total>0</thr:total></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-6959495683334200101.post-6175111240544375906</id><published>2019-12-09T12:40:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2019-12-09T14:36:31.313-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Our comment on COPPA</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;Responsibility is our number one priority at YouTube, and this includes protecting kids and their privacy. Over the last few years, we’ve significantly invested in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtube.googleblog.com/2019/06/an-update-on-our-efforts-to-protect.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;policies&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtube.googleblog.com/2018/04/introducing-new-choices-for-parents-to.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;products&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtube.googleblog.com/2017/11/5-ways-were-toughening-our-approach-to.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;practices&lt;/a&gt; to help us do this, including launching &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/kids/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;YouTube Kids&lt;/a&gt; in 2015. In July 2019, the Federal Trade Commission (FTC) &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ftc.gov/news-events/press-releases/2019/07/ftc-seeks-comments-childrens-online-privacy-protection-act-rule&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;began accepting comments&lt;/a&gt; on the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA). Many creators have already participated in this process and today, we submitted our comment to the FTC as well.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;h3 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;Support access to high-quality kids content&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;br /&gt;YouTube is built on the premise of openness. Based on this open platform, millions of creators around the world have been able to make their content globally accessible, for free, to audiences of diverse backgrounds. On YouTube, creators are bringing visibility and opportunity to kids and families with special needs, using crafts to explore the world, offering fun ways to get kids moving, and more.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Many creators have expressed concern about the complexity of COPPA, their ability to comply with it, and its effect on the viability of their businesses. Questions range from what content is directed at children, to how to treat adults who might be watching kids content. This is particularly difficult for smaller creators who might not have access to legal resources. Balanced and clear guidelines will help creators better comply with COPPA and live up to their legal obligations, while enabling them to continue producing high-quality kids content that is accessible to everyone, everywhere.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;h3 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;Treat adults as adults&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Currently, the FTC’s guidance requires platforms must treat anyone watching primarily child-directed content as children under 13. This does not match what we see on YouTube, where adults watch favorite cartoons from their childhood or teachers look for content to share with their students. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Creators of such videos have also conveyed the value of product features that wouldn’t be supported on their content. For example, creators have expressed the value of using comments to get helpful feedback from older viewers. This is why we support allowing platforms to treat adults as adults if there are measures in place to help confirm that the user is an adult viewing kids content.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;h3 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;Provide clarity on what is made for kids&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The question creators ask us the most is, “What is made for kids content?” Sometimes, content that isn’t intentionally targeting kids can involve a traditional kids activity, such as DIY, gaming and art videos. Are these videos “made for kids,” even if they don’t intend to target kids? This lack of clarity creates uncertainty for creators.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The FTC shared &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ftc.gov/news-events/blogs/business-blog/2019/11/youtube-channel-owners-your-content-directed-children&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;some guidance&lt;/a&gt; in November — and while this is a positive step in the right direction, we believe there needs to be more clarity about when content should be considered primarily child-directed, mixed audience or general audience. When providing these distinctions, it’s important to not only consider the actual content of the video, but also its context.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;h3 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;Work with the FTC&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We strongly support COPPA’s goal of providing robust protections for kids and their privacy. We also believe COPPA would benefit from updates and clarifications that better reflect how kids and families use technology today, while still allowing access to a wide range of content that helps them learn, grow and explore. We continue to engage on this issue with the FTC and other lawmakers (we previously participated in the FTC’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ftc.gov/news-events/audio-video/video/future-coppa-rule-ftc-workshop-session-2&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;public workshop&lt;/a&gt;) and are committed to continue doing so.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The comment period closes Wednesday, December 11. If you’re interested in providing feedback of your own, you can do so on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ftc.gov/news-events/press-releases/2019/12/ftc-extends-deadline-comments-coppa-rule-until-december-11&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;FTC’s website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='replies' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://youtube-creators.googleblog.com/feeds/6175111240544375906/comments/default' title='Post Comments'/><link rel='replies' type='text/html' href='http://youtube-creators.googleblog.com/2019/12/our-comment-on-coppa.html#comment-form' title='0 Comments'/><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://www.blogger.com/feeds/6959495683334200101/posts/default/6175111240544375906'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://www.blogger.com/feeds/6959495683334200101/posts/default/6175111240544375906'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://youtube-creators.googleblog.com/2019/12/our-comment-on-coppa.html' title='Our comment on COPPA'/><author><name>YouTube Creators</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/00450486760991148551</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><thr:total>0</thr:total></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-6959495683334200101.post-8159552338760833863</id><published>2019-12-03T09:00:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2019-12-03T09:00:05.464-08:00</updated><title type='text'>‘Tis the Season of Giving on YouTube!</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;Today we kick off the final sprint in YouTube’s Season of Giving! Over the past few weeks, creators from all over the country&amp;nbsp;&lt;span style=&quot;background-color: white; color: #545454; font-family: &amp;quot;roboto&amp;quot; , &amp;quot;arial&amp;quot; , sans-serif; font-size: 14px;&quot;&gt;–&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;and the world&amp;nbsp;&lt;span style=&quot;background-color: white; color: #545454; font-family: &amp;quot;roboto&amp;quot; , &amp;quot;arial&amp;quot; , sans-serif; font-size: 14px;&quot;&gt;–&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;have rallied their fans to raise money and awareness for causes near and dear to their hearts.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;This week the creator frenzy-of-goodness goes into overdrive with livestreams, collabs and special events focused on bringing the YouTube community together, all in the name of generosity.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Read on for all the details!&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;table align=&quot;center&quot; cellpadding=&quot;0&quot; cellspacing=&quot;0&quot; class=&quot;tr-caption-container&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-0GIYJZ-tZR8/XeWmcHwpuhI/AAAAAAAACaE/VlLrfVElaiUwibfjEblQn0sC7q5BlyVzwCLcBGAsYHQ/s1600/191008_PlayLive_042.jpg&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;1067&quot; data-original-width=&quot;1600&quot; src=&quot;https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-0GIYJZ-tZR8/XeWmcHwpuhI/AAAAAAAACaE/VlLrfVElaiUwibfjEblQn0sC7q5BlyVzwCLcBGAsYHQ/s1600/191008_PlayLive_042.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;tr-caption&quot; style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;docs-internal-guid-318b35f1-7fff-38a2-6ada-de5285e72af9&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.38; margin-bottom: 0pt; margin-top: 0pt;&quot;&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;docs-internal-guid-318b35f1-7fff-38a2-6ada-de5285e72af9&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: &amp;quot;arial&amp;quot;; font-size: 10pt; font-style: italic; vertical-align: baseline; white-space: pre-wrap;&quot;&gt;Stephanie and MatPat of The Game Theorists at St. Jude in Memphis.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;h3 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The Game Theorists take over Giving Tuesday for St. Jude&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Warning: You aren&#39;t going to get anything done this Tuesday, because you’re going to be watching The Game Theorists’ all-day livestream in support of St. Jude Children’s Research Hospital!&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;MatPat and Stephanie Patrick are bringing together some of your favorite creators for a 9-hour livestream like no other. You know amazing things are going to happen when &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/user/bgfilms&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Binging with Babish&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/user/ThatOneVideoGamer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;The Completionist&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/user/dawkosgames&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Dawko&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/user/lilpumpkinpie05&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Jackie Aina&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCvG04Y09q0HExnIjdgaqcDQ&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Because Science&lt;/a&gt; (Kyle Hill), &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/user/markiplierGAME&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Markiplier&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/user/mirandasings08&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Miranda Sings&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/user/NateWantsToBattle&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;NateWantstoBattle&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCo8bcnLyZH8tBIH9V1mLgqQ&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;TheOdd1sOut&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/user/RhettandLink&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Rhett and Link&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/user/RosannaPansino&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Rosanna Pansino&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/user/trolldawgz&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;SomethingElseYT&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCpi8TJfiA4lKGkaXs__YdBA&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;The Try Guys&lt;/a&gt;, and&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/user/Vsauce3&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;VSauce3&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;band together. This mighty crew of creators is dedicated to helping St. Jude defeat childhood cancer and other life-threatening childhood diseases. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;And just to up the ante, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/user/animdude/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Scott Cawthon&lt;/a&gt;, creator of the insanely popular game, Five Nights at Freddy’s, has committed that he’ll personally donate $500,000 to St. Jude if fans can find easter eggs in an unreleased, made-just-for-the-event game, launching on Tuesday, within one hour of the game going live. Join MatPat, Markiplier and Dawko as they work together to unlock money for St. Jude and #CancelCancer.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The livestream kicks off at 10 a.m. PT. You aren’t going to want to miss a moment!&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/KEA8wis3FIs&quot; width=&quot;560&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;h3 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;Have you bought your tree yet?&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/user/MrBeast6000&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;MrBeast&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/user/onemeeeliondollars&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Mark Rober,&lt;/a&gt; the creators and masterminds behind &lt;a href=&quot;https://teamtrees.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;#TeamTrees,&lt;/a&gt; joined forces with the goal of raising $20 million to plant 20 million trees by January 1, 2020. The juggernaut campaign is rolling into its final weeks, with only 4 million trees to go!&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;From all over the world, people have rallied behind the simplicity of the campaign: $1 raised plants 1 tree. Donations flooded in from the start. Within the first 48 hours of launch, #TeamTrees raised &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/teamtreesofficl/status/1188533388287733760&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;$5 million&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp;And within the first week, people uploaded over 3,800 videos with the #TeamTrees tag on YouTube.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;#TeamTrees has proven that the sum of many small actions of kindness can make a huge, positive impact on the world. And there is still time to buy a tree, join the movement and become part of this historic fundraiser!&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;h3 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;Creators choose, everyone wins!&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;br /&gt;This week YouTube will be filled with opportunities to learn more about causes and share donations. Check out the many fundraisers: from the 13th annual Project for Awesome from Hank and John Green (aka &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/user/vlogbrothers&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;vlogbrothers&lt;/a&gt;)&amp;nbsp;to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/user/khanacademy&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Khan Academy&lt;/a&gt;’s All in for Education livestream to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/user/eldad75&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Hope For Paws&lt;/a&gt; rescuing animals and much more.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We’ve created a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=DwN9Tow6z0Q&amp;amp;list=PLbpi6ZahtOH5Vh6VMF4MRPVgtqsMMBhG0&amp;amp;index=2&amp;amp;t=0s&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;playlist&lt;/a&gt; to help you find some of the top fundraisers planned for Giving Week. Come for the great videos, stay for the great causes!&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The spirit of generosity and support is one of the things that makes our community so special. On behalf of everyone at YouTube, thank you to all of the creators, fans and friends who are using their voices to make the world a better place.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;i&gt;— The YouTube Team&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='replies' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://youtube-creators.googleblog.com/feeds/8159552338760833863/comments/default' title='Post Comments'/><link rel='replies' type='text/html' href='http://youtube-creators.googleblog.com/2019/12/tis-season-of-giving-on-youtube.html#comment-form' title='0 Comments'/><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://www.blogger.com/feeds/6959495683334200101/posts/default/8159552338760833863'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://www.blogger.com/feeds/6959495683334200101/posts/default/8159552338760833863'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://youtube-creators.googleblog.com/2019/12/tis-season-of-giving-on-youtube.html' title='‘Tis the Season of Giving on YouTube!'/><author><name>YouTube Creators</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/00450486760991148551</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-0GIYJZ-tZR8/XeWmcHwpuhI/AAAAAAAACaE/VlLrfVElaiUwibfjEblQn0sC7q5BlyVzwCLcBGAsYHQ/s72-c/191008_PlayLive_042.jpg" height="72" width="72"/><thr:total>0</thr:total></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-6959495683334200101.post-6116414416992361779</id><published>2019-11-21T09:00:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2019-12-05T10:50:19.795-08:00</updated><title type='text'>My final letter in 2019: Updates for this year</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;&lt;table cellpadding=&quot;0&quot; cellspacing=&quot;0&quot; class=&quot;tr-caption-container&quot; style=&quot;float: right; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-mAvp965d8h0/XdXIySUcHcI/AAAAAAAACZA/0UD6cFrfOPEXl_Rwfg6l3dYz4B89zdYHQCLcBGAsYHQ/s1600/YT_1.png&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;844&quot; data-original-width=&quot;1500&quot; src=&quot;https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-mAvp965d8h0/XdXIySUcHcI/AAAAAAAACZA/0UD6cFrfOPEXl_Rwfg6l3dYz4B89zdYHQCLcBGAsYHQ/s1600/YT_1.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;tr-caption&quot; style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;Illustrations by Christopher DeLorenzo&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Dear creators and artists,&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Every quarter, I give you an update on the highlights of the past few months. In August, I did something different and &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtube-creators.googleblog.com/2019/08/preserving-openness-through-responsibility.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;wrote to you&lt;/a&gt; about our top priority: the importance of striking the right balance between openness and responsibility. I did this because I received a number of questions about the viability of an open platform, and I wanted to emphasize our commitment to both openness and responsibly protecting our community.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Today I’m returning to our usual format because there are so many new updates to share on our three key priorities: supporting creator and artist success, improving communication and engagement, and living up to our responsibility. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/GSOyIdxNjF4&quot; width=&quot;560&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;But before I jump into these sections, I want to let all of you know that YouTube as a platform for creators continues to thrive. Compared to last year, the number of creators with a million or more subscribers has grown 65 percent, and creators earning five or six figures, annually, has increased more than 40 percent. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We always say that creators are the heart of YouTube. So, with that, let me move to our next section… supporting your success!&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;h3 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;Supporting creator and artist success&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;One of the biggest issues we heard about from you this year was around copyright claims, in particular about aggressive manual claiming of short music clips used in monetized videos. Those claims often resulted in all revenue going to the rightsholder, regardless of the length of the music claimed. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I’m glad to report we&#39;ve made progress. A few months ago, we made changes that removed the financial incentive to claim very short and unintentional music use. We also required timestamps for all manual claims so you know exactly which part of your video is being claimed, and made updates to our editing tools so you can &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=EmkiEWIlqtI&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;easily remove&lt;/a&gt; manually claimed content from your videos.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;In the months ahead, we’re working to move all creators to the new-and-improved YouTube Studio. We’re making this switch because Classic Studio was built on older technology that doesn’t allow us to put out bug fixes or introduce the new features you’ve requested as quickly as we’d like. Many of YouTube Studio’s updates are inspired by requests from creators, and we think you’ll like its exclusive features, including the new dashboard, powerful analytics, and real-time performance metrics. Access to Classic will be removed for the majority of creators early next year, and you’ll be individually notified in advance of a change to your access. We know it can be hard to change the tools you work with every day, but we believe this new foundation will help us innovate more quickly on your behalf.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-_g0lgB1CR0Y/XdXIiWsM1sI/AAAAAAAACY4/zlZAumom2RQ69JLPTSb7U4xMLQRC92wtwCLcBGAsYHQ/s1600/YT_6b.png&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;876&quot; data-original-width=&quot;1600&quot; src=&quot;https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-_g0lgB1CR0Y/XdXIiWsM1sI/AAAAAAAACY4/zlZAumom2RQ69JLPTSb7U4xMLQRC92wtwCLcBGAsYHQ/s1600/YT_6b.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We’re also looking to support your success by helping you monetize in new ways that go beyond traditional ad revenue and tap into the viewer-creator connection. Today, thousands of channels have more than doubled their YouTube revenue by using &lt;a href=&quot;https://creatoracademy.youtube.com/page/course/monetization-options?hl=en&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;new features&lt;/a&gt; that help fans engage with creators, like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=bnx7kckso88&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Super Chat&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=RXQO_lQz-T0&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Channel Memberships&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=HSVEySFKWTY&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Merchandise&lt;/a&gt;. More than 100,000 channels have received Super Chat, and some streams are earning more than $400 per minute as fans reach out to creators to say hello, send congratulations, or just to connect. And we’re building on the success of Super Chat by expanding the launch of Super Stickers to eligible creators in 60 countries around the world.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;And since we expanded YouTube Stories last year, more creators are using &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=H3sIHuMMZec&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Stories&lt;/a&gt; not just to connect with existing subscribers, but also to find new ones. Over the last year, creators who used an active Story on their channel saw an average increase to their subscriber count of more than eight percent compared to creators without Stories.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We’re also running experiments to help match content that could be considered edgy with advertising that fits their brand. As you know, yellow icons are a signal that only limited advertising can run on a particular video because of its content. We’re working to identify advertisers who are interested in edgier content, like a marketer looking to promote an R-rated movie, so we can match them with creators whose content fits their ads. In its first month, this program resulted in hundreds of thousands of dollars in ads on yellow icon videos. You can learn more &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=bsHoSp85d8c&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-JkHIVVTaPpE/XdXVtATTodI/AAAAAAAACZw/RhwcWbZt_L0L0JvvsJKf4e1iYHxj_EA7wCLcBGAsYHQ/s1600/YT_7.png&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;1329&quot; data-original-width=&quot;1600&quot; src=&quot;https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-JkHIVVTaPpE/XdXVtATTodI/AAAAAAAACZw/RhwcWbZt_L0L0JvvsJKf4e1iYHxj_EA7wCLcBGAsYHQ/s1600/YT_7.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;For gaming creators, we’ve heard loud and clear that our policies need to differentiate between real-world violence and gaming violence. We have a policy update coming soon that will do just that. The new policy will have fewer restrictions for violence in gaming, but maintain our high bar to protect audiences from real-world violence.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;h3 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;Improving communication and engagement&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Meeting creators is always a highlight for me, and this year I’ve met with YouTubers around the globe. A few months ago in London, I sat down with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=gMINAiDWI6g&amp;amp;t=1838s&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Alfie Deyes&lt;/a&gt;, and celebrated the 10 year anniversary of his first YouTube video. I recently spoke with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCpuSRwCaWi-VqTlYviNW3hQ&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Juanpa Zurita&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0RuYEzD4_wQ&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Emma Chamberlain&lt;/a&gt; about their creative process, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=EBhoWwL1Rzs&amp;amp;t=&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;took some tough questions&lt;/a&gt; from MatPat of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCo_IB5145EVNcf8hw1Kku7w&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;The Game Theorists&lt;/a&gt; at YouTube’s first-ever Gaming Creator Summit. I also met with a group of creators in Europe this summer, including &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC0KiGuCTrehqzSQ7ikjxSQw&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Patricia Bright&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC-lHJZR3Gqxm24_Vd_AJ5Yw&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PewDiePie&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCYzPXprvl5Y-Sf0g4vX-m6g&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Jacksepticeye&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCPNqPbXJHMvrH3NwRKKR5IQ&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Sallys Welt&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCT3v6vL2H5HK4loLMc8pmCw&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;VisualPolitik&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCM2vdqz-7e4HAuzhpFuRY8w&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Mrbruff&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCDdi0yUyGW1PKzYXaIACnuA&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Jessica Kellgren-Fozard&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;To help creators have a better understanding of our guidelines, we will expand our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=bK2xupRNgaU&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Self Certification pilot &lt;/a&gt;next year to hundreds of thousands of YouTube Partner Program (YPP) creators. This program lets creators self-report how their video complies with ad policies. It’s a reinforcing process: the more accurate you are in your self-reporting, the more our system trusts you. Not only does Self Certification give creators more control, it also provides specific feedback on why a video might have monetization issues. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We’ve also heard creators say it feels like an inconvenience when we run experiments or make changes. They ask why we’re trying to fix something that doesn’t seem broken, and they want more of a heads up. So I wanted to give more insights into our development processes.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We are always looking for ways to improve the YouTube experience. Every change we make was tested many times, in several variations, before we roll it out. In the last year alone, we launched over 2,500 updates to YouTube. That means every new feature is developed after we test three or four potential versions to determine what works best for users and creators. It’s through all these changes ⁠— big and small ⁠— that we deliver a better product for you to broadcast yourself and make a living in the new creative economy. We’ll do a better job of communicating with you about why we’re undertaking these efforts and how they might impact you. Please remember that our experiments enable us to ultimately have a better outcome for all viewers and creators.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-eQLM7CNQA-U/XdXUxriaf6I/AAAAAAAACZg/hm2xXeY3I5MuJ1SK50POsCkYEqyRtZzJQCLcBGAsYHQ/s1600/YT_12a.png&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;969&quot; data-original-width=&quot;1600&quot; src=&quot;https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-eQLM7CNQA-U/XdXUxriaf6I/AAAAAAAACZg/hm2xXeY3I5MuJ1SK50POsCkYEqyRtZzJQCLcBGAsYHQ/s1600/YT_12a.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Lastly, I wanted to mention that we continue to work to support your well being. Many of you have shared your stories about burnout, and we appreciated your honesty. We want to encourage you to &lt;a href=&quot;https://creatoracademy.youtube.com/page/course/well-being&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;take care of yourself&lt;/a&gt; and invest in recovery. In particular, I’ve heard some creators say they feel like they &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=SINjqNsWMlU&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;can’t take a break&lt;/a&gt; from filming because they’re concerned their channel will suffer. So I asked the product team at YouTube to look into it. They went over data from the last six years and found good news. Across millions of channels and hundreds of different time frames for breaks, the same thing was true: On average, channels had more views when they returned than they had right before they left. If you need to take some time off, your fans will understand. After all, they tune into your channel because of you. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;h3 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;Living up to our responsibility&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;You’ve heard me say before that my number one priority is to balance our responsibility to protect our community with the responsibility to protect freedom of expression. One of the most common questions I get is about how we make policy changes and why it seems to take so long. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-NdiwByJ2zFk/XdXLBs3rdAI/AAAAAAAACZM/M9Dfh1S-HwIu1_zC2fxs9IIbytnN9axSACEwYBhgL/s1600/YT_15.png&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;701&quot; data-original-width=&quot;1600&quot; src=&quot;https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-NdiwByJ2zFk/XdXLBs3rdAI/AAAAAAAACZM/M9Dfh1S-HwIu1_zC2fxs9IIbytnN9axSACEwYBhgL/s1600/YT_15.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;These changes take time because, behind the scenes we bring together hundreds of people at YouTube, in consultation with outside experts. When we updated our hate speech policy a few months ago, we consulted with experts in areas like violent extremism, supremacy, civil rights and free speech. These in-depth conversations help us determine how to write guidelines that will protect our community in the long run. We went through a similar process earlier this year when we updated our policy toward pranks and challenges.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We need to ensure our policies address how these issues arise in different cultures and languages, and we also want to make sure our policies can be easily understood by users around the world. YouTube trains all of our reviewers before we implement a new policy, so it will be applied consistently, regardless of what country a user is in when they use YouTube. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We also make sure that every policy works in practice and not just in theory. Before a new policy is launched, we test to make sure that our reviewers rate content with a high level of accuracy under the new guidelines. If they don’t, we send the guidelines back and try again. We want to ensure that content is consistently rated correctly, rather than rushing through a change.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Right now, we’re in the process of updating our harassment policy guidelines, and we’ll keep you posted as they’re finalized. As with all our policy updates, we’re talking with creators to make sure we’re addressing the issues that are most important to the YouTube community.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We’re also changing how we treat data for children’s content on YouTube as part of a settlement with the U.S. Federal Trade Commission and the New York Attorney General that addresses &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtube.googleblog.com/2019/09/an-update-on-kids.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;COPPA concerns.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;In order to identify content made for kids, we recently implemented a new audience setting where creators must designate whether their content is made for kids. Starting in January, certain features that rely on user data, such as comments and personalized advertising, will no longer be available on content made for kids. We know there are still many questions about how this is going to affect creators and we’ll provide &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-JzXiSkoFKw&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;updates&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;along the way. You can read more about this change &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.google.com/youtube/thread/13557434&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Finally, I wanted to share some thoughts as I’ve spent more time with policymakers around the world, from New Zealand Prime Minister Jacinda Ardern to legislators in Washington, D.C. to regulators in Europe who are translating Article 17, the EU copyright directive previously called Article 13, into local law. In all of these conversations, it’s clear that we need to continue to help people understand the creator economy, how it contributes to jobs around the world, and how regulation could impact your businesses.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-jWuX_vg2Xbk/XdXLdoA-yYI/AAAAAAAACZU/KmfO88tb8iUurCTPIb3ooV8KTacPHyPDACLcBGAsYHQ/s1600/YT_17.png&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;1134&quot; data-original-width=&quot;1600&quot; src=&quot;https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-jWuX_vg2Xbk/XdXLdoA-yYI/AAAAAAAACZU/KmfO88tb8iUurCTPIb3ooV8KTacPHyPDACLcBGAsYHQ/s1600/YT_17.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Last year, I wrote to you about how Article 17 could have unintended consequences that might impact your livelihood. Thanks to all of the creator involvement, we were able to make improvements to the legislation — in particular, securing liability protections when we make best efforts to match copyright material with rights owners. This change made a big difference and moved the copyright directive in a better direction for the internet and YouTube. Now it’s up to European countries to turn the legislation into national laws. As the process moves forward, we&#39;re meeting with governments and inviting local creators to help explain to legislators how Article 17 could affect creators like you.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We’re in this together. We&#39;ll continue to keep you posted as we advocate for responsible copyright reform. We hope to see some early drafts of the new legislation in 2020, but it will take a few years for each EU country to implement Article 17.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I’d like to close by saying how powerful it is when creators do good work around the world. So many of you were inspired by Mr. Beast and Mark Rober’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://teamtrees.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;#teamtrees challenge&lt;/a&gt; to help plant 20 million trees by January 2020. Last month, I was honored to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=KEA8wis3FIs&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;join in the challenge&lt;/a&gt; and plant a tree with Mark.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The response from creators to #teamtrees has been so impressive. If you keep up this pace, we’ll hit the goal of 20 million trees! We&#39;re excited to help creators support their favorite causes with tools like the YouTube Donate button. In the next few months, the Donate button will come   out of beta and become available to thousands of creators in the U.S. — and later expand to more countries — giving you the opportunity to embed a fundraising campaign next to your videos and live streams.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;It’s so inspiring to see all of your great work. Keep it up! &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;i&gt;Susan Wojcicki&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='replies' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://youtube-creators.googleblog.com/feeds/6116414416992361779/comments/default' title='Post Comments'/><link rel='replies' type='text/html' href='http://youtube-creators.googleblog.com/2019/11/my-final-letter-in-2019.html#comment-form' title='0 Comments'/><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://www.blogger.com/feeds/6959495683334200101/posts/default/6116414416992361779'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://www.blogger.com/feeds/6959495683334200101/posts/default/6116414416992361779'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://youtube-creators.googleblog.com/2019/11/my-final-letter-in-2019.html' title='My final letter in 2019: Updates for this year'/><author><name>YouTube Creators</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/00450486760991148551</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-mAvp965d8h0/XdXIySUcHcI/AAAAAAAACZA/0UD6cFrfOPEXl_Rwfg6l3dYz4B89zdYHQCLcBGAsYHQ/s72-c/YT_1.png" height="72" width="72"/><thr:total>0</thr:total></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-6959495683334200101.post-6630371422462323873</id><published>2019-11-05T10:00:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2019-11-05T10:00:00.222-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Introducing Super Stickers: Another way to help you earn money while connecting with your viewers</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-P9k8T28Hpbc/XcA2AEC9azI/AAAAAAAACVM/Dcw7w5kaLjQasUMkz21-LCpgVi_ZOcu4ACLcBGAsYHQ/s1600/1kitty.gif&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;1024&quot; data-original-width=&quot;1024&quot; height=&quot;200&quot; src=&quot;https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-P9k8T28Hpbc/XcA2AEC9azI/AAAAAAAACVM/Dcw7w5kaLjQasUMkz21-LCpgVi_ZOcu4ACLcBGAsYHQ/s200/1kitty.gif&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;Like Bushiba over there, your fans want to say hello, connect with you, and even share their appreciation.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-L5EEP6irqNo/Xb_AxRYPYVI/AAAAAAAACUE/KVwBuP1Nyg8n5YYBf7Kdsbx5b-7E5ELIwCLcBGAsYHQ/s1600/1hippo.gif&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;clear: right; float: right; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-left: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;512&quot; data-original-width=&quot;512&quot; height=&quot;200&quot; src=&quot;https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-L5EEP6irqNo/Xb_AxRYPYVI/AAAAAAAACUE/KVwBuP1Nyg8n5YYBf7Kdsbx5b-7E5ELIwCLcBGAsYHQ/s200/1hippo.gif&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Whether it’s to congratulate you for a game well played!&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-ZBsaNV6QKs8/Xb_BNlUkSQI/AAAAAAAACUY/CLaZKIgRAXMzNbXDjz_L-wgIsT5gOAkGACLcBGAsYHQ/s1600/1lemon.png&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;512&quot; data-original-width=&quot;512&quot; height=&quot;200&quot; src=&quot;https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-ZBsaNV6QKs8/Xb_BNlUkSQI/AAAAAAAACUY/CLaZKIgRAXMzNbXDjz_L-wgIsT5gOAkGACLcBGAsYHQ/s200/1lemon.png&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;Or thank you for keeping up the good work, your fans are looking to deepen their connections with you in fun, new ways. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;That is why we’re so excited to launch Super Stickers! &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-ysmIQhn-vKY/Xb_BrudiccI/AAAAAAAACUk/YsySQJDzoXY0uO4-fsCct8eeJShcmbgfgCLcBGAsYHQ/s1600/1cool.png&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;clear: right; float: right; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-left: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;1024&quot; data-original-width=&quot;1024&quot; height=&quot;200&quot; src=&quot;https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-ysmIQhn-vKY/Xb_BrudiccI/AAAAAAAACUk/YsySQJDzoXY0uO4-fsCct8eeJShcmbgfgCLcBGAsYHQ/s200/1cool.png&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;Super Stickers are launching today in 60 countries to all &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.google.com/youtube/answer/9277801&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;eligible creators&lt;/a&gt; (same creator eligibility criteria as Super Chat), allowing your viewers to buy cool stickers to connect with you during live streams and Premieres. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Our initial release comes with 8 distinct sticker packs, 5 of which are animated and have unique bios that add even more color to your connections with fans. If your viewers like Popo the hippopotamus, they can send you stickers the next time you’re on a hot streak. Once you enable Super Stickers, be sure to explore the sticker packs to learn more about Energetic Lemon and Baby Lemon, Bushiba, Biggest Fans, and others! &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-N2RS7kzukGY/Xb_AcJRNm3I/AAAAAAAACT4/F2dATE-ZzmEP4SaG0PbrE9YzLPiA77eKwCLcBGAsYHQ/s1600/Super%2BStickers%2BImage.png&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;624&quot; data-original-width=&quot;1600&quot; src=&quot;https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-N2RS7kzukGY/Xb_AcJRNm3I/AAAAAAAACT4/F2dATE-ZzmEP4SaG0PbrE9YzLPiA77eKwCLcBGAsYHQ/s1600/Super%2BStickers%2BImage.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-dRwmBl4mYpI/XcA0_h1iwXI/AAAAAAAACU0/hW99bXRL9YsXCgFSwdmylvDCtjvN-sRyQCLcBGAsYHQ/s1600/1incredible.gif&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;clear: right; float: right; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-left: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;1024&quot; data-original-width=&quot;1024&quot; height=&quot;200&quot; src=&quot;https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-dRwmBl4mYpI/XcA0_h1iwXI/AAAAAAAACU0/hW99bXRL9YsXCgFSwdmylvDCtjvN-sRyQCLcBGAsYHQ/s200/1incredible.gif&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;A new way to help you earn money on YouTube&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Super Stickers are inspired by the success we’ve seen with Super Chat, which allows fans to purchase messages that stand out within a live chat and Premieres. There are now over 100,000 channels who have received Super Chats, with some streams earning more than $400 per minute.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Enabling Super Stickers is as simple as a click of a button! And if you already use Super Chat, you’ll be automatically opted in. Your fans can also choose from a wide range of prices. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;h3 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;Connect with even more fans including your international viewers! &lt;/h3&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-IrcrBftaNtA/XcA1FRTJ1bI/AAAAAAAACU4/UZSk9cK98RMVKPEFL4C2Phi_oFPBktPgwCLcBGAsYHQ/s1600/1merci.gif&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;512&quot; data-original-width=&quot;512&quot; height=&quot;200&quot; src=&quot;https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-IrcrBftaNtA/XcA1FRTJ1bI/AAAAAAAACU4/UZSk9cK98RMVKPEFL4C2Phi_oFPBktPgwCLcBGAsYHQ/s200/1merci.gif&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;Our first launch and upcoming launches of Super Stickers include translated sticker packs for English, French, Japanese, Korean, and Portuguese, making it easier for your international viewers to connect with you, even if they don’t share the same language.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;h3 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;More stickers coming soon! &lt;/h3&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-OOWrzQps4dk/XcA1K7gEQRI/AAAAAAAACU8/epsGCrwjxycPFdEZzMpSWfvJCsYEAN2_QCLcBGAsYHQ/s1600/1planet.png&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;1024&quot; data-original-width=&quot;1024&quot; height=&quot;200&quot; src=&quot;https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-OOWrzQps4dk/XcA1K7gEQRI/AAAAAAAACU8/epsGCrwjxycPFdEZzMpSWfvJCsYEAN2_QCLcBGAsYHQ/s200/1planet.png&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;We want to continue building great connections between you and your fans, while building more ways to help you to earn revenue. In the coming months, we’re excited to create and release more sticker packs for you and your fans. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;If you haven’t used Super Chat yet, learn how to get started with Super Stickers &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.google.com/youtube/answer/9277801&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;! &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;i&gt;Posted by Zhouzhou He, Product Manager &lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='replies' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://youtube-creators.googleblog.com/feeds/6630371422462323873/comments/default' title='Post Comments'/><link rel='replies' type='text/html' href='http://youtube-creators.googleblog.com/2019/11/introducing-super-stickers.html#comment-form' title='0 Comments'/><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://www.blogger.com/feeds/6959495683334200101/posts/default/6630371422462323873'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://www.blogger.com/feeds/6959495683334200101/posts/default/6630371422462323873'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://youtube-creators.googleblog.com/2019/11/introducing-super-stickers.html' title='Introducing Super Stickers: Another way to help you earn money while connecting with your viewers'/><author><name>YouTube Creators</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/00450486760991148551</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-P9k8T28Hpbc/XcA2AEC9azI/AAAAAAAACVM/Dcw7w5kaLjQasUMkz21-LCpgVi_ZOcu4ACLcBGAsYHQ/s72-c/1kitty.gif" height="72" width="72"/><thr:total>0</thr:total></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-6959495683334200101.post-3100998369039799201</id><published>2019-10-25T12:00:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2019-10-25T12:00:01.088-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Pasta Grannies: Sharing pasta with the world, one nonna at a time</title><content type='html'>&lt;table align=&quot;center&quot; cellpadding=&quot;0&quot; cellspacing=&quot;0&quot; class=&quot;tr-caption-container&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-_CsD8nBlW8o/XbM8t2Xej8I/AAAAAAAACTQ/dtWGvRERazIrS6iLhcH_Tggy7PMxEu3GACLcBGAsYHQ/s1600/PG_thumbnail_06.png&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;900&quot; data-original-width=&quot;1600&quot; src=&quot;https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-_CsD8nBlW8o/XbM8t2Xej8I/AAAAAAAACTQ/dtWGvRERazIrS6iLhcH_Tggy7PMxEu3GACLcBGAsYHQ/s1600/PG_thumbnail_06.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;tr-caption&quot; style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;docs-internal-guid-3cfec242-7fff-3b1c-709c-ecc7f9fbd33b&quot;&gt;&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.38; margin-bottom: 0pt; margin-top: 0pt;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Arial; font-size: 11pt; font-style: italic; font-variant-east-asian: normal; font-variant-numeric: normal; vertical-align: baseline; white-space: pre-wrap;&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp;Nonna Bridiga demonstrates her technique for tagliatelle in her Italian home kitchen&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Arial; font-size: 11pt; font-variant-east-asian: normal; font-variant-numeric: normal; vertical-align: baseline; white-space: pre-wrap;&quot;&gt;. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Arial; font-size: 11pt; font-style: italic; font-variant-east-asian: normal; font-variant-numeric: normal; vertical-align: baseline; white-space: pre-wrap;&quot;&gt;(YouTube)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Arial; font-size: 11pt; font-style: italic; font-variant-east-asian: normal; font-variant-numeric: normal; vertical-align: baseline; white-space: pre-wrap;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;br /&gt;A bowl of homemade pasta is one of the most comforting foods in the world, but making it by hand is no mean feat. It can take years to master the delicate art of perfect tortellini and ravioli, and as families get busier and busier, the traditional art of making homemade pasta is dwindling, even in Italy. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Enter &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/user/pastagrannies/featured&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Pasta Grannies&lt;/a&gt;! Food writer Vicky Bennison started her &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/user/pastagrannies/featuredhttps://www.youtube.com/user/pastagrannies/featured&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;channel&lt;/a&gt; as a way to catalogue the traditional handmade pasta skills of Italy’s grandmothers. For the past five years, she has crisscrossed the country, inviting her audience into the homes of these nonnas as they lovingly prepare their favorite dishes. Whether it’s demonstrating a rare regional specialty or sharing their techniques for mastering the classics, the Pasta Grannies are&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.refinery29.com/en-gb/pasta-grannies-cookbook-recipes&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; inspiring the next generation of home cooks&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/0jRX0xq24AU&quot; width=&quot;560&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;But it’s more than just a cooking tutorial, it’s also helping to preserve centuries-old culinary culture. As Vicky says, “YouTube is just the most fantastic way for these women to pass on their skills and traditions to their grandchildren, their great-grandchildren and the rest of the world.”&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;YouTube traveled to Italy with Vicky to learn more about what propels her vision for Pasta Grannies, the art of making pasta by hand, and to meet the nonnas in person.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;i&gt;Jodi Ropert&lt;/i&gt;</content><link rel='replies' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://youtube-creators.googleblog.com/feeds/3100998369039799201/comments/default' title='Post Comments'/><link rel='replies' type='text/html' href='http://youtube-creators.googleblog.com/2019/10/pasta-grannies-sharing-pasta-with-world.html#comment-form' title='0 Comments'/><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://www.blogger.com/feeds/6959495683334200101/posts/default/3100998369039799201'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://www.blogger.com/feeds/6959495683334200101/posts/default/3100998369039799201'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://youtube-creators.googleblog.com/2019/10/pasta-grannies-sharing-pasta-with-world.html' title='Pasta Grannies: Sharing pasta with the world, one nonna at a time'/><author><name>YouTube Creators</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/00450486760991148551</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-_CsD8nBlW8o/XbM8t2Xej8I/AAAAAAAACTQ/dtWGvRERazIrS6iLhcH_Tggy7PMxEu3GACLcBGAsYHQ/s72-c/PG_thumbnail_06.png" height="72" width="72"/><thr:total>0</thr:total></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-6959495683334200101.post-6920905785985672280</id><published>2019-09-19T10:00:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2019-09-20T15:11:07.808-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Updates to YouTube&#39;s verification program</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Update as of 3 p.m. on 9/20/19:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Yesterday, we announced changes to the verification badge. The idea behind this update was to protect creators from impersonation and address user confusion. Every year, we receive tens of thousands of complaints from creators about impersonation. Also, nearly a third of YouTube users told us that they misunderstood the badge’s meaning, associating it with *endorsement of content*, and not an indicator of *identity*. While rolling out improvements to this program, we completely missed the mark. We’re sorry for the frustration that this caused and we have a few updates to share.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;First, we heard loud and clear how much the badge means to you. Channels that already have the verification badge will now keep it and don’t have to appeal. We’ll continue reviewing those channels to ensure we’re protecting creators from impersonation. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Just like in the past, all channels that have over 100,000 subscribers will still be eligible to apply. We’ll reopen the application process by the end of October. Going forward, we’ll review those channels to verify their identity. If we determine that a channel is attempting to impersonate, we won’t verify that channel and may take additional action. We’ve improved the process and will verify channels that are:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Authentic: Your channel must represent the real creator, brand, or entity you’re claiming to be. We’ll look at a variety of factors to help verify your identity, and may also ask for additional info or documentation.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;li&gt;Complete: Your channel must be public and have a description, channel icon, and content, and be active on YouTube.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-pUO_I6ilgXQ/XYVOLyeyjbI/AAAAAAAACP8/1id2z7epts0TwZhCWkNxz5ziCBl0pFjaACLcBGAsYHQ/s1600/verification-tweet-v4-01.jpg&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;800&quot; data-original-width=&quot;1600&quot; src=&quot;https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-pUO_I6ilgXQ/XYVOLyeyjbI/AAAAAAAACP8/1id2z7epts0TwZhCWkNxz5ziCBl0pFjaACLcBGAsYHQ/s1600/verification-tweet-v4-01.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Yesterday, we also announced a new look for the verification badge that will be displayed consistently across screens. Due to all the changes we’re announcing today, the new badge will roll out next year.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We hope that these clarifications are helpful and that these changes will improve the program for creators in the long run.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br class=&quot;Apple-interchange-newline&quot; /&gt; &lt;hr /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;When viewers come to YouTube, it’s important that they know the channel they are watching is the official presence of the creator, artist, public figure or company that it represents. With that in mind, we’re announcing upcoming changes to our channel verification program starting in late October. There are two parts to the new verification program, a new look and new eligibility requirements. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;h3 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;New look&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Currently, verified channels have a checkmark next to their channel name. Through our research, we found that viewers often associated the checkmark with an endorsement of content, not identity. To reduce confusion about what being verified means, we’re introducing a new look that helps distinguish the official channel of the creator, celebrity or brand it represents. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-2NIpkee5SPA/XYKPnqgNqqI/AAAAAAAACPk/7-FyN4DXKO0MJrRye19RUyysyvAPTvpWgCLcBGAsYHQ/s1600/Creators---V3.gif&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;470&quot; data-original-width=&quot;836&quot; height=&quot;221&quot; src=&quot;https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-2NIpkee5SPA/XYKPnqgNqqI/AAAAAAAACPk/7-FyN4DXKO0MJrRye19RUyysyvAPTvpWgCLcBGAsYHQ/s400/Creators---V3.gif&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-nj6ePNnXvTM/XYKO9FFxx_I/AAAAAAAACPY/AqPIYmXluVEr2tKWgXctTZbLvZNeWyG_gCEwYBhgL/s1600/Music---V3.gif&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;470&quot; data-original-width=&quot;836&quot; height=&quot;221&quot; src=&quot;https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-nj6ePNnXvTM/XYKO9FFxx_I/AAAAAAAACPY/AqPIYmXluVEr2tKWgXctTZbLvZNeWyG_gCEwYBhgL/s400/Music---V3.gif&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-zLO8Km9PeXU/XYKOxtSSWPI/AAAAAAAACPU/smllRtOFw1InpyuXr7TZaAKiKTi7NwOhACLcBGAsYHQ/s1600/Creators---V3.gif&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-zLO8Km9PeXU/XYKOxtSSWPI/AAAAAAAACPU/smllRtOFw1InpyuXr7TZaAKiKTi7NwOhACLcBGAsYHQ/s1600/Creators---V3.gif&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;As YouTube has expanded features where viewers interact with channels, including community posts, live chats and comments, the checkmark has been displayed inconsistently. The new look will be displayed more consistently across channel pages, search and comments, and is more difficult to replicate, so that viewers can be sure of a channel’s identity. This new look will also replace the existing music note on Official Artist Channels on YouTube.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;h3 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;New eligibility requirements&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Under our current eligibility requirements, channels with more than 100,000 subscribers can be verified regardless of need for proof of authenticity. That worked well when YouTube was smaller, but as YouTube has grown and the ecosystem has become more complex, we needed a new way to verify the identity of channels and help users find the official channel they’re looking for. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Our new criteria prioritizes verifying prominent channels that have a clear need for proof of authenticity. We look at a number of factors to determine if a channel meets this criteria, including:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;ul style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Authenticity:&lt;/b&gt;&amp;nbsp;Does this channel belong to the real creator, artist, public figure or company it claims to represent?&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Prominence:&lt;/b&gt;&amp;nbsp;Does this channel represent a well-known or highly searched creator, artist, public figure or company? Is this channel widely recognized outside of YouTube and have a strong presence online? Is this a popular channel that has a very similar name to many other channels?&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The new criteria will apply for all channels. Channels that meet the new requirements no longer need to apply; we will automatically apply the new verified treatment. For more info about verification and eligibility, check out our &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.google.com/youtube/answer/3046484&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Help Center.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;i&gt;Jonathan McPhie, Product Manager&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;ul style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='replies' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://youtube-creators.googleblog.com/feeds/6920905785985672280/comments/default' title='Post Comments'/><link rel='replies' type='text/html' href='http://youtube-creators.googleblog.com/2019/09/updates-to-youtubes-verification-program.html#comment-form' title='0 Comments'/><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://www.blogger.com/feeds/6959495683334200101/posts/default/6920905785985672280'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://www.blogger.com/feeds/6959495683334200101/posts/default/6920905785985672280'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://youtube-creators.googleblog.com/2019/09/updates-to-youtubes-verification-program.html' title='Updates to YouTube&#39;s verification program'/><author><name>YouTube Creators</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/00450486760991148551</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-pUO_I6ilgXQ/XYVOLyeyjbI/AAAAAAAACP8/1id2z7epts0TwZhCWkNxz5ziCBl0pFjaACLcBGAsYHQ/s72-c/verification-tweet-v4-01.jpg" height="72" width="72"/><thr:total>0</thr:total></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-6959495683334200101.post-8161751282393975313</id><published>2019-08-27T10:30:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2019-09-03T08:53:14.272-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Susan Wojcicki: Preserving openness through responsibility</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;Dear creators and artists,&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;As I do every &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtube-creators.googleblog.com/2019/04/addressing-creator-feedback-and-update.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;quarter&lt;/a&gt;, I’d like to pause and reflect on my priorities and how I can help you be successful on YouTube. But rather than our usual update on this quarter’s highlights and lowlights, I want to take a minute to talk about something that is incredibly important to me personally, and the future of this platform: openness and how we balance that with our responsibility to protect the community. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;YouTube is built on the premise of openness. Based on this open platform, millions of creators around the world have connected with global audiences and many of them have built thriving businesses in the process. But openness comes with its challenges, which is why we also have &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/yt/about/policies/#community-guidelines&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Community Guidelines&lt;/a&gt; that we update on an ongoing basis. Most recently, this includes our&lt;a href=&quot;https://youtube.googleblog.com/2019/06/our-ongoing-work-to-tackle-hate.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; hate speech policy&lt;/a&gt; and our &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtube.googleblog.com/2019/06/taking-harder-look-at-harassment.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;upcoming harassment policy&lt;/a&gt;. When you create a place designed to welcome many different voices, some will cross the line. Bad actors will try to exploit platforms for their own gain, even as we invest in the systems to stop them. As more issues come into view, a rising chorus of policymakers, press and pundits are questioning whether an open platform is valuable... or even viable. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Despite these concerns, I believe preserving an open platform is more important than ever. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;First, openness leads to opportunity. Today’s creators have built an entire creative economy and are redefining the face of media. They are truly next-generation media businesses, with millions of views and global brands, who are contributing to local and global economies, and creating jobs. These are creators that would not have had a chance to break through in a more closed media landscape. Creators like Swedish robotics enthusiast &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC3KEoMzNz8eYnwBC34RaKCQ&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Simone Giertz&lt;/a&gt; and blind lifestyle vlogger &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCwf9TcLyS5KDoLRLjke41Hg&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Molly Burke&lt;/a&gt;, both unconventional in their appeal and passed over by traditional media, are finding huge success on YouTube managing businesses, selling merchandise, creating jobs for other people and creating real economic value in their communities. Or creators like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/user/LauraVitalesKitchen&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Laura Vitale&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=V2ffyfoXJOY&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Sallys Welt&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCMmZEL8jV1B61NKAXcyW87A&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Helen&#39;s Recipes&lt;/a&gt; have turned their passion for food into full-time professions, complete with successful channels, cookbooks and more. And they are not alone. A &lt;a href=&quot;https://drive.google.com/file/d/1frDtTaR-y7qHQuECH-4M83zOhfBk-t2Z/view&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;report&lt;/a&gt; from Ryerson University found that YouTube creators have created 28,000 full time jobs just in Canada. And 20% of eligible Canadian creators are creating jobs for others. Around the globe, the number of channels earning more than $100,000 continues to climb 40% year over year.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Openness has also helped foster community. On an open platform, a shared experience can unite people in amazing ways. For example, Ryleigh Hawkins from New Zealand started her channel, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCNOume_VesWl0SxPJ9vXLTw&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Tourettes Teen&lt;/a&gt;, to spread awareness about what it’s like to live with Tourette’s syndrome. Her informative, joyful and humorous videos have earned her fans around the world and let others with this potentially isolating condition know they are not alone. And teens are sharing their &lt;a href=&quot;https://mashable.com/article/college-rejection-youtube-videos/#FB9y3Wjdtmq7&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;college rejection videos&lt;/a&gt;, serving as a reminder that this painful moment happens to everyone and people do bounce back.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;And finally, openness leads to learning. As a daughter of two teachers and a lifelong learner, I’ve been especially inspired to see Edutubers like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCiB8h9jD2Mlxx96ZFnGDSJw&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Origin of Everything&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/user/iberethenorio/about&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Manual do Mundo&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/user/misterwootube&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Eddie Woo&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/user/ExcelIsFun&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Excel is Fun&lt;/a&gt; turn YouTube into the world’s largest classroom. Every time I meet someone new and ask them about YouTube, I hear a story about something they learned on the site: how YouTube helped a student ace her math homework, a mom fix a broken garage door, or an employee master a new job skill.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Let me be clear, none of this happens without openness. Without an open system, diverse and authentic voices have trouble breaking through. And the voices that do get a platform often sound like those who already have one. That small business built on someone sharing their passion for soapmaking &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=EkPCzwZ_x58&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;never takes off&lt;/a&gt;. That bullied teen can’t find a community that looks and feels like them and lets them know that &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/user/itgetsbetterproject&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;it gets better&lt;/a&gt;. And that curious person obsessed with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=qFjw6Lc6J2g&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;planetary physics&lt;/a&gt; and looking for a few videos is probably out of luck. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;A commitment to openness is not easy. It sometimes means leaving up content that is outside the mainstream, controversial or even offensive. But I believe that hearing a broad range of perspectives ultimately makes us a stronger and more informed society, even if we disagree with some of those views. A large part of how we protect this openness is not just &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/yt/about/policies/#community-guidelines&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;guidelines&lt;/a&gt; that allow for diversity of speech, but the steps that we’re taking to ensure a responsible community. I’ve said a &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtube-creators.googleblog.com/2019/04/addressing-creator-feedback-and-update.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;number&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtube-creators.googleblog.com/search?updated-max=2019-02-19T05:00:00-08:00&amp;amp;max-results=7&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;of&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2019/04/17/business/youtube-ceo-susan-wojcicki.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;times&lt;/a&gt; this year that this is my number one priority. A responsible approach toward managing what’s on our platform protects our users and creators like you. It also means we can continue to foster all the good that comes from an open platform. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Problematic content represents a fraction of one percent of the content on YouTube and we’re constantly working to reduce this even further. This very small amount has a hugely outsized impact, both in the potential harm for our users, as well as the loss of faith in the open model that has enabled the rise of your creative community. One assumption we’ve heard is that we hesitate to take action on problematic content because it benefits our business. This is simply not true — in fact, the cost of not taking sufficient action over the long term results in lack of trust from our users, advertisers, and you, our creators. We want to earn that trust. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;This is why we’ve been investing significantly over the past few years in the teams and systems that protect YouTube. Our approach towards responsibility involves four “Rs”:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;ul style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;We REMOVE content that violates our policy as quickly as possible. And we’re always looking to make our policies clearer and more effective, as we’ve done with&lt;a href=&quot;https://support.google.com/youtube/thread/1063345?hl=en&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; pranks and challenges&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtube.googleblog.com/2019/06/an-update-on-our-efforts-to-protect.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;child safety&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtube.googleblog.com/2019/06/our-ongoing-work-to-tackle-hate.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;hate speech&lt;/a&gt; just this year. We aim to be thoughtful when we make these updates and consult a wide variety of experts to inform our thinking, for example we talked to dozens of experts as we developed our updated hate speech policy. We also report on the removals we make in our quarterly Community Guidelines enforcement report. I also appreciate that when policies aren’t working for the creator community, you let us know. One area we’ve heard loud and clear needs an update is creator-on-creator harassment. I said in my &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtube-creators.googleblog.com/2019/04/addressing-creator-feedback-and-update.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;last letter&lt;/a&gt; that we’d be looking at this and we will have more to share in the coming months.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;ul style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;We RAISE UP authoritative voices when people are looking for breaking news and information, especially during breaking news moments. Our breaking and top news shelves are available in 40 countries and we’re continuing to expand that number.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;ul style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;We REDUCE the spread of content that brushes right up against our policy line. Already, in the U.S. where we &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtube.googleblog.com/2019/01/continuing-our-work-to-improve.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;made changes&lt;/a&gt; to recommendations earlier this year, we’ve seen a 50% drop in watch time to this type of content, meaning quality content has more of a chance to shine. And we&#39;ve begun experimenting with this change in the UK, Ireland, South Africa and other English-language markets.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;ul style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;And we set a &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.google.com/youtube/answer/1311392?hl=en&amp;amp;ref_topic=9153642&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;higher bar&lt;/a&gt; for what channels can make money on our site, REWARDING trusted, eligible creators. Not all content allowed on YouTube is going to match what advertisers feel is suitable for their brand, we have to be sure they are comfortable with where their ads appear. This is also why we’re &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtube.googleblog.com/2019/07/live-from-vidcon-creating-new.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;enabling&lt;/a&gt; new revenue streams for creators like Super Chat and Memberships. Thousands of channels have more than doubled their total YouTube revenue by using these new tools in addition to advertising. &lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The stories I hear from creators like you inspire me every day. The community you’ve created is living proof that an internet that reflects a broad range of ideas can change the world for the better. You’ve built something incredible; it’s our job to strike the right balance between openness and responsibility so that future generations of creators and users can, as well. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;i&gt;Susan Wojcicki&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='replies' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://youtube-creators.googleblog.com/feeds/8161751282393975313/comments/default' title='Post Comments'/><link rel='replies' type='text/html' href='http://youtube-creators.googleblog.com/2019/08/preserving-openness-through-responsibility.html#comment-form' title='0 Comments'/><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://www.blogger.com/feeds/6959495683334200101/posts/default/8161751282393975313'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://www.blogger.com/feeds/6959495683334200101/posts/default/8161751282393975313'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://youtube-creators.googleblog.com/2019/08/preserving-openness-through-responsibility.html' title='Susan Wojcicki: Preserving openness through responsibility'/><author><name>YouTube Creators</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/00450486760991148551</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><thr:total>0</thr:total></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-6959495683334200101.post-6049033526483405532</id><published>2019-08-15T11:00:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2019-08-15T11:00:00.149-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Updates to our manual Content ID claiming policies</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;In Susan’s April &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtube-creators.googleblog.com/2019/04/addressing-creator-feedback-and-update.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Creator Letter,&lt;/a&gt; she shared that improving creators’ experience with copyright claims is one of our top priorities. One concerning trend we’ve seen is aggressive manual claiming of very short music clips used in monetized videos. These claims can feel particularly unfair, as they transfer all revenue from the creator to the claimant, regardless of the amount of music claimed. &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtube-creators.googleblog.com/2019/07/better-tools-to-resolve-manual-Content-ID-claims.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;A little over a month ago,&lt;/a&gt; we took a first step in addressing this by requiring copyright owners to provide timestamps for all manual claims so you know exactly which part of your video is being claimed. We also made updates to our editing tools in Creator Studio that allow you to use those timestamps to remove manually claimed content from your videos, automatically releasing the claim and restoring monetization. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Today, we’re announcing additional changes to our &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.google.com/youtube/answer/9142671#manual_claiming&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;manual claiming policies&lt;/a&gt; intended to improve fairness in the creator ecosystem, while still respecting copyright owners’ rights to prevent unlicensed use of their content. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Including someone else’s content without permission — regardless of how short the clip is — means your video can still be claimed and copyright owners will still be able to prevent monetization or block the video from being viewed. However, going forward, our policies will forbid copyright owners from using our Manual Claiming tool to monetize creator videos with very short or unintentional uses of music. This change only impacts claims made with the Manual Claiming tool, where the rightsholder is actively reviewing the video. Claims created by the Content ID match system, which are the vast majority, are not impacted by this policy. Without the option to monetize, some copyright owners may choose to leave very short or unintentional uses unclaimed. Others may choose to prevent monetization of the video by any party. And some may choose to apply a &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.google.com/youtube/answer/2797370#c-subject&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;block policy.   &lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;As always, the best way to avoid these issues is to not use unlicensed content in your videos, even when it’s unintentional music playing in the background (i.e. vlogging in a store with music playing in the background). Instead, choose content from trusted sources such as the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/audiolibrary/music?nv=1&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;YouTube Audio Library&lt;/a&gt;, which has new tracks added every month. If you do find yourself with an unintended claim, you can use our editing tools to remove the claimed content and the restrictions that come with it. And, of course, if you feel that your use qualifies for an exception to copyright, like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/yt/about/copyright/fair-use/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Fair Use&lt;/a&gt;, be sure you understand what that means and how our &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.google.com/youtube/answer/2797454&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;dispute process&lt;/a&gt; works before uploading your video. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Our enforcement of these new policies will apply to all new manual claims beginning in mid-September, providing adequate time for copyright owners to adapt. Once we start enforcement, copyright owners who repeatedly fail to adhere to these policies will have their access to Manual Claiming suspended.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We strive to make YouTube a fair ecosystem for everyone, including songwriters, artists, and YouTube creators. We acknowledge that these changes may result in more blocked content in the near-term, but we feel this is an important step toward striking the right balance over the long-term. Our goal is to unlock new value for everyone by powering creative reuse and content mashups, while fairly compensating all rightsholders.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;i&gt;— The YouTube Team&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='replies' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://youtube-creators.googleblog.com/feeds/6049033526483405532/comments/default' title='Post Comments'/><link rel='replies' type='text/html' href='http://youtube-creators.googleblog.com/2019/08/updates-to-manual-claiming-policies.html#comment-form' title='0 Comments'/><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://www.blogger.com/feeds/6959495683334200101/posts/default/6049033526483405532'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://www.blogger.com/feeds/6959495683334200101/posts/default/6049033526483405532'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://youtube-creators.googleblog.com/2019/08/updates-to-manual-claiming-policies.html' title='Updates to our manual Content ID claiming policies'/><author><name>YouTube Creators</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/00450486760991148551</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><thr:total>0</thr:total></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-6959495683334200101.post-4829758484827047581</id><published>2019-07-11T16:30:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2019-07-11T16:30:15.160-07:00</updated><title type='text'>VidCon 2019</title><content type='html'>Happy 10th annual VidCon, creators! We&#39;re here with our Chief Product Officer, Neal Mohan, who&#39;s keynoting it up. His main message? All the ways YouTube will continue to support and help drive new opportunities for you in the next decade and beyond. Read how YouTube&#39;s planning to do all this — thanks to some of our new initiatives — &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtube.googleblog.com/2019/07/live-from-vidcon-creating-new.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;background-color: white; color: #545454; font-family: &amp;quot;roboto&amp;quot; , &amp;quot;arial&amp;quot; , sans-serif; font-size: small;&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;— The YouTube Team&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/span&gt;</content><link rel='replies' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://youtube-creators.googleblog.com/feeds/4829758484827047581/comments/default' title='Post Comments'/><link rel='replies' type='text/html' href='http://youtube-creators.googleblog.com/2019/07/vidcon-2019.html#comment-form' title='0 Comments'/><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://www.blogger.com/feeds/6959495683334200101/posts/default/4829758484827047581'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://www.blogger.com/feeds/6959495683334200101/posts/default/4829758484827047581'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://youtube-creators.googleblog.com/2019/07/vidcon-2019.html' title='VidCon 2019'/><author><name>YouTube Creators</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/00450486760991148551</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><thr:total>0</thr:total></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-6959495683334200101.post-4949574077491885106</id><published>2019-07-09T11:00:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2019-07-09T11:00:04.021-07:00</updated><title type='text'>More information and better tools to resolve manual Content ID claims</title><content type='html'>As Susan mentioned in her April &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtube-creators.googleblog.com/2019/04/addressing-creator-feedback-and-update.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Creator Letter&lt;/a&gt;, we’re making it easier for creators to understand and remove manually claimed content in their videos. We’ve heard from creators that the recent uptick of manual claims, especially for short segments, has led to some confusion, as the claims sometimes lack key information that can help to resolve the issue. While it’s important that creators understand and respect copyright, it’s also important that they have knowledge of who is claiming content in their videos, where it appears, and what they can do about it. Starting today, we will require copyright owners to provide timestamps to indicate exactly where their content appears in videos they manually claim, and we’re improving our video editing tools in Creator Studio to make it easier for creators to remove the content associated with these claims.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Manual Claiming is a tool within &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.google.com/youtube/answer/2797370&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Content ID&lt;/a&gt; that allows select copyright owners to manually make claims on videos that were not automatically made by our Content ID matching system. Previously, we did not require copyright owners using the Manual Claiming tool to provide timestamps, so it was sometimes unclear to creators which parts of their videos were being claimed and in addition, unlike edits that removed content identified by automated claims, the claims wouldn’t be automatically released.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We’re making the experience better for you in two important ways:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;b&gt;1. Copyright owners must now provide timestamps for exactly what part of your video is being manually claimed.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Just as you would if you receive an automatic claim from our Content ID matching system, you’ll now see timestamps in Creator Studio when you get a manual claim. Check out the Video Copyright Info page in &lt;a href=&quot;https://studio.youtube.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;YouTube Studio&lt;/a&gt; that offers a visualization of where the manually-claimed content appears in your video, and also, it provides more info about the content being claimed. We’ll be evaluating the accuracy of these timestamps. Copyright owners who repeatedly fail to provide accurate data will have their access to manual claiming revoked.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;b&gt;2. You can use our editing tools to remove the content claimed manually in your video which will now automatically release the claims.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We’ve updated our editing tools to make it easier to remove manually claimed content from your video. If you choose to remove the content, the claim will now be released automatically. Below are some of the options you have without having to edit and upload a new video:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Mute all sound when the claimed song plays:&lt;/b&gt; If you get a claim for a piece of music in your video, you can now mute the time-stamped segment.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Replace the song:&lt;/b&gt; If you don’t want to mute the audio entirely, you can instead swap out the music with one of our free-to-use songs from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/audiolibrary/music&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;YouTube Audio Library&lt;/a&gt;. We also added new visual indicators below the video player, which show exactly what segment of the video is claimed. This can help you position the audio track in such a way that will remove the claims from your video.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Trim out the content:&lt;/b&gt; You also have the option to cut out the time-stamped segment from your video using the Trim feature in the YouTube Editor.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;We’re still working on several improvements here, like having an explicit Trim option in the Video Copyright Info page that will allow you to trim out the claimed content with just one click. You can learn more about these changes in our &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.google.com/youtube/answer/9374251&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Help Center.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Remember, if you &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.google.com/youtube/answer/6013276?hl=en&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;receive a claim&lt;/a&gt; that you believe is incorrect, you have the right to dispute it. You know the most about the content in your videos and whether it was used appropriately, so we built the dispute process to empower you to escalate any problems to the copyright owner, and even as far as the courts, if you choose. If both you and the person claiming your video are attempting to monetize it, we will continue to show ads on the video during the dispute process and make sure the appropriate party gets the revenue once the dispute is resolved.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Our work won’t stop here. We’re always looking to find ways to improve the creator copyright experience while also balancing the rights of copyright owners. Stay tuned for more to come.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;i&gt;Julian Bill, Product Manager&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;</content><link rel='replies' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://youtube-creators.googleblog.com/feeds/4949574077491885106/comments/default' title='Post Comments'/><link rel='replies' type='text/html' href='http://youtube-creators.googleblog.com/2019/07/better-tools-to-resolve-manual-Content-ID-claims.html#comment-form' title='0 Comments'/><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://www.blogger.com/feeds/6959495683334200101/posts/default/4949574077491885106'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://www.blogger.com/feeds/6959495683334200101/posts/default/4949574077491885106'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://youtube-creators.googleblog.com/2019/07/better-tools-to-resolve-manual-Content-ID-claims.html' title='More information and better tools to resolve manual Content ID claims'/><author><name>YouTube Creators</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/00450486760991148551</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><thr:total>0</thr:total></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-6959495683334200101.post-6904112904229420295</id><published>2019-05-16T09:00:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2019-05-16T09:00:05.814-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Breaking down barriers to VR</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;YouTube is where people go to experience VR videos. With over one million VR videos and experiences, YouTube VR offers a diverse library of immersive content for everyone to enjoy and explore the world from a new perspective. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;But to make VR for everyone, we have to continue breaking down barriers on how people create and watch VR content on YouTube. To do this, we’re focused on offering YouTube VR on even more platforms, celebrating award-winning VR content and improving creator education programs.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Offering YouTube VR on even more platforms&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Since the initial launch of the YouTube VR app in November 2016, we’ve been focused on bringing the app to as many people with a VR headset as possible. It’s already available on Daydream View, HTC Vive, Playstation VR, Samsung Gear VR, Oculus Go and Oculus Rift. And when Oculus Quest becomes available on Tuesday, May 21, the YouTube VR app will be available as a launch title.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Celebrating award-winning VR content on YouTube&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;br /&gt;VR allows creators to transport their audiences to new, amazing and even impossible places. We’ve partnered with creators to bring immersive experiences to YouTube. And, over the last six months, these VR videos have been recognized with a number of standout awards, including Emmy®, Webby and Streamy awards. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;iframe allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/DR1gT36OtJQ&quot; width=&quot;560&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Baobab Studios recently nabbed multiple Emmy® awards for the animated short film,&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=DR1gT36OtJQ&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp;“Crow: The Legend VR&lt;/a&gt;.” With a star-studded cast&amp;nbsp;&lt;span style=&quot;background-color: white; color: #222222; font-family: &amp;quot;georgia&amp;quot; , serif; font-size: 15px;&quot;&gt;—&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;including John Legend, Oprah, Liza Koshy and Constance Wu&amp;nbsp;&lt;span style=&quot;background-color: white; color: #222222; font-family: &amp;quot;georgia&amp;quot; , serif; font-size: 15px;&quot;&gt;—&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;this immersive short film is animated VR content at its best.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;iframe allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/o3_byIkXF7Q&quot; width=&quot;560&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;But the Emmy® awards didn’t stop there. NASA Jet Propulsion Laboratory won an Emmy® for their “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hFjzFSidX3s&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Cassini&#39;s Grand Finale 360°” videos &lt;/a&gt;and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=o3_byIkXF7Q&amp;amp;list=PLTiv_XWHnOZofSNYaXYOg9moAgrwmBxQF&amp;amp;index=6&amp;amp;t=3348s&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;NASA&#39;s first 360° livestream&lt;/a&gt;. These 360-degree videos transport viewers to space, unlocking an out-of-this-world experience. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;iframe allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/JqXC46b1uUg&quot; width=&quot;560&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;“&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=JqXC46b1uUg&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Isle of Dogs: Behind the Scenes (in Virtual Reality)&lt;/a&gt;” won two Webby Awards and the Clio Entertainment Gold award. The immersive video takes the audience behind-the-scenes of the film, featuring on-set interviews with the cast and an inside look at the unique craft of stop-motion animation.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Improving creator education through the YouTube VR Creator Lab&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;br /&gt;As part of our efforts to continue democratizing VR content creation, we’re currently accepting &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/yt/space/london/vr-creator-lab/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;applications&lt;/a&gt; for the European edition of the YouTube VR Creator Lab. This three-month, learning and production intensive helps creators embrace &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtube.googleblog.com/2017/06/the-world-as-you-see-it-with-vr180.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;YouTube’s VR180 format&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Selected participants get to attend a three-day boot camp at a YouTube Space and receive advanced education from leading VR instructors and filmmakers, ongoing mentoring, a shiny VR180 camera to keep, and $20,000 USD in funding toward the production of their dream projects. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;iframe allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/x8_j-SQ7JEI&quot; width=&quot;560&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Since the program launched in 2017, we’ve hosted six &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=x8_j-SQ7JEI&amp;amp;feature=youtu.be&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;YouTube VR Creator Labs&lt;/a&gt; with over 60 creators across the globe in Los Angeles, London and Tokyo. Participants have gone on to win &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.jpl.nasa.gov/news/news.php?feature=7232&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Emmy&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vFuC_7bhjgc&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Streamy&lt;/a&gt; awards for their VR content created during the lab. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We’re excited to see where VR will bring us next! &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;i&gt;Posted by Julia Hamiton Trost, Head of VR/AR Content &amp;amp; Partnerships, who recently watched “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Jjsd-6O9GD0&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Cirque du Soleil&#39;s VOLTA Hair Suspension in VR180&lt;/a&gt;,” and Kurt Wilms, Product Lead, VR, who recently watched “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2_JJ9gDLwHU&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Engineering for Mars: Building the Mars 2020 Mission (360 video)&lt;/a&gt;”&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='replies' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://youtube-creators.googleblog.com/feeds/6904112904229420295/comments/default' title='Post Comments'/><link rel='replies' type='text/html' href='http://youtube-creators.googleblog.com/2019/05/breaking-down-barriers-to-vr.html#comment-form' title='0 Comments'/><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://www.blogger.com/feeds/6959495683334200101/posts/default/6904112904229420295'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://www.blogger.com/feeds/6959495683334200101/posts/default/6904112904229420295'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://youtube-creators.googleblog.com/2019/05/breaking-down-barriers-to-vr.html' title='Breaking down barriers to VR'/><author><name>YouTube Creators</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/00450486760991148551</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://img.youtube.com/vi/DR1gT36OtJQ/default.jpg" height="72" width="72"/><thr:total>0</thr:total></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-6959495683334200101.post-7138659765332299348</id><published>2019-05-03T09:05:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2019-05-03T09:36:15.694-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Creator Summit: What 6 creators had to say</title><content type='html'>&lt;table align=&quot;center&quot; cellpadding=&quot;0&quot; cellspacing=&quot;0&quot; class=&quot;tr-caption-container&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-BC7slkjecRg/XMxfqlnkECI/AAAAAAAACMY/uE9ZHnd8ark_vS2YKecT-q-pxl4Wn8hhACLcBGAs/s1600/creatorsummit-collage.jpg&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;1579&quot; data-original-width=&quot;1600&quot; height=&quot;632&quot; src=&quot;https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-BC7slkjecRg/XMxfqlnkECI/AAAAAAAACMY/uE9ZHnd8ark_vS2YKecT-q-pxl4Wn8hhACLcBGAs/s640/creatorsummit-collage.jpg&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;tr-caption&quot; style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;Photos by Alexander Stein&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Over the past couple days, we hosted our fifth annual North American Creator Summit, where we brought together over a hundred of our most influential creators and artists for inspirational conversations. It was candid, it was fun, and there was &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/thephysicsgirl/status/1123711675008471041&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;a lot &lt;/i&gt;of latte art&lt;/a&gt;.  From burning questions posed to YouTube Leadership to meaningful discussions with peers, the creators and artists who joined us fostered a special kind of community this year. There was &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/EhBeeFamily/status/1123677956822458373&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;energy and excitement&lt;/a&gt; in the air that was palpable and spirited, which gave the &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/smartereveryday/status/1123791820541001728&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;rollerskating extravaganza&lt;/a&gt; extra pizzazz.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We caught up with a few creators right after Susan Wojcicki (CEO), Neal Mohan (CPO) and Robert Kyncl (CBO) spoke about how creators and artists are the very heart of YouTube.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;“The Internet’s always going to be asking for more, but hearing them talk about it in person — their steps and plans, what they’re planning to do to fix it, and how many people are part of the team to work on very specific issue — it’s comforting to hear them say that and know that they’re on our side,” said Lily Hevesh, the domino artist behind &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/hevesh5/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Hevesh5&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;i&gt;Interviews have been condensed for clarity.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;table align=&quot;center&quot; cellpadding=&quot;0&quot; cellspacing=&quot;0&quot; class=&quot;tr-caption-container&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-0zck76ObIXI/XMxiaMdgEAI/AAAAAAAACMk/AihSHjsRbQQSupy3GU7sXs9QWZMMjOSPACLcBGAs/s1600/creatorsummit-sam.jpg&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;667&quot; data-original-width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;426&quot; src=&quot;https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-0zck76ObIXI/XMxiaMdgEAI/AAAAAAAACMk/AihSHjsRbQQSupy3GU7sXs9QWZMMjOSPACLcBGAs/s640/creatorsummit-sam.jpg&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;tr-caption&quot; style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;Sam Tsui performing at Creator Summit (Photo by Alexander Stein)&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?time_continue=10&amp;amp;v=ylDmCWp0_9s&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Sam Tsui&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;i&gt;Sam Tsui is a singer-songwriter who’s been on YouTube since August 2011.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;b&gt;YouTube: Favorite part so far?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;b&gt;Sam Tsui:&lt;/b&gt; It’s incredible to have the face-to-face with YouTube, with Susan [Wojcicki], and all the people who make this platform possible. There’s a lot to learn and a lot to know. … It’s always so amazing that YouTube wants us to come out and hear what we think, give us a heads up on what’s coming and all that good stuff. … Between that and all the fun activities, it’s totally amazing, overwhelming, and a ton of fun.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;b&gt;YouTube: Key takeaway after hearing Susan, Neal and Robert on stage?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;b&gt;Sam Tsui:&lt;/b&gt; [It’s] wonderful to hear how healthy the platform is. The statistics about the number of creators who have over one million subs is growing, and the engagement, and the fact that this is, as ever, the place for the kind of stuff you want to be doing.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;table align=&quot;center&quot; cellpadding=&quot;0&quot; cellspacing=&quot;0&quot; class=&quot;tr-caption-container&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-l_WBmJfoVhE/XMxioB9ktSI/AAAAAAAACMo/wejbx_4YoqIYHl1jkpEk5hLTD-2kPXWLgCLcBGAs/s1600/creatorsummit-natalie.jpg&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;1194&quot; data-original-width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; src=&quot;https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-l_WBmJfoVhE/XMxioB9ktSI/AAAAAAAACMo/wejbx_4YoqIYHl1jkpEk5hLTD-2kPXWLgCLcBGAs/s640/creatorsummit-natalie.jpg&quot; width=&quot;536&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;tr-caption&quot; style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;Natalie and Dennis (Photo by Nesrin Danan)&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=uPbXhKmlQbo&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Natalie &amp;amp; Dennis Show&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;i&gt;Natalie and Dennis got married in December 2017 after six years of dating. Natalie also has her own separate channel called &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=yBSQFws2n04&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Natalies Outlet&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;b&gt;YouTube: Favorite part so far?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;b&gt;Natalie:&lt;/b&gt; It’s such an honor to be in a room full of some of the most powerful people on the Internet. Especially having the speakers come in and talk to you so genuinely, and without a third wall and so real. Sometimes I think we get caught up in the business of YouTube, and it all comes down to the passion.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;b&gt;Dennis:&lt;/b&gt; The hospitality is always so nice. We always have packages when we arrive. We feel cared for.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;b&gt;YouTube: Key takeaway after hearing Susan, Neal and Robert on stage?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;b&gt;Natalie:&lt;/b&gt; Sometimes you don’t really see what they’re doing behind-the-scenes. You just think, “Oh, they represent YouTube.” But they really did show that they’re working on policies. They’re working on making sure as creators, we’re continuing to monetize. It’s nice to see that they’re so caring and they answered real questions, even though [the questions are] kind of hot sometimes.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;table align=&quot;center&quot; cellpadding=&quot;0&quot; cellspacing=&quot;0&quot; class=&quot;tr-caption-container&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-8_XNqqm0yyQ/XMxi2CE5NaI/AAAAAAAACMw/RPyUaoQULUcca-nRjudiKW40fnl9hl3IwCLcBGAs/s1600/creatorsummit_hyunee.jpg&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;667&quot; data-original-width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;426&quot; src=&quot;https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-8_XNqqm0yyQ/XMxi2CE5NaI/AAAAAAAACMw/RPyUaoQULUcca-nRjudiKW40fnl9hl3IwCLcBGAs/s640/creatorsummit_hyunee.jpg&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;tr-caption&quot; style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;Hyunee (Photo by Nesrin Danan)&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=q8b3aIta4CQ&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Hyunee Eats&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;i&gt;Hyunee’s mukbang channel has 1.2 million subscribers, and this is her first year at Creator Summit. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;b&gt;YouTube: Key takeaway after hearing Susan, Neal and Robert on stage?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;b&gt;Hyunee Eats:&lt;/b&gt; We complain a lot about the faults that they have, but knowing that they’re working hard to improve everything and actually seeing them talk to us in person has helped us learn about what they actually do behind-the-scenes. ... They’re like real people, like us.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;table align=&quot;center&quot; cellpadding=&quot;0&quot; cellspacing=&quot;0&quot; class=&quot;tr-caption-container&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-sr4A2PpEwpE/XMxnyaDYPgI/AAAAAAAACNI/DoxS3mgRN5QLZG7CSHnoZW9A6iB1w2-kgCLcBGAs/s1600/LilyHevesh.jpg&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;821&quot; data-original-width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;525&quot; src=&quot;https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-sr4A2PpEwpE/XMxnyaDYPgI/AAAAAAAACNI/DoxS3mgRN5QLZG7CSHnoZW9A6iB1w2-kgCLcBGAs/s640/LilyHevesh.jpg&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;tr-caption&quot; style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;Lily Hevesh (far right) Photo by Alexander Stein&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?time_continue=4&amp;amp;v=18_RjKQICvQ&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Lily Hevesh of Hevesh5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;i&gt;Lily Hevesh has been making domino art videos since 2009. This is also her first Creator Summit!&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;b&gt;YouTube: Favorite part so far?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;b&gt;Lily Hevesh:&lt;/b&gt; I don’t really get the opportunity to meet other people who make videos for a living, so bringing all the top creators in one room is super exciting.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;b&gt;YouTube: Key takeaway after hearing Susan, Neal and Robert on stage?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;b&gt;Lily Hevesh:&lt;/b&gt; Just seeing them in person and hearing them speak — to me, it felt like they really do deeply care about the creators, fans and advertisers. And they’re trying their best to please all of them. While there are lots of issues with the site, they’re working as hard as they can to try and solve them. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;table align=&quot;center&quot; cellpadding=&quot;0&quot; cellspacing=&quot;0&quot; class=&quot;tr-caption-container&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-5oJldN2BZPY/XMxi994gbKI/AAAAAAAACM4/UGrKPoABFvkXJr8ewlaaCf-qjpaCHawewCLcBGAs/s1600/creatorsummit_remi.jpg&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;1250&quot; data-original-width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; src=&quot;https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-5oJldN2BZPY/XMxi994gbKI/AAAAAAAACM4/UGrKPoABFvkXJr8ewlaaCf-qjpaCHawewCLcBGAs/s640/creatorsummit_remi.jpg&quot; width=&quot;512&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;tr-caption&quot; style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;MissRemiAshten (Photo by Nesrin Danan)&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=S5yFL8eZfFo&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;MissRemiAshten&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;i&gt;Remi Cruz is a 23-year-old lifestyle and wellness creator with 2.5 million subscribers. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;b&gt;YouTube: Favorite part so far? &lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;b&gt;MissRemiAshten:&lt;/b&gt; We’re only on day one, and this has been my favorite one, for sure. Getting to see Julie Rice, the co-founder of SoulCycle, and getting to see her interact with Blogilates, who’s one of my favorite YouTubers and one of my really good friends. I feel like they’re two people I look up to so much, and I live by Soulcycle so I genuinely feel like they tailored a lot of stuff to our interests today.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;b&gt;YouTube: Key takeaway after hearing Susan, Neal and Robert on stage? &lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;b&gt;MissRemiAshten:&lt;/b&gt; There are so many things that go on behind the scenes that I don’t even know about. So it’s interesting to hear that. … It’s nice that YouTube has this whole conference for us in general, because no other platform does it. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;i&gt;— The YouTube Team&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;</content><link rel='replies' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://youtube-creators.googleblog.com/feeds/7138659765332299348/comments/default' title='Post Comments'/><link rel='replies' type='text/html' href='http://youtube-creators.googleblog.com/2019/05/creator-summit-what-6-creators-said.html#comment-form' title='0 Comments'/><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://www.blogger.com/feeds/6959495683334200101/posts/default/7138659765332299348'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://www.blogger.com/feeds/6959495683334200101/posts/default/7138659765332299348'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://youtube-creators.googleblog.com/2019/05/creator-summit-what-6-creators-said.html' title='Creator Summit: What 6 creators had to say'/><author><name>YouTube Creators</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/00450486760991148551</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-BC7slkjecRg/XMxfqlnkECI/AAAAAAAACMY/uE9ZHnd8ark_vS2YKecT-q-pxl4Wn8hhACLcBGAs/s72-c/creatorsummit-collage.jpg" height="72" width="72"/><thr:total>0</thr:total></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-6959495683334200101.post-7050269050545094893</id><published>2019-04-30T12:12:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2019-05-20T12:10:27.056-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Addressing creator feedback and an update on my 2019 priorities</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;Dear Creators and Artists,&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;It’s hard to believe it’s only April given all that we’ve already witnessed this year. We’ve seen new creative peaks reached by our global creator community, showing even further that you are the heart of YouTube. But we’ve also faced incredible challenges. And given the scale and impact of YouTube, there’s nothing more important than managing our role as a platform responsibly.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;iframe allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/76WOBUhuFL8&quot; width=&quot;560&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;h3&gt;1. Living up to our responsibility&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;br /&gt;My top priority is responsibility. We’re always balancing maintaining an open platform with managing our community guidelines. But to combat a number of concerning incidents we’ve seen in the last few months, we’ve had to take more aggressive action. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;In February, we &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtube-creators.googleblog.com/2019/02/more-updates-on-our-actions-related-to.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;announced&lt;/a&gt; the suspension of comments on most YouTube videos that feature minors. We did this to protect children from predatory comments (with the exception of a small number of channels that have the manpower needed to actively moderate their comments and take additional steps to protect children). We know how vital comments are to creators. I hear from creators every day how meaningful comments are for engaging with fans, getting feedback, and helping guide future videos. I also know this change impacted so many creators who we know are innocent—from professional creators to young people or their parents who are posting videos. But in the end, that was a trade-off we made because we feel protecting children on our platform should be the most important guiding principle.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The following month, we took unprecedented action in the wake of the Christchurch tragedy. Our teams immediately sprung into action to remove the violative content. To counter the enormous volume of uploaded videos showing violent imagery, we chose to temporarily break some of our processes and features. That meant a number of videos that didn’t actually violate community guidelines, including a small set of news and commentary, were swept up and kept off the platform (until appealed by its owners and reinstated). But given the stakes, it was another trade-off that we felt was necessary.  And with the devastating Sri Lankan attacks, our teams worked around the clock to make sure we removed violative content. In both cases, our systems triggered authoritative news and limited the spread of any hate and misinformation. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;These issues have also been top-of-mind for policy-makers, press, brands, and advertisers, whom I met with on recent trips to Washington and Asia. I updated them all on the steps we’ve taken around responsibility and also praised the extraordinary talents and importance of our creator economy. You’ve helped drive a remarkable transformation in the media landscape—where we’ve gone from a handful of broadcast networks to millions of channels that connect deeply with each and every person. Your videos not only touch lives, but have created new jobs and the next generation of media companies. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-QYGiZb-mTng/XMiW3YZNcrI/AAAAAAAACLs/kCDT1QGLSDgf_Gx-NVXrclQHm6nEa0sUQCLcBGAs/s1600/Wei_Frame6_Neighborhood.jpg&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;950&quot; data-original-width=&quot;1600&quot; height=&quot;380&quot; src=&quot;https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-QYGiZb-mTng/XMiW3YZNcrI/AAAAAAAACLs/kCDT1QGLSDgf_Gx-NVXrclQHm6nEa0sUQCLcBGAs/s640/Wei_Frame6_Neighborhood.jpg&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;h3&gt;2. Support creator and artist success&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Everywhere I go I try to meet with creators. Recently, I sat down with a number of creators in Japan and India and did videos with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/koreagrandma&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Korea Grandma&lt;/a&gt; in Seoul and Prajakta Koli, or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCvCyIiKSCA1fHKSCOKJyjXA&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;MostlySane&lt;/a&gt;, in Mumbai. Back at home, I shared drinks and some honest conversation with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/user/shane&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Shane Dawson&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCucot-Zp428OwkyRm2I7v2Q&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;James Charles&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/user/CollinsKey&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Collins&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/user/devan11art&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Devan Key&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/user/h2h2productions&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Ethan and Hila Klein&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCbAwSkqJ1W_Eg7wr3cp5BUA&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Safiya Nygaard&lt;/a&gt;. It was inspiring to see how all these creators have invested so deeply in YouTube. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-F14JWhFKyfQ/XMiXhp4toaI/AAAAAAAACL4/IZh72BtXoIc78UICfzkDFPsENPQn4H6rQCLcBGAs/s1600/Wei_Frame8_creator_sitdown.jpg&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;950&quot; data-original-width=&quot;1600&quot; height=&quot;380&quot; src=&quot;https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-F14JWhFKyfQ/XMiXhp4toaI/AAAAAAAACL4/IZh72BtXoIc78UICfzkDFPsENPQn4H6rQCLcBGAs/s640/Wei_Frame8_creator_sitdown.jpg&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The feedback I heard from these discussions was especially important. A top issue was wanting more clarity around community guidelines and advertiser friendly policies so there’s more predictability on monetization and our recommendation system. They’re also looking for better representation of creators on trending. They’re frustrated with copyright claims that are less than 10 seconds or incidental. And they say the online harassment from fellow creators is growing and needs to be addressed.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I’d like to address these issues one by one. First, we &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=IhfYlNUL9pE&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;plan&lt;/a&gt; to add more detail to our policies so that creators can make the best decisions on their content. Our Self Certification pilot is a great example of why this is so crucial. With this program, creators can self report how their video complies with ad policies and build up trust that our systems adjust to. This helps creators gain a better understanding of our guidelines and delivers clearer results for them and for advertisers. We’ve rolled out this pilot to over one thousand channels and I’m hopeful we will find a way to make it available to more monetizing channels. And on monetization, we’ll continue to focus on increasing the accuracy of the classifiers representing the advertising friendly guidelines, something we know is important for all creators. Since January, we’ve already improved the precision of the classifier by 25%.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;On the trending tab, we’ve heard it doesn’t seem to reflect what people are watching on the platform and that too many of the same creators show up time and time again. One thing to keep in mind is that trending is meant to show content that a wide range of viewers would find interesting. We are especially careful about the safety of what appears here, so we have filters to make sure we don’t show videos that contain mature content (i.e. language, imagery, etc.), violence, or are otherwise inappropriate, such as disparaging others in the community. Eligible videos are then ranked based on a calculation of their “temperature”—how quickly that video is generating views. But we want to better showcase our creators. Going forward, our goal is to have at least half the videos on trending come from YouTubers (with the remainder coming from music and traditional media), something we’re close to already but will expand on. We also plan to make sure this is a diverse set of creators. And we’ll continue to ramp up our Creator on the Rise and Gaming Creator on the Rise initiatives. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We also heard firsthand that our Manual Claiming system was increasingly being used to claim very short (in some cases one second) content or incidental content like when a creator walks past a store playing a few seconds of music. We were already looking into this issue but hearing this directly from creators was vital. We are exploring improvements in striking the right balance between copyright owners and creators.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Finally, I take it very seriously when creators share stories of experiencing harassment on the platform. While criticism from fellow creators can be constructive, any threats or doxing crosses the line. Such behavior is already prohibited by our policies. But stay tuned as we will do more to discourage this from happening on the platform.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;To help more creators find their audience, we’ve been ramping up our NextUp creator camps, with recent editions in Jakarta and London. And we’re seeing exciting momentum for YouTube around the world, not just for creators but also artists.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-nFOjgvs5iqY/XMiZ1nBBT4I/AAAAAAAACME/OyKWExc0joYCLZPWzl0x9Ntjr7YVYm_EwCLcBGAs/s1600/Wei_Frame15_Creators_highfive.jpg&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;950&quot; data-original-width=&quot;1600&quot; height=&quot;380&quot; src=&quot;https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-nFOjgvs5iqY/XMiZ1nBBT4I/AAAAAAAACME/OyKWExc0joYCLZPWzl0x9Ntjr7YVYm_EwCLcBGAs/s640/Wei_Frame15_Creators_highfive.jpg&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;With the launch of YouTube Music in India, Japan, and Argentina, we’ve witnessed musical artists big and small reach new audiences internationally, and the free, ad-supported streaming app is now available in 43 countries, with more to come.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;But we are also still very concerned about Article 13 (now renamed Article 17) — a part of the Copyright directive that recently passed in the E.U. While we support the rights of copyright holders—YouTube has deals with almost all the music companies and TV broadcasters today—we are concerned about the vague, untested requirements of the new directive. It could create serious limitations for what YouTube creators can upload. This risks lowering the revenue to traditional media and music companies from YouTube and potentially devastating the many European creators who have built their businesses on YouTube. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;While the Directive has passed, there is still time to affect the final implementation to avoid some of the worst unintended consequences. Each E.U. member state now has two years to introduce national laws that are in line with the new rules, which means that the powerful collective voice of creators can still make a major impact.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We must continue to stand up and speak out for open creativity.  Your actions have already led to the most popular &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.change.org/p/european-parliament-stop-the-censorship-machinery-save-the-internet&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Change.org petition&lt;/a&gt; in history and encouraged people to reach across borders. This is not the end of our movement but only the beginning.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;h3&gt;3. Improving communication and engagement&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Personally, and as a company, we are committed to listening to your feedback and concerns. Just like last year, we’ll be making a big push to meet creators where they want to communicate— through social, video, and one-on-one sessions. I plan on sitting down with more creators in 2019, focusing on the issues that are most important to you. Let me know who you’d like to see me meet with - I’m open to suggestions!&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Hopefully, most of you have tried out YouTube Studio Beta, which we’ve built to give creators even more updates and news. It offers a Known Issues bulletin on the dashboard that lists outages, bugs, or issues going on with YouTube, and a new Analytics experience with long-requested metrics like impressions, thumbnail click-through rates, and unique viewers. We&#39;ve also recently improved our support of InfoCards and EndScreens in the new Studio, as well as Comparisons in Analytics. Your feedback has been crucial to these improvements, and more real-time data is coming soon.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Since so many creators have told us that the community guidelines strike system felt inconsistent and confusing, we &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtube-creators.googleblog.com/2019/02/making-our-strikes-system-clear-and.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;updated&lt;/a&gt; our policies to a simpler and more transparent system. Every creator now gets a one-time warning that allows them to learn about our policies before they face penalties on their channel. Each strike, no matter if it comes from the videos, thumbnails, or links, gets the same penalty. On top of adding new mobile and in-product notifications about a strike, our email and desktop notifications will provide more details on which policy was violated. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Like all of you, YouTube is continually adapting to keep up with a fast-changing world. But the one thing that won’t change is the fact that our past, present, and future success starts with our creators. Many of you have been with us since our early days, and have built YouTube into the vibrant community it is today.  And that’s why we’re focused on supporting your growing businesses, both through improving responsibility on the platform and by creating more opportunities for you to engage and build audiences.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-eYjh5Fe72n4/XMiaXDjeGSI/AAAAAAAACMM/WBulmpddq3UJnkKUKSBYs9tkRXyvkoOLQCLcBGAs/s1600/Wei_Frame16_thankyou.jpg&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;950&quot; data-original-width=&quot;1600&quot; height=&quot;380&quot; src=&quot;https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-eYjh5Fe72n4/XMiaXDjeGSI/AAAAAAAACMM/WBulmpddq3UJnkKUKSBYs9tkRXyvkoOLQCLcBGAs/s640/Wei_Frame16_thankyou.jpg&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Being a creator can be rewarding, exhilarating, challenging, and exhausting all at once. But the hard work is worth it. You’re at the cutting edge of culture.Your stories are helping the world to connect and learn. Please continue to share your voice and your feedback with us—it helps us make our platform stronger.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Susan Wojcicki&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='replies' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://youtube-creators.googleblog.com/feeds/7050269050545094893/comments/default' title='Post Comments'/><link rel='replies' type='text/html' href='http://youtube-creators.googleblog.com/2019/04/addressing-creator-feedback-and-update.html#comment-form' title='0 Comments'/><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://www.blogger.com/feeds/6959495683334200101/posts/default/7050269050545094893'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://www.blogger.com/feeds/6959495683334200101/posts/default/7050269050545094893'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://youtube-creators.googleblog.com/2019/04/addressing-creator-feedback-and-update.html' title='Addressing creator feedback and an update on my 2019 priorities'/><author><name>YouTube Creators</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/00450486760991148551</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://img.youtube.com/vi/76WOBUhuFL8/default.jpg" height="72" width="72"/><thr:total>0</thr:total></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-6959495683334200101.post-8005979909916902417</id><published>2019-02-28T10:05:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2019-02-28T10:07:32.806-08:00</updated><title type='text'>More updates on our actions related to the safety of minors on YouTube</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;Dear Creators,&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We know that many of you have been closely following the actions we’re taking to protect young people on YouTube and are as deeply concerned as we are that we get this right. We want to update you on some additional changes we’re making, particularly in regards to comments, building on the efforts &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.google.com/youtube/thread/1805616&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;we shared last week.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We recognize that comments are a core part of the YouTube experience and how you connect with and grow your audience. At the same time, the important steps we’re sharing today are critical for keeping young people safe.  Thank you for your understanding and feedback as we continue our work to protect the YouTube community.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Below is a summary of the main steps we’ve taken to improve child safety on YouTube since our &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.google.com/youtube/thread/1805616&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;update&lt;/a&gt; last Friday:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;h3 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;Disabling comments on videos featuring minors&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Over the past week, we disabled comments from tens of millions of videos that could be subject to predatory behavior. These efforts are focused on videos featuring young minors and we will continue to identify videos at risk over the next few months. Over the next few months, we will be broadening this action to suspend comments on videos featuring young minors and videos featuring older minors that could be at risk of attracting predatory behavior.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;A small number of creators will be able to keep comments enabled on these types of videos. These channels will be required to actively moderate their comments, beyond just using our moderation tools, and demonstrate a low risk of predatory behavior.  We will work with them directly and our goal is to grow this number over time as our ability to catch violative comments continues to improve. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;h3 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;Launching a new comments classifier&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;While we have been removing hundreds of millions of comments for violating our policies, we had been working on an even more effective classifier, that will identify and remove predatory comments. This classifier does not affect the monetization of your video. We accelerated its launch and now have a new comments classifier in place that is more sweeping in scope, and will detect and remove 2X more individual comments.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;h3 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;Taking action on creators who cause egregious harm to the community&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;No form of content that endangers minors is acceptable on YouTube, which is why we have terminated certain channels that attempt to endanger children in any way. Videos encouraging harmful and dangerous challenges targeting any audience are also clearly against our policies. We will continue to take action when creators violate our policies in ways that blatantly harm the broader user and creator community. Please continue to &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.google.com/youtube/answer/2802027&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;flag&lt;/a&gt; these to us.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Thank you for your understanding as we make these changes,&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;i&gt;TeamYouTube&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='replies' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://youtube-creators.googleblog.com/feeds/8005979909916902417/comments/default' title='Post Comments'/><link rel='replies' type='text/html' href='http://youtube-creators.googleblog.com/2019/02/more-updates-on-our-actions-related-to.html#comment-form' title='0 Comments'/><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://www.blogger.com/feeds/6959495683334200101/posts/default/8005979909916902417'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://www.blogger.com/feeds/6959495683334200101/posts/default/8005979909916902417'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://youtube-creators.googleblog.com/2019/02/more-updates-on-our-actions-related-to.html' title='More updates on our actions related to the safety of minors on YouTube'/><author><name>YouTube Creators</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/00450486760991148551</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><thr:total>0</thr:total></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-6959495683334200101.post-7677479451723192930</id><published>2019-02-19T05:00:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2019-02-19T05:00:06.451-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Making our strikes system clear and consistent</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;We’re updating the way we give &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/yt/about/policies/#community-guidelines&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Community Guidelines&lt;/a&gt; strikes to a new, simpler system. We’ve worked with creators to understand what’s working and what’s not, and you told us that consistent enforcement, clear policies, and transparency about the impact of a strike are most important. So we’re introducing more opportunities for everyone to understand our policies, a consistent penalty for each strike, and better notifications. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;iframe allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/zgoF7HpB55g&quot; width=&quot;560&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;h3 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;More opportunities to learn YouTube’s policies&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Although 98% of you never break our Community Guidelines, they are vital to making YouTube a strong community and balancing freedom of expression with the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/yt/about/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;freedom to belong.&lt;/a&gt; That’s why&lt;span style=&quot;background-color: white; color: #545454; font-family: &amp;quot;roboto&amp;quot; , &amp;quot;arial&amp;quot; , sans-serif; font-size: x-small;&quot;&gt;—&lt;/span&gt;from our earliest days&lt;span style=&quot;background-color: white; color: #545454; font-family: &amp;quot;roboto&amp;quot; , &amp;quot;arial&amp;quot; , sans-serif; font-size: x-small;&quot;&gt;—&lt;/span&gt;we’ve relied on a three-strikes system and email notices to give everyone a chance to review and understand what went wrong before they face more severe consequences. And it works: 94% of those who do receive a first strike never get a second one.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We want to give you even more opportunities to learn about our policies, so starting February 25, all channels will receive a one-time warning the first time they post content that crosses the line, with no penalties to their channel except for the removal of that content. This is to make sure everyone takes the time to learn about our Community Guidelines, and then can quickly get back to creating great content and engaging with their audience in a way that complies with our rules.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Along with this new warning, we are also expanding the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/yt/about/policies/#community-guidelines&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;policy resources&lt;/a&gt; available in our help center to give more detail about what behavior will result in a strike. This includes new, detailed examples of the kind of content we commonly see that breaks our rules.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;Consistent strikes across all of YouTube&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We’re also making the penalty for violating our Community Guidelines the same wherever it happens. While most strikes result from videos, our Community Guidelines cover all content on YouTube, including stories, custom thumbnails, or links to other websites included in a video’s description or infocard. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Previously, not all strikes had the same penalty on your channel. For example, first strikes on videos would trigger a 90-day freeze on live streaming, and second strikes would result in a two-week freeze on new video uploads. We heard from many of you that this was confusing and the penalty didn’t match the source of the strike. Now, based on your feedback, all Community Guidelines strikes will have the same penalty:  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;As mentioned, everyone who uploads content to YouTube will now receive a warning the first time their content crosses the line. Although the content will be removed, there will be no other penalty on the channel. There will be only one warning and unlike strikes, the warning will not reset after 90 days. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;ul style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;The first strike will result in a one-week freeze on the ability to upload any new content to YouTube, including live streaming, and other channel activities. Strikes will expire after 90 days.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;The second strike in any 90-day period will result in a two-week freeze on the ability to upload any new content to YouTube.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;The third strike in any 90-day period will result in channel termination.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;h3 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;Transparency about your channel status&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Finally, we always want to make it clear why a strike occurred, what it means for your channel, and the next steps that are available&lt;span style=&quot;background-color: white; color: #545454; font-family: &amp;quot;roboto&amp;quot; , &amp;quot;arial&amp;quot; , sans-serif; font-size: x-small;&quot;&gt;—&lt;/span&gt;including appealing the decision in case you think it was a mistake. To that end, we’re making our email and desktop notifications clearer, and they will provide more details on which policy was violated. We are also adding new mobile and in-product notifications to make sure you have all the important information about a strike available at a glance. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;These updates are part of our ongoing work to make sure that YouTube is the best place to listen, share, and create community through your stories. Our strikes system is an important way for us to help creators and artists understand when they’ve crossed the line by uploading content that undermines that goal, and your feedback has helped to make this system work better for the entire community. We’ll build on this and all the progress we’ve made over the last year by continuing to consult with you as we strengthen enforcement and update our policies. We want to make sure they&#39;re easy to understand and address the needs of the global YouTube community.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;i&gt;— The YouTube Team&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='replies' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://youtube-creators.googleblog.com/feeds/7677479451723192930/comments/default' title='Post Comments'/><link rel='replies' type='text/html' href='http://youtube-creators.googleblog.com/2019/02/making-our-strikes-system-clear-and.html#comment-form' title='0 Comments'/><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://www.blogger.com/feeds/6959495683334200101/posts/default/7677479451723192930'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://www.blogger.com/feeds/6959495683334200101/posts/default/7677479451723192930'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://youtube-creators.googleblog.com/2019/02/making-our-strikes-system-clear-and.html' title='Making our strikes system clear and consistent'/><author><name>YouTube Creators</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/00450486760991148551</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://img.youtube.com/vi/zgoF7HpB55g/default.jpg" height="72" width="72"/><thr:total>0</thr:total></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-6959495683334200101.post-4804335291590277037</id><published>2019-02-05T12:00:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2019-02-05T12:00:02.391-08:00</updated><title type='text'>YouTube in 2019: Looking back and moving forward</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;Dear Creators,&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I’m excited to share some thoughts about 2019 and the year ahead, but first wanted to take a moment and reflect on what was an unprecedented 2018. While we experienced tremendous growth across the platform, it was also a time of some tough growing up.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;First, some milestones that we hit: the channels with over one million subscribers nearly doubled in the last year, and the number of creators earning five or six figures in the last year grew more than 40%. You’re creating the next generation of media companies and we’re thrilled to see how much the YouTube creator economy is thriving.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;table align=&quot;center&quot; cellpadding=&quot;0&quot; cellspacing=&quot;0&quot; class=&quot;tr-caption-container&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-NIz-yHTkioE/XFix1AzuIdI/AAAAAAAACIs/8axVrMxq8X0KN-5Hxfu2aOSe5J1NgwfwQCLcBGAs/s1600/2_colour.jpg&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;563&quot; data-original-width=&quot;1000&quot; src=&quot;https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-NIz-yHTkioE/XFix1AzuIdI/AAAAAAAACIs/8axVrMxq8X0KN-5Hxfu2aOSe5J1NgwfwQCLcBGAs/s1600/2_colour.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;tr-caption&quot; style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;Illustrations by Martina Paukova&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;But one record we definitely didn’t set out to break was the most disliked video on the Internet. Even at home, my kids told me our 2018 Rewind was “cringey.” We hear you that it didn’t accurately show the year’s key moments, nor did it reflect the YouTube you know. We’ll do better to tell our story in 2019. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Last year, we also saw how the bad actions of a few individuals can negatively impact the entire creator ecosystem, and that’s why we put even more focus on responsible growth. We implemented a number of product and policy changes, from information cards on common conspiracies and breaking news shelves from authoritative sources, to consequences for creators who bring harm to that crucial trust you’ve built up with users and advertisers.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;This year, I have three priorities: 1) Supporting creator and artist success; 2) Improving communication and engagement; and 3) Living up to our responsibility. Read on for an update on each.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;iframe allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/C1gTRlAF74Q&quot; width=&quot;560&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;h3 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;1. Supporting creator and artist success&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We know how vital monetization is to creators, and recognize it remains a pain point for many of you. Just as a reminder, we started last year with many of our largest advertisers paused because of brand safety concerns. We worked incredibly hard to build the right systems and tools to make sure advertisers feel confident investing in YouTube, and most are now back. On the creator side, we’ve been improving our classifiers so that we make the right monetization decision for each video. We’ve increased the accuracy of the monetization icon by 40% and are also making it easier for creators to appeal when we make the wrong call. But there’s still more work to do on both of these fronts and we’re committed to getting it right for everyone. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-DaBM9MFQC8w/XFiyo3vpFaI/AAAAAAAACI4/DRthPWof1Ac4SOn37mZHYgJCBlksOZvZQCLcBGAs/s1600/5_colour.jpg&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;563&quot; data-original-width=&quot;1000&quot; src=&quot;https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-DaBM9MFQC8w/XFiyo3vpFaI/AAAAAAAACI4/DRthPWof1Ac4SOn37mZHYgJCBlksOZvZQCLcBGAs/s1600/5_colour.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We’ve also been building new ways for you to make money beyond advertising. We expanded YouTube Music and YouTube Premium and made both available in 29 countries, up from just five at the beginning of 2018. We’ve also added other solutions to help you diversify revenue, including Super Chat, Channel Memberships, Merchandise, and Ticketing. Last quarter, we opened up Merch shelf access to all &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.google.com/youtube/answer/9158148?hl=en&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;eligible&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;creators globally. We also continued to make channel memberships more broadly available, lowering the subscriber threshold from 100,000 to 30,000. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;On the issue of Article 13: A big thank you to all the creators who helped bring attention to the unintended consequences of the proposal—one that threatens the livelihoods of so many creators in Europe and around the world— through your videos, stories, op-eds and shared ideas. You’ve proven to be an influential voice in the debate. Your videos were viewed hundreds of millions of times and a near-record 4.6 million people signed the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.change.org/p/european-parliament-stop-the-censorship-machinery-save-the-internet&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;petition&lt;/a&gt; at Change.org. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-mwdkEHTvox0/XFiy_pUye5I/AAAAAAAACJA/yAO1E5Yo0HU9yQj6b1TY-wC668DMIW-GACLcBGAs/s1600/7_colour.jpg&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;563&quot; data-original-width=&quot;1000&quot; src=&quot;https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-mwdkEHTvox0/XFiy_pUye5I/AAAAAAAACJA/yAO1E5Yo0HU9yQj6b1TY-wC668DMIW-GACLcBGAs/s1600/7_colour.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;That awareness you created was critical, since it was clear to me last year when meeting with policymakers in Strasbourg that many of them had heard from large companies, but lacked an understanding of the European creator economy’s impact and size. I shared with legislators the huge economic benefit you all bring to your home countries. In France alone, we have more than 190 channels with more than 1 million subscriptions, with the number of E.U. channels reaching that milestone up 70% year over year. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The debate around Article 13 remains ongoing. This could be decided in the next few weeks, so please keep speaking out on this critical issue for all YouTube creators.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;h3 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;2. Improving communication and engagement &lt;/h3&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;In 2018, we took steps to communicate better with you. We introduced YouTube Studio, a new home base which will be available to all creators this year, and are constantly adding new features to it. Some of the latest include Known Issues, News widgets, and new metrics like thumbnail click-through rates and Merch options. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Many of you told us you prefer hearing from us through social posts, so we set a goal to be more responsive through those channels. In the last year, we’ve increased our number of responses by 150% and made our response times 50% faster. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-ZcQZAfkzJXE/XFi0REWbvTI/AAAAAAAACJM/gX8Sv2GhRHILIa95VgrQIQwu6wzvFGNpgCLcBGAs/s1600/9_colour.jpg&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;563&quot; data-original-width=&quot;1000&quot; src=&quot;https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-ZcQZAfkzJXE/XFi0REWbvTI/AAAAAAAACJM/gX8Sv2GhRHILIa95VgrQIQwu6wzvFGNpgCLcBGAs/s1600/9_colour.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;But we also love meeting you in person. In 2018, we held more than 480 events with over 18,000 creators—from Fanfests, to Creator Summits, to workshops. We even had the opportunity to sit down with some of you for your channels. If you haven’t already seen it, I highly recommend Luisito’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=sGBr0Bl8y2U&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;chat&lt;/a&gt; with our chief product officer Neal Mohan. Watch this space, as we will invest even more in communication this year.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;And it’s the engagement between creators and viewers that truly sets YouTube apart  from traditional media like TV.  Our goal is to grow this in new ways. One addition last year was the Premieres feature that allows creators to generate a shared experience with fans around new videos. Creators like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCi9cDo6239RAzPpBZO9y5SA&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Lele Pons&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC78cxCAcp7JfQPgKxYdyGrg&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Emma Chamberlain&lt;/a&gt; used Premieres on their way to racking up millions of views. At its peak, Ariana Grande’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=gl1aHhXnN1k&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;“thank u, next”&lt;/a&gt; had 829,000 unique viewers watching and interacting simultaneously, making this video the biggest Premiere ever on YouTube. I’m sure we’ll see even more of these moments in 2019.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-TRcLJEkEPTQ/XFi0kOA-TbI/AAAAAAAACJU/paFZ33CHgmY7-k432RYN4z-7UrpGHI9wQCLcBGAs/s1600/1_emma.jpg&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;563&quot; data-original-width=&quot;1000&quot; src=&quot;https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-TRcLJEkEPTQ/XFi0kOA-TbI/AAAAAAAACJU/paFZ33CHgmY7-k432RYN4z-7UrpGHI9wQCLcBGAs/s1600/1_emma.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We also recently made Stories available to all eligible creators with more than 10,000 subscribers, and opened up Community posts to all channels with more than 1,000 subscribers. Billions of comments were made on YouTube in 2018, and for a better experience, we improved comment ranking, added @mentions in comments and introduced a feature where creators can hold inappropriate comments for review in 10 languages. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;h3 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;3. Living up to our responsibility&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;It is my personal mission to ensure that we&#39;re living up to our responsibilities to our users, as well as to you, the creator community. We made a lot of improvements here in 2018 but recognize there’s still much more to do. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;First, more and more people are coming to YouTube for news. Not only have we made changes to ensure they’re having a good experience when they visit, but we’ve prioritized supporting the journalism community. One key effort is the Google News Initiative YouTube innovation funding program, &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtube.googleblog.com/2018/07/building-better-news-experience-on.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;announced&lt;/a&gt; last summer.  Hundreds of organizations submitted proposals and we awarded grants to &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtube.googleblog.com/2018/12/gni-youtube-innovation-funding.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;87 recipients&lt;/a&gt; to help them build up their video capabilities. We also expanded our breaking news shelf and top news shelves to 31 countries and look forward to expanding them even further this year. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Another focus was on more quickly and effectively removing the content that violates our Community Guidelines, as shown in our &lt;a href=&quot;https://transparencyreport.google.com/youtube-policy/removals&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;report&lt;/a&gt;. But we know we need to more clearly communicate about the policies that impact you. Most recently we &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.google.com/youtube/thread/1063345?hl=en&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;updated guidance&lt;/a&gt; to creators about our policies on custom thumbnails, external links, and pranks and challenges. And our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCGg-UqjRgzhYDPJMr-9HXCg&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Creator Insider&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;channel covered how we address &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VWAdzMmNLy0&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;profanity&lt;/a&gt;. Look for more of these types of updates in the months to come. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-hckoWczLnO4/XFi01lbEyvI/AAAAAAAACJc/YlSwtM5w8-Q5NIcQLQoknt5LbiTHElPuACLcBGAs/s1600/13_colour.jpg&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;563&quot; data-original-width=&quot;1000&quot; src=&quot;https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-hckoWczLnO4/XFi01lbEyvI/AAAAAAAACJc/YlSwtM5w8-Q5NIcQLQoknt5LbiTHElPuACLcBGAs/s1600/13_colour.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;A major highlight for me in 2018 was watching how creators used YouTube as a way to give back. More than 40 creators worked together last year to benefit eight charities with &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtube-creators.googleblog.com/2018/08/introducing-youtube-giving-new-tools.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;YouTube Giving&lt;/a&gt;, which included our first annual &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtube.googleblog.com/2018/11/the-giving-season-is-upon-us.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;#YouTubeGiving Week&lt;/a&gt; program in November. YouTuber Matpat and Stephanie of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/user/MatthewPatrick13&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;The Game Theorists&lt;/a&gt; helped us kick it off with a special livestream and Matpat said it was “one of the highlights of [his] seven years YouTubing.” &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Finally, we’ve seen the incredible momentum around learning and education on YouTube and we’re investing to support its growth. Last year, we introduced the Learning Fund and awarded grants to 65 creators chosen from more than 1,000 submissions. Recipients will be developing multi-session learning content for YouTube, so stay tuned for more details on when that will roll out. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-wJBB4AZTSII/XFi1C1ivMJI/AAAAAAAACJg/X4hBZsyrMTs9I6RDgaARbKPK9pvA9XsHACLcBGAs/s1600/14_colour.jpg&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;563&quot; data-original-width=&quot;1000&quot; src=&quot;https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-wJBB4AZTSII/XFi1C1ivMJI/AAAAAAAACJg/X4hBZsyrMTs9I6RDgaARbKPK9pvA9XsHACLcBGAs/s1600/14_colour.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Also, keep an eye out for our first EduCon of 2019, which is coming up in the U.K. in February. We hosted four EduCon conferences around the world in 2018, engaging with nearly 450 creators in the U.S., Mexico, Brazil and India.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Personally, I depended on the learning content more times than I can count. With YouTube’s incredibly busy year, I turned to the platform for some of my workouts and have a lot of appreciation for the yoga YouTubers. The work of all educational creators has brought incredible enrichment to so many lives in so many ways.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;All in all, 2018 was a year of change, challenges, and opportunity. This year will undoubtedly be more of the same. Keep the feedback coming—even though sometimes it’s hard to read—it’s your questions and comments that help make YouTube the very best video community for all of us. The creator community is what inspires me daily and makes this platform so special...so thank you again.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;i&gt;Susan Wojcicki, CEO of YouTube&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='replies' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://youtube-creators.googleblog.com/feeds/4804335291590277037/comments/default' title='Post Comments'/><link rel='replies' type='text/html' href='http://youtube-creators.googleblog.com/2019/02/youtube-in-2019-looking-back-and-moving.html#comment-form' title='21 Comments'/><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://www.blogger.com/feeds/6959495683334200101/posts/default/4804335291590277037'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://www.blogger.com/feeds/6959495683334200101/posts/default/4804335291590277037'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://youtube-creators.googleblog.com/2019/02/youtube-in-2019-looking-back-and-moving.html' title='YouTube in 2019: Looking back and moving forward'/><author><name>YouTube Creators</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/00450486760991148551</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-NIz-yHTkioE/XFix1AzuIdI/AAAAAAAACIs/8axVrMxq8X0KN-5Hxfu2aOSe5J1NgwfwQCLcBGAs/s72-c/2_colour.jpg" height="72" width="72"/><thr:total>21</thr:total></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-6959495683334200101.post-6024266860067629757</id><published>2018-11-29T09:00:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2018-11-29T09:00:00.389-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Introducing more ways to share your Stories on YouTube</title><content type='html'>&lt;br /&gt;As a creator, you&#39;re always looking to strengthen your relationship with your audience. You bring them along on your travels, give them a backstage pass to one of your videos,  or even a sneak peek at your upcoming video. Through testing the Stories format with a small group of you over the past year, we’ve seen you do just that, from FashionbyAlly giving updates on what’s coming next, to Colin and Samir bringing their fans into the creative process. We applied feedback that we got from you to build a product specifically designed with you, the YouTube creator, in mind. And starting today, we are excited to announce that we are rolling out YouTube Stories to all eligible creators with 10K+ subscribers.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;iframe allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/qM-dOYiyvCA&quot; width=&quot;560&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Creating with Stories is lightweight, easy, and fun. Stories will have the fun creation tools that you know and love. You can add text, music, filters, YouTubey stickers, and more to make your story uniquely you! To create a story, just open the YouTube mobile app, tap on the video camera icon, and select &quot;Create Story.&quot;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We’ve also added comments to Stories, so the entire community can be a part of the conversation. Your fans can comment, thumbs up and thumbs down comments, and you can heart comments. And all of the comment moderation tools that are available on video uploads will also be available on Stories. You can now also respond directly to a fan comment with a photo or video for the entire community to see! &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;table align=&quot;center&quot; cellpadding=&quot;0&quot; cellspacing=&quot;0&quot; class=&quot;tr-caption-container&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-hkrt9XKiMjk/W_9AQYANpaI/AAAAAAAACIM/CYSuSVkcgZAsDSrggBXmitStCE5FrnNUACLcBGAs/s1600/two%2Bphones_stories.png&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;1048&quot; data-original-width=&quot;1280&quot; height=&quot;524&quot; src=&quot;https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-hkrt9XKiMjk/W_9AQYANpaI/AAAAAAAACIM/CYSuSVkcgZAsDSrggBXmitStCE5FrnNUACLcBGAs/s640/two%2Bphones_stories.png&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;tr-caption&quot; style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;Images via &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCamLstJyCa-t5gfZegxsFMw&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Colin and Samir&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Once posted, Stories are available in the mobile app for 7 days to ensure that your fans have a chance to see it. Stories may show up to both subscribers on the Subscriptions tab and non-subscribers on Home and in the Up Next list below videos. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We’re excited to see how you continue to use Stories to reach out to your community. Give it a try today! &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;i&gt;Todd Sherman, Product Lead for YouTube Stories&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;</content><link rel='replies' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://youtube-creators.googleblog.com/feeds/6024266860067629757/comments/default' title='Post Comments'/><link rel='replies' type='text/html' href='http://youtube-creators.googleblog.com/2018/11/introducing-more-ways-to-share-your.html#comment-form' title='0 Comments'/><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://www.blogger.com/feeds/6959495683334200101/posts/default/6024266860067629757'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://www.blogger.com/feeds/6959495683334200101/posts/default/6024266860067629757'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://youtube-creators.googleblog.com/2018/11/introducing-more-ways-to-share-your.html' title='Introducing more ways to share your Stories on YouTube'/><author><name>YouTube Creators</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/00450486760991148551</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://img.youtube.com/vi/qM-dOYiyvCA/default.jpg" height="72" width="72"/><thr:total>0</thr:total></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-6959495683334200101.post-5077099391598959349</id><published>2018-11-12T10:17:00.003-08:00</published><updated>2018-11-13T11:31:59.166-08:00</updated><title type='text'>New ways to create and watch VR videos</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;VR videos deliver a powerful way to share and experience the world. From going behind the curtain with&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=tGzF9yawei4&amp;amp;t=316s&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp;Cirque du Soleil&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;nbsp;to&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ecajlIKwlCg&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;diving into iconic pieces of art&lt;/a&gt;, to a&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=mI8ELfmmG0w&amp;amp;feature=youtu.be&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;behind-the-scenes studio tour&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;with a TV super star, you can transport your viewers to experience moments as if they’re actually there.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We’ve heard that you want to make and see even more immersive videos on YouTube. That’s why we’re continuing to expand the ways anyone can create and watch VR content.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;h3 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;More ways to watch YouTube VR&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;br /&gt;With all the great content that’s available on YouTube today, we want to continue our effort to bring the YouTube VR app to everyone with a VR headset. Starting today, the app will be available on Oculus Go headsets via the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.oculus.com/experiences/go/1458129140982015/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Oculus Store&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;h3 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;Making it easier to create VR180 content&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Last year we introduced VR180, a new video format that focuses on what’s in front of the camera while delivering a 3D effect in a VR headset. By focusing only on the 180-degree view of what’s in front of the camera, it made VR video production easier for creators like you, encouraging&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLU8wpH_Lfhmu_kk955BFwvV0yT0PEcenA&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;more VR videos&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;than ever before.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Since then we’ve introduced new tools to make this type of video creation even easier. We launched the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://vr.google.com/vr180/apps/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;VR180 Creator Tool&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;that makes it faster to process footage, add metadata and publish. The tool is available on MacOS, Linux and now on Windows.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;With the latest&lt;a href=&quot;https://theblog.adobe.com/creative-editorial-with-faster-workflows/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp;editing tools&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;from Adobe, it’s also significantly easier for you to edit, add effects and publish your content. And with new VR180 capable cameras from&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kandaovr.com/en/qoocam/#/overview?keywords=qoocam&amp;amp;camp=1525110401&amp;amp;adgroup=56808458325&amp;amp;placement=&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Kandao&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kandaovr.com/en/qoocam/#/overview?keywords=qoocam&amp;amp;camp=1525110401&amp;amp;adgroup=56808458325&amp;amp;placement=&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Vuze&lt;/a&gt;, you now have more options for capturing VR180 to complement cameras from&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.z-cam.com/180-vr-camera-k1-pro/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Z-Cam&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lenovo.com/us/en/daydreamvr/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Lenovo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;h3 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;Creating more immersive VR videos&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Spatial audio can help make&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=iCIaNFr2Nfg&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;haunted houses more scary&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and imaginary&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8ieIar09dRk&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;video game worlds&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;more real. That’s because it matches realistic sounds and picture together for a more immersive experience. We’ve recently added support for head-locked audio, which means that you can add narration and background music that will sound the same no matter where you look.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;VR videos unlock a world of experiences. With new and easier ways to create and watch VR content, we look forward to seeing what stories you tell, locations you transport viewers to and experiences you uncover.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;i&gt;Posted by Erin Teague, VR Product Lead, who recently watched&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9GlIfC8UlXw&amp;amp;feature=youtu.be&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&quot;Alvin Ailey&#39;s Judith Jamison Speaks on Cry in VR180 | Black Girls Rock!&quot;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='replies' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://youtube-creators.googleblog.com/feeds/5077099391598959349/comments/default' title='Post Comments'/><link rel='replies' type='text/html' href='http://youtube-creators.googleblog.com/2018/11/new-ways-to-create-and-watch-vr-videos.html#comment-form' title='1 Comments'/><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://www.blogger.com/feeds/6959495683334200101/posts/default/5077099391598959349'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://www.blogger.com/feeds/6959495683334200101/posts/default/5077099391598959349'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://youtube-creators.googleblog.com/2018/11/new-ways-to-create-and-watch-vr-videos.html' title='New ways to create and watch VR videos'/><author><name>YouTube Creators</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/00450486760991148551</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><thr:total>1</thr:total></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-6959495683334200101.post-7007578418434291414</id><published>2018-11-12T03:26:00.003-08:00</published><updated>2018-11-12T03:30:43.067-08:00</updated><title type='text'>The Potential Unintended Consequences of Article 13</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;This op-ed originally appeared in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ft.com/content/266e6c2a-e42e-11e8-a8a0-99b2e340ffeb&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Financial Times&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Creativity has long been a guiding force in my life, which is why I jumped at the opportunity to be YouTube’s chief executive nearly five years ago.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Creators have used YouTube to share their voices, inspire their fans, and build their livelihoods. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCsXVk37bltHxD1rDPwtNM8Q&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Kurzgesagt — In a Nutshell&lt;/a&gt; recently became the number one channel in Germany by creating videos that help others fall in love with science. Artists like Dua Lipa and Ed Sheeran reached fans on YouTube long before they were discovered by a label. And acclaimed musicians like Elton John have used our site to breathe new life into iconic songs.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We have worked hard to ensure creators and artists are fairly compensated for their work. In the last year, YouTube paid content owners across the EU €800m. We have also paid the global music industry more than €1.5bn from advert-generated revenue alone.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;However, this creator economy is under threat from a section of the EU’s efforts to revise its copyright directive, known as &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ft.com/content/0675de12-b4fe-11e8-bbc3-ccd7de085ffe&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;article 13&lt;/a&gt;, which holds internet companies directly responsible for any copyright infringement in the content shared on their platform.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;While we support the goals of article 13, the European Parliament’s current proposal will create unintended consequences that will have a profound impact on the livelihoods of hundreds of thousands of people.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The parliament’s approach is unrealistic in many cases because copyright owners often disagree over who owns what rights. If the owners cannot agree, it is impossible to expect the open platforms that host this content to make the correct rights decisions.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Take the global music hit “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=kJQP7kiw5Fk&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Despacito&lt;/a&gt;”. This video contains multiple copyrights, ranging from sound recording to publishing rights. Although YouTube has agreements with multiple entities to license and pay for the video, some of the rights holders remain unknown. That uncertainty means we might have to block videos like this to avoid liability under article 13. Multiply that risk with the scale of YouTube, where more than 400 hours of video are uploaded every minute, and the potential liabilities could be so large that no company could take on such a financial risk.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We have already taken steps to address copyright infringement by developing technology, like our Content ID programme, to help rights holders manage their copyrights and earn money automatically. More than 98 per cent of copyright management on YouTube takes place through Content ID. To date, we have used the system to pay rights holders more than €2.5bn for third party use of their content. We believe Content ID provides the best solution for managing rights on a global scale.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The consequences of article 13 go beyond financial losses. EU residents are at risk of being cut off from videos that, in just the last month, they viewed more than 90bn times. Those videos come from around the world, including more than 35m EU channels, and they include language classes and science tutorials as well as music videos.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We welcome the chance to work with policymakers and the industry to develop a solution within article 13 that protects rights holders while also allowing the creative economy to thrive. This could include more comprehensive licensing agreements, collaboration with rights holders to identify who owns what, and smart rights management technology, similar to Content ID.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Platforms that follow these rules, and make a good effort to help rights holders identify their content, shouldn’t be held directly liable for every single piece of content that a user uploads. We ask policymakers to find a solution that protects rights holders and creators alike, and listen to the growing number of EU voices, including some member countries, who agree there’s a better way forward.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;Susan Wojcicki, CEO of YouTube&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='replies' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://youtube-creators.googleblog.com/feeds/7007578418434291414/comments/default' title='Post Comments'/><link rel='replies' type='text/html' href='http://youtube-creators.googleblog.com/2018/11/i-support-goals-of-article-13-i-also.html#comment-form' title='44 Comments'/><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://www.blogger.com/feeds/6959495683334200101/posts/default/7007578418434291414'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://www.blogger.com/feeds/6959495683334200101/posts/default/7007578418434291414'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://youtube-creators.googleblog.com/2018/11/i-support-goals-of-article-13-i-also.html' title='The Potential Unintended Consequences of Article 13'/><author><name>YouTube Creators</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/00450486760991148551</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><thr:total>44</thr:total></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-6959495683334200101.post-8856035538557174174</id><published>2018-10-22T09:00:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2018-10-25T08:33:45.716-07:00</updated><title type='text'>A Final Update on Our Priorities for 2018</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;Dear Creators,&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Since 2005, YouTube has transformed from a single video at the zoo to a global video library where billions of people turn to each day for knowledge, creativity and connection. Today, YouTube is a diverse community of creators who are building the next generation of media companies and drawing fans from every corner of the world. You are making history and changing the way people watch video, engage with each other and share their voice. I feel honored to help you do this, and I continue to be inspired by what I see.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;In the last year, the number of channels with over 1 million subscribers has increased by 75%. Each month, more than one billion fans come to YouTube to be part of music culture and discover new songs and artists. Building on that momentum, we’ve expanded YouTube Music to the UK, Ireland, Germany, Austria, France, Italy, Spain, Sweden, Norway, Finland, Russia, Canada, Denmark, Belgium, the Netherlands, Luxembourg and Brazil. We also rolled out three new stories on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=QIz5MHKV1nk&amp;amp;feature=youtu.be&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Janelle Monáe&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=qZ9hBdgC4lo&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;J Balvin&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ZYkvxtriIrI&amp;amp;feature=youtu.be&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Shawn Mendes&lt;/a&gt; in our YouTube Artist Spotlight series over the last few months. And we launched 13 YouTube Originals in the last quarter, including three in Germany and two in France. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;All of this is possible because of the creative economy powered by you. However, this growing creative economy is at risk, as the EU Parliament &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.independent.co.uk/life-style/gadgets-and-tech/news/eu-parliament-copyright-memes-latest-vote-internet-article-11-13-a8534121.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;voted on Article 13, copyright legislation&lt;/a&gt; that could drastically change the internet that you see today. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Article 13 as written threatens to shut down the ability of millions of people -- from creators like you to everyday users -- to upload content to platforms like YouTube. And it threatens to block users in the EU from viewing content that is already live on the channels of creators everywhere. This includes YouTube’s incredible video library of educational content, such as language classes, physics tutorials and other how-to’s.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;This legislation poses a threat to both your livelihood and your ability to share your voice with the world. And, if implemented as proposed, Article 13 threatens hundreds of thousands of jobs, European creators, businesses, artists and everyone they employ. The proposal could force platforms, like YouTube, to allow only content from a small number of large companies. It would be too risky for platforms to host content from smaller original content creators, because the platforms would now be directly liable for that content.&amp;nbsp; We realize the importance of all rights holders being fairly compensated, which is why we built Content ID and a platform to pay out all types of content owners. But the unintended consequences of article 13 will put this ecosystem at risk.&amp;nbsp; We are committed to working with the industry to find a better way.&amp;nbsp; This language could be finalized by the end of the year, so it’s important to speak up now.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Please take a moment to &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtube.com/yt/saveyourinternet&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;learn more&lt;/a&gt; about how it could affect your channel and take action immediately. Tell the world through social media (#SaveYourInternet) and your channel why the creator economy is important and how this legislation will impact you.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Please read on for an update on our priorities for 2018.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;h3 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;Communication &amp;amp; Transparency&lt;/h3&gt;As I’ve written to you before, we’ve made a conscious effort to communicate with you more in the place where your conversations are taking place--social and video. Based on your feedback, we’ve also increased the number of product updates or “heads up” messages regarding changes to YouTube, including smaller tests or experiments, on our @TeamYouTube handle and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCGg-UqjRgzhYDPJMr-9HXCg&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Creator Insider channel&lt;/a&gt;. And we continue to share helpful tutorials and inspiring creator stories on our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCkRfArvrzheW2E7b6SVT7vQ&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;YouTube Creators channel&lt;/a&gt;, formerly the Creator Academy channel. We’re working to increase these efforts. I’m posting &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=sWXDNPLlovE&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;more videos&lt;/a&gt; to my own channel and the Creator Insider channel just posted their 100th video!&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We’ve heard that you want communication from us in a simplified way and in one central location. To that point, we launched &lt;a href=&quot;https://studio.youtube.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;YouTube Studio&lt;/a&gt;, the new one-stop shop for platform news and product updates. This is the primary place for getting YouTube-related information, such as announcements about new features, creator academy videos and Creator Insider weekly news flashes. This easy-to-view dashboard is THE place you can go to find the latest news and will be the new homepage for all creators by end of the year.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Finally, our leadership continues to meet face-to-face with creators around the world. Robert Kyncl and Neal Mohan spoke to creators from across Europe, the Middle East and Africa at the Creator Summit in Berlin. Robert continued his series of Creator Interviews &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=p8w7SheU5qs&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;with Caspar Lee in Berlin&lt;/a&gt; and Gautam Anand, Managing Director of YouTube APAC, sat down with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=KL3n5z-KKDY&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Korean creator Dotty in Seoul&lt;/a&gt;. We saw incredible turn out at our Creator Summit in Seoul, with creators from across Asia Pacific, and, we look forward to hosting Latin American creators at our final 2018 Creator Summit in November.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;h3 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;Helping you succeed&lt;/h3&gt;Monetization is the heart of your business. To that end, we released an update to our monetization systems this quarter, which improved the accuracy of monetization icons by 10%.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;In my last letter, I talked about our pilot to test a new video upload flow that asks creators to provide specific information about what’s in their video as it relates to our advertiser-friendly guidelines. Most creators in the pilot were able to accurately represent the content in their video, and it is providing more transparency to creators in terms of what type of content is suitable for ads. We hope to offer self certification to more creators before end of year and plan to expand broadly in early 2019.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;This summer, we announced Channel Memberships, and since then, we’ve seen thousands of creators take advantage of this feature. For instance, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCcXhhVwCT6_WqjkEniejRJQ/join&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Wintergatan&lt;/a&gt;, creator of the Marble Machine, grew his revenue by more than 50% since adding channel memberships and is using it to fund his next generation Marble Machine and a World Tour. Gaming creator &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC7_YxT-KID8kRbqZo7MyscQ/join&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Markiplier&lt;/a&gt; increased his revenue by 20% and Comedy creator &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/user/mikefalzone/join&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Mike Falzone&lt;/a&gt; tripled his YouTube revenue. We’ve also seen creators use Memberships to support creative endeavours, such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/user/tristargymcanada/join&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;TriStar Gym&lt;/a&gt; offering exclusive Brazilian Jiu Jitsu technique videos and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/user/fearedse/join&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Ola Englund&lt;/a&gt; offering guitar lessons online to members. Because of this success, we&#39;re accelerating the roll-out of memberships to more channels and lowering the subscriber threshold from 100,000 to 50,000 subscribers. We plan to expand memberships to even more of you in the months to come.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Over the past few weeks, we&#39;ve hosted three special editions of our &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtube-creators.googleblog.com/2018/09/meet-creators-heading-to-three-special.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;NextUp&lt;/a&gt; camps designed to support up-and-coming Black, Latino and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.standard.co.uk/tech/women-to-watch-youtube-space-london-a3936296.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;women creators&lt;/a&gt;. We received more applications for this round than any other before it. If you missed your chance to apply this time, please stay tuned for the next round. We are hosting two more in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil and St. Petersburg, Russia and plan to announce more in the coming months.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;h3 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;Giving people more ways to engage&lt;/h3&gt;Since &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Wbi_Ic1DDwQ&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;we announced Premieres&lt;/a&gt; this summer, creators have been using this new feature to generate more views, more engagement and more revenue for their channel. For instance, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/user/twentyonepilots&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Twenty One Pilots&lt;/a&gt; premiered their new video &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/8mn-FFjIbo8&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;My Blood&lt;/a&gt; to more than 75,000 fans who watched it together and engaged over live chat and comments. One of our top gaming creators, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/user/theRadBrad&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;TheRadBrad&lt;/a&gt;, tried it out and told his fans in his live chat that “it was one of the coolest experiences in my 8 years on YouTube.” And &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCXuqSBlHAE6Xw-yeJA0Tunw&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Linus Tech Tips’&lt;/a&gt; premiere of his &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=5HNnXJMJkY0&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;recent tech reviews&lt;/a&gt; was one of his best performing videos. I’m happy to announce that premieres is now available to all creators.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We recently introduced &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtube-creators.googleblog.com/2018/08/introducing-youtube-giving-new-tools.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;YouTube Giving&lt;/a&gt;, a suite of features that allow creators and nonprofits to raise funds for causes they care about directly on YouTube videos and live streams. While these features are currently in beta, we’ve seen creators use them to create inspiring impact. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7xkh30Hb42Y&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Hope for Paws&lt;/a&gt; raised over $100,000 in the first 10 days, and over 12 gaming creators have teamed up with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?time_continue=1&amp;amp;v=NGQ2Zhrkk4o&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;St. Jude Children’s Research Hospital&lt;/a&gt; to raise over $125,000 throughout Childhood Cancer Awareness Month. Our hope is to expand these features soon to more creators so that they can give back and support causes they care about.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Finally, we’re building a stronger gaming community on YouTube with features, such as our new &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/gaming&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Gaming Destination&lt;/a&gt;, Gaming Creator on the Rise and dedicated pages for over 80,000 games. We’ll also be retiring the standalone gaming app next year. We know this change impacts a lot of you, but it will allow gaming creators to have greater access to fans while still providing a unique gaming experience.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;h3 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;Tightening and enforcing our policies&lt;/h3&gt;One of our biggest priorities from a policy perspective has been investing in the news experience on YouTube and tackling misinformation. In close collaboration with many of our news partners, we&#39;ve rolled out a number of changes to address them. For example, we have worked to make credible sources more readily available to users and rolled out &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.google.com/youtube/answer/9057101&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;breaking news and top news&lt;/a&gt; shelves in 23 countries. We also hosted the first YouTube News working group meeting at our headquarters and used this opportunity to listen to news organizations, academics, and creators on how we can improve news on the platform. Finally, we’re supporting journalism with technology that allows news to thrive, including an innovation fund to help news organizations sustainably build their video capabilities. We know we have more to do to combat misinformation, and we will continue to invest in innovative solutions to address this.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We also continue to provide updates to our YouTube Community Guidelines enforcement report, which you can &lt;a href=&quot;https://transparencyreport.google.com/youtube-policy/overview&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;read here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;h3 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;Learning and education&lt;/h3&gt;Learning is one of the best parts of YouTube. In recent months, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/07/31/books/booktubers-youtube.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;BookTubers&lt;/a&gt; came together for their annual &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCZhmQgR4l0MMisH-OGO729Q&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;BookTubeAThon&lt;/a&gt;, during which creators read books, shared their thoughts via their channels and inspired people around the world to do the same. We also saw &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wsj.com/articles/quiet-im-cramming-for-finalsby-watching-someone-else-study-1528045886&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;“Study with me”&lt;/a&gt; videos gain popularity--&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCc1tG1M1qP4IE6AQLXXWyww?mod=article_inline&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;motivating users&lt;/a&gt; to persevere through their own study sessions. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We’re committed to empowering both the creators who want to share their knowledge with the world and the users who come to our platform to learn--from home improvements to the basics of physics to grammar lessons. Today I’m happy to announce we’re investing $20 million in YouTube Learning, an initiative to support education focused creators and expert organizations that create and curate high quality learning content on YouTube. Part of this investment includes a Learning Fund to support creators who want to build multi-session learning content for YouTube. If you’re interested in this program, &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSeUTXdkXpUP9Mv__uAi925nAQXGz7TRJCoPDT7-L3PRqkGK6w/viewform&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;please fill out this form&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;As part of efforts to support creators who are sharing their knowledge on the platform, we also launched &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCdxpofrI-dO6oYfsqHDHphw&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Learning&lt;/a&gt;, a new channel of curated tutorials, DIY videos, skill-based playlists, and other high-quality educational content from a range of creators. And we hosted three YouTube EduCon gatherings in Los Angeles, Mexico City and Rio de Janeiro. These conferences were great opportunities for Edutubers to network and learn new skills, and we’re planning to hold more conferences in new places in the upcoming year. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;At YouTube, we hope to give back. We’ve worked with Lily Singh to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=t_RbKWvHaTM&amp;amp;feature=youtu.be&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;support girls’ education&lt;/a&gt; and fight violence against children, and we teamed up with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ErW-0LhR1Fs&amp;amp;feature=youtu.be&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Priyanka Chopra&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/Yt77js8T5SQ&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;BB Ki Vines&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/4XoP44U3H8s&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;MostlySane&lt;/a&gt; to encourage girls’ literacy and education around the world. Please take a moment to watch and support theses causes.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Thank you for making YouTube an incredible source of creativity, knowledge and inspiration. As always, keep the feedback coming. I’m listening.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;i&gt;Susan Wojcicki,&amp;nbsp;CEO of YouTube&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='replies' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://youtube-creators.googleblog.com/feeds/8856035538557174174/comments/default' title='Post Comments'/><link rel='replies' type='text/html' href='http://youtube-creators.googleblog.com/2018/10/a-final-update-on-our-priorities-for.html#comment-form' title='280 Comments'/><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://www.blogger.com/feeds/6959495683334200101/posts/default/8856035538557174174'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://www.blogger.com/feeds/6959495683334200101/posts/default/8856035538557174174'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://youtube-creators.googleblog.com/2018/10/a-final-update-on-our-priorities-for.html' title='A Final Update on Our Priorities for 2018'/><author><name>YouTube Creators</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/00450486760991148551</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><thr:total>280</thr:total></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-6959495683334200101.post-8425078597468727884</id><published>2018-09-18T09:36:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2018-09-18T09:36:00.824-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Gaming gets a new home on YouTube</title><content type='html'>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;Cross-posted from the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://youtube.googleblog.com/2018/09/gaming-gets-new-home-on-youtube.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Official YouTube Blog&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;YouTube is where the world watches gaming. More than 200 million of you come to YouTube every single day to watch gaming videos and streams. That’s like the entire country of Brazil heading to YouTube daily. And that’s because of you, the community of gamers and creators who have turned YouTube into the gaming video platform it is today. From mobile gaming to strategy guides, Let’s Plays to Esports and charity live streams, you’ve created a place for everyone, from hard core to casual gamers. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-19EpHD6HTM4/W5__l36CukI/AAAAAAAACHU/f6MsqFqaVjQpF2TpSYd8A0umprf8TVZhwCLcBGAs/s1600/YT_Gaming_Infographic_17Sept_EN-US.png&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;1600&quot; data-original-width=&quot;546&quot; src=&quot;https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-19EpHD6HTM4/W5__l36CukI/AAAAAAAACHU/f6MsqFqaVjQpF2TpSYd8A0umprf8TVZhwCLcBGAs/s1600/YT_Gaming_Infographic_17Sept_EN-US.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We’re always working to make the gaming experience on YouTube better. Over the past few years we’ve focused on building tools and experiences that the gaming community has been asking for. That’s why in 2015, we launched &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtube.googleblog.com/2015/06/a-youtube-built-for-gamers.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;YouTube Gaming&lt;/a&gt;, a standalone app for gamers where we tested new features like Game Pages for better discoverability, Super Chat and Channel Memberships to help fans show support for their favorite creators, Dark Theme and even a new live streaming platform based on the gaming community’s feedback. The response to these features has been so positive that we brought them over from the YouTube Gaming app to the main YouTube experience. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Today, we’re launching a new Gaming destination to give gamers a home on YouTube! You can find the new YouTube Gaming destination at &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtube.com/gaming&quot;&gt;youtube.com/gaming&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-n3HohRcaH_I/W6B2loynMPI/AAAAAAAACIA/S-7aAso6hOY8K1IlU5ELcUFJ-9nDLgnZQCLcBGAs/s1600/Screen%2BShot%2B2018-09-17%2Bat%2B8.51.14%2BPM.png&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;1152&quot; data-original-width=&quot;1308&quot; src=&quot;https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-n3HohRcaH_I/W6B2loynMPI/AAAAAAAACIA/S-7aAso6hOY8K1IlU5ELcUFJ-9nDLgnZQCLcBGAs/s1600/Screen%2BShot%2B2018-09-17%2Bat%2B8.51.14%2BPM.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;At the very top of the page you’ll see personalized gaming content based on what you like to watch. You’ll also see top live games and the latest gaming videos from your subscriptions, bringing the best of uploaded videos and live gaming to one destination. We’ve also built dedicated shelves for live streams and trending videos. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Everyone has a favorite game. You can now find gaming videos from all over YouTube, related to that specific game on new game pages. These include popular videos, live streams, and other games from the same publisher or developer. With tens of thousands of different game pages, you’ll be able to find content no matter how big or small the game is.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We want to do more to help our smaller creators grow on YouTube too, so we’ll be highlighting gaming creators who are “On The Rise” on the Gaming destination and in Trending. Each week we’ll showcase a new up and coming gaming creator to help more fans discover their content. This is launching in the U.S., and we’ll continue to roll this out to more countries in the future.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We have a strong and vibrant audience on the YouTube Gaming app, but the amount of gamers we are able to reach is far bigger on YouTube. After all, YouTube is where more than 200 million gamers come to engage with your favorite games and creators every day, watching over 50 billion hours of gaming content in the last 12 months alone. That’s why, in March 2019, we’ll retire the YouTube Gaming app and focus all of our gaming efforts on YouTube where we can reach our entire gaming community.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;From creators like elrubiusOMG who has &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/Fwiz/status/978360614249615360&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;hit live gaming records&lt;/a&gt;, to Ninja, the fastest growing creator in YouTube’s history who helped usher in the era of Fortnite, or itsFunneh who became one of our biggest gaming creators by making us all laugh with Minecraft and Roblox videos, we thank you for building a strong gaming community on YouTube. We’re committed to helping gaming creators succeed and look forward to seeing how you all continue to shape the future of gaming. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://gaming.youtube.com/&quot;&gt;Visit the new YouTube Gaming&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;i&gt;Posted by Christina Chen, Director of Product Management, who recently watched &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hndyTy3uiZM&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Warbringers: Azshara&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><link rel='replies' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://youtube-creators.googleblog.com/feeds/8425078597468727884/comments/default' title='Post Comments'/><link rel='replies' type='text/html' href='http://youtube-creators.googleblog.com/2018/09/gaming-gets-new-home-on-youtube.html#comment-form' title='1 Comments'/><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://www.blogger.com/feeds/6959495683334200101/posts/default/8425078597468727884'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://www.blogger.com/feeds/6959495683334200101/posts/default/8425078597468727884'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://youtube-creators.googleblog.com/2018/09/gaming-gets-new-home-on-youtube.html' title='Gaming gets a new home on YouTube'/><author><name>YouTube Creators</name><uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/00450486760991148551</uri><email>noreply@blogger.com</email><gd:image rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail' width='16' height='16' src='https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif'/></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-19EpHD6HTM4/W5__l36CukI/AAAAAAAACHU/f6MsqFqaVjQpF2TpSYd8A0umprf8TVZhwCLcBGAs/s72-c/YT_Gaming_Infographic_17Sept_EN-US.png" height="72" width="72"/><thr:total>1</thr:total></entry></feed>