<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?><rss version="2.0" xml:base="https://www.splcenter.org/rss" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hatewatch | Southern Poverty Law Center</title>
    <link>https://www.splcenter.org/rss</link>
    <description>Hatewatch is a blog that monitors and exposes the activities of the American radical right.</description>
    <language>en</language>
     <atom:link href="https://www.splcenter.org/hatewatch/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
    <title>Conspiracy Theories About Pelosi Attack Spread Unchecked on &#039;Alt-tech&#039; Sites, Conservative Media </title>
    <link>https://www.splcenter.org/hatewatch/2022/11/04/conspiracy-theories-about-pelosi-attack-spread-unchecked-alt-tech-sites-conservative-media</link>
    <description>Conspiracy theories about the home invasion and hammer attack on Paul Pelosi, husband of House Speaker Nancy Pelosi, continue to spread across conservative media, social media and “alt-tech” sites, even as a federal criminal complaint appears to debunk false narratives extremists and right-wing influencers have spread.
</description>
     <pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2022 14:34:15 -0500</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Jason Wilson</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.splcenter.org/hatewatch/2022/11/04/conspiracy-theories-about-pelosi-attack-spread-unchecked-alt-tech-sites-conservative-media</guid>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>Omaha Police Cancel Deal With Far Right-Linked Gun Shop</title>
    <link>https://www.splcenter.org/hatewatch/2022/11/04/omaha-police-cancel-deal-far-right-linked-gun-shop</link>
    <description>The Omaha Police Department (OPD) in Nebraska confirmed to Hatewatch it has permanently scrapped a proposed equipment swap with a far right-linked gun shop.
</description>
     <pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2022 09:00:02 -0500</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Creede Newton</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.splcenter.org/hatewatch/2022/11/04/omaha-police-cancel-deal-far-right-linked-gun-shop</guid>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>Former ICE Chief Taps Anti-Muslim Hate Group To Help Run Border-Focused Project</title>
    <link>https://www.splcenter.org/hatewatch/2022/11/03/former-ice-chief-taps-anti-muslim-hate-group-help-run-border-focused-project</link>
    <description>Tom Homan, a former acting director of U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement (ICE) and prominent conservative media figure, is collaborating with an anti-Muslim hate group on a new project aimed at fearmongering about the U.S. Southern border. The project held a fundraising event at former President Donald Trump’s Mar-a-Lago resort in Florida on Nov. 1.
</description>
     <pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 11:30:51 -0500</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Caleb Kieffer</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.splcenter.org/hatewatch/2022/11/03/former-ice-chief-taps-anti-muslim-hate-group-help-run-border-focused-project</guid>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>Liberty Counsel Used Documents From Gab, ADF for Its Anti-COVID Vaccine Campaign</title>
    <link>https://www.splcenter.org/hatewatch/2022/11/01/liberty-counsel-used-documents-gab-adf-its-anti-covid-vaccine-campaign</link>
    <description>The Liberty Counsel (LC) took documents from outside hate groups and hard-right figures to craft religious-based vaccine exemption requests during the COVID-19 pandemic, leaked documents reviewed by Hatewatch appear to show.
</description>
     <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2022 09:38:25 -0500</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Creede Newton</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.splcenter.org/hatewatch/2022/11/01/liberty-counsel-used-documents-gab-adf-its-anti-covid-vaccine-campaign</guid>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>Newsweek Embraces the Anti-Democracy Hard Right</title>
    <link>https://www.splcenter.org/hatewatch/2022/11/04/newsweek-embraces-anti-democracy-hard-right</link>
    <description>Newsweek positioned political activist Josh Hammer to run their opinion pages during the runup to the 2020 presidential election, and since that time, the publication has taken a marked radical right turn by buoying extremists and promoting authoritarian leaders.
</description>
     <pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2022 13:25:07 -0500</pubDate>
 <dc:creator />
 <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.splcenter.org/hatewatch/2022/11/04/newsweek-embraces-anti-democracy-hard-right</guid>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>Protesters Maced at Canceled Far-right ‘Comedy’ Event at Penn State</title>
    <link>https://www.splcenter.org/hatewatch/2022/10/25/protesters-maced-canceled-far-right-comedy-event-penn-state</link>
    <description>Right-wing agitators allegedly sprayed protesters with mace at a far-right “comedy” event on Penn State’s campus in State College, Pennsylvania, on Monday night.
</description>
     <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 16:08:25 -0500</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Jason Wilson</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.splcenter.org/hatewatch/2022/10/25/protesters-maced-canceled-far-right-comedy-event-penn-state</guid>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>Far-right Student Organization Brings Extremists McInnes, Doyle to Penn State and Tennessee</title>
    <link>https://www.splcenter.org/hatewatch/2022/10/20/far-right-student-organization-brings-extremists-mcinnes-doyle-penn-state-and-tennessee</link>
    <description>Uncensored America (UA), a student organization sanctioned at three university campuses, plans to host  Proud Boys founder Gavin McInnes at Penn State University and far-right social media performer John Doyle at the University of Tennessee, Knoxville, in coming weeks.
</description>
     <pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2022 13:42:51 -0500</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Jason Wilson</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.splcenter.org/hatewatch/2022/10/20/far-right-student-organization-brings-extremists-mcinnes-doyle-penn-state-and-tennessee</guid>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>Alex Jones must pay Sandy Hook families almost $1 billion</title>
    <link>https://www.splcenter.org/hatewatch/2022/10/13/alex-jones-must-pay-sandy-hook-families-almost-1-billion</link>
    <description>The conspiracy theorist and extremist Alex Jones must pay the families of Sandy Hook mass shooting victims almost $1 billion in damages for false claims that they were actors complicit in a hoax.
</description>
     <pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2022 14:22:22 -0500</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Jason Wilson</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.splcenter.org/hatewatch/2022/10/13/alex-jones-must-pay-sandy-hook-families-almost-1-billion</guid>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>Libertarian Party Loses State Parties, Donors After Hard-right Turn</title>
    <link>https://www.splcenter.org/hatewatch/2022/10/11/libertarian-party-loses-state-parties-donors-after-hard-right-turn</link>
    <description>The Libertarian Party (LP) faces the departures of two state-level parties as membership dues drop and some donors flee the party over questions about economic stewardship and the party’s turn to far-right messaging, Hatewatch has found through documents and interviews with former LP members.
</description>
     <pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2022 11:44:31 -0500</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Creede Newton</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.splcenter.org/hatewatch/2022/10/11/libertarian-party-loses-state-parties-donors-after-hard-right-turn</guid>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>Hate Group FAIR Continues To Partner With Sheriffs To Target Immigrants</title>
    <link>https://www.splcenter.org/hatewatch/2022/09/19/hate-group-fair-continues-partner-sheriffs-target-immigrants</link>
    <description>A group of sheriffs associated with the extremist constitutional sheriff movement lent their support to the anti-immigrant hate group Federation for American Immigration Reform at a press conference in Washington, D.C., on Friday to promote a “crisis” happening at the Southern border.
</description>
     <pubDate>Mon, 19 Sep 2022 12:22:46 -0500</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Caleb Kieffer and Rachel Goldwasser</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.splcenter.org/hatewatch/2022/09/19/hate-group-fair-continues-partner-sheriffs-target-immigrants</guid>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>Patriot Front Replaces Lawyer of Choice With Extremist</title>
    <link>https://www.splcenter.org/hatewatch/2022/09/09/patriot-front-replaces-lawyer-choice-extremist</link>
    <description>Patriot Front members have replaced their former first-choice lawyer Brent Gleason with Jason Lee Van Dyke in recent months, according to court documents, leaked chats, sources with knowledge of the group’s internal workings, and online materials reviewed by Hatewatch.
</description>
     <pubDate>Thu, 08 Sep 2022 11:29:51 -0500</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Jeff Tischauser and Jason Wilson</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.splcenter.org/hatewatch/2022/09/09/patriot-front-replaces-lawyer-choice-extremist</guid>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>New York Fired Racist Prison Guard for Identity Evropa Membership</title>
    <link>https://www.splcenter.org/hatewatch/2022/08/29/new-york-fired-racist-prison-guard-identity-evropa-membership</link>
    <description>A former corrections officer sought to spread propaganda for a white nationalist group involved with the deadly 2017 “Unite the Right” rally while employed at a New York state prison, Hatewatch found.
</description>
     <pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2022 14:21:19 -0500</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Hannah Gais and Creede Newton</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.splcenter.org/hatewatch/2022/08/29/new-york-fired-racist-prison-guard-identity-evropa-membership</guid>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>White Nationalist Group Exploits Amazon To Fund Their Cause</title>
    <link>https://www.splcenter.org/hatewatch/2022/08/23/white-nationalist-group-exploits-amazon-fund-their-cause</link>
    <description>The white supremacists behind Antelope Hill, a hate group that churns out books that idealize fascism and denigrate marginalized groups, exploit the low standards for entry of online retailers such as Amazon to run their business.
</description>
     <pubDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2022 13:01:40 -0500</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Michael Edison Hayden and Hannah Gais</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.splcenter.org/hatewatch/2022/08/23/white-nationalist-group-exploits-amazon-fund-their-cause</guid>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>Emails Show Omaha Police Planned Deal With Far Right-linked Gun Shop</title>
    <link>https://www.splcenter.org/hatewatch/2022/08/22/emails-show-omaha-police-planned-deal-far-right-linked-gun-shop</link>
    <description>The Omaha Police Department (OPD) in Nebraska plans to trade tens of thousands of dollars&#039; worth of expired helmets and bulletproof gear for roughly $3,000 worth of firearm equipment in a deal with a local tactical shop that has hosted international far-right politicians and an anti-Muslim speaker.
</description>
     <pubDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2022 10:09:30 -0500</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Creede Newton</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.splcenter.org/hatewatch/2022/08/22/emails-show-omaha-police-planned-deal-far-right-linked-gun-shop</guid>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>Far-right Extremism and Gun Violence: Reimagining Prevention</title>
    <link>https://www.splcenter.org/hatewatch/2022/08/16/far-right-extremism-and-gun-violence-reimagining-prevention</link>
    <description>As the U.S. reels from another spate of mass shootings, experts and practitioners concerned with understanding and preventing harms related to extremist radicalization are renewing calls for a more robust system of prevention and support for those at risk.
</description>
     <pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2022 13:07:09 -0500</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Hannah Gais</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.splcenter.org/hatewatch/2022/08/16/far-right-extremism-and-gun-violence-reimagining-prevention</guid>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>&#039;Unite the Right&#039; 5 Years Later: Where Are They Now?</title>
    <link>https://www.splcenter.org/hatewatch/2022/08/11/unite-right-5-years-later-where-are-they-now</link>
    <description>Five years after white supremacists descended on Charlottesville, Virginia, the statue they came to protect is gone, and the “alt-right” coalition they embodied has imploded. At the same time, the existential threat that far-right extremism poses to the U.S. has arguably never been more severe.
</description>
     <pubDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2022 09:32:07 -0500</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Michael Edison Hayden, Hannah Gais, Cassie Miller, Megan Squire and Jason Wilson </dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.splcenter.org/hatewatch/2022/08/11/unite-right-5-years-later-where-are-they-now</guid>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>How Antigovernment Extremists and QAnon took over the Southern Border</title>
    <link>https://www.splcenter.org/hatewatch/2022/08/08/how-antigovernment-extremists-and-qanon-took-over-southern-border</link>
    <description>In Sasabe, Arizona, along the U.S.-Mexico border, far-right Christian nationalists and QAnon adherents have steadily visited the area trying to detain migrants to stop a supposed migrant invasion.
</description>
     <pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2022 13:42:40 -0500</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Freddy Cruz</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.splcenter.org/hatewatch/2022/08/08/how-antigovernment-extremists-and-qanon-took-over-southern-border</guid>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>Cadre of Nativist Groups, Figures Have Long Pushed Replacement-by-Immigration Ideas into Mainstream</title>
    <link>https://www.splcenter.org/hatewatch/2022/07/14/cadre-nativist-groups-figures-have-long-pushed-replacement-immigration-ideas-mainstream</link>
    <description>For decades, a network of Washington, D.C., nativist groups and their political allies have advanced ideas resembling a “great replacement” spurred on by immigration, as seen in materials associated with the suspect alleged to be responsible for the mass shooting at a Buffalo, New York, supermarket on May 14.
</description>
     <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2022 14:21:28 -0500</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Caleb Kieffer</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.splcenter.org/hatewatch/2022/07/14/cadre-nativist-groups-figures-have-long-pushed-replacement-immigration-ideas-mainstream</guid>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>Andrew Yang To Speak Alongside Far-right Figures at &#039;FreedomFest&#039;</title>
    <link>https://www.splcenter.org/hatewatch/2022/07/13/andrew-yang-speak-alongside-far-right-figures-freedomfest</link>
    <description>Former Democratic presidential candidate Andrew Yang will speak Saturday about his new Forward Party and creating political coalitions at the 2022 FreedomFest in Las Vegas, which will feature far-right libertarians with ties to white nationalists and antisemites.
</description>
     <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2022 11:39:18 -0500</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Creede Newton</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.splcenter.org/hatewatch/2022/07/13/andrew-yang-speak-alongside-far-right-figures-freedomfest</guid>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>Oath Keepers a Threat to Democracy: Jan. 6 Select Committee</title>
    <link>https://www.splcenter.org/hatewatch/2022/07/12/oath-keepers-threat-democracy-jan-6-select-committee</link>
    <description>The House committee investigating the events surrounding the Jan. 6, 2021, insurrection focused Tuesday on the  Proud Boys and  Oath Keepers, two extremist groups involved in the attempt to stop the certification of President Joe Biden’s electoral victory.
</description>
     <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2022 17:54:19 -0500</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Creede Newton</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.splcenter.org/hatewatch/2022/07/12/oath-keepers-threat-democracy-jan-6-select-committee</guid>
  </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
