<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<rdf:RDF
 xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
 xmlns="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/"
 xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
 xmlns:taxo="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/taxonomy/"
 xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
 xmlns:syn="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
 xmlns:admin="http://webns.net/mvcb/"
>

<channel rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/">
<title>q-bio updates on arXiv.org</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">Quantitative Biology (q-bio) updates on the arXiv.org e-print archive</description>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:date>2022-11-03T20:30:00-05:00</dc:date>
<dc:publisher>www-admin@arxiv.org</dc:publisher>
<dc:subject>Quantitative Biology</dc:subject>
<syn:updateBase>1901-01-01T00:00+00:00</syn:updateBase>
<syn:updateFrequency>1</syn:updateFrequency>
<syn:updatePeriod>daily</syn:updatePeriod>
<items>
 <rdf:Seq>
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01603" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01698" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01867" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01885" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01960" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01978" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.02019" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.02024" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2003.13825" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2102.02649" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2103.16606" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2204.10189" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2205.02645" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.01123" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.16993" />
 </rdf:Seq>
</items>
<image rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif" />
</channel>
<image rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif">
<title>arXiv.org</title>
<url>http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif</url>
<link>http://arxiv.org/</link>
</image>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01603">
<title>Using Signal Processing in Tandem With Adapted Mixture Models for Classifying Genomic Signals. (arXiv:2211.01603v1 [q-bio.GN])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01603</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Genomic signal processing has been used successfully in bioinformatics to
analyze biomolecular sequences and gain varied insights into DNA structure,
gene organization, protein binding, sequence evolution, etc. But challenges
remain in finding the appropriate spectral representation of a biomolecular
sequence, especially when multiple variable-length sequences need to be handled
consistently. In this study, we address this challenge in the context of the
well-studied problem of classifying genomic sequences into different taxonomic
units (strain, phyla, order, etc.). We propose a novel technique that employs
signal processing in tandem with Gaussian mixture models to improve the
spectral representation of a sequence and subsequently the taxonomic
classification accuracies. The sequences are first transformed into spectra,
and projected to a subspace, where sequences belonging to different taxons are
better distinguishable. Our method outperforms a similar state-of-the-art
method on established benchmark datasets by an absolute margin of 6.06%
accuracy.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/q-bio/1/au:+Jaiswal_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Saish Jaiswal&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/q-bio/1/au:+Nema_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Shreya Nema&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/q-bio/1/au:+Murthy_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Hema A Murthy&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/q-bio/1/au:+Narayanan_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Manikandan Narayanan&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01698">
<title>Scaling up the self-optimization model by means of on-the-fly computation of weights. (arXiv:2211.01698v1 [nlin.AO])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01698</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The Self-Optimization (SO) model is a useful computational model for
investigating self-organization in &quot;soft&quot; Artificial life (ALife) as it has
been shown to be general enough to model various complex adaptive systems. So
far, existing work has been done on relatively small network sizes, precluding
the investigation of novel phenomena that might emerge from the complexity
arising from large numbers of nodes interacting in interconnected networks.
This work introduces a novel implementation of the SO model that scales as
$\mathcal{O}\left(N^{2}\right)$ with respect to the number of nodes $N$, and
demonstrates the applicability of the SO model to networks with system sizes
several orders of magnitude higher than previously was investigated. Removing
the prohibitive computational cost of the naive $\mathcal{O}\left(N^{3}\right)$
algorithm, our on-the-fly computation paves the way for investigating
substantially larger system sizes, allowing for more variety and complexity in
future studies.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/nlin/1/au:+Weber_N/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Natalya Weber&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/nlin/1/au:+Koch_W/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Werner Koch&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/nlin/1/au:+Froese_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Tom Froese&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01867">
<title>Macrophage anti-inflammatory behaviour in a multiphase model of atherosclerotic plaque development. (arXiv:2211.01867v1 [q-bio.CB])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01867</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Atherosclerosis is an inflammatory disease characterised by the formation of
plaques, which are deposits of lipids and cholesterol-laden macrophages that
form in the artery wall. The inflammation is often non-resolving, due in large
part to changes in normal macrophage anti-inflammatory behaviour that are
induced by the toxic plaque microenvironment. These changes include higher
death rates, defective efferocytic uptake of dead cells, and reduced rates of
emigration. We develop a free boundary multiphase model for early
atherosclerotic plaques, and we use it to investigate the effects of impaired
macrophage anti-inflammatory behaviour on plaque structure and growth. We find
that high rates of cell death relative to efferocytic uptake results in a
plaque populated mostly by dead cells. We also find that emigration can
potentially slow or halt plaque growth by allowing material to exit the plaque,
but this is contingent on the availability of live macrophage foam cells in the
deep plaque. Finally, we introduce an additional bead species to model
macrophage tagging via microspheres, and we use the extended model to explore
how high rates of cell death and low rates of efferocytosis and emigration
prevent the clearance of macrophages from the plaque.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/q-bio/1/au:+Ahmed_I/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ishraq U. Ahmed&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/q-bio/1/au:+Byrne_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Helen M. Byrne&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/q-bio/1/au:+Myerscough_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Mary R. Myerscough&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01885">
<title>Using U-Net Network for Efficient Brain Tumor Segmentation in MRI Images. (arXiv:2211.01885v1 [eess.IV])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01885</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Magnetic Resonance Imaging (MRI) is the most commonly used non-intrusive
technique for medical image acquisition. Brain tumor segmentation is the
process of algorithmically identifying tumors in brain MRI scans. While many
approaches have been proposed in the literature for brain tumor segmentation,
this paper proposes a lightweight implementation of U-Net. Apart from providing
real-time segmentation of MRI scans, the proposed architecture does not need
large amount of data to train the proposed lightweight U-Net. Moreover, no
additional data augmentation step is required. The lightweight U-Net shows very
promising results on BITE dataset and it achieves a mean
intersection-over-union (IoU) of 89% while outperforming the standard benchmark
algorithms. Additionally, this work demonstrates an effective use of the three
perspective planes, instead of the original three-dimensional volumetric
images, for simplified brain tumor segmentation.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/eess/1/au:+Walsh_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jason Walsh&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/eess/1/au:+Othmani_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Alice Othmani&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/eess/1/au:+Jain_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Mayank Jain&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/eess/1/au:+Dev_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Soumyabrata Dev&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01960">
<title>FingerFlex: Inferring Finger Trajectories from ECoG signals. (arXiv:2211.01960v1 [q-bio.NC])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01960</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Motor brain-computer interface (BCI) development relies critically on neural
time series decoding algorithms. Recent advances in deep learning architectures
allow for automatic feature selection to approximate higher-order dependencies
in data. This article presents the FingerFlex model - a convolutional
encoder-decoder architecture adapted for finger movement regression on
electrocorticographic (ECoG) brain data. State-of-the-art performance was
achieved on a publicly available BCI competition IV dataset 4 with a
correlation coefficient between true and predicted trajectories up to 0.74. The
presented method provides the opportunity for developing fully-functional
high-precision cortical motor brain-computer interfaces.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/q-bio/1/au:+Lomtev_V/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Vladislav Lomtev&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/q-bio/1/au:+Kovalev_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Alexander Kovalev&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/q-bio/1/au:+Timchenko_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Alexey Timchenko&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01978">
<title>PEMP: Leveraging Physics Properties to Enhance Molecular Property Prediction. (arXiv:2211.01978v1 [q-bio.BM])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01978</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Molecular property prediction is essential for drug discovery. In recent
years, deep learning methods have been introduced to this area and achieved
state-of-the-art performances. However, most of existing methods ignore the
intrinsic relations between molecular properties which can be utilized to
improve the performances of corresponding prediction tasks. In this paper, we
propose a new approach, namely Physics properties Enhanced Molecular Property
prediction (PEMP), to utilize relations between molecular properties revealed
by previous physics theory and physical chemistry studies. Specifically, we
enhance the training of the chemical and physiological property predictors with
related physics property prediction tasks. We design two different methods for
PEMP, respectively based on multi-task learning and transfer learning. Both
methods include a model-agnostic molecule representation module and a property
prediction module. In our implementation, we adopt both the state-of-the-art
molecule embedding models under the supervised learning paradigm and the
pretraining paradigm as the molecule representation module of PEMP,
respectively. Experimental results on public benchmark MoleculeNet show that
the proposed methods have the ability to outperform corresponding
state-of-the-art models.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/q-bio/1/au:+Sun_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yuancheng Sun&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/q-bio/1/au:+Chen_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yimeng Chen&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/q-bio/1/au:+Ma_W/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Weizhi Ma&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/q-bio/1/au:+Huang_W/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Wenhao Huang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/q-bio/1/au:+Liu_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Kang Liu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/q-bio/1/au:+Ma_Z/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Zhiming Ma&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/q-bio/1/au:+Ma_W/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Wei-Ying Ma&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/q-bio/1/au:+Lan_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yanyan Lan&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.02019">
<title>Extending the analogy between intracellular motion in mammalian cells and glassy dynamics. (arXiv:2211.02019v1 [cond-mat.soft])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.02019</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The physics of how molecules, organelles, and foreign objects move within
living cells has been extensively studied in organisms ranging from bacteria to
human cells. In mammalian cells, in particular, cellular vesicles move across
the cell using motor proteins that carry the vesicle down the cytoskeleton to
their destination. We have recently noted several similarities between the
motion of such vesicles and that in disordered, &quot;glassy&quot;, systems, but it
remains unclear whether that is a general observation or something specific to
certain vesicles in one particular cell type. Here we follow the motion of
mitochondria, the organelles responsible for cell energy production, in several
mammalian cell types over timescales ranging from 50 ms up to 70 s. Qualitative
observations show that single mitochondria remain stalled, remaining within a
spatially limited region, for extended periods of time, before moving longer
distances relatively quickly. Analysing this motion quantitatively, we observe
a displacement distribution that is roughly Gaussian for shorter distances
($\lesssim$ 0.05 $\mu$m) but which exhibits exponentially decaying tails at
longer distances (up to 0.40 $\mu$m). We show that this behaviour is
well-described by a model originally developed to describe the motion in glassy
systems. These observations are extended to in total 3 different objects
(mitochondria, lysosomes and nano-sized beads enclosed in vesicles), 3
different mammalian cell types, from 2 different organisms (human and mouse).
We provide further evidence that supports glass-like characteristics of the
motion by showing a difference between the time it takes to move a longer
distance for the first time and subsequent times, as well as a weak ergodicity
breaking of the motion. Overall, we demonstrate the ubiquity of glass-like
motion in mammalian cells, providing a different perspective on intracellular
motion.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Corci_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;B. Corci&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Hooiveld_O/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;O. Hooiveld&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+Dolga_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;A. M. Dolga&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cond-mat/1/au:+%7B%5CAA%7Dberg_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;C. &amp;#xc5;berg&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.02024">
<title>fMRI from EEG is only Deep Learning away: the use of interpretable DL to unravel EEG-fMRI relationships. (arXiv:2211.02024v1 [physics.med-ph])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.02024</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The access to activity of subcortical structures offers unique opportunity
for building intention dependent brain-computer interfaces, renders abundant
options for exploring a broad range of cognitive phenomena in the realm of
affective neuroscience including complex decision making processes and the
eternal free-will dilemma and facilitates diagnostics of a range of
neurological deceases. So far this was possible only using bulky, expensive and
immobile fMRI equipment. Here we present an interpretable domain grounded
solution to recover the activity of several subcortical regions from the
multichannel EEG data and demonstrate up to 60% correlation between the actual
subcortical blood oxygenation level dependent sBOLD signal and its EEG-derived
twin. Then, using the novel and theoretically justified weight interpretation
methodology we recover individual spatial and time-frequency patterns of scalp
EEG predictive of the hemodynamic signal in the subcortical nuclei. The
described results not only pave the road towards wearable subcortical activity
scanners but also showcase an automatic knowledge discovery process facilitated
by deep learning technology in combination with an interpretable domain
constrained architecture and the appropriate downstream task.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Kovalev_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Alexander Kovalev&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Mikheev_I/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ilia Mikheev&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/physics/1/au:+Ossadtchi_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Alexei Ossadtchi&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2003.13825">
<title>On the role of theory and modeling in neuroscience. (arXiv:2003.13825v5 [q-bio.NC] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2003.13825</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;In recent years, the field of neuroscience has gone through rapid
experimental advances and a significant increase in the use of quantitative and
computational methods. This growth has created a need for clearer analyses of
the theory and modeling approaches used in the field. This issue is
particularly complex in neuroscience because the field studies phenomena across
a wide range of scales and often requires consideration of these phenomena at
varying degrees of abstraction, from precise biophysical interactions to the
computations they implement. We argue that a pragmatic perspective of science,
in which descriptive, mechanistic, and normative approaches each play a
distinct role in defining and bridging levels of abstraction will facilitate
neuroscientific practice. This analysis leads to methodological suggestions,
including selecting a level of abstraction that is appropriate for a given
problem, identifying transfer functions to connect models and data, and the use
of models themselves as a form of experiment.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/q-bio/1/au:+Levenstein_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Daniel Levenstein&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/q-bio/1/au:+Alvarez_V/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Veronica A. Alvarez&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/q-bio/1/au:+Amarasingham_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Asohan Amarasingham&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/q-bio/1/au:+Azab_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Habiba Azab&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/q-bio/1/au:+Chen_Z/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Zhe Sage Chen&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/q-bio/1/au:+Gerkin_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Richard C. Gerkin&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/q-bio/1/au:+Hasenstaub_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Andrea Hasenstaub&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/q-bio/1/au:+Iyer_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ramakrishnan Iyer&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/q-bio/1/au:+Jolivet_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Renaud B. Jolivet&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/q-bio/1/au:+Marzen_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Sarah Marzen&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/q-bio/1/au:+Monaco_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Joseph D. Monaco&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/q-bio/1/au:+Prinz_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Astrid A. Prinz&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/q-bio/1/au:+Quraishi_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Salma Quraishi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/q-bio/1/au:+Santamaria_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Fidel Santamaria&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/q-bio/1/au:+Shivkumar_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Sabyasachi Shivkumar&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/q-bio/1/au:+Singh_M/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Matthew F. Singh&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/q-bio/1/au:+Traub_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Roger Traub&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/q-bio/1/au:+Rotstein_H/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Horacio G. Rotstein&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/q-bio/1/au:+Nadim_F/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Farzan Nadim&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/q-bio/1/au:+Redish_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;A. David Redish&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2102.02649">
<title>A step towards a reinforcement learning de novo genome assembler. (arXiv:2102.02649v3 [q-bio.GN] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2102.02649</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The use of reinforcement learning has proven to be very promising for solving
complex activities without human supervision during their learning process.
However, their successful applications are predominantly focused on fictional
and entertainment problems - such as games. Based on the above, this work aims
to shed light on the application of reinforcement learning to solve this
relevant real-world problem, the genome assembly. By expanding the only
approach found in the literature that addresses this problem, we carefully
explored the aspects of intelligent agent learning, performed by the Q-learning
algorithm, to understand its suitability to be applied in scenarios whose
characteristics are more similar to those faced by real genome projects. The
improvements proposed here include changing the previously proposed reward
system and including state space exploration optimization strategies based on
dynamic pruning and mutual collaboration with evolutionary computing. These
investigations were tried on 23 new environments with larger inputs than those
used previously. All these environments are freely available on the internet
for the evolution of this research by the scientific community. The results
suggest consistent performance progress using the proposed improvements,
however, they also demonstrate the limitations of them, especially related to
the high dimensionality of state and action spaces. We also present, later, the
paths that can be traced to tackle genome assembly efficiently in real
scenarios considering recent, successfully reinforcement learning applications
- including deep reinforcement learning - from other domains dealing with
high-dimensional inputs.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/q-bio/1/au:+Padovani_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Kleber Padovani&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/q-bio/1/au:+Xavier_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Roberto Xavier&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/q-bio/1/au:+Carvalho_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Andre Carvalho&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/q-bio/1/au:+Reali_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Anna Reali&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/q-bio/1/au:+Chateau_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Annie Chateau&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/q-bio/1/au:+Alves_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ronnie Alves&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2103.16606">
<title>Functional and spatial rewiring jointly generate convergent-divergent units in self-organizing networks. (arXiv:2103.16606v2 [q-bio.NC] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2103.16606</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Self-organization through adaptive rewiring of random neural networks
generates brain-like topologies comprising modular small-world structures with
rich club effects, merely as the product of optimizing the network topology. In
the nervous system, spatial organization is optimized no less by rewiring,
through minimizing wiring distance and maximizing spatially aligned wiring
layouts. We show that such spatial organization principles interact
constructively with adaptive rewiring, contributing to establish the networks&apos;
connectedness and modular structures. We use an evolving neural network model
with weighted and directed connections, in which neural traffic flow is based
on consensus and advection dynamics, to show that wiring cost minimization
supports adaptive rewiring in creating convergent-divergent unit structures.
Convergent-divergent units consist of a convergent input-hub, connected to a
divergent output-hub via subnetworks of intermediate nodes, which may function
as the computational core of the unit. The prominence of minimizing wiring
distance in the dynamic evolution of the network determines the extent to which
the core is encapsulated from the rest of the network, i.e., the
context-sensitivity of its computations. This corresponds to the central role
convergent-divergent units play in establishing context-sensitivity in neuronal
information processing.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/q-bio/1/au:+Li_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jia Li&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/q-bio/1/au:+Rentzeperis_I/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ilias Rentzeperis&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/q-bio/1/au:+Leeuwen_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Cees van Leeuwen&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2204.10189">
<title>Neural Topic Modeling of Psychotherapy Sessions. (arXiv:2204.10189v2 [cs.CL] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2204.10189</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;In this work, we compare different neural topic modeling methods in learning
the topical propensities of different psychiatric conditions from the
psychotherapy session transcripts parsed from speech recordings. We also
incorporate temporal modeling to put this additional interpretability to action
by parsing out topic similarities as a time series in a turn-level resolution.
We believe this topic modeling framework can offer interpretable insights for
the therapist to optimally decide his or her strategy and improve psychotherapy
effectiveness.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Lin_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Baihan Lin&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Bouneffouf_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Djallel Bouneffouf&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Cecchi_G/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Guillermo Cecchi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/cs/1/au:+Tejwani_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ravi Tejwani&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2205.02645">
<title>PyDaddy: A Python package for discovering stochastic dynamical equations from timeseries data. (arXiv:2205.02645v2 [q-bio.QM] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2205.02645</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Most real-world ecological dynamics, ranging from ecosystem dynamics to
collective animal movement, are inherently stochastic in nature. Stochastic
differential equations (SDEs) are a popular modelling framework to model
dynamics with intrinsic randomness. Here, we focus on the inverse question: If
one has empirically measured time-series data from some system of interest, is
it possible to discover the SDE model that best describes the data. Here, we
present PyDaddy (PYthon library for DAta Driven DYnamics), a toolbox to
construct and analyze interpretable SDE models based on time-series data. We
combine traditional approaches for data-driven SDE reconstruction with an
equation learning approach, to derive symbolic equations governing the
stochastic dynamics. The toolkit is presented as an open-source Python library,
and consists of tools to construct and analyze SDEs. Functionality is included
for visual examination of the stochastic structure of the data, guided
extraction of the functional form of the SDE, and diagnosis and debugging of
the underlying assumptions and the extracted model. Using simulated time-series
datasets, exhibiting a wide range of dynamics, we show that PyDaddy is able to
correctly identify underlying SDE models. We demonstrate the applicability of
the toolkit to real-world data using a previously published movement data of a
fish school. Starting from the time-series of the observed polarization of the
school, pyDaddy readily discovers the SDE model governing the dynamics of group
polarization. The model recovered by PyDaddy is consistent with the previous
study. In summary, stochastic and noise-induced effects are central to the
dynamics of many biological systems. In this context, we present an easy-to-use
package to reconstruct SDEs from timeseries data.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/q-bio/1/au:+Nabeel_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Arshed Nabeel&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/q-bio/1/au:+Karichannavar_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ashwin Karichannavar&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/q-bio/1/au:+Palathingal_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Shuaib Palathingal&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/q-bio/1/au:+Jhawar_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jitesh Jhawar&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/q-bio/1/au:+M_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Danny Raj M&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/q-bio/1/au:+Guttal_V/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Vishwesha Guttal&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.01123">
<title>Towards Learned Simulators for Cell Migration. (arXiv:2210.01123v2 [q-bio.QM] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.01123</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Simulators driven by deep learning are gaining popularity as a tool for
efficiently emulating accurate but expensive numerical simulators. Successful
applications of such neural simulators can be found in the domains of physics,
chemistry, and structural biology, amongst others. Likewise, a neural simulator
for cellular dynamics can augment lab experiments and traditional computational
methods to enhance our understanding of a cell&apos;s interaction with its physical
environment. In this work, we propose an autoregressive probabilistic model
that can reproduce spatiotemporal dynamics of single cell migration,
traditionally simulated with the Cellular Potts model. We observe that standard
single-step training methods do not only lead to inconsistent rollout
stability, but also fail to accurately capture the stochastic aspects of the
dynamics, and we propose training strategies to mitigate these issues. Our
evaluation on two proof-of-concept experimental scenarios shows that neural
methods have the potential to faithfully simulate stochastic cellular dynamics
at least an order of magnitude faster than a state-of-the-art implementation of
the Cellular Potts model.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/q-bio/1/au:+Minartz_K/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Koen Minartz&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/q-bio/1/au:+Poels_Y/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Yoeri Poels&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/q-bio/1/au:+Menkovski_V/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Vlado Menkovski&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.16993">
<title>STN: a new tensor network method to identify stimulus category from brain activity pattern. (arXiv:2210.16993v2 [q-bio.NC] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.16993</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Neural decoding is still a challenge and hot topic in neurocomputing science.
Recently, many studies have shown that brain network pattern containing rich
spatial and temporal structure information, which represented the activation
information of brain under external stimuli. The traditional method is to
extract brain network features directly from the common machine learning
method, then put these features into the classifier, and realize to decode
external stimuli. However, this method cannot effectively extract the
multi-dimensional structural information, which is hidden in the brain network.
The tensor researchers show that the tensor decomposition model can fully mine
unique spatio-temporal structure characteristics in multi-dimensional structure
data. This research proposed a stimulus constrain tensor brain model(STN),
which involved the tensor decomposition idea and stimulus category constraint
information. The model was verified on the real neuroimaging data sets (MEG and
fMRI). The experimental results show that the STN model achieved more 11.06%
and 18.46% compared with others methods on two modal data sets. These results
imply the superiority of extracting discriminative characteristics about STN
model, especially for decoding object stimuli with semantic information.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/q-bio/1/au:+Liu_C/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Chunyu Liu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/q-bio/1/au:+Zhang_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Jiacai Zhang&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
</rdf:RDF>