<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>The Data Science Bowl</title>
	<atom:link href="http://datasciencebowl.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://datasciencebowl.com</link>
	<description>Passion. Curiosity. Purpose</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2020 19:52:47 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.0.3</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Using Data Science to Advance Educational Tools for Young Children: Fifth Annual Data Science Bowl Announces Winners; Thousands Participated in Worldwide Competition</title>
		<link>https://datasciencebowl.com/using-data-science-to-advance-educational-tools-for-young-children-fifth-annual-data-science-bowl-announces-winners-thousands-participated-in-worldwide-competition/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2020 19:52:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://datasciencebowl.com/?p=5917</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>COMPETITION HOSTED BY BOOZ ALLEN HAMILTON AND KAGGLE, WITH PARTNER PBS KIDS, YIELDS 75,000 MODELS DESIGNED TO HELP BUILD BETTER DIGITAL EDUCATIONAL GAMES AND LEARNING TECHNOLOGIES April 09, 2020 McLean, Va. – Booz Allen Hamilton (NYSE: BAH) and Kaggle, in partnership with PBS KIDS, today announced the winners of the 2019 Data Science Bowl® which [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://datasciencebowl.com/using-data-science-to-advance-educational-tools-for-young-children-fifth-annual-data-science-bowl-announces-winners-thousands-participated-in-worldwide-competition/">Using Data Science to Advance Educational Tools for Young Children: Fifth Annual Data Science Bowl Announces Winners; Thousands Participated in Worldwide Competition</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://datasciencebowl.com">The Data Science Bowl</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;">COMPETITION HOSTED BY BOOZ ALLEN HAMILTON AND KAGGLE, WITH PARTNER PBS KIDS, YIELDS 75,000 MODELS DESIGNED TO HELP BUILD BETTER DIGITAL EDUCATIONAL GAMES AND LEARNING TECHNOLOGIES</p>
<p>April 09, 2020</p>
<p><b>McLean, Va.</b> – <a href="http://www.boozallen.com/">Booz Allen Hamilton</a> (NYSE: BAH) and <a href="http://www.kaggle.com/">Kaggle</a>, in partnership with <a href="https://pbskids.org/">PBS KIDS</a>, today announced the winners of the 2019 Data Science Bowl<sup>®</sup> which challenged participants to use artificial intelligence (AI) to advance innovation in educational media for young children. Over the course of 90 days, thousands of data scientists used AI to create algorithms to analyze anonymous game-play data from <a href="https://pbskids.org/apps/pbs-kids-measure-up.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">PBS KIDS Measure Up!</a>, a free game-based learning app. The winners’ algorithms most effectively analyzed data about how children use the app to predict users’ performance on in-game math assessments. The submissions will help to improve the technology behind these educational games, as measuring performance is a key step towards providing experiences that are tailored to the needs of individual users.</p>
<p>Research shows much of the most critical brain development in children takes place <a href="http://www.aft.org/sites/default/files/periodicals/TheEarlyCatastrophe.pdf">before they reach kindergarten</a>. Access to effective early learning resources is critical, and research demonstrates that high-quality educational media can help support young learners. The learnings from the fifth annual Data Science Bowl will chart a path for the greater application of AI to digital education tools and help PBS KIDS and others to create new content and solutions that ensure every child is learning the important skills these tools aim to teach. Insights gleaned from these algorithms also have implications that will help improve digital media and technology to support young children’s learning. From future adaptive and personalized educational games, to potential classroom applications, these approaches are stepping stones that can lead to innovation in early childhood learning.</p>
<p>“Since launching the Data Science Bowl in 2014, our mission has always been to enable and inspire people to use data science for good,” said <a href="https://www.boozallen.com/e/bio/leadership/joshua-sullivan.html">Dr. Josh Sullivan</a>, executive vice president and leader of Booz Allen Hamilton’s Analytics and AI business. “We believe that, with the right talent, tools, and knowledge, collective ingenuity can change the world for the better. This year’s competition demonstrates the power and profound impact data science and AI can have on early childhood education. Algorithms developed in this competition can help design new technologies and tools to provide the best learning experience that will ultimately help young kids thrive in school and life.”</p>
<p>The Data Science Bowl brings together data scientists, technologists, and domain experts across industries to take on the world’s challenges with data and technology. It’s a platform through which individuals can harness their passion for social good, unleash their curiosity, and amplify their impact to effect change on a global scale. The 2019 competition brought together over 4,400 participants who submitted more than 75,000 entries—the highest number of submissions since the inaugural Data Science Bowl launched in 2014. Participants this year collectively dedicated an estimated 280,000 hours developing the algorithms.</p>
<p>“PBS KIDS provides free access to media content that is proven to help children learn. A key piece of information when trying to measure learning gains from technology is being able to identify what players are and are not yet capable of,” said Jeremy Roberts, Senior Director of Learning Technologies, PBS KIDS Digital. “The approaches from this year’s Data Science Bowl will help us build more effective educational games to make available to all kids, so that they can learn important skills. We couldn’t be more thrilled with the exciting world of possibilities that have opened up to us though the collaboration with Booz Allen Hamilton, Kaggle and this year’s participants.”</p>
<p><a href="https://pbskids.org/apps/pbs-kids-measure-up.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">PBS KIDS Measure Up!</a> was developed as a part of the Ready To Learn Initiative, funded by the U.S. Department of Education, which supports the development of innovative early childhood learning efforts of the Corporation for Public Broadcasting (CPB) and PBS KIDS.</p>
<p>The top teams from the 2019 Data Science Bowl winners all tackled the Data Science Bowl for the first time this year with impressive results:</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<ul>
<li><b>1</b><sup><b>st</b></sup><b> Place: Team zr &amp; oyx<br />
</b>The first place team, Zhuoran Ma and Xuan Ouyang, began competing in data science competitions three years ago. This is their first time winning a competition and their first year participating in the Data Science Bowl. The team said of the competition, “We believe that data science can make meaningful contributions to help improve children’s learning through educational gameplay and we wanted to use our skills to help.”</li>
<li><b>2</b><sup><b>nd</b></sup><b> Place: Team Fuson<br />
</b><b> </b>Team Fuson—Yuki Abe, Kosuke Shingyouchi, and Toshiki Ishikawa—includes two university students and a software engineer, each with varying degrees of familiarity with data science. This diversity was key to their success: “We learned from each other and by studying the public kernels and discussion boards during the competition,” Team Fuson said.</li>
<li><b>3</b><sup><b>rd</b></sup><b> Place: Team Limerobot<br />
</b>Sanghoon Kim, a data scientist working for an online retailer, started competing in Kaggle competitions last year. Also a newcomer to the Data Science Bowl, Kim joined the competition with about a month before closing, using deep neural networks to help solve this year’s challenge.</li>
</ul>
<p>The top five winning teams will split $160,000 in cash prizes. The three teams with the best score comprised entirely of actively registered university students (Fall/Winter 2019/2020 enrollees) was awarded a separate $8,500 University prize by Booz Allen. Over 150 students participated in the 2019 Data Science Bowl.</p>
<p>“Over five years, the Data Science Bowl has drawn tens of thousands of data scientists, technologists, and other experts, which is simply astounding,” said <a href="https://www.kaggle.com/antgoldbloom">Anthony Goldbloom</a>, CEO, Kaggle. “We continue to be inspired by the wealth of knowledge and diverse backgrounds of participants from around the world, who donate their spare time and skills to affect positive change in areas from early cancer detection to childhood education.”</p>
<p>Over the last five competitions, more than 54,000 Data Science Bowl teams have developed and submitted over 189,000 AI models aimed at improving everything from the detection of <a href="https://www.boozallen.com/e/media/press-release/nearly-10-000-global-problem-solvers-yield-winning-formulas-to-i.html">lung cancer</a> and <a href="https://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20151214005646/en/Annual-Data-Science-Bowl-Crowd-Sources-Solutions-Transform">heart disease</a> to monitoring <a href="https://www.boozallen.com/e/media/press-release/booz-allen-kaggle-announce-winner-of-the-data-science-bowl.html">ocean health</a> and <a href="https://www.boozallen.com/e/media/press-release/2018-data-science-bowl-results.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">helping accelerate life-saving medical research</a>.</p>
<p>For more information about past Data Science Bowl competitions, visit <a href="https://datasciencebowl.com/about/competitions/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">DataScienceBowl.com/Competitions</a>.</p>
<p><i>The contents of the PBS KIDS Measure Up! app were developed under a grant from the Department of Education. However, those contents do not necessarily represent the policy of the Department of Education, and you should not assume endorsement by the Federal Government. The app is funded by a Ready To Learn grant (PR/AWARD No. U295A150003, CFDA No. 84.295A) provided by the Department of Education to the Corporation for Public Broadcasting.</i></p>
<p style="text-align: center;">###</p>
<p><b>About Booz Allen Hamilton</b><b> </b></p>
<p>For more than 100 years, business, government, and military leaders have turned to Booz Allen Hamilton to solve their most complex problems. As a consulting firm with experts in analytics, digital, engineering and cyber, we help organizations transform. We are a key partner on some of the most innovative programs for governments worldwide and trusted by the most sensitive agencies. We work shoulder to shoulder with clients, using a mission-first approach to choose the right strategy and technology to help them realize their vision. With global headquarters in McLean, Virginia, our firm employs nearly 27,000 people globally, and had revenue of $6.70 billion for the 12 months ended March 31, 2019. To learn more, visit <a href="http://www.boozallen.com/">www.boozallen.com</a>. (NYSE: BAH)</p>
<p><b>About Kaggle </b></p>
<p>Kaggle is the world’s largest online data science competition community. With more than 4 million+ members across 194 countries, the Kaggle community uses its diverse set of academic backgrounds to solve complex data science problems. Working as individuals or in teams, the winning competitors are awarded prizes and industry recognition for their accomplishments.</p>
<p><b>About PBS KIDS</b></p>
<p>PBS KIDS, the number one educational media brand for kids, offers children ages 2-8 the opportunity to explore new ideas and new worlds through television, digital media, and community-based programs. PBS KIDS and local stations across the country support the entire ecosystem in which children learn, including their teachers, parents and community. Provided by stations, the free PBS KIDS 24/7 channel and live stream is available to more than 95% of U.S. TV households. Kidscreen- and Webby Award-winning <a href="http://www.pbskids.org/">pbskids.org</a> provides engaging interactive content, including digital games and streaming video. PBS KIDS offers mobile apps to help support young children’s learning, including the PBS KIDS Video app, which is available on a variety of mobile devices and on platforms such as Roku, Apple TV, Amazon Fire TV, Android TV, Samsung TV and Chromecast. PBS KIDS also offers parent and teacher resources to support children’s learning anytime and anywhere. For more information on PBS KIDS content and initiatives supporting school readiness and more, visit <a href="http://pbs.org/pressroom">pbs.org/pressroom</a>, or follow PBS KIDS on <a href="http://twitter.com/pbskids">Twitter</a>, <a href="https://www.facebook.com/CorporationForPublicBroadcasting">Facebook</a> , and <a href="https://www.instagram.com/pbskids">Instagram</a>.</p>
<p><b>About the Corporation for Public Broadcasting</b></p>
<p>The Corporation for Public Broadcasting (CPB), a private, nonprofit corporation created by Congress in 1967, is the steward of the federal government’s investment in public broadcasting. It helps support the operations of nearly 1,500 locally owned and operated public television and radio stations nationwide. CPB is also the largest single source of funding for research, technology and program development for public radio, television and related online services. For more information, visit <a href="http://www.cpb.org/">www.cpb.org</a> and follow us on Twitter<a href="https://twitter.com/CPBmedia">@CPBmedia</a>, <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/company/corporation-for-public-broadcasting">LinkedIn</a>, and <a href="https://www.facebook.com/CorporationForPublicBroadcasting">Facebook</a>, and <a href="http://www.cpb.org/subscribe">subscribe</a> for email updates.</p>
<p><b>About The Ready To Learn Initiative</b></p>
<p>The Ready To Learn Initiative is a cooperative agreement funded and managed by the U.S. Department of Education’s Office of Elementary and Secondary Education (OESE). It supports the development of innovative educational television and digital media targeted to preschool and early elementary school children and their families. Its general goal is to promote early learning and school readiness, with a particular interest in reaching low-income children. In addition to creating television and other media products, the program supports activities intended to promote national distribution of the programming, effective educational uses of the programming, community-based outreach and research on educational effectiveness.</p>
<p>BAHPR-CO</p>
<p><b>Contacts</b></p>
<p>Media Relations – Joseph Campbell, <a href="mailto:campbell_joseph@bah.com">campbell_joseph@bah.com</a>, 703-377-4422</p>
<p><i>The contents of the PBS KIDS Measure Up! app were developed under a grant from the Department of Education. However, those contents do not necessarily represent the policy of the Department of Education, and you should not assume endorsement by the Federal Government. The app is funded by a Ready To Learn grant (PR/AWARD No. U295A150003, CFDA No. 84.295A) provided by the Department of Education to the Corporation for Public Broadcasting.</i></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://datasciencebowl.com/using-data-science-to-advance-educational-tools-for-young-children-fifth-annual-data-science-bowl-announces-winners-thousands-participated-in-worldwide-competition/">Using Data Science to Advance Educational Tools for Young Children: Fifth Annual Data Science Bowl Announces Winners; Thousands Participated in Worldwide Competition</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://datasciencebowl.com">The Data Science Bowl</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Harnessing Algorithms for Healthier Hearts</title>
		<link>https://datasciencebowl.com/harnessing-algorithms-for-healthier-hearts/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2020 19:22:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Data Science]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://datasciencebowl.com/?p=5908</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>“The passion and technical expertise of the global data science community that is harnessed by the Data Science Bowl is extraordinary. They have been able to push the boundaries of what’s possible in this extremely complex and important challenge.” -Josh Sullivan, Booz Allen Hamilton senior vice president and artificial intelligence lead Each year, Booz Allen [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://datasciencebowl.com/harnessing-algorithms-for-healthier-hearts/">Harnessing Algorithms for Healthier Hearts</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://datasciencebowl.com">The Data Science Bowl</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>“The passion and technical expertise of the global data science community that is harnessed by the Data Science Bowl is extraordinary. They have been able to push the boundaries of what’s possible in this extremely complex and important challenge.”</em></p>
<p><em>&#8211;</em><a href="https://datasciencebowl.com/data-science-bowl-algorithm-could-transform-cardiac-care/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>Josh Sullivan</em></a>, Booz Allen Hamilton senior vice president and artificial intelligence lead</p>
<p>Each year, Booz Allen partners with Kaggle, the world’s leading online data science community, to challenge people across the globe to use their passion, grit, and curiosity to change the world in areas from <a href="https://www.3blmedia.com/News/Hatfield-Marine-Science-Center-Director-Praises-Data-Science-Bowl" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">ocean health</a> to <a href="https://www.3blmedia.com/News/Booz-Allen-Kaggle-Challenge-Data-Scientists-Medical-Community-Improve-Cancer-Screening-using" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">lung cancer detection</a> to <a href="https://www.3blmedia.com/News/Booz-Allen-Kaggles-Annual-Data-Science-Competition-Puts-Artificial-Intelligence-Work" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">biomedical research</a>.</p>
<p>During a 90-day period, participants gain access to unique data sets and are issued a specific challenge using the power of data science and artificial intelligence. The 2019 competition is focused on <a href="https://www.3blmedia.com/News/Booz-Allen-Kaggle-PBS-KIDS-Team-2019-Data-Science-Bowl" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">improving early childhood education</a>, and concludes next week with winners to be announced in early next month.</p>
<p>In recognition of American Heart Month this February, we’re highlighting a past challenge focused on cardiac health, and its lasting impact.</p>
<p><strong>A slow, manual process</strong></p>
<p>The heart’s ability to efficiently pump blood—a key indicator of heart disease—is traditionally measured through magnetic resonance imaging (MRI). It can take a specially trained cardiologist up to 20 minutes to read MRI images. The process is manual—and during this time, the physician could be delivering other aspects of patient care.</p>
<p>In a Data Science Bowl competition with the National Institutes of Health (NIH), Booz Allen and Kaggle rallied the global data science community in a challenge: develop an algorithm to automate the assessment process—and drastically cut the time and cost of diagnosing heart disease.</p>
<p><strong>An unprecedented pool of data</strong></p>
<p>The National Institutes of Health and Children’s National Medical Center compiled images from more than 1,000 patients—a data set larger than any previously released data set of its kind. Images represented a broad spectrum of individuals with different ages and genders, to ensure that algorithms would reflect the demands of real-world patient-care.</p>
<p>In 2016,  nearly 5,000 participants responded to the Data Science Bowl challenge, submitting 9,300 algorithms for consideration. The winning algorithms used AI to achieve in just seconds what takes a skilled cardiologist up to 20 minutes.</p>
<p><strong>An enduring impact on cardiac care—and MRI analysis</strong></p>
<p>The impact lasts beyond the 90-day challenge. A more efficient measurement process enhances physicians’ ability to diagnose heart conditions early—and proactively create robust treatment plans for stopping this silent killer.</p>
<p>The Data Science Bowl also inspired further progress in the area of MRI analysis. Researchers from around the world have been training algorithms to detect contours in the heart, which are critical for cardiologists’ diagnoses. In one example, NIH researchers are using artificial intelligence and an open-source processing platform to analyze MRI images—delivering results, including the heart’s contours, within 20-30 seconds.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://datasciencebowl.com/harnessing-algorithms-for-healthier-hearts/">Harnessing Algorithms for Healthier Hearts</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://datasciencebowl.com">The Data Science Bowl</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Get Smart: Resources for Data Science</title>
		<link>https://datasciencebowl.com/get-smart-resources-for-data-science/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2019 14:00:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Data Science]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://datasciencebowl.com/?p=5903</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Data science saw a 56% increase in job openings in the US in the last year according to LinkedIn. It’s also been at the top of Glassdoor’s Best Jobs in America for three consecutive years. If competing in the Data Science Bowl has you thinking about a career in data science, or simply boosting your [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://datasciencebowl.com/get-smart-resources-for-data-science/">Get Smart: Resources for Data Science</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://datasciencebowl.com">The Data Science Bowl</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Data science saw a 56% increase in job openings in the US in the last year according to LinkedIn. It’s also been at the top of Glassdoor’s <a href="https://www.techrepublic.com/article/the-10-best-tech-jobs-in-america-for-2018/">Best Jobs in America</a> for three consecutive years. If competing in the Data Science Bowl has you thinking about a career in data science, or simply boosting your skill set, our own Kirk Borne has compiled a list of resources to help.</p>
<p>Kirk Borne, Principal Data Scientist at Booz Allen, recommends starting with <a href="https://www.boozallen.com/s/insight/publication/field-guide-to-data-science.html">The Booz Allen Field Guide to Data Science</a> and then diving deep into some of these resources:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://courses.nvidia.com/courses" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">NVIDIA Deep Learning Institute</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.thisismetis.com/bootcamp-prep" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Metis Data Science Training</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.teamleada.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Leada’s online analytics labs</a></li>
<li><a href="https://generalassemb.ly/data/data-science" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Data Science Training by General Assembly</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.datacamp.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Learn Data Science Online by DataCamp</a></li>
<li><a href="http://datascience.community/colleges" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">(600+) Colleges and Universities with Data Science Degrees</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.datasciencegraduateprograms.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Data Science Master’s Degree Programs</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.edx.org/course/subject/data-analysis-statistics" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Data Analytics, Machine Learning, &amp; Statistics Courses at edX</a></li>
<li><a href="https://courses.analyticsvidhya.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Data Science Certifications</a> (by AnalyticsVidhya)</li>
<li><a href="https://www.analyticsvidhya.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Learn Everything About Analytics</a> (by AnalyticsVidhya)</li>
<li><a href="http://nycdatascience.com/data-science-bootcamp/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">NYC Data Science Academy</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.bigbang-datascience.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Big Bang Data Science Solutions</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.commonlounge.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">CommonLounge</a></li>
<li><a href="https://intellipaat.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">IntelliPaat Online Training</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.dataquest.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">DataQuest</a></li>
<li><a href="http://analytics.ncsu.edu/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">NCSU Institute for Advanced Analytics</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.districtdatalabs.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">District Data Labs</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.dataschool.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Data School</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.coursera.org/specialization/jhudatascience/1" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Coursera</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.udacity.com/course/data-scientist-nanodegree--nd025" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Udacity Nanodegree Program to Become a Data Scientist</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.udemy.com/courses/Business/Data-and-Analytics/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Udemy – Data &amp; Analytics</a></li>
<li><a href="http://insightdatascience.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Insight Data Science Fellows Program</a></li>
<li><a href="http://datasciencemasters.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">The Open Source Data Science Masters</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.jigsawacademy.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Jigsaw Academy Post Graduate Program in Data Science &amp; Machine Learning</a></li>
<li><a href="http://shop.oreilly.com/category/learning-path.do?cmp=pe-data-books-videos-product-promo_kdnuggets_lp_em" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">O’Reilly Media Learning Paths</a></li>
<li><a href="https://godatadriven.com/training-overview" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Data Engineering and Data Science Training by Go Data Driven</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.simplilearn.com/resources-to-learn-data-science-online-article" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">18 Resources to Learn Data Science Online</a> (by Simplilearn)</li>
<li><a href="https://www.learndatasci.com/best-data-science-online-courses/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Top Online Data Science Courses to Learn Data Science</a></li>
</ul>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://datasciencebowl.com/get-smart-resources-for-data-science/">Get Smart: Resources for Data Science</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://datasciencebowl.com">The Data Science Bowl</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Help for Data Scientists Surrounded by Those Not Yet Indoctrinated – by Kirk Borne</title>
		<link>https://datasciencebowl.com/help-for-data-scientists-surrounded-by-those-not-yet-indoctrinated-by-kirk-borne/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2019 14:00:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Data Science]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://datasciencebowl.com/?p=5900</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>One of the most important roles that we should be embracing right now is training the next-generation workforce in the art and science of data. Data literacy is a fundamental literacy that should be imparted at the earliest levels of learning, and it should continue through all years of education. While it’s never too early [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://datasciencebowl.com/help-for-data-scientists-surrounded-by-those-not-yet-indoctrinated-by-kirk-borne/">Help for Data Scientists Surrounded by Those Not Yet Indoctrinated – by Kirk Borne</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://datasciencebowl.com">The Data Science Bowl</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>One of the most important roles that we should be embracing right now is training the next-generation workforce in the art and science of data. Data literacy is a fundamental literacy that should be imparted at the earliest levels of learning, and it should continue through all years of education. While it’s never too early to begin teaching the fundamentals, it’s also never too late.</p>
<p>If you are participating in the Data Science Bowl and have family or friends who simply don’t understand what it’s all about, or what you do ‘with computers’ in your job, then these are the resources for you.</p>
<p>I recently gave a keynote titled, “<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ILPp-1fGEhI">Data Science for All</a>” during the 7<sup>th</sup> International Big Data &amp; Analytics Conference. In the video, you’ll hear informative and accessible examples of data science, machine learning, and statistics that can be used to communicate the power, uses, and possible misuses of data to non-data scientists, including students (of all ages), colleagues, and even your parents so they can understand what makes data literacy so much fun and such a valuable ally in any organization or career.</p>
<p>Two “…For Dummies” books can also help to bring data literacy to non-technical folks:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://amzn.to/2MJk4Vg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Data Science for Dummies</a> by <a href="https://twitter.com/BigDataGal" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Lillian Pierson</a></li>
<li><a href="https://amzn.to/2D7b4Fj" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Data Mining for Dummies</a> by <a href="https://twitter.com/metabrown312" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Meta Brown</a></li>
</ul>
<p>And just for good measure, here’s one more that I believe is an excellent data literacy companion: <a href="http://datajournalismhandbook.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">The Data Journalism Handbook</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://datasciencebowl.com/help-for-data-scientists-surrounded-by-those-not-yet-indoctrinated-by-kirk-borne/">Help for Data Scientists Surrounded by Those Not Yet Indoctrinated – by Kirk Borne</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://datasciencebowl.com">The Data Science Bowl</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Published in Nature Methods &#8211; Nucleus segmentation across imaging experiments: the 2018 Data Science Bowl</title>
		<link>https://datasciencebowl.com/published-in-nature-methods-nucleus-segmentation-across-imaging-experiments-the-2018-data-science-bowl/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2019 14:38:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Data Science]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://datasciencebowl.com/?p=5898</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The Broad Institute of MIT and Harvard has recently published its analysis of the 2018 Data Science Bowl in Nature Methods. (here) (PDF here). As stated by Dr. Anne Carpenter of the Broad Institute, “The top three solutions were very different from each other and offered unique insights to the problem, especially in pre/post processing [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://datasciencebowl.com/published-in-nature-methods-nucleus-segmentation-across-imaging-experiments-the-2018-data-science-bowl/">Published in Nature Methods &#8211; Nucleus segmentation across imaging experiments: the 2018 Data Science Bowl</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://datasciencebowl.com">The Data Science Bowl</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Broad Institute of MIT and Harvard has recently published its analysis of the 2018 Data Science Bowl in Nature Methods. (<a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/31636459">here</a>) (<a href="https://personal.broadinstitute.org/anne/publications/127_Caicedo_NatMethods_2019.pdf">PDF here</a>).</p>
<p>As stated by Dr. Anne Carpenter of the Broad Institute, “The top three solutions were very different from each other and offered unique insights to the problem, especially in pre/post processing techniques. Overall, the Broad Institute conclude that the challenge was successful: top models can instantly segment an image from an unseen experiment with no parameter tweaking or fine tuning or image annotations to a level that exceeds an expert quickly tuning a classical image processing pipeline. There is even a user-friendly web interface for one of the models stemming from this competition (<a href="https://www.nucleaizer.org">https://www.nucleaizer.org</a>) and already we are seeing many computer vision papers citing use of the annotated images from this competition, a tremendous resource for the community!”</p>
<p>All authors are members of the Broad Institute lab with the exception of d CherKeng Heng, whom they invited to contribute based on his many helpful comments during the course of the 2018 competition.</p>
<p>Overview: Segmenting the nuclei of cells in microscopy images is often the first step in the quantitative analysis of imaging data for biological and biomedical applications. Many bioimage analysis tools can segment nuclei in images but need to be selected and configured for every experiment. The 2018 Data Science Bowl attracted 3,891 teams worldwide to make the first attempt to build a segmentation method that could be applied to any two-dimensional light microscopy image of stained nuclei across experiments, with no human interaction. Top participants in the challenge succeeded in this task, developing deep-learning-based models that identified cell nuclei across many image types and experimental conditions without the need to manually adjust segmentation parameters. This represents an important step toward configuration-free bioimage analysis software tools. To continue reading, visit Nature Methods (<a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/31636459">here</a>) (<a href="https://personal.broadinstitute.org/anne/publications/127_Caicedo_NatMethods_2019.pdf">PDF here</a>).</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://datasciencebowl.com/published-in-nature-methods-nucleus-segmentation-across-imaging-experiments-the-2018-data-science-bowl/">Published in Nature Methods &#8211; Nucleus segmentation across imaging experiments: the 2018 Data Science Bowl</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://datasciencebowl.com">The Data Science Bowl</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>TweetChat &#8211; 2019 Data Science Bowl, November 14, 13:00 &#8211; 14:00 EDT #DataSciChat</title>
		<link>https://datasciencebowl.com/tweetchat-2019-data-science-bowl-november-14-1300-1400-edt-datascichat/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2019 13:51:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Data Science]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://datasciencebowl.com/?p=5896</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Mark Your Calendar: We will be hosting a 2019 Data Science Bowl TweetChat/#DataSciChat on Twitter, November 14, 2019 from 13:00 - 14:00 EDT (1-2pm EDT/US Eastern). The conversation will be hosted by Kirk Borne (@KirkDBorne) of @BoozAllen. He will be joined by Joe Rohner (@RohnerJoe), @BoozAllen, Data Science Bowl Lead; Jeremy Roberts (@JeremyR46362652), Director of [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://datasciencebowl.com/tweetchat-2019-data-science-bowl-november-14-1300-1400-edt-datascichat/">TweetChat &#8211; 2019 Data Science Bowl, November 14, 13:00 &#8211; 14:00 EDT #DataSciChat</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://datasciencebowl.com">The Data Science Bowl</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Mark Your Calendar:</strong></p>
<p>We will be hosting a 2019 Data Science Bowl TweetChat/#DataSciChat on Twitter, November 14, 2019 from 13:00 &#8211; 14:00 EDT (1-2pm EDT/US Eastern).</p>
<p>The conversation will be hosted by Kirk Borne (@KirkDBorne) of <a href="https://www.kaggle.com/BoozAllen">@BoozAllen</a>. He will be joined by Joe Rohner (@RohnerJoe), <a href="https://www.kaggle.com/BoozAllen">@BoozAllen</a>, Data Science Bowl Lead; Jeremy Roberts (@JeremyR46362652), Director of Learning Technologies <a href="https://www.kaggle.com/PBSKIDS">@PBSKIDS</a>; and other Data Science Bowl team members.</p>
<p>Come join the conversation about #DataScience #MachineLearning #EarlyChildhoodEducation #DataSciBowl.</p>
<p>To join and view the chat during the session, use the hashtag #DataSciChat. We&#8217;ll cover questions on Data Science, Social Good and Early Childhood Learning as it relates to this year&#8217;s competition purpose.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://datasciencebowl.com/tweetchat-2019-data-science-bowl-november-14-1300-1400-edt-datascichat/">TweetChat &#8211; 2019 Data Science Bowl, November 14, 13:00 &#8211; 14:00 EDT #DataSciChat</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://datasciencebowl.com">The Data Science Bowl</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Booz Allen, Kaggle and PBS KIDS Partner to Leverage Data Science Tools in Media for Early Childhood Education Insight</title>
		<link>https://datasciencebowl.com/booz-allen-kaggle-and-pbs-kids-partner-to-leverage-data-science-tools-in-media-for-early-childhood-education-insight/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2019 13:00:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Data Science]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://datasciencebowl.com/?p=5890</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>FIFTH ANNUAL DATA SCIENCE BOWL WILL ANALYZE DIGITAL GAME PLAY TO HELP BUILD MORE EFFECTIVE EDUCATIONAL MEDIA TOOLS FOR CHILDREN McLean, Va. [October 24, 2019] – Over the last four years, more than 50,000 participants have developed and submitted over 114,000 artificial intelligence (AI) algorithms to improve everything from detection of lung cancer and heart [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://datasciencebowl.com/booz-allen-kaggle-and-pbs-kids-partner-to-leverage-data-science-tools-in-media-for-early-childhood-education-insight/">Booz Allen, Kaggle and PBS KIDS Partner to Leverage Data Science Tools in Media for Early Childhood Education Insight</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://datasciencebowl.com">The Data Science Bowl</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h4>FIFTH ANNUAL DATA SCIENCE BOWL WILL ANALYZE DIGITAL GAME PLAY TO HELP BUILD MORE EFFECTIVE EDUCATIONAL MEDIA TOOLS FOR CHILDREN</h4>
<p><a name="_GoBack"></a> McLean, Va. [October 24, 2019] – Over the last four years, more than 50,000 participants have developed and submitted over 114,000 artificial intelligence (AI) algorithms to improve everything from detection of <a href="https://www.boozallen.com/e/media/press-release/nearly-10-000-global-problem-solvers-yield-winning-formulas-to-i.html">lung cancer</a> and <a href="https://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20151214005646/en/Annual-Data-Science-Bowl-Crowd-Sources-Solutions-Transform">heart disease</a>, to monitoring <a href="https://www.boozallen.com/e/media/press-release/booz-allen-kaggle-announce-winner-of-the-data-science-bowl.html">ocean health</a> and <a href="https://www.boozallen.com/e/media/press-release/2018-data-science-bowl-results.html">helping accelerate life-saving medical research</a> as part of the annual <a href="http://www.datatsciencebowl.com/">Data Science Bowl</a>®.</p>
<p>In partnership with PBS KIDS, this year’s competition will look at advancements in early childhood education. The results will lead to better designed games and improved learning outcomes, empowering children, parents, caregivers and educators across the globe with insights into how young children learn through media and which approaches work best to help them build on foundational learning skills. The 90-day Data Science Bowl competition will award winning participants with a share of $160,000 in cash prizes.</p>
<p>Research shows much of the most critical brain development in children takes place <a href="http://www.aft.org/sites/default/files/periodicals/TheEarlyCatastrophe.pdf">before they even reach kindergarten</a>. Child development experts indicate it is during these first five years that children develop linguistic, cognitive, social, emotional, and regulatory skills that predict their later functioning in many domains. Yet early education approaches around the world vary in quality, accessibility, technique and engagement, leading to disparities in children’s learning and development. Further, access to effective early learning resources is critical, as research demonstrates that high-quality educational media can help support young learners. To better understand these challenges and develop the most effective approaches to high-quality early educational media, <a href="http://www.boozallen.com/">Booz Allen Hamilton</a> (NYSE: BAH) and <a href="http://www.kaggle.com/">Kaggle</a> today launched the fifth annual <a href="http://www.datatsciencebowl.com/">Data Science Bowl</a>®, the world’s largest data science competition focused on social good.</p>
<p>“Early childhood education is a pivotal point in a child’s development that can provide them with a profound advantage and set the foundation for lifelong success,” said Dr. Josh Sullivan, senior vice president, Booz Allen Hamilton and leader of the firm’s analytics and AI business. “For the fifth annual Data Science Bowl, we’re excited to harness the collective power of people around the world to uncover how children learn and develop more beneficial and effective educational tools for children.”</p>
<p><b>The 2019 Data Science Bowl At-A-Glance: </b></p>
<ul>
<li><b>Why does this challenge matter?</b> The first five years of a child’s life are <a href="https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02568543.2016.1273285">critical to their development</a> as it’s when they learn and cultivate linguistic, cognitive, social, emotional and regulatory skills that predict their later functioning in many domains. Access to high-quality, effective early learning resources is critical during the early childhood developmental period and supporting education at an early age is also key for other long-term <a href="https://science.sciencemag.org/content/333/6040/299">success factors</a> such as increased qualifications, employment, and earnings.</li>
<li><b>What will participants do?</b> Participants will be provided with anonymous gameplay data from the <a href="https://pbskids.org/apps/pbs-kids-measure-up.html">PBS KIDS Measure Up!</a> app, which was developed as a part of the CPB-PBS Ready to Learn Initiative with funding from the U.S. Department of Education. They will be tasked with creating algorithms that utilize information about how players use the app to determine what they know and are learning from the experience, in order to discover important relationships between their engagement with educational media and learning. The insights gleaned from these solutions will help PBS KIDS and other organizations create new solutions, content and products that help ensure each and every user has the best chance to learn important skills, helping improve childhood learning access and achievement.</li>
<li><b>Privacy and data security.</b> PBS KIDS is committed to creating a safe and secure environment that family members of all ages can enjoy. The PBS KIDS Measure Up! app does not collect any personally identifying information, such as name or location. All of the data used in the competition is anonymous. The Data Science Bowl and the use of data for this year’s competition has been reviewed to ensure that it meets requirements of applicable child privacy regulations by PRIVO. <a href="http://privo.com/">PRIVO</a> is a leading global industry expert in children’s online privacy and delegated consent management.</li>
</ul>
<p>“We’re thrilled to be a part of this year’s Data Science Bowl, which will harness the power of technology to help drive the future of learning,” said Lesli Rotenberg, Chief Programming Executive and General Manager, Children’s Media and Education, PBS. “PBS KIDS has long been an innovator in the educational media space, and through this year’s competition we look forward to gaining new insights into how to build games that help children thrive in school and life.”</p>
<p>“We’re excited to once again partner with Booz Allen to use the combined power of crowdsourcing and data science to affect change in an important field,” said Anthony Goldbloom, CEO of Kaggle. “This competition not only has the potential to impact the way we understand and approach learning but how we continue cultivating the data scientists of the future.”</p>
<p>To participate in the competition, please register and download the data set <a href="https://www.kaggle.com/c/data-science-bowl-2019/overview">here</a>. To learn more about the Data Science Bowl, including more information about past Data Science Bowl competitions, visit <a href="http://www.datatsciencebowl.com/">DataScienceBowl.com</a>.</p>
<p>For more information about past Data Science Bowl competitions, visit <a href="http://cts.businesswire.com/ct/CT?id=smartlink&amp;url=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.datasciencebowl.com%2Fcompetitions&amp;esheet=51492809&amp;newsitemid=20170112005573&amp;lan=en-US&amp;anchor=DataScienceBowl.com%2FCompetitions&amp;index=12&amp;md5=1538865d3cd7f83c8de7faca12e519a5" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">DataScienceBowl.com/Competitions</a>.</p>
<p>###</p>
<p><b>About Booz Allen Hamilton</b><b> </b></p>
<p>For more than 100 years, military, government, and business leaders have turned to Booz Allen Hamilton to solve their most complex problems. As a consulting firm with experts in analytics, digital, engineering, and cyber, we help organizations transform. We are a key partner on some of the most innovative programs for governments worldwide and trusted by their most sensitive agencies. We work shoulder to shoulder with clients, using a mission-first approach to choose the right strategy and technology to help them realize their vision. With global headquarters in McLean, Virginia and more than 80 offices worldwide, our firm employs more than 26,300 people and had revenue of $6.7 billion for the 12 months ending March 31, 2019. To learn more, visit <a href="http://www.BoozAllen.com/">BoozAllen.com</a>. (NYSE: BAH)</p>
<p><b>About Kaggle </b></p>
<p>Kaggle is the world&#8217;s largest community of data scientists. Join us to compete, collaborate, learn, and do your data science work. Kaggle&#8217;s platform is the fastest way to get started on a new data science project. Spin up a Jupyter notebook with a single click. Build with our huge repository of free code and data. Stumped? Ask the friendly Kaggle community for help. Follow us on <a href="http://twitter.com/kaggle">twitter</a> for helpful resources and interesting competitions.</p>
<p><b>About PBS KIDS</b></p>
<p>PBS KIDS, the number one educational media brand for kids, offers children ages 2-8 the opportunity to explore new ideas and new worlds through television, digital media and community-based programs. PBS KIDS and local stations across the country support the entire ecosystem in which children learn, including their teachers, parents and community. Provided by stations, the free PBS KIDS 24/7 channel and live stream is available to more than 95% of U.S. TV households. Kidscreen- and Webby Award-winning <a href="http://www.pbskids.org/">pbskids.org</a> provides engaging interactive content, including digital games and streaming video. PBS KIDS offers mobile apps to help support young children’s learning, including the PBS KIDS Video app, which is available on a variety of mobile devices and on platforms such as Roku, Apple TV, Amazon Fire TV, Android TV, Samsung TV and Chromecast. PBS KIDS also offers parent and teacher resources to support children’s learning anytime and anywhere. For more information on PBS KIDS content and initiatives supporting school readiness and more, visit <a href="http://pbs.org/pressroom">pbs.org/pressroom</a>, or follow PBS KIDS on <a href="http://twitter.com/pbskids">Twitter</a>, <a href="http://www.facebook.com/pbskids">Facebook</a> and <a href="https://www.instagram.com/pbskids">Instagram</a>.</p>
<p><b>About the Corporation for Public Broadcasting</b></p>
<p>The Corporation for Public Broadcasting (CPB), a private, nonprofit corporation created by Congress in 1967, is the steward of the federal government’s investment in public broadcasting. It helps support the operations of nearly 1,500 locally owned and operated public television and radio stations nationwide. CPB is also the largest single source of funding for research, technology and program development for public radio, television and related online services. For more information, visit <a href="http://www.cpb.org/">www.cpb.org</a> and follow us on Twitter <a href="https://twitter.com/CPBmedia">@CPBmedia</a>, <a href="https://www.facebook.com/CorporationForPublicBroadcasting">Facebook</a> and <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/company/corporation-for-public-broadcasting">LinkedIn</a>, and <a href="http://www.cpb.org/subscribe">subscribe</a> for email updates.</p>
<p><b>About The Ready To Learn Initiative</b></p>
<p>The Ready To Learn Initiative is a cooperative agreement funded and managed by the U.S. Department of Education’s Office of Elementary and Secondary Education (OESE)Office of Innovation and Improvement. It supports the development of innovative educational television and digital media targeted to preschool and early elementary school children and their families. Its general goal is to promote early learning and school readiness, with a particular interest in reaching low-income children. In addition to creating television and other media products, the program supports activities intended to promote national distribution of the programming, effective educational uses of the programming, community-based outreach and research on educational effectiveness.</p>
<p><b>Contacts</b></p>
<p>Media Relations – <a href="mailto:campbelll_joseph@bah.com">Joseph Campbell</a>, 703-377-4422</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://datasciencebowl.com/booz-allen-kaggle-and-pbs-kids-partner-to-leverage-data-science-tools-in-media-for-early-childhood-education-insight/">Booz Allen, Kaggle and PBS KIDS Partner to Leverage Data Science Tools in Media for Early Childhood Education Insight</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://datasciencebowl.com">The Data Science Bowl</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Illuminate Learning. Ignite Possibilities.</title>
		<link>https://datasciencebowl.com/illuminate-learning-ignite-possibilities/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2019 17:45:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Competitions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://datasciencebowl.com/?p=5874</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The Challenge  This year’s Data Science Bowl, presented by Booz Allen Hamilton and Kaggle, focuses on identifying factors to help measure how young children learn from media and which approaches work best to help them build on those foundational skills. Using anonymous gameplay data from the PBS KIDS Measure Up! app, developed as [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://datasciencebowl.com/illuminate-learning-ignite-possibilities/">Illuminate Learning. Ignite Possibilities.</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://datasciencebowl.com">The Data Science Bowl</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><div class="fusion-fullwidth fullwidth-box fusion-builder-row-1 nonhundred-percent-fullwidth non-hundred-percent-height-scrolling" style="background-color: rgba(255,255,255,0);background-position: center center;background-repeat: no-repeat;padding-top:0px;padding-right:0px;padding-bottom:40px;padding-left:0px;margin-bottom: 0px;margin-top: 0px;border-width: 0px 0px 0px 0px;border-color:#eae9e9;border-style:solid;" ><div class="fusion-builder-row fusion-row"><div class="fusion-layout-column fusion_builder_column fusion-builder-column-0 fusion_builder_column_1_1 1_1 fusion-one-full fusion-column-first fusion-column-last" style="margin-top:0px;margin-bottom:20px;"><div class="fusion-column-wrapper fusion-flex-column-wrapper-legacy" style="background-position:left top;background-repeat:no-repeat;-webkit-background-size:cover;-moz-background-size:cover;-o-background-size:cover;background-size:cover;padding: 0px 0px 0px 0px;"><style type="text/css"></style><div class="fusion-title title fusion-title-1 fusion-sep-none fusion-title-text fusion-title-size-three" style="margin-top:0px;margin-right:0px;margin-bottom:30px;margin-left:0px;"><h3 class="title-heading-left" style="margin:0;">The Challenge</h3></div><div class="fusion-text fusion-text-1"><p>This year’s Data Science Bowl, presented by Booz Allen Hamilton and Kaggle, focuses on identifying factors to help measure how young children learn from media and which approaches work best to help them build on those foundational skills. Using anonymous gameplay data from the PBS KIDS Measure Up! app, developed as a part of the CPB-PBS Ready To Learn Initiative with funding from the U.S. Department of Education, participants will create an algorithm that will lead to better designed games and greater learning outcomes, benefiting all in the children’s learning ecosystem.</p>
</div><div class="fusion-clearfix"></div></div></div></div></div><div class="fusion-fullwidth fullwidth-box fusion-builder-row-2 fusion-parallax-none hundred-percent-fullwidth non-hundred-percent-height-scrolling" style="background-color: #5d173b;background-image: url(&quot;https://datasciencebowl.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/watermark-cropped2.png&quot;);background-position: center center;background-repeat: no-repeat;padding-top:80px;padding-right:0px;padding-bottom:80px;padding-left:0px;margin-bottom: 0px;margin-top: 0px;border-width: 0px 0px 0px 0px;border-color:#eae9e9;border-style:solid;-webkit-background-size:cover;-moz-background-size:cover;-o-background-size:cover;background-size:cover;" ><div class="fusion-builder-row fusion-row"><div class="fusion-layout-column fusion_builder_column fusion-builder-column-1 fusion_builder_column_1_1 1_1 fusion-one-full fusion-column-first fusion-column-last" style="margin-top:0px;margin-bottom:0px;"><div class="fusion-column-wrapper fusion-flex-column-wrapper-legacy" style="background-position:left top;background-repeat:no-repeat;-webkit-background-size:cover;-moz-background-size:cover;-o-background-size:cover;background-size:cover;padding: 0px 0px 0px 0px;"><div class="fusion-video fusion-youtube fusion-aligncenter" style="max-width:1100px;max-height:619px; width:100%"><div class="video-shortcode"><iframe title="YouTube video player 1" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/45Da3eqQKXQ?wmode=transparent&autoplay=0&amp;rel=0" width="1100" height="619" allowfullscreen allow="autoplay; fullscreen"></iframe></div></div><div class="fusion-clearfix"></div></div></div></div></div><div class="fusion-fullwidth fullwidth-box fusion-builder-row-3 fusion-parallax-none background-cover hide hundred-percent-fullwidth non-hundred-percent-height-scrolling" style="background-color: rgba(255,255,255,0);background-image: url(&quot;https://datasciencebowl.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/illustration-cells-web-bg2.jpg&quot;);background-position: center center;background-repeat: repeat-x;padding-top:20px;padding-right:0px;padding-bottom:0px;padding-left:0px;margin-bottom: 0px;margin-top: 0px;border-width: 0px 0px 0px 0px;border-color:#eae9e9;border-style:solid;" ><div class="fusion-builder-row fusion-row"><div class="fusion-layout-column fusion_builder_column fusion-builder-column-2 fusion_builder_column_1_1 1_1 fusion-one-full fusion-column-first fusion-column-last" style="margin-top:0px;margin-bottom:0px;"><div class="fusion-column-wrapper fusion-flex-column-wrapper-legacy" style="background-position:left top;background-repeat:no-repeat;-webkit-background-size:cover;-moz-background-size:cover;-o-background-size:cover;background-size:cover;padding: 0px 0px 0px 0px;"><div class="imageframe-align-center"><span class=" fusion-imageframe imageframe-none imageframe-1 hover-type-none"><img width="1000" height="1135" title="illustration-cells-1.3" src="https://datasciencebowl.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/illustration-cells-1.3.jpg" alt class="img-responsive wp-image-5880" srcset="http://bahdatascience.wpenginepowered.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/illustration-cells-1.3-200x227.jpg 200w, http://bahdatascience.wpenginepowered.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/illustration-cells-1.3-400x454.jpg 400w, http://bahdatascience.wpenginepowered.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/illustration-cells-1.3-600x681.jpg 600w, http://bahdatascience.wpenginepowered.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/illustration-cells-1.3-800x908.jpg 800w, http://bahdatascience.wpenginepowered.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/illustration-cells-1.3.jpg 1000w" sizes="(max-width: 800px) 100vw, 1000px" /></span></div><div class="fusion-clearfix"></div></div></div></div></div><div class="fusion-fullwidth fullwidth-box fusion-builder-row-4 nonhundred-percent-fullwidth non-hundred-percent-height-scrolling" style="background-color: rgba(255,255,255,0);background-position: center center;background-repeat: no-repeat;padding-top:76px;padding-right:0px;padding-bottom:40px;padding-left:0px;margin-bottom: 0px;margin-top: 0px;border-width: 0px 0px 0px 0px;border-color:#eae9e9;border-style:solid;" ><div class="fusion-builder-row fusion-row"><div class="fusion-layout-column fusion_builder_column fusion-builder-column-3 fusion_builder_column_1_1 1_1 fusion-one-full fusion-column-first fusion-column-last" style="margin-top:0px;margin-bottom:0px;"><div class="fusion-column-wrapper fusion-flex-column-wrapper-legacy" style="background-position:left top;background-repeat:no-repeat;-webkit-background-size:cover;-moz-background-size:cover;-o-background-size:cover;background-size:cover;padding: 0px 0px 0px 0px;"><div class="fusion-text fusion-text-2"><h3>Why focus on early childhood education?</h3>
<p>Studies show that much of the most critical brain development in children takes place before they even reach kindergarten. Child development experts indicate it is during these first five years that children develop linguistic, cognitive, social, emotional, and regulatory skills that predict their later functioning in many domains, which is why access to high-quality, effective early learning resources is critical. Research demonstrates that supporting education at an early age is also key for long-term success, and efficacy research from the CPB-PBS Ready To Learn Initiative finds that high-quality educational media moves the needle on children’s learning.</p>
</div><div class="fusion-clearfix"></div></div></div></div></div><div class="fusion-fullwidth fullwidth-box fusion-builder-row-5 nonhundred-percent-fullwidth non-hundred-percent-height-scrolling" style="background-color: rgba(255,255,255,0);background-position: center center;background-repeat: no-repeat;padding-top:0px;padding-right:0px;padding-bottom:20px;padding-left:0px;margin-bottom: 0px;margin-top: 0px;border-width: 0px 0px 0px 0px;border-color:#eae9e9;border-style:solid;" ><div class="fusion-builder-row fusion-row"><div class="fusion-layout-column fusion_builder_column fusion-builder-column-4 fusion_builder_column_1_1 1_1 fusion-one-full fusion-column-first fusion-column-last" style="margin-top:0px;margin-bottom:20px;"><div class="fusion-column-wrapper fusion-flex-column-wrapper-legacy" style="background-position:left top;background-repeat:no-repeat;-webkit-background-size:cover;-moz-background-size:cover;-o-background-size:cover;background-size:cover;padding: 0px 0px 0px 0px;"><div class="fusion-text fusion-text-3"><h3>What is the prize?</h3>
<p>We’ll award $160,000 in cash to the top placing teams, as follows:</p>
</div><div class="fusion-content-boxes content-boxes columns row fusion-columns-5 fusion-columns-total-5 fusion-content-boxes-1 content-boxes-icon-on-top content-left" data-animationOffset="top-into-view" style="margin-top:0px;margin-bottom:0px;"><style type="text/css">.fusion-content-boxes-1 .heading .content-box-heading {color:#333333;}
					.fusion-content-boxes-1 .fusion-content-box-hover .link-area-link-icon-hover .heading .content-box-heading,
					.fusion-content-boxes-1 .fusion-content-box-hover .link-area-link-icon-hover .heading .heading-link .content-box-heading,
					.fusion-content-boxes-1 .fusion-content-box-hover .link-area-box-hover .heading .content-box-heading,
					.fusion-content-boxes-1 .fusion-content-box-hover .link-area-box-hover .heading .heading-link .content-box-heading,
					.fusion-content-boxes-1 .fusion-content-box-hover .link-area-link-icon-hover.link-area-box .fusion-read-more,
					.fusion-content-boxes-1 .fusion-content-box-hover .link-area-link-icon-hover.link-area-box .fusion-read-more::after,
					.fusion-content-boxes-1 .fusion-content-box-hover .link-area-link-icon-hover.link-area-box .fusion-read-more::before,
					.fusion-content-boxes-1 .fusion-content-box-hover .fusion-read-more:hover:after,
					.fusion-content-boxes-1 .fusion-content-box-hover .fusion-read-more:hover:before,
					.fusion-content-boxes-1 .fusion-content-box-hover .fusion-read-more:hover,
					.fusion-content-boxes-1 .fusion-content-box-hover .link-area-box-hover.link-area-box .fusion-read-more,
					.fusion-content-boxes-1 .fusion-content-box-hover .link-area-box-hover.link-area-box .fusion-read-more::after,
					.fusion-content-boxes-1 .fusion-content-box-hover .link-area-box-hover.link-area-box .fusion-read-more::before,
					.fusion-content-boxes-1 .fusion-content-box-hover .link-area-link-icon-hover .icon .circle-no,
					.fusion-content-boxes-1 .heading .heading-link:hover .content-box-heading {
						color: #6ac6c1;
					}
					.fusion-content-boxes-1 .fusion-content-box-hover .link-area-box-hover .icon .circle-no {
						color: #6ac6c1 !important;
					}.fusion-content-boxes-1 .fusion-content-box-hover .link-area-box.link-area-box-hover .fusion-content-box-button {background: #6ac6c1;color: #282828;}.fusion-content-boxes-1 .fusion-content-box-hover .link-area-box.link-area-box-hover .fusion-content-box-button .fusion-button-text {color: #282828;}
					.fusion-content-boxes-1 .fusion-content-box-hover .link-area-link-icon-hover .heading .icon > span {
						background-color: #6ac6c1 !important;
					}
					.fusion-content-boxes-1 .fusion-content-box-hover .link-area-box-hover .heading .icon > span {
						border-color: #6ac6c1 !important;
					}</style><div class="fusion-column content-box-column content-box-column-1 col-lg-2 col-md-2 col-sm-2 fusion-content-box-hover content-box-column-first-in-row"><div class="col content-box-wrapper content-wrapper link-area-link-icon icon-hover-animation-fade" style="background-color:rgba(255,255,255,0);" data-animationOffset="top-into-view"><div class="heading heading-with-icon icon-left"><div aria-hidden="true" class="image"><img src="https://datasciencebowl.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/icon-trophy-1st-e1554145059627.png" width="150" height="87.75" alt="Trophy Icon First Place" /></div><h3 class="content-box-heading" style="font-size:18px;line-height:23px;">$100,000 – 1st Prize</h3></div></div></div><div class="fusion-column content-box-column content-box-column-2 col-lg-2 col-md-2 col-sm-2 fusion-content-box-hover "><div class="col content-box-wrapper content-wrapper link-area-link-icon icon-hover-animation-fade" style="background-color:rgba(255,255,255,0);" data-animationOffset="top-into-view"><div class="heading heading-with-icon icon-left"><div aria-hidden="true" class="image"><img src="https://datasciencebowl.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/icon-trophy-2nd-e1554145097504-300x176.png" width="150" height="88" alt="Trophy Icon Second Place" /></div><h3 class="content-box-heading" style="font-size:18px;line-height:23px;">$30,000 – 2nd Prize</h3></div></div></div><div class="fusion-column content-box-column content-box-column-3 col-lg-2 col-md-2 col-sm-2 fusion-content-box-hover "><div class="col content-box-wrapper content-wrapper link-area-link-icon icon-hover-animation-fade" style="background-color:rgba(255,255,255,0);" data-animationOffset="top-into-view"><div class="heading heading-with-icon icon-left"><div aria-hidden="true" class="image"><img src="https://datasciencebowl.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/icon-trophy-3rd-e1554145299593-800x468.png" width="150" height="87.75" alt="Trophy Icon Third Place" /></div><h3 class="content-box-heading" style="font-size:18px;line-height:23px;">$10,000 – 3rd Prize</h3></div></div></div><div class="fusion-column content-box-column content-box-column-4 col-lg-2 col-md-2 col-sm-2 fusion-content-box-hover "><div class="col content-box-wrapper content-wrapper link-area-link-icon icon-hover-animation-fade" style="background-color:rgba(255,255,255,0);" data-animationOffset="top-into-view"><div class="heading heading-with-icon icon-left"><div aria-hidden="true" class="image"><img src="https://datasciencebowl.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/icon-medal-e1554145330806-800x468.png" width="150" height="87.75" alt="Medal Award" /></div><h3 class="content-box-heading" style="font-size:18px;line-height:23px;">$10,000 – 4th Prize</h3></div></div></div><div class="fusion-column content-box-column content-box-column-5 col-lg-2 col-md-2 col-sm-2 fusion-content-box-hover content-box-column-last content-box-column-last-in-row"><div class="col content-box-wrapper content-wrapper link-area-link-icon icon-hover-animation-fade" style="background-color:rgba(255,255,255,0);" data-animationOffset="top-into-view"><div class="heading heading-with-icon icon-left"><div aria-hidden="true" class="image"><img src="https://datasciencebowl.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/icon-medal-e1554145330806-800x468.png" width="150" height="87.75" alt="Medal Award" /></div><h3 class="content-box-heading" style="font-size:18px;line-height:23px;">$10,000 – 5th Prize</h3></div></div></div><style type="text/css">
						.fusion-content-boxes-1 .fusion-content-box-hover .heading-link:hover .icon i.circle-yes,
						.fusion-content-boxes-1 .fusion-content-box-hover .link-area-box:hover .heading-link .icon i.circle-yes,
						.fusion-content-boxes-1 .fusion-content-box-hover .link-area-link-icon-hover .heading .icon i.circle-yes,
						.fusion-content-boxes-1 .fusion-content-box-hover .link-area-box-hover .heading .icon i.circle-yes {
							background-color: #6ac6c1 !important;
							border-color: #6ac6c1 !important;
						}</style><div class="fusion-clearfix"></div></div><div class="fusion-clearfix"></div></div></div></div></div><div class="fusion-fullwidth fullwidth-box fusion-builder-row-6 nonhundred-percent-fullwidth non-hundred-percent-height-scrolling" style="background-color: rgba(255,255,255,0);background-position: center center;background-repeat: no-repeat;padding-top:0px;padding-right:0px;padding-bottom:40px;padding-left:0px;margin-bottom: 0px;margin-top: 0px;border-width: 0px 0px 0px 0px;border-color:#eae9e9;border-style:solid;" ><div class="fusion-builder-row fusion-row"><div class="fusion-layout-column fusion_builder_column fusion-builder-column-5 fusion_builder_column_1_1 1_1 fusion-one-full fusion-column-first fusion-column-last" style="margin-top:0px;margin-bottom:20px;"><div class="fusion-column-wrapper fusion-flex-column-wrapper-legacy" style="background-position:left top;background-repeat:no-repeat;-webkit-background-size:cover;-moz-background-size:cover;-o-background-size:cover;background-size:cover;padding: 0px 0px 0px 0px;"><div class="fusion-text fusion-text-4"><h3>Where does the data for the competition come from?</h3>
<p>The data used in this competition is anonymous, tabular data of interactions with the PBS KIDS Measure Up! app. Select data, such as a user’s in-app assessment score or their path through the game, is collected by the PBS KIDS Measure Up! app, a game-based learning tool.</p>
<p>PBS KIDS does not collect any personally identifying information, such as name or location. PBS KIDS is committed to creating a safe and secure environment that family members of all ages can enjoy. Any information that PBS KIDS collects is used to improve content. This allows for gaming experiences to meet kids where they are and support their learning. To view the full PBS KIDS privacy policy, please visit: <a href="https://pbskids.org/privacy/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">pbskids.org/privacy/</a>.</p>
<p>No one will be able to download the entire data set and the participants do not have access to any personally identifiable information about individual users. Winning solutions from the Data Science Bowl will be open sourced, enabling access for everyone to leverage learnings to improve early childhood education outcomes through media. The Data Science Bowl and the use of data for this year’s competition has been reviewed to ensure that it meets requirements of applicable child privacy regulations by PRIVO.</p>
<h3>What is the PBS KIDS Measure Up! app?</h3>
<p>In the PBS KIDS Measure Up! app, children ages 3 to 5 learn early STEM concepts focused on length, width, capacity, and weight while going on an adventure through Treetop City, Magma Peak, and Crystal Caves. Joined by their favorite PBS KIDS characters from <i>Dinosaur Train</i>, <i>Peg + Cat</i>, and <i>Sid the Science Kid</i>, children can also collect rewards and unlock digital toys as they play.</p>
<p>PBS KIDS Measure Up! was developed as part of the <a href="https://www.pbslearningmedia.org/readytolearn/">CPB-PBS Ready To Learn Initiative</a>, with funding from the U.S. Department of Education. To learn more about PBS KIDS Measure Up!, please click <a href="https://pbskids.org/apps/pbs-kids-measure-up.html">here</a>.</p>
</div><div class="fusion-sep-clear"></div><div class="fusion-separator fusion-full-width-sep" style="margin-left: auto;margin-right: auto;margin-bottom:40px;width:100%;"></div><div class="fusion-sep-clear"></div><div class="fusion-text fusion-text-5"><h2 style="text-align: center;">Presented By:</h2>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img class="alignnone size-400 wp-image-5338" src="https://datasciencebowl.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/bah-400x64.png" alt="" width="400" height="64" srcset="http://bahdatascience.wpenginepowered.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/bah-200x32.png 200w, http://bahdatascience.wpenginepowered.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/bah-300x48.png 300w, http://bahdatascience.wpenginepowered.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/bah-400x64.png 400w, http://bahdatascience.wpenginepowered.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/bah-600x97.png 600w, http://bahdatascience.wpenginepowered.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/bah-768x124.png 768w, http://bahdatascience.wpenginepowered.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/bah-800x129.png 800w, http://bahdatascience.wpenginepowered.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/bah-1024x165.png 1024w, http://bahdatascience.wpenginepowered.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/bah-1200x193.png 1200w" sizes="(max-width: 400px) 100vw, 400px" /><img class="alignnone wp-image-5336" src="https://datasciencebowl.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/kaggle-300x136.png" alt="" width="150" height="68" srcset="http://bahdatascience.wpenginepowered.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/kaggle-200x91.png 200w, http://bahdatascience.wpenginepowered.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/kaggle-300x136.png 300w, http://bahdatascience.wpenginepowered.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/kaggle-400x182.png 400w, http://bahdatascience.wpenginepowered.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/kaggle-600x273.png 600w, http://bahdatascience.wpenginepowered.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/kaggle-768x349.png 768w, http://bahdatascience.wpenginepowered.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/kaggle-800x364.png 800w, http://bahdatascience.wpenginepowered.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/kaggle-1024x465.png 1024w, http://bahdatascience.wpenginepowered.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/kaggle.png 1056w" sizes="(max-width: 150px) 100vw, 150px" /></p>
<h2 style="text-align: center;">Data Partner:</h2>
<div class="imageframe-align-center"><span class=" fusion-imageframe imageframe-none imageframe-2 hover-type-none" style="max-width:150px;"><img width="413" height="400" alt="PBS Kids" title="PBSKIDS_logo_web" src="https://datasciencebowl.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/PBSKIDS_logo_web.png" class="img-responsive wp-image-5876" srcset="http://bahdatascience.wpenginepowered.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/PBSKIDS_logo_web-200x194.png 200w, http://bahdatascience.wpenginepowered.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/PBSKIDS_logo_web-400x387.png 400w, http://bahdatascience.wpenginepowered.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/PBSKIDS_logo_web.png 413w" sizes="(max-width: 800px) 100vw, 413px" /></span></div>
</div><div class="fusion-sep-clear"></div><div class="fusion-separator fusion-full-width-sep" style="margin-left: auto;margin-right: auto;margin-bottom:80px;width:100%;"></div><div class="fusion-sep-clear"></div><div class="fusion-text fusion-text-6 footnote"><p><i>PBS KIDS and the PBS KIDS Logo are registered trademarks of PBS. Used with permission.<br />
</i><i>The contents of PBS KIDS Measure Up! were developed under a grant from the Department of Education. However, those contents do not necessarily represent the policy of the Department of Education, and you should not assume endorsement by the Federal Government. The project is funded by a Ready To Learn grant (PR/AWARD No. U295A150003, CFDA No. 84.295A) provided by the Department of Education to the Corporation for Public Broadcasting.</i></p>
</div><div class="fusion-clearfix"></div></div></div></div></div><div class="fusion-fullwidth fullwidth-box fusion-builder-row-7 submit-your-ideas-block nonhundred-percent-fullwidth non-hundred-percent-height-scrolling fusion-equal-height-columns" style="background-color: #6ac6c1;background-position: center center;background-repeat: no-repeat;padding-top:50px;padding-right:0px;padding-bottom:50px;padding-left:0px;margin-bottom: 0px;margin-top: 0px;border-width: 0px 0px 0px 0px;border-color:#eae9e9;border-style:solid;" ><div class="fusion-builder-row fusion-row"><div class="fusion-layout-column fusion_builder_column fusion-builder-column-6 fusion_builder_column_1_2 1_2 fusion-one-half fusion-column-first" style="width:50%;width:calc(50% - ( ( 0 ) * 0.5 ) );margin-right: 0px;margin-top:0px;margin-bottom:20px;"><div class="fusion-column-wrapper fusion-flex-column-wrapper-legacy" style="background-position:left top;background-repeat:no-repeat;-webkit-background-size:cover;-moz-background-size:cover;-o-background-size:cover;background-size:cover;padding: 50px 0px 50px 0px;"><div class="fusion-column-content-centered"><div class="fusion-column-content"><div class="imageframe-align-center"><span class=" fusion-imageframe imageframe-none imageframe-3 hover-type-none"><img width="200" height="268" alt="Ideas" title="Ideas" src="https://datasciencebowl.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/idea-bulb.png" class="img-responsive wp-image-100"/></span></div></div></div><div class="fusion-clearfix"></div></div></div><div class="fusion-layout-column fusion_builder_column fusion-builder-column-7 fusion_builder_column_1_2 1_2 fusion-one-half fusion-column-last" style="width:50%;width:calc(50% - ( ( 0 ) * 0.5 ) );margin-top:0px;margin-bottom:20px;"><div class="fusion-column-wrapper fusion-flex-column-wrapper-legacy" style="background-position:left top;background-repeat:no-repeat;-webkit-background-size:cover;-moz-background-size:cover;-o-background-size:cover;background-size:cover;padding: 0px 50px 0px 30px;"><div class="fusion-column-content-centered"><div class="fusion-column-content"><div class="fusion-text fusion-text-7"><h2>Submit Your Ideas</h2>
<h4>Got a big idea for us?<br />
Ready to re-invent the future?<br />
See potential ahead?</h4>
<p>In our first contest, we dove deep with a microscopic lens to improve ocean health. In our last, we went on a life-saving mission to spot nuclei to diagnose killer diseases. In each case, we did what couldn’t be done before: bring the awesome creativity and capability of data scientists to open the doors to new approaches.</p>
<p>What should we tackle next? If you have ideas, let us hear from you!</p>
<p>We’re in the hunt for the next big problem to solve—a problem with the potential to change the world. If selected, the power of the entire data science community will be harnessed against it.</p>
<p><a href="https://datasciencebowl.com/contact/"><strong>Contact us</strong></a> to submit your ideas or email <a href="mailto:DataScienceBowl@bah.com"><strong>DataScienceBowl@bah.com</strong></a>. Include an overview of the problem, your contact information, a brief description of the data, and where it can be obtained.</p>
</div><div class="fusion-button-wrapper"><style>.fusion-body .fusion-button.button-1{border-radius:2px 2px 2px 2px;}</style><a class="fusion-button button-flat fusion-button-default-size button-default button-1 fusion-button-default-span fusion-button-default-type" target="_self" href="https://datasciencebowl.com/contact/"><span class="fusion-button-text">Contact Us</span><i class="fa-angle-right fas button-icon-right" aria-hidden="true"></i></a></div></div></div><div class="fusion-clearfix"></div></div></div></div></div>
</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://datasciencebowl.com/illuminate-learning-ignite-possibilities/">Illuminate Learning. Ignite Possibilities.</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://datasciencebowl.com">The Data Science Bowl</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>2018 Data Science Bowl Winners Announced</title>
		<link>https://datasciencebowl.com/2018winners/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 08 May 2018 16:07:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Data Science]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://datasciencebowl.com/?p=44</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Imagine unleashing the power of artificial intelligence to automate a critical component of biomedical research, expediting life-saving research in the treatment of almost every disease from rare disorders to the common cold. This could soon be a reality, thanks to the fourth Data Science Bowl, a 90-day competition in which, for the very first time, [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://datasciencebowl.com/2018winners/">2018 Data Science Bowl Winners Announced</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://datasciencebowl.com">The Data Science Bowl</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-45" src="https://datasciencebowl.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/C.12.004.17_Data-Science-Bowl_dsb-1920x1080-v2-300x169.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="169" srcset="http://bahdatascience.wpenginepowered.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/C.12.004.17_Data-Science-Bowl_dsb-1920x1080-v2-300x169-200x113.jpg 200w, http://bahdatascience.wpenginepowered.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/C.12.004.17_Data-Science-Bowl_dsb-1920x1080-v2-300x169.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />Imagine unleashing the power of artificial intelligence to automate a critical component of biomedical research, expediting life-saving research in the treatment of almost every disease from rare disorders to the common cold. This could soon be a reality, thanks to the fourth Data Science Bowl, a 90-day competition in which, for the very first time, participants trained deep learning models to examine images of cells and identify nuclei, regardless of the experimental setup—and without human intervention. Algorithms developed in this competition could save researchers hundreds of thousands of hours of effort per year. <span id="more-5414"></span><br />
<a href="http://www.boozallen.com">Booz Allen Hamilton</a> and <a href="http://www.kaggle.com">Kaggle</a> today announced the winners of this year’s Data Science Bowl. The competition brought together nearly 18,000 global participants, the most ever for the Data Science Bowl. Collectively, they submitted more than 68,000 algorithms and worked an estimated 288,000 hours to automate the vital, but time-consuming, process of nuclei detection. Identifying nuclei allows researchers to find each individual cell in a sample and, by measuring how cells react to various treatments, understand the underlying biological processes at work.</p>
<p>“These solutions represent a paradigm shift in the way microscopy images are processed in biomedical research and will make research more accurate and efficient,” said Dr. Anne Carpenter, director of the Imaging Platform at Broad Institute of MIT and Harvard. The next step being investigated is to create a user-friendly and open-sourced software that biomedical researchers can begin using in their day-to-day work.</p>
<p><strong><a href="https://www.kaggle.com/c/data-science-bowl-2018/leaderboard">2018 Data Science Bowl winners</a> include:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>First Place:</strong> Victor Durnov, Alexander Buslaev, and Selim Seferbekov, an international team from Russia and Germany who have competed against each other in previous crowdsourcing competitions but formed a team with the specific goal of winning this year’s competition.</li>
<li><strong>Second Place:</strong> Minxi Jiang, who finished in the top one percent in <a href="https://www.boozallen.com/e/media/press-release/nearly-10-000-global-problem-solvers-yield-winning-formulas-to-i.html">last year’s Data Science Bowl</a>.</li>
<li><strong>Third Place:</strong> Angel Lopez-Urrutia, a marine ecologist in Spain who uses machine learning to automatically classify images of plankton, a challenge that was central to the <a href="https://www.boozallen.com/e/media/press-release/booz-allen-kaggle-announce-winner-of-the-data-science-bowl.html">inaugural Data Science Bowl</a>.</li>
</ul>
<p>“By identifying nuclei quickly and accurately, the algorithms developed in this competition can free up biologists to focus on other aspects of their research, shortening the approximately 10 years it takes for each new drug to come to market and, ultimately, improving quality of life,” said Ray Hensberger, a Booz Allen Hamilton principal. “This year’s Data Science Bowl was fascinating because nuclei detection is crucial to biomedical research, but detection methods require time-consuming biologist oversight. Until now, there have never been any deep learning models available that can identify nuclei across multiple experimental setups and testing conditions.”</p>
<p>For this year’s Data Science Bowl, <a href="https://www.broadinstitute.org/">Broad Institute of MIT and Harvard</a>, a non-profit biomedical and genomics research institute, provided participants with data from thousands of nuclei from a wide variety of imaging experiments. Using this data, participants created algorithms that can identify nuclei in any cell image, thereby expediting the detection process and allowing biologists to conserve time for other efforts.</p>
<p>“We’re thrilled that this year’s Data Science Bowl convened thousands of the world’s top minds and rallied them around a pressing scientific challenge,” said Anthony Goldbloom, CEO, Kaggle. “In just 90 days, participants submitted over 68,000 algorithms, which is nearly 280 percent more than last year’s competition. The large numbers of forum posts and kernels resulting from this year’s competition demonstrate that we have fostered a growing community that is willing to share and learn together, which is truly inspiring.”</p>
<p>Creators of the top algorithms will split $170,000 in cash and prizes, including powerful NVIDIA® GPU hardware for deep learning such as the NVIDIA DGX Station and the NVIDIA TITAN GPU. The competition receives sponsorship and support from several leading health and technology organizations, including the Broad Institute, <a href="http://www.nvidia.com/page/home.html">NVIDIA</a>, and <a href="http://www.perkinelmer.com/">PerkinElmer, Inc</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://datasciencebowl.com/2018winners/">2018 Data Science Bowl Winners Announced</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://datasciencebowl.com">The Data Science Bowl</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>2018 DSB Tutorial (&#034;Kernel&#034;) Winners Announced</title>
		<link>https://datasciencebowl.com/2018tutorialwinners/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 17 Apr 2018 19:30:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Data Science]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://datasciencebowl.com/2018_close-copy/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The Data Science Bowl has made a truly impressive and positive impact using data science for social good. Participating in the challenge is an extraordinary opportunity to apply strategy and skills, gain new ones and fully embrace being a part of the analytics community. Data Science Bowl presenters, Booz Allen Hamilton and Kaggle, are pleased [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://datasciencebowl.com/2018tutorialwinners/">2018 DSB Tutorial (&quot;Kernel&quot;) Winners Announced</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://datasciencebowl.com">The Data Science Bowl</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Data Science Bowl has made a truly impressive and positive impact using data science for social good. Participating in the challenge is an extraordinary opportunity to apply strategy and skills, gain new ones and fully embrace being a part of the analytics community.</p>
<p>Data Science Bowl presenters, Booz Allen Hamilton and Kaggle, are pleased to recognize the Top 3 voted on Tutorials &#8211; known as &#8220;Kernels&#8221; within the Kaggle competition platform. This recognition was based on the community’s response to posted Kernels during the 2018 Data Science Bowl competition. Prize packs will be awarded to:</p>
<ol>
<li><a href="https://www.kaggle.com/keegil/keras-u-net-starter-lb-0-277?scriptVersionId=2164855">Keras U-Net starter tutorial</a> by Kjetil Amdal-Saevik with 739 upvotes</li>
<li><a href="https://www.kaggle.com/stkbailey/teaching-notebook-for-total-imaging-newbies">Teaching notebook for total imaging newbies tutorial</a> by Stephen Bailey with 354 upvotes</li>
<li><a href="https://www.kaggle.com/kmader/nuclei-overview-to-submission">Nuclei overview to submission tutorial</a> by Kevin Mader with 240 upvotes</li>
</ol>
<p>Congratulations to each of our winners! You truly embraced the spirit of the competition and we thank each of you for helping us to advance the art of data science.<br />
Kaggle will reach out to each of our winners privately about next steps for claiming their prize pack.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://datasciencebowl.com/2018tutorialwinners/">2018 DSB Tutorial (&quot;Kernel&quot;) Winners Announced</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://datasciencebowl.com">The Data Science Bowl</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
