<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0">

   <channel>
      <title>viXra.org e-prints</title>
      <description>Preprints from viXra.org site</description>
      <link>http://viXra.org/</link>
      <lastBuildDate>Fri Nov 04 23:37:16 EDT 2022</lastBuildDate>
      <pubDate>Fri Nov 04 23:37:16 EDT 2022</pubDate>
      <item>
   <title><![CDATA[The Model of Four Color Theorem]]></title>
   <link>http://viXra.org/abs/2211.0036</link>
   <pubDate>2022-11-04 02:12:57 </pubDate>
   <category>Combinatorics and Graph Theory</category>
   <description> <![CDATA[
     <b>reference:</b> viXra:2211.0036v1<br/>
     <b>title:</b>     The Model of Four Color Theorem<br/>
     <b>authors:</b>   Hui Liu<br/>
     <b>category:</b>  Combinatorics and Graph Theory<br/>
     <b>type:</b>      submission<br/>
     <b>date:</b>      2022-11-04 02:12:57 <br/>
     <b>abstract:</b>  
There is no perfect solution to the four-color theorem, although mathematicians have demonstrated it with computers. People have been asking: What is the essence of the four-color theorem? We think that the four color theorem is a space partition problem. We started from one-dimensional space, then expanded from one-dimensional space to two-dimensional space, and the problem was solved perfectly.
  
   ]]> </description>
</item>
<item>
   <title><![CDATA[The Origin of the Measured Proton-Electromagnetic-Structure Anomaly]]></title>
   <link>http://viXra.org/abs/2211.0035</link>
   <pubDate>2022-11-04 13:36:10 </pubDate>
   <category>High Energy Particle Physics</category>
   <description> <![CDATA[
     <b>reference:</b> viXra:2211.0035v1<br/>
     <b>title:</b>     The Origin of the Measured Proton-Electromagnetic-Structure Anomaly<br/>
     <b>authors:</b>   Sylwester Kornowski<br/>
     <b>category:</b>  High Energy Particle Physics<br/>
     <b>type:</b>      submission<br/>
     <b>date:</b>      2022-11-04 13:36:10 <br/>
     <b>abstract:</b>  
Theoretical results obtained in this paper are perfectly consistent with the Jefferson Lab data presented by R. Li, et al. (2022). Here we have linked the definitions of electric and magnetic polarizabilities to the internal structure of the proton described in the Scale-Symmetric Theory (SST). We then show that we should observe a local enhancement of the polarizabilities (an anomaly) for the squared four-momentum transfer from 0.31 up to 0.42 squared giga-electron volts - it follows from the internal dynamics of the proton. We calculated also the proton polarizability radii and the maximum polarizability for the anomalous region.
  
   ]]> </description>
</item>
<item>
   <title><![CDATA[Lorentz Volumes Paradox: Limits of Special Relativity in Application]]></title>
   <link>http://viXra.org/abs/2211.0034</link>
   <pubDate>2022-11-05 02:01:59 </pubDate>
   <category>Relativity and Cosmology</category>
   <description> <![CDATA[
     <b>reference:</b> viXra:2211.0034v1<br/>
     <b>title:</b>     Lorentz Volumes Paradox: Limits of Special Relativity in Application<br/>
     <b>authors:</b>   Michael Girgis<br/>
     <b>category:</b>  Relativity and Cosmology<br/>
     <b>type:</b>      submission<br/>
     <b>date:</b>      2022-11-05 02:01:59 <br/>
     <b>abstract:</b>  
When applying the Lorentz transformations of the coordinates of space to different types of volumes such as the volume of a gas and the rational volume between the gas and its molecules in a thermodynamic system, the observer gets contradictory results in the same frame of reference, Although the contradictory results are for different types of volumes, but both types are thermodynamic variables, or in other words, both types have an effect on gas pressure, Thus, the observer gets contradictory results also in the same frame of reference for relativistic pressure, as a result, the Lorentz transformations for different volumes represent a new paradox in special relativity, this paradox is not a mistake in special relativity, but it reveals to us the limits of the special theory of relativity in application, and the reasons for the failure to combine special relativity with thermodynamics.
  
   ]]> </description>
</item>
<item>
   <title><![CDATA[Prime Numbers Estimation in A Special Palindromic Number]]></title>
   <link>http://viXra.org/abs/2211.0033</link>
   <pubDate>2022-11-05 02:02:35 </pubDate>
   <category>Number Theory</category>
   <description> <![CDATA[
     <b>reference:</b> viXra:2211.0033v1<br/>
     <b>title:</b>     Prime Numbers Estimation in A Special Palindromic Number<br/>
     <b>authors:</b>   Zhi Li, Hua Li<br/>
     <b>category:</b>  Number Theory<br/>
     <b>type:</b>      submission<br/>
     <b>date:</b>      2022-11-05 02:02:35 <br/>
     <b>abstract:</b>  
The repunit number refers to the natural number composed of all the numbers 1, which is a special palindromic number. Whether the number of prime numbers in the repunit number is infinite, and how to calculate the number of prime numbers less than a certain integer have not been determined. This paper proves that the number of prime numbers of this kind is infinite by using the method of probability and statistics, and derives the calculation formula of it. On this basis, two conjectures are further proposed, that is, the ratio of the number of prime numbers in this palindromic number to the number of prime numbers in Mersenne number is 16ln (2)/(15ln (10)), and the number of prime numbers less than 24862048 digits is close to 15.
  
   ]]> </description>
</item>
<item>
   <title><![CDATA[Possible Proof of the Riemann Hypothesis Resulting From Prediction of Exact Values of the Landau Constants]]></title>
   <link>http://viXra.org/abs/2211.0032</link>
   <pubDate>2022-11-05 02:05:15 </pubDate>
   <category>Number Theory</category>
   <description> <![CDATA[
     <b>reference:</b> viXra:2211.0032v1<br/>
     <b>title:</b>     Possible Proof of the Riemann Hypothesis Resulting From Prediction of Exact Values of the Landau Constants<br/>
     <b>authors:</b>   Miroslav Sukenik<br/>
     <b>category:</b>  Number Theory<br/>
     <b>type:</b>      submission<br/>
     <b>date:</b>      2022-11-05 02:05:15 <br/>
     <b>abstract:</b>  
Based on the predicted value of the Landau constants L = 0.5331588u2026.and A = 0.7301772..., it is possible to identify the critical line x=0.5 with the horizon line. It is known that the size of entropy is proportional to the size of the surface of the horizon, and according to the holographic principle, all information must lie on this surface. So also the zero points of the Riemann Zeta function, which carry information about the distribution of primenumbers.
  
   ]]> </description>
</item>
<item>
   <title><![CDATA[On the Navier and Stokes Equations]]></title>
   <link>http://viXra.org/abs/2211.0031</link>
   <pubDate>2022-11-05 02:06:06 </pubDate>
   <category>Mathematical Physics</category>
   <description> <![CDATA[
     <b>reference:</b> viXra:2211.0031v1<br/>
     <b>title:</b>     On the Navier and Stokes Equations<br/>
     <b>authors:</b>   Thomas Brouard<br/>
     <b>category:</b>  Mathematical Physics<br/>
     <b>type:</b>      submission<br/>
     <b>date:</b>      2022-11-05 02:06:06 <br/>
     <b>abstract:</b>  
Here is proposed a solution to this (https://www.claymath.org/sites/default/files/navierstokes.pdf) three dimensions Navier-Stokes equations problem, described in cartesian coordinates. Are given the ex- pression of a velocity defined as the initial one, conditions verifications, calculus description, and the proof of the existence of the pressure math- ematical solution.
  
   ]]> </description>
</item>
<item>
   <title><![CDATA[Transformation of Altitudes From One Geodetic System to Another]]></title>
   <link>http://viXra.org/abs/2211.0030</link>
   <pubDate>2022-11-05 02:06:44 </pubDate>
   <category>Geophysics</category>
   <description> <![CDATA[
     <b>reference:</b> viXra:2211.0030v1<br/>
     <b>title:</b>     Transformation of Altitudes From One Geodetic System to Another<br/>
     <b>authors:</b>   Abdelmajid Ben Hadj Salem<br/>
     <b>category:</b>  Geophysics<br/>
     <b>type:</b>      submission<br/>
     <b>date:</b>      2022-11-05 02:06:44 <br/>
     <b>abstract:</b>  
With the introduction of GPS (Global Positioning System) technology, which provides the user with his three-dimensional (X,Y,Z) position in the global geocentric system called WGS84 (World Geodetic System 1984), it is necessary to know the transformation of altitudes from the world geodetic system to the national or local geodetic system. We present below some models of transformations of passage of altitudes between geodetic systems.
  
   ]]> </description>
</item>
<item>
   <title><![CDATA[Convergent Fundamental Constants of the Universe]]></title>
   <link>http://viXra.org/abs/2211.0029</link>
   <pubDate>2022-11-05 02:07:27 </pubDate>
   <category>Relativity and Cosmology</category>
   <description> <![CDATA[
     <b>reference:</b> viXra:2211.0029v1<br/>
     <b>title:</b>     Convergent Fundamental Constants of the Universe<br/>
     <b>authors:</b>   Ankur S. Bhatt, F. M. Becker<br/>
     <b>category:</b>  Relativity and Cosmology<br/>
     <b>type:</b>      submission<br/>
     <b>date:</b>      2022-11-05 02:07:27 <br/>
     <b>abstract:</b>  
Several theoretical equations are derived which determine the vacuum permittivity, vacuum permeability, free impedance and speed of light to a highly convergent value on the order of $10^{-8}$ to $10^{-9}$. Their dependence is related to the particle horizon, Hubble horizon, Planck length, proton wavelength and the fine structure constant. Due to these highly convergent equations, an image of both the photon and the vacuum may start to emerge.
  
   ]]> </description>
</item>
<item>
   <title><![CDATA[Shock Initiation of Explosives Through Shock Wave-Induced Electrical Breakdown]]></title>
   <link>http://viXra.org/abs/2211.0028</link>
   <pubDate>2022-11-05 02:08:31 </pubDate>
   <category>Thermodynamics and Energy</category>
   <description> <![CDATA[
     <b>reference:</b> viXra:2211.0028v1<br/>
     <b>title:</b>     Shock Initiation of Explosives Through Shock Wave-Induced Electrical Breakdown<br/>
     <b>authors:</b>   Yuanjie Huang, Zhiqiang Chen<br/>
     <b>category:</b>  Thermodynamics and Energy<br/>
     <b>type:</b>      submission<br/>
     <b>date:</b>      2022-11-05 02:08:31 <br/>
     <b>abstract:</b>  
Shock initiation of high explosive (HE) is very important for both the civilian and defense communities, and the hotspot mechanism has been widely recognized as the dominant regime. However, how the hotspots can generate conspicuous reaction of the surrounding bulk HE has still been a challenging topic in recent decades. In this work, using the physics of shock polarization and Yuheng Zhang equation, the shock wave-induced electrical breakdown (SWIEB) mechanism and the related chemical reaction rate equation was proposed for shock initiation of HE. It was found that the SWIEB mechanism agreed with most experimental observations on the shock initiation phenomena. As indicated by the performed experiments on the electrical breakdown of ammonia borne (NH3BH3) in this work, the electrical breakdown cannot only remarkably accelerate the reaction rate even at room temperature but also result in a reaction route different from the thermal reaction route, thereby yielding distinct reaction products. The experimental results suggested that the SWIEB may be an important and rational mechanism for the reaction of bulk HE around the hotspots. Overall, the proposed SWIEB may pave a new and reasonable way of understanding the physics of shock initiation and may help people design much safer HE in both the civilian and defense fields.
  
   ]]> </description>
</item>
<item>
   <title><![CDATA[A Comprehensive Identification of Coexisting Cellular Automata Replicators Varying by State-Set Permutations.]]></title>
   <link>http://viXra.org/abs/2211.0027</link>
   <pubDate>2022-11-05 02:13:00 </pubDate>
   <category>Physics of Biology</category>
   <description> <![CDATA[
     <b>reference:</b> viXra:2211.0027v1<br/>
     <b>title:</b>     A Comprehensive Identification of Coexisting Cellular Automata Replicators Varying by State-Set Permutations.<br/>
     <b>authors:</b>   Perry W. Swanborough<br/>
     <b>category:</b>  Physics of Biology<br/>
     <b>type:</b>      submission<br/>
     <b>date:</b>      2022-11-05 02:13:00 <br/>
     <b>abstract:</b>  
A study to determine state-set permutated replicators of opposite handedness coexisting with John Byl&#8217;s 1989 replicator subsequently suggested the task of identifying the comprehensive set of all left- and right-handed state-set permutated replicators coexisting with the Byl replicator. This work reports the lists of both left- and right-handed state-set permutated replicators coexisting with replication of the original Byl structure replicating under Moore state-transition rules, and as such supplements previous work described in viXra:2101.0075 and viXra:2107.0172.
  
   ]]> </description>
</item>
<item>
   <title><![CDATA[Hierarchy of Quantum Fields, Scalar Field Neutrinos, Neutrino Dark Matter, Spacetime as a Product of Rotating Quantum Fields in a Higher Dimensional Bulk, The Nature of the Temporal Dimension]]></title>
   <link>http://viXra.org/abs/2211.0026</link>
   <pubDate>2022-11-04 01:10:46 </pubDate>
   <category>Quantum Physics</category>
   <description> <![CDATA[
     <b>reference:</b> viXra:2211.0026v1<br/>
     <b>title:</b>     Hierarchy of Quantum Fields, Scalar Field Neutrinos, Neutrino Dark Matter, Spacetime as a Product of Rotating Quantum Fields in a Higher Dimensional Bulk, The Nature of the Temporal Dimension<br/>
     <b>authors:</b>   Charlie Dawson<br/>
     <b>category:</b>  Quantum Physics<br/>
     <b>type:</b>      submission<br/>
     <b>date:</b>      2022-11-04 01:10:46 <br/>
     <b>abstract:</b>  
We postulate that quantum fields are more fundamental than spacetime. There is a hierarchy of fields, with the scalar, Higgs field being the most fundamental and the vector and spinor fields being a result of the 2-dimensional scalar field, being synonymous with a 2-brane, rotating through some higher dimensional bulk. As this field rotates the path integral of all possible paths of rotation through the higher dimensions can be summed into a projection into 1 extra dimension. The incorporation of another dimension creates a 3-brane that houses all of the vector fields. This brane, being coupled to the 2-brane, continues to rotate and the continued rotation produces a 4-brane to house all of the spinor fields. With 2 complete rotations the spinor fields will yield some paths in which a point of the scalar field would have 2 complete rotations bound up in its path back to its starting point on the scalar field, which would be the paths of spinor field particles. There would also be some paths which some points on the scalar field could complete 2 full rotations and instead of having those rotations bound up in the path, the particular paths would essentially unwind the part of the field along those paths. The would-be spinor fields would become a scalar field. The would-be spinor particles would become scalar values. We postulate that these would be spin &#189; particles might be right-handed neutrinos. Applying this possibility to recent work by Latham Boyle, Neil Turok, Kieran Finn and others, we explore the possibility that these paths might be the source of Dark Matter.
  
   ]]> </description>
</item>
<item>
   <title><![CDATA[[An Attempt at] a Final Theory of General Relativity]]></title>
   <link>http://viXra.org/abs/2211.0025</link>
   <pubDate>2022-11-04 01:14:13 </pubDate>
   <category>Relativity and Cosmology</category>
   <description> <![CDATA[
     <b>reference:</b> viXra:2211.0025v1<br/>
     <b>title:</b>     [An Attempt at] a Final Theory of General Relativity<br/>
     <b>authors:</b>   Manfred U. E. Pohl<br/>
     <b>category:</b>  Relativity and Cosmology<br/>
     <b>type:</b>      submission<br/>
     <b>date:</b>      2022-11-04 01:14:13 <br/>
     <b>abstract:</b>  
It is briefly shown that all physical theories fall back on a mathematical application of the circle number &#960; and that Gravitation, Electricity and Magnetism are united by understanding that in addition to Einsteins finding - that the Vacuum constant speed of light represents the dimension of time in Vacuum at rest - we need also to consider that Vacuum permeability and Vacuum permittivity represent the dimension of length in Vacuum at rest.
  
   ]]> </description>
</item>
<item>
   <title><![CDATA[A Real TI-83 Craps Simulation Teaches Beginning Probability]]></title>
   <link>http://viXra.org/abs/2211.0024</link>
   <pubDate>2022-11-03 10:40:52 </pubDate>
   <category>General Mathematics</category>
   <description> <![CDATA[
     <b>reference:</b> viXra:2211.0024v1<br/>
     <b>title:</b>     A Real TI-83 Craps Simulation Teaches Beginning Probability<br/>
     <b>authors:</b>   Timothy W. Jones<br/>
     <b>category:</b>  General Mathematics<br/>
     <b>type:</b>      submission<br/>
     <b>date:</b>      2022-11-03 10:40:52 <br/>
     <b>abstract:</b>  
Simple craps, a Vegas casino game, is easily modeled using a TI-83's programming, list, and statistics features.  Roll two dice.  If the coming out roll, as it is called is 2, 3, or 12, the player immediately loses.  If a 7 or 11 is rolled, they immediately win.  If any of the remaining totals are rolled, if the player rolls that number before rolling a 7, they win, not they lose.  A program can be initialized with a bank roll and a standard, non-changing bet.  Using the list feature 999 rolls, the maximum size of a list, can be stored in a built-in list.  A bar chart for the distribution of numbers is easily generated and confirms the calculated probabilities.  The code to mimic the game is straight-forward.  The user repeatedly plays the game until the stake is 0, an inevitability given say a stake of $100 and a bet of $5.  This certainty instills the truth: it's a loser's game.
  
   ]]> </description>
</item>
<item>
   <title><![CDATA[Critical Behavior in Continuous Dimensions and Early-Universe Cosmology]]></title>
   <link>http://viXra.org/abs/2211.0023</link>
   <pubDate>2022-11-03 13:30:00 </pubDate>
   <category>Relativity and Cosmology</category>
   <description> <![CDATA[
     <b>reference:</b> viXra:2211.0023v1<br/>
     <b>title:</b>     Critical Behavior in Continuous Dimensions and Early-Universe Cosmology<br/>
     <b>authors:</b>   Ervin Goldfain<br/>
     <b>category:</b>  Relativity and Cosmology<br/>
     <b>type:</b>      submission<br/>
     <b>date:</b>      2022-11-03 13:30:00 <br/>
     <b>abstract:</b>  
It is known that large-scale dynamical systems can sustain a rich variety of collective phenomena. This brief note argues that the cosmology of the early Universe can be viewed as critical behavior in continuous dimensions. We find that the self-similar properties of the metric near the Big Bang singularity are comparable to the effects produced by minimal fractality of spacetime far above the electroweak scale.
  
   ]]> </description>
</item>
<item>
   <title><![CDATA[De Tegenslagen van de Theoretische Natuurkunde (The Misadventures of Theoretical Physics)]]></title>
   <link>http://viXra.org/abs/2211.0022</link>
   <pubDate>2022-11-04 01:23:13 </pubDate>
   <category>Mathematical Physics</category>
   <description> <![CDATA[
     <b>reference:</b> viXra:2211.0022v1<br/>
     <b>title:</b>     De Tegenslagen van de Theoretische Natuurkunde (The Misadventures of Theoretical Physics)<br/>
     <b>authors:</b>   Hans van Leunen<br/>
     <b>category:</b>  Mathematical Physics<br/>
     <b>type:</b>      submission<br/>
     <b>date:</b>      2022-11-04 01:23:13 <br/>
     <b>abstract:</b>  
De zoektocht naar een betrouwbare basis van de fysieke werkelijkheid heeft veel tegenslagen gekend en verloopt traag. Er werden zijwegen genomen die niet tot het gewenste doel leidden. Dit document laat zien dat er een alternatief pad is dat leidt tot een beter resultaat. Dit resultaat kan in &#233;&#233;n zin worden weergegeven. Deze zeer korte samenvatting behoeft wel de nodige uitleg. Het documnt geeft deze uitleg. Het document toont ook de relatie tussen de basis en verschillende aspecten van de natuurkunde, zoals kwantumfysica, klassieke fysica, optica en kosmologie.<p>The search for a reliable basis of physical reality has seen many setbacks and progresses slowly. Side roads were taken that did not lead to the desired goal. This document shows that there is an alternative path that leads to a better result. This result can be displayed in one sentence. This very short summary does require some explanation. The document provides this explanation. The paper also shows the relationship between the basics and various aspects of physics, such as quantum physics, classical physics, optics and cosmology.
  
   ]]> </description>
</item>
<item>
   <title><![CDATA[The Assumption of a Continuous Lorentzian Spacetime Manifold in Quantum Gravity]]></title>
   <link>http://viXra.org/abs/2211.0021</link>
   <pubDate>2022-11-04 01:24:31 </pubDate>
   <category>Quantum Gravity and String Theory</category>
   <description> <![CDATA[
     <b>reference:</b> viXra:2211.0021v1<br/>
     <b>title:</b>     The Assumption of a Continuous Lorentzian Spacetime Manifold in Quantum Gravity<br/>
     <b>authors:</b>   Ren&#233; Friedrich<br/>
     <b>category:</b>  Quantum Gravity and String Theory<br/>
     <b>type:</b>      submission<br/>
     <b>date:</b>      2022-11-04 01:24:31 <br/>
     <b>abstract:</b>  
Spacetime is more and more often suspected of being at the origin of the problem of quantum gravity, and it is said that the concept of spacetime needs to be revised. In this paper, we want to provide the concrete reason why the Lorentzian spacetime manifold is not compatible with quantum gravity, by showing that it is a man-made artefact: unlike the Euclidean metric, no Lorentzian pseudometric is able to span up a real-valued manifold. This is why - since its introduction with Minkowski's famous lecture "Space and time" and until today - Lorentzian manifolds require always the addition of a second metric in order to override the appearance of negative squares and of imaginary values. This artificial "patchwork" of two opposite metrics is not only incompatible with quantum mechanics, it is even contradicting the very principles of general relativity.
  
   ]]> </description>
</item>
<item>
   <title><![CDATA[Mass Wave Model and Speed Propagation Estimation]]></title>
   <link>http://viXra.org/abs/2211.0020</link>
   <pubDate>2022-11-04 01:27:04 </pubDate>
   <category>Relativity and Cosmology</category>
   <description> <![CDATA[
     <b>reference:</b> viXra:2211.0020v1<br/>
     <b>title:</b>     Mass Wave Model and Speed Propagation Estimation<br/>
     <b>authors:</b>   Enrique Dominguez Pinos<br/>
     <b>category:</b>  Relativity and Cosmology<br/>
     <b>type:</b>      submission<br/>
     <b>date:</b>      2022-11-04 01:27:04 <br/>
     <b>abstract:</b>  
Full analogy between electromagnetism and gravity, with mass wave calculation through solar system simulation sourced with ephemeris data fromhorizons. Argument of mercury perihelion precession against general relativity.
  
   ]]> </description>
</item>
<item>
   <title><![CDATA[How is Russia Disrupting the NATO Alliance and Challenging the United States of America&#8217;s Hegemony Through the Ukrainian Invasion?]]></title>
   <link>http://viXra.org/abs/2211.0019</link>
   <pubDate>2022-11-03 01:44:05</pubDate>
   <category>Economics and Finance</category>
   <description> <![CDATA[
     <b>reference:</b> viXra:2211.0019v1<br/>
     <b>title:</b>     How is Russia Disrupting the NATO Alliance and Challenging the United States of America&#8217;s Hegemony Through the Ukrainian Invasion?<br/>
     <b>authors:</b>   Love Trivedi , Akshan Toshniwal<br/>
     <b>category:</b>  Economics and Finance<br/>
     <b>type:</b>      submission<br/>
     <b>date:</b>      2022-11-03 01:44:05<br/>
     <b>abstract:</b>  
  
The Russia-Ukraine war has sparked a series of controversies and debates as to what VladimirPutin's goals are. This paper aims to outline Putin's short-term goal: to disrupt the NATO alliance by weaponizing inflation. Putin is choking the European fuel supply as a response to various economic sanctions; however, the European Union is working towards finding alternatives. The commission is establishing a network of scientists working to find energy alternatives and increase the efficiency of their nuclear reactors. Putin is also working toward his long-term goal of disrupting US hegemony by skirting the SWIFT system. The US government has abolished the Russian financial institutions from its enhancedfinancial messaging system, with companies like Google Pay, PayPal, etc., exiting the Russian market. Russia is developing alternate methods by employing a vast network of programmers to develop an alternative to the SWIFT System and various currency swap agreements. Putin is employing a short-term and long-term strategy to establish a multipolar order and reinvigorate Russia's global standing.
  

  
   ]]> </description>
</item>
<item>
   <title><![CDATA[Time and Tts Properties]]></title>
   <link>http://viXra.org/abs/2211.0018</link>
   <pubDate>2022-11-03 01:46:21 </pubDate>
   <category>History and Philosophy of Physics</category>
   <description> <![CDATA[
     <b>reference:</b> viXra:2211.0018v1<br/>
     <b>title:</b>     Time and Tts Properties<br/>
     <b>authors:</b>   Aleksander Maltsev<br/>
     <b>category:</b>  History and Philosophy of Physics<br/>
     <b>type:</b>      submission<br/>
     <b>date:</b>      2022-11-03 01:46:21 <br/>
     <b>abstract:</b>  
An analysis of the causes, the application of the concept of time, an abstract essence. The reasons for the complexity of determining the movement of time are considered. To determine the essence of time, the process of time movement is considered from the point of view of the internal and external observer. The conclusion is drawn about the movement of time, the transformation of the future into the past. The period of transformation is recorded as the existence of the present. The sum of the transformation periods is recorded as the duration of the event. The property of time periodicity allows measuring its duration using various periodic phenomena and their sums. Continuity of transformation creates the continuity of the movement of time. The conditions of the transformation are considered, one of which is the existence of 3-dimensional space. An analysis is made of the causes, the probabilistic nature of events, in quantum mechanics.Keywords: time, space, matter, transformation, dimensionality of space, quantum uncertainty, cosmology.
  
   ]]> </description>
</item>
<item>
   <title><![CDATA[Equivalence of Information Flow and Time]]></title>
   <link>http://viXra.org/abs/2211.0017</link>
   <pubDate>2022-11-02 16:33:35 </pubDate>
   <category>Thermodynamics and Energy</category>
   <description> <![CDATA[
     <b>reference:</b> viXra:2211.0017v1<br/>
     <b>title:</b>     Equivalence of Information Flow and Time<br/>
     <b>authors:</b>   Friedhelm M. J&#246;ge<br/>
     <b>category:</b>  Thermodynamics and Energy<br/>
     <b>type:</b>      submission<br/>
     <b>date:</b>      2022-11-02 16:33:35 <br/>
     <b>abstract:</b>  
A formula is developed that describes a quadratic relationship between Information and time and at the same time the equivalence of Information flow and Time.
  
   ]]> </description>
</item>
<item>
   <title><![CDATA[The Acceleration of Multi-Factor Merton Model on FPGA]]></title>
   <link>http://viXra.org/abs/2211.0015</link>
   <pubDate>2022-11-03 01:50:04 </pubDate>
   <category>Artificial Intelligence</category>
   <description> <![CDATA[
     <b>reference:</b> viXra:2211.0015v1<br/>
     <b>title:</b>     The Acceleration of Multi-Factor Merton Model on FPGA<br/>
     <b>authors:</b>   Pengyu Guo<br/>
     <b>category:</b>  Artificial Intelligence<br/>
     <b>type:</b>      submission<br/>
     <b>date:</b>      2022-11-03 01:50:04 <br/>
     <b>abstract:</b>  
Credit risk stands for the risk of losses caused by unwanted events, such as the default of an obligor. The managing of portfolio credit risks is crucial for financial institutions. The multi-factor Merton model is one of the most widely used tools that modelling the credit risks for financial institutions. Typically, the implementation of the multi-factor Merton model involves Monte Carlo simulations which are time-consuming. This would significantly restrict its usability in daily credit risk measurement. In this report, we propose an FPGA architecture for credit-risk measurements in the multi-factor Merton models. The presented architecture uses a variety of optimization techniques such as kernel vectorization and loop unrolling, to optimize the performance of the FPGA implementation. The evaluation results show that compare to a basic C++ implementation running on a single-core Intel i5-4210 CPU, our proposed FPGA implementation can achieve an acceleration of up to 22 times, with a precision loss of less than 10&#8722;8.
  
   ]]> </description>
</item>
<item>
   <title><![CDATA[Parallel Parameter Estimation for Gilli-Winker Model Using Multi-Core CPUs]]></title>
   <link>http://viXra.org/abs/2211.0014</link>
   <pubDate>2022-11-03 01:50:31 </pubDate>
   <category>Artificial Intelligence</category>
   <description> <![CDATA[
     <b>reference:</b> viXra:2211.0014v1<br/>
     <b>title:</b>     Parallel Parameter Estimation for Gilli-Winker Model Using Multi-Core CPUs<br/>
     <b>authors:</b>   Pengyu Guo<br/>
     <b>category:</b>  Artificial Intelligence<br/>
     <b>type:</b>      submission<br/>
     <b>date:</b>      2022-11-03 01:50:31 <br/>
     <b>abstract:</b>  
Agent-based modeling is a powerful tool that is widely used to model global financial systems. When the parameters of the model are appropriate, the price time series generated by the model exhibit marked similarities with actual financial time series and even reproduces some of their statistical characteristics.By using Kirman&#8217;s Ant model as a prototype, this report systematically explored Gilli and Winker&#8217;s parameter optimization method. In view of some limitations of this method, this report promoted some improvements, including a local-restart strategy to enhance the convergence ability of the original optimization method, as well as incorporate Simulated Annealing into the original method to help the algorithm escape from local optimums. Furthermore, since the parameter optimization of agent-based modeling tends to be very time-consuming, an acceleration method was also proposed to speed up this procedure. In the end, the presented methods have been validated with the EUR/USD exchange rate.
  
   ]]> </description>
</item>
<item>
   <title><![CDATA[A Model for Combining Classical and Quantum Physics Based on Lorentz Invariants (Part 2)]]></title>
   <link>http://viXra.org/abs/2211.0013</link>
   <pubDate>2022-11-02 01:06:25 </pubDate>
   <category>Mathematical Physics</category>
   <description> <![CDATA[
     <b>reference:</b> viXra:2211.0013v1<br/>
     <b>title:</b>     A Model for Combining Classical and Quantum Physics Based on Lorentz Invariants (Part 2)<br/>
     <b>authors:</b>   Aleksander Maltsev<br/>
     <b>category:</b>  Mathematical Physics<br/>
     <b>type:</b>      submission<br/>
     <b>date:</b>      2022-11-02 01:06:25 <br/>
     <b>abstract:</b>  
A mathematical description of the phase transition of matter from the solid state to the liquid state, gas, and the difference of matter's energy, in a rectilinear motion and in the gaseous state, has been obtained. The transition of linear motion into rotational motion is explained. The transformation, presented, is analogous to the motion that creates a new degree of dimensionality. Transformation of physical vacuum into matter is represented by the analog of gas condensation into a solid state. The cause of neutron instability in the free state is considered. A variant of the origin of matter and physical vacuum from the previous state is proposed. The existence of the present as a mediator between the past and the future is analyzed. Evolution of the Universe in Space and Time is described. Astonishment is expressed by the coincidence of the description of the Universe evolution with the ancient Greek description of the Ouroboros.
  
   ]]> </description>
</item>
<item>
   <title><![CDATA[A Simple Method to Compute Sums of Powers and Polynomials]]></title>
   <link>http://viXra.org/abs/2211.0012</link>
   <pubDate>2022-11-01 06:41:21 </pubDate>
   <category>General Mathematics</category>
   <description> <![CDATA[
     <b>reference:</b> viXra:2211.0012v1<br/>
     <b>title:</b>     A Simple Method to Compute Sums of Powers and Polynomials<br/>
     <b>authors:</b>   Kai Cheung<br/>
     <b>category:</b>  General Mathematics<br/>
     <b>type:</b>      submission<br/>
     <b>date:</b>      2022-11-01 06:41:21 <br/>
     <b>abstract:</b>  
This paper introduces a simpler method to compute sums of powers and polynomials, which can be done by hand, and efficiently implemented in software.
  
   ]]> </description>
</item>
<item>
   <title><![CDATA[Explanation of Bird Migration Using Ultimate Acceleration]]></title>
   <link>http://viXra.org/abs/2211.0011</link>
   <pubDate>2022-11-01 11:02:59 </pubDate>
   <category>Relativity and Cosmology</category>
   <description> <![CDATA[
     <b>reference:</b> viXra:2211.0011v1<br/>
     <b>title:</b>     Explanation of Bird Migration Using Ultimate Acceleration<br/>
     <b>authors:</b>   Huaiyang Cui<br/>
     <b>category:</b>  Relativity and Cosmology<br/>
     <b>type:</b>      submission<br/>
     <b>date:</b>      2022-11-01 11:02:59 <br/>
     <b>abstract:</b>  
In analogy with the ultimate speed c, there is an ultimate acceleration &#946;, nobody's acceleration can exceed this limit &#946;, in the solar system, &#946;=2.961520e+10(m/s2). Because this ultimate acceleration is large, any effect related to &#946; will become easy to test, including quantum gravity tests. In this paper, an approach is put forward to connect the ultimate acceleration with quantum theory, and is applied to sunspot problems. The sunspot cycle is calculated to be 10.93 years due to the ultimate acceleration. Due to quantum effect of the ultimate acceleration, the atmospheric constructive interference condition takes place at certain latitudes where are traditional habitats of migratory birds, so this relativistic approach provides a direction guidance for bird migration.
  
   ]]> </description>
</item>
<item>
   <title><![CDATA[]]></title>
   <link>http://viXra.org/abs/2211.0010</link>
   <pubDate>2022-11-03 01:31:50 </pubDate>
   <category>Number Theory</category>
   <description> <![CDATA[
     <b>reference:</b> viXra:2211.0010v2<br/>
     <b>title:</b>     <br/>
     <b>authors:</b>   <br/>
     <b>category:</b>  Number Theory<br/>
     <b>type:</b>      withdrawal<br/>
     <b>date:</b>      2022-11-03 01:31:50 <br/>
     <b>abstract:</b>  
   ]]> </description>
</item>
<item>
   <title><![CDATA[Determination of the Exact Value of the Landau Constant is a Possible Proof of the Riemann Hypothesis]]></title>
   <link>http://viXra.org/abs/2211.0010</link>
   <pubDate>2022-11-02 01:10:40 </pubDate>
   <category>Number Theory</category>
   <description> <![CDATA[
     <b>reference:</b> viXra:2211.0010v1<br/>
     <b>title:</b>     Determination of the Exact Value of the Landau Constant is a Possible Proof of the Riemann Hypothesis<br/>
     <b>authors:</b>   Miroslav Sukenik, Magdalena S&#250;ken&#237;kov&#225;<br/>
     <b>category:</b>  Number Theory<br/>
     <b>type:</b>      submission<br/>
     <b>date:</b>      2022-11-02 01:10:40 <br/>
     <b>abstract:</b>  
Based on the predicted value of the Landau constant L = 0.5396455, it is possible to identify the critical line x=0.5 with the horizon line. It is known that the size of entropy is proportional to the size of the surface of the horizon, and according to the holographic principle, all information must lie on this surface. So also the zero points of the Riemann Zeta function, which carry information about the distribution of prime numbers.
  
   ]]> </description>
</item>
<item>
   <title><![CDATA[Equipossibility, Over-Inflated Basket Balls, Photons and Polarizers]]></title>
   <link>http://viXra.org/abs/2211.0009</link>
   <pubDate>2022-11-01 00:39:50</pubDate>
   <category>History and Philosophy of Physics</category>
   <description> <![CDATA[
     <b>reference:</b> viXra:2211.0009v1<br/>
     <b>title:</b>     Equipossibility, Over-Inflated Basket Balls, Photons and Polarizers<br/>
     <b>authors:</b>   Georgina Woodward<br/>
     <b>category:</b>  History and Philosophy of Physics<br/>
     <b>type:</b>      submission<br/>
     <b>date:</b>      2022-11-01 00:39:50<br/>
     <b>abstract:</b>  
  
  
An explanation for the statistical results for photon and polarizer experiments, that differ from classical expectation and linear output variation with changing angle.  Brief discussion of what is equipossibility. Basket ball inflation analogy used to help visualize the issue. Positing polarizers produce a population of photons with different wave component orientations with different ease of passing different orientations of polarizer, rather than a uniform population. In this way talk of the necessity for faster than light communication or need to abandon local realism becomes superfluous. Relevant to Bell's inequalities.
  

  

  
   ]]> </description>
</item>
<item>
   <title><![CDATA[Neutron Lifetime Constrains the Gravitational Constant]]></title>
   <link>http://viXra.org/abs/2211.0008</link>
   <pubDate>2022-11-01 00:43:40 </pubDate>
   <category>High Energy Particle Physics</category>
   <description> <![CDATA[
     <b>reference:</b> viXra:2211.0008v1<br/>
     <b>title:</b>     Neutron Lifetime Constrains the Gravitational Constant<br/>
     <b>authors:</b>   Shan-Hong Li<br/>
     <b>category:</b>  High Energy Particle Physics<br/>
     <b>type:</b>      submission<br/>
     <b>date:</b>      2022-11-01 00:43:40 <br/>
     <b>abstract:</b>  
We improved the neutron lifetime formula and the gravitational constant formula to generate stronger constraints between them. And improved their calculation accuracy, so that they are in better agreement with the experimental data. By calculating the improved formulas, the neutron lifetime is 877.7495 &#55349;&#56416;, and the gravitational constant is 6.6742986&#215;10&#8722;11 &#55349;&#56410;3/(&#55349;&#56408;&#55349;&#56404;&#183;&#55349;&#56416;2).
  
   ]]> </description>
</item>
<item>
   <title><![CDATA[The Black Hole Fallacy]]></title>
   <link>http://viXra.org/abs/2211.0007</link>
   <pubDate>2022-11-01 00:44:24 </pubDate>
   <category>Relativity and Cosmology</category>
   <description> <![CDATA[
     <b>reference:</b> viXra:2211.0007v1<br/>
     <b>title:</b>     The Black Hole Fallacy<br/>
     <b>authors:</b>   A. J. Owen<br/>
     <b>category:</b>  Relativity and Cosmology<br/>
     <b>type:</b>      submission<br/>
     <b>date:</b>      2022-11-01 00:44:24 <br/>
     <b>abstract:</b>  
It is shown here that the currently accepted solution in general relativity predicting black holes and an event horizon is unphysical. The spacetime outside a point mass is entirely regular, the effective gravitational mass decreases to zero as a test object comes into close proximity of it, and free-fall velocities do not exceed the speed of light.
  
   ]]> </description>
</item>
<item>
   <title><![CDATA[Finite Dimensional Series and Its Applications in Number Theory and Mathematical Analysis]]></title>
   <link>http://viXra.org/abs/2211.0006</link>
   <pubDate>2022-11-01 00:50:49 </pubDate>
   <category>Number Theory</category>
   <description> <![CDATA[
     <b>reference:</b> viXra:2211.0006v1<br/>
     <b>title:</b>     Finite Dimensional Series and Its Applications in Number Theory and Mathematical Analysis<br/>
     <b>authors:</b>   Shazly Abdullah<br/>
     <b>category:</b>  Number Theory<br/>
     <b>type:</b>      submission<br/>
     <b>date:</b>      2022-11-01 00:50:49 <br/>
     <b>abstract:</b>  
In this study we used an algebraic method that uses elementary algebra and binomial theorem to create finite binomial series. This is a type of series that has several properties in variables. We used these series to prove results in congruences and primitive roots, Diophantine equation. We also obtained several results in finite series.
  
   ]]> </description>
</item>
<item>
   <title><![CDATA[What Experiments Can Confirm the Chronofield Hypothesis]]></title>
   <link>http://viXra.org/abs/2211.0005</link>
   <pubDate>2022-11-01 00:52:03 </pubDate>
   <category>Relativity and Cosmology</category>
   <description> <![CDATA[
     <b>reference:</b> viXra:2211.0005v1<br/>
     <b>title:</b>     What Experiments Can Confirm the Chronofield Hypothesis<br/>
     <b>authors:</b>   V. E. Yumashev<br/>
     <b>category:</b>  Relativity and Cosmology<br/>
     <b>type:</b>      submission<br/>
     <b>date:</b>      2022-11-01 00:52:03 <br/>
     <b>abstract:</b>  
Any hypothesis, in order to become a theory, must be confirmed by experiment. Recently, devices have appeared that can be used to try to confirm the existence of a chronofield in our universe. Two possible experiments are considered that can confirm this.
  
   ]]> </description>
</item>
<item>
   <title><![CDATA[On the Riemann Hypothesis]]></title>
   <link>http://viXra.org/abs/2211.0004</link>
   <pubDate>2022-11-01 00:52:57 </pubDate>
   <category>General Mathematics</category>
   <description> <![CDATA[
     <b>reference:</b> viXra:2211.0004v1<br/>
     <b>title:</b>     On the Riemann Hypothesis<br/>
     <b>authors:</b>   Abdelkrim Ben Mohamed<br/>
     <b>category:</b>  General Mathematics<br/>
     <b>type:</b>      submission<br/>
     <b>date:</b>      2022-11-01 00:52:57 <br/>
     <b>abstract:</b>  
In this paper we try to disprove the Riemann hypothesis.
  
   ]]> </description>
</item>
<item>
   <title><![CDATA[Using Finite Binomial Series to Prove Results in Prime Numbers and Congruences]]></title>
   <link>http://viXra.org/abs/2211.0003</link>
   <pubDate>2022-11-01 00:56:47 </pubDate>
   <category>Number Theory</category>
   <description> <![CDATA[
     <b>reference:</b> viXra:2211.0003v1<br/>
     <b>title:</b>     Using Finite Binomial Series to Prove Results in Prime Numbers and Congruences<br/>
     <b>authors:</b>   Shazly Abdullah<br/>
     <b>category:</b>  Number Theory<br/>
     <b>type:</b>      submission<br/>
     <b>date:</b>      2022-11-01 00:56:47 <br/>
     <b>abstract:</b>  
In this work used an algebraic method that uses elementary algebra and binomial theorem to create finite binomial series.This is a type of series that has several properties in variables. We used these series to prove results in congruences and prime numbers.
  
   ]]> </description>
</item>
<item>
   <title><![CDATA[The Overlook Effect]]></title>
   <link>http://viXra.org/abs/2211.0002</link>
   <pubDate>2022-11-01 00:44:15 </pubDate>
   <category>General Science and Philosophy</category>
   <description> <![CDATA[
     <b>reference:</b> viXra:2211.0002v1<br/>
     <b>title:</b>     The Overlook Effect<br/>
     <b>authors:</b>   Clark M. Thomas<br/>
     <b>category:</b>  General Science and Philosophy<br/>
     <b>type:</b>      submission<br/>
     <b>date:</b>      2022-11-01 00:44:15 <br/>
     <b>abstract:</b>  
Humans typically envision things parallel to wherethey are standing on the Earth. The overlook effect(OE) seems to be something out of the emergingspace age. However, it has been around as long asproto-humans first lived in trees. The OE is a keyaspect of general relativity, not related to speciousGeneral Relativity. Our survival depends partly onunderstanding the real OE in our modern world.
  
   ]]> </description>
</item>
<item>
   <title><![CDATA[Spacetime and Gravity Are 2D Around Planck Scales: a Universal Property of Consistent Quantum Gravity]]></title>
   <link>http://viXra.org/abs/2211.0001</link>
   <pubDate>2022-11-01 00:59:45 </pubDate>
   <category>Quantum Gravity and String Theory</category>
   <description> <![CDATA[
     <b>reference:</b> viXra:2211.0001v1<br/>
     <b>title:</b>     Spacetime and Gravity Are 2D Around Planck Scales: a Universal Property of Consistent Quantum Gravity<br/>
     <b>authors:</b>   Stephane H. Maes<br/>
     <b>category:</b>  Quantum Gravity and String Theory<br/>
     <b>type:</b>      submission<br/>
     <b>date:</b>      2022-11-01 00:59:45 <br/>
     <b>abstract:</b>  
This short paper shows that General Relativity (GR) combined with Quantum Physics implies spacetime and quantum gravity with 2D degrees of freedom at very small scales.The result is obtained independently of any other assumption on the underlying theory of quantum gravity other than the existence of quantum fluctuations, the formation of black holes if masses or energy sources are very high, and the properties of interactions with and among Black holes.Implications include universality of particles as microscopic black holes, asymptotic safety of quantum gravity for consistent theories and physical justifications, and hints of a physical justification for chirality of spacetime, and massive fermions/particles; something that will be exploited to explain the early universe, and the absence of GUTs in upcoming publications.
  
   ]]> </description>
</item>
<item>
   <title><![CDATA[Flat Rotation Curves of Spiral Galaxies]]></title>
   <link>http://viXra.org/abs/2210.0167</link>
   <pubDate>2022-10-31 11:44:37 </pubDate>
   <category>Astrophysics</category>
   <description> <![CDATA[
     <b>reference:</b> viXra:2210.0167v1<br/>
     <b>title:</b>     Flat Rotation Curves of Spiral Galaxies<br/>
     <b>authors:</b>   Stefan Bernhard Ruester<br/>
     <b>category:</b>  Astrophysics<br/>
     <b>type:</b>      submission<br/>
     <b>date:</b>      2022-10-31 11:44:37 <br/>
     <b>abstract:</b>  
In this article, a simple but quite accurate model conforming to observations and solving the modified Poisson equation is utilized in order to compute the rotation curves as well as the radial acceleration relations of spiral galaxies being composed of several components: the central region of the bulge, the bulge, the disk, and dark matter. With this model, flat rotation curves of spiral galaxies are obtained, because the modified Poisson equation approximately meets the requirement of conservation of total energy in Newton's theory of gravity, wherefore the model contains the exact circular speeds of test particles which are caused by the dark matter component of the respective considered spiral galaxies. The computed rotation curves are fitted to the observed speeds in spiral galaxies taken from SPARC. It turns out, that the simple model in this article is able to explain the observed flat rotation curves as well as the increasing rotation curves at large distances from the center of spiral galaxies with a very good accuracy.
  
   ]]> </description>
</item>
<item>
   <title><![CDATA[Hidden Premises in Galois Theory]]></title>
   <link>http://viXra.org/abs/2210.0166</link>
   <pubDate>2022-10-31 14:48:57 </pubDate>
   <category>Algebra</category>
   <description> <![CDATA[
     <b>reference:</b> viXra:2210.0166v1<br/>
     <b>title:</b>     Hidden Premises in Galois Theory<br/>
     <b>authors:</b>   Timothy W. Jones<br/>
     <b>category:</b>  Algebra<br/>
     <b>type:</b>      submission<br/>
     <b>date:</b>      2022-10-31 14:48:57 <br/>
     <b>abstract:</b>  
This is a primer for Chapter 3 of Hadlock's book Field Theory and Its Classical Problems: Solution by Radicals.  We take a rather naive perspective and consider the linear and quadratic cases afresh and evolve what is really met by solving a polynomial by radicals.  There are what we consider to be several hidden premises that some students might be subconsciously puzzled about.
  
   ]]> </description>
</item>
<item>
   <title><![CDATA[The Information as Absolute: Update]]></title>
   <link>http://viXra.org/abs/2210.0165</link>
   <pubDate>2022-10-31 01:01:39 </pubDate>
   <category>General Science and Philosophy</category>
   <description> <![CDATA[
     <b>reference:</b> viXra:2210.0165v1<br/>
     <b>title:</b>     The Information as Absolute: Update<br/>
     <b>authors:</b>   Sergey V. Shevchenko, Vladimir V. Tokarevsky<br/>
     <b>category:</b>  General Science and Philosophy<br/>
     <b>type:</b>      submission<br/>
     <b>date:</b>      2022-10-31 01:01:39 <br/>
     <b>abstract:</b>  
This article presents and grounds (i.e. presents proof of the existence, the truth, the self-consistence and the completeness of) the informational concept ("the Information as Absolute" concept) in philosophy and sciences, which was developing from 2007 year till now. The concept defines the Information as ultimately common, real and fundamental "absolute" phenomenon, which exists as absolutely infinite set ("Information" Set) of elements (members) and informational (e.g., logical) links between the elements; where any element itself is some informational structure also. Correspondingly, for example, Matter as the substance, radiation, etc., is some system of informational patterns, constituting a specific, and practically infinitesimal comparing to the Set, element "Matter" of the "Information" Set. The concept allows for the resolution, or at least for a consideration on a higher level of rational comprehension, of basic ontological and epistemological problems in philosophy and natural sciences; it clarifies basic fundamental notions such as space, time, energy, etc., and so is the fundamental base for real development of science
  
   ]]> </description>
</item>
<item>
   <title><![CDATA[Theorem on Second Digits in the Powers of n]]></title>
   <link>http://viXra.org/abs/2210.0164</link>
   <pubDate>2022-10-31 01:03:58 </pubDate>
   <category>Number Theory</category>
   <description> <![CDATA[
     <b>reference:</b> viXra:2210.0164v1<br/>
     <b>title:</b>     Theorem on Second Digits in the Powers of n<br/>
     <b>authors:</b>   Victor Sorokine<br/>
     <b>category:</b>  Number Theory<br/>
     <b>type:</b>      submission<br/>
     <b>date:</b>      2022-10-31 01:03:58 <br/>
     <b>abstract:</b>  
In a number system with a prime base n>2, among n-1 powers of dn (d=1, u2026 n-1) there is a number whose second (from the end of the number) digit is not equal to 0. (The key lemma in the simplest proof of Fermat's Last Theorem.)
  
   ]]> </description>
</item>
<item>
   <title><![CDATA[The Electromagnetic Field Strength and the Lorentz Force in Geometric Algebra Cl(3,0)]]></title>
   <link>http://viXra.org/abs/2210.0163</link>
   <pubDate>2022-10-30 18:17:35 </pubDate>
   <category>Classical Physics</category>
   <description> <![CDATA[
     <b>reference:</b> viXra:2210.0163v1<br/>
     <b>title:</b>     The Electromagnetic Field Strength and the Lorentz Force in Geometric Algebra Cl(3,0)<br/>
     <b>authors:</b>   Jes&#250;s S&#225;nchez<br/>
     <b>category:</b>  Classical Physics<br/>
     <b>type:</b>      submission<br/>
     <b>date:</b>      2022-10-30 18:17:35 <br/>
     <b>abstract:</b>  
In this paper, we will calculate the electromagnetic field strength and the Lorentz force in Geometric Algebra Cl(3,0). And we will compare it with their equivalent in the tensor covariant formalism. Leading to a one-to-one map in the four equations.Also, we will obtain another four extra equations that do not appear in the classical formalism, and we will explain its meaning. In the same way, we will expand the Electromagnetic field strength elements and the velocity multivector of the particle.This will lead to new equations and new elements appearing that will be explained. The most important one, is the Electromagnetic trivector Bxyz.Lastly, an insight of the possible implications in the Dirac Equation of these acquirements will be commented.
  
   ]]> </description>
</item>
<item>
   <title><![CDATA[Heat Energy Transfer to Space via Graphene: Heat Transfer Analysis]]></title>
   <link>http://viXra.org/abs/2210.0162</link>
   <pubDate>2022-10-31 01:06:05 </pubDate>
   <category>Thermodynamics and Energy</category>
   <description> <![CDATA[
     <b>reference:</b> viXra:2210.0162v1<br/>
     <b>title:</b>     Heat Energy Transfer to Space via Graphene: Heat Transfer Analysis<br/>
     <b>authors:</b>   Deepanker Shukla<br/>
     <b>category:</b>  Thermodynamics and Energy<br/>
     <b>type:</b>      submission<br/>
     <b>date:</b>      2022-10-31 01:06:05 <br/>
     <b>abstract:</b>  
The idea of transferring heat via graphene is analysed with respect to altitude in COMSOLMultiphysics and results have been documented in this paper.
  
   ]]> </description>
</item>
<item>
   <title><![CDATA[An [Attempt at] Refutation of General Relativity and Quantum Theories]]></title>
   <link>http://viXra.org/abs/2210.0161</link>
   <pubDate>2022-10-31 01:10:43 </pubDate>
   <category>Mathematical Physics</category>
   <description> <![CDATA[
     <b>reference:</b> viXra:2210.0161v1<br/>
     <b>title:</b>     An [Attempt at] Refutation of General Relativity and Quantum Theories<br/>
     <b>authors:</b>   Manfred U. E. Pohl<br/>
     <b>category:</b>  Mathematical Physics<br/>
     <b>type:</b>      submission<br/>
     <b>date:</b>      2022-10-31 01:10:43 <br/>
     <b>abstract:</b>  
It is briefly shown that all physical theories that fall back on a mathematical application of the circle number &#960; as an irrational dimensionless number are irrational and incorrect in their explanatory content, since they divide the physical dimensions of space (L) and time (T) into an incorrect and make an irrational connection.
  
   ]]> </description>
</item>
<item>
   <title><![CDATA[The Zero-dimensional Physical Theory (V): Information, Energy, Efficiency, and Intelligence]]></title>
   <link>http://viXra.org/abs/2210.0160</link>
   <pubDate>2022-10-31 01:12:19 </pubDate>
   <category>Mathematical Physics</category>
   <description> <![CDATA[
     <b>reference:</b> viXra:2210.0160v1<br/>
     <b>title:</b>     The Zero-dimensional Physical Theory (V): Information, Energy, Efficiency, and Intelligence<br/>
     <b>authors:</b>   Stephen H. Jarvis<br/>
     <b>category:</b>  Mathematical Physics<br/>
     <b>type:</b>      submission<br/>
     <b>date:</b>      2022-10-31 01:12:19 <br/>
     <b>abstract:</b>  
Proposed here is the case for a number theory derived from a mathematical description of zero-dimensional time (as a moment) and zero-dimensional space (as a point) as the underlying mathematical information base of physical phenomena. In support of this, the proposed zero-dimensional number theory is scaled with the charge of the electron and speed of light to translate into a physical theory confirming known mathematical descriptions of physical phenomena together with proposing new mathematical descriptions for physical phenomena that physics has yet to attain by its current mathematical approach. Specifically, examined here is how this process of physical theory formulation prescribes the contemporary ideas of information, energy, efficiency, and intelligence. By such, the modern scientific method is examined and found both problematic and limited in attempting to relate numbers and geometry directly to physical phenomena. Proposed here therefore is the case for the zero-dimensional number theory as the core mathematical information base of physical phenomena as per its indirect physical phenomenal route of mathematical and geometric execution.
  
   ]]> </description>
</item>
<item>
   <title><![CDATA[Tetravalent Logic in Mathematics and Physics]]></title>
   <link>http://viXra.org/abs/2210.0159</link>
   <pubDate>2022-10-31 01:36:24 </pubDate>
   <category>Mathematical Physics</category>
   <description> <![CDATA[
     <b>reference:</b> viXra:2210.0159v1<br/>
     <b>title:</b>     Tetravalent Logic in Mathematics and Physics<br/>
     <b>authors:</b>   S&#233;bastien Lablanche, G&#233;rard Lablanche<br/>
     <b>category:</b>  Mathematical Physics<br/>
     <b>type:</b>      submission<br/>
     <b>date:</b>      2022-10-31 01:36:24 <br/>
     <b>abstract:</b>  
In this work, we solve the main mathematical puzzles of the UMMO file which contains severalthousand postal letters sent since the 1960s addressing many fields such as philosophy, mathematics, human sciences, biology, cosmology, theoretical physics, among others. "The UMMO affair" refers to more than 200 listed documents, representing at least 1300 typed pages (the "Ummite letters"), which are said to have been sent since 1966 to numerous recipients, in particular in Spain and France by editors - the Ummites - claiming to be extraterrestrials on an observation mission on Earth and which have four centuries of technological advance on the terrestrial human technologies. We demonstrate the importance of angular tetravalent logic in mathematics and theorical physics. As an example, we give a proof of Fermat&#8217;s last theorem using angular tetravalent logic, as suggested by the Ummites. Then, we will pierce the secrets of the universe always using the tetravalent logic, we will explain the reasoning which proves the existence of a twin universe and we give the mathematical formula for the folding of space-time which separates the two twin universes and finally we explain why the curvature of the universe is necessarily negative.
  
   ]]> </description>
</item>
<item>
   <title><![CDATA[The Atypical Structural Connotational Accordance Between Letters And Words Consisting Of Them]]></title>
   <link>http://viXra.org/abs/2210.0158</link>
   <pubDate>2022-10-31 01:53:38 </pubDate>
   <category>General Science and Philosophy</category>
   <description> <![CDATA[
     <b>reference:</b> viXra:2210.0158v1<br/>
     <b>title:</b>     The Atypical Structural Connotational Accordance Between Letters And Words Consisting Of Them<br/>
     <b>authors:</b>   Andy Lockett<br/>
     <b>category:</b>  General Science and Philosophy<br/>
     <b>type:</b>      submission<br/>
     <b>date:</b>      2022-10-31 01:53:38 <br/>
     <b>abstract:</b>  
This is a strong piece which accommodates many ideas, those of faith, forms, destiny, ideals. It is advised you take anything written here with a grain of salt, for you should yourself see the prosperous infinity of the world we live in.
  
   ]]> </description>
</item>
<item>
   <title><![CDATA[Wiring of a Jaycar Null Model Cable: First Results]]></title>
   <link>http://viXra.org/abs/2210.0157</link>
   <pubDate>2022-10-30 01:08:28 </pubDate>
   <category>Classical Physics</category>
   <description> <![CDATA[
     <b>reference:</b> viXra:2210.0157v1<br/>
     <b>title:</b>     Wiring of a Jaycar Null Model Cable: First Results<br/>
     <b>authors:</b>   Sunny Daniels<br/>
     <b>category:</b>  Classical Physics<br/>
     <b>type:</b>      submission<br/>
     <b>date:</b>      2022-10-30 01:08:28 <br/>
     <b>abstract:</b>  
I completed the null modem cable testing apparatus that I described in https://vixra.org/abs/2208.0032 (for recovery of the old 1990s e-mails from Dr Michael Lennon: https://vixra.org/abs/2201.0097) and used it to attempt to discover the exact wiring of the null modem cable from Jaycar. It appears that I succeeded! My results are published here.  However, a word of warning: I have not checked these results thoroughly. I would like to re-check these in the near future. If readers think that any particular part of these results is wrong, PLEASE TELL ME!
  
   ]]> </description>
</item>
<item>
   <title><![CDATA[One-to-One Map of Dirac Equation Between Matrix Algebra and Geometric Algebra Cl(3,0)]]></title>
   <link>http://viXra.org/abs/2210.0156</link>
   <pubDate>2022-10-30 01:09:08 </pubDate>
   <category>Quantum Physics</category>
   <description> <![CDATA[
     <b>reference:</b> viXra:2210.0156v1<br/>
     <b>title:</b>     One-to-One Map of Dirac Equation Between Matrix Algebra and Geometric Algebra Cl(3,0)<br/>
     <b>authors:</b>   Jes&#250;s S&#225;nchez<br/>
     <b>category:</b>  Quantum Physics<br/>
     <b>type:</b>      submission<br/>
     <b>date:</b>      2022-10-30 01:09:08 <br/>
     <b>abstract:</b>  
In this paper, it is created a one-to-one map between the Dirac Equation in Matrix Algebra and the Dirac Equation in Geometric Algebra Cl(3,0). First, the Dirac Equation and the representation of the wavefunction in Geometric Algebra Cl(3,0) is obtained. The equivalent representation for standard Matrix Algebra is presented. And finally, a one-to-one mapping between both representations is obtained.
  
   ]]> </description>
</item>
<item>
   <title><![CDATA[Lecture Notes On Celestial Mechanics: Elements of Central Configuration For Undergraduate Students (Part I)]]></title>
   <link>http://viXra.org/abs/2210.0155</link>
   <pubDate>2022-10-30 01:10:36 </pubDate>
   <category>Classical Physics</category>
   <description> <![CDATA[
     <b>reference:</b> viXra:2210.0155v1<br/>
     <b>title:</b>     Lecture Notes On Celestial Mechanics: Elements of Central Configuration For Undergraduate Students (Part I)<br/>
     <b>authors:</b>   Abdelmajid Ben Hadj Salem, Richard Moeckel<br/>
     <b>category:</b>  Classical Physics<br/>
     <b>type:</b>      submission<br/>
     <b>date:</b>      2022-10-30 01:10:36 <br/>
     <b>abstract:</b>  
From the lectures for an advanced course on celestial mechanics  which Prof. Richard Moeckel gave in Trieste in 1994 on the topic - Central configurations of the n-body problem - that was one of his favorites, I have decided to develop a part of it as an introduction course for the undergraduate students where I have added more details (gray boxes) of the proofs to  be understood by undergraduate students.It is based on the handwritten notes from the 1994 Trieste course. Part I of the notes concerns 3 chapters :- chapter 1: introduction,- chapter 2: the two-body problem,- chapter 3: special solutions to the n body problem.
  
   ]]> </description>
</item>
<item>
   <title><![CDATA[The Hydrogen Atom Quantum Wave Function or Probability Density Graphs Match Exactly With the Shapes of the CMB, Black Hole Physics, Star Formation Rates and Many Other Macro Phenomenon Graphs]]></title>
   <link>http://viXra.org/abs/2210.0154</link>
   <pubDate>2022-10-30 01:11:45 </pubDate>
   <category>Quantum Physics</category>
   <description> <![CDATA[
     <b>reference:</b> viXra:2210.0154v1<br/>
     <b>title:</b>     The Hydrogen Atom Quantum Wave Function or Probability Density Graphs Match Exactly With the Shapes of the CMB, Black Hole Physics, Star Formation Rates and Many Other Macro Phenomenon Graphs<br/>
     <b>authors:</b>   Harsimran Singh Dhaliwal<br/>
     <b>category:</b>  Quantum Physics<br/>
     <b>type:</b>      submission<br/>
     <b>date:</b>      2022-10-30 01:11:45 <br/>
     <b>abstract:</b>  
Graphs of the hydrogen atom&#8217;s wave function or probability density were compared to observational data of cosmic macro phenomena such as photons orbits around black holes, black hole masses, LIGO detected gravitational waves, the CMB, quasars distributions , galaxy rotation curves, galaxy distributions, supernova events and numerous other cosmic graphs. There is an identical symmetry between graphs of cosmic macro phenomena and the graphs of the hydrogen wave function or its probability density. The hydrogen atom&#8217;s wave function or probability density describes macro phenomena, or macro phenomena describes hydrogen atom&#8217;s wave function or probability density, or both.
  
   ]]> </description>
</item>

   </channel>

</rss>

