<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns:yt="http://www.youtube.com/xml/schemas/2015" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
 <link rel="self" href="http://www.youtube.com/feeds/videos.xml?channel_id=UCkLHy_jxeaHTZCfGalg6QaA"/>
 <id>yt:channel:UCkLHy_jxeaHTZCfGalg6QaA</id>
 <yt:channelId>UCkLHy_jxeaHTZCfGalg6QaA</yt:channelId>
 <title>Conn Maciel Carey LLP</title>
 <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCkLHy_jxeaHTZCfGalg6QaA"/>
 <author>
  <name>Conn Maciel Carey LLP</name>
  <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCkLHy_jxeaHTZCfGalg6QaA</uri>
 </author>
 <published>2015-07-09T18:25:14+00:00</published>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:xDq7vBuJaOk</id>
  <yt:videoId>xDq7vBuJaOk</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCkLHy_jxeaHTZCfGalg6QaA</yt:channelId>
  <title>Preventing and Responding to Workplace Violence</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=xDq7vBuJaOk"/>
  <author>
   <name>Conn Maciel Carey LLP</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCkLHy_jxeaHTZCfGalg6QaA</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-10-14T14:28:22+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-10-15T13:25:23+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Preventing and Responding to Workplace Violence</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/xDq7vBuJaOk?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i1.ytimg.com/vi/xDq7vBuJaOk/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>In 2020, physical assault was identified as the 4th leading cause of workplace deaths. Nearly 2 million American workers experience violent acts at work annually. As the COVID-19 pandemic appears to be entering the endemic phase and workers begin to transition back into the workplace, experts predict even more of an increase in workplace violence. Thus, employers will want to be prepared to prevent these types of incidents and protect their employees to the extent possible, as well as ensure they are doing all that’s required from a regulatory standpoint.

Workplace violence has been a focus for both the Occupational Safety and Health Administration (“OSHA”) and the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission (“EEOC”) well before the pandemic and remains so now. While OSHA has no specific standard for workplace violence, the OSH Act's General Duty Clause requires employers to provide a workplace free from recognized serious hazards, and OSHA has instituted enforcement actions under its General Duty Clause after incidents of workplace violence. OSHA has also initiated a rulemaking to address workplace violence in specific industries. For its part, the EEOC has also prioritized ways to effectively prevent and address workplace violence, particularly in the form of workplace harassment. And outside of OSHA and the EEOC, employers can also be held liable for workplace violence through other claims such as negligent hiring and supervision.

In this webinar, attendees learned:

• What constitutes workplace violence
• EEOC and OSHA enforcement priorities related to workplace violence
• Best practices for workplace violence prevention
• Tips for responding to a workplace violence incident in your work environment

A webinar from Conn Maciel Carey LLP.

Use of this video does not in any manner constitute or establish an attorney-client relationship between Conn Maciel Carey and the viewer. This video may be deemed &quot;attorney advertising&quot; in jurisdictions from which it is accessed. The decision to hire a lawyer is a serious one and should be undertaken after consideration of all relevant information, not only information on this video.</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="3" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="115"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:w0USdlRVgVY</id>
  <yt:videoId>w0USdlRVgVY</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCkLHy_jxeaHTZCfGalg6QaA</yt:channelId>
  <title>How to Best Ensure ADA Compliance for Your Property’s Website</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=w0USdlRVgVY"/>
  <author>
   <name>Conn Maciel Carey LLP</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCkLHy_jxeaHTZCfGalg6QaA</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-09-23T17:03:38+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-09-25T09:39:00+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>How to Best Ensure ADA Compliance for Your Property’s Website</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/w0USdlRVgVY?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i4.ytimg.com/vi/w0USdlRVgVY/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>Another year has gone by, and yet the lawsuits filed against hotels and other places of public accommodation alleging violations of the Americans with Disabilities Act (“ADA”) continues to increase. We still see hundreds of lawsuits filed each month against hotels for their failure to identify and describe accessible features at their properties in sufficient detail on their websites. Many of these lawsuits continue to allege that Online Travel Agencies (“OTAs”) such Expedia, Hotels.com, or Orbitz fail to provide information about the accessible amenities of the hotel, including its rooms, to individuals with disabilities, or fail to allow an individual with a disability to book an accessible guestroom. While it may seem counterintuitive that a Hotel would be responsible for the information provided on the OTAs website, that often is the case.

A ton of ADA lawsuits also continue to be filed every day alleging that hotel websites cannot be used by individuals with visual or hearing impairments (in particular websites that utilize PDFs). Thus, it is extremely important that businesses ensure the accessibility of their websites while also providing an appropriate “accessibility statement” explaining to users the steps you have taken to improve your website’s accessibility.

During this webinar participants learned about:

• What accessible features to list on your website to reduce your legal exposure
• What questions to ask OTAs to ensure that they are not creating liability for your property
• Best practices for ensuring that your website is accessible
• Tips for drafting an appropriate website accessibility statement
• How to decrease your overall legal exposure

A webinar from Conn Maciel Carey LLP.

Use of this video does not in any manner constitute or establish an attorney-client relationship between Conn Maciel Carey and the viewer. This video may be deemed &quot;attorney advertising&quot; in jurisdictions from which it is accessed. The decision to hire a lawyer is a serious one and should be undertaken after consideration of all relevant information, not only information on this video.</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="0" average="0.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="42"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:mUrxtsKaqng</id>
  <yt:videoId>mUrxtsKaqng</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCkLHy_jxeaHTZCfGalg6QaA</yt:channelId>
  <title>The Importance of Injury and Illness Recordkeeping</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=mUrxtsKaqng"/>
  <author>
   <name>Conn Maciel Carey LLP</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCkLHy_jxeaHTZCfGalg6QaA</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-09-20T16:01:24+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-09-22T10:09:40+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>The Importance of Injury and Illness Recordkeeping</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/mUrxtsKaqng?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i2.ytimg.com/vi/mUrxtsKaqng/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>Although OSHA’s injury and illness recordkeeping and reporting rules may seem clear on their face, there are many nuances in the applicable standards that can create challenges to accurately making and maintaining those required records and reports. And the accuracy of injury and illness records could be becoming even more essential in light of the changes OSHA has proposed to the current e-recordkeeping rule, which would increase the availability and use of injury and illness data.

Already, e-recordkeeping data is collected by OSHA and used in developing and executing its Site-Specific Targeting (“SST”) Program based on an employer’s 300A Summary. Per the changes proposed in the current rulemaking effort, OSHA intends to expand who is required to submit recordkeeping data, what data is collected, and what data is shared with the public. This would result in more employers’ injury and illness data being under the microscope and incorporated into OSHA’s enforcement efforts. Indeed, as COVID-19 recordkeeping continues to drive up DART rates for a number of employers due to the need for COVID-19 positive employees to isolate, more may be pulled in OSHA’s SST Program. Thus, it is important for employers to understand the changes possibly to come in e-recordkeeping, as well as what those changes could mean in the context of evaluating and recording/reporting injuries and illnesses.

Participants in this webinar learned about:

• Why its more important than ever to get recordkeeping right
• Requirements for submission to OSHA under the current E-Recordkeeping Rule
• Enforcement efforts related to injury and illness recordkeeping
• Proposed changes to the E-Recordkeeping Rule and their impact
• Examples of recordkeeping challenges
• Evaluating cases of COVID-19 for recordability and reportability

A webinar from Conn Maciel Carey LLP.

Use of this video does not in any manner constitute or establish an attorney-client relationship between Conn Maciel Carey and the viewer. This video may be deemed &quot;attorney advertising&quot; in jurisdictions from which it is accessed. The decision to hire a lawyer is a serious one and should be undertaken after consideration of all relevant information, not only information on this video.</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="3" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="165"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:TfcRmX64Oo8</id>
  <yt:videoId>TfcRmX64Oo8</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCkLHy_jxeaHTZCfGalg6QaA</yt:channelId>
  <title>What Employers Need to Know About the Monkeypox Virus</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=TfcRmX64Oo8"/>
  <author>
   <name>Conn Maciel Carey LLP</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCkLHy_jxeaHTZCfGalg6QaA</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-09-07T18:46:18+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-10-27T09:56:20+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>What Employers Need to Know About the Monkeypox Virus</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/TfcRmX64Oo8?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i1.ytimg.com/vi/TfcRmX64Oo8/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>On July 23rd, the World Health Organization declared Monkeypox a Public Health Emergency of International Concern. By late July, the U.S. surpassed 10,000 total cases, and the Biden Administration declared it a public health emergency. While the Monkeypox Virus is less transmissible than COVID-19 and rarely fatal in its current form, there are still workplace safety and health considerations employers will have to address.

Participants in this webinar learned:

• Background about the Monkeypox Virus, including common symptoms and modes of transmission
• Strategies for employers to prevent workplace exposures while complying with Federal and State level labor employment laws
• Employee communication strategies about this latest public health crisis
• Potential OSHA recordkeeping and reporting obligations

A webinar from Conn Maciel Carey LLP.

Use of this video does not in any manner constitute or establish an attorney-client relationship between Conn Maciel Carey and the viewer. This video may be deemed &quot;attorney advertising&quot; in jurisdictions from which it is accessed. The decision to hire a lawyer is a serious one and should be undertaken after consideration of all relevant information, not only information on this video.</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="0" average="0.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="95"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:jLTsQt5wibQ</id>
  <yt:videoId>jLTsQt5wibQ</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCkLHy_jxeaHTZCfGalg6QaA</yt:channelId>
  <title>A Deep Dive Into Periodic Lockout/Tagout Inspections</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=jLTsQt5wibQ"/>
  <author>
   <name>Conn Maciel Carey LLP</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCkLHy_jxeaHTZCfGalg6QaA</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-08-19T14:14:53+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-10-29T20:07:12+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>A Deep Dive Into Periodic Lockout/Tagout Inspections</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/jLTsQt5wibQ?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i3.ytimg.com/vi/jLTsQt5wibQ/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>Year in and year out, OSHA’s Lockout/Tagout (Energy Control) standard is one of the most frequently cited standards. With the National Emphasis Program on Amputations continuing in 2022, employers are subject to inspections focusing on their LOTO programs and practices even if there are no serious injuries or complaints made about them. With increased scrutiny comes a greater risk of citations—particularly repeat violations—which can lead to employers being placed in OSHA’s Severe Violator Enforcement Program. Despite being such an important standard, OSHA’s LOTO rule continues to be one of the least understood. This webinar will take a deep dive into arguably one of the most confusing (not to mention, one of the most frequently cited) aspects of the LOTO rule – periodic inspections.

Participants in this webinar will learn about:

• OSHA’s enforcement of LOTO violations, including those around periodic inspections
• What the LOTO standard requires with respect to periodic inspections and how to conduct them in a manner that complies with the standard
• Common mistakes employers make regarding periodic LOTO inspections
• Compliance tips and best practices to help protect against Lockout/Tagout periodic inspection violations

A webinar from Conn Maciel Carey LLP.

Use of this video does not in any manner constitute or establish an attorney-client relationship between Conn Maciel Carey and the viewer. This video may be deemed &quot;attorney advertising&quot; in jurisdictions from which it is accessed. The decision to hire a lawyer is a serious one and should be undertaken after consideration of all relevant information, not only information on this video.</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="5" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="292"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:9I7NSMMhFmU</id>
  <yt:videoId>9I7NSMMhFmU</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCkLHy_jxeaHTZCfGalg6QaA</yt:channelId>
  <title>Wage &amp; Hour Best Practices</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9I7NSMMhFmU"/>
  <author>
   <name>Conn Maciel Carey LLP</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCkLHy_jxeaHTZCfGalg6QaA</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-08-18T12:23:10+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-09-08T06:49:19+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Wage &amp; Hour Best Practices</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/9I7NSMMhFmU?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i2.ytimg.com/vi/9I7NSMMhFmU/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>Presented by Ashley D. Mitchell, Megan S. Shaked, and Samuel S. Rose

Employers are subject to numerous federal and state laws governing employee wages, the hours of work for which an employee must be paid, and the frequency and duration of breaks an employee is entitled to during the workday. Wage and hour issues are further complicated by a shift to remote work during the pandemic. Even the best-intentioned employers could face a multimillion-dollar wage and hour class action. This webinar will give you a blueprint for best practices and common pitfalls to avoid and mitigate the risk of future wage and hour litigation.

Participants in this webinar will learn about:

• Independent contractor status, and the implications of misclassifying an employee as an independent contractor.
• Exempt vs. non-exempt employees including discussion of the “White Collar” exemptions
• State meal and rest period requirements
• Other wage and hour considerations such as the regular rate of pay for overtime purposes, off-the-clock work, and time and wage statement requirements
• Top legal considerations for employees working remotely
• Collective action trends including a discussion of California’s Private Attorneys General Act (PAGA), known as the “Bounty Hunter” statute, and why employers with a presence outside of California should take notice

A webinar from Conn Maciel Carey LLP.

Use of this video does not in any manner constitute or establish an attorney-client relationship between Conn Maciel Carey and the viewer. This video may be deemed &quot;attorney advertising&quot; in jurisdictions from which it is accessed. The decision to hire a lawyer is a serious one and should be undertaken after consideration of all relevant information, not only information on this video.</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="0" average="0.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="43"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:ujl0-YOenuc</id>
  <yt:videoId>ujl0-YOenuc</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCkLHy_jxeaHTZCfGalg6QaA</yt:channelId>
  <title>Appearance Discrimination Issues, the CROWN Act, and Unconscious Bias</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ujl0-YOenuc"/>
  <author>
   <name>Conn Maciel Carey LLP</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCkLHy_jxeaHTZCfGalg6QaA</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-07-22T13:40:30+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-10-21T20:37:36+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Appearance Discrimination Issues, the CROWN Act, and Unconscious Bias</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/ujl0-YOenuc?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i2.ytimg.com/vi/ujl0-YOenuc/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>Appearance-based discrimination occurs when someone is treated differently based on how they look. Although there is no federal law that prohibits “appearance discrimination” in employment, claims involving such issues are typically brought in the context of prohibited race, sex, or disability discrimination allegations. While there was a case several years ago that garnered a good deal of media attention involving a female bank employee who claimed she was told she was “too sexy” for her position, it is more common to encounter claims by women (and men) that they were treated less favorably than a coworker whom the boss found attractive. Obese workers have alleged that they were perceived as disabled because of their weight and employees who wear certain garments and/or jewelry as part of their religion have also filed claims of discrimination. Meanwhile, hairstyles and types are now on the cutting edge of fair employment law compliance.

For years, savvy employers recognized that there may be a need to accommodate certain religious beliefs pertaining to hairstyles, but a growing number of jurisdictions have passed or are considering laws that prohibit race-based hair discrimination such as the CROWN Act (“Creating a Respectful and Open World for Natural Hair”) which is focused on ending the denial of employment and educational opportunities because of hair texture or protective hairstyles including braids, locs, twists or bantu knots.

Participants in this webinar will learn:

• How the EEOC and other fair employment agencies evaluate appearance discrimination claims
• What proactive employers can and should do to avoid such claims
• Which states and local jurisdiction have passed or will likely soon pass CROWN Act laws
• How employers can create policies and procedures that address appearance discrimination
• Best practices for avoiding appearance discrimination claims

A webinar from Conn Maciel Carey LLP.

Use of this video does not in any manner constitute or establish an attorney-client relationship between Conn Maciel Carey and the viewer. This video may be deemed &quot;attorney advertising&quot; in jurisdictions from which it is accessed. The decision to hire a lawyer is a serious one and should be undertaken after consideration of all relevant information, not only information on this video.</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="2" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="108"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:GT7M6eQRIdQ</id>
  <yt:videoId>GT7M6eQRIdQ</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCkLHy_jxeaHTZCfGalg6QaA</yt:channelId>
  <title>OSHA and Climate Change (Heat Illness, Wildfire Smoke, and Super Storms)</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=GT7M6eQRIdQ"/>
  <author>
   <name>Conn Maciel Carey LLP</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCkLHy_jxeaHTZCfGalg6QaA</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-07-13T16:21:13+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-10-15T17:36:57+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>OSHA and Climate Change (Heat Illness, Wildfire Smoke, and Super Storms)</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/GT7M6eQRIdQ?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i4.ytimg.com/vi/GT7M6eQRIdQ/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>Recent studies show that workers are often the first to experience the effects of climate change and may be affected for longer durations and at greater intensities. NIOSH cites a 2014 study indicating that workers are “the canaries in the coal mine of climate change impacts.” Accordingly, OSHA has embarked on one of the broadest, most significant rulemakings it has undertaken in over a decade – to develop a comprehensive occupational standard to regulate heat illness associated with exposure to heat on the job – in outdoors as well as indoor settings.

A heat standard will impact scores of employers in every region of the country and may include requirements to provide conditioned air or increased building ventilation, shade tents, regular paid cool down rest periods, rigorous acclimatization periods, biological monitoring to ensure employees are not dehydrated or showing signs of heat stress, and even turn employers into the water police. The standard has become a top priority for the Biden Administration as part of their interagency effort to address climate change and the impact it is having on US worker populations, especially since most elements of the Administration’s climate agenda died with the unsuccessful Build Back Better legislation.

This webinar discussed OSHA’s heat illness rulemaking – its status, scope and what it may require – as well as the other significant steps OSHA is taking to address heat illness, including the emergent National Emphasis Program (NEP) on heat illness. The program also delved into other impacts of climate change on OSHA’s regulatory scheme, such as expectations around major storm preparation and response, as well as exposure to wildfire smoke.

A webinar from Conn Maciel Carey LLP.

Use of this video does not in any manner constitute or establish an attorney-client relationship between Conn Maciel Carey and the viewer. This video may be deemed &quot;attorney advertising&quot; in jurisdictions from which it is accessed. The decision to hire a lawyer is a serious one and should be undertaken after consideration of all relevant information, not only information on this video.</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="1" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="202"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:Hj9dyb9lKAU</id>
  <yt:videoId>Hj9dyb9lKAU</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCkLHy_jxeaHTZCfGalg6QaA</yt:channelId>
  <title>Evacuating the Workplace Exit Routes and Exit Doors</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Hj9dyb9lKAU"/>
  <author>
   <name>Conn Maciel Carey LLP</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCkLHy_jxeaHTZCfGalg6QaA</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-06-09T17:09:38+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-09-09T22:28:53+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Evacuating the Workplace Exit Routes and Exit Doors</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/Hj9dyb9lKAU?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i1.ytimg.com/vi/Hj9dyb9lKAU/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>Evacuating the workplace during an emergency is critical. However, consistently maintaining compliant exit access, routes, and doors in a busy workplace is often challenging, especially in warehouses, manufacturing facilities, and retail settings. OSHA routinely cites egress violations as Serious because of the potential for injury or death. It is an easy violation for inspectors to identify during on-site inspections, which often leads to the issuance of costly Repeat or Willful citations.

Temporary or permanent storage of materials can create several compliance issues related to OSHA’s egress requirements, but there are several ways to maintain compliant exit routes and doors and ensure that they are always accessible. Identifying and maintaining egress routes and exits is an important element of a workplace’s emergency action plan. Employers should carefully develop emergency action plans and ensure employees understand not only how to evacuate the workplace during an emergency but how to maintain proper egress routes and exits throughout their work shifts, as it provides employees with a safer workplace and may even save lives.

Participants in this webinar will learn about:

• OSHA enforcement history related to egress violations
• The requirements for egress, exits, and emergency lighting, including acceptable means of egress for occupants to safely exit a building, illumination requirements, and rules for markings and signage to guide occupants to the exits
• How to identify and address potential egress violations
• How to create an effective emergency action plan
• Tips to audit your workplace for compliance with 1910.36, 1910.37, and 1910.38

A webinar from Conn Maciel Carey LLP.

Use of this video does not in any manner constitute or establish an attorney-client relationship between Conn Maciel Carey and the viewer. This video may be deemed &quot;attorney advertising&quot; in jurisdictions from which it is accessed. The decision to hire a lawyer is a serious one and should be undertaken after consideration of all relevant information, not only information on this video.</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="12" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="356"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:Zxgynqqg45o</id>
  <yt:videoId>Zxgynqqg45o</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCkLHy_jxeaHTZCfGalg6QaA</yt:channelId>
  <title>A Chat with EEOC Commissioner Keith Sonderling: Artificial Intelligence in the Workforce</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Zxgynqqg45o"/>
  <author>
   <name>Conn Maciel Carey LLP</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCkLHy_jxeaHTZCfGalg6QaA</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-06-08T17:36:13+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-09-09T17:31:25+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>A Chat with EEOC Commissioner Keith Sonderling: Artificial Intelligence in the Workforce</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/Zxgynqqg45o?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i3.ytimg.com/vi/Zxgynqqg45o/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>On May 12, 2022, the EEOC issued a Technical Assistance (“TA”) document entitled, “The Americans with Disabilities Act (“ADA”) and the Use of Software, Algorithms, and Artificial Intelligence to Assess Job Applicants and Employees” focused on providing “clarity to the public regarding existing requirements” under the ADA and agency policy. This is the first guidance document the EEOC has issued regarding the use of Artificial Intelligence (“AI”) in employment decision-making since announcing its Al Initiative in October 2021.

It’s no secret that more employers have turned to AI to enhance their work processes over the years. An estimated 83% of employers have engaged AI or algorithmic tools to screen or assess applicants and workers, and some have even adopted a broad framework applicable to everything from resume scanners and “virtual assistants” or chatbots to video interviewing software and testing software that assess personality, aptitude, skills and perceived &quot;cultural fit.&quot; However, if employers are not careful, these tools could result in disability discrimination violating the ADA.

In this special event with EEOC Commissioner Sonderling, we facilitated a deep dive discussion covering:

• The impact of AI in the workplace
• How the COVID-19 Pandemic has accelerated digitization in our businesses
• Potential risks facing employers implementing algorithmic processes
• Recommended EEOC practices to reduce the likelihood of disability discrimination
• Workplace trends and issues facing employers in 2022 and beyond

A webinar from Conn Maciel Carey LLP.

Use of this video does not in any manner constitute or establish an attorney-client relationship between Conn Maciel Carey and the viewer. This video may be deemed &quot;attorney advertising&quot; in jurisdictions from which it is accessed. The decision to hire a lawyer is a serious one and should be undertaken after consideration of all relevant information, not only information on this video.</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="1" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="120"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:i6g5phaFwa4</id>
  <yt:videoId>i6g5phaFwa4</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCkLHy_jxeaHTZCfGalg6QaA</yt:channelId>
  <title>OSHA's Training Issues: Proof of Training, Language, and More</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=i6g5phaFwa4"/>
  <author>
   <name>Conn Maciel Carey LLP</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCkLHy_jxeaHTZCfGalg6QaA</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-05-31T21:09:48+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-09-08T10:52:45+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>OSHA's Training Issues: Proof of Training, Language, and More</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/i6g5phaFwa4?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i2.ytimg.com/vi/i6g5phaFwa4/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>To satisfy OSHA, workplace safety and health training must be more than a “check-the-box” exercise where a trainer stands in front of an audience, delivers a lecture, hands out a test and grades the answers. If your employees are not able to adequately explain or communicate the concepts covered in training when they are interviewed by an OSHA compliance officer, the agency will almost certainly conclude that the training was not effective and issue one or more citations. In other words, you do not comply with the applicable standards simply by delivering the training and/or sending a series of sign-in sheets to OSHA—you comply by providing effective training in a manner that is understood by your employees such that it can be applied and readily explained by them. If employees are not trained in a language and/or vocabulary they understand, they will almost certainly be unable to apply or explain what was presented to them.

During this webinar, participants will learn about:

• Notable training requirements found in key OSHA standards
• What compliant training generally looks like
• Types of citations an employer may receive for failing to properly train employees
• How lack of training can impact potential defenses to an OSHA citation
• Other ways inadequate training impacts the workplace
• Best practices to help employees grasp and retain information presented during training sessions

A webinar from Conn Maciel Carey LLP.

Use of this video does not in any manner constitute or establish an attorney-client relationship between Conn Maciel Carey and the viewer. This video may be deemed &quot;attorney advertising&quot; in jurisdictions from which it is accessed. The decision to hire a lawyer is a serious one and should be undertaken after consideration of all relevant information, not only information on this video.</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="7" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="628"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:483ntvfKmco</id>
  <yt:videoId>483ntvfKmco</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCkLHy_jxeaHTZCfGalg6QaA</yt:channelId>
  <title>Employment Law Update in D.C., MD, VA and Illinois</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=483ntvfKmco"/>
  <author>
   <name>Conn Maciel Carey LLP</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCkLHy_jxeaHTZCfGalg6QaA</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-05-25T13:49:50+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-08-24T15:35:19+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Employment Law Update in D.C., MD, VA and Illinois</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/483ntvfKmco?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i1.ytimg.com/vi/483ntvfKmco/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>​The District of Columbia, Maryland, and Virginia have enacted or are considering a host of changes that employers need to keep track of in 2022, including increases to the minimum wage and amendments to anti-discrimination laws. Maryland revised its Fair Employment Practices Act to extend the time period for filing a charge of discrimination alleging an unlawful employment practice other than harassment, introduced new requirements for employers to comply with when conducting mass layoffs, amended its leave laws to account for paid bereavement leave, and passed a law permitting employers to file for peace orders on behalf of an employee facing threats or acts of violence in the workplace. The District of Columbia passed a law banning non-compete agreements for almost all employees. Virginia amended its Overtime Wage Act, which now provides overtime protections for employees under state law and establishes a three-year statute of limitations. Virginia also added “disability” to the list of characteristics protected from discrimination under the Virginia Human Rights Act (VHRA), which came shortly after the VHRA was expanded last year to cover most Virginia employers.

Participants in this webinar will learn about:

• How to comply with D.C.’s new Non-Compete Ban
• Amendments to state anti-discrimination and wage and hour laws;
• Which policies and procedures should be reviewed and/or revised;
• Employment issues related to lawful use of marijuana; and
• Steps to comply with Maryland’s revised discrimination laws and Mini-WARN Act

A webinar from Conn Maciel Carey LLP.

Use of this video does not in any manner constitute or establish an attorney-client relationship between Conn Maciel Carey and the viewer. This video may be deemed &quot;attorney advertising&quot; in jurisdictions from which it is accessed. The decision to hire a lawyer is a serious one and should be undertaken after consideration of all relevant information, not only information on this video.</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="6" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="171"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:gzqkRXKT2uQ</id>
  <yt:videoId>gzqkRXKT2uQ</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCkLHy_jxeaHTZCfGalg6QaA</yt:channelId>
  <title>Employers Coalition to Work on OSHA’s Electronic Recordkeeping Rulemaking</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=gzqkRXKT2uQ"/>
  <author>
   <name>Conn Maciel Carey LLP</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCkLHy_jxeaHTZCfGalg6QaA</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-04-28T15:01:59+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-07-30T18:29:32+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Employers Coalition to Work on OSHA’s Electronic Recordkeeping Rulemaking</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/gzqkRXKT2uQ?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i4.ytimg.com/vi/gzqkRXKT2uQ/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>A webinar from Conn Maciel Carey LLP.

Use of this video does not in any manner constitute or establish an attorney-client relationship between Conn Maciel Carey and the viewer. This video may be deemed &quot;attorney advertising&quot; in jurisdictions from which it is accessed. The decision to hire a lawyer is a serious one and should be undertaken after consideration of all relevant information, not only information on this video.</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="6" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="147"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:Krg-8ZJZfe0</id>
  <yt:videoId>Krg-8ZJZfe0</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCkLHy_jxeaHTZCfGalg6QaA</yt:channelId>
  <title>Religious and Disability Accommodations</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Krg-8ZJZfe0"/>
  <author>
   <name>Conn Maciel Carey LLP</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCkLHy_jxeaHTZCfGalg6QaA</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-04-08T16:58:02+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-07-22T10:33:47+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Religious and Disability Accommodations</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/Krg-8ZJZfe0?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i4.ytimg.com/vi/Krg-8ZJZfe0/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>Employee requests for medical and/or religious accommodations in the workplace are not new. However, never before have these accommodation requests been such a hot-button topic, nor have these accommodation requests been used so frequently (and in particular, religious accommodation requests). The imposition of COVID-19 vaccine mandates has changed that, particularly with regard to religious accommodation requests, which has become the ultimate “gray area,” as both employers and employees alike have learned that sincerely held religious belief can include an employee's religious-based objection to vaccinations. As a result, the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission (“EEOC”) has issued guidance regarding the obligations of employers under Title VII when an employee presents with a religious objection to a mandatory COVID-19 vaccination policy, which actually builds upon prior EEOC guidance regarding COVID-19 vaccinations in the employment context. Thus, there are multiple issues that employers need to keep in mind and juggle when addressing these vaccination accommodation requests.

Participants in this webinar learned how to best deal with such requests by their employees, including:

• Tips for determining whether an employee has a sincerely held religious belief under Title VII or a disability under the ADA;
• How to legitimately assess whether the proposed accommodation poses a direct threat to your organization;
• Factors to understand as to whether the accommodation would be considered an “undue hardship;”
• Reminders on how to initiate and participate in the interactive process;
• Analysis of most recent EEOC guidance on this topic.

A webinar from Conn Maciel Carey LLP.

Use of this video does not in any manner constitute or establish an attorney-client relationship between Conn Maciel Carey and the viewer. This video may be deemed &quot;attorney advertising&quot; in jurisdictions from which it is accessed. The decision to hire a lawyer is a serious one and should be undertaken after consideration of all relevant information, not only information on this video.</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="11" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="451"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:GxjuX5bmifw</id>
  <yt:videoId>GxjuX5bmifw</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCkLHy_jxeaHTZCfGalg6QaA</yt:channelId>
  <title>New Employment Laws and Updates from the Dept of Labor Under a Biden Administration</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=GxjuX5bmifw"/>
  <author>
   <name>Conn Maciel Carey LLP</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCkLHy_jxeaHTZCfGalg6QaA</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-03-17T21:20:30+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-09-08T11:15:41+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>New Employment Laws and Updates from the Dept of Labor Under a Biden Administration</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/GxjuX5bmifw?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i4.ytimg.com/vi/GxjuX5bmifw/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>As we transitioned into the Biden Administration in January 2021, questions swirled about what the Department of Labor (“DOL”) would look like and predictions were made as to the issues and initiatives it would prioritize, as well as what would come of Trump-era DOL policies. Now, almost a year and a half into the President Biden’s term, we will review some of the most significant rulemakings and changes we have seen from the DOL under Biden. Though the Emergency Temporary Standards issued by the Occupational Safety and Health Administration generally took center stage, the DOL promulgated other significant and impactful regulations, particularly in the areas of tipped employees and joint employment.

Specifically, the DOL promulgated a rule that narrowed the standard for whom an employer can take a tip credit under the Fair Labor Standards Act, which had been significantly broadened by the DOL under Trump. It also rescinded a rule issued during the Trump Administration that more clearly defined and restricted when a company will be found to be a joint employer. We will also review what appears to be coming down the pipeline and make more predictions about what employers can expect from the Biden Administration’s DOL throughout the remainder of this presidential term.

Participants in this webinar will learn about:

• Biden Administration’s DOL Regulatory Agenda, including rulemaking and policy setting priorities
• New rules from the DOL and their impact on important issues like tip credits, tip pooling, and joint employment
• Enforcement initiatives and guidance from the DOL and its sub-agencies
• Predictions for the Department of Labor over the next 2.5 years

A webinar from Conn Maciel Carey LLP.

Use of this video does not in any manner constitute or establish an attorney-client relationship between Conn Maciel Carey and the viewer. This video may be deemed &quot;attorney advertising&quot; in jurisdictions from which it is accessed. The decision to hire a lawyer is a serious one and should be undertaken after consideration of all relevant information, not only information on this video.</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="6" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="408"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
</feed>
