<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<rdf:RDF
 xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
 xmlns="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/"
 xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
 xmlns:taxo="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/taxonomy/"
 xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
 xmlns:syn="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
 xmlns:admin="http://webns.net/mvcb/"
>

<channel rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/">
<title>stat.CO updates on arXiv.org</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">Statistics -- Computation (stat.CO) updates on the arXiv.org e-print archive</description>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:date>2022-11-03T20:30:00-05:00</dc:date>
<dc:publisher>help@arxiv.org</dc:publisher>
<dc:subject>Statistics -- Computation</dc:subject>
<syn:updateBase>1901-01-01T00:00+00:00</syn:updateBase>
<syn:updateFrequency>1</syn:updateFrequency>
<syn:updatePeriod>daily</syn:updatePeriod>
<items>
 <rdf:Seq>
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01429" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01492" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01591" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01746" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/abs/2205.04539" />
 </rdf:Seq>
</items>
<image rdf:resource="http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif" />
</channel>
<image rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif">
<title>arXiv.org</title>
<url>http://arxiv.org/icons/sfx.gif</url>
<link>http://arxiv.org/</link>
</image>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01429">
<title>Fast Bayesian estimation of brain activation with cortical surface fMRI data using EM. (arXiv:2211.01429v1 [stat.ME])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01429</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Task functional magnetic resonance imaging (fMRI) is a type of neuroimaging
data used to identify areas of the brain that activate during specific tasks or
stimuli. These data are conventionally modeled using a massive univariate
approach across all data locations, which ignores spatial dependence at the
cost of model power. We previously developed and validated a spatial Bayesian
model leveraging dependencies along the cortical surface of the brain in order
to improve accuracy and power. This model utilizes stochastic partial
differential equation spatial priors with sparse precision matrices to allow
for appropriate modeling of spatially-dependent activations seen in the
neuroimaging literature, resulting in substantial increases in model power. Our
original implementation relies on the computational efficiencies of the
integrated nested Laplace approximation (INLA) to overcome the computational
challenges of analyzing high-dimensional fMRI data while avoiding issues
associated with variational Bayes implementations. However, this requires
significant memory resources, extra software, and software licenses to run. In
this article, we develop an exact Bayesian analysis method for the general
linear model, employing an efficient expectation-maximization algorithm to find
maximum a posteriori estimates of task-based regressors on cortical surface
fMRI data. Through an extensive simulation study of cortical surface-based fMRI
data, we compare our proposed method to the existing INLA implementation, as
well as a conventional massive univariate approach employing ad-hoc spatial
smoothing. We also apply the method to task fMRI data from the Human Connectome
Project and show that our proposed implementation produces similar results to
the validated INLA implementation. Both the INLA and EM-based implementations
are available through our open-source BayesfMRI R package.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/stat/1/au:+Spencer_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Daniel A. Spencer&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/stat/1/au:+Bolin_D/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;David Bolin&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/stat/1/au:+Mejia_A/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Amanda F. Mejia&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01492">
<title>Fast, effective, and coherent time series modeling using the sparsity-ranked lasso. (arXiv:2211.01492v1 [stat.ME])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01492</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;The sparsity-ranked lasso (SRL) has been developed for model selection and
estimation in the presence of interactions and polynomials. The main tenet of
the SRL is that an algorithm should be more skeptical of higher-order
polynomials and interactions *a priori* compared to main effects, and hence the
inclusion of these more complex terms should require a higher level of
evidence. In time series, the same idea of ranked prior skepticism can be
applied to the possibly seasonal autoregressive (AR) structure of the series
during the model fitting process, becoming especially useful in settings with
uncertain or multiple modes of seasonality. The SRL can naturally incorporate
exogenous variables, with streamlined options for inference and/or feature
selection. The fitting process is quick even for large series with a
high-dimensional feature set. In this work, we discuss both the formulation of
this procedure and the software we have developed for its implementation via
the **srlTS** R package. We explore the performance of our SRL-based approach
in a novel application involving the autoregressive modeling of hourly
emergency room arrivals at the University of Iowa Hospitals and Clinics. We
find that the SRL is considerably faster than its competitors, while producing
more accurate predictions.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/stat/1/au:+Peterson_R/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Ryan Peterson&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/stat/1/au:+Cavanaugh_J/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Joseph Cavanaugh&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01591">
<title>A Bayesian Semiparametric Method For Estimating Causal Quantile Effects. (arXiv:2211.01591v1 [stat.ME])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01591</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Standard causal inference characterizes treatment effect through averages,
but the counterfactual distributions could be different in not only the central
tendency but also spread and shape. To provide a comprehensive evaluation of
treatment effects, we focus on estimating quantile treatment effects (QTEs).
Existing methods that invert a nonsmooth estimator of the cumulative
distribution functions forbid inference on probability density functions
(PDFs), but PDFs can reveal more nuanced characteristics of the counterfactual
distributions. We adopt a semiparametric conditional distribution regression
model that allows inference on any functionals of counterfactual distributions,
including PDFs and multiple QTEs. To account for the observational nature of
the data and ensure an efficient model, we adjust for a double balancing score
that augments the propensity score with individual covariates. We provide a
Bayesian estimation framework that appropriately propagates modeling
uncertainty. We show via simulations that the use of double balancing score for
confounding adjustment improves performance over adjusting for any single score
alone, and the proposed semiparametric model estimates QTEs more accurately
than other semiparametric methods. We apply the proposed method to the North
Carolina birth weight dataset to analyze the effect of maternal smoking on
infant&apos;s birth weight.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/stat/1/au:+Xu_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Steven G. Xu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/stat/1/au:+Yang_S/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Shu Yang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/stat/1/au:+Reich_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Brian J. Reich&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01746">
<title>Log-density gradient covariance and automatic metric tensors for Riemann manifold Monte Carlo methods. (arXiv:2211.01746v1 [stat.CO])</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01746</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;A metric tensor for Riemann manifold Monte Carlo particularly suited for
non-linear Bayesian hierarchical models is proposed. The metric tensor is built
from here proposed symmetric positive semidefinite log-density gradient
covariance (LGC) matrices. The LGCs measure the joint information content and
dependence structure of both a random variable and the parameters of said
variable. The proposed methodology is highly automatic and allows for
exploitation of any sparsity associated with the model in question. When
implemented in conjunction with a Riemann manifold variant of the recently
proposed numerical generalized randomized Hamiltonian Monte Carlo processes,
the proposed methodology is highly competitive, in particular for the more
challenging target distributions associated with Bayesian hierarchical models.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/stat/1/au:+Kleppe_T/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Tore Selland Kleppe&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://arxiv.org/abs/2205.04539">
<title>Efficient algorithms for building representative matched pairs with enhanced generalizability. (arXiv:2205.04539v2 [stat.ME] UPDATED)</title>
<link>http://arxiv.org/abs/2205.04539</link>
<description rdf:parseType="Literal">&lt;p&gt;Many recent efforts center on assessing the ability of real-world evidence
(RWE) generated from non-randomized, observational data to produce results
compatible with those from randomized controlled trials (RCTs). One noticeable
endeavor is the RCT DUPLICATE initiative (Franklin et al., 2020, 2021). To
better reconcile findings from an observational study and an RCT, or two
observational studies based on different databases, it is desirable to
eliminate differences between study populations. We outline an efficient,
network-flow-based statistical matching algorithm that designs well-matched
pairs from observational data that resemble the covariate distributions of a
target population, for instance, the target-RCT-eligible population in the RCT
DUPLICATE initiative studies or a generic population of scientific interest. We
demonstrate the usefulness of the method by revisiting the inconsistency
regarding a cardioprotective effect of the hormone replacement therapy (HRT) in
the Women&apos;s Health Initiative (WHI) clinical trial and corresponding
observational study. We found that the discrepancy between the trial and
observational study persisted in a design that adjusted for study populations&apos;
cardiovascular risk profile, but seemed to disappear in a study design that
further adjusted for the HRT initiation age and previous
estrogen-plus-progestin use. The proposed method is integrated into the R
package match2C.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
<dc:creator> &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/find/stat/1/au:+Zhang_B/0/1/0/all/0/1&quot;&gt;Bo Zhang&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
</item>
</rdf:RDF>